<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000220" url="http://www.liquidcalories.com/qa.htm" time="2012-07-12-15:24" support="5" score="0.007098332080641511" bingtitle="WHAT AM I EATING - McDonald&apos;s 30-day Diet" webtitle="WHAT AM I EATING">
			<query id="000365" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="000458" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000961" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="001118" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="000867" bing-rank="47"/>
	<description>I try and get a receipt with the meals. Q. But, anyone ... If that is true and everything you say you eat is ... I could achieve the same results at any fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		HOW CAN I
KNOW YOUR CLAIMS ARE VALID? 

   

 Questions
and Answers 

   

 Q. How did the project start? 

   

 A. Good question. Allow me to explain. At 5:44am, Friday, March 26 th ,
I woke up and proceeded to weigh-in, get taped, and head out for my first meal
at McDonalds. I try and get a receipt with the meals. 

   

   

 Q. But, anyone can claim they are doing
thisI mean, you can buy the meals and throw them awaya receipt is not proof. 

   

 A. Introduce the video camera. It doesnt lie. 

   

   

 Q. Yeah, but anyone can tape
anythinghow do you document the date and time? Those can be set to anytime. 

   

 A. I use my Sprint PCS phone. The time and date are satellite controlled. I
cant set that! I display this information at every meal. 

   

   

 Q. But , you mean you tape you getting the meals,
but that doesnt prove anything. You can still throw them away! 

   

 A. Oh no, the video doesnt stop rolling thereI film the whole thingyep,
me eating everything I order for myself! 

   

   

 Q. Filming a couple of meals still isnt
proof that you eat EVERY meal, right? 

   

 A. Wrongevery meal, every fry, in my belly and caught on tape! 

   

   

 Q. If that is true and everything you
say you eat is true and your weight claims are valid, then you must be throwing
up your food after the camera stops rolling, right? 

   

 A. Hmmmm good point. Never thought
of thatyeah right! Any doctor could examine me for
thattrust me, I aint throwin up any food I pay for! 

   

   

 Q. If you arent barfing your meals, then you must be exercising your butt off!!! 

   

 A. My exercise routine is posted on the weband the log is accurate! This is
not filmed, but can be verified by other individuals. 

   

   

 Q. Why did you pick McDonalds? Why not
Burger King or Wendys? 

   

 A. I chose McDonalds because the movie was based on McDonalds food. If I
would have chosen Burger King, and lost weight and
became healthier, then the impression would be that Burger King is healthier. I
could achieve the same results at any fast food restaurant. 

   

   

 Q. Your project goes against everything
I have been told about fast food, you are just the
exception to the rule! 

   

 A. I believe this could happen to many people. Maybe even you! 

   

   

   

 Woody
	</body>
</document>
