<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000007" url="http://muppet.wikia.com/wiki/Sesame_Street_Video_Player:_Classic_Clips" time="2012-07-12-15:11" support="7" score="0.0083084674790509" bingtitle="Sesame Street Video Player: Classic Clips - Muppet Wiki" webtitle="Sesame Street Video Player: Classic Clips - Muppet Wiki">
			<query id="000379" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="001426" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="001434" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="001421" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000786" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="001414" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="000651" bing-rank="122"/>
	<description>Grover’s Fast Food Restaurant – A customer orders some ... I Love Trash” – Oscar sings about the garbage ... 3 – Painter paints the number 3 with condiments.</description>
	<body>
		Wikia
 Skip to Content Skip to Wiki Navigation Skip to Site Navigation 
Wikia Navigation

 Start a wiki 
 Video Games 
 What&apos;s Hot 
 Batman: Fire Rises Super Mario Bros. U Halo 4 Anarchy Reigns More... 
 Fall&apos;s Finest 
 Far Cry 3 Borderlands 2 Assassin&apos;s Creed III Resident Evil 6 More... 
 Game Guides 
 Skyrim Mass Effect 3 Infinity Blade 2 Kingdoms of Amalur: Reckoning More... 
 Spec Ops: The Line 
 Walkthrough Martin Walker Delta Force The Exiles More Spec Ops... 
 
 Entertainment 
 What&apos;s Trending 
 Comic-Con Wikia Book Club Summer Animé Guide Fall TV Schedule More... 
 Movies 
 The Amazing Spider-Man Prometheus Brave Savages More... 
 TV 
 Dallas Breaking Bad Falling Skies Weeds More... 
 Music 
 Aerosmith on Tour Summer Albums Guide Carly Rae Jepsen Katy Perry More... 
 
 Lifestyle 
 Body 
 BBQ Recipes Athlepedia Healthy Recipes Nail Color More... 
 Mind 
 Space Travel Human Science How-To Liberapedia More... 
 Soul 
 Art Toys Gardening Travel More... 
 Of Note 
 2012 Olympics Literature Tea Alternative History More... 
 
 
 
 
 Log in Username Password Forgot your password? Stay logged in Or Connect Sign up 
 
 
 
Navigation

 Random Muppet The Muppets  
 The Muppets (2011) Kermit the Frog Miss Piggy Fozzie Bear Animal More characters Episode guide 
 Sesame Street  
 Elmo Ernie and Bert Cookie Monster Mr. Snuffleupagus Oscar the Grouch More characters Episode guide 
 Community  
 Current Events Recent Discussions New Images New Pages About Us 
 
 Random Page Wiki Activity Watchlist Recent changes 
 16 Talk 

Sesame Street Video Player: Classic Clips
 Edit 
 History 
 Added by MuppetDude 
The following is a list of videos currently available at Sesamestreet.org for viewing in their &quot;Videos&quot; section that are labeled as &quot;classic&quot; segments (before the 25th season ).
 -- Classic videos are given this label, though some currently do not.
See also Sesame Street Video Player: Current Clips .

 
Contents
 
 1 Symbols 2 # 3 A 4 B 5 C 6 D 7 E 8 F 9 G 10 H 11 I 12 J 13 K 14 L 15 M 16 N 17 O 18 P 19 Q 20 R 21 S 22 T 23 U 24 V 25 W 26 X 27 Y 28 Z 
 

 Symbols 

 ”cold” With Linda And Luis – Linda and Luis build the word ‘cold’. ( SSvideo ) 

 # 

 1-10: Hat Rack – Kids count hats as they appear on a rack. ( SSvideo ) 1-5 Counting Zoo Animals – Zoo animals are counted in this song. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) 10-1 Russian Dolls – Ten nesting dolls become one nesting doll. (animation) ( SSvideo ) 10: Computer – A strange face counts 10 objects. ( SSvideo ) 10: Pinball Animation – A counting pinball game focuses on “10.” ( SSvideo ) 11: Pinball Animation – A counting pinball game focuses on “11.” ( SSvideo ) 12 Cans Stacked In A Store – A man stacks 12 cans in a display. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) 12: Pinball Animation – A counting pinball game focuses on “12.” ( SSvideo ) 2, 3, 4 Art Gallery – Biff labels paintings in an art gallery. ( SSvideo ) 2: Letters Kissing – The letters in “beso” kiss each other. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) 2: The Mad Painter – A painter paints a “2” on a sailboat. ( SSvideo ) 2: Pinball Animation – A counting pinball game focuses on “2.” ( SSvideo ) 3: Pinball Animation – A counting pinball game focuses on “3.” ( SSvideo ) 39 Stairs – A Monsterpiece Theater presentation. (w/ Grover ) ( SSvideo ) 4: Kids On A Mat – The Count counts 4 kids as they roll in. ( SSvideo ) 4: Pinball Animation – A counting pinball game focuses on “4.” ( SSvideo ) 5: Beat The Game Show – Grover has one minute to find five dairy items. (w/ Guy Smiley ) ( SSvideo ) 5: Police&amp;Fire Fighter – Kids dressed up as firefighters and police. ( Three of These Kids ) ( SSvideo ) 5: Starfish&amp;Eels – A singing fish loves the number five. ( SSvideo ) 6 Dots – 6 dots are shown arranged in many ways. (animation) ( SSvideo ) 6: Pinball Animation – A counting pinball game focuses on “6.” ( SSvideo ) 6: Umbrellas – One of the kids in the rain is getting wet! ( Three of These Kids ) ( SSvideo ) 7 Fish With Elmo – Elmo tap dances around seven goldfish. ( SSvideo ) 7: Pinball Animation – A counting pinball game focuses on “7.” ( SSvideo ) 8: The Mad Painter – A bald head is a good canvas for the number 8. ( SSvideo ) 8: Pinball Animation – A counting pinball game focuses on “8.” ( SSvideo ) 9: Bumble Ardy – A rhyming story about Bumble’s birthday. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) 9: Counting People – Nine people hold still so you can count them. (w/ Maria , Luis , David , and kids) ( SSvideo ) 9: Martian Beauty – A Martian beauty has 9 of each body part. ( SSvideo ) 9: Pinball Animation – A counting pinball game focuses on “9.” ( SSvideo ) 

 A 

 &quot; Abcs Of The Swamp &quot; - Kermit sings the alphabet in the swamp. ( SSvideo ) A And The Small Story – Animated story about small a and “a” words. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) A Bee At Work – A bee collects pollen from flowers. (film) ( SSvideo ) A Boy And Cart -- A boy and father think of how to make a cart. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ A Boy From Indiana ” – Bob sings about a boy growing up. ( SSvideo ) A Clown Removes His Makeup – A man shows the parts of his clown face. (film) ( SSvideo ) A Dog As Bird – What if a dog had a beak and feathers? (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) A Dull Day -- A detective exercises on his day off. (cartoon) A Fly In My Soup -- Grover&apos;s customer has a fly in his soup. ( SSvideo ) A Happy Dog - A dog is happy to get a treat. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) A Mouse Remembers -- A mouse remembers where he left his pet. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) A Piece Of Cake -- Ernie&apos;s far-fetched cake story comes true. (w/ Bert and Beautiful Day Monster ) ( SSvideo ) &quot; A Pig&apos;s Love Song &quot; -- A pig loves being a pig. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) A Sad State – The Cosby Kids talk about different feelings. (w/ Telly , Malcolm-Jamal Warner , Lisa Bonet , Tempestt Bledsoe , Keshia Knight Pulliam ) ( SSvideo ) &quot; A Song From Kermit &quot; -- Kermit sings a song to wish you well. ( SSvideo ) A Terrible Interview - Candice Bergen interviews Oscar. ( SSvideo ) A Words – Lots of words begin with the letter “A.” (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) A: Airplane – A talking typewriter types ‘a’ for airplane. ( SSvideo ) A: Alligator – Alligator begins with the letter A. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) A: Debo, Kermit and Grover – Debo knows that this is the letter ‘A.&apos; ( SSvideo ) A: Maestro – A maestro asks for notes and gets an “A.” (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) A: The Fonz – Fonzie pronounces the letter ‘A.’ ( SSvideo ) ” Abierto ” – Everything in this house is open! (w/ Maria and Anything Muppets ) ( SSvideo ) Abierto And Cerrado -- Luis opens and closes the Fix-It Shop . (w/ Bob and Susan ) ( SSvideo ) Abierto Cerrado – A box demonstrates two Spanish words. (cartoon w/ added music and sound effects) ( SSvideo ) Above/Below – Bud the Bird loves to go above and below. (animation) ( SSvideo ) ” Above It All Song ” – A song about “above” and “below.” (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Adding And Subtracting – Bob, Maria and Susan add and subtract. ( SSvideo ) ” Adding Is Putting Together ” – Adding and subtracting cookies. (w/ Cookie Monster ) ( SSvideo ) Adding To Five – Bert , Ernie and Shala add with their fingers. ( SSvideo ) ” African Alphabet ” – Kermit and a Zulu tribe sing an alphabet song. ( SSvideo ) African Animals – Kids talk about wild animals and what they do. (film) ( SSvideo ) African Numbers 1-20 -- Counting from 1 to 20. (animation) ( SSvideo ) After A Bath With Bert&amp;Ernie – Ernie forgets an important bathtime step. ( SSvideo ) Agua – “Agua” means “water” in Spanish. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Ailey Dance Class With Robert -- Robert takes a dance class. (film) &quot; Air! &quot; – A man sings about air and breathing. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Airplane Propeller – Two pilots work together to start an airplane. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Ake Words – 5 words in the –ake family. (animation) ( SSvideo ) All About Water – A musical video shows water in many forms. (film) ( SSvideo ) ” All Dressed Up ” – Bert dresses warm for the winter. (w/ Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Alice in Wonderland - Kermit reports on Alice in Wonderland. Alice Explores Olivia -- Alice explores Sesame Street to find Olivia. (w/ Mr. Snuffleupagus and Uncle Wally ) ( SSvideo ) Alligator King&amp;His 7 Sons -- Which alligator son will win the crown? (cartoon) ” Alone Song ” – Sometimes it’s nice to play all by yourself. (film) ( SSvideo ) Alphabet Chat : Letter B – Mr. Chattaly interviews Mr. Bull about ‘B.’ ( SSvideo ) Alphabet Chat: Letter H – Mr. Chattaly interviews a hare about ‘H.’ (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Alphabet Chat: Letter O -- Mr. Chattaly talks about the letter O. Alphabet Conversation – Two kids say the alphabet. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Alphabet Secret – Monsters pass along the alphabet as a secret. (w/ Herry Monster and Grover) ( SSvideo ) Amazing Mumford: Pineapples -- The Amazing Mumford&apos;s pineapples disappear. (w/ Grover) ( SSvideo ) American Indian Beads -- Some Native American words are easy to learn. (animation) ( SSvideo ) Amor - Love with Cookie Monster. ( SSvideo ) An Automobile Factory – Kids narrate video of a taxi being made. (film) ( SSvideo ) An Elephant Counts To 20 -- An elephant counts to twenty. (cartoon by Owe Gustafson ) ( SSvideo ) &quot; An Old Lady Who Swallowed A Fly &quot; - José Feliciano sings an old song. Angry Annie -- Annie learns to share. (animation w/ added sound effects and music) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Animal Babies &quot; -- Learn the names for different animal babies! ( SSvideo ) Animal Charades – Kids take turns pretending to be animals. (w/ Big Bird and David) ( SSvideo ) ” Animal Elevator Song ” – Count the animals as they board an elevator. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) ” Animal Hospital Song ” – Children take pets to an animal doctor. (film) ( SSvideo ) Animal Houses – Animals live in different kinds of homes. (film) ( SSvideo ) Animal Nods Head – An antelope nods his head ‘yes.’ (film) ( SSvideo ) Animal Riddle: Fish -- Whitman Mayo gives hints about an animal. ( SSvideo ) Animal Soup Alphabet – An animal for every letter of the alphabet. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Animals Eat Raw Vegetables – Animated animals all eat crunchy foods. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Annette Bening : Here And There -- Annette and Cookie Monster show here&amp;there. ( SSvideo ) Answer Lady&amp;The Two Kittens – The Answer Lady can’t tell her kittens apart. ( SSvideo ) Ant Hill Cooperation – Ants work together to finish the ant hill. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) ” Antarctica! ” – Muppets sing about the cold continent. (w/ Wolfgang the Seal and Penguins ) ( SSvideo ) Ants March To A Bakery – Ants rush to a bakery only to find it closed. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Anything In The World -- Oscar answers game show questions. (w/ Guy Smiley) ( SSvideo ) Apes At Play – Apes play at the zoo. (film; 1969 version) ( SSvideo ) Apple Indecision – A man can’t decide how many apples he needs. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Apple Raisin Walnut Cookies -- Cookie Monster and Ernie bake cookies. ( SSvideo ) Apple Riddle – A riddle about an apple. (animation) ( SSvideo ) &quot;Apple, Orange, And Pear Song&quot; -- Fruits dance together, despite differences. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Aristotle Makes Lunch -- Aristotle helps David make lunch. ( SSvideo ) Arthur Ashe Does The Alphabet – Kids shout letters as Arthur Ashe practices. ( SSvideo ) Astronaut Drawing – Kids direct how to draw an astronaut. ( Today&apos;s Secret Drawing ) ( SSvideo ) ” At School ” – Kids rap about things that happen at school. (film/animation) ( SSvideo ) At The Coastline - The land and the ocean meet at the coast. (animation) Attention: Body Parts – A film that points out the parts of the body. (animation) ( SSvideo ) Autum To Winter (film) -- ( SSvideo ) 

 B 

 &quot; B Is For Bubble &quot; -- Kids chew bubblegum and blow bubbles. (original version) ( SSvideo ) B: Ball – A talking typewriter types ‘b’ for ball. ( SSvideo ) B: Beard – The word ‘beard’ begins with the ‘buh’ sound. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) B: Bug – The word ‘bug’ begins with the letter ‘b.’ (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) B: Bus – Kids sound out ‘bus’ on a bus. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) B: Jack And The B Stalk – Jack climbs a b-stalk to the land of “b.” (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Baby Steps – A baby learns to walk. (film) ( SSvideo ) Baby Eats Cookie - A baby messily eats a cookie. (w/ Cookie Monster voice-over) Baby’s First Honk – Honkers teach a baby how to honk. ( SSvideo ) Back&amp;Front With Grover – Grover has trouble showing “front” and “back.” (w/ sound effects added) ( SSvideo ) Back&amp;Front With Herry – Herry and some kids demonstrate back/front. ( SSvideo ) Back And Front: Horsing Around – The front of the horse can’t follow the back. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Back And Front: Turtle&amp;Bird – A bird and a turtle show “front” and “back.” (cartoon w/ added sound effects) ( SSvideo ) Backscratching Apes – Two apes scratch each other’s backs. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Backwards Forwards Skating -- Skating backwards and forwards. (film) Bad Bart -pays Bartender – The bartender gets what’s coming to him. (w/ Clementine ) ( SSvideo ) Bad Luck To Be Born A Duck -- A duck learns to be proud of who he is. (w/ Roosevelt Franklin ) ( SSvideo ) Baker #1 - The number one! ( SSvideo ) Baker Number 10 – Let’s sing a song of 10. ( SSvideo ) Baker #2 - Counting to the number 2. ( SSvideo ) Baker Number 3 – Counting things in groups of three. ( SSvideo ) Baker #4 - Counting to the number 4. ( SSvideo ) Baker Number 5 – Counting things in groups of five. (edited version) ( SSvideo ) Baker #6 - Counting to the number 6. ( SSvideo ) Baker Number 7 -- Counting things in groups of seven. ( SSvideo ) Baker #8 - Counting to the number 8. ( SSvideo ) Baker #9 - Counting to the number nine. (w/ Rowlf the Dog ) ( SSvideo ) Ball Fall – A man learns a word that rhymes with ‘ball.’ (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Ball Powder Number 3 – An elaborate track for the number 3. ( SSvideo ) ” Ballad of Casey Macphee ” – Cookie Monster drives a train through snow. ( SSvideo ) Ballet Between – Luis, Maria and David dance ballet. ( SSvideo ) Banana In Ernie’s Ear – Bert tells Ernie he has a banana in his ear. ( SSvideo ) Banana In Ernie’s Ear Part 2 – Ernie pulls a joke on Bert. ( SSvideo ) ” Barn In The USA ” – Animals in the barn make different sounds. (w/ Bruce Stringbean ) ( SSvideo ) Baseball And Football – One of these kids is doing a different sport. ( SSvideo ) Basketball And Baseball – One of these kids is doing a different sport. ( SSvideo ) Bathtub Water Comes From Rain – Water down the drain later becomes rain. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Batty Bat &quot; – The Count does a dance he leared as a boy. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Be With Me &quot; – Carly Simon sings about friendship. (w/ Telly Monster ) ( SSvideo ) Bears Doing Exercises -- Kermit leads bears at the zoo in exercises. ( SSvideo ) Beat The Time : From The Sky – The Count has 20 seconds to do a task. (w/ Guy Smiley) ( SSvideo ) Before And After Circus – Luis and Linda demonstrate before and after. (ending cut off) ( SSvideo ) ” Beginning Middle End Song ” – Every story has a beginning, middle, and end. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Beginning, Middle&amp;End Story – Beginning&amp;End tell their parts of a story. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) ” Beginning, Middle, End ” – A monster sings the three parts of his song. (w/ Maurice Monster ) ( SSvideo ) Being Five Years Old – Kids show things a five year old can do. (film) ( SSvideo ) Bellhop : 10 Terriers – A bellhop takes ten terriers for a walk. ( SSvideo ) Bert – Bert asks Ernie to clean up his things . (originally titled “Bert And Ernie Clean Up I”) ( SSvideo ) Bert – Ernie’s cleaning makes a mess for Bert. (originally titled “Bert And Ernie Clean Up II”) ( SSvideo ) Bert&amp;Ernie At The Beach – Ernie only brings one thing to the beach. ( SSvideo ) Bert&amp;Ernie At The Movies – A tall hat blocks Ernie’s view of the screen. ( SSvideo ) Bert&amp;Ernie Go To Egypt -- Bert&amp;Ernie visit a mysterious pyramid! ( SSvideo ) Bert&amp;Ernie Plan A Bath – Ernie needs strange items for his bath. ( SSvideo ) Bert&amp;Ernie Play Drums – Ernie plays drums and Bert plays front door. ( SSvideo ) Bert&amp;Ernie Pretend – Bert and Ernie play a sound guessing game. ( SSvideo ) Bert&amp;Ernie Show More&amp;Less – Ernie has more pizza and juice than Bert. ( SSvideo ) Bert&amp;Ernie Watch TV -- Bert and Ernie each want to sit on the chair. (w/ Herry; ending is cut off) ( SSvideo ) Bert And Ernie&apos;s Rhyming Game -- Bert and Ernie play a rhyming game. ( SSvideo ) Bert&amp;Ernie&apos;s Special Day -- Ernie decorates for a special visitor. ( SSvideo ) Bert And Ernie: Basketball – Ernie forgets to put his basketball away. ( SSvideo ) Bert And Ernie: Jump – Bert and Ernie exercise and jump up and down. ( SSvideo ) Bert Almost Shops For Dinner – Bert gets locked out of the apartment. (w/ Ernie) ( SSvideo ) Bert And Ernie Blow A Fuse -- Ernie and Bert argue but then make up. ( SSvideo ) Bert And Ernie In The Rain – Ernie talks about how rain makes him feel. ( SSvideo ) Bert And Ernie Water Sports – Bert gets his nephew ready for a bath. ( SSvideo ) Bert Feels Cold – Ernie finds warm clothes for Bert. ( SSvideo ) Bert Feels Silly -- Bert feels silly, and Ernie tries to help. ( SSvideo ) Bert Gets Angry -- Ernie makes Bert get angry too many times. ( SSvideo ) Bert Ice Skates – Bert imagines himself ice skating. (w/ Ernie) ( SSvideo ) Bert Is Locked Out -- Ernie keeps Bert locked out of the apartment. ( SSvideo ) Bert Teaches Pigeon Checkers -- Bert and Bernice play checkers. (w/ Ernie) ( SSvideo ) Bert Teaches Quiet and Loud -- Bert teaches Ernie quiet but gets too loud. (original version) ( SSvideo ) Bert Tries To Make A Call – Bert gets a phone line of his own. (w/ Ernie) ( SSvideo ) Bert’s Big Sneeze – Bert sneezes his nose off! (w/ Ernie) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Bert&apos;s Blanket &quot; -- How a wool blanket is made. (w/ Bert and Erie) ( SSvideo ) Bert&apos;s Bottlecap -- Ernie&apos;s not excited by Bert&apos;s bottlecaps. ( SSvideo ) Bert&apos;s Brother Bart -- Bert&apos;s twin brother Bart comes to visit. (w/ Ernie) ( SSvideo ) Bert&apos;s Bust -- Ernie&apos;s Bert sculpture is missing something. ( SSvideo ) Bert’s Lost Paperclips – Bert and John-John talk about feelings. ( SSvideo ) Bert’s Nap – Ernie checks to see if Bert is asleep. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Bert&apos;s Number 6 &quot; -- Bert sings a song about his favorite number. ( SSvideo ) Bert&apos;s Physical -- Ernie plays doctor and gives Bert a checkup. ( SSvideo ) Bert&apos;s Portrait -- Ernie&apos;s portrait of Bert looks strange. ( SSvideo ) Bert, Ernie&amp;Shala – They hold a brick and a feather. ( SSvideo ) Bert, Ernie&amp;Shala Letter X -- Bert, Ernie&amp;Shala talk about the letter &apos;X&apos;. ( SSvideo ) Bert, Ernie&amp;Shala: Balls -- Four balls of different sizes. ( SSvideo ) Bert, Ernie,&amp;Shala: Between – Bert, Ernie and Shala take turns being between. ( SSvideo ) Bert, Ernie&amp;Shala: Letter A – Ernie, Bert and Shala with the letter A. ( SSvideo ) Bert, John John And Sherlock Hemlock – They count from 1 to 10. ( SSvideo ) Between Subway -- People are &quot;between&quot; others on the subway. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Between The Elephants -- A mouse is wedged between two elephants. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Big Jeffie Sings - Big Jeffie sings about surprises . (w/ Little Jerry , Gina, David, and the kids) ( SSvideo ) Biff And Sully Move A Piano – Biff and Sully play a piano as they move it. ( SSvideo ) Big Bird And Snuffy Ice Skate -- Snuffleupagus learns to ice skate. Big Bird Conducts Mariachi – Kids sing and dance with Big Bird. ( SSvideo ) Big Bird Learns Cuban Games – Big Bird learns to play new games. ( SSvideo ) Big Bird Makes A Mask – Big Bird and kids make masks for a parade. ( SSvideo ) Big Bird Rhymes Hooper - Big Bird recites eight rhymes for Hooper . ( SSvideo ) Big Bird Sings About Mistakes -- Big Bird sings about mistakes. (w/ Captain Vegetable and the kids) ( SSvideo ) Big Bird Visits A Casita – Big Bird visits a garden in East Harlem. ( SSvideo ) Big Bird Visits A Rodeo – Big Bird learns how to be a ‘charro’. ( SSvideo ) Big Bird Visits The Desert – Big Bird learns about life in the desert. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Big Bird&apos;s Alphabet Song &quot; -- Big Bird sings about the alphabet. (w/ Susan) (first season version) ( SSvideo ) Big Bird’s Home Movies – A projector plays film forward and backward. (w/ Luis) ( SSvideo ) Big Bird: Me – Big Bird uses objects to build a sculpture. ( SSvideo ) Big Burger -- Grover serves Fat Blue a big burger. (w/ sound effects added) ( SSvideo ) “ Big Round Nose ” – A man sings about his love of noses. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Billy Crystal : Unbelieveable – A giant letter U appears on Sesame Street. ( SSvideo ) Billy Wears His Seat Belt -- It&apos;s important to remember your safety belt. (cartoon) &quot; Bird On Me &quot; -- A song about birds landing on bigger animals. (film) ( SSvideo ) Bird Twosomes -- A short video about pairs of birds. (film) ( SSvideo ) Birds And Worms -- A bird feeds her babies and counts to ten. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Blackout On Sesame Street -- Ernie can&apos;t sleep during a blackout. (w/ Bert) ( SSvideo ) Blobs Fall In Count 1-8 – A kid counts 8 falling blobs. (animation) ( SSvideo ) Bluegrass Music – Bob, Luis and friends play music. (w/ Robie McGrath ) ( SSvideo ) Bo Peep – Bo Peep goes to the lost and found. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Bob Builds A 12 – Bob has some trouble building a 12. ( SSvideo ) Body Part Functions - Some body parts work just like tools. (film) Body Parts In Spanish – Michelle teaches Herry some words in Spanish. ( SSvideo ) “ Body Rhythms ” – A song about the sounds your body makes. (w/ Little Jerry and the Monotones ) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Bones Song &quot; - The Count sings about bones. ( SSvideo ) “ Born To Add ” – Springsteen parody song about addition. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Box City Recycle Rap &quot; -- Kids use old boxes to make a model city. ( SSvideo ) Boy And Two By Four -- A boy finds many uses for a board. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Break Dance At The Bus Stop -- Bill Irwin break dances at the bus stop. ( SSvideo ) Breakdance Pencil -- A breakdancing pencil writes the word dance. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Brian&amp;Kermit Here and There – Brian and Kermit talk about here and there. ( SSvideo ) Brian And Kermit’s Faces – Brian shows Kermit the parts of his face. ( SSvideo ) Broken Wrist – Megan gets a cast on her arm. (film) ( SSvideo ) Bruce The Moose -- Bruce the moose and his friend the goose. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Bruno &amp;The Trashmen -- Singing &quot;In The Trash Can&quot; Song (w/ Gina ) Brush Your Teeth March -- Toothpaste marches into a boy&apos;s bedroom. ( SSvideo ) Buffy Sainte-marie : “The Moon” – Buffy sings about moon cycles. ( SSvideo ) “ Bugs in Your Neighborhood ” – Placido Flamingo sings about bugs. (w/ Bob) ( SSvideo ) Bunny Hop Pulls Up Carrot -- Rabbits work together to pull up a carrot. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Bus – Maria reads the word ‘bus.’ (animation) ( SSvideo ) Bus Children – Here comes the bus! (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Bus Stop Tour – A woman’s tour group uses the bus stop. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) 

 C 

 C3PO and R2D2 on Sesame Street - C3PO and R2D2 land on Sesame Street. (w/ Big Bird, Maria, Luis and David, from episode 1364 ) &quot; C Is For Candice &quot; - Candice Bergen dances to her favorite song. (w/ Maria) ( SSvideo ) “ C Is For Cookie ” – Cookie Monster sings about the letter ‘C.’ (original version) ( SSvideo ) C: Cap – The word ‘cap’ begins with the letter ‘c.’ (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) C: Carrot – The word ‘carrot’ begins with the letter ‘c.’ (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) C: Cat – A talking typewriter types ‘C’ for cat. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Calcutta Joe &quot; -- A silly rhyming song about animals. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Call Of The Wild – A man sounds out the word &quot;call&quot;. ( SSvideo ) Calling All Pigeons -- Bert coos to call pigeons. ( SSvideo ) Camel Shadow Puppet -- Shadow puppets come to life! (film) ( SSvideo ) Camouflaged Animals – Animals that blend with their environment. (film) ( SSvideo ) Camping With The Rhymies - The Rhymies get a scare from a bear! Camp Wanna Go Homa: It’s Alive – Kids identify what is alive and what is not. (w/ Grover) ( SSvideo ) Can A Cat Bark? -- A cat tries to bark like a dog. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Can A Dog Meow? -- A dog tries to meow like a cat. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ Can Do ” – Bob sings a song about being proud. ( SSvideo ) Can Opener – Luis demonstrates how to use a can opener. ( SSvideo ) Canadian Brass Fugue – The Canadian Brass play on Sesame Street. ( SSvideo ) Capoeira Dance Class - A boy tries capoeira for the first time. (film) ( SSvideo ) Captain Elmo Cousteau -- Seven goldfish sing about the number seven. (w/ Elmo) ( SSvideo ) Captain Finney: Ocean -- The ocean stretches to many places! (animation) ( SSvideo ) Captain Vegetable C Words - Letter &quot;C&quot; vegetables with Captain Vegetable. (w/Big Bird, David, and David ) ( SSvideo ) Captain Vegetable Sings “ Crunch ” – Captain Vegetable tells kids to crunch! (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Captain Vegetable&apos;s Apples -- Captain Vegetable counts apples. (w/Gordon, Susan, and the kids) ( SSvideo ) Car Imagination – A girl imagines hirself as a car. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Caribbean Amphibian &quot; -- Kermit sings about his cousin. ( SSvideo ) Caribbean Collage -- A paper collage becomes Puerto Rico. (animation) ( SSvideo ) Carol Burnett : Rubber Duckie – Carol Burnett kisses Rubber Duckie . ( SSvideo ) Carrots – A woman talks about carrots. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Casa -- &quot;Casa&quot; means &quot;house&quot; in Spanish. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Casa Maria – A house is built around Maria. ( SSvideo ) Case Of The Broken Window -- Ernie&apos;s window has a mysterious hole in it. (w/ Sherlock Hemlock) ( SSvideo ) Case Of The Four Flyers -- One flyer is not the same as the others. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Casting The Big Bad Wolf -- Kermit casts the Three Little Pigs . ( SSvideo ) Cat – Maria reads the word ‘cat.’ (animation) ( SSvideo ) Cat And Mouse Chase -- A cat and mouse knock rhythms on a wall. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Catch The Kitty -- A girl finds ways to get her kitty to play. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Cavemen Invent : Don&apos;t Walk -- Cavemen invent a crosswalk sign. (w/ Ernie, Bert) ( SSvideo ) Cavemen Invent: Exit -- A brilliant caveman invents the exit sign. (w/ Ernie, Sherlock Hemlock) ( SSvideo ) Cavemen Invent: Paper -- A caveman king dislikes stone tables. (w/ Ernie, Sherlock Hemlock) ( SSvideo ) Cavemen Invent: Toothbrush -- Cavemen invent the toothbrush. (w/ Ernie, Sherlock Hemlock) ( SSvideo ) Celia Cruz : “ Zunzun ” – Celia Cruz performs a song with Big Bird. ( SSvideo ) “ Cerrado ” – Everything in this house is closed! (w/ Maria, Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Cerrado Abierto Door – Maria opens a closed door. (w/ Luis) ( SSvideo ) Chair Help – Luis needs help to move a chair. (w/ Bob, Susan, Gordon , Luis) ( SSvideo ) Chariots of Fur -- A Monsterpiece Theater presentation. (w/ Grover and Herry Monster) ( SSvideo ) Cheese Factory – How cheese is made. (film) ( SSvideo ) Chicken Valentine -- What if chickens were the symbol for love? (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Children&apos;s Alphabet -- Kids form letters of the alphabet. (film) ( SSvideo ) Chocolate Ice Cream Swap -- Ernie offers Bert a chocolate icecream substitute. (w/ Oscar) Choosing Between A Cat And A Dog – Two sisters argue which pet would be best. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Chris Columbus Explores Ants -- Chris explores ants, and ants explore Chris. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Christopher Clumsy: 2 Holes -- Christopher Clumsy jumps over a hole. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Christopher Clumsy: Brick Wall – Christopher Clumsy doesn&apos;t fall in a hole. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Christoper Clumsy: Shapes -- Christopher Clumsy makes four shapes. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Cinco De Mayo-- Kids celebrate Cinco de Mayo at a festival. (film) ( SSvideo ) Circle Big/small – A boy is inside a circle that changes sizes. (Anything Muppet) ( SSvideo ) Circle Salesman – Bob encounters a man selling shapes. ( SSvideo ) City&amp;Country -- A man describes what the city is like. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) City And Country – A man talks of things he will see in a city. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) City Garden -- Kids shows off their neighborhood garden. (film) ( SSvideo ) City Kid Visits Country Kid -- A city boy visits his friend in the country. (film) ( SSvideo ) City Shapes: Circles -- Find round fruit at the grocery store. (film) ( SSvideo ) City Shapes: Mix -- A doorknob is made of a circle and rectangle. (film) ( SSvideo ) City Shapes: Triangles -- Find triangles in this picture of a gate. (film) ( SSvideo ) Cinderella Sings The Alphabet -- Jane Curtin , Two Headed Monster Sing Alphabet (w/ Olivia and Maria) Circle March -- A marching band marches in a circle. (film) Closed Door – David has trouble keeping the door closed. ( SSvideo ) Closed Mouth -- It&apos;s important to brush your teeth every day. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Clothesline -- Billy Crystal &amp; Martin Short solve a problem. ( SSvideo ) Coffee Sounds -- A man comes across a sign and sounds it out. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Cold Matches Cold -- Recognize the word &quot;cold&quot;. (animation) ( SSvideo ) Conservation -- Trees are important. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Consonant Sound C-at -- &quot;Cat&quot; begins with the letter &quot;C.&quot; (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Consonant Sound F-face -- Different emotions we can show on our face. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Cookie And Count Cooperate – The Count counts as Cookie Monster eats. ( SSvideo ) Cookie And Eggs -- A boy counts eggs and cookies. (film) ( SSvideo ) Cookie And Melody Subtract – Cookie asks a girl how many cookies are left. ( SSvideo ) Cookie Bunny Adds Cookies – Cookie Bunny adds 2 blue cookies and 1 white. (w/ Ernie) ( SSvideo ) Cookie Buys A Rhyme – Cookie goes to the bakery. (w/ Guy Smiley) ( SSvideo ) Cookie Counter – Cookie Monster shows off his Cookie Counter. (w/ Ernie) ( SSvideo ) Cookie Jar: Empty And Full – The Amazing Mumford makes cookies vanish! (w/ Cookie Monster) ( SSvideo ) Cookie Makes A Sandwich -- Cookie Monster tries to make a sandwich. ( SSvideo ) Cookie Monster&amp;Genelle Count – Genelle and Cookie Monster count to twenty. ( SSvideo ) Cookie Monster&amp;The Telephone – Cookie Monster talks about the telephone. (w/ Maria and Luis) ( SSvideo ) Cookie Monster Chooses Cookies -- Are many cookies better than one cookie? (w/ Ernie) ( SSvideo ) Cookie Monster Exits – Cookie Monster reads an exit sign, then exits. ( SSvideo ) Cookie Monster In The Library – Cookie tries to get cookies at the library. ( SSvideo ) Cookie Monster Shares A Cookie – Cookie Monster shares his cookie with a girl. ( SSvideo ) Cookie Monster Shrinks -- Cookie Monster shrinks to win a cookie. ( SSvideo ) Cookie Monster’s Baby Cousin – Ernie notices similarities and differences. ( SSvideo ) Cookie Monster&apos;s Sorting Song -- Cookie plays a game with cookies. ( SSvideo ) Cookie Monster: Bus Stop -- Cookie Monster shows us a bus stop. ( SSvideo ) Cookie Shows Fast&amp;Slow -- Cookie Monster&apos;s lesson on &quot;fast&quot; and &quot;slow&quot;. (w/ Ernie) ( SSvideo ) Cookie&apos;s Nighmare Part Ii -- Cookie Monster sleeps over with Ernie. ( SSvideo ) Cookie&apos;s Nightmare Part I -- Cookie Monster sleeps over with Ernie. ( SSvideo ) Cookies In Bed -- Ernie shouldn&apos;t eat cookies in bed. (w/ Bert) ( SSvideo ) Copycat: Building Houses -- A boy and girl both build houses with blocks. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Count to Eleven – Hands try to count to eleven on their fingers. (Muppets) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Count on Each Other &quot; -- Loretta Lynn and the Count sing together. &quot; Count&apos;s First Day of School &quot; -- Count counts the students in his class! ( SSvideo ) Count’s Storybook: Countilocks – Countilocks likes to count bears. ( SSvideo ) Countdown Rocket – A man counts down for a rocket launch. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Counting Apples -- Cookie Monster takes and replaces an apple. (w/ Ernie) ( SSvideo ) Counting Feet – Big Bird and Snuffy count Snuffy’s feet. ( SSvideo ) Counting Laundry – Kids count as shirts are put on a clothesline. ( SSvideo ) Counting Legs And Heads – Shala, Fanny and Kermit count legs and heads. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Counting To Nine &quot; -- The Count sings to the number nine. ( SSvideo ) Counting To Ten -- Many ways to count to ten. (w/ David, Luis, and Linda) ( SSvideo ) Country Mouse , City Mouse 1 -- The city mouse visits his country cousin. ( SSvideo ) Country Mouse, City Mouse 2 -- The country mouse visits his city cousin. ( SSvideo ) “Country #5 Song” – A song about silly things happening on a farm. ( Donnie Budd ) ( SSvideo ) “ Cow Dog ” – A dog sings about his life herding cattle. (film) ( SSvideo ) Crane – A crane can be used to knock things down. (film) ( SSvideo ) Crane And Giraffe – A giraffe looks similar to a crane machine. (film) ( SSvideo ) Crane And Power Drill – A crane sometimes resembles a power drill. (film) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Cripple Creek &quot; -- Buffy Sainte-Marie shares a mouth bow. (w/ Fred the Wonder Horse) ( SSvideo ) ” Crocodile Smiles Song ” -- An operetta about dental care. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Cross Country Skiing -- Cross country skiing. (from episode 3061 ) ( SSvideo ) Cuckoo&apos;s Nest -- A Monsterpiece Theater presentation. ( SSvideo ) Cyranose de Bergerac - Monsterpiece Theater presents. (w/ Cookie Monster and Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) 

 D 

 D-dog -- Recognizing the letter &quot;D.&quot; (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) D: &quot; Daddy Dear &quot; Song -- A song featuring words that begin with &quot;d.&quot; (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) D: Daisy -- A talking typewriter types a &quot;d&quot; for daisy. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) D: Museum – Maria, Bob and Big Bird go to a ‘D’ exhibit. ( SSvideo ) “ Daddy Helps With The Dishes ” -- The whole family does chores. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Danger – The word ‘danger’ demonstrates some dangers. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ Danger ” – Muppets sing about the word ‘danger’. (w/ Little Jerry and the Monotones) ( SSvideo ) Danger Sneeze – A man thinks there’s no danger here. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Danger&apos;s No Stranger &quot; -- A music video about danger. (w/ How Now Brown and the Moo Wave ) ( SSvideo ) Danny Devito : Heh Heh Heh – Oscar and Danny have a laughing contest. ( SSvideo ) Dark Bark Bump Dump -- There&apos;s a dog bark in the dark. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Dave Winfield : On Being Tall – Dave Winfield tells Big Bird to feel proud. ( SSvideo ) David And Bert Make Faces – Bert and a boy show mad and happy faces. ( SSvideo ) David Cheers Up Olivia – “It feels good when you sing a song.” (This video currently does not have a &quot;classic&quot; label.) ( SSvideo ) David Disco Skates – David skates around Central Park. (film) ( SSvideo ) David Opens Doors – David encounters a series of curious doors. ( SSvideo ) David Shows Open And Closed – David tries to close a door and a window. ( SSvideo ) Describe Me – A man describes a lost person. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Detective Grover: The Wind -- Grover the detective tries to solve a case. ( SSvideo ) Detective Series : The Clue -- A detective gets to the bottom of a case. ( SSvideo ) Dinner Party Gorillas – One of these guests is not like the others. (w/ Maria and Bob) ( SSvideo ) Dinosaur Cave People -- How to get around a dinosaur. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Dinosaur Gets The Apple -- A dinosaur builds steps until he can reach. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ Disco Frog ” – Kermit sings about a dancing frog. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Do What I Do &quot; -- Ernie sings about how to show your feelings. (w/ added sound effects and music) ( SSvideo ) ” Do De Duckie Ernie in Tub &quot; -- Ernie and friends sing a bathtime song. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Do-op Hop &quot; with Kermit -- Hop! Don&apos;t Stop! ( SSvideo ) Doc Holiday - The Old West – Sinister Sam looks for Doc Holiday . ( SSvideo ) Doc Meets Mean Manny -- Doc meets up with Mean Manny for a shot. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Doctor Flies Into Town -- A doctor flies to an Alaskan town in winter. (film) ( SSvideo ) Doctor Monster – Cookie Monster pretends to be a doctor. (w/ Ernie) ( SSvideo ) Doctor Visits -- A doctor gives a check up to children. (film) ( SSvideo ) Does Air Move Things? -- Maria asks Bill Irwin a question. (film) ( SSvideo ) Dog Balances Hamburgers – A boy demonstrates addition with a dog trick. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ Dog Paddle Song ” -- A song about swimming like a dog. (film) ( SSvideo ) Doghouse Ruler -- It&apos;s important to measure before you build. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Doin&apos; The Pigeon &quot; – Bert does his pigeon dance. ( SSvideo ) “Doin’ the Pigeon” – Bert dances his favorite dance. (w/ new intro) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Dollhouse Number 2 &quot; -- Song about two dolls in two girls&apos; dollhouse. (film) ( SSvideo ) &quot;Don&apos;t Pollute&quot; -- What an icky mess it would be! (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ Don&apos;t Sing This Song ” – Oscar doesn’t have to sing along. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Don&apos;t Throw Your Trash &quot; -- A song about where to put your trash. (w/ Ernie and Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Don&apos;t Walk &quot; -- A groom sings about the don&apos;t walk sign. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Double Dutch Jump Tricks – A girl shows some double dutch tricks. ( SSvideo ) Double Dutch With Olivia – Olivia joins some girls at double dutch. ( SSvideo ) Dr Annie Eyeball: Breathing -- Dr. Annie Eyeball talks about breathing. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Dr. Geo: Mountain -- Dr. Geo has a visual aid to teach &quot;mountain.&quot; (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Dr. Livingstone I Presume – Bert and Ernie have a question for the doctor. ( SSvideo ) Dr Nancy Einstein: Ice Cube -- Dr. Nancy Einstein explores ice. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Dr. Nancy Einstein: Ice Cube -- Nancy observes what happens to ice cubes. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Dr. Nancy Einstein: The Itch -- Dr. Nancy Einstein talks about itching. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Drawing A Face – A girl draws the neck first and the mouth last. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Drawing Bert’s Face – A purple pen highlights areas of Bert’s head. ( SSvideo ) Drawing Me – A boy sketches a self-portrait. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ Dressed Up Birds ” – A film about fancy feathered birds. ( SSvideo ) “ Drink Of Water ” – Kids drink from a water fountain. (film) ( SSvideo ) 

 E 

 E: Ear – A talking typewriter types an ‘e’ for ear. ( SSvideo ) E: Elephant -- An elephant wins an award. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) E: Letter Of The Day -- Guy Smiley presents pageant finalists. ( SSvideo ) Earth, Rain And Mud – Slimey and his band sing. (w/ Oscar, David, Luis) ( SSvideo ) Earthworm -- An earthworm and a tree depend on one another. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Eating Apples -- Herry and kids eat apples. ( SSvideo ) Eating Telephone -- Cookie Monster eats a telephone. ( SSvideo ) Eating Utensils – Ernie explains about knives, forks and spoons. (w/ Cookie Monster) ( SSvideo ) Egg And Motorcycle Chicken -- Count the chickens that come out of an egg. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Eggs – Maria reads the word ‘eggs’. (animation) ( SSvideo ) Eggs And Cookies – Ernie counts eleven cookies and one egg. (w/ Cookie Monster) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Eight Beautiful Notes &quot; -- The Count counts the notes on his organ. ( SSvideo ) Eight Little Spiders -- Spiders show subtraction. (cartoon w/ added sound effects) ( SSvideo ) “El Numero Comparsa ” – Celia Cruz sings about numbers and counting. (w/ Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Elections Day -- Voting on election day. (w/ Big Bird, Snuffy, David, Olivia, Gordon) ( SSvideo ) Elephant And Bird – An elephant and bird sort their skins. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Elephant Bird -- A bird and elephant change in a locker room. (cartoon w/ added sound effects and music) ( SSvideo ) Elephant Picture – Salesman tries to get Ernie to buy a picture. (w/ Bert) ( SSvideo ) Elephant Shadow Puppet - Shadow puppets come to life! (film) ( SSvideo ) Elephant Trunk -- An elephant eats with his trunk. (film) ( SSvideo ) Elmo Explores – Elmo demonstrates what it means to ‘explore.’ (w/ Susan) ( SSvideo ) Elmo Helps Kermit -- Elmo tries to help Kermit at the post office. ( SSvideo ) Elmo Interviews Candice Bergen – Elmo asks Candice about her feelings. ( SSvideo ) Elmo Scares Julia Roberts – Juila Roberts and Elmo demonstrate fear. ( SSvideo ) Elmo Sings Ooh Wah Ditty - Little Chrissie teaches Elmo a song. (w/ Big Jeffy ) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Elmo&apos;s Song &quot; -- Elmo sings with Snuffy and Big Bird. ( SSvideo ) Empty and Full: The Playground – A playground quickly becomes full and empty. (film) ( SSvideo ) En-ter With Bob – Bob, pretending to be a clown, is puzzled. ( SSvideo ) Entrada – “Entrada” means “Enter” in Spanish. (film) ( SSvideo ) Erik And Grover Rhyming -- Grover talks to Erik about rhyming. ( SSvideo ) Ernie And Bert’s Ice Cream Soda – Ernie makes a drink for Bert. ( SSvideo ) Ernie And The Doctor -- Ernie plays doctor. (w/ Bert) ( SSvideo ) Ernie As Robin Hood – Ernie auditions people for the merry men. (w/ Harvey Kneeslapper) ( SSvideo ) Ernie Brings Home A Puppy – Ernie has a surprise for Bert. ( SSvideo ) Ernie Buries Bert In Sand – Sherlock Hemlock finds Bert at the beach. ( SSvideo ) (currently not labeled under classic videos; ending cut) Ernie Counts Cups&amp;Saucers -- Ernie counts teacups while Bert worries. ( SSvideo ) Ernie Counts Sheep -- Ernie&apos;s sheep-counting disturbs Bert&apos;s sleep. ( SSvideo ) Ernie Describes A Ball – Ernie describes a ball to Herry. ( SSvideo ) Ernie Doesn&apos;t Wake Bert -- Ernie stays quiet so he doesn&apos;t wake Bert. ( SSvideo ) Ernie Gets Bert to Exercise -- Ernie tries to get Bert to exercise with him. ( SSvideo ) Ernie Is Here! – Bert thought Ernie wasn’t home! ( SSvideo ) Ernie Jennifer Same/Different – Ernie and Jennifer are similar and different. ( SSvideo ) Ernie Lowers Bert&apos;s Volume -- Bert is annoyed by Ernie&apos;s loud radio. ( SSvideo ) Ernie Matches Cookies – Ernie matches cookies that look the same. (w/ Cookie Monster) ( SSvideo ) Ernie Matches Shoes And Gloves – Ernie arranges things that match in pairs. (w/ Cookie Monster) ( SSvideo ) Ernie Returns Home From Camp – Ernie missed Bert while he was at summer camp. ( SSvideo ) Ernie Shares Bert’s Cookie – Ernie convinces Bert to share his cookie. ( SSvideo ) Ernie Shares Bert&apos;s Paper -- Bert and Ernie share a newspaper. ( SSvideo ) Ernie Takes Bert&apos;s Cookie -- All the stolen cookie clues lead to Ernie. (w/ Bert) ( SSvideo ) Ernie Talks About Shapes -- Ernie lies awake, thinking about shapes. Ernie Tries to Remember -- Ernie has a special way of remembering. (w/ Bert) ( SSvideo ) Ernie Visits Herbert Birdsfoot -- Ernie speculates about what Herbert will do. ( SSvideo ) Ernie&apos;s Baby Cousin Ernestine -- Ernie looks for a family resemblance with Ernestine. ( SSvideo ) Ernie’s Band – Bert tries to listen to a radio program. ( SSvideo ) Ernie’s Disguises – Ernie tries to fool Bert with disguises. (w/ new music) ( SSvideo ) Ernie’s Feelings Game – Ernie gets Bert to play a game about feelings. ( SSvideo ) Ernie&apos;s Gadget -- Ernie&apos;s gadget shows letters of objects. (w/ Grover) ( SSvideo ) Ernie&apos;s Geometric Cookies -- Ernie bakes cookies in different shapes. (w/ Cookie Monster) ( SSvideo ) Ernie’s Guessing Game – Bert plays Ernie’s game about body parts. ( SSvideo ) Ernie’s Guessing Game – Bert has to guess what Ernie has. ( SSvideo ) Ernie’s Love Boat – Ernie expresses his love for a boat. (w/ Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Ernie&apos;s New Rubber Duckie -- Ernie&apos;s new rubber duckie. (w/ Oscar; part 2 of a 2-part clip) ( SSvideo ) Ernie&apos;s Quick Clean Up -- Ernie cleans quickly to get Bert&apos;s dessert. ( SSvideo ) Ernie’s Scale – Ernie uses a scale to measure cookies. (w/ Cookie Monster) ( SSvideo ) Ernie&apos;s Seven Cupcakes -- Cookie Monster takes one of Ernie&apos;s seven cupcakes. ( SSvideo ) Ernie&apos;s Shopping List -- Ernie searches for something to write with. (w/ Bert) ( SSvideo ) Esme Fixes Her Doll -- Esme fixes her toy instead of discarding it. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ Every Bit O’ Litter Hurts ” – Trash belongs in the garbage can. (animation) ( SSvideo ) Everybody Dance -- People on Sesame Street dance. (from Sesame Street Test Show 1 ) &quot; Everybody Eats &quot; -- Adults, kids, and animals all eat! (remake) ( SSvideo ) Everybody Knocks - Oscar tricks the people on Sesame Street (w/Bob, Maria, Olivia, Gordon, Bruno, and the kids) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Everybody Makes Mistakes &quot; -- It&apos;s ok, everybody makes mistakes. (w/ Big Bird, Mr. Hooper, Susan, Gordon, Bob, Oscar) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Everybody Sleeps &quot; -- It&apos;s ok, everybody sleeps. (remake) ( SSvideo ) Everybody&apos;s Different -- Ernie is glad everybody is different. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Everybody&apos;s Song &quot; -- A jazz song for everybody. (Bip Bippadotta, and pigs) ( SSvideo ) “ Everyone In My Family ” – Big Bird remembers when he learned to skate. ( SSvideo ) Excuse Me Chair -- A chair looks for it&apos;s glasses. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) ” Exercise &quot; with Grover -- A song about exercising. (w/ Grover and Betty Lou ) ( SSvideo ) Exit -- A bear makes his own exit. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Exit – Luis finds a door with an ‘exit’ sign. ( SSvideo ) “ Exit ” – Exit is the way way way way out. (w/ Little Chrissy and the Alphabeats ) ( SSvideo ) Exit – X is in the word ‘exit’. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Exit Ball – A ball follows signs that say ‘exit’. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Exit Door – The word ‘exit’ walks out the door. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Exit Silent Movie W/kids – Kid tell a movie actress to go to the exit. (film) ( SSvideo ) Exit Train – A creature jumps on a train to make his exit. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Eye Examination – Stacy goes to the eye doctor’s office. (film) ( SSvideo ) Eyeglasses Princess -- A princess needs to get glasses. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) 

 F 

 F Cheer Version 1 -- Four Anything Muppets cheer for the letter F. ( SSvideo ) F Cheer Version 2 -- Four Anything Muppets cheer for the letter F. ( SSvideo ) F Cheer Version 3 -- Four Anything Muppets cheer for the letter F. ( SSvideo ) F Cheer Version 4 -- Four Anything Muppets cheer for the letter F. ( SSvideo ) F Cheer Version 5 -- Five Anything Muppets cheer for the letter F. (w/ Beautiful Day Monster ) ( SSvideo ) F: Alphabet Dancers – Kids dance and form the letter ‘F.’ ( SSvideo ) F: Fly – A talking typewriter types a ‘f’ for fly. ( SSvideo ) F: Football – The word ‘football’ begins with ‘f’. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Face Facts Song -- Face it, your face has different parts. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Factory Countdown – A factory counts backwards from 10 to 0. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Fall Song &quot; -- A fun fall song. (film) ( SSvideo ) Family Making Noodles -- A boy explains how to make Chinese noodles. (film) ( SSvideo ) Family Mountain Hike – A boy hikes with his motner and brother. (film) ( SSvideo ) Farmer Jones This is Your Life – Forgetful Jones appears on a game show. (w/ Guy Smiley) ( SSvideo ) “ Fat Cat ” – Four Muppets perform a rhyming song. ( SSvideo ) “ Find The Opposite ” – A boy finds opposites in the world around him. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Finding The Right Size – Maria and Grundgetta go shoe shopping. (w/ Andrea Martin ) ( SSvideo ) Firefighters In Training - Nicole talks about firefighter schoo. (film) ( SSvideo ) “ Firefly ” – Olivia and Linda perform a song. ( SSvideo ) Fireworks Alphabet -- A fireworks display of the alphabet. (film) ( SSvideo ) First And Last – Kermit, Grover and Kimberly show first and last. ( SSvideo ) First And Last -- Some Muppets demonstrate first and last. (w/ Hippie and &quot; Old Grover &quot;) ( SSvideo ) Fisherman Jones -- A fisherman&apos;s boat is in, on, and under. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Fishing Boat – A boy tells what happens on a fishing boat. (film) ( SSvideo ) Fishing With Abuelo -- A girl goes fishing with her Abuelo. (film) ( SSvideo ) “ Five Feet High And Rising ” – Johnny Cash sings his classic song with Biff. ( SSvideo ) Five Good Men – The sheriff counts men to find Bad Bart. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Five People In My Family &quot; -- A song about a family of five. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Five Plus One – A mathematical showing of five plus one. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Flower Pattern -- What flower comes next in the pattern? (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Flower: Open And Close – A flower opens and closes. (film) ( SSvideo ) Flowers Allergy -- A bot is allergic to flowers. (cartoon) Flowers Everywhere - Flowers can live anywhere. (film) &quot; Flying With Elmo &quot; - Elmo sings about flying. “ Follow The Leader ” – Bob and some kids play follow the leader. (1975 version) ( SSvideo ) Fonzie On Off Part 1 – Fonzie turns the juke box off and on. (film) ( SSvideo ) Fonzie On Off Part 2 – Fonzie turns the juke box off and on. (film) ( SSvideo ) Fonzie On Off Part 3 – Fonzie turns the juke box off and on. (film) ( SSvideo ) Forgetful Jones Calls – Forgetful calls his cousin on her birthday. (w/ Clementine) ( SSvideo ) Forgetful Jones Daniella No – A girl reads the word on Forgetful’s sign. ( SSvideo ) Forgetful Jones In The Dark – He forgets how to turn on the light. ( SSvideo ) Forgetful Jones Takes A Trip – Forgetful Jones at the train station. ( SSvideo ) Forgetful Jones: Bath Time -- Forgetful Jones forgets to take a bath. ( SSvideo ) Forgetful Jones: Brush Teeth -- Forgetful Jones forgets to brush his teeth. (re-filmed version) ( SSvideo ) Forgetful’s Four Friends – The Cosby Kids try to help Forgetful Jones. ( SSvideo ) “ Forty Blocks From Home ” – A boy counts the blocks between home and school. ( SSvideo ) Four Cheers – Four friends give 4 cheers for the number 4. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Four Friends Cooperate Song &quot; -- Four animals work together to wash a car. (w/ remade audio) ( SSvideo ) Four Plus One – A mathematical showing of four plus one. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “Four Seasons” – A boy experiences all 4 seasons. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ Frazzle ” – Frazzle’s expressions are hard to tell apart. ( SSvideo ) Fred The Fish -- Birds have to fly and fish have to swim. (clay animation w/ Jim Thurman voiceover) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Frogs In The Glen &quot; -- Kermit sings about being a frog. ( SSvideo ) Front&amp;Back Cheer -- Girls perform a routine showing front&amp;back. (film) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Fruit Song &quot;: What To Do With -- A song about fruit. (film) ( SSvideo ) “ Fugue For Readers ” – Bob, Susan and Big Bird sing of things to read. ( SSvideo ) Fun In The Snow - Kids have fun playing in the snow. (film) “ Furry Blue Mommy Of Mine ” – Herry sings a touching song about his mother. (w/ Bob, Big Bird, Gordon, Mr. Hooper ) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Furry Little Me And My Shadow &quot; -- Grover sings a song about his shadow. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Fuzzy And Blue &quot; -- Grover, Herry Monster and Cookie Monster in a vaudeville act. ( SSvideo ) 

 G 

 G: Glue – A talking typewriter types a ‘g’ fro glue. ( SSvideo ) G: Goose – The word ‘goose’ begins with the ‘guh’ sound. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) G: The Gorilla -- A smart, animated gorilla writes &quot;G&quot; words. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Gangster Alphabet – Gangsters say the alphabet down by the docks. (w/ Lefty the Salesman) ( SSvideo ) Gangsters - An Plan -- Gangsters make a plan that all ends in -an. (w/Lefty the Salesman) ( SSvideo ) Gardening – Kids prepare vegetables grown at home. (film) ( SSvideo ) Gargantuan Big -- Knights come across something huge. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Garbageman&apos;s Blues Song &quot; -- Where does garbage go? (film) ( SSvideo ) Geometry of Circles - Different shapes found using circles. (cartoon; version w/ intersecting lines and circle slices) ( SSvideo ) George Washington&apos;s Father - Kermit reports from Washington&apos;s orchard. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Get Along &quot; - Kermit sings about getting along. “Gimme Five” – A soft, sweet song about the number five. (w/ Bob, David, Luis, and Gordon) ( SSvideo ) Girls Track Team – The Flashettes run in a competition. (film) ( SSvideo ) Give Me Five – Harvey Kneeslapper tries to play a trick. ( SSvideo ) Glass Of Water – Ernie brings glasses of water outside. (w/ Bert) ( SSvideo ) Gloria Globe : Australia -- Gloria gets a kangaroo back to Australia . (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Goats Cooperation -- Goats cooperate to cross a mountain path. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ Goin&apos; For A Ride ” – Kids sing about vehicles they will travel in. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Golden Cabbage Of Snufertiti - Jeff Goldblume hunts for the golden cabbage. (from episode 2687 , w/ Bob, Big Bird, Snuffy, Luis and Gordon) ( SSvideo ) Gone With The Wind -- A Monsterpiece Theater presentation. (w/ Kermit the Frog) ( SSvideo ) “ Gonna Get To You Song ” – Cecille sings about transportation. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Good Morning Mister Sun &quot; -- Big Bird sings a greeting to the morning sun. (1990s version w/ Luis, Mr. Handford, Kids, Honkers, Gordon, Barkley, and Lillian) ( SSvideo ) “ Good Morning, Morning ” – Herry sings about waking up in the morning. (w/ Telly, Elmo, Prairie Dawn, Ruby ) ( SSvideo ) “ Good Night / Wake Up ” – Big Bird and Hoots sing about night time. ( SSvideo ) Goodbye, Mr. Hooper -- Big Bird looses his best friend. (street scenes from episode 1839 ) ( SSvideo ) “ Goodbye Little Cookie ” – Cookie Monster sings goodbye to his cookie. ( SSvideo ) Gordon And Susan Meet Sam -- Gordon and Susan meet Sam. ( SSvideo ) Gordon’s Hair – David and Maria imagine hairstyles for Gordon. (w/ Oscar) ( SSvideo ) Gordon’s Morning Run – Gordon jogs in the neighborhood. ( SSvideo ) Great Inventor: Balloon Gloves -- How the balloon was created. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Great Inventor: Earl Sandwich -- How the sandwich was created. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Great Inventor: Soda Straw -- How the straw was created. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) ” Green Grow Rushes Song ” -- Counting backwards in a silly song. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Grouch Girls Don&apos;t Have Fun &quot; - Grouch girls don&apos;t wanna have fun. (w/ Grundgetta and Micki) ( SSvideo ) Grover&amp;Butterfly -- Grover watches a butterfly in the forest. ( SSvideo ) Grover&amp;Chelsea Body Parts -- Chelsea and Grover talk about body parts. ( SSvideo ) Grover&amp;Frazzle: Emotions -- Grover talks to Frazzle about his feelings. ( SSvideo ) Grover&amp;Heather Back Scratch – Heather and Grover scratch each others’ backs. ( SSvideo ) Grover&amp;Heather Stand Up -- Grover and Heather play a simple game. ( SSvideo ) Grover&amp;Herry Find Triangles – Grover makes triangles from a square. ( SSvideo ) Grover&amp;Jesse Talk About Love – Jesse tells Grover how he expresses love. ( SSvideo ) Grover&amp;John John Count 1 – Grover and John John count one penny. ( SSvideo ) Grover&amp;Karlena: Love -- Karlena reads the word &apos;love&apos;. ( SSvideo ) Grover&amp;Kermit Count To Two – Kermit, Grover and friends count to 2. ( SSvideo ) Grover&amp;The Telephone Booth – Grover’s empty phone booth gets full quickly. ( SSvideo ) Grover And Erik Fur/skin – Erik and Grover learn how skin and fur differ. ( SSvideo ) “ Grover And Georgie ” – The hard and soft sounds of the letter “G”. ( SSvideo ) Grover And Herb Count 1-20 -- Grover and Herb count to twenty. ( SSvideo ) Grover And Herry: Here&amp;There – Grover and Herry explain’here’ and ‘there’. ( SSvideo ) Grover And John John Count – Grover and John John take turns counting. ( SSvideo ) Grover And John John Count – They count from 1 to 10 and then from 10 to 1. ( SSvideo ) Grover And Katie Hug – Hugs are Grover’s favorite thing in the world. ( SSvideo ) Grover And Oscar Play Sound ID – Oscar tries to make Grover want to go away. ( SSvideo ) Grover And The Alphabet Soup -- Blue&apos;s alphabet soup is missing some letters. ( SSvideo ) Grover And The Shadow -- Grover learns not to be afraid of his shadow. (w/ Herbert Birdsfoot) ( SSvideo ) Grover And The Telephone -- Grover is in a telephone booth. ( SSvideo ) Grover Caroline You – Caroline tells Grover what this word is. ( SSvideo ) Grover Chelsea Yes/no – Grover and Chelsea talk about yes and no. ( SSvideo ) Grover Comes In From The Cold -- Grover tries to figure out how to get warm. (w/ Kermit) Grover Counts Blocks -- 3 is 3, no matter how the blocks are arranged. (w/ Grover and Herbert Birdsfoot ) ( SSvideo ) “ Grover Disco Alphabet Song ” – Grover is a disco king. ( SSvideo ) Grover Explains About Knees – Grover talks about all the things knees do. (w/ Maria) ( SSvideo ) Grover Explains Exit – Grover shows a very active “EXIT.” (1970 version) ( SSvideo ) Grover Finds A Bird’s Nest – Mommy bird mistakes Grover for a baby bird. ( SSvideo ) Grover Gets A Surprise -- Grover tries to surprise Ernie. (w/ Herry) ( SSvideo ) Grover In The Dark – Grover talks about being afraid of the dark. (w/ Grover&apos;s Mommy ) ( SSvideo ) Grover In The Library -- Grover can&apos;t be quiet enough in the library. ( SSvideo ) Grover Invents The Wheel -- Grover uses shapes to push a rock uphill. (w/ Biff) ( SSvideo ) Grover Presents G Words – The word ‘grow’ starts with the letter ‘G’. ( SSvideo ) Grover Serves A Burger -- Grover recommends the little hamburger. (w/ Mr. Johnson) ( SSvideo ) Grover Serves A Sandwich -- Grover serves an incomplete sandwich platter. (w/ Mr. Johnson) ( SSvideo ) Grover Serves Soup – Grover’s customer can’t eat the chicken soup. ( SSvideo ) Grover Shows Back&amp;Front – Grover demonstrates back and front. ( SSvideo ) Grover The Flight Attendant – Grover helps a passenger warm up. ( SSvideo ) Grover The Lifeguard -- Grover applies for a new job. ( SSvideo ) Grover Walks -- Grover teaches us about the word &quot;walk&quot;. ( SSvideo ) Grover’s Body Parts Lecture – Professor Grover shows parts of Maria’s head. ( SSvideo ) Grover’s Chicken Sandwich – Grover tries to understand a lunch order. (w/ Simon Soundman ) ( SSvideo ) Grover’s Echoes – Grover recites the numbers 1 through 10. ( SSvideo ) Grover’s Fast Food Restaurant – A customer orders some “fast” food. ( SSvideo ) Grover&apos;s First In Line -- Grover demonstrates first and last. (w/ Harry , Bruce , Maurice ) ( SSvideo ) Grover&apos;s Following Orders -- Waiter Grover remembers the customer&apos;s order. ( SSvideo ) Grover’s Health Minute: Teeth – Kermit won’t show Grover his teeth. ( SSvideo ) Grover&apos;s Important Meal -- Waiter Grover explains the food chain to a customer. ( SSvideo ) Grover&apos;s Near and Far -- Being &quot;near&quot; and &quot;far&quot; exhausts Grover. (1970s version) ( SSvideo ) Grover, Weather Salesman – Grover tries to sell Kermit a weather machine. ( SSvideo ) Grover: All Out Of Food -- Grover the waiter has no food to serve. (w/ Mr. Johnson) ( SSvideo ) Grover: Finally A New Waiter! -- Grover and a new waiter rush their service. (w/ Mr. Johnson) ( SSvideo ) Grover: Full and Empty -- Monsters make an &quot;empty&quot; room full. ( SSvideo ) Grover: Heavy&amp;Light -- Grover tries to show &quot;heavy&quot; and &quot;light&quot;. (w/ Big Bird) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Grow High Grow Low &quot; -- Ernie learns about how plants grow on a farm. ( SSvideo ) Grow Sign -- A man fixes a sign so it says &apos;grow&apos;. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Growing A Flower Together – Kids work together to get a seed to grow. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Guitar Drawing - A hand draws a landscape. (cartoon) Guys&amp;Dolls -- A Monsterpiece Theater presentation. (w/ Herry Monster, Ruby) ( SSvideo ) Gymnastics – Kids try gymnastics at an outdoor camp. (film) ( SSvideo ) 

 H 

 H: Hand – A talking typewriter types “h” for hand. ( SSvideo ) H: Horse – The word ‘horse’ begins with the letter ‘H’. ( Speech Balloon cartoon) ( SSvideo ) H: Horse – The word ‘horse’ begins with the ‘huh’ sound. (Consonant Sound cartoon) ( SSvideo ) ” Hace Frio! ” With Telly -- Telly learns &quot;hace frio&quot; means &quot;it&apos;s cold&quot;. ( SSvideo ) Hair Piece Salesman -- Grover tries to sell Kermit hair supplies. ( SSvideo ) Hammer And Nail – Maria demonstrates how to use a hammer. ( SSvideo ) Hand And Pencil: Telephone – A hand with pencil draws a telephone. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Hand Print Matching -- Match the hand with the right print. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Hand Sign -- A man fixes a sign so it says &quot;hand&quot;. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ Hand Talk ” – People can communicate with their hands! (w/ Big Bird , Oscar , Cookie Monster , Placido Flamingo , Seiji Ozawa ) ( SSvideo ) Handclapping -- Hand claps help create a rhythm for a song. (w/ Anything Muppets ) ( SSvideo ) Handclapping Chants -- Girls teach a younger girl a playground song. (film) ( SSvideo ) “ Hands Can Do ” – The Count sings about things hands can do. ( SSvideo ) Happiness Begins At Forty -- A family counts to forty together. (w/ Guy Smiley) ( SSvideo ) Happy And Sad – Kermit and Elmo talk about emotions. ( SSvideo ) Happy Cheer -- Girls sing and stomp about happiness. (film) ( SSvideo ) Happy / Sad Cookie – Ernie and Cookie Monster both want a cookie. ( SSvideo ) “ Happy Tapping With Elmo ” – Elmo imagines he’s a famous tap dancer. (w/ Savion , Gina , Luis , Snuffy ) ( SSvideo ) Hare And Tortoise -- A race to get to the top. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Harlem Globetrotters – Playing basketball with different body parts. ( SSvideo ) Harmonica Workings -- It explains how to play a harmonica. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Harvey Kneeslapper D -- Harvey Kneeslapper has a joke about the letter D. ( SSvideo ) Harvey Kneeslapper Open Closet – Harvey tries his trick a third time. ( SSvideo ) Harvey Kneeslapper Open Closet 1 – Harvey plays a trick, but it backfires. ( SSvideo ) Harvey’s Bucket Joke – Harvey Kneeslapper tries to play a trick. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Has Anybody Seen My Dog? &quot; -- Grover helps a boy find his missing dog. ( SSvideo ) “ Hat, Coat, And Pants ” – Bob and Linda teach sign language and a song. ( SSvideo ) Hats: Same And Different -- A store sells only one kind of hat. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Haunted House -- Don&apos;t be afraid in old houses. (w/ Prairie Dawn) ( SSvideo ) He&apos;s Mad -- A boy gets mad, but it doesn&apos;t last long. (animation) ( SSvideo ) Health Minutes: The Checkup -- Grover&apos;s check-up at the doctor&apos;s office. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Healthy Foods &quot; -- Cookie Monster raps about healthy food. ( SSvideo ) Heather&amp;Grover Try To Rhyme – Grover can’t think of a rhyme for ‘cow’. ( SSvideo ) “ Heavy&amp;Light ” – Telly’s is heavy, but Elmo’s is light. ( SSvideo ) Heavy&amp;Light: Ball&amp;Seal -- A ball is &quot;light&quot; but a seal is &quot;heavy.&quot; (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Heavy&amp;Light: Feather&amp;Bird -- An animated demonstration of heavy and light. ( SSvideo ) Heavy/Light Scale – A scale measures people’s weight. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ Hello Sammy ” – Carol Channing sings to Sammy the Snake . ( SSvideo ) Herbie Hancock Makes Sounds – Herbie Hancock shows kids electronic music. (w/ Maria) ( SSvideo ) Here And There – Maria and David explain ‘here’ and ‘there’. (w/ Grover) ( SSvideo ) Here / There Guru – A man seeks explanation of here and there. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Here Fishy Fishy! - Ernie calls fish into the boat. (w/ Bert) Here is Your Life: Book – Guy Smiley reunites a tooth with past friends. ( SSvideo ) Here is Your Life House -- Guy Smiley introduces people in a home&apos;s life. ( SSvideo ) Here Is Your Life: Oak Tree -- Guy Smiley reunites an oak tree with past friends. (w/ Granny Fanny Nesselrode ) ( SSvideo ) Here Is Your Life: Sneaker -- A sneaker reunited with people in its past. (w/ Guy Smiley) ( SSvideo ) Herry&amp;John John Count 20 -- Herry and John John count to twenty together. ( SSvideo ) Herry&amp;Michael Talk Of Love -- Michael tells Herry Monster about love. ( SSvideo ) Herry And Christopher Talk – Herry and Christopher discuss similarities. ( SSvideo ) Herry And John John Loud Soft – Herry and John John speak loudly and softly. ( SSvideo ) Herry And Kim Talk About Love – Kim and Herry talk about people they love. ( SSvideo ) Herry Sings: “ First And Last ” – One boy’s first and the other is always last. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Herry Sleeps – The letter ‘Z’ often shows someone is asleep. ( SSvideo ) Herry’s Exercise Class – Hery directs exercises and Kermit joins in. ( SSvideo ) &quot;Hey Diddle Song&quot; -- A turtle sings &quot;Hey Diddle Diddle.&quot; (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Hey Food &quot; -- Cookie Monster sings with the band . ( SSvideo ) Hidden Jungle Animals -- Can you find all the animals in this picture? (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Hidden Sheep In A Tree -- A shepherd finds his sheep. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Hide And Seek: Balls -- Two balls play hide and seek among shapes. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Hide And Seek With Z – A boy plays hide and seek with 3 letter ‘z’s. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) High 12 With Forgetful Jones – Forgetful Jones meets Sinister Sam . (w/ Clementine and Fred the Wonder Horse ) ( SSvideo ) Hill Street Twos -- Ernie&amp;Grover fight crime in pairs. ( SSvideo ) Hippo Sitting On Ball -- A girl&apos;s toy ball gets trapped under a hippo. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “Home is City/jungle/igloo” -- Homes in different places in the world. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Homer The Pet Elephant -- A man sings to describe his lost pet. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Homes Around The World -- Homes in different nations. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ Honker Duckie Dinger Jamboree ” – Ernie and friends sing a silly song. (w/ Honkers , Dinger , Rubber Duckie ) ( SSvideo ) Honkers Honk 1 To 20 – The Count counts honker honks. ( SSvideo ) Horse and Crane – A crane looks similar to a horse. (film) ( SSvideo ) “ Horse Sense ” – Judy Collins and Fred sing about common sense. ( SSvideo ) Hortense Series: 1 Drum -- A song about the number one. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Hortense Series: 3 Peas -- Hortense and three peas or trees. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Hortense Series: 4 Ants -- Hortense and four dancing ants. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Hortense Series: 5 Brooms -- Hortense and five waltzing brooms. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Hot Dog – ‘Hot dog’ begins with the ‘huh’ sound. (cartoon by Paul Fierlinger ) ( SSvideo ) “ Hot In The City ” -- Kids cool off by playing with water and ice. (film) ( SSvideo ) House Building -- A fast motion video of men building a house. (film) ( SSvideo ) How A Scale Works -- It shows He and She how to measure weight. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) How A Trumpet Works – Fred Mills shares his trumpet with some kids. ( SSvideo ) How Does Santa Get In? -- Kermit and Grover interview kids. (from Christmas Eve on Sesame Street ) ( SSvideo ) How Hard It Is To Be 15 -- Fifteen sings about being the hardest teen. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) How Plants Travel – Plant seeds travel in many different ways. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ How To Get From Here To There ” -- A song about using feet, buses, and planes. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) &quot; How To Get To Yellowstone Park &quot; -- Don Music and Kermit write a song together. (w/ Little Chrissy and the Alphabeats) ( SSvideo ) How To Sign ‘Closed’ – Linda teaches a boy how to sign ‘closed’. ( SSvideo ) How To Sign ‘Don’t Walk’ – Linda teaches a boy how to sign ‘don’t walk’. ( SSvideo ) How To Sign ‘One Way’ – Linda teaches a boy how to sign ‘one way’. ( SSvideo ) How To Sign ‘Open’ – Linda teaches a boy how to sign ‘open’. ( SSvideo ) How To Sign ‘Wet Paint’ – Linda teaches a boy how to sign ‘wet paint’. ( SSvideo ) Howard Coolsell In Exercise -- Exercise makes you strong and healthy. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Hummingbird Helicopter -- The hummingbird inspired helicopter design. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) 

 I 

 I Am Somebody -- Jesse Jackson encourages kids to be proud. ( SSvideo ) I Can Remember -- A girl has to remember mom&apos;s grocery list. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; I Don&apos;t Want To Live On The Moon &quot; -- Ernie sings about places he&apos;d like to visit. ( SSvideo ) &quot; I Get There &quot; -- A slow turtle sings &quot;I get there.&quot; (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) I Got It Alphabet – One man recites the alphabet to another man. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; I Gotta Be Clean &quot; -- Bert sings about being clean. ( SSvideo ) &quot; I Hate Christmas! &quot; -- Oscar sings about the holidays. (from ‘’Christmas Eve on Sesame Street’’) ( SSvideo ) “ I Just Adore Four ” – Big Bird sings a ballad about the number ‘4.’ ( SSvideo ) “ I Like / I Don’t Like ” – Bob sings about changing his mind. ( SSvideo ) ” I Like Alaska ” -- Lots of kids like to live and play in Alaska. (film) ( SSvideo ) ” I Like My Name ” – Bob and Olivia are proud of their names. (This video currently does not have a “classic” label.) ( SSvideo ) &quot; I Love A March &quot; -- March along and sing with Bert. (w/ Ernie and Olivia) ( SSvideo ) “ I Love Trash ” – Oscar sings about the garbage he loves. (1991 version) ( SSvideo ) I Love You – How to say “I love you” in sign language. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; I Make Up Songs &quot; -- Helen Reddy makes up a song. ( SSvideo ) “ I Stand Up Straight And Tall ” – Grover sings about the letter ‘i’. ( SSvideo ) &quot; I Think That It Is Wonderful &quot; -- Muppets sing about life&apos;s wonders. (w/ Bert, Ernie) ( SSvideo ) I Thought A Big Thought -- A man&apos;s big thoughts become animated. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ I Wanna Be Me Song ” -- Cecille sings about being me. (animation) ( SSvideo ) I Wonder Why – A man has questions about things around him. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; I Wish I Had a Friend &quot; -- Bert is feeling lonely. (w/ Ernie) ( SSvideo ) Ice Skating Whistle -- Everyone wonders where a sound is coming from. (w/ Oscar, Bert, Betty Lou, the Count, Grover, Big Bird, and Cookie Monster; from the Ice Follies ) ( SSvideo ) &quot; If I Was A Cloud In The Sky &quot; -- Snuffy dresses like a cloud for a play! (w/ Big Bird) ( SSvideo ) &quot; I&apos;ll Love You In Springtime &quot; -- A song about the seasons and love. (w/ Guy Smiley) ( SSvideo ) “ I’m A Big Girl Now ” – Olivia tells Gordon she’s not a kid anymore. ( SSvideo ) “ I’m Cold ” – A girl shivers outdoors in winter. (Anything Muppet) ( SSvideo ) “ I’m Going Somewhere ” – Bob sings about going to sleep. ( SSvideo ) “ I’m Going To Get My Haircut ” – Cookie Monster tells Jeff not to be afraid. ( SSvideo ) “ I’m Gonna Be A Country Girl ” – Buffy Sainte-Marie sings about the country. (w/ Gladys the Cow ) ( SSvideo ) I’m Six – A mouse is excited about his sixth birthday. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) I&apos;m Special With Bert&amp;Ernie -- Bert helps Ernie feel special. ( SSvideo ) I&apos;ve Got A Mind -- A rhyming story a fish and using your mind. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) I-beam – A stell construction beam is manufactured. (film) ( SSvideo ) &quot; I-in The Sky &quot; -- A song about the letter &quot;I&quot;. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) I: A Dog’s Bone – A dog mistakes the letter ‘I’ for a bone. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) I: Alphabet Dancers – Kids dance and form the leter ‘I.’ ( SSvideo ) I: Alphabet Dancers – Kids dance and form the letter ‘i.’ ( SSvideo ) I: Letter Candles – Two candles shaped like ‘I’ and ‘i’. ( SSvideo ) Ice – An animation of the word ‘ICE’. ( SSvideo ) Ice Cream Cone – Ernie orders a very special ice cream cone. ( SSvideo ) Ice Cream Map -- A man asks for directions to a parking area. (cartoon by Paul Fierlinger) ( SSvideo ) “ If I Had A Kid Like You ” – Gordon sings wistfully about fatherhood. ( SSvideo ) &quot; If The Moon Were A Cookie &quot; -- Cookie Monster sings a ballad. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Image That &quot; with Ernie -- Ernie imagines himself in different roles. ( SSvideo ) Imagining A Land Of E -- The ways to spell&amp;rhyme with the letter E. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Imagination Girl -- A girl shows what imagination can do. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Imagination With Elmo &quot; -- Elmo sings about where imagination takes you. (w/ Hoots the Owl, Wolfgang the Seal) ( SSvideo ) “In And Out Fever” – Monsters dance the in and out disco boogie. ( SSvideo ) “ In My Book ” – Many magic things exist in one boy’s book. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) In On The Hill – A man reads the word ‘in’, then goes inside. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ In The Middle Of Your Face ” – Elmo sings about parts of the face. ( SSvideo ) &quot; In&amp;Out Song &quot; -- Barkley can&apos;t decide if he wants in or out! (w/ Maria) ( SSvideo ) Inchworm Measures -- An inchworm measures the length of toys. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Indians Pride -- Not everything in movies and on TV is true. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Ingrid Counts In Spanish -- The Count learns to count in Spanish. ( SSvideo ) Is Snow Cold? -- A boy tells us: &quot;Yes!&quot; Snow is cold. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Is This Me? – A boy shows things that are not ‘me.’ (w/ Farley ) ( SSvideo ) Island Map – People explore a Caribbean island. (film/animation) ( SSvideo ) Island Song - An island is surrounded by water. (animation) ( SSvideo ) “ It&apos;s Alive ” – Kermit sings about what is alive. ( SSvideo ) “ It’s A Circle ” – Herry and Cookie Monster sing about circles. ( SSvideo ) It’s A Dog’s World – Maria imagines life surrounded by only dogs. (w/ Barkley) ( SSvideo ) It&apos;s Alive! -- How to tell if you&apos;re rock is a dinosaur! (cartoon w/ added sound effects) ( SSvideo ) &quot; It&apos;s Hip To Be A Square &quot; -- It&apos;s really hip to be a square. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ It&apos;s Zydeco ” – A band plays a song about zydeco music. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Itzhak Perlman: Easy / Hard – Itzhak Perlman and a girl demonstrate. ( SSvideo ) Itzhak, Rafael And Big Bird – Itzhak and Rafael talk about disabilities. ( SSvideo ) 

 J 

 “ J Friends ” – Muppets sing about words that start with “J”. (Anything Muppets) (This video currently does not have a “classic” label.) ( SSvideo ) J Train - The letter J makes words. (cartoon) J: Jaguar – ‘Jaguar’ begins with the ‘juh’ sound. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) J: Juggle – The word ‘juggle’ begins with the letter ‘j’. (w/ Bob) ( SSvideo ) J: Jump - A talking typewriter types &quot;j&quot; for jump. James Earl Jones : Alphabet -- James Earl Jones says the alphabet. James Earl Jones: Counting -- Counting 1-10 with James Earl Jones. ( SSvideo ) Jay Leno Prepares For A Ride – Jay Leno talks about his safety gear. (w/ Big Bird) ( SSvideo ) Jazz Number 4 -- An animated song about the number four. ( SSvideo ) Jazz Number 7 – An animated song about the number seven. ( SSvideo ) Jill Went Up The Hill – A rhyme about Jill who went up the hill. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Joe Williams: “ Birdland Jump ” – Joe Williams performs at the Birdland Club. (w/ Hoots the Owl ) ( SSvideo ) John John&amp;Herry Up And Down – John John shows Herry what up and down means. ( SSvideo ) John Moschitta: Long Baby Name – This baby has a relly long name! ( SSvideo ) John Moschitta: P Products – This company sells things that start with ‘P’. ( SSvideo ) Johnny Cash: “ Nasty Dan ” – Johnny Cash sings a song that Oscar loves. ( SSvideo ) José Feliciano: “Four Fingers” – José Feliciano sings about finger symbols. ( SSvideo ) Judy Collins And Snuffy Sing – An opera about the alphabet. (w/ Big Bird/Judy intro and tag) ( SSvideo ) Julius&amp;Jasper: Apple -- Julius asks Jasper to describe an apple. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Julius&amp;Jasper: Lost Elbow – Julius helps Jasper find his elbow. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Julius&amp;Jasper: Two Legs – Julius asks Jasper why one leg’s in the air. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Jungle Add And Subtract – Animals add and subtract as they walk. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Jungle Ladybugs And Lizards – Ladybugs and lizards add and subtract 5. (cartoon w/ new music) ( SSvideo ) “ Just Around The Corner ” – People sing about places in the neighborhood. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) “ Just The Way You Are ” – Billy Joel and Marlee Matlin sing with Oscar. ( SSvideo ) “Just The Way You Are” – Billy Joel and Marlee Matlin serenade Oscar. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Just Throw It My Way &quot; - Oscar sings a ballad about not littering. ( SSvideo ) Jyah&apos;s Dance Class -- Jyah takes us to her dance class. (film) ( SSvideo ) 

 K 

 K Cheer -- Kids cheer about things that begin with &apos;K.&apos; (film) ( SSvideo ) K: Kangaroo – A kangaroo shows words that start with ‘K’. (cartoon) K: Kangaroo – A man talks about kangaroos. (cartoon) K: Kangaroo – Kangaroo begins with the ‘kuh’ sound. (cartoon) K: Kick -- A football player kicks a &apos;k&apos;. (cartoon) K: The Cheer -- Fans cheer for the letter K. (Anything Muppets) K: The Kiss -- An animated letter &quot;K&quot; gives a duck a kiss. Kate And Grover Make Faces – Kate and Grover show emotions with their faces. Kate And Grover Talk About Snow – Kate tells Grover about snow. Kate And Grover: I Like You – Kate and Grover hug and kiss. Katie And The King – Olivia reads about a king who liked ‘K.” (w/ Anything Muppets) Katydids -- Can you count the katydids? &quot; Keep Christmas With You &quot; -- Linda and the kids surprise Bob. (from Christmas Eve on Sesame Street ) Keep Nature Clean -- Cookie Monster takes care of his trash. (w/ Baby Bear ; from Sing-Along Earth Songs ) ( SSvideo ) Keith Haring : Exit – Everybody exits, even the painted characters. (film/animation) Keith Haring: Telephone – Painted characters use a telephone. (cartoon) Kermit&amp;Grover Short&amp;Long -- Kermit&amp;Grover sing, hop and tickle. ( SSvideo ) Kermit And Alfonso Discuss Exit – Alfonso and Kermit talk about the word ‘exit.’ Kermit And Brian Loud/soft – Brian demonstrates soft and loud for Kermit. Kermit And Chris Count Ears – Chris and Stephanie both have two ears. Kermit And Chris Count To 20 – Chris counts from 1 to 20 for Kermit. Kermit And Elmo Loud And Quiet – Elmo helps Kermit talk about loud and quiet. Kermit And Girls: Giraffes – Kermit tries to talk to girls about giraffes. Kermit And Grover Here There – Grover tries to set some bricks down ‘there’. Kermit And Joey Alphabet – Kermit and Joey say the alphabet. ( SSvideo ) Kermit And Joey Body Parts – Joey and Kermit label their body parts. ( SSvideo ) Kermit And Joey Count to 20 – Kermit and Joey count from 1 to 20. ( SSvideo ) Kermit And Joey: Up and Down – Joey and Kermit talk about up and down. ( SSvideo ) Kermit And John John: Sounds - Kermit and John John show loud and soft. Kermit And Julia Animal Sounds -- Kermit and Julia identify different animal sounds. Kermit And The Three Pigs – The Wolf retells the classic tale. Kermit Calls a Plumber -- Grover and Kermit discuss size. Kermit Counts 1 - 10 -- Kermit and a young girl count to ten. Kermit Counts Monkeys – Kermit manages some monkey business. Kermit Counts To Five -- Kermit and Tracy count to five. Kermit Explains Big And Little -- Kermit compares monsters&apos; sizes. (w/ Beautiful Day Monster and Splurge ) ( SSvideo ) Kermit Explains Round -- Kermit talks about things balls can do. Kermit Explains Short And Tall – Sam and Harry help Kermit demonstrate. Kermit Guesses From Clues -- Kermit figures things out by observing. (w/ Beautiful Day Monster) Kermit News : 1st Day of School – Kermit learns not to be afraid of school. (w/ Cookie Monster) Kermit News: Cinderella -- The prince shows off his fancy things. Kermit News: Daycare – Kermit asks kids what they want to be. (w/ Cookie Monster) Kermit News: Elmo’s Idea – Elmo shares his new game idea with Kermit. Kermti News: Goody Basket – Little Red Riding Hood’s basket. (w/ Cookie Monster) Kermit News: Humpty Dumpty – Kermit reports on Humpty Dumpty’s fall. Kermit News: Jack And Jill -- Kermit covers Jack and Jill. ( SSvideo ) Kermit News: Old Macdonald - Kermit investigates a spaceship. (w/ Martians) Kermit News: Report with Telly – Telly and Kermit report on cooperation. Kermit News: Santa Claus – Kermit tries to get an interview with Santa. Kermit News: Six Dollar Man – A scientist has built a man from spare parts. Kermit News: Sleeping Beauty – The Prince comes near to wake the Princess. Kermit News: Sleeping Beauty – Prince Charming fails to wake Sleeping Beauty. Kermit Shala Fanny: Next To – Shala, Fanny and Kermit show ‘next to’. Kermit Shows The Letter B – Cookie Monster keeps eating Kermit’s letter. Kermit Subtracts Eggs – Subtracting hatching eggs and leaving chicks. Kermit Talks About Feet -- Kermit talks about feet. ( SSvideo ) Kermit Telephone – Kermit reads the word ‘telephone’. Kermit’s Telephone Demo – Kermit and Forgetful Jones use a telephone. Kermit&amp;Jennifer: Knees -- Kermit and Jenifer bend their knees. (w/ Grover) ( SSvideo ) Kermit: &quot; Bein&apos; Green &quot; -- Kermit sings about being green. (1969 version) Kermit: &quot; Bein&apos; Green &quot; -- Kermit sings about being green. (1970s version) Kermit: Z -- Kermit works with a &quot;Z&quot; or an &quot;N&quot;. Kid Paints Letter X – A kid stamps and paints the letter ‘x’. (animation) Kids Build Sand Castles – Kids make all kinds of things in the sand. (film) Kids Demonstrate Open – Kids demonstrate the word ‘open’. (cartoon) Kids Far&amp;Wide- Bali -- A girl describes a cultural holiday in Bali. (cartoon) Kids Far&amp;Wide: Colombia -- Sports and the marketplace in Colombia. (cartoon) Kids Far&amp;Wide: India -- A boy describes his daily life in India. (cartoon) Kids Far&amp;Wide: Sierra Leone -- A boy fishes all day in Sierra Leone. (cartoon) Kids Far&amp;Wide: Thailand -- A celebration of beginnings in Thailand. (cartoon) Kids Form A Rectangle – 4 kids lie down in the shape of a rectangle. (w/ Big Bird, Olivia) Kids Form A Square – Four kids lie down in the shape of a square. (w/ Big Bird, Olivia) Kids Form A Triangle – 3 kids lie down in the shape of a triangle. (w/ Big Bird, Olivia) “ Kids Just Love To Brush ” – A musical number about brushing teeth. (Anything Muppets) Kids Looking At Themselves – Kids examine their own images. (cartoon) Kids Make Cornbread – Students mix the ingredients for cornbread. (film) “ King of 8 ” – The King of Eight thinks “8” is great. (animation) King Minus – King Minus defeats dragons with subtraction. (cartoon) Kiss Me Sounds -- A man comes across a sign and sounds it out. (cartoon) Kittens – Boys talk about kittens in English and Spanish. (film) “Knees, Shoulders And Ankles” – Silly scarecrows sing a song about body parts. (w/ David, Maria, Luis, Bob) 

 L 

 L: Alphabet Dancers – Kids dance and form the letter ‘L.’ L: Light – The word ‘light’ begins with the letter ‘l’. (cartoon) L: Lion – Lion begins with the letter L. (cartoon) L: Lion – A talking typewriter types an “l” for lion. L: Lips – The word ‘lips’ starts with the letter ‘l.’ &quot; Ladybugs&apos; Picnic &quot; – Twelve ladybugs have a picnic. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Lambaba! &quot; With Count -- The Count has an up-tempo bedtime song. ( SSvideo ) Lena Horne Sings the Alphabet – Lena Horne sings with the Muppets. ( SSvideo ) Lena Horne: &quot; Bein&apos; Green &quot; – Lena Horne sings with Kermit the Frog. ( SSvideo ) Lena Horne: &quot; How Do You Do? &quot; – Grover learns not to be shy. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Let&apos;s Go Driving &quot; -- Let&apos;s take a ride in a car! (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Let&apos;s Go Tubbing &quot; - It&apos;s tub time. (film) &quot; Let&apos;s Make A Face &quot; – Bob and Luis sing about facial expressions. ( SSvideo ) Letter For Me – Kids try to figure out who a letter is for. (cartoon) Letter O In Grocery Store Sign – A man tries to fix his grocery store sign. (cartoon) Letter O Tag – Madeline Kahn says the letter ‘O.’ Letters Make Words: B – Kids talk about words that begin with ‘B’. (film) Levitation Magic – The Amazing Mumford performs. (w/ Grover, Herry) License Plate Back And Front – Maria helps Oscar install his license plate. Life Without Bert - Ernie imagines if Bert wasn&apos;t around. Lifestyles Of The Big&amp;Little -- A tour of homes of big and little creatures. (Anything Muppets) Linda The Wind-Up Toy – Linda signs the word ‘toy’. (w/ Big Bird) Lines Construction -- A little girl draws buildings. (cartoon) Lion And Mouse -- A mouse and lion help each other. (cartoon; 1970s version) Listen For Traffic – A man listens to noise on the street. (cartoon) “ Listen To The Bells ” – A boy sings about different types of bells. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Listen to the Wind &quot; - A song about listening to the wind. (w/ Buffy) ( SSvideo ) Listening To Danger – Listening can tell you many things. (cartoon) Little Bird Imagination Game - Little Bird plays the imagination game. (w/Herry) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Little Plant Song &quot; – Ernie cares for his indoor house plant. ( SSvideo ) Lobster Fisherman – A video about lobster fishing. &quot; Lonely &quot; – A Muppet sings about how lonely he is. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) “ Long Time No See : Haircut” – A long haired man gets a haircut. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Lost Boy Remembers Way Home -- A boy figures out how to get back home. (cartoon) Love Bird -- A man shows the word &quot;love&quot; and its meaning. (cartoon) Love My Bones -- Learning about bones. (cartoon) &quot; Lowercase L Words &quot; -- Bert and Ernie sing about the letter &quot;L&quot;. ( SSvideo ) Luis And Maria Love Each Other - Maria and Luis decide to get married. (w/ Big Bird) Luis Looks For Agua – ‘Agua’ is the Spanish word for ‘water’. Luis Talks About Tools – Luis shows kids his tools at the Fix-It Shop. Luis The Magician – Luis counts 1, 2, and 3 people. (w/ David and Maria) Luis Teaches About Love -- Luis tells Sam the Robot about love. ( SSvideo ) 

 Lunchbox Alphabet – Construction workers have an unusual lunch. (cartoon) 

 M 

 M With Herb Birdsfoot -- Herb Birdsfoot has an uncooperative letter M. M: Art Supplies – Art supplies make the letters ‘M’ and ‘m’. (animation) M: Letter Sound – Peanut butter makes Grover say “Mmmmm.” (w/ Herbert Birdsfoot) M: Magic – A talking typewriter types an ‘m’ for magic. M: Melvin The Moving Man – Melvin moves things that begin with ‘M’. (cartoon) M: Milk -- Milk starts with a lowercase m. (cartoon) M: Mom -- The letter &apos;M&apos; begins &apos;mom&apos; and &apos;milk&apos;. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) M: Moon – The word ‘moon’ begins with the letter ‘m’. (cartoon) Mr. Hooper In The Hospital -- Mr. Hooper takes a picture with kids in the hospital. (from episode 0823 , w/ Susan) ( SSvideo ) Macneil Report -- Rober Macneil interviews Cookie Monster. (w/ Kermit the Frog) ( SSvideo ) Mad Painter # 3 – Painter paints the number 3 with condiments. (film) Madrigal Alphabet - A song about the alphabet. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Madeline Kahn Sings “me” – Madeline Kahn sings and speaks the word “me.” Madeline Kahn: Counting To 20 – Two women count to twenty together. Magic Finger K – Kermit shows how to write the letter “K”. (w/ Grover) Magic Finger Q – Kermit shows how to write the letter “Q”. (w/ Grover) Magician Addition 1-10 -- Addition of one is like a magic trick. (cartoon) Mailman Drawing -- Children describe how to draw a mailman. (cartoon w/ sound effects) Mailman Drawing – Children direct how to draw a mailman. (cartoon) Making A Face -- A musical stage production about the face. (w/ Prairie Dawn, Ernie, Herry Monster, Cookie Monster, Bert, Grover) Making A Stool In Appalachia -- How to make a stool from scratch. (film) ( SSvideo ) Making Bird Feeders – People make bird feeders from sunflower seeds. (film) Making Crayons – A video about how crayons are made. Mandrill Mother and Baby – A mandrill mother looks after her baby. (film) Manhole - Abierto -- A boy pulls &quot;abierto&quot; out of an OPEN manhole. (cartoon) Man Walks Forward And Backward -- Everything in the city runs backwards! (film) Many Me&apos;s -- A boy describes his different emotions. (cartoon) Map Maker – A woman uses aerial photos to make a map. (film) Mapping A Trip To Mexico -- A friend takes a trip to Mexico. (cartoon) Marbles - Children in Africa play games. (film) Marching Band 1 - Drum one time. (film) Marching Band 2 - Drum two times. (film) Marching Band 4 - Drum four times. (film) Marching Band Counts 1-20 - A marching band counts from 1-20. (film) Maria Builds With Blocks – Maria tries to copy a house with blocks. Maria Buys Some Shoes – Maria decides on a pair of shoes. (w/ Grundgetta and Andrea Martin ) Marshal Grover -- Marshal Grover is on horseback backwards! Martian Music -- A band from outer space performs. (cartoon w/ original sound effects) Martian Trees – A martian makes two trees match. (cartoon) Martians And The Telephone -- The aliens encounter a ringing phone. Martians Discover Love -- The Martians discover love. (w/ Maria and Luis) Martians Find The Earth – Martians use a book to help identify Earth. Martians Meet A Clock – The Martians confuse a clock with a person. Martians Radio -- The Martians discover a radio. Martians Read Book -- Martians discover a book..yup! “ Mary Had A Little Lamb ” – Don Music and Kermit write a song together. Mary Lou Williams: Scatting – Mary Lou Williams teaches some kids to scat. “ Mary Sunshine #11 ” – A song about animals in groups of 11. (cartoon) Mayonnaise Jar -- Jars get made, used, reused, and recycled. (animation) Me Girl and Witch – A witch can’t stop the girl from being ‘me.’ (cartoon) &quot; Me Gotta Be Blue &quot; -- Cookie Monster sings a song about being blue. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Me And My Chair &quot; -- A boy sings about things he can do. (film) &quot; Me And You Song – Two rhinos at a zoo. (film) “ Me Lost Me Cookie At The Disco ” – Cookie sings about his missing cookie. Me Monolith – Cavemen argue with the word ‘me’. (cartoon w/ sound effects) Me Monolith -- Cavemen explain what the word &quot;me&quot; means. (cartoon) Me On TV – A man wants everyone to know he is on TV. (cartoon) Me Sign On TV -- Hey look, a big &quot;me&quot; sign on TV! (cartoon w/ new music) Me Snowshoe – A man spells ‘me’ in the snow. (film) Me Tarzan You Parrot – Tarzan has a disagreement with his parrot. (cartoon) Me: Grover -- Grover sees and yells the word &quot;ME.&quot; Meal First, Next and Last – Grover serves a meal in the wrong order. Measuring Devices -- Devices we can use to measure things. (cartoon) Measuring Distance -- Two friends measure the distance between them. (Anything Muppets) Meet The Martians -- Ernie imagines Bert went to Mars. (w/ Martians) Mice&amp;Elephant Monster -- Mice use imagination to describe an elephant. (cartoon) Milk – Maria reads the word ‘milk’. (animation) Miners And Mules: Subtraction -- Miners subtract mules in this short cartoon. Mix-up Game Show: School – A woman must unscramble the word ‘school’. (w/ Guy Smiley) Mixed Up Body Parts – Animals find their body parts are switched. (cartoon) Mixed Up Town -- A traffic cop sorts some confused deliveries. (cartoon) &quot;Mo Yet&quot; Song -- Harry Belafonte sings a song. Model Airplane – A model airplane needs 2 wings the same size. (w/ Gordon) &quot; Mom And Me &quot; -- A girl sings about different families. (film) ( SSvideo ) Mom’s Having a Baby – There’s a brand new baby at Katie’s house. (film) Monkey Baby Swing -- A baby monkey hangs and swings around a cage. (film) Monster Best Friend -- Walking dogs is exercise for them and you. (w/ Grover) Monster Fixit Team -- Monsters repair at Kermit&apos;s. (w/ Grover and Herry) “ Monster In The Mirror ” – Celebrities sing with Grover. &quot;Monster In The Mirror&quot; -- Grover sings Wubba Wubba Woo. Monster On / In / Under – A Monsterpiece Theatre presentation. Morning Chores -- Children in city and country both do chores. (film) Mother Goose: The Shoe People – Mother Goose writes a verse. (Anything Muppets) Mother Goose: &quot;When I Grow Up&quot; -- Mother Goose sings about nursery rhymes. (w/ Maria) ( SSvideo ) Mother Tucks Child Into Beds – Girls in 2 countries talk about their mothers. Mr. and Mrs. Snow -- Labelling parts of a snowman and snowwoman. (film) Mumford Demonstrates Surprise – The Amazing Mumford explains ‘surprise’. (w/ Herry) Mumford’s Rhyming Trick – Mumford pulls things from his hat that rhyme. (w/ Grover) ” Muppets Rhyme In School ” -- Muppet students sing a rhyming song. (Anything Muppets) Murphy Brownbag – Cookie Monster and Murphy discuss lunch. My Cat Story -- A girl writes about her cat. (cartoon) My Dog Pete -- A gril tells us all about her dog, Pete. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) ” My Favorite Letter P” -- Song about words that start with &quot;P&quot;. (Anything Muppets) My Rock Show And Tell -- Bert sings about his rock at show and tell. ( SSvideo ) My Skin -- A girl tells us about her skin. (cartoon) “ My Street ” – Big Bird and Olivia sing about their home. (w/ Mr. Hooper) Mysterious Theatre : Toast -- Sherlock Hemlock investigates missing food. ( SSvideo ) Mystery Box -- Kermit and Cookie Monster play a guessing game. Mystery Mix-up Game Show – A contestant must make the word ‘school’. (w/ Guy Smiley) 

 N 

 N-tv -- A music video about the letter N . (Anything Muppets) N: Nose – The word ‘nose’ begins with the ‘nuh’ sound. (cartoon) N: Nose – A talking typewriter types an “n” for nose. N: The Interview -- A reporter interviews the letter n. (cartoon) N: &quot; The Lonely N Song &quot; -- A song of two lonely lower-case letter &quot;n&quot;s. (cartoon) Name That Food! -- Name that food - and eat it! (cartoon) Name That Sound! – Grover on a game show with Guy Smiley . Native American Boy – James talks about his family, school and home. (film) “ New Baby ” – A monster becomes an older sister. New Ball In Town -- A new ball makes friends with three others. (cartoon) &quot; New Way To Walk &quot; – The Oinker Sisters walk with pride. News : Angry Reporter -- No one on the street will talk to Kermit . (w/ Grover ) News: Boston T Party -- Kermit helps colonists with their &quot;T&quot; party. News: Children&apos;s Zoo -- Kermit reports on favorite animals. News: Hickory Dickory Dock -- Kermit watches a horse try to run up a clock. (w/ Gladys the Cow ) News: Jack&amp;The Beanstalk -- Kermit climbs up and down the beanstalk. News: Jack Jumps Over -- Jack jumps all over the candlestick. (w/ Kermit) News: Mother Hubbard -- Old Mother Hubbard can&apos;t feed her dog a bone. (w/ Kermit) News: Pinocchio -- Kermit talks about &quot;long&quot; and &quot;short&quot;. News: Rapunzel -- Prince Charming isn&apos;t loud enough. (w/ Kermit) News: Rumpelstiltskin -- Kermit is taken by Rumpelstiltskin . News: The Princess&amp;Mattress -- Kermit reports on the princess&apos; mattress. News: Three Little Pigs – The Count&apos;s counting ruins Kermit&apos;s report. News: Three Pigs -- Kermit reports on the Three Little Pigs . News: Tortoise&amp;Hare -- Kermit reports on a tortoise and hare race. Newspaper -- You&apos;ll find lots of things in a newspaper! (cartoon) Newspaper Hat News -- Grover learns a newspaper is for reading. Newspaper Interruption – Ernie waits to ask Bert a question. Next To Little Bird -- Little Bird is surprised by who is &quot;next to&quot; him. (w/ Cookie Monster ) Nim Matches Teddy Bear Nose – A chimpanzee touches his nose. (film) Nim Places His Nose – A chimpanzee puts the nose on a picture. (film) No – A boy tries to find his ‘no’. (film) No A Go Go – A man can’t catch the word ‘no’. (cartoon) No A Go Go -- A man chases after the word &quot;NO.&quot; (cartoon w/ music added) No Excitement At The Zoo - Ernie tells Bert about his trip to the zoo. No Joke – Herry , Bert , and Ernie with a no sign. No Park – A woman says ‘no’ to a gorilla . (film) Noses On Animals, Noses On Man -- A face has different noses drawn on it. (cartoon) “ Nothing To Count ” – The Count imagines things to count. Nursing Baby Animals - Baby animals drink milk from their mothers. (film) 

 O 

 O: A Horse And An O – A funny story about a lowercase ‘o.’ (cartoon) “ O Imagination Song ” -- An imaginative song about the letter O. (cartoon) Octagon Umbrella Stop Sign -- Two common octagonal objects. (animation) &quot; Octopus Blues &quot; -- An octopus is sad. Octopus Film Tag – Shala hugs Kermit. Oh What A Fabulous Party -- Strange guests sit next to each other at a party. (cartoon) Old King Cole Adds Up to 3 – Ernie adds fiddlers until there are three. (w/ Anything Muppets) &quot; On My Pond &quot; -- Kermit sings to keep his pond clean. &quot; One Banana Can&apos;t Grow Alone &quot; -- Bananas always grow in bunches. (Anything Muppets) &quot; One Fine Face &quot; -- Elmo and Ernie show off their faces. One Of These Things Spies – Bob and Maria meet down by the docks. &quot; One Potato &quot; - The Count counts potatoes and other things. ( SSvideo ) “ One Thing Leads To Another ” – Judy Collins and Biff sing together. &quot; One, Two, Three &quot; -- Song about one, two, three. (w/ Deadly Nightshade ) One Way -- A man reads a one way sign out loud. (cartoon) One Way Signs – A boy finds his way with ‘one way’ signs. (cartoon) One Way Sounds -- A man comes across a sign and sounds it out. (cartoon w/ added sound effects) One Way Traffic – Kids follow a one way sign. (film) Ookyook Song -- It&apos;s &quot;ookyook&quot; in the Alaskan winter. (film) Open – A man reads the word ‘open’. (cartoon) Open – The word ‘open’ is demonstrated. (film) Open The Toy Closet – Harvey Kneeslapper’s plan backfires. (Anything Muppets) Opera Blending -- An opera that sounds out words. (w/ Madame Schwartzhead ) Operatic Orange – An orange sings Habanera from Carmen. (animation) ” Opposite Song ” -- Cecille sings about opposites. (cartoon) “ Opposite Stuff ” – A man sings and demonstrates opposites. (Anything Muppets) Orange Commercial – A poem about ways to enjoy an orange. (animation) Orange - unpeeled/peeled -- An adult cuts and kids eat an orange. (animation w/ revised music) &quot; Oscar&apos;s Junk Band &quot; - Oscar has his own band. (edited) ( SSvideo ) Oscar And The Chicken – A chicken lays an egg on Oscar’s head. (w/ David ) Othmar the Grouch Lands On Sesame Street – Oscar welcomes a Grouch from outer space. (w/ Olivia , Linda , Luis ) Otters Swim – Otters swim and play in the water. (film) Out – Characters run out of the word ‘out’. (cartoon) Over, Under, Around, Through -- A tennis match with Martina Navratilova . (w/ Maria and Luis) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Over And Under And Through &quot; -- Grover runs around a set of swinging doors. Oysters&amp;Castles -- Baby oysters by the seashore. (cartoon) 

 P 

 P: Pencil – A talking typewriter types a ‘p’ for pencil. P: Penguin – ‘Penguin’ begins with the ‘puh’ sound. (cartoon) P: Picnic -- A picnic of foods that all begin with P. (cartoon) Painting the Letter B -- Kids paint things that begin with &apos;B&apos;. (edited film w/ new music) ( SSvideo ) Panda – A giant panda eats and walks around. (film) Paper Bag Game – Maria has to guess what’s in the paper bag. (w/ Luis ) “ Paper Clip Song ” – Bert sings about why he loves paper clips. (w/ Ernie) Park Ranger: Nature Detectives -- Kids discover animals in a city park. (film) Parrot Shadow Puppet – Hands form a shadow puppet on the wall. (film) Parts Of An Apple – All, none, and some of an apple. (animation) Pass The Football On 1 – Pass the football with Joe Namath . ( SSvideo ) Paul Simon: “ Me&amp;Julio ” – Kids enjoy a song with Paul Simon . “ Paying Attention Song ” – Sometimes it’s nice to be quiet and listen. (film) Peanut Butter And Bread – Bert and Ernie decide to share what they have. &quot; Peanut Butter Factory &quot; -- How peanut butter is made. (film; 1980s version) Peggy Fleming: Letter O – Peggy Fleming skates a letter ‘o’. (film) Peggy Fleming: Number 6 – Peggy Fleming skates a numeral 6. (film) Peggy Fleming: Under – Peggy Fleming skates under two partners. (film) Peligro Bird -- An owl warns a boy of &quot;peligro.&quot; (cartoon) Penguins 1-20 -- Kids count as 20 penguins slide into a pool. Penguins Take A Bath -- Penguins swim around and take a bath. &quot; People In Your Neighborhood &quot; (from Sesame Street, Special ; w/ Bob, Oscar, Bruno, Barbara Walters , Martina Navratilova , Ralph Nader ) ( SSvideo ) &quot;People In Your Neighborhood&quot; -- Bob meets a dentist and a bus driver. “People In Your Neighborhood” – Bob meets a teacher and a newsdealer. &quot;People In Your Neighborhood&quot; -- Bob meets a grocer and a doctor. &quot;People In Your Neighborhood&quot; -- Learn who works at night. (w/ Hoots and Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) &quot;People In Your Neighborhood&quot; -- A librarian and a plumber are your neighbors. (w/ David and Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Peter’s Chair – Barbara Bush reads a book aloud. (w/ Big Bird and the Count) “ Phone Book Alphabet ” – Bob and Big Bird sing names in a phone book. Piano Practice -- Practicing helps you play piano better. (film) Pig In A China Shop -- Animals barge into a fragile store. (w/ Simon Soundman ) “ Pigeons On Parade ” – Bert and his pigeons put on a show. (w/ Big Bird , Olivia , Mr. Hooper , Luis) &quot; Piggies Alphabet &quot; -- A boogie-woogie farm ABC song. (w/ The Oinker Sisters ) Ping Pong Paddle – David can’t play without a paddle. (w/ Maria) Pink Elephant -- A man has trouble getting a balloon through a door. (cartoon) Pirates Plan Ahead -- Pirates bring along extra supplies. (cartoon) PIYN: Lifeguard and Carpenter -- Bob meets two people in your neighborhood. &quot; Placido Peligro &quot; – Placido sings about dangers. Planning Clothes To Wear -- A girl plans what she will wear in the snow. (cartoon) Planning For The Flood – Ernie prepares for a chance of rain. (w/ Bert) Planting Letters F – A girl grows ‘F’ and ‘f’ in her garden. (animation) Playing Chopsticks – The Two Headed Monster plays the piano. &quot; Please Be Careful &quot; -- Be careful when you cross the street. (w/ The Four Tops ) ( SSvideo ) Poem About Hands - Elmo recites a poem he wrote. (w/ Luis, David, Big Bird, Oscar and Linda) Policeman Drawing – Kids direct how to draw a police officer. (animation) Practice Riding Eggbeaters – Teeny Little Super Guy helps Jane practice. Practice Violin – A boy practices playing his violin. (cartoon) Prairie Dawn Invites 3 -- Prairie Dawn invites monsters over for dinner. (w/ Cookie Monster, Grover, Herry Monster) ( SSvideo ) Prairie Dog -- Prairie dogs playing in a video set to music. Pretenting With Grover -- Playing pretend is out of this world! ( SSvideo ) &quot; Pretty Little Song &quot; -- A man tries to remember how a song ends. (Anything Muppets) Prince And Princess Fairytale – Fairy godmonster Grover tells a story. (w/ David, Maria, Kermit, Gladys the Cow) Prince Charming And Oscar - Prince Charming cannot find Sleeping Beauty . (w/Bob) ( SSvideo ) Professor Fred’s Body Parts – Fred the Horse and kids talk about body parts. Professor Grover Listens -- Professor Grover on the importance of listening. Professor Grover: School -- Grover tries to teach kids about school. Professor Grover: Tub Tips -- Grover teaches us about taking a bath. “ Proud Of Me ” – Grover is proud to be himself. &quot; Proud to be a Cow &quot; -- Gladys is proud to be a cow. (w/ Buster the Horse and Fred the Wonder Horse ) “ Put Down The Duckie ” – Ernie has to set Rubber Duckie down to play. (celebrity version w/o Paul Reubens ) &quot;Put Down The Duckie&quot; -- Ernie puts down the duck and picks up a sax. (w/ Hoots the Owl ) Puzzle Cowboy&amp;Horse -- A cowboy&apos;s horse literally falls to pieces. (cartoon) 

 Q 

 Q: Herry And John John – Herry and John John talk about the letter ‘Q’. ( SSvideo ) Q: Quarter – The letter “Q” and the word “quarter”. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Q: Quiet – A talking typewriter types a “q” for quiet. ( SSvideo ) Q: Quiet – Grover and his friends spell out ‘walk.’ ( SSvideo ) Queen Latifah: “ The Letter O ” – Queen Latifah raps with Prairie and Telly . (w/ Merry Monster ) ( SSvideo ) “ Queen Of 6 ” – The Queen of Six has a lovely garden. ( SSvideo ) “ Quiet Is ” – Gordon and Olivia sing a song about quiet. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Quiet Time &quot; With Ernie -- Ernie takes some time to rest and relax. (w/ Gladys the Cow) ( SSvideo ) 

 R 

 R-un Blending -- Muppets sound out the word &quot;run&quot;. R: Rhinoceros – Rhinoceros begins with the ‘ruh’ sound. (cartoon) R: Rope – A talking typewriter types an “r” for rope. R: Run, Roar -- Telly and a lion make the letter R sound. Rain Dance -- A family on a farm waits for rain. (clay animation) Rainy Day Memories – Oscar tells the story of when he met Slimey . “ Rainy Day Song ” – Rain is important in many different ways. (film) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Raise Your Hand &quot; -- A song about raising your hand in class. (with Little Chrissy ) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Rappin&apos; Alphabet &quot; -- Grover break dances with an alphabet rap. (w/ Ferlinghetti Donizetti ) ( SSvideo ) Rat, Mat And Fat – Ernie and Jason make words that end with –at. Rattlers Short and Long -- Being long isn&apos;t better than being short. (cartoon) Ray Charles Sings The Alphabet – Ray Charles performs with kids. Ray Charles: “ I Got A Song ” – Bert and Ernie perform with Ray Charles. “ Reach Your Hand Up High ” – A song about reaching for things. (film) &quot; Readers of the Open Range &quot; -- Two cowboys and one cowgirl read signs. Reading And Jumping Rope – One of these kids is doing his own thing. Reading Lesson -- Aristotle shows how to read braille. (w/Big Bird) ( SSvideo ) Real Grouches Don&apos;t Dance -- Tito Puente plays the drums. (w/ Oscar) ( SSvideo ) Recycling Aluminum Cans -- Cans go to a plant to get made into new cans. (film) ( SSvideo ) Recycling Newspaper -- A girl learns how newspaper is recycled. (film) ( SSvideo ) Redwood Tree Song -- Three turtles sing a round of music. (cartoon) “ Remember I Love You ” – Forgetful Jones always remembers love. (w/ Clementine ) Remember The Loaf Of Bread -- A boy remembers to buy a loaf of bread. (cartoon) Rhinoceros Tag – Madeline Kahn loves rhinoceroces. Rhinos In Love - &quot; Pretty Baby &quot; -- A song about two rhinos in love. (film) &quot; Rhyme Out &quot; - A song about rhyming. (w/ Maria, Luis and Big Bird) ( SSvideo ) Rhyming And Stealing -- He shows who took his clothes! (cartoon) Rhyme: Animals Clothes -- A man&apos;s wardrobe is taken by rhymes! (cartoon) Rhyming: Cat Bat -- A fat cat chases a rat with a baseball bat. (cartoon) Rhythm In Names – A teacher sounds out children’s names. (film) River -- Animals and people depend on the river. Robot Star – People work together to shoot a movie. (cartoon) Rock Music School – Different ways to sing the word ‘baby’. (w/ Olivia and Anything Muppets) Rock &apos;N Roll Star - Little Jerry comes to Sesame Street. (w/Gina, David, and Big Jeffy ) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Rocking Rocks &quot; -- Spin around with these rotating rocks! (animation) ( SSvideo ) Rocks Do Somersaults – Rocks learn to tumble. (animation) Rocks Number 12 -- Counting to twelve with talking rocks. (animation) &quot; Rolling On the River &quot; -- A man rows down the river. (animation) Romancing The Q -- Jeff Goldblume discusses the letter Q. (from episode 2687 ) Room Cerrado -- A Spanish-language clip about open&amp;closed. (cartoon) Roosevelt Franklin : Here/There – Roosevelt tells his class about here and there. Rosie And Elmo&apos;s Alphabet - Rosie and Elmo say the alphabet. Rosita Meets Prairie Dawn – Prairie Dawn meets Rosita for the first time. (from episode 2888 ) “ Rubber Duckie ” – Ernie sings to his rubber duck in the bath. (1970 version) Rube Numbers -- Counting to 20. (cartoon) 

 S 

 S: Grover And Debo – Debo and Grover look at the letter ‘S’. ( SSvideo ) S: Snail – The word ‘snail’ begins with the ‘sss’ sound. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) S: Snake – A snake talks about the letter ‘s’. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) S: Spring – A talking typewriter types a ‘s’ for spring. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Sad &quot; -- Little Jerry and the Monotones sing. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Sad &quot; With Herry -- Herry overslept and missed playing baseball. ( SSvideo ) Salida – Luis finds a door with a ‘salida’ sign. ( SSvideo ) Salida Sign – Kids exit through a door marked ‘salida’. (film) ( SSvideo ) “Salute To The Banana” – A song about ways to enjoy a banana. (animation) ( SSvideo ) Sam the Robot Falls In Love -- Sam the Robot falls in love again. (w/Luis and Gordon) ( SSvideo ) Same And Different – Kermit and Kimberly talk about same and different. ( SSvideo ) Same&amp;Different Song -- Twin performers sing about being the same. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Same&amp;Different With Ernie -- In some ways, Cookie Monster and Ernie are the same. ( SSvideo ) Same&amp;Different With Kermit -- Cookie Monster eats things that are the same. (w/ Kermit) ( SSvideo ) Same As Yours – The Fonz points out his body parts. (film) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Sammy The Snake &quot; – Sammy looks and sounds like the letter &quot;S.&quot; ( SSvideo ) Sand Animation -- Lowercase and uppercase &quot;I&quot; in moving sand. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Save Your Energy For Me &quot; -- Polly Darton asks us to conserve electricity. ( SSvideo ) Savion Glover Rhymes&amp;Taps – Savion taps, claps, snaps, and flaps. (early 1990s version) ( SSvideo ) Say the Word Game Show : Stop – Will he say the word before the buzzer? (w/ Guy Smiley and Maurice Monster ) ( SSvideo ) Scarecrow -- Kids on a farm build a scarecrow. (film) ( SSvideo ) Scared Myself -- A boy befriends his fear of the dark. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) School – The sign ‘school’ is in front of a school. (film) ( SSvideo ) School Game Quiz Show -- Guy Smiley hosts a game show about school. ( SSvideo ) School Pageant : Flower -- Prairie Dawn&apos;s play about how to grow a flower. (w/ Ernie, Herry Monster, Cookie Monster, Bert) ( SSvideo ) School Pageant: Food – Elmo, Leo , Telly and Herry portray food. (w/ Prairie Dawn; ending edited out) ( SSvideo ) School Pageant: Seasons -- Prairie Dawn&apos;s pageant of &quot;The Four Seasons&quot;. (w/ Grover, Bert, Ernie, Herry, Cookie Monster) ( SSvideo ) “ School Song ” – A film of students in a school. ( SSvideo ) School Sounds -- A man rearranges letters to spell school. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) School Stop Action – Things in a classroom prepare for class. (animation) ( SSvideo ) ” Scratch My Back ” -- Monsters take turns scratching backs. (w/ Bip Bippadotta) ( SSvideo ) Secret Drawing: Camel -- Kids instruct how to draw a camel. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Secret Drawing: Fireman -- Kids describe how to draw a fire fighter. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Secret Drawing: Nurse -- Children describe how to draw a nurse. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Secrets Of The Pyramids -- How the pyramids were built using a seesaw. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Seven Giant Teeth – A girl mistakes teeth for fence boards. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Sewing The King&apos;s Pants -- A needle and thread cooperate. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Sh: Falling Leaves – The wind blows leaves and makes the shh sound. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Shala, Bert&amp;Ernie Make Faces – Bert, Ernie and Shala show emotions. ( SSvideo ) “ Sharing ” -- Grover and Prairie Dawn share like friends. ( SSvideo ) Sharing A Bicycle – Cookie Monster and Herry share a bicycle. (w/ Kermit) ( SSvideo ) “ Sharing Swing Song ” – A boy asks another boy for a turn on a swing. (film) ( SSvideo ) Sheep Jumping Over Creek – Seven sheep hop right over a creek. (film) ( SSvideo ) Shoe Factory -- A pair of shoes is manufactured. (film) Shoeing A Horse -- A girl and her grandpa put shoes on a horse. (film) ( SSvideo ) Showing Angry – Andrea Martin and Oscar argue about anger. (w/ Maria) ( SSvideo ) Sick With The Flu -- A man talks about when he had the flu. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Signing Alphabet – The American Sign Language alphabet. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Sing After Me &quot; – Madeline Kahn and Grover sing a duet. ( SSvideo ) Singing In The Rain -- Grover and Prairie sing in the rain. ( SSvideo ) Sitting In For Johnny – Jay Leno plays because Johnny is unavailable. (w/ Big Bird) ( SSvideo ) “Six Kids Subtract In Classroom” – Kids wait for adults to pick them up. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Skating 1-20 – Maria counts kids as they skate by. (film) ( SSvideo ) Sleeping Beauty Is Found -- Prince Charming wakes up Sleeping Beauty. ( SSvideo ) Sleeping Grouch – Oscar kisses the sleeping grouch to wake her. (w/ Grundgetta) ( SSvideo ) Slimey Crosses The Street – Slimey practices crossing the street. (w/ Gordon) ( SSvideo ) Slow Motion Adding Chairs – Mr. Hooper adds chairs in slow motion. ( SSvideo ) Small, Smaller, Smallest -- Each creature is smaller than the last! (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Small, Smaller And Smallest -- A ball brags about being the smallest. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Smokey Robinson: “ It Takes Time ” – Smokey Robinson tells Telly to be patient. ( SSvideo ) “ Snakercise ” – A snake finds exercises he can do. (animation) ( SSvideo ) Snow Dance - Kids dance in the falling snow. (w/ Gordon, Bob, Maria and Oscar) Snow White – Snow White tries counting Dwarves. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) “ The Snuffle Shuffle ” – Snuffleupagus teaches a simple dance. (w/ Susan and the Kids) ( SSvideo ) Snuffle-upa-bus – Snuffleupagus takes a different bus. (w/ Gordon, Linda) ( SSvideo ) Snuffy&amp;Barkley At The Park – Barkley and Snuffy play outdoors. ( SSvideo ) Snuffy And Joey Alphabet – Joey helps Snuffy remember the alphabet. ( SSvideo ) Snuffy Finds Fluffy -- Telly tries to convince Snuffy is real. (w/ David and Gordon) Snuffy Revealed -- Sesame Street sees Mr. Snuffleupagus face-to-face for the first time. (Street scenes from Episode 2096 ) ( SSvideo ) Snuffy’s First Steps – Snuffy shows a home movie of his first steps. (w/ Big Bird, Susan, Gordon) ( SSvideo ) Sofa Imagines -- Imagination becomes a girl&apos;s entertainment. (cartoon w/ added sound effects) ( SSvideo ) Someone To Play With – Stephanie says she will play with Grover. ( SSvideo ) Someone To Watch Over Me -- Ernie watches Bert read a book. ( SSvideo ) Something Is Missing -- Complete a pattern with &quot;ribbit&quot; or &quot;woof.&quot; (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ Song Of The Count ” – The Count sings of his love for counting. ( SSvideo ) “ Song For Judith ” – Judy Collins sings a song about friendship. ( SSvideo ) Song: &quot; Amigo &quot; -- Greeting a new friend who speaks Spanish. (w/ Betty Lou ) ( SSvideo ) Song: Birds Count 1 - 20 -- 20 animated birds are counted in this song. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Song: “ Bus Stop Sign ” – That sign says ‘bus stop’. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Song: &quot; Count It Higher &quot; -- A song about counting higher and higher. (w/ Little Chrissy and the Alphabeats ) ( SSvideo ) Song: “ El Condor Pasa ” – Paul Simon performs on Sesame Street. ( SSvideo ) Song: “ Look Around ” -- A song about a plant in different seasons. (film) ( SSvideo ) Song: &quot; Proud &quot; – A band sings of what makes them feel proud. ( SSvideo ) Song: &quot; Subway &quot; -- A large cast sings about riding the subway. (w/ Bert, Kermit) ( SSvideo ) Song: &quot; Women Can Be &quot; -- Women sing about their wonderful jobs. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Sorting A Family -- A family sorts themselves in different ways. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Sorting Shapes – Maria and Gordon sort shapes by type and color. ( SSvideo ) Sound Man Buys A Saw – A noisy guy has trouble buying a saw. ( SSvideo ) Sound Man Buys A Saw – A shopkeeper figures out a request. ( SSvideo ) Sound Of Letters – A man plays music with different letters. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Sound Man Buys A Trumpet -- A noisy guy has trouble buying a trumpet. ( SSvideo ) Spaceship Surprise -- Exploring the planet &quot;CH&quot;. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Spaceship Surprise: Planet H -- The crew members arrive on the planet H. Special Of The Day: 9 -- Grover recites the menu for a customer . ( SSvideo ) Special Olympics -- Everyone has different strengths. (film) Speedo Skato Bridge -- A short video of an ice skating race. ( SSvideo ) Speedy Maria Subtracts Chairs – Maria takes one chair away. ( SSvideo ) Spinning A Top -- A thumb must work with fingers to spin a top. (Muppet hands) ( SSvideo ) Split Screen Alphabet – Characters recite the alphabet. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Spring In The Woods -- A film about the forest in springtime. ( SSvideo ) &quot;Spring Is Here&quot; -- Everyone sings about the arrival of spring. (w/ Telly, Big Bird, Elmo, The Count, Gordon, Maria, Bob, Forgetful Jones, Oscar, Luis, Oscar and Susan) ( SSvideo ) &quot;Spring Song&quot; -- Sing a spring song. (film) ( SSvideo ) Stair Scales – A ball plays scales on a musical staircase. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Stand By Your Can &quot; – Hammy Swinette sings about using trashcans. ( SSvideo ) “ Starfish Song ” -- Girl sings about a starfish. (film) ( SSvideo ) Start And Stop The Race – This race has to stop before it starts. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Staten Island Ferry Ride – Two brothers ride the ferry together. (film) ( SSvideo ) Steamroller – A steamroller and other tools make a street. (film) ( SSvideo ) Steamshovel – A steamshovel moves dirt. (film) ( SSvideo ) Steel Drum Rhythm -- The world flows to a rhythm. (film) Stevie Wonder With Grover – Grover and Stevie Wonder skat. ( SSvideo ) Stevie Wonder: Loud&amp;Soft – Grover and Stevie Wonder sing loud and soft. ( SSvideo ) Stevie Wonder: Short And Long – Grover and Stevie sing short and long notes. ( SSvideo ) Sticky Four – Harvey Kneeslapper plays a joke. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Still, We Like Each Other &quot; -- Grover sings that friends can be different. ( SSvideo ) ” Stones Don&apos;t Grow ” -- A song about being alive. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Stop – The letter o in the word stop stops bouncing. (animation w/ sound effects) ( SSvideo ) Stop – A quick animation of the word ‘stop’. ( SSvideo ) Stop And Dance – Kids tell dancers when to stop. (w/ Anne Marie and Skeeter Rabbit) ( SSvideo ) Stop And Go – Humphrey teaches Natasha ‘stop’ and ‘go.’ ( SSvideo ) Stop Dance Kids – Dancing kids freeze when they hear “stop”. (film) ( SSvideo ) Stop Sign – Abstract animation of a stop sign. ( SSvideo ) Stop Sign – A picture of a sign that says ‘stop’. (film) ( SSvideo ) Stop That Bus Stop – Grouches install a bus stop in Kermit’s home. (w/ Oscar) ( SSvideo ) Stop The Music – A conductor tells the violinist to stop. (film) ( SSvideo ) Story Of Seven Mice – Bob reads a story of seven mice. (w/ Street intro) ( SSvideo ) Story Of Sheep -- A story about how sheep are raised. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Stranger And The City -- A man lost in a desert finds the city. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Street Bunny -- A bunny reads a ‘street’ sign before crossing. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Street Bunny -- A bunny tells us about the word &quot;street&quot;. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ Street Garden Cooperation ” – Making a garden takes cooperation. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) Subtraction Bowl Round One – A girl wins by writing a subtraction sentence. (w/ Gordon, Maria, Luis, Mr. Hooper) ( SSvideo ) Subtraction Bowl Round Two – A girl wins by subracting on her fingers. ( SSvideo ) “ Sugar Beets ” – Sugar is harvested from sugar beets. (film) ( SSvideo ) Sully Supplies Music – Sully builds a piano for Biff . ( SSvideo ) Sunflower Growing – A boy monitors how tall a sunflower grows. (film) ( SSvideo ) Sunglass Salesman -- Grover tries to sell Kermit sunglasses. ( SSvideo ) Super Grover Barber – Super Grover discovers haircuts don&apos;t hurt. ( SSvideo ) Super Grover Exit – A boy helps himself out of a fence gate. ( SSvideo ) Super Grover Stops The Fight -- Grover sees two boys fighting in the park. (w/ new intro) ( SSvideo ) Super Grover Taking A Bus – A boy figures out how to catch a bus home. (w/ new intro) ( SSvideo ) Super Grover Taking A Bus – A boy figures out how to catch a bus home. ( SSvideo ) Super Grover Telephone – A lost girl calls her mother on the telephone. ( SSvideo ) Super Grover&apos;s Boxes -- Super Grover helps a girl move heavy boxes. ( SSvideo ) Super Grover: Broken Bag – Super Grover helps a girl carry her groceries. (w/ new intro) ( SSvideo ) Super Grover: Cross the Street -- A girl needs help to cross the street. ( SSvideo ) Surprising The British -- George Washington and Grover prepare. ( SSvideo ) Susan Sarandon Counting Knocks – Susan Sarandon and the Count knock on a door. ( SSvideo ) “ Swamp Mushy Muddy ” – Oscar sings a ballad about a swamp he loves. ( SSvideo ) Swan Shadow Puppet – Kids guess what animal a shadow puppet is. (film) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Swim Like Animals -- Leap frog song. (film) ( SSvideo ) “ Swim Like Sea Lions ” – Kids show how they can swim like sea lions. (film) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Swimming Rabbit &quot; -- A rabbit eats grapes and goes for a swim. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ Swingin’ Alphabet ” – A song about letters that have fun at a club. (w/ Olivia, Susan, Maria) ( SSvideo ) 

 T 

 T: Alphabet Dancers – Kids dance and form the letter ‘T.’ ( SSvideo ) T: Party – Some letter ‘T’s throw a T party. (Muppets) ( SSvideo ) T: Train – A talking typewriter types a ‘t’ for train. ( SSvideo ) T: Turtle – Turtle begins with the ‘tuh’ sound. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ Take A Breath ” – All animals need to breathe. (remade film) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Take Care Of That Smile &quot; -- Kids and animals brush their teeth. (film) ( SSvideo ) “ Take My Hand ” – A boy seeks help before he crosses a street. ( Anything Muppets ) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Take A Rest &quot; – Cookie Monster , Grover and Bert sing about resting after doing fun things. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Take The Hand Of One You Love &quot; -- Patti LaBelle sings about love. Taking Care Of My Pet -- Taking care of a dog is worth the work. ( SSvideo ) Taking A Nap – Bert, Ernie , and Shala try to take a nap. ( SSvideo ) Taking a Picture -- Olivia tries to take a picture of Ernestine . ( SSvideo ) Talking With Dolphins-- Kids learn to communicate with dolphins. (film) ( SSvideo ) Tall And Short Ducks -- Two ducks talk about their height. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Tall, Taller, Tallest – Ernie explains tall, taller, and tallest. (w/ Bert and Big Bird ) ( SSvideo ) Taming Of The Shoe -- A Monsterpiece Theater presentation. (w/ Grover) ( SSvideo ) Taxi Sounds – A man fixes a sign so it says &quot;taxi.&quot; (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Teeny Little Super Guy Game -- A girl finds the courage to ask kids to play. ( SSvideo ) Teeny Little Super Guy Traffic -- R.W. asks an adult to get his hat back. ( SSvideo ) Teeny Little Super Guy: Pets -- R.W. learns how to care for a pet. ( SSvideo ) Teeny Little Super Guy: School -- Eugene learns that school is fun. ( SSvideo ) Teeny Little Super Guy: Sleep -- Harry learns the importance of sleep. ( SSvideo ) Telephone – A man makes a call from a telephone booth. (film) ( SSvideo ) Telephone – Maria reads the word ‘telephone’. (animation) ( SSvideo ) “ Tell A Joke ” – Harvey Kneeslapper sings about telling jokes. (w/ Luis , Susan , Bob ) ( SSvideo ) Telly Is Cold – Telly makes the word ‘cold.’ ( SSvideo ) &quot; Ten Commandments of Health &quot; -- A musical guide to staying healthy. (w/ Dr. Thad and the Medications ) ( SSvideo ) That Is Not A Rock -- A caveman discovers his rock is not a dinosaur. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot;That Only Happens At Birdland&quot; - Olivia sings a jazz song with Hoots and the kids. (NOTE: the video this description is attached to what is actually a video featuring Bobby McFerrin scatting the alphabet with Hoots and David.) ( SSvideo ) &quot; That&apos;s What Friends Are For &quot; -- Bert wants to sleep, Ernie wants to sing. ( SSvideo ) ” The Aardvark Song ” – An aardvark sings a song about himself. (1970s version) ( SSvideo ) The Abcs Of Cooperation -- 2-Headed Monsters cooperate with Jane Curtin . ( SSvideo ) The Addition Game – Herry and contestants win by adding. (w/ Guy Smiley and Anything Muppets ) ( SSvideo ) The Air Salesman – Ernie buys air from a sneaky salesman . (w/ Bert) ( SSvideo ) The Alien And The Boy – An alien asks a boy for directions. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Alphabet With Kermit – Kermit talks to Chris and Stephanie. ( SSvideo ) The Amazing Mumford : Rabbits – Grover interferes with Mumford’s practice. ( SSvideo ) The Audience Goes To Lunch - Guy Smiley takes his studio audience to lunch. ( SSvideo ) The Beach After A Storm – A boy explores the beach after a storm. (film) ( SSvideo ) The Beach Bully - A bully brings Bert ice cream to apologize. (w/ Ernie and Tough Eddie ) ( SSvideo ) The Bite In The Apple – Sherlock Hemlock finds an apple&apos;s owner. (w/ Ernie) ( SSvideo ) The Box Salesman -- A salesman sells Ernie an empty box. (w/ Bert) ( SSvideo ) The Bridgekeeper -- The Bridgekeeper is looking for a triangle. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Broken Ukelele, Part One - Ernie tries to make a monster feel better. (w/ Beautiful Day Monster) ( SSvideo ) The Busby Twins Buy A Candle – A shopkeeper figures out what the boys want. ( SSvideo ) The Busby Twins Buy A Hammer – A shopkeeper figures out what the boys want. ( SSvideo ) The Busby Twins Buy A Rocket – A shopkeeper figures out what the boys want. ( SSvideo ) The Cooking Choir – Don Music helps liven up Hooper&apos;s Store . (w/ David ) ( SSvideo ) ”The Cooperation Song -- Kids work together to build a fun fort. (film) ( SSvideo ) The Count Counts Apples – Cookie Monster eats the apples being counted. ( SSvideo ) The Count Counts Flowers – The Count counts first flowers, then sneezes. ( SSvideo ) The Count Proposes - The Count counts proposals. ( SSvideo ) The Count Sleeps Over 1 -- The Count has a sleepover with Bert and Ernie. ( SSvideo ) The Count Sleeps Over 2 -- The Count has a sleepover with Bert and Ernie. ( SSvideo ) The Count Subtracts Candles – The Count takes away candles until it’s dark. ( SSvideo ) The Count’s Picnic – The Count counts things that ants carry away. ( SSvideo ) The Count: 5 Telephone Rings -- The Count won&apos;t let Ernie answer the phone. ( SSvideo ) The Count: Mailbags 1-12 -- The Count counts letters he wrote to himself. ( SSvideo ) The Desert – Plants grow in the dry desert. (film) ( SSvideo ) &quot; The Disco Song &quot; -- Cookie Monster sings a disco song. ( SSvideo ) The Dog And The Bone – A dog loses his bone while acting greedy. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Dog Who Said No – A dog refuses to say yes. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Earmuff Salesman -- Grover tries to sell Kermit some earmuffs. ( SSvideo ) The Electric Fan -- Ernie&apos;s cool fan makes Bert hot and bothered. ( SSvideo ) The Emotions Robot -- A robot that expresses different emotions. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Empty Box – Prairie Dawn has a trash adventure. ( SSvideo ) The Exercise Song -- A bug sings a song to exercise to. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Fairy Godmother -- Cookie Monster is turned into a prince. ( SSvideo ) The Fisherman&amp;The Clam -- Big fish need little fis, which need plants. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Fox&amp;The Grapes – A fox can’t reach the grapes he wants to eat. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “The Garden Song” – Gardening and farming, spring to fall. (film) ( SSvideo ) “ The Google Bugle Song ” – Cookie Monster performs a silly song. (w/ Kermit) ( SSvideo ) The Great Cookie Thief -- Cookie Monster can&apos;t be the cookie thief! ( SSvideo ) ” The Grouch Explorers ” – The Grouch Explorers sing their theme song. (w/ Oscar ) ( SSvideo ) The Half-eaten Sandwich – Sherlock Hemlock investigates Ernie’s lunch. ( SSvideo ) The Ice Capades -- Figure skaters perform a routine. (film) ( SSvideo ) The Ice Cream Salesman -- Ernie buys an invisible ice cream cone. (w/ Lefty the Salesman) ( SSvideo ) The Important Call – An ape boxx will only take important calls. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Itchy Panda -- A panda has an itch that needs scratching. (film) ( SSvideo ) The King And I – A Monsterpiece Theatre presentation. ( SSvideo ) The King Who Ate Only Chicken -- A king learns about eating a balanced meal. (w/ Luis and Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) The King Gives A Picnic – Everyone shows up with the same food! (w/ Maria and Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) The Klutzy Spider -- A very klutzy spider makes his web. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Land Of No Shoelaces -- Edna Lovelaces invents shoelaces. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Leaky Faucet – Martians like the drip of a leaky faucet. ( SSvideo ) The Letter O – Madeline Kahn says the letter ‘o.’ (surprised version) ( SSvideo ) The Letter O – Madeline Kahn says the letter ‘o.’ (questioning version) ( SSvideo ) The Letter O – Madeline Kahn says the letter ‘o.’ (understanding version) ( SSvideo ) The Letter O – Madeline Kahn says the letter ‘o.’ (bashful version) ( SSvideo ) The Lion And The Mouse -- Lion and mouse help one other in unique ways. (1980s cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Lost Elephant -- An elephant asks for directions to the zoo. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Lost Kid -- A lost boy finds a policeman to help him. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) The Love Hug -- The word &quot;love&quot; is hugged by a pair of arms. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; The Mad Goat Song &quot; -- A goat knows it&apos;s ok to get mad sometimes. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Magic Apple – Ernie helps Bob tell a story. (w/ Bert, Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) The Magic Counting Cloth - Cookie Monster discovers a magic cloth. (w/ Kermit) The Magic Finger Square -- Kermit draws a square with his finger. ( SSvideo ) The Magic Finger Triangle -- Kermit teaches kids about triangles. ( SSvideo ) The Most Beautiful Woman -- A man leads a search for a lost boy&apos;s mother. (w/ Bob and Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) “ The Mountain Of Love ” – Little Jerry and the Monotones climb and sing. ( SSvideo ) The Mouse and Elephant -- What if a mouse and elephant switched places? (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Mystery Of The 4 Dragons - A son must find 4 dragons before midnight. ( SSvideo ) The National Bird – How the Bald Eagle was chosen. (w/ Herry, Elmo , Telly, Ernie, Bert, Oscar) ( SSvideo ) The Number 5 Song -- A song about the number five. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Once And Purple King – Savion reads a story about diversity. (w/ Telly, Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) &quot; The Opposites Song &quot; -- A song about differences and opposites. ( Little Chrissy ) ( SSvideo ) The Other Shoe – Ernie won’t sleep until the second shoe drops. (w/ Bert) ( SSvideo ) The Ponca Dance -- The Ponca have a dance contest. (film) ( SSvideo ) The Post Office – A mail carrier describes how mail gets sent. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; The Q-question Song &quot; -- A song about words that begin with Q. (w/ Grover) ( SSvideo ) The Rectangle With Kermit – Kermit describes a rectangle. (w/ Cookie Monster) ( SSvideo ) The Scale Salesman -- A salesman tries to sell Ernie a scale. ( SSvideo ) The Scary Movie -- Ernie can&apos;t keep his feelings quiet enough. (w/ Bert) ( SSvideo ) The Sculptor -- What will he create from the block? (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Seahorses -- A video of seahorses in water, set to music. ( SSvideo ) The Shagri-Las - The shagri-las sing about their shaggy parts. (w/ Athena the Owl) ( SSvideo ) The Skeleton Fish -- Skeleton fish glow and swim in this video. ( SSvideo ) &quot; The Skin Song &quot; -- Close up shots of skin. (film) “ The Sound That’s In The Air ” – Elmo sings about sounds heard all around. ( SSvideo ) The Stop Sign Salesman -- A salesman tries to sell Ernie a stop sign. ( SSvideo ) The Stop Song -- The letter O in STOP needs to stop bouncing. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Story of Umeko And Kuma - A Japanese folk tale about hidden beauty. (w/ Bob, Oscar and Slimey) The Subtraction Tappers – Tap dancers start disappearing one by one. (film) ( SSvideo ) The Telephone Aligator -- An alligator uses the telephone. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Telephone Call -- Someone calls Ernie about a strange picnic. (w/ Bert) ( SSvideo ) The Tire Pump -- A man pumps up a balloon with more air. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Trading Game – Guy Smiley hosts a game show. (w/ Oscar) ( SSvideo ) The Trash Hunt -- Hiroshi makes trash out of art. (w/Oscar, Bruno the Trashman , Gina , Luis, and Maria) ( SSvideo ) The Tree Surgeon -- A tree surgeon takes care of a tree. (film) ( SSvideo ) The Up and Downhill -- Slimey skies up and down a hill. (from episode 3061 ) The Waking Plant – Plants need water to live. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) The Walrus – A video of walruses swimming around. ( SSvideo ) ” The Word Is No – Gina and Maria sing a song about ‘no’. ( SSvideo ) “ There’s A Hole In The Bucket ” – Liza tells Henry how to fix the bucket. (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) There&apos;s A Zoo in Me -- A boy models his emotions after animals. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) There’s No Place Like Home – Mary thinks about places she could live. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) These Shoes are Too Big – A girl pulls pairs of shoes out of the closet. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; They Can’t Take That Away &quot; -- Cookie Monster&apos;s cookies are taken away. (w/ Guy Smiley) ( SSvideo ) &quot; This Frog &quot; - Kermit sings about his hopes and dreams. ( SSvideo ) Thomas Jefferson Needs a Quill – How the Declaration of Independence began. (w/ Don Music and Grover) ( SSvideo ) Three Black Birds In A Tree -- Three blackbirds with three eggs. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Three Plus One – A mathematical showing of three plus one. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Tickle Stop Game – Christopher and Grover play a tickle game. ( SSvideo ) Tiger At School – Tiger talks about reasons to go to school. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Tim Robbins : Seasons Pageant -- Prairie Dawn and Tim Robbins present seasons. ( SSvideo ) Tim Robbins: Surprise – Elmo tries to surprise Tim Robbins. ( SSvideo ) Tito Puente: El Timbalon – Tito Puente plays the drums on Sesame Street. ( SSvideo ) To Tell a Face Game Show -- Baby Bobby picks his grandmother. (w/ Guy Smiley) ( SSvideo ) To The Moon, Oscar – Oscar and Othmar blast off to the moon. (w/ Olivia ) ( SSvideo ) Tony Danza Gets Mad With Oscar – Tony Danza gets mad with Oscar. ( SSvideo ) Tony Danza Jumps -- Tony Danza talks about jumping rope. ( SSvideo ) Tony Danza: Twenty Love – Big Bird and Tony Danza play tennis. ( SSvideo ) Tools For Writing – Kids talk about things they use to write with. (film) ( SSvideo ) Tortillas - Women make tortillas in a competition. (film) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Touch and Feel &quot; - Kids pet animals at a petting zoo. (film) ( SSvideo ) Toy – Maria reads the word ‘toy.’ (animation) ( SSvideo ) Toymaker Airplane -- Watch a carpenter make a wooden airplane. (film) ( SSvideo ) Tracy And Kermit Close and Far – Kermit and Tracy talk about close and far. ( SSvideo ) Trapeze Add And Subtract – Trapeze artists add and subract people. (film) ( SSvideo ) Trapeze Add&amp;Subtract – Trapeze artists combine and separate. (film) ( SSvideo ) Trapeze Up and Down – Trapeze artists demonstrate up and down. (film) ( SSvideo ) Tree Fashion Report -- Ernie reports what trees will be wearing this year. ( SSvideo ) Triangle Is Right Game Show -- A game show about the triangle. (w/ Guy Smiley, Prairie Dawn, Gladys the Cow ) ( SSvideo ) Tricycle Workings – It’ explains how a tricycle works. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ True Blue Miracle ” – A song about what happens at Christmas. (from ‘’ Christmas Eve on Sesame Street ’’) ( SSvideo ) Tuba Or Not Tuba -- Bert tries to make the sound of a tuba. (w/ Simon Soundman and Gladys the Cow) ( SSvideo ) Tug O’war -- Circles work together to move a giant square. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Twinkle Twinkle -- Don Music sings Twinkle Twinkle. (w/ Kermit) Twelve Angry Men – A Monsterpiece Theater presentation. ( SSvideo ) Twiddlebugs Party - Kermit counts 6 Twiddlebugs. ( SSvideo ) Twiddlebugs Postage Stamp – The Twiddlebugs hang a new picture. ( SSvideo ) Twiddlebugs Using the Door -- Twiddlebugs get outside by using the door. ( SSvideo ) Two And Three Mix-up – Maria and David solve a problem. ( SSvideo ) Two Boys Play And Eat -- A boy has dinner at his friend Jamal&apos;s house. (film) ( SSvideo ) Two Headed Monster Shares – The two headed monster shares a pillow. ( SSvideo ) Two Headed Monster Telephone -- The two headed monster answers the telephone. ( SSvideo ) Two Headed Monster: Bubbles -- The two headed monster tries to blow bubbles. ( SSvideo ) Two Headed Monster: Emotions -- The two headed monster shows emotions. ( SSvideo ) Two Headed Monster: Feet -- The two headed monster builds the word &apos;feet&apos;. ( SSvideo ) Two Headed Monster: Honk – The two headed monster reads the word ‘honk.’ (w/ Honkers ) ( SSvideo ) Two Headed Monster: Lullaby – One monster sings a lullaby for another. ( SSvideo ) Two Headed Monster: Mirrors – The two headed monster finds similarities. ( SSvideo ) Two Headed Monster: Mountains -- The 2-headed Monster makes travel plans. (w/ Cookie Monster) ( SSvideo ) Two Headed Monster: Pencil – The two headed monster plays with a pencil. ( SSvideo ) Two Headed Monster: Pop – The two headed monster reads the word ‘pop.’ ( SSvideo ) Two Headed Monster: School – The 2-headed monster reads the word ‘school.’ ( SSvideo ) Two Headed Monster: Soup -- The two headed monster eats with a spoon. ( SSvideo ) Two Headed Monster: Toothbrush – The two headed monster brushes his teeth. ( SSvideo ) Two Headed Monster: Wash – The two headed monster takes a bath. ( SSvideo ) Two-headed Monster Cooperation -- Olivia reads a story about cooperation. (w/ Count Von Count) ( SSvideo ) Two-headed Monster School -- Telly&amp;Elmo act like the Two-Headed Monster. ( SSvideo ) Two Plus One – A mathematical showing of two plus one. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) “ Tying Your Shoelace ” – Savion teaches Elmo how to tie his shoes. (This video currently does not have a “classic” label.) ( SSvideo ) Typewriter Alphabet – Ernie reads Bert the alphabet story he wrote. (1970s version) ( SSvideo ) 

 U 

 “ U Really Got A Hold On Me ” –- Smokey Robinson sings about the letter ‘U.’ ( SSvideo ) U/v Salesman – A salesman tries to sell Ernie a letter. ( SSvideo ) U: The Dog -- An animated letter &quot;U&quot; shows a dog &quot;U&quot; words. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) U: Umbrella – A talking typewriter types a ‘u’ for umbrella. ( SSvideo ) Underwater Ten To One – Animated sea creatures help count backwards. ( SSvideo ) Up&amp;Down: Balls -- Balls fall &quot;up&quot; and &quot;down&quot; in this animation. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Up&amp;Down: Window Shade -- An animation about the words &quot;up&quot; and &quot;down.&quot; (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Up And Down &quot; -- Herry sings about up and down. (w/ Cookie Monster) ( SSvideo ) Upside Down&amp;Right Side Up – One of these kids is doing her own thing. ( SSvideo ) Upstairs, Downstairs -- A Monsterpiece Theater presentation. (w/ Grover) ( SSvideo ) Uses Of An Object -- A family&apos;s big black pot gets a lot of use. (cartoon w/ revised audio) ( SSvideo ) 

 V 

 V: Alphabet Dancers – Kids dance and form the leter ‘v.’ ( SSvideo ) V: Va-voom! – Some words that begin with the letter ‘V.’(cartoon) ( SSvideo ) V: Vacuum – A talking typewriter types a ‘v’ for vacuum. ( SSvideo ) V: Violin – The word violin begins with the ‘vuh’ sound. (Consonant Sound cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Vacuum Cleaner Workings -- How a vacuum cleaner works. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Valentine - I Love You -- A girl writes &quot;I love you&quot; in a heart. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Victor Borge : Practicing -- Victor Borge talks about practicing. ( SSvideo ) Visiting The Baby – A boy visits his new brother at the hospital. (film) ( SSvideo ) 

 W 

 W: Debo And Kermit – Debo knows that the letter ‘W.’ W: Little Girl -- A little girl introduces us to capital &quot;W.&quot; (cartoon) W: Wall – A talking typewriter types a ‘w’ for wall. W: Witch – The word ‘witch’ begins with the sound ‘wuh.’ (cartoon) Waiting For Lefty’s 3 Knocks – Lefty can’t remember the secret knock. (Anything Muppets) Walk – People cross when the sign says ‘walk.’ (film) Walk Animals – Different creatures can all walk. (cartoon) Walk Cars – Cars walk across an intersection. (cartoon) Walk On Grover – The word ‘walk’ walks on Grover. Wanda the Witch - W -- Wanda the Witch&apos;s story is full of &quot;W&quot; words. (cartoon) Wanna Buy An Eight? – Salesman tries to sell Ernie the number 8. &quot; Wash Your Hands &quot; -- A song about the importance of washing hands. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Wash Your Hands Before You Eat &quot; - Olivia sings a song about washing hands. (w/ Big Bird) ( SSvideo ) “ Washing The Dog ” – Neighborhood dogs all get a bath. (film) &quot; Watching All The Triangles Go By &quot; - Telly sings about watching triangles go by. (w/ Luis, Lillian, Savion and Gabi) Water Conservation – Turn off the faucet to save water! (cartoon) Water Fowl – A film of ducks, swans, geese, and flamingoes. &quot; Ways to Get to School &quot; -- There are lots of ways to get to school. (film) &quot; We All Sing The Same Song &quot; -- Kids sing a song about similarities. (film) ( SSvideo ) &quot; We Are All Earthlings &quot; -- A song about how we are all part of the Earth. (w/ Elmo and Big Bird) &quot; Wedding Day &quot; -- A song about a wedding day. (from episode 2485 ) ( SSvideo ) “ We&apos;ll Watch Out for You ” – Bob, Maria and Gordon play police officers. (w/ Leo , Telly, Dexter ) ( SSvideo ) “ We’re A Family ” – Not all families are the same. (w/ David and Anything Muppets) &quot; We’re All The Same &quot; -- A song about how kids have the same feelings. (film) “ Wet And Dry ” – Little Chrissie has fun if he’s wet or dry. (w/ Mr. Handford , Maria) &quot; Wet Paint &quot; -- A music video about wet paint. (w/ / How Now Brown and the Moo Wave ) Wet Paint Lion – A painter paints a lion. (cartoon) “Wet Paint Music Video” – A music video all about wet paint. (w/ Anything Muppet introduction) Whales Swimming And Diving -- Kids observe whales at sea. ( SSvideo ) Whales Swimming And Diving -- Whales are different from fish. (film w/ added music) ( SSvideo ) What&apos;s Inside Herry - Kermit shows what&apos;s inside Herry. “ What Comes After Three? ” – The Count forgets how to count. &quot; What Do I Do When I Am Alone &quot; -- Grover sings of things he does if he&apos;s alone. What Does This Lever Do? – A detective speculates what a lever might do. (cartoon) What Does Love Mean? – Christopher explains love to Grover. What Happens Next Machine – Kermit has a machine that turns on the radio. What Is Love? – Chelsea explains love to Grover. What Is Marriage? – Grover and Jesse discuss what marriage is. What Rhymes With Bert? -- Ernie writes a poem. “What’s Inside?” – Looking inside containers in the kitchen. (w/ Cookie Monster) What&apos;s My Part? – Guy Smiley hosts a body part game show. ( Mr. Foot version) &quot;What&apos;s New Spring Song&quot; -- Singing a spring song. (film) ( SSvideo ) “ What’s The Name Of That Song? ” – Forgetful Jones sings with his friends. (w/ Clementine ) “What’s the Name of That Song?” – No one can remember a song’s name. (1974 version) “What’s the Name of That Song?” – What is that song called? (1991 version) What’s That Line? – A fish is drawn from lines and shapes. (cartoon) &quot; When Bert&apos;s Not Here &quot; -- Ernie tries to sleep in the room alone. Where Do I Belong? -- Contestants learn where they belong. (w/ Guy Smiley) Where&apos;s Mr. Hooper -- Why is Mr. Hooper&apos;s store closed? (from episode 0871 , w/ Big Bird, Bob, Gordon and Mr. Hooper) ( SSvideo ) Whoopi Goldberg Is Proud – Hoots and Whoopi are proud of their bodies. Whoopi Goldberg: Whoopee! -- Whoopi shows the WH sound. ( SSvideo ) Whoopi’s Skin&amp;Elmo’s Fur – Whoopi Goldberg and Elmo compare skin and fur. Why Bears Smile -- A bear covers her nose when sneezing. (cartoon) &quot;Why We Love W&quot; – The National Association of W Lovers meet. (w/ Bert) Wind -- Children witness the wind in several ways. (film) Winter Clotes And Shorts – One of these kids is dressed differently. Without Bert – Ernie plays in ways that would annoy Bert. Wolves – A live action film of wolves. “ Wonderful, Yucky ” – Some things you like, others may not like. (w/ Anything Muppets, Little Bird , Mr. Hooper , Oscar) “ World Without Music ” – What would the world be like without music? (w/ José Feliciano ) &quot; Would You Like To Buy An O? &quot; -- A singing salesman sells Ernie the letter &quot;O&quot;. Write It Down -- Maria and the gang write and rap. (w/Luis, David, and Forgetful Jones ) ( SSvideo ) Writing A Story -- Big Bird and Snuffy write a story together. ( SSvideo ) Wrong Way Grover – Grover explains about a ‘one way’ sign. “ Wynkin, Blynkin And Nod ” – Buffy Ste. Marie sings a song about 3 boys. 

 X 

 &quot; X Marks The Spot &quot; – Sherlock Hemlock sings about the letter X. ( SSvideo ) X: Alphabet Dancers – Kids dance and form the letter ‘X.’ ( SSvideo ) X: Debo, Grover and Kermit – Grover and Debo identify the letter ‘X.’ ( SSvideo ) X: X-ray – A talking typewriter types an ‘x’ for x-ray. ( SSvideo ) 

 Y 

 Y: The Yak -- A &quot;yakkity&quot; yak talks about letter &quot;y&quot;. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Y: Yak -- An animation about the letter &quot;Y&quot; sound. ( SSvideo ) Y: Yo-yo – A talking typewriter types a “y” for yo-yo. ( SSvideo ) Yankee Doodle – Don Music and Kermit write a song together. (w/ Little Chrissy and the Alphabeats) ( SSvideo ) Yes Chase – A man and the word ‘yes’ run. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Yes Machine – A computer that can only answer ‘yes.’ (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Yes Park – A womak keeps saying ‘yes’ when to bananas. (film) ( SSvideo ) Yes Sculptor – A man chisels the word ‘yes.’ (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Yes We Can &quot; -- The Pointer Sisters sing that they can. &quot; Yes We Can Can &quot; -- The Pointer Sisters sing about cooperation. ( SSvideo ) Yes/no Dog – A smart dog answers yes/no questions. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Yesterday, Today, Tomorrow &quot; -- Judy Collins sings about time. ( SSvideo ) Yo Yo Ma: The Jam Session – Yo-Yo Ma plays for Hoots in the arbor. ( SSvideo ) Yoga for Kids – Gordon and kids do some yoga stretches. (film) ( SSvideo ) “ You Can Be A Birdketeer ” – Big Bird sings a Birdketeer song. ( SSvideo ) You Say Yummy; I Say Yucky - Gordon and Oscar like different things. (w/Susan and Fluffy ) ( SSvideo ) Your Mind -- A boy explains things to do with your mind. (w/ Herry Monster) ( SSvideo ) &quot; Young Gifted And Black &quot; -- A song about being proud. (w/ Nina Simone ) ( SSvideo ) 

 Z 

 Z: Climbing -- Mountaineers climb the letter Z. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Z: Zebu – The word ‘zebu’ beginz with the ‘zuh’ sound. (cartoon) ( SSvideo ) Z: Zoo – A talking typewriter types a ‘z’ for zoo. ( SSvideo ) &quot; Zz Blues &quot; -- There aren&apos;t enough Z words for the blues! (Anything Muppets) ( SSvideo ) 
 Retrieved from &quot; http://muppet.wikia.com/wiki/Sesame_Street_Video_Player:_Classic_Clips?oldid=624128 &quot; 
Related Categories
 Category :
 Sesame Street Web Content 
 
Pages on Muppet Wiki
 Add a Page 25,234 pages on
this wiki Advertisement | Your ad here 
Featured Videos
 Are you sure you want to remove this video? Please wait wile we are removing the video Add a video to this page Remove this video Paste this URL in the video embed tool Error occured while loading data. Please recheck your connection and refresh the page. 51 Featured Videos Add a video 07:57 BAFTA 2012 - Miss Piggy&apos;s Red Carpet Show - Orange UK 01:31 Sesame Street OK Go - Three Primary Colors 01:31 Sesame Street &quot;Another Monster at the End of This Book&quot; App Preview St… 01:47 Behind the Scenes of &quot;Song of the Cloud Forest&quot; 02:37 Animal, Merv Griffin and Kermit 00:52 Kermit and Pepe on the London Eye 01:52 Sesame Street Will.i.am Sings &quot;What I Am&quot; 02:54 Visual Thinking 03:55 Bear - It Takes All Kinds 02:37 Muppets Hollywood Walk of Fame Star 02:55 Kermit and Oscar PBS pledge 01:16 Kermit&apos;s Party - Episode 1 Chef&apos;s Catering Catastrophe 02:21 Sesame Workshop honours UNICEF Executive Director Ann M.... 03:47 &quot;I&apos;m Gonna Always Love You&quot; music video 02:54 The Muppet Movie credits alternate audio 01:04 The Muppets Bollywood Spoof trailer Official HD 02:32 Scientific Bear 00:28 Weirdo Express 02:21 Gorilla Television 00:13 Big Bird&apos;s names for Mr. Hooper 01:23 Kermit&apos;s Party - Episode 2 Gonzo Stunt Spectacular! 03:26 Mouse on Mars 01:23 Henson Cat and Mouse 01:23 THE MUPPETS - Kermit and Miss Piggy - Hollywood Walk of Fame Interview 02:13 Miss Piggy 1st appearance 00:58 Weirdo Zone 03:09 Sesame Street Imagine That With Ernie 01:37 Kermit&apos;s Party - Episode 3 Bunsen&amp;Beaker Science Can Be Messy 03:36 Evelyn Glennie and Oscar 00:31 Mr. Johnson Fat Blue 00:13 Sally Ride A Astronaut 01:55 The Jim Henson Hour &quot;Waldo&quot; 01:06 Pointer Sisters Yes We Can Can 00:58 Miss Piggy&amp;Dr. Sanjay Gupta Talk Botox 00:49 Great Muppet Movie Ride 01:47 Muppets Go Hollywood Boogie Motion 02:06 Miss Piggy and Leeora Catalan from Noir Jewelry chat about Fashion 05:33 Scooter at TED 04:36 When Foxy met Kermit and Pepe 01:06 &apos;Coopie&apos; Presents Miss Piggy with First Anderson Award 03:17 Red Book Blog &quot;RCA Stereo Demo&quot; 01:04 Carpenters Sing 02:09 BBC1 promos for Muppets Tonight 02:28 Sesame Place - Thriller 01:14 Bert and Ernie recording for Garmin GPS - Demo 02:25 Bird Family Sesame Street News Flash 07:28 Scott Jurek&amp;Cookie Monster at TEDMED 2012 00:25 Here Come the Muppets commercial 00:31 Miss Piggy Campaign for Real Beauty 03:19 Sesame Street Kermit Sings Disco Frog 01:18 Jim&apos;s Red Book &quot;RCA Car Race&quot; Be the first to add a video 1 of 17 See more&gt; Take our video survey 
Latest photos
 Add a Photo 79,712 photos on this wiki 
 by Scarecroe 
 2012-07-12T01:34:50Z 
Posted in Kyra Sedgwick by Scarecroe 
 2012-07-12T01:23:02Z 
Posted in Muppet Theater Stage by Aleal 
 2012-07-12T01:04:13Z 
Posted in Emanuel Vardi by Scarecroe 
 2012-07-12T00:33:05Z 
Posted in Thread:Toughpigs/@comment-Oscarfan-20120626181121/@comment-Scarecroe-20120712003437 by Armsof.putty 
 2012-07-11T21:35:12Z 
Posted in Gabriel Velez by LegalizeAnythingMuppets 
 2012-07-11T19:18:29Z 
Posted in Sesame Bits ,  more... by Scarecroe 
 2012-07-11T17:25:05Z 
Posted in Thread:Toughpigs/@comment-Oscarfan-20120626181121/@comment-Scarecroe-20120711172519 by JParanoid 
 2012-07-11T17:19:06Z 
Posted in Muppets Who Grow Teeth and Tongues by Jbrangwynne53 
 2012-07-11T01:02:53Z 
Posted in Little Anything Muppets ,  more... by Jbrangwynne53 
 2012-07-11T01:02:53Z 
Posted in Little Anything Muppets ,  more... by Jbrangwynne53 
 2012-07-11T01:02:52Z 
Posted in Little Anything Muppets See all photos 
 See more &gt; 
Recent Wiki Activity

 Oscar&apos;s trash can edited by Scarecroe 1 minute ago Violin and Bow edited by Jbrangwynne53 22 minutes ago Rapunzel edited by Jbrangwynne53 48 minutes ago Fenwick edited by Jbrangwynne53 58 minutes ago 
 See more &gt; 
Around Wikia&apos;s network
 Random Wiki 
 
 
Wikia Inc Navigation
 [ Entertainment ] 
 About Community Central Careers Advertise API Contact Wikia Terms of Use Privacy Policy Content is available under CC-BY-SA .
	</body>
</document>
