<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000576" url="http://reportyourcomplaint.com/adt-security-service-a-review-of-a-big-corporate-scam/" time="2012-07-12-15:52" support="1" score="0.001903780231929769" bingtitle="ADT security service - a review of a big corporate scam! | Report ..." webtitle="ADT security service - a review of a big corporate scam! | Report Your Complaint.com">
			<query id="001292" bing-rank="28"/>
	<description>... tried to overcharge me and also messed up my order ... in the mean time i am still expected to pay the bill on ... fast food fast food restaurant food fraud health Helpful helpful ...</description>
	<body>
		Log In 
 
 RYC (Home) Companies Complaints Reviews Compliments Helpful tips&amp;info Credit repair About us Site Index Blog 
 

 
Random Posts

 North Carolina State Troopers Complaint - They Gave Me A Ticket I Should Not Have Recieved! WebHostingPad.com Amazon.com, a review of the A to Z guarantee program and how consumers are fraudulantly getting free items! UNCC, police, recent marijuana arrests involving students and could they be using their time more wisely? Its Just Lunch Dating Service Scam - Wasted My Money And Time On Pointless Dates American Eagle Complaint - Store Visa Credit Card Offer Which Resulted In A Headache! Yankee Candle Home Frangrance Oil Warmer and Scents Compliment - Amazing Fragrances That Are Inexpensive and Perfect For Your Home! Rug Doctor carpet steam cleaner - clearly the best for DIY in home rug cleaning! VacMaster Pro90 Vacuum Sealer Review - Bass Pro Shops High Quality Vacuum Sealer Sold At A Great Price! Goldwell Shampoo and Conditioner for color treated hair is the only shampoo and conditioner I have tried that doesn&apos;t make my skin break out. 
 
Recent Comments

 skyday on Great Stuff insulating foam sealant review–this stuff works great for sealing and insulating gaps and cracks SCAM on Childhood leukemia Foundation–a review of a shady charity that uses auto dialers and other shady practices to get donations Mike on HomeVestors home buyers is a shady scam and offers you far less than your home is worth! Chris Brady on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? Lee on Stanley Steemer–fraudulant business practices, abusive telemarketing and a bad rug cleaning experience! Lisa Carroll on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? brenda on Walgreen’s pharmacy–incorrectly filled prescription and they refused to fix it! S.K. Thompson on Virginia State Troopers Complaint–Police officers have too much power and get away with breaking laws! 
 Privacy Policy 
ADT security service–a review of a big corporate scam!
 By Boffmanoa 
 




You’d be hard pressed to drive through any neighborhood and not see an ADT security sign somewhere.  ADT has become one of the largest home security and protection service related companies in the United States.  Unfortunately they’ve put revenues above all else.  They have one of the worst customer service and billing reputations out there.

ADT has been fined and otherwise penalized in many states for abusive billing and sales practices.  Just look them up on the internet and you will see thousands of complaints and some of these will blow your mind.  This is basically what happened to me.  ADT was preinstalled in the house that I purchased and so I decide to start up their service.  This ended up being a huge mistake, but anyway, I and their sales rep negotiated and we agreed at a price of $40 per month.  The sales rep stated that it would never go up during the period of the contract.  The contract in question was for three years.

 Restore worn and cloudy headlights to new again at great savings! 

Well just about six or seven months into the contract ADT sent me a letter stating that my price was going to increase.  I called ADT customer service to tell them that that was not in my policy.   I signed and agreed with their sales representative that my price was going to be exactly what we agreed to–the $40 per month.  I told him that my sales representative stated that for the period of my contract of three years the price could not increase at all.

Then I found out that when you look at the contract and the small print which of course the sales  representative did not go over or apparently even adhere to, stated that ADT has the right to increase your rates a few months into the contract.  So their sales representatives completely lie to you and then ADT doesn’t care and adheres to their contract.  They were even going to listen to me at all.




 Your Ad Here 


I even filed a complaint with the local Better Business Bureau and ADT laughed at them.  Only after several responses and the fact that I found that ADT was in the news in California for all sorts of bad business and billing practices did they finally relent and let me out of the contract.  Apparently ADT had a bunch of unethical executives there that are all about the bottom line profits.  They completely forgot about servicing customers and trying to get repeat business.  They look as these contracts as a guaranteed payment for a period of three years or more and they didn’t care if they provided a service or not during that time.

 Learn how our readers are downloading the latest movies, music, software and games 100% free and safe with the best in VPNs! 

Well, in the end ADT is now hurting from their unethical behavior as they have more complaints than all the other home security companies put together.  ADT has also had to pay more fines and faced more penalties and similar than all the other security companies put together.  That is a terrible record and a company that I definitely cannot recommend to anyone.  I advised you completely stay away from the three letters ADT!  When they come calling run the other way–don’t walk!



 
Posts Related to ADT security service - a review of a big corporate scam!

 
 Most popular posts, complaints, reviews and raves along with the top keywords and phrases for June on ReportYourComplaint. 

// I just finished tallying the results for the most popular posts and complaints on RYC for the month of June. I also decided to ...
 
 CLEAR internet service complaint–DO NOT USE CLEAR INTERNET! 

// WHAT EVER YOU DO, DO NOT USE CLEAR INTERNET SERVICE. TRUST ME, YOU WILL BE SORRY. CLEAR IS A NEW INTERNET CARRIER CO. THAT ...
 
 Sokolove law firm and Accutane – are they for real or is this all a scam? 

// This may sound weird, but it really isn&apos;t and I&apos;ll explain to you why in just a second. When I was 16 years old ...
 
 Top complaints, reviews and compliments on ReportYourComplaint for August 2010! 

// It&apos;s that time again to post the top articles, complaints, reviews and more for the month of August 2010. There are some changes this ...
 
 Nigerian scams are still alive and well–look at what I received in my email today! 

// You would think that with all the publicity surrounding scams and TV shows like American Greed and others that these Nigerian type scammers would ...
 
 
 Tags: ADT , ADT security , bad customer service , complaint , Not recommended , scam , sucks , Terrible 
 
15 Responses to ADT security service–a review of a big corporate scam! 
 Newer Comments→ 
 Freddy G. on April 22, 2010 at 6:03 AM 

I agree with you. From my experience ADT is a scam. They installed my system and were not able to get it to work. After 2 months of repeated repairs, reinstallations, etc…it still did not work. Yet they billed me the whole time. Then when I wanted to end the contract because the system did not work they said that was fine but sent me a bill for the entire amount of the 3 year contract–$1,879! Can you believe that. When I refused to pay it they sent me to collections and placed a negative entry on my credit report! I am still battling with them to get it off my credit report. I have sent complaints to my state attorney general and the Better Business Bureau to no avail as of yet! Does anyone have any helpful tips for me of what other steps I can take to get ADT to stop these wrongful billing practices?
 
Well-loved. Like or Dislike: 6   1 
 Sharlene Montemarano on July 8, 2010 at 12:36 PM 

I don’t have a ADT security and never did. Yet, they keep calling me and telling me that if I don’t pay them on my account that they will send it to collections. I never signed up with ADT and I don’t even have a security system in my house other than my dog. Someone please tell them to stop calling me–this is grasping at its worst as they call me multiple times each and every single day and it’s in a threatening manner.

Like or Dislike: 3   1 
 Marketiva S. on July 19, 2010 at 12:32 AM 

Yes, ADT screwed me over too. They installed a faulty security system and refused to stop billing me even though the system didn’t work. They are slimeballs and creeps.

Like or Dislike: 3   1 
 BOB on September 3, 2010 at 8:06 AM 

ADT is Garbage!
 
Well-loved. Like or Dislike: 4   0 
 Peter Pan on October 23, 2010 at 9:42 AM 

Such a usefule blog…wow !!!!
 
Well-loved. Like or Dislike: 5   0 
 Nonya on November 1, 2010 at 12:26 PM 

ADT sucks! I am paying a penalty to terminate my contract early with them and I am happy to pay the penalty because the new security company is not a rip off!

Like or Dislike: 3   0 
 tracey on November 2, 2010 at 2:58 PM 

I want to also warn anyone of getting adt. My house was robbed anyway. when i called ADT they said they would be out in 2 hours and never came that night. They rescheduled for the next day at 8 am and when did they come? at 2 pm. I missed a whole day at work waiting for the tech to basically tell me the system failed and i was taken by one of ADT subcontractors because they didn’t even install the right system. They scheduled a week later to put in a new system in the mean time i am still expected to pay the bill on a system that wasn’t even working and i am still waiting for the contractor to show up to install it. he’s only 7 hours late and another day of work lost. my home owners has $1000 deductible i have to come up with cause of course adt won’t pay it. whatever you do. DO NOT GET ADT!

Like or Dislike: 2   0 
 nick on January 3, 2011 at 4:40 PM 

Same thing happened here too. System never worked. I had a balance of 70$ for a fix they did in the connection (there was a preinstalled system). I tried to pay it several times through their website which couldn’t accept my credit card. Eventually they ended up calling me and putting me on hold. Can you believe this. Their system would call me 3 times per day or more and put me on hold for over 30 minutes. I called them several times to come and fix the system. They never came. I canceled the contract and although the sales person said there was not going to be any termination fee. Guess what, I am battling with collection agencies now.
ADT is really the biggest scam. Very expensive 35$/month and they require a 3 year contract that makes no sense. Why 3 years? Do they commit resources? Do they have to do planning? all they do is just call the police. ADT security is a 100% scam!

Like or Dislike: 1   0 
 Nathan on January 5, 2011 at 2:32 PM 

I don’t know if my system works or not but I have rarely used it since I got it installed. It became more of a hassle to work with then it was to just leave it be. I tried canceling but decided I couldn’t afford a huge fee all at once to cancel. 2 years now into my contract and I’ve moved to a new house. They don’t offer any sort of transfer of my service. I have to pay $578 dollars for the remaining service and then another $228 installation fee and sign a NEW contract for 3 MORE years?!?!? This is the worst scam I’ve ever seen. I obviously opted to just continue service at the old house which I still own until the contract is up so I can get out of it all at that point. I HIGHLY recommend staying as far away from ADT as humanly possible. It’s the most ridiculous setup that I’ve ever seen.

Like or Dislike: 1   0 
 peter on February 16, 2011 at 2:21 PM 

I have a business and the building I lease is being foreclosed on. ADT wants to charge me $600 to terminate the contract. ADT told me I have a five year contract. I have looked through the papers but cannot find any such information.

Spend ten minutes surfing Google and you’ll find hundreds of people who continue to complain about ADT. This will be the last time I use ADT or Tyco. I have an insurance policy so I’ll opt not to get any security system in the future.

And after talking with my brother in-law, who’s a cop, I’m 100% sure I will never get another security system. Aside from the time delay, the cops won’t get there in time to catch someone breaking in. So what’s the difference if the cops come at 2AM or at 8AM when I open?

Peter West Michigan

Like or Dislike: 1   0 
 
 Newer Comments→ 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
Search Website
 Most Popular
Complaints, Reviews, and Compliments! Want your company&apos;s product or service reviewed?
 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 Your Ad Here 
Tags
 automotive Awesome bad customer service car car dealer car dealership chain restaurants Charlotte Charlotte NC complaint compliment Customer service disgusting Educational fast food fast food restaurant food fraud health Helpful helpful information highly recommended honest review Horrible horrible customer service horrible service How to illegal Interesting Not recommended rave recommended restaurant review ripoff rude save money scam sucks Terrible unfair business practices unhealthy untrustworthy Walmart website Copyright©2012 Report Your Complaint.com . All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
