<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000885" url="http://articles.chicagotribune.com/keyword/kfc" time="2012-07-12-16:14" support="1" score="0.0019567720536585076" bingtitle="Articles about Kfc - Chicago Tribune - Featured Articles From The ..." webtitle="Articles about Kfc - Chicago Tribune">
			<query id="000257" bing-rank="131"/>
	<description>... manager during a robbery at a South Side fast-food restaurant ... stated that he was going to shoot the cashier if ... Recently he sought to confirm that it was a ...</description>
	<body>
		Advertisement 
 Front Page News Sports Business Entertainment Opinion Lifestyle 
 
 All Sections 
 Front Page News Sports Business Entertainment Opinion Lifestyle 
 
 Home &gt; Featured Articles &gt; Kfc IN THE NEWS 
Kfc
 FIND MORE STORIES ABOUT: 
 Restaurant Redeye Chicken Paul Mccartney Fast-food Restaurant |   More 
 FEATURED ARTICLES ARTICLES BY DATE NEWS 
 Dangerous voting 
 By Doug Zook | July 6, 2004 A working stiff who votes Republican is like a chicken voting for KFC. NEWS 
 UPDATE 2-Li Ning CEO steps down, founder and TPG exec to lead 
 Reuters | July 4, 2012 * Chief executive steps down with immediate effect * Founder Li Ning to help run firm during search for new CEO * Shares jump on hopes of stronger management By Donny Kwok HONG KONG, July 5 (Reuters) - China&apos;s best known local sportswear group Li Ning Co Ltd, grappling with a slowdown that has halved its share price in recent months, replaced its chief executive on Thursday and said it will focus more on its business in China. The company said founder and Olympic gymnast Li Ning and executive vice-chairman Kim Jin-Goon, who is a managing director at U.S. private equity fund TPG Capital that invested in the retailer this year, will lead the firm during the search for a new CEO after the departure of Zhang Zhiyong. Advertisement NEWS 
 Country Fried Tees 
 June 15, 2007 If you like &quot;vintage&quot; tees, check out kfc.com. Our favorite? The one that reads: &quot;I march to the beat of my own drumstick.&quot; They sell for $15. All proceeds go to KFC Colonel&apos;s Scholars, benefiting high school seniors. NEWS 
 Yankees 4, Mets 3 
 Reuters | June 23, 2012 The Sports Xchange Yankees 4, Mets 3 NEW YORK - On the verge of their fourth loss in a row and second straight to the New York Mets, the Yankees used the weapon that&apos;s bailed them out of trouble most of the season. Raul Ibanez hit a three-run homer in the seventh and Eric Chavez later added his first career pinch-hit homer as the Yankees erased a three-run deficit to beat the Mets 4-3 Saturday night. It was the Mets&apos; first loss in their last five games and it came before 42,122, the largest crowd in Citi Field history. NEWS 
 Fried goodness 
 September 21, 2007 Jennifer Lopez and Marc Anthony get the VIP treatment just about wherever they go -- now including KFC. The fast-food chain reportedly has offered the super-couple an &quot;all-access pass&quot; to any of its locations after catching wind of Anthony&apos;s KFC &quot;addiction,&quot; &quot;Access Hollywood&quot; reported. &quot;You have a bucketful of choices for &apos;afterparty&apos; locations because KFC has more than 5,500 restaurants across the country,&quot; KFC president Gregg Dedrick wrote in an open letter to the couple. NEWS 
 Ibanez, Chavez homers pace Yanks to 4-3 win over Mets 
 Reuters | June 23, 2012 The Sports Xchange Ibanez, Chavez homers pace Yanks to 4-3 win over Mets By Dave Buscema The Sports Xchange NEW YORK -- New York Yankees manager Joe Girardi has countered talk of his hitters&apos; struggles with runners in scoring position this season by pointing out they are always a home run away from erasing the issue. That&apos;s again what happened Saturday night as a pair of seventh-inning home runs helped them avoid a fourth straight loss and a second in a row to the Mets in a 4-3 Subway Series victory. NEWS 
 KFC opens second Indian outlet: Defying militants&apos; threats... 
 October 24, 1995 KFC opens second Indian outlet: Defying militants&apos; threats and government action, Kentucky Fried Chicken opened its second restaurant in India, in an upscale district of New Delhi, the capital, late last week. While serving its internationally known fried chicken, KFC also is providing vegetarian burgers and other items, which are cooked separately, to respect Indian sensitivities. KFC&apos;s first Indian outlet, in the southern city of Bangalore, has been plagued by problems since it opened last June. NEWS 
 UPDATE 1-Burger King eyes China expansion 
 Reuters | June 15, 2012 * Joint venture deal plans 1,000 restaurants in coming years * Deal gives partners exclusive rights to expand in China June 15 (Reuters) - Burger King Worldwide Holdings Inc said on Friday it plans to open 1,000 of its namesake restaurants in China over the next five to seven years under a newly-formed joint venture. China is the world&apos;s fastest growing major economy and U.S. restaurant companies such as Yum Brands Inc, McDonald&apos;s Corp and Starbucks Corp each plan to build hundreds of restaurants there in the coming years. NEWS 
 Vote Reversal Grants Approval To Kfc On Randall Square Lot 
 By Lisa Sloan | November 20, 1997 In a reversal of their Nov. 3 vote, Geneva City Council members have approved the site plan for a KFC restaurant to be built on Randall Road. Council members voted 7-2 to approve a KFC restaurant on the western side of Randall Road in a lot of the Randall Square Shopping Center after the matter was brought before the council by Ald. Renee Brenner, who previously had opposed the plan. At the city&apos;s request, over the past several months, KFC had altered its original site plan substantially, changing the type and color of brick to coordinate with other Randall Square tenant buildings, replacing its standard bright red plastic awnings with a more muted red canvas, shortening its trademark cupola, adding to the landscaping around the garbage area, increasing the length of the drive-through lane, and removing the Col. Sanders image from all signs. ENTERTAINMENT 
 Reviews from Just for Laughs Chicago: Kevin Smith, Hannibal Buress, Janeane Garofalo + Kyle Kinane, Scott Adsit + Kevin Dorff, Patton Oswalt and Stephen Merchant 
 Steve Johnson and Tribune reporter | June 15, 2012 Going into &quot;An Evening with Kevin Smith,&quot; it was difficult to imagine Smith answering audience questions as a Chicago Theatre show and one of the centerpieces of this year&apos;s TBS Just for Laughs Chicago comedy festival. Watching the 41-year-old director hold forth for two hours Thursday night on, mostly, sex, film, weight and weed didn&apos;t do much to change that opinion. Like the joke he made about seeing no need for a 3D version of &quot;Clerks&quot; - his talky, minimally produced breakthrough first feature - the show was a bit lost in one of the city&apos;s big, ornate, showcase spaces. NEWS 
 PETA plans tactics to embarrass KFC 
 By Items compiled from Tribune news services | January 12, 2003 After failing to talk KFC into raising and slaughtering chickens more humanely, People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals said last week it would start a worldwide Kentucky Fried Cruelty campaign featuring a cartoon Col. Sanders grinning wickedly as he slices open a live bird. PETA wants KFC to kill chickens using gas, not knives, and to increase their living space. The group claims &quot;chickens are inquisitive and interesting ... and are thought to be at least as intelligent as dogs or cats.&quot; NEWS 
 Rectangle Oreos and cucumber gum, made in China for China 
 John Ruwitch and Reuters | June 7, 2012 SUZHOU, China (Reuters) - There are no bad ideas inside Kraft Foods&apos; biscuit research lab in China, according to director Maggie Wang. Not even the chewing gum Oreo cookie that a colleague asked her to bite into one day. Instead of creamy white &quot;stuff&quot; in the centre, a glob of gum was sandwiched neatly between a pair of Oreo&apos;s iconic dark chocolate biscuits. &quot;The taste was ok. The problem was that you could not swallow it,&quot; said Wang, a Kraft food scientist with two decades of experience in the biscuit industry. NEWS 
 KFC refuses to talk with PETA&apos;s Pam Anderson ... CBS&apos; Les... 
 November 10, 2003 KFC refuses to talk with PETA&apos;s Pam Anderson ... CBS&apos; Les Moonves addresses &quot;Reagans&quot; cancellation ... Queen Elizabeth honors Pink Floyd&apos;s Dave Gilmour. ---------- Edited by RedEye staff (ritaredeye@tribune.com) NEWS 
 PRESS DIGEST-New Zealand newspapers - May 31 
 Reuters | May 30, 2012 WELLINGTON, May 31 (Reuters) - Following are some of the lead stories from New Zealand metropolitan newspapers on Thursday. Stories may be taken from either the paper or Internet editions of the papers. Reuters has not verified these stories and does not vouch for their accuracy. DOMINION POST(www.stuff.co.nz) Smart, cuddly and special: Grieving parents speak of triplets: The parents of Kiwi triplets lost in the Doha fire have spoken about their children - Lillie, Willsher and Jackson - for the first time, describing them as cuddly, smart, and &quot;very special&quot;. NEWS 
 Claiming Diversion Of Grain, Farmers Sack Chicken Restaurant 
 By Gary Borg | January 31, 1996 Farmers opposed to foreign multinational companies ransacked a Kentucky Fried Chicken (KFC) restaurant in the southern India city of Bangalore on Tuesday. Police said some 50 farmers of the Karnataka State Farmers&apos; Association raided the restaurant after surrounding it during the lunch hour, breaking furniture and kitchenware. A company spokesman in India said KFC was a legitimate investor in the country and had sought all necessary clearances from New Delhi and the state government of Karnataka, of which Bangalore is the capital. FEATURES 
 No Tlc: Farmers Trash Kfc 
 February 6, 1996 Despite what the TV ad claims, not everybody needs a little KFC. Especially not a group of farmers in Bangalore, in southern India. At lunch-time last Tuesday, about 50 ransacked a Kentucky Fried Chicken restaurant, breaking furniture and kitchenware. The farmers, members of a local business group called the Karnataka State Farmers&apos; Association, say foreign businesses like KFC are bad for local business. And they say KFC&apos;s chickens gobble up their limited grain crop, which should feed people. BUSINESS 
 Kfc Branded `Poison&apos; In India 
 By Knight-Ridder/Tribune | October 30, 1995 Defying militants&apos; threats and government action, Kentucky Fried Chicken opened its second restaurant in an upscale district of the capital this month . &quot;We are proud to be here,&quot; said Sandeep Kohli, managing director of KFC India Holdings Pvt. Ltd. &quot;The people of Delhi will be served the same finger-lickin&apos; chicken that 7 million consumers eat every day at 9,400 KFC outlets in more than 78 countries.&quot; KFC also is providing vegetarian burgers and other items, cooked separately, to respect Indian sensitivities. 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 | Next 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 | Next Terms of Service Privacy Policy Index by Date Index by Keyword www.chicagotribune.com Connect 
 Like us on Facebook Follow us on Twitter
	</body>
</document>
