<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000409" url="http://www.qype.co.uk/place/503780-jamies-italian-Bath" time="2012-07-12-15:39" support="5" score="0.004108137569482565" bingtitle="jamie&apos;s italian - Bath - Italian &amp; Pizza Restaurants" webtitle="jamie&apos;s italian - Bath - Italian&amp;Pizza Restaurants">
			<query id="000141" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="001346" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="001342" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="001344" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="001331" bing-rank="181"/>
	<description>It felt like a fast food restaurant, a very busy, stressful ... over tins of tomatoes and the tea-towel napkins. ... The bar area is so small, with so few seats, that ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip navigation 
 Business owner? Write a review Sign up/Login 
 English 
 German French Spanish Portuguese (BP) Portuguese Polish Italian Dutch Turkish 
 Bath 
 Search for: (pizza, pub, the ivy) Where? (town, suburb, postcode...) 
 Bath North and NE Some... South West UK Bath Wiltshire South West UK 
 (2) 
 Search 
 Home Eating&amp;Drinking Nightlife Shopping Arts&amp;Entertainment Services Health&amp;Beauty 
 All 
 
 You are in: United Kingdom » Bath » Eating and Drinking » Restaurant » Italian&amp;Pizza Restaurants »jamie&apos;s italian Events | GUIDES | GROUPS | PEOPLE Close @cookie_info 
Qype uses cookies. By using our site you accept our use of cookies. More information on cookies and preventing cookies. 
 Tweet Add to guide Bookmark Email by kristianak &lt; 
 
 &gt; Upload photo Close 
You can upload as many photos as you want.

Video uploading is a premium business feature. 

 Find out more 
 All photos 
 Unable to upload because Flash is not installed 

Please follow link below to install Flash Player
 Please Install Flash Cancel 
 
jamie&apos;s italian

Bath

 21 reviews Rating details 
 Star distribution 
21 reviews
 3 
 13 
 3 
 2 
 These are other people&apos;s reviews.
How would you rate this place?
 Write a review 
 Write a review Follow us 0 Italian&amp;Pizza Restaurants Bath Address: 
Shire&apos;s Yard, Milsom Street, Bath BA1 1BZ
 Contact us: JamiesItalianUK 

 www.jamieoliver.com/italian/ 
 Opening hours: Open all day Something wrong with this information? 
 This place is listed on Qype multiple times That&apos;s not the name of this place This place has shut down The position on the map is incorrect The category is incorrect This is not a real place! 
 
 User&apos;s info 
 Price range: Pricey Alcohol specialty: Beer/Wine Dress code: Casual Credit cards accepted: Yes Child friendly: Yes Air conditioning: Yes Parking: Street Vegan: No Best for: Friends Groups: Yes Best for: Lunch Give your opinion 
 
 Additional information 
19 reviews of jamie&apos;s italian in English 
 See reviews in more languages 
 German
 (2) 
 
 Cancel Save 
 Thallulah 
Bath
8 reviews Offensive content? 1 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 31 January 2012
 
The food was very disappointing. It felt like a fast food restaurant, a very busy, stressful environment, certainly no place to relax. If you enjoy chain restaurants you would be better advised to go to Cafe Rouge!
 Give the first compliment Compliment 
 Comment Be the first to comment on this review for jamie&apos;s italian 

 Yes, notify me about replies 
 stusdinners 
Bath
24 reviews Offensive content? 4 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 29 August 2011
 
Quite a few people seem to bitch about the antipasta meat plank at Jamies, saying it is too small, expensive , poor quality etc. Must be a different meat plank than the ones I keep getting. This was our sixth visit and a plank of superb quality Italian meats, cheese, music bread, pickles again was excellent, enough to share between two and at less than £7 for two a good starter. Prawn linguini as good as ever, pork chop special seemed to be well appreciated. Service friendly and attentive even though we didn’t leave until 11.45. There are other Italian restaurants in Bath where the food is as good but you cannot beat the buzz of Jamies
 Give the first compliment Compliment 
 Comment Be the first to comment on this review for jamie&apos;s italian 

 Yes, notify me about replies 
 j_tawton 
Bath
16 reviews Offensive content? 2 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 4 August 2011
 
Went here this week as a treat with my wife and was struck immediately by how ambient, well presented and staffed this place is. In fact, I don’t think I’ve ever seen so many staff in a restaurant! It meant we were served very quickly, but it felt like being in the gangway of a sinking ship with the amount of rushing past our table that was going on! Good service though.

And that’s what the stars are for, the decor and the service.

The food was a massive disappointment. It looked great but was bland and not very well cooked I’m afraid.

The nachos were interesting, but seemed to be deep-fried to death and not really anything like nachos.
I then had the meat plank which, whilst varied, was just a bunch of thin slices of supermarket standard salami, ham etc. Very uninspiring. You’d get better from Chandos Deli round the corner.
But my main was very weak. I had Wild Boar sausages in lentils, with posh chips on the side. The sausages were ok, but pitifully small and the lentils literally tasted of tinned tomatoes. That was the entire taste experience.
At the other end of the spectrum were the chips. Deep fried again, so much so that I had trouble getting my fork into them, and completely tasteless.

It was very disapponting, and I’m sure lots of people have nice experiences there, but I’ll not go there again, when there are so many better Italian restaurants in Bath.

Must try harder Jamie.
 Give the first compliment Compliment 
 Comment Be the first to comment on this review for jamie&apos;s italian 

 Yes, notify me about replies 
 susanom 
21 reviews Offensive content? 4 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 22 April 2011
(updated on 23 April 2011
 ) 
was looking forward to trying these. Jamie&apos;s has good ingredients and approach to food. it was good and give it 4 stars instead of 3 ;)
 
Reviewed using iPhone. Get the app 
 Give the first compliment Compliment 
 Comment 3 comments on this review show all 

 Rutchen , 22 April 2011: 
Cool. If you enjoyed it, why only * ?
 susanom , 23 April 2011: 
Hi there, I guess I am a food snob! The food was good (but I used to live in Italy and so it is hard to compare to the food there), but definitely good!
 Rutchen , 26 April 2011: 
Ah! Thank you for explaining. I know what you mean about eating food in Italy :D
 Yes, notify me about replies 
 rachelh83 
5 reviews Offensive content? 4 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 15 March 2011
 
First of all, I should say that I had extremely high expectations for Jamie’s Italian in Bath before visiting, due to the abundance of rave reviews I had heard from friends and family and the media hype surrounding the restaurant. I visited Jamie’s on a Friday lunchtime and, although we had to wait 10 minutes before we were taken upstairs to be seated, I was pleasantly surprised at how quick we were served, having heard stories of ridiculously long waiting times.

The first thing that struck me about this place was that the atmosphere is a lot more relaxed than I’d imagined, it really felt as though I was in an Italian kitchen. It has a rustic feel with metal and wood chairs, meats and breads hanging around the walls and drawers of pasta on display. I think this actually worked against the restaurant and made me feel as though the prices were slightly exaggerated for the informal environment. The restaurant is full of gimmicks including the antipasti served over tins of tomatoes and the tea-towel napkins. I didn’t like the obvious Jamie Oliver marketing, with books and t-shirts lined up in between the wine glasses etc. I did get the feeling that the entire restaurant was trying that little bit too hard.

The menu was full of classic Italian dishes with an interesting Jamie Oliver twist (although there was no lasagne). I had the Turbo Fusilli Arrabiata (a spicy tomato pasta) and it was delicious. We shared a portion of polenta chips and posh chips (chips made with truffle oil and sprinkled with parmesan), and they were definitely up there with my favourites. I didn’t want a dessert but my mother ordered the Tiramisu and that looked gorgeous (again, a generous portion). The menu is fairly pricey even though the servings are quite large and, as is the nature of pasta, very filling. The staff are very friendly (sometimes annoyingly so) and exceptionally attentive. Service was suitably speedy, which is obviously a necessity at lunchtime.

I’m not sure how Jamie’s compares to other restaurants in Bath (I was visiting for the day), especially for evening meals, as I’m guessing you could have a meal in a more elaborate restaurant for the same money. As for the food, I couldn’t really fault it – beautiful!
 Give the first compliment Compliment 
 Comment Be the first to comment on this review for jamie&apos;s italian 

 Yes, notify me about replies 
 cassyput 
Bath
64 reviews Offensive content? 1 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 29 July 2009
(updated on 23 January 2011
 ) 
Overpriced with standard and pretty badly cooked &apos;Italian&apos;. Jamie Oliver trying to make money rather than friends.
 1 compliment Compliment 
 Comment Be the first to comment on this review for jamie&apos;s italian 

 Yes, notify me about replies 
 digitalgr... 
Bath
3 reviews Offensive content? 5 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 11 January 2011
 
Ive been to this restaurant countless times.
Its become a favourite and any time we go for something bigger than pub food/ Spoons/ Nanados/ etc., its where we head. Very good food at affordable prices. the first time we went just for lunch to see what it was like. The food was so tasty and the booth/seating area was so comfy we ended up staying for a few hours and stuffed ourselves silly. We&apos;ve been back so many times, taking friends there for new years, my mother in law for her birthday, and my parents for my pre-wedding celebrations. Fantastic food, and I&apos;ll be back again and again and again.
 Give the first compliment Compliment 
 Comment Be the first to comment on this review for jamie&apos;s italian 

 Yes, notify me about replies 
 Issun_boshi 
Bath
21 reviews Offensive content? 4 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 10 December 2010
(updated on 23 December 2010
 ) 
Food was nice, but not amazing. The pasta was nice, but the grill was just run of the mill.

Service was very good and it had a good atmosphere (even on a Tuesday.

But overall given the amount of italian restaurants in Bath im sure you could get the same or better elsewhere.
 
Reviewed using Android. Get the app 
 Give the first compliment Compliment 
 Comment Be the first to comment on this review for jamie&apos;s italian 

 Yes, notify me about replies 
 jmgj27 
Bath
12 reviews Offensive content? 2 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 19 October 2010
 
There are much better Italian restaurants in Bath. I&apos;ve been three times now and found the food to be very variable in quality. I had a lovely carbonara, which I would definitely have again but, on the other hand, had a couple of prawn pasta dishes which were almost cold when I got them and had about two prawns apiece with no spicy kick to them at all. Waiting staff were preoccupied with better looking diners and apart from an on-the-ball manageress, rather rude overall. The meal was also rather pricey for the quality - costing about £20 per head for two courses and soft drinks. It&apos;s also always rammed and the tables, as others have mentioned, are far too close together - not enjoyable if you have personal space issues! On the upside - good gin and tonic while you&apos;re waiting!
 Give the first compliment Compliment 
 Comment Be the first to comment on this review for jamie&apos;s italian 

 Yes, notify me about replies 
 stcatriona 
Bath
32 reviews Offensive content? 4 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 3 September 2010
 
I went with my husband one (early) lunchtime, just out of interest. The atmosphere was good, the service was excellent and the food was very tasty. The final bill was fine (I&apos;ve had cheaper deals in Bath at lunchtime). Overall, we were pleasantly surprised by the experience but I suspect that a lot had to do with the time we chose to go (I&apos;d heard it&apos;s sometimes difficult to get a table in the evening). The tables were fairly close together so I imagine (although I could be wrong) that it may get very noisy during the evening rush. At the table next to us a mother and son were served with the same efficient, friendly manner and good service as we were and that really helped reinforce my view of what a well-run place it was. We were unsure of which wine to chose and were offered a (generous) sample before committing ourselves to a bottle - that earned extra brownie points! Would recommend it to friends and would definitely go again.
 Give the first compliment Compliment 
 Comment Be the first to comment on this review for jamie&apos;s italian 

 Yes, notify me about replies 
 kristianak 
London
188 reviews Offensive content? 4 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 5 May 2010
 
I agree, I think one of the best things about this place is the service.
Yes, it&apos;s got Jamie&apos;s name on it for the caché, and the design is a bit funky, modern diner style(think metal chairs like Leon, wooden floors and white walls with occasional bursts of colour) Essentially though, it&apos;s just a good Italian with a bustling atmosphere.
As you first walk in and wait for a table there is a small seating / bar area, and the shop where you can buy all the essentials like cookbooks and cutlery ( all with Jamie&apos;s signature on it - natch).

The first floor here opens off a huge counter area / open kitchen hung with cured meats. We were taken up to the second floor which also features on open kitchen and views over the rear buildings. It&apos;s an interesting building in itself, typical sandstone georgian with an extension of glass and metal on the top floor.
There were big trays of dried pasta on display ( not sure if these were for eating or purchase, but hopefully not after many small children have run their hands through it! )
Anyway, the food. We ordered the seasonal meat and vegetable mixed planks which included capers, olives, meats and cheese with chutney, slaw etc. Liked the presentation - served on wooden boards raised on 2 tins of Italian tomatoes and only £6.65 p.p. Kitchy-cute!
We also tried artisian breads with oil and desserts - the chocolate raspberry and amaretto brownie and the lemon ricotta cheescake were both to die for at £4.95.
The most expensive main here is the steak at £16.95, so on the whole it&apos;s pretty reasonable and the food was served quickly.
Our waitress was attentive and smiling and not too pushy. Even though it was really busy we didn&apos;t feel like we were being pushed out to make room for the next group.
These seem to be rolling out across the country at an astonishing pace, so if you can&apos;t get to Bath then I&apos;m sure there will be one near you!
 Give the first compliment Compliment 
 Comment Be the first to comment on this review for jamie&apos;s italian 

 Yes, notify me about replies 
 hayjane 
London
156 reviews Offensive content? 4 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 20 April 2010
 
For a Monday night this place was rammed, so we were lucky to be seated straight away as they don&apos;t accept bookings unless you&apos;re in a big party. The restaurant really hits the nail on the head in terms of the &apos;Jamie Oliver&apos; vibe, with a funky shabby/retro interior, scooter wallpaper and little tea towels for napkins.

The food was really tasty. To start, between three of us we shared some stuffed sweet chilli peppers, some &apos;Italian nachos&apos; (crispy, fried ravioli pasta) and a big bowl of bread. Our main courses were big plates of rustic deliciousness. My carbonara was crammed with flavour, and the thick strands of fresh spaghetti were cooked to pasta-ry perfection.

My parents had the pork belly special (perhaps a tad fatty but really tender) and the &apos;chicken cooked under a brick&apos;, which was deliciously moist with a yummy smoky flavour. We also got sides of &apos;posh truffle chips&apos; (chips drizzled in truffle oil with parmesan) and green beans in a tomato sauce.

The service was really friendly and our waitress knew each of the dishes and specials really well.

The restaurant itself is located in a little courtyard called Milsom Place. We were seated in the mezzanine level next to the cold food preparation area, but watching the chefs slice the meats and prepare the salads and antipasti &apos;planks&apos; (which they casually balance on your table on tins of chopped tomatoes) added to the atmosphere. I was a bit surprised to see them heating the desserts in a microwave - I&apos;m sure most restaurants do this - but normally in the kitchen, rather than in the dining area in full view of everyone.

Also, probably worth noting that, despite being an Italian-themed restaurant, it doesn&apos;t do pizzas.

Overall the restaurant had a great ambiance, the grub was hearty and it really did feel like you were in (one of) Jamie&apos;s kitchen(s). Whether or not Mr Oliver himself has actually stepped foot in this eatery is another question entirely...
 Give the first compliment Compliment 
 Comment Be the first to comment on this review for jamie&apos;s italian 

 Yes, notify me about replies 
 YankeeGirl 
Birmingham
209 reviews Offensive content? 4 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 30 March 2010
 
Jamie Oliver&apos;s Italian restaurant in Bath is not only a restaurant named for a famous chef and using his recipes, but also a unique and interesting dining experience.

Firstly, Jamie&apos;s don&apos;t take bookings unless it&apos;s for a group of 8 or more. So you can&apos;t really plan to go out there. You just have to rock up, prepared for a wait, and see if you luck out. That&apos;s weird, not good. But it keeps things interesting.

Secondly, the seating arrangements are all very close -- there are a few seperate tables, but they&apos;re all pretty close to each other, except in the small, circular back room, where the tables are normally spaced.

In the upstairs seating section, there are benches and chairs laid out in one long table, so you eat family style, similarly to Wagamama&apos;s. It&apos;s fine, as you aren&apos;t close enough to feel awkward, but you are close enough that talking about your monthly cycle may not be a brilliant plan.

We really enjoyed the vibe at the Bath Jamie&apos;s Italian. The hostess/front of house girl was really friendly, and gave us a beeper to hold which would go off when our table was ready. We were told we&apos;d wait half an hour, but were seated within ten minutes.

We first ordered drinks at the bar whilst we waited. The bar area is so small, with so few seats, that it really doesn&apos;t work at all for a restaurant that doesn&apos;t take bookings, and can result in a crowded, uncomfortable bar area while the inevitable wait ensues.

The drinks were very good, only 6 cocktails, or wine or beer. I had a Mojito and my sister had a Bellini, and they were both fine.

We were then seated in a cute, kitschy round room that had wallpaper ripped off in a very fashionable way -- messy is the new clean, dahhlings. The only thing that really clashed with the decor was the trite red acrylic chandelier that just looked like something I&apos;ve seen in a thousand Ikea set ups.

Onto the meal, bad stuff first:

Our waitress was terrible. She brought our food fast enough, no long waits or anything, but was really dismissive, uninterested, didn&apos;t make eye contact, and said, &quot;Um, I don&apos;t know&quot; about every question we asked.

My sister ordered the chicken ceasar salad meal, for £11, but asked to have prawns with it instead, offering to pay the difference if there was one. The girl said they did no substitutions, but then came back and said it was ok. Unfortunately, when she brought it out, she&apos;d brought the starter sized salad, resulting in my sister&apos;s main meal being a small bowl of salad leaves and four prawns. Cheap and tacky, and not Jamie&apos;s style!

Now the good stuff:

the food was aMAZing. So tasty, so fresh, very complex and delicious.

For starters we had the mushrooms baked with cheese and the calimari (both called something different, but I no speaka Italiano).

The calimari was good, not just squid rings, but baby squids as well (ack -- gave those to my sis). The garlic mayonnaise served with it was to die for -- salty, lemony, garlicky and obviously freshly made. You could taste the egg and the spices. Gorgeous.

The mushrooms were very good, and the cheese used with it tasted a bit like a smoky roquefort. The mushrooms and cheese were served on a base of thin fried polenta. All very tasty.

My main was the most beautiful dish, full of intense and interesting flavours. It was wild black truffles with tagliatelle in a butter, parmesan, nutmeg and lemon sauce. It sounds like it wouldn&apos;t work, but there was only a hint of lemon, and the nutmeg just served to bring out the flavour of the truffles. It was fantastic.

All in all, if the service had been better, we&apos;d have really enjoyed our time. But our waitress was getting consistently more neglectful and harried, even with only five tables to wait, so we avoided post-drink cocktails and dessert, and went on somewhere else.

I&apos;d highly recommend Jamie&apos;s Italian for the tremendous food, all priced very reasonably.
 2 compliments Compliment 
 Comment 3 comments on this review show all 

 Leaftop , 30 March 2010: 
He&apos;s a busy lad, did he jet in to make your meal specially? Oh, and absolutely nothing to be ashamed about, I talk openly about my daily cycle, (down to the shops and back!) ;-)
 YankeeGirl , 30 March 2010: 
Do you know, he couldn&apos;t be bothered to show up! Well offended, like, I was.
 Leaftop , 1 April 2010: 
his loss! ;-)
 Yes, notify me about replies 
 SirQuenti... 
Bath
5 reviews Offensive content? 2 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 16 December 2009
 
Went here for my christmas frivolities as part of a large group.

I know that it can be a bit of a mission at times with large parties, but the amount of chefs I saw in the kitchen gave me comfort - at least they had prepared for the sudden rush we would give them! Or so I thought.

Starter was a nice selection of meats on a huge wooden platter for 4. This was nice, the meats were not chilled which is great to see and the motadello was particularly pleasent.

From here on in however, things got a little rusty. My belly of pork was something I was greatly looking forward to. Mostly because I love belly pork, but also because I was keen to see what could be achieved when in the hands of a culinary great such as Jamie Oliver. Disappointing - the &apos;crackling&apos; chewy, the pork flavour almost drowned in a sea of over zested stuffing. I did see some sultanas in there somewhere that were pining to be tasted, but the slightly bitter zest flavour banished it from the plate (which incidentally was scarred with heat dried &apos;jus&apos; of some description. This I was unable to taste because I couldn&apos;t scrape it off with my knife).

The sides were pleasent - some fine french beans and potatoes that were nicely cooked.

Dessert was a &apos;tiramisu&apos; of sorts, with all sorts of other stuff in it. Fine, but not what I was ready for. The caramel rocks on the side were so sloppily done. Sigh.

Anyway all in all, I&apos;ll never go back unless somebody pays me.
 Give the first compliment Compliment 
 Comment Be the first to comment on this review for jamie&apos;s italian 

 Yes, notify me about replies 
 matthew 
2 reviews Offensive content? 4 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 23 August 2009
 
been 5 times in the past 6 months.
great place to spend a chilled sat or sun lunch time catching up with pals,

friendly staff who don’t rush or pester you.

menu continues to develop and always surprised at the more than reasonable prices.

great flavours, never been disappointed
 Give the first compliment Compliment 
 Comment Be the first to comment on this review for jamie&apos;s italian 

 Yes, notify me about replies 
 the_trave... 
Bristol
26 reviews Offensive content? 5 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 6 June 2009
 
First time i came here i wasn’t sure what to expect, would it be an overpriced celebrity chef resaurant or something much more, which very reasonably priced, tastey food served by nice (and attractive, i think this must be one of the selection criteria at interview, lol) staff. Thankfuly it was the latter. On both of my visits so far i’ve managed to squeeze in 3 courses and each visit averaged at about just over £25 including a beer.

Of particular note is the Truffle Tagliatelle main course and the very flavoursome Trio of Sorbe dessert.

Like others have mentioned though, get there early if you dont wish to queue. I’ve arrived at around 6pm on a weekday on both previous visits and been seated straight away, however when leaving at 7.30-8 each time there was a queue outside.
 Give the first compliment Compliment 
 Comment Be the first to comment on this review for jamie&apos;s italian 

 Yes, notify me about replies 
 samhat 
Cardiff
100 reviews Offensive content? 5 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 2 June 2009
 
I loved this restaurant!!It is a lovely place to eat with beautiful food,excellent service and great ambiance.They do not take bookings but you can sit and enjoy a glass of wine whilst waiting.The menu was mouthwatering with a good mix of Italian dishes,prices are reasonable and a lot cheaper than I expected them to be.
 Give the first compliment Compliment 
 Comment Be the first to comment on this review for jamie&apos;s italian 

 Yes, notify me about replies 
 MelM 
Dorking
83 reviews Offensive content? 4 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 29 April 2009
 
Get there early as they get very busy. It’s good but it is expensive, so be diligent when choosing.
 
Reviewed using iPhone. Get the app 
 Give the first compliment Compliment 
 Comment Be the first to comment on this review for jamie&apos;s italian 

 Yes, notify me about replies 
 tryingtob... 
Bath
75 reviews Offensive content? 4 Review of jamie&apos;s italian from 21 February 2009
 
Good, honest, freshly cooked Italian food under the Jamie Oliver brand.

They don’t take bookings, so at busy times you need to queue for a table (there is a bar area where you can wait), or choose to go at less busy times (5 pm opn a Friday seems to work well for us!).

Pasta, meat, fish, good specials as well as the standard menu. The antipasti on a plank is great, they literally balance a piece of wood, loaded with meat and cheese, on two tins of tomatoes on your table.

The kids menu is on a toy that I remember form the seventies, but have no idea of the name - it’s a red plastic eye piece that you hold up to your eyes, look through, and press a little lever to cycle through the choices.

We’ve gone back twice to eat again as it’s so good.
 Give the first compliment Compliment 
 Comment 1 comment on this review 

 firtree , 8 January 2011: 
way to expensive thats if you can get in !!
 Yes, notify me about replies 
 
Write your review of jamie&apos;s italian
 
 1 2 3 4 5 
 Your star rating? Click on the stars You haven&apos;t written anything yet! 
 Not sure Budget Average Pricey High end 
 
Price:
 
What&apos;s your opinion?
 
 Follow jamie&apos;s italian and be the first to know about its latest reviews, special offers, updates and news by email! 
 Publish review 
Places nearby jamie&apos;s italian
 
 The Eastern Eye 8A Quiet Street , Bath BA1 2JS 

 

 Thallulah: “Highly recommended! Stunning decor and space, excellent authentic food and very friendly waiters. We also found this place to be very child friendly!” more... 
 
 ASK Broad Street , Bath BA1 5LP 

 

 cassyput: “I was pleasantly surprised - it doesn&amp;#8217;t feel like part of a chain. The pizzas are not the very, very best but certainly very good and the sta...” more... 
 Print a map View larger map Get Directions 
CHECK-INS
 
With The Qype Mobile App you can find out what&apos;s nearby, check-in at your favourite places and share your location with friends.

Score the most check-ins at a place to become the Champion .
 46470 
Bristol
Champion at jamie&apos;s italian
(1 Check-In) 
 
 1 CHECK-IN Download App 
PLACES NEARBY ...
 
 ... of jamie&apos;s italian 

 
 The Eastern Eye 

 8A Quiet Street , Bath BA1 2JS 

 9 reviews
 
 ASK 

 Broad Street , Bath BA1 5LP 

 6 reviews
 
 Cafe Rouge 

 15 Milsom Street , Bath BA1 1DE 

 6 reviews
 
 Moon&amp;Sixpence Bath 

 6a Broad Street , Bath BA1 5LJ 

 2 reviews
 
 Minibar Gastro Winebar 

 1 John Street , Bath BA1 2JL 

 3 reviews
 
 
 Your bookmark has been removed 
 
 Your bookmark has been saved 
 
 Did you know? 

You can access your bookmarks from our mobile apps!
 
 Want to be updated on this place? 

 - Be the first to know about special offers - Find out about the latest reviews and updated details - Get the latest news 

 Do you want to get our email updates? 

 No thanks Follow us 
 Thanks! 
From now on, we&apos;ll make sure you get updates about this place.
 
 Close
	</body>
</document>
