<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000598" url="http://vactek.tripod.com/904chassisnumbers.html" time="2012-07-12-15:53" support="5" score="0.0031059874296269453" bingtitle="Porsche Chassis Numbers" webtitle="Porsche Chassis Numbers">
			<query id="000270" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="000738" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="000748" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000742" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000734" bing-rank="119"/>
	<description>... US, though we have yet been able to confirm to whom. Werkes Car ... Dieter recalls 904 011) from &quot;906&quot; in order ... A fast-food restaurant pioneer, Mr. Wetanson is ...</description>
	<body>
		Porsche 904 

 
 Number History 

 
 904-001 

 





906-001 
 
 6 
 Cyl., Factory.
1964 : 1000 km Paris - Herbert Linge/Gerhard Mitter DNF. 1965 : Targa 
 Florio - Umberto Maglioli/Herbert Linge 3 OA 2 cl. 1965 : 1000 Km Nürburgring 
 Umberto Maglioli/Herbert Linge 5 OA. 3 cl. 1965 : 24 Hours Le Mans - 
 Herbert Linge/Peter Nöcker 4 OA.1 cl. 1966 : Targa Florio - Vincenzo 
 Arena/Antonio Pucci / I Gerhard Mitter / D Jo Bonnier / S Hans Herrmann 
 / D Dieter Glemser DNS. 1966 : Upgraded with 6 cylinders with leather 
 interior.


1964 : 1000 km Paris Linge/Mitter DNF. 1965 : Targa Florio - Maglioli/Linge 
 3 OA. 1965 : 1000 Km Nürburgring - Maglioli/Linge 5 OA 2cl. 24 
 Hours Le Mans - Nocker/Linge 4 OA 1cl . 1966 : Targa Florio practice 
 car.
24/10/1966 : Sold to Deiter Eberhardt without engine. 1/12/1967 : Sold 
 to Schneider. 29/9/1999 : STPO. 
 
 904-002 

 












































906-002 
 Built 
 in 1963, this car was originally used by the factory as a prototype 
 for testing. Subsequently, it was housed in the factory museum. 
 In 
 1965, it was prepared as a road car for eventual sale to a private customer. 
 For this purpose, it was fitted with a newly available 160 DIN HP, 2.0 
 L, 6-cylinder type 901 motor. 

 In 
 addition, like 904-001 and 904-003, it was rather exotically trimmed 
 with a leather interior. The dash, door panels, sills, seats and the 
 shift-linkage tunnel were all finished with this material. The dash 
 pod was of a unique design, containing three gauges : a speedometer 
 with mileage counters, a tachometer in the center and a three-in-one 
 unit measuring oil pressure, oil temperature, and fuel level. And, though 
 not unique, it was also fitted with a Webasto gas heater. Unlike the 
 production 904s, 904-002 was fitted with 6 X 15&quot;forged alloys 
 and 185/70 tires. To accommodate wider wheels, the rear fenders were 
 slightly enlarged. 

 Painted 
 light blue, it was sold to a Dr. Schubart of Germany. In the early 1970&apos;s, 
 it made its way to Mexico City, where it was owned for a short time 
 by Victor Hugo O&apos;Farrel. Mr. O&apos;Farrel traded the car to Bill Jones of 
 San Antonio, Texas, who cleaned up the car and installed VW door handles.
By the mid 1970&apos;s, Jones sold 904-002 to Bob Davidson of Santa Rosa, 
 California. Mr. Davidson showed the car at PCA events and kept it in 
 pristine condition until it was sold to another Californian in the 1978. 
 The car now regularly appears at Southern California car meets. 2002 
 : USA. 

 2003 
 : Mail From a previous owner : I owned 904002 from 74 to 78. Joe Rusz 
 published an article and photos in Porsche Sport 1976/77. I could photo 
 you a copy if you don&apos;t have it. 904002 was one of three test cars and 
 was never sold as a new car. Instead it was shoved in a corner until 
 Dr. Schubart, a Porsche factory exec had it prepared for his personal 
 street use. The factory dropped a new 1967 911S motor in it. Dr. Schubart 
 later sold the car to the Porsche VW regional importer Bill Reynolds(?) 
 in San Antonio Texas. Bill imported the car via Mexico, and registered 
 it in Texas. I bought it from Bill for $15,000 (the highest price anyone 
 had heard of to date) and then drove it direct to an auto cross Santa 
 Rosa CA and competed. On the way, in West Texas, we blew the doors off 
 a Cadillac Coupe de Ville (that damn Caddy did an honest 125 MPH). I 
 got her airborne several times on the humpy road between Barstow and 
 Bakersfield (no air dam). The way you know your airborne in a 904 is 
 when the tack red-lines (no drag on the rear wheels). I registered the 
 car in California...license plate: IXOIV. We actively campaigned the 
 car for 4 years in PCA events including, autocross, concourse and rally. 
 Took second place in the unlimited class at the 78 Parade (lost to a 
 908 but beat the 935 that just returned from Le Mans. Generally took 
 4th in the concourses. I also ran her at&quot;Cannonball speeds&quot;from Santa Cruz, CA to the Aspen Parade in 78. 1060 miles in 12 hours 
 45 minutes...83 MPH average speed. On a new freeway in Colorado, I was 
 able to hold her at 165 MPH for ver an hour. At the time, I believed 
 I had more road time behind the wheel of a 904 than anyone else in the 
 world. I can&apos;t remember who I sold her to in 78 but the price was $28,000--I 
 needed the dough to start my business. The buyer claimed to own another 
 904 at the time...one that the factory actually raced. Oh, and he lived&quot;across the street from Roger Penske&quot;. 904002 was the cover 
 car for the Porsche sales brochure, but instead of velour interior, 
 the factory did the interior up in a special blue leather. It was kind 
 of&quot;rolled and tucked&quot;a la Tijuana. The paint scheme is the 
 same as 904001 that is in the factory museum, only its a baby blue over 
 midnight blue.



 1964 : Porsche Werke - 1966 
 : Michael Weber of Offenbach - 1968 : Berny Barns, US Air Force MAjor, 
 Pirmasens - 1970 : Harro Schneider - 1979 Herren Löhr&amp;Becker 
 - 1987 : Dr Tang of Bonn - 1999 : Lara Resende, Brazil. 

 Being 
 factory car N°906-002, this was the second of very few original, 
 factory built 904s fitted with the new 901 type 6 cylinder engine of 
 a 2 liter displacement.
As a factory car, in December 1964 it underwent a testing program in 
 Monza, where several solex carburetor tests were conducted with H. Linge, 
 against 906 001, fitted with Weber carburetors.
Tire tests were also conducted. 

 Michael 
 Weber, the next owner, a hillclimb driver, is featured in an article 
 in Autosport magazine, dated Sept. 24, 1965 as having won a round of 
 the european Hillclimb Championship in Gaisberg, Austria, with a 904 
 GTS.
in 1980 FIA papers declare that the car was used for historic racing. 
 Dr Tang participated in several historic racing events, such as the 
 1985, 1986&amp;1988“Oltimer Grand Prix”.
AndréLara Resende competed in the April 1999“Tour Auto”historic rally in France (competition category). 

 2002 
 : restored, Le Mans classic. 

 Restoration 
 : Body work was exceptionally original, with evidence of only a nose 
 clip having been replaced at some time. Rust in the stamped steel chassis 
 was minimal, and the basic structure was very straight. The fiberglass 
 was redone only as necessary to clean up years of racing wear and tear. 
 The car was finished in dark green. A modern roll cage of chrome molybdenum 
 steel was buit and installed for safety. The fender flares were removed, 
 bringing the car to its original factory specification bodywork. The 
 upholstery was redone in original type blue german cloth. Mechanically, 
 everything was inspected, cleaned and rebuilt where applicable, and 
 the original open megaphone-exhausts re-installed for racing. 
 904-003 Factory 
 Prototype.
904-003 was used for journalist joy rides at Solitude and was tested 
 by Car&amp;Driver in 1964.
It was first delivered to Robert Hess in the US. It was delivered and 
 used as a road car.
The third of three testing prototypes, 904-003 was used by the Factory 
 as a development car. The most obvious aesthetic differences between 
 this car and production 904s are the air grills that appear on the rear 
 bodywork instead of scoops. Also, the door contours are squared off. 
 Finally, the oil cooler opening lacks the brake cooling ducts and fog 
 lights that were to be found on production models.
The interior sports a unique, two-spoke steering wheel that is set higher 
 and at a sharper angle than the production cars. Like 904-002 it has 
 leather trim. In addition, 904-003 was delivered with a 4-Cylinder, 
 4-Cam motor.
904-003 eventually found its way to Guatemala. It was acquired in the 
 late 1980&apos;s, subsequent to its owners death by G&amp;W Motorwerks 
 of Waynesboro, Virginia. It is still owned by G&amp;W and has been 
 for sale since the mid-1990s. 
 Sold 
 to Robert Hess, sold to Schwartzmann. 2000 : for sale USA . 
 906-003 Spyder 
 - destroyed 904-004 Sold 
 to Mary. USA destroyed. 2002 : rumours says that a replica car is in 
 construction in Belgium in the same body shop as 904 016. 906-004 1965 
 : Hill Climb Freiburg - Gerhard Mitter 2 OA . 1965 : Hill Climb Ollon 
 Villars - Gerhard Mitter DNS. Spyder. 1966 : 12 Hours Sebring with Kolb, 
 DNF. 
 Owners 
 : Charlie Kolb. Steve Beizer. 1974 Gerry Sutterfield, Burt Norris. 1978 
 Joe Pendergast, Mickey Sims, Bill Bradley England. 1987 Gerry Sutterfield, 
 Robert Hendrickson, Ron Finger. 1998 : Leonard, sold to Tom Claridge. 
 2002 : Sold to England. Sold to Viessman in Germany. 
 
 904-005 

 










 

















906-005 

 
 
 Originally 
 a Factory race car, it was driven to the following results in 1964: 

 - 
 April 26th, Davis&amp;Pucci, 1st - Targa Florio;
- May 17th, wore #41, Jurgen Barth, 5th - Spa 500 Km;
904-005 then received the latest Factory upgrades, including the larger 
 rear air intakes, for the 1965 season. In 1965, it achieved the following 
 results:
- March 27, wore #40, Gunther Klass&amp;Lake Underwood, 5th - Sebring;
- May 9, Gerhard Koch&amp;Antonio Pucci, 5th - Targa Florio;
- May 23, Gerhard Koch&amp;Ben Pon, 25th - Nurburgring 1000 KM;
Herbert Mueller then used 904-005, as a Factory entry, in the 1965 European 
 Hillclimb Championship. He achieved the following results:
- June 6, 4th - Mont Ventoux - Müller;
- June 12, 2nd - Rossfeld; 

 - 
 July 25, 4th - Cesana Sestriere;
- August 8, DNF - Freiburg Schaunisland;
- August 29, 4th - Ollon-Villars;
904-005 was then shipped to the US in early 1966, where it achieved 
 the following results :
- February 5, 1966, Gerhard Mitter&amp;Joe Buzzetta, 7th - Daytona 
 24 Hours;
- March 26, 1996, Dieter Glemser&amp;Udo Schutz, DNF - Sebring 12 
 Hours;
Through its office in Teaneck, New Jersey, the car was then sold to 
 American.
Kent Morgan of Arcadia, California, acquired 904-005 in the 1970&apos;s.
He sold it in the 1980&apos;s to acquire and restore 906-157.
In the mid-1990&apos;s the car reappeared for sale through Dale Miller. 

 Subsequently, 
 and almost 30 years after he raced the car at Daytona in 1966, Joe Buzzetta, 
 of St. James, New York, acquired 904-005. Since, Mr. Buzzetta has acquired 
 a 906 that he also raced, a 910, a 907, and a 908/02. 904-005 has made 
 a number of appearances at vintage races in the US, including the 1998 
 Monterey Historic Races. 

 

 Prototype 
 crash test. Sold to Dramm, 911 engine, 2200cc. Sold to Morgan. 1972 
 : for sale 12500 $. 1991 : Valerio. 
 
 904-006 

 

 
























906-006 
 Originally 
 a Factory race car, it was driven to the following results:
- April 26th, 1964, wore #84, Gianni Balzarini&amp;Herbert Linge, 
 2nd - Targa Florio;
- May 31st, 1964, Gerhard Mitter&amp;Herbert Linge, 12th - Nurburgring 
 1000 KM;
- June 20th, 1964, wore #31, Gerhard Koch&amp;Heinz Schiller, 10th 
 - Le Mans 24 Hours;
- September, 1964, Weber/Müller DNF - Tour de France;
- 1965, wore #150, Eugen Bohringer, 2nd - Monte Carlo Rally;
Perhaps the most evocative photographs of any 904 are those of 904-006 
 running in the snow during the 1965 Monte Carlo Rally. Its 2nd place 
 finish has to be considered one of the highlights of 904 racing history.
In early 1966, 904-006 was sold through Fa. Gauser&amp;Co. KG in Austria 
 to Robert Berenz.
From Austria, the car was imported by Dan O&apos;Longhlin, to his residence 
 in Burbank, California. From him, the car passed to Dirk Layer of San 
 Diego. At that time Mr. Layer was considering the daunting task of rebuilding 
 and restored the burnt 904-038. Instead, he sold 904-038 and focused 
 on 904-006. In 1995, Mr. Layer decided to put the car up for sale and 
 it appeared in few magazines.
It was acquired thereafter by Scott Gauthier. A young jewellery designer 
 and manufacturer from Scottsdale, Arizona, Mr. Gauthier has since acquired 
 a collection of the most beautiful racing cars, including a 550 Spyder, 
 a 1600 GTL Abarth Berlinetta, a 906, an Alfa TZ 1, and a Fantuzzi-bodied 
 Maserati 150 S. All are in stunning condition and appear regularly at 
 vintage events and, particularly, the Gauthier Classic, an event that 
 Scott Gauthier organizes and that is run around the time of the Auction 
 in Arizona. 
 In 
 the late 1990&apos;s, 904-006 found its way Stan Gold with the help of Mark 
 Leonard, in some sort of an exchange for his 1600 GTL Abarth Berlinetta, 
 # 1005. Mr. Gold, who has hosted Porsche gatherings at his home in Beverly 
 Hills, is an avid enthusiast who uses and shares his beautifully kept 
 Porsche racing cars, including a 550, a Carrera GT Speedster, and a 
 910.
At the 2001 inaugural running of the Gauthier Classic, 904-006 was crashed 
 in a road accident. Since, the car has been completely repaired in Florida. 
 2002 : Le Mans Classic. 2003 sold to England. 
 
Factory test car for new aerodinamics without side air scoop
Sold to Vassel Polak who raced it with Minter (see race results), sold 
 to Will, sold to Hayes. 2002 : Sold to Leonard.
2002 STPO.

 
 904-007 

 
 
 Originally delivered to Louis Anfossi in Paris, France. He quickly sold 
 the car to a gentleman racer from Perpignan, France, named Lavain.“1877 
 AE 74”, the car was very badly crashed and, essentially, written 
 off.
The remains of the car were sold in the 1980&apos;s to Bernard Comte.
Registration was used by Tourroul to race another 904. in the TDF 1969. 
 906-007 Spyder. 
 1965 : Targa Florio - Colin Davis/Gerhard Mitter 2 OA 1 cl. 1965 : 1000 
 Km Nürburgring - Gerhard Mitter/Colin Davis/Jo Bonnier/Jochen Rindt 
 DNS. 1965 : Hill Climb Rossfeld Gerhard Mitter 1 OA.1 cl. 1965 : sold 
 to Hamilton. 1966 : Australian racing car. Chassis replaced with a new 
 unit from the factory. 1967 : 1 OA in Victorian and South Australian 
 Sports Cars Championships, 2 OA in Australian Sports Cars Championships 
 and Autralian Hill Climb Championships and 3 OA in 12 Hours Surfer’s 
 Paradise. 1968 : 1000 Km Nürburgring. 1971 : 1 OA. Australian Hill 
 Climb Championships. Sold to Pat Burke. 1984 : sold to Hamilton again. 
 Engine 2300 cc. 1985 : auction, sold. 1986 : Melbourne auction, sold 
 1989 London Auction. 1990 Melbourne : Auction. 1991 : Monaco Auction. 
 Sold by Fantasy Junction to Jubst.
3 Cars exist with same numbers. 2001: First in England 
 
NB : races results confusion between 906007 and 906008

The car was owned by Aln Hamilton who in 1965 was working at the Porsche 
 Factory. Hamilton purchased the Kangaroo which came second in the 1965 
 targa Florio driven by Mitter/Davis. This car had chassis nr. 906 007. 
 Hamilton had the factory remove the eight cylinder engine and replace 
 it with a 6 cylinder because it would have been very difficult to mantain 
 the 8 cylinder for him in Australia where he is living. Hamilton imported 
 the car in Australia in 1965 under under a custom document called&quot;section 
 162&quot;(temprary import) which allowed him not to pay duty and sales 
 taxes. The car was raced successfully by him towards 1966. At the end 
 of 1966 Hamilton ordered from the factory a new updated chassis complete 
 with suspension brakes, and body. The new car had no chassis number 
 and Hamilton transferred chassis 007 to the new car as well as the original 
 motor gearbox and other technical components. As said by Hamilton, the 
 old chassis did in a legal sense no more exist. By the end of 1967 the 
 car had to be exported, because, the custom paper were expiring and 
 the taxes had to be paid. Hamilton sold the car to Richard Wong in Singapore 
 who had a lot of fun with the car before getting in jail. It is as this 
 time that Teddy Yip got involved into the car, which he shared with 
 Dr Henry Lee of Singapore. Mr Lee, died passed away and his wife decided 
 to sell the car.The car travel for UK
 
 
 904-008 

 














904/8 008 
 
 Originally 
 a Factory race car 8 cylinders, it was driven to the following results 
 : 1964, wore # 186, Barth/Maglioli 6th-Targa Florio ; 1964, #127 1000 
 km Nürburgring Barth DNF accident. Also Le Mans 1964, Sebring 1965, 
 Le Mans 1965. 

 For 
 1965, it was upgraded with the latest factory modifications. At that 
 time it received the larger air intakes on the rear bodywork. Subsequent 
 to its racing career, 904-008 was retired and sat, unused, until it 
 was sold in mid-1966 to King Hussein of Jordan. The King, a notable 
 sportsman, actually raced the car and added to the car&apos;s successes. 
 He ran 904-008 on at least two occasions and obtained the following 
 results : October 10th, 1966, 1 OA Rumman Hillclimb ; May 12th, 1967, 
 1 OA Rumman Hillclimb; 

 It 
 appears that the car was retired from competition in 1967 and was parked 
 and forgotten in the King&apos;s garages. In 1975, 904-008 was apparently 
 given to Porsche for its museum. In exchange, the factory gave King 
 Hussein a new car for his personnal use. 

 

1964 Targa Florio Edgar Barth /Umberto Maglioli 6 OA .1964 1000 KM Nurburgring 
 Colin Davis / Edgar Barth DNF. 1964 24 Hours Le Mans .Colin Davis /Gerhard 
 Mitter DNF .1965 12 Hours Sebring Gerhard Mitter /Herbert Linge 9 OA 
 .1 cl . 1965 1000 KM Nurburgring Gerhard Mitter /Colin Davis 9 OA .1965 
 24 Hours Le Mans Colin Davis / Gerhard Mitter DNF 
 
 904-009 

 

 





904/8 009 

 

 
 
 8 
 Cylinders - 1964 : 1000 Km Nürburgring - Jo Bonnier/Richie Ginther 
 5 OA . 1964 : 24 Hours Le Mans - Edgar Barth/Herbert Linge DNF. 1964 
 : 12 Hours Reims - Edgar Barth /Colin Davis DNF. 1964 : 1000 km de Paris 
 - Edgar Barth /Colin Davis 3 OA 1 cl.
1965 : Targa Florio - Bonnier/ Hill 4 OA 3 cl. 1965 : 1000 Km Nürburgring 
 - Jo Bonnier /Jochen Rindt 3 OA 1 cl. 1965 : sold to Capriles. Venezuela. 
 1995 : rumours says that Feustel has built a replica using this number 
 with the help of Heinz Heinrich USA who said that he bought this car 
 in South America. New body/chassis. 2002 : Le Mans classic with a 6 
 cylinders, DNF, accident. 

 

 1964 
 1000 KM Nurburgring Jo Bonnier / Richie Ginther 5 OA .1964 24 Hours 
 Le Mans Edgar Barth / Herbert Linge DNF. 1964 12 Hours Reims Edgar Barth 
 /Colin Davis DNF .1964 1000 km de Paris Edgar Barth /Colin Davis 3 OA 
 .1 cl 

 1965 
 Targa Florio Jo Bonnier /Graham Hill / GB DNS - Colin Davis / GB DNS 
 - Gerhard Mitter .4 OA .3 cl. 1965 1000 KM Nurburgring Jo Bonnier /Jochen 
 Rindt 3 OA .1 cl . 1965 24 Hours Le Mans Dieter Glemser / Gnther Klass 
 / D Peter Ncker / D Gerhard Koch DNS 
 904 
 010 Sold 
 to Germany. Completly destroyed. 1968 : the damaged parts were bought 
 by Kurek and in 1988 Kurek built a complete new car using new chassis 
 and body made by himself. The construction of the car was finished in 
 1993 where it was sold to Heinrich USA but the car was picked up in Munich 
 and brought to Feustel’s office where it was sold to a new german 
 owner. It was supplied with a fake American title even though the car 
 had never been in USA ! 
 904-011 

 































  
















906-011 
 
 This, 
 the first customer 904, was first delivered to Otto Zipper&apos;s Precision 
 Motor Cars in Los Angeles. As a Precision Motors or Zipper entry, it 
 was raced extensively and likely was the car used to obtain the following 
 results in 1964:
- March 21st, wore #36, Ritchie Ginther&amp;Ronnie Bucknum, DNF - 
 Sebring 12 Hours;
- April 26th, wore #33, driven by Scooter Patrick, 3rd OA - Riverside 
 USRRC GT;
- May 3rd, wore #33, driven by Scooter Patrick, 5th OA - Laguna Seca 
 USRRC GT;
The car was then sold to an amateur racer, also from the Los Angeles 
 area. He sold the car to Roger Pitts of Dana Point, California. By the 
 late 1960&apos;s 904-011 had suffered the indignity of being equipped with 
 a Chevrolet Corvair motor and, generally, becoming a tired old racecar.
In 1971, 904-011 found its way to Calgary, Alberta, in the hands of 
 Norbert Glimpel for $4800. Though offered the disassembled 4-Cam, Mr. 
 Glimpel chose instead to acquire the car with the Corvair motor, that 
 he would soon replace with a solex-carbureted 911 motor. In addition, 
 he would adapt 904-011 to the Northern climate by installing a gas heater. 
 Mr. Glimpel used the car for ice-racing in the winter of 1971 and then 
 run in hillclimbs and road races in the summer.
From Glimpel, 904-011 was sold to Californian Floyd Shannon, who had 
 run an ad looking for a 904 in 1972. Norbert remembers getting about 
 $5500 for the car. It then found its way to Don Orosco, a real estate 
 developer from Fresno, California. This would be one of many racing 
 Porsches that Mr. Orosco would come to own. He offered the car for sale 
 in the late 1970&apos;s for $45,000, proving that by that time 904&apos;s were 
 already in fairly great demand and, no longer relatively cheap. By comparison, 
 a 911 would sell for about $10,000 in 1972, whereas in 1978 an SC would 
 sell for about $20,000. Around 1978 904-011 was acquired by Syd Baker, 
 of Bellevue, Washington. With it, he acquired two 4-Cam motors (one, 
 newly rebuilt by Jim Wellington, would replace Cordell Bahn&apos;s recently 
 expired motor in 904-069) and a 911 motor (that would be traded for 
 a new crankshaft for the other 4-Cam).
In the late 1970&apos;s Syd undertook a complete restoration of the car that 
 would last five years. Though the body was not removed from the chassis, 
 the chassis had been carefully checked for rust and the bond between 
 the body and the chassis was also carefully inspected. The undertaking 
 was completely documented in hundreds of photos. Remarkably, Syd undertook 
 much of the work himself. 

 A 
 trained aeronautical aerodynamics specialist, Syd has a remarkable eye 
 for detail and took enormous care in restoring the car with utmost accuracy. 
 He made a mold to fabricate a new dash that was the source for numerous 
 other dashes that have appeared for sale through Heinz Heinrichs and 
 Warren Eads. In addition, he went to great lengths to reproduce the 
 blotchy blue painted finish of the interior fiberglass, at a time when 
 few knew that Porsche had supplied the cars this way. 

 Norbert 
 Glimpel, for one, saw it at the Monterey Historic Races in 1983 and 
 did not recognize 904-011! In a letter to Syd, he remarked that,&quot;the 
 work done on it is simply unbelievable.&quot;Subsequently, Syd showed 
 it at Porsche Concours events and ran it in a variety of vintage races 
 in the Pacific Northwest, enjoying the car immensely. 

 In 
 October of 2002, Syd and I met in Kingston, Ontario of all places. There, 
 he spent an afternoon with me, generously offering the use of his huge 
 collection of photographs, documenting the restoration of 904-011. This 
 incredibly modest and talented man must be remembered as a pivotal figure 
 in the 904 world. His restoration was, dare I say, seminal; authentic 
 at a time when there was little in the way of references for authenticity. 

 In 
 1986, 904-011 followed the tide of 904&apos;s that were crossing the Pacific 
 to Japan, being sold to a collector for $ 80,000. It was purchased for 
 a Museum, where it stayed until about 2000. From Japan, it has recently 
 returned to the US, though we have yet been able to confirm to whom. 

 
 Werkes Car : 
 1965-1968 - After being built in 1965, 906-011 first served as a‘werkes’car. Its most notable use was at the Le Mans trials in April 1965 (#33 
 driven by Linge-Mitter-Buchet).
Factory records do not reflect any other race entries. Porsche continued 
 to own the car until it was sold in 1968 to Vasek Polak, a Los Angeles-based 
 Porsche dealer active in racing.
According to Dieter Inzenhofer, mechanic for Vasek Polak and crew chief 
 of the car in 1970-71, Polak bought just the chassis. Dieter then found 
 suspension parts and an engine. In order to run in SCCA’s A-Production 
 class, a 4-cylinder engine was put in the car. Dieter also claims to 
 have changed the chassis plate to one with a&quot;904&quot;prefix 
 (Dieter recalls 904 011) from&quot;906&quot;in order to avoid hassles 
 with SCCA about whether the car had to run in the proto-type SCCA class.
Ordinary tube-frame 906’s had to run as proto-types because so 
 few were made. 906-011 was just a late-run 904 chassis with a 6-cylinder 
 engine. SCCA Career : 1969 - 1971 - 906-011 was sold to Mr. Brent Doell 
 and Mr. Gerry Gregory. Each owned 50%, and Gregory drove the car under 
 the&quot;Doell-Gregory Racing&quot;banner. Around July 1969, Gregory 
 sold his share to Jim Cook, and Cook took over as driver. Initially, 
 the car’s color scheme was silver with three relatively narrow 
 red(?) racing stripes. However, after hitting a Corvette and catching 
 fire at Sears Point (Sept. 1970?), the car was painted an unusual shade 
 of yellow for a brief period. 

 In 
 1970, Jim Cook bought out Doell’s interest and continued to race 
 the car. At this time, Cook had the car painted black with red stripes. 
 Since the shop maintaining the car was doing a poor job, the car was 
 not finishing races. Cook then arranged to have Vasek Polak’s 
 shop maintain the car and sponsor it. And, the color scheme returned 
 to silver (without any racing stripes). Dieter Inzenhofer, a mechanic 
 for Polak, became the crew chief. 

 The 
 car was campaigned successfully through 1971 in West Coast (SCCA, A-Production) 
 races. A partial record of the car’s SCCA race history has been 
 established primarily with the help of photos kept by Sandy Cook (Jim 
 Cook’s widow). It follows : 1969 Doell-Gregory/Cook Sil/red stripes 
 2 - Riverside Doell-Gregory/Cook Sil/red stripes 2 - Feb70 Riverside 
 Cook/Cook Blk/red stripes 2 - Aug70 Willow Springs Cook/Cook Blk/red 
 stripes 2 - Sep70 Sears Pt Cook/Cook Silver - 1970 Laguna Seca Cook-VPolak/Cook 
 Silver 12 - Aug71 Kent, WA Cook-VPolak/Cook Silver 2 1st AP - 1971 Vacaville, 
 CA Cook-VPolak/Cook Silver 20 3rd AP - 1971 CSCC-SCCA /Cook 2nd AP - 
 Nov 71 Road Atlanta Nat Cook-VPolak/Cook Silver 12. - 1972 : The car 
 stopped being campaigned because it was no longer competitive and was 
 moved to the showroom of Polak’s car dealership for several years. 
 When it was sold and to whom, is unknown at this time. 1980 to 1985 
 - In 1980, Jamey Mazotta, a well-known west coast vintage racer, found 
 the car through an ad. He bought it from a man in Washington State. 
 It was fitted with a 4-cylinder, 4-cam engine and original wheels. Then, 
 because his brother wanted to participate in vintage races with him, 
 Jamey sold the car at his cost to Joey Mazotta of San Diego, California. 
 After a brief period of racing, the car’s engine needed work and 
 was sent to a shop for repair. When a year went by and the engine work 
 was still incomplete, Joey was convinced to sell the car. Jamey arranged 
 the sale to Jeff Lewis of Newport Beach, California in 1985. 

 1985 
 to 1999 - Lewis had the car meticulously restored to participate in 
 vintage racing, including re-installing a correct 6-cylinder (901) engine. 
 During this restoration, the incorrectness of the chassis plate surfaced. 
 It did not jibe with the car’s&quot;906&quot;features: large 
 air scoops behind the side windows, center of the hood fuel filler, 
 center/interior rear-hood latch, short side doors, side windows that 
 raise/lower, etc. After proper research confirmed the correctness of 
 the 906-011 identification, a new chassis plate was attached. The car 
 debuted at the 1987 Monterey Historics and subsequently ran in over 
 25 vintage events through 1999 with Lewis as driver. Kevin Ryan (Ryan 
 Racing Restoration, Costa Mesa, CA) maintained the car during most of 
 Lewis’s ownership. 1999 to Present - In November 1999, Dean Meiling 
 purchased the car from Lewis through Dale Miller of Miller Historic 
 Motor Cars. Ryan Racing Restoration (relocated to Plain City, OH in 
 2002) still services the car, which continues to be vintage raced. 

 In 
 2000, the engine was rebuilt and new CV joints were fitted to the rear 
 half-shafts for safety. In 2001, the lower front edge of the car was 
 re-done in its original shape (protruding lower lip) using moulds from 
 the sister car (906-012; Porsche built 904 chassis in pairs). Also, 
 new exhaust headers and megaphones were installed to enhance the car’s 
 performance particularly at lower RPMs. As of 16 September 2002. 

 
 
 904-012 

 


































906-012 
 
 This, 
 the second customer 904, was first delivered to Steve Earle, through 
 Otto Zipper&apos;s Precision Motor Cars in Los Angeles. Now the organizer 
 of the Monterey Historic Races, it does not appear that Mr. Earle raced 
 the car. 

 From 
 him, it passed to fellow Californian, Steve Berg. Mr. Berg, a racing 
 benefactor of sorts, ostensibly acquired the car to be raced by young 
 and talented aspiring California racers. At least in its early events, 
 it appeared with Precision Motor Car colors. Under his ownership, it 
 was raced extensively and likely was the car used to obtain the following 
 results: 

 - 
 April 26th, 1964, wore #32, Kurt Neumann, 8th OA - Riverside USRRC GT;
- May 3rd, 1964, wore #32, Kurt Neumann, 7th OA - Laguna Seca USRRC 
 GT;
- June, 1964, wore #32, Kurt Neumann, 3rd OA - Willow Springs SCCA Divisional;
- September 19th, 1964, wore #37, Skip Scott, 2nd OA - Bridgehampton 
 Double 500;
- October 10th, 1964, wore #32, Kurt Neumann ? - Riverside 3 Hour Enduro;
- May 2nd, 1965, wore #32, Kurt Neumann, DNF - Riverside USRRC GT;
- May 9th, 1965, wore # 32, Kurt Neumann, 5th OA - Laguna Seca USRRC 
 GT;
- October 31st, 1965, wore #49, Denny Harrison, ? - LA Times GP at Riverside; 

 
From Berg, the car then passed to Robert Redford, the actor. How he 
 used the car is, unfortunately, not known. 

 Likely 
 from Redford, 904-012 was then sold to Ray Stewart, then of Long Beach, 
 California. Stewart had the car for sale in the late 1970&apos;s for $ 35,000.
Presumably from Stewart, Jim Tidwell of San Diego, California acquired 
 904-012 in 1979. He apparently owned the car until 1982, when it passed 
 to Nelson Rath. 

 In 
 1989, 904-012 was acquired by a Belgian collector. At that time, it 
 appears that the car did not have a motor and was missing various other 
 parts. For him the car was restored in Belgium, where it was fitted 
 with a 2.0 Liter 911 motor and was painted British Racing Green. With 
 the registration CXX-689, it appeared at an International 356 Meet in 
 the 1990&apos;s. It remains in Belgium as of the writing of this book. 

 


1965 : 1000 Km Nürburgring - Peter Nöcker/Günther Klass 
 6 OA. 1965 : 24 Hours Le Mans - Günther Klass/Dieter Glemser DNF. 
 1966 : sold to Drolsom for 4000 $ without engine (see 904 013). 1967 
 : Sold to Covert USA. Destroyed in racing (Elkhart Lake) was send back 
 to factory who replace the chassis. but now with 4 cams engine to Vern 
 Covert. Driven back to California by road. Modified to T Top car with 
 two removable panels and fitted with 906 engine turbo charged. 2001 
 : sold to Asia. Accident in Tour Auto 2002, repaired by S.H.K in Germany. 
 Sold to England. 
 904-013 Sold 
 to Robert Hagestadt USA. sold to George Drolsom who raced it and the 
 car was. destroyed at 1965 Midowdale Chicago. Drolsom contacted the 
 factory and for 4 000 $ Porsche agreed to repair the car without seen 
 it ! The car was send to Germany and then Porsche refused to repair 
 the car as it was too much damaged. Instead for the same amount of money, 
 the factory sold 906 012 without engine. M. Drolsom received back from 
 the factory all the good remaining parts of 904 013 even the aluminium 
 chassis plate as a trophy. 1967 : Kurek bought some damaged parts and 
 built a complete new car. The construction of the car was finished in 
 1970 and was road registered as a Porsche Kurek. (We saw the registration 
 papers from 1970 to 1983). 2003: sold for 135 000 euros to M. Reis. 904-014 Originally 
 sold to Frank Rand, who quickly turned the car over to Harry Heuer of 
 Chicago, Illinois. Mr Heuer, of the brewing&quot;Heuers&quot;, had 
 apparently acquired the car. 
 Shortly 
 thereafter, 904-014 was sold to another brewing heir, Eddie Weschler 
 of Milwaukee, Wisconsin, but was not raced. A few months later, it was 
 sold to Jacques Duval, the enthusiastic and talented Porsche privateer 
 from Montreal Canada. 

 Mr. 
 Duval, who worked as a radio personality, had raced Porsches in Quebec 
 since 1960. Starting with a 356 roadster in 1960, he had obtained a 
 Lightweight 356 Coupe for &apos;61, &apos;62 and &apos;63, and a 1600 GTL Abarth Coupe 
 (chassis # 1004) for 1964. 

 Acquired 
 in the winter of 1965 for the sum of $7500, Duval drove 904-014 home 
 from Milwaukee. To deal with snow, he mounted VW wheels with snow tires 
 that he obtained along the way. Though remembered by many a racer for 
 having a pretty girl by his side, his true talent (for a racer, anyway) 
 was his ability to obtain sponsorship. During his ownership, the car 
 was painted yellow to complement his Mr. Muffler (a Quebec exhaust repair 
 chain) sponsorship, then blue (Porsche Club of Canada color) and, finally, 
 red to go with his G. Lebeau (a body repair shop) logos. 

 In 
 1965, Duval and 904-014 won its class in the Quebec Championship. This 
 series comprised 12 events held, predominantly, at Mt. Tremblant, a 
 beautiful and challenging racetrack near Ste. Jovite, about 70 miles 
 north of Montreal. The following details some of the results obtained 
 by Duval during 1965 and 1966: 

 - 
 May, 1965, 6th-Pepsi Cola Trophy (Tremblant);
- 1965, 13th-Mosport GP, #58;
- 1965, with Horst Kroll, 3rd-Sundown 4 Hr GP (Tremblant);
- 1966, with Horst Kroll, 2nd in class-Sebring 12 Hrs, #56;
- 1966, 2nd-Player&apos;s 200 (Tremblant); 

 Near 
 the end of the 1966 season, 904-014 was sold to Victor Herman Haus, 
 also from Montreal. At his first outing, the ACAM 6 Hrs, held at Tremblant 
 on October 17, 1966, he rolled the car shortly after the start of the 
 race.
From Mr. Haus, the car made its way to Rainer Brezinka and to Mr. Campbell 
 of Vancouver.
Tony Campbell raced it in 1968 and 1969. In &apos;69 racing season, Tony 
 finished 3d in the Northern Pacific Division/SCCA point standings
It was then sold to Dick Barbour, the 935 racer and Porsche collector. 
 And from him it passed to a Mr. Harming and then to Paul Harmatuk. Tony 
 Singer&amp;Jay Rosenfield from New York acquired 904-014 and had it 
 restored.
From Singer, in 1975, the car passed to Tim Kuser of Bordentown, New 
 Jersey 
 904-015 Factory. 
 sold to Wester, sold to Bishoff who advertised it for sale in 1969, 
 sold to Randel USA. Car was destroyed and a replica bought from Germany 
 exists in Belgium, the owner was asking in 2001 to buy 904 papers and 
 finally got a funny title from Heinrich USA. Car was put together in 
 Brussels and the owner refused to show me his replica. (I had a lot 
 of correspondence in 2001 during wich he asked if it was possible to 
 buy papers for the car). 904-016 Sold 
 to Brandage, sold to Cassel, sold to Neumann. Destroyed in fire. 2002 
 : rumours says that a car is in construction in Belgium using the original 
 chassis of 904 073 and small parts of the original body. The body shop 
 who built the car agreed to let me see the car but when the owner found 
 out that I was coming about the book he refused to let me see it. 904-017 Sold 
 to Hansen raced by Wester, sold to Clay, sold to Randle, sold to Bishoff, 
 sold to Wester. 1971 : poor condition, sold to T&amp;M Motors. Sold 
 to Gildred who was ambassador to Argentina under Pdt Reagan. 2001 : 
 Silver USA. 904-018 Originally 
 delivered to Herb Wetanson of New York. A fast-food restaurant pioneer, 
 Mr. Wetanson is now an enthusiastic vintage racer and owns an RS 60, 
 s/n 718061, amongst other racing exotics. Unfortunately, Wetanson was 
 unhappy with the car&apos;s weight, a bloated 1750 lbs. As a result, he returned 
 904-018 to Porsche of America.
From Porsche of America, the car was sold to Briggs Cunningham, the 
 well-known Le Mans entrant, car manufacturer, yachtsman, and all-round 
 sportsman, who was nearing the end of his racing career in 1964.
With Lake Underwood, Mr. Cunningham finished 9th at the 1964 Sebring 
 12 Hrs (number 37). Then in 1965, Cunningham shared the car with John 
 Fitch and Bill Bencker to finish 20th at Sebring (number 44). And finally, 
 in 1966, with John Fitch and Dave Jordan the car failed to finish, again, 
 at Sebring (number 47).
Subsequent to racing at Sebring in 1966, it appears that 904-018 was 
 retired and later reappeared as an exhibit at Briggs Cunningham&apos;s museum 
 in Costa Mesa, California.
In the early 1980&apos;s Mr. Cunningham&apos;s extensive collection of racecars 
 was sold to Miles Collier of Naples, Florida. Son of post-war US racing 
 pioneer and close friend to Briggs Cunningham, Miles Collier, it has 
 been suggested by Forbes magazine, gained control of his family&apos;s vast 
 Florida real estate fortune on a coin toss!
His collection of sports racing cars is among the best in the world 
 and, was, for a time open to the public. 904-018 has been kept roughly 
 as&quot;last-raced&quot;and sits next 904-046 (at least when I last 
 saw it in the 80&apos;s). 904-019 Originally sold to Carel Godin de Beaufort, the well-known racer from 
 the Netherlands. 
 It 
 came to the US for the 1964 12 Hours of Sebring and after was sold to 
 Bruce Nole. From Nole, it passed to Charles Austin and after to Chuck 
 Stoddard, who has owned the car for about thirty years. Mr. Stoddard, 
 who raced an Alfa TZ1 at Sebring against 904s in 1964, went on to build 
 one of the stalwarts of the Porsche restoration parts businesses, which 
 was later sold to the Porsche factory. 

 904-019 
 remains as one of the most original, little-used 904s extant. It has 
 lived out its casual retirement in Ohio next a 550 RS A, a long-tail 
 907 and a mighty 917. 
 904-020 “37 
 GK 03”Sold to Ligier. 1964 : 500 Km Spa - Guy Ligier 17 OA. 1964 
 : sold to Chevillon who raced it in France. 1965 : Mont Ventoux Chevillon 
 4 cl. 1967 : Mont Ventoux Chevillon.“763 GW 26”“121 
 JE 26” 904-021 Sold to Buchet&quot;821 FK 86&quot;. 1964 : Rallye Bordeaux - Buchet/Delavalle 
 1 OA. 24 Hours le Mans (see chassis 904-106 ). Rallye Lorraine - Buchet/Gauvin 
 2 OA. Rallye Limousin - Buchet/Valadas 2 OA . Hill Climb Andelys 2 OA. 
 Hill Climb Chamrousse 3 OA. Tour Corse - Buchet/Wuetherich DNF. 1965 
 : Rallye Routes du Nord - Buchet/Wuetherich DNF. Rallye Limousin - Buchet/Valadas 
 2 OA. Rallye Ouest - Buchet/Valadas 1 OA. Rallye Lorraine - Buchet/Coolen 
 5 OA. Rallye Bordeaux - Buchet/Coolen 1 OA. 12 Hours Reims - Robert 
 Buchet/Guy Ligier 10 OA.4 cl. 1965 : 24 Hours Le Mans - Ben Pon/Robert 
 Buchet DNF. 1965 : Coupes Alpes - Buchet/Marbaque DNF accident destroyed. 
 Cote Bayonne, Basque Buchet 1 OA (new car with same chassis number). 
 Rallye Automne, Buchet/Barthe 1 OA.
1966 : Routes Nord, Buchet/Ferrand 1 OA. Rallye Limousin - Buchet/Ferrand 
 6 OA . Rallye la Baule, Buchet/Barthe 1 OA. Sold to Pigeaux&quot;8859 
 TC 75&quot;. 1968 : sold to Collector&quot;8385 GW 78&quot;. 1971 : 
 sold to Balsa&quot;8173 Y 94&quot;. 1983 : STPO with 6 cylinders 2700 
 cc France. 904-022 Sold 
 to Switzerland, Schiller. Look also 904 039 and 904 069. 904-023 
 Originally 
 delivered to Ben Pon and his Dutch Racing Team. Ben Pon himself, has 
 indicated that the car was used as follows:
- 1964, driven by Ben Pon, 8th OA - Spa 500 KM;
- 1964, driven by Rob Slotemaker, DNF (the car suffered a very bad crash 
 and was essentially destroyed) - Nurburgring Sprint Race;
Subsequent to the crash at the Nurburgring, 904-023 was returned to 
 the Factory and rebuilt. It then achieved the following results:
- 1965, driven by Rob Slotemaker, DNF - Spa 500 KM;
- June 5, 1965, ran at the Player&apos;s 200 at Mosport;
At some point the motors from 904-023 and 904-055, the other Dutch Racing 
 team 904, were exchanged. Subsequent to the 1965 season, the car was 
 freshened and sold.It was acquired in 1966 by Fraser Grant of Concord, 
 California, directly from Ben Pon in 1970, he advertised the car for 
 sale in&quot;excellent condition&quot;, at the price of $ 6500. 

 From 
 Grant, 904-023 was sold to Bill Jackson of Denver, Colorado. Mr. Jackson 
 put together a serious Porsche collection in the 1970&apos;s and early 1980&apos;s, 
 including a 1600 GTL Abarth and a couple of RSRs. Subsequent to his 
 death, his collection was sold to a dealer in California named Mr. Milo. 
 904-023 was still for sale in mid 2002. It is currently painted orange, 
 the Dutch Racing Team&apos;s color.2005 For Sale by Bernardi Germany ( this 
 one claims that it was 055 who was crash in 1964, I propose to Bernarbi 
 to justify his comments but he refuse !) 
 904-024 Originally 
 delivered to Tage Hansen of Lexington, Mass. for General Motors. GM 
 kept the car until 1971 for use in its development of the Corvette. 
 The car was sold in 1971 to Marvin Wienman of Rhode Island. Though unverified, 
 and possibly urban legend, the story goes that Mr. Wienman could not 
 find reverse and pretty much gave up on the car after only eight months. 
 He sold the car to Bill Steen of Shreveport, Louisiana. Mr. Steen was 
 904-024&apos;s third owner and kept her for close to thirty years. At the 
 end of his ownership the car had fewer than 9000 miles. 
 1976, 
 Magazine of Bob Rassa :“This particular car has a very interesting 
 history, having been sold to GM by the Porsche factory in July of 1964 
 for experimental evaluation. GM styling boss Bill Mitchell used the 
 car as his personnal vehicle for a while, having had numerous“improvements”made such as restyled surrounds, engine grill, new seats, new safety 
 glass windshield and backlight, and winshield garnish molding, among 
 the most prominent. In 1968, the car passed to one or two private owners 
 and finally came to rest at Stoddartd Imported Car showrooms in 1974. 
 Bill Stee, an eye surgeon from Shreveport Louisiana, bought the car 
 from Stoddard’s in October 1974 and immediatly began an“as 
 new”restoration. Of course, all the GM improvements had to go, 
 but this was the least of the problems. Rust had attacked the subframe 
 in several places and Bill rebuilt the frame with a steel plate after 
 which he rustproofed the entire frame The wiring harness, dashboard, 
 seats and pedal assembly were completly replaced with parts either made 
 or scavenged. Making new parts is just about as difficult as scavenging 
 old ones. The blue velour seats were bought in England and were removed 
 from a 904 which have been wrecked. Bill purchased a second 904 026 
 from an owner in Hawaïand this car supplied a new pedal assembly. 
 Chuck Stoddard just happened to have a new beily pan and the new dashboard 
 was fabricated by hand over a specialy made moid. New weather striping 
 for the doors was also fabricated and that isn’t the easiest thing 
 to do. Arrangements were made with a rubber manufacturer to have a special 
 die made, and a thousand feet or so of rubber weatherstripping was extruded, 
 matching the original.” 

 Through 
 an intermediary, 904-024 has found its way to Pablo Picasso&apos;s son, Claude 
 Ruiz-Picasso, in France. Mr. Ruiz-Picasso has had the car prepared for 
 racing and has entered it in a number of European events. It was shown 
 at Bagatelle in 2000 and ran in the Tour Auto in 2001. 904-024 now shares 
 a garage with a 550, a 906 and a 910. 
 
 904-025 Sold to Stirling Moss. 1964 : 1000 Km Nürburgring - David Hobbs 
 /Lloyd Casner 9 OA. Sold to Schneider. 1972 : sold to Gratama Holland 
 sold to Lohr und Becker. Sold to dealer, sold to Streve Mulhens. 1990 
 : Auction Paris. Owned by Klaus Werner. Restored 2001. 2002 : For sale 
 in UK. During its life car was destroyed and rebuilt. 904-026 
 Originally 
 delivered to Fritz Leineweber in Germany. This car has been recorded 
 as having been raced by Michael Weber in hillclimbs. Sold to Jurgen 
 Gauser.
The car was then sold to John Robbins of Omaha, Nebraska.
In 1973 sold by Cruz, it passed to Flavio Espino, a Venezuelan, who 
 ran the car in Venezuela and in SCCA races in Florida, where it apparently 
 suffered crash damage to its rear end. By this time it had been fitted 
 with motor number 99 099.
In this condition, it was sold to Jim Way, who brought the car to his 
 home in Hawaii. From Way, 904-026 was acquired by Bill Steen for parts 
 to restore 904-024. It appears that, at least, the pedal assembly was 
 removed for 904-024.
The car then resurfaced in the mid 1980&apos;s in the hands of Nick Soprano 
 of Motor Classic Corp, of White Plains, New York. It was apparently 
 complete and restored at that time. Soprano advertised the car for sale 
 in 1986. Raymond Perroud of Genolier, Switzerland purchased 904-026 
 from Soprano in 1986. Mr. Perroud currently owns the car. 
 904-027 Sold 
 to Ludwig Blendl. May have been sold to Redolfi for racing in Italy 
 with Barbuscia. (see 1967 1000 km Monza). Sold to Venezuela. Marcottuli 
 raced it with a 6 cylinders engine. 904-028 Sold 
 to Koch who raced it and sold to Ising who raced it also. 1966 : Sold 
 to USA Vasek Polak. Sold to Kirk White, Jerry Craft, sold to Kuhn, sold 
 to Will, sold to Alexander Pollock. 2001 : Color White/Black. 904-029 Sold 
 to Weber. Hill Climb - Rossfeld Michel Weber 6 OA 1 cl. Hill Climb - 
 Freiburg Michel Weber DNS. Sold to Bartels and sold to USA to Leonard 
 Schenkel. Sold to Chandler USA
 904-030 Sold 
 to Brockhaus. 1964 : Hill Climb Rossfeld - Werner Brockhaus 11 OA. 1964 
 : Hill Climb Freiburg - Werner Brockhaus 10 OA. 1965 : Hill Climb Freiburg 
 - Werner Brockhaus 9 OA.Sold to France to Bernard Halter who sold it 
 to Dominique Thiry who raced it in rallyes, the car was seized by the 
 french custom because the taxes had not been paid. 2003 Marcel Petitjean 
 told me that the chassis plate between 904030 and 904041 had been changed 
 and that the real 904041 is today 904030. 904-031 Originally 
 delivered to German, Dr. Josef Ruby. Under his ownership, the car was 
 used sparingly but does have the following history: 
 - 
 May 31st, 1964, with Greger, was entered but did not start the Nurburgring 
 1000 KM;
- May 8th, 1965, 5th - Nurburgring GT 2.5 L race; 

 Eventually, 
 it found its way to Japan and, is likely now, the 904 displayed at the 
 Shikoku Museum.
 
 904-032 Sold 
 to Lehmann who raced it a lot. Sold to Werlich. Sold to Moser. Germany. 904-033 
 Sold 
 to Walter. 1964 : 500 Km Spa Heini Walter 18 OA . Hill Climb - Rossfeld 
 Heini Walter 8 OA 2 cl. 1964 : Hill Climb - Freiburg Heini Walter 6 
 OA 2 cl.Hill Climb - Sierra Montagna Heini Walter 12 OA . 1964 : Hill 
 Climb Turkheim 3 Epis, Walter DNF big accident. After this accident 
 Walter bought“904 105”. Sold to Clement who raced it.“842 
 BE 05”. 1967 sold to Rampal. 1971 : Color white/orange.&quot;980 
 FT 55&quot;Sold to USA to Akly. 2001 : France. Car was completely dismanteld 
 for duplicate the 904 047.“842 BE 05”“4108 CX 13”. 
 
 904-034 

 
 
 Sold 
 to Muller Engine 912. Destroyed in road accident. Sold to Crossland, 
 sold to Jurgensen, sold to Buras, sold to Walter. 1999 : Quai Lodge 
 Auction. 

 904/8 
 - 034
1964 500 Km Spa, Herbert Müller 14 OA 4 cl.
Hill Climb - Sierra Montagna Herbert Müller 2 OA 1 cl. 

 Warning 
 : a second car exists. 

 Michelin 
 test car given to the museum of Le Mans. Suspension Hydraulic Citroën 
 DS. 2002 : Le Mans museum. 
 904-035 Sold 
 to Eugster
1964 : 3 Hours Monza Hansueli Eugstler 5 OA . Sold to Gildo de Guidi 
 who raced it in Italy, sold to Laubscher Von Arx Switzerland. 904-036 Schutz 
 raced in 1964. At the Nürburgring August 2, 1964 .The car ended 
 upside down in the trees. Rebuilt at the factory. 
 By 
 September of 1964, the factory was making the 904’s with a different&quot;glass&quot;for the body and had changed several of the body and 
 mechanical components. This chassis had large oil lines and fittings. 
 The original engine, transmission, dash components and other components 
 were utilized in the rebuilding of the car and the original tail. This 
 early tail section had the small air vents on the sides. Raced for part 
 of 1965 by Mr. Schutz. 

 1966 
 Mr. Rudi Lins raced the car in hill climb events and other events. Mr. 
 Lins was a Porsche Austria - 1967 Sold Mr. Frank Werner USA. The car 
 was in perfect condition with silver color. The title transfer was in 
 the name of Udo Schutz, not Mr. Lins. Werner raced at Elkhart Lake in 
 Wisconsin in the&quot;June Sprints&quot;and other races the car was 
 in his garage and in August of 1969, a young Mr. Rullman walking past 
 sees the car and inquires if it is for sale. Not for sale, but Rullman 
 says in effect‘anything 
 
is for sale at the right price&quot;. Mr. Frank offers the car then 
 for a high price. Mr. Rullman says he’ll be back later with his 
 mother or grandmother and checkbook. A few hours later, the sale was 
 consummated.
Mr. Rullman drives the car, on the street and some racing, for some 
 time and something broke in the transmission. This was repaired and 
 then he started hearing a strange noise in the engine. About that time, 
 Henry Payne of Charleston, West Virginia, offered an engine for sale 
 from his 904 (ex Lee Sturtivant, ex Archie Walker, and was the yellow 
 car driven by Bill Wensthoff at the June Sprints in 1964). Henry Payne 
 had converted to a 2.5 Liter 911S engine as covered in an article in&quot;Christophorous Magazine&quot;several years back. 
 Mr. 
 Rullman purchased the engine from Mr. Payne and had it installed in 
 #904036. He became disenchanted with the car and offered it for sale. 
 During Mr. Rullman’s ownership, the car fell into some state of 
 disrepair. The car was painted orange color and, did a horrible job. 
 there was overspray everywhere !
The car with the spare engine was sold to Mr. Jerry Hudson of Wichita, 
 Kansas in 1969. Mr. Hudson drove the car from the Chicago area to Wichita. 
 The car was raced in the Kansas area until the second engine suffered 
 a failed rod bearing. The original engine was never rebuilt and sat 
 in storage. 

 Mr. 
 Hudson decided to restore the car and so began disassembly of the chassis 
 beginning with the rear. This never proceeded past the disassembly stage. 
 Sold to Dr. Gary Quast of Omaha, Nebraska in 1973 in a disassembled 
 condition. The only assembly done was to reassemble the rear suspension 
 so that the car could be rolled onto a trailer. The two engines had 
 been disassembled and were unsorted and contained in multiple boxes. 

 Dr. 
 Quast placed the car in storage. Since Dr. Quast’s garage space 
 at home was limited, he prevailed on his neighbor to store the 904 in 
 the horse barn. It occupied a small corner and hay bales were placed 
 around it to protect it.
Over the next few years, the parts that were missing or in need of replacement 
 were purchased. Parts that were in need of restoration were completed 
 and then placed in storage. Bodywork was done and the original engine 
 was completely assembled with new parts and placed in the car. The engine 
 work was done by Vern Covert and Kurt Kiebler. The car was partially 
 assembled in 1978 and the engine was&quot;run in&quot;and tuned. This 
 was done by Grady Clay in Denver. The assembly was not completed at 
 that time and the car was placed back in a controlled environment for 
 storage. Later, the Restoration by Paul Willison USA 

 The 
 project was approximately 18 months and all work was done at the Willison 
 Werkstatt. have a light blue with orange stripes characteristic of the 
 Gulf cars of that era. These colors were discovered during the restoration 
 process.
The car was sold in 1998 but never picked up by the new owner. A 6-cylinder 
 engine and a fuel cell has been installed. 

 Owner 
 : USA, Bobby Rahal 
 
 904-037 

 
 
 Sold 
 to Michel, Sold to Osterfedt Germany - 1964 : 500 Km Spa, Gerhard Osterfeldt 
 DNF. Sold to Schutz and sold again to Abels. 1965 : 1000 Km Nürburgring 
 Manfred Abels/Günther Selbach 14 OA 2 cl. 

 The 
 904-037 was in 1965 bought from Germany by&quot;Svenska BP&quot;, Swedish 
 BP and they had Gunnar&quot;Persbergarn&quot;Carlsson to drive the 
 car in Swedish events. 1966 Gustav Dieden bought the car from BP but 
 without engine. Dieden put in different engines, a 911 engine and even 
 a Carrera 6 engine was fitted in it at one time. From 1979 the car was 
 owned by the Porsche dealer in Karlstad, Sweden, Lasse Jönsson 
 and the car was racing last year at Nürburgring, Old Timer Grand 
 Prix. It now has a four cylinder engine. 

 
 904-038 This 
 car may have been sold originally in the US. Unfortunately, little of 
 its early history is known. Early on, though, it returned to Europe 
 in the hands of a dealer, a Mr. Gramling from Karlsruhe. At that time, 
 it was apparently modified for road use. 
 Still 
 in the 1960&apos;s, 904-038 made its way to South Africa, the only 904 to 
 have done so. There, it was acquired by David Cohen, a well-known diamond 
 specialist and car collector, who has since moved on to Vancouver, where 
 he keeps an immaculate &apos;38 Alfa 8C 2900B Touring Berlinetta, a 550 RS 
 A, and various other exotica. He raced 904-038 in South Africa in the 
 late 1960&apos;s and 1970&apos;s. 

 In 
 a bizarre twist, the car was badly damaged by a firebomb while on display 
 at a shopping mall in Johannesburg in the 1980&apos;s. In this burned condition, 
 race-worn, and showing approximately 63000 km, the car was acquired 
 by Dirk Layer of San Diego in 1987/8. He had it shipped to California. 
 On seeing the car, and the extent of the damage, Layer chose to sell 
 the car and, instead, restore 904-006. 

 From 
 Layer, the car passed to Dr. Barney Gardner of Palo Alto, California 
 in 1988. Thereafter, it became the subject of a lengthy and intensely 
 accurate restoration by Cavaglieri Restorations of Sherman Oaks, California, 
 the story of which was fully recounted in Excellence&apos;s February, 1995 
 issue. It won Best of show at the 1994 Hillsborough Concours, won the 
 Honorary Judge&apos;s Choice Award at the 1995 Porsche Cub of America Annual 
 Meet, and has run at the Monterey Historic Races. 

 More 
 recently, it has been acquired by Ranson Webster of Reno, Nevada and 
 joins one of the finest collections of Porsches in the world. Many of 
 his Porsches, including 904- 
 904-039 Originally 
 sold through Heinz Schiller in Genf, Switzerland. To the best of our 
 knowledge, 904-039 was racing in France and in Germany. 
 It 
 was acquired by Gene Dodd of Indianapolis, Indiana in the late 1960&apos;s. 
 Dodd was an active and well-known PCA member in the 1960&apos;s. He would 
 later race a 906 in SCCA events. During his ownership, 904-039 appeared 
 on the cover of an early 1970&apos;s issue of Panorama. Dodd advertised the 
 car for sale in 1971, asking $ 8000. 

 As 
 a result of the ad, Dodd sold the car to David Redszus of Lake Forest, 
 Illinois, a suburb of Chicago. At one time, Mr. Redszus was a serious 
 IMSA racer, having run at Sebring in the early 1980&apos;s. Though 904-039 
 is not currently fully assembled, it is still owned by David Redszus. 
 Unfortunately, we were unable to obtain a photo of the car for the book. 
 904-040 Sold 
 to Dernier. Hill Climb Laroche - Samre&quot;Eldé&quot;1 OA. 
 1964 : 500 Km Spa Eldé. 1964 : 1000 Km Nürburgring -&quot;Eldé&quot;/AndréPilette DNF. 1964 : Hill Climb Ste Cécile - Herbeumont 2 OA. 
 1964 : Hill Climb Citadelle de Namur -&quot;Eldé&quot;2 OA. 
 1965 : 500 Km Spa -&quot;Eldé&quot;10 OA 2 cl. Sold to Verdoedt. 
 Sold to Hoffman, Germany. 2001 : under restoration with complete new 
 body. 904-041 
 Originally 
 delivered to well-known Parisien privateer, Jean Kerguen.
Having raced, among others, a Zagato-bodied Aston Martin DB4GT, Mr. 
 Kerguen was a seasoned and quite respectively fast gentleman racer. 
 With 904-041, he obtained the following results: 

 - 
 June 20th, 1964, wearing #32, with Jacques Dewez (using the pseudonym&quot;Franc&quot;), 12th - Le Mans 24 Hours;
- July 5th, 1964, with Dewez, 16th - Reims 12 Hours;
- September 20th, 1964, 6th - Coupe de Paris at Montlhery;
- October 11th, 1964, with Dewez, 9th - Paris 1000 KM at Montlhery;
- June 19th, 1965, wearing #38, with Dewez, DNF - Le Mans 24 Hours; 

 In 
 1966, 904-041 was sold to a gentleman by the name of Barret. From him, 
 the car was sold in 1967 to a Mr. Petitjean, who used it in the following 
 events:
- 1968, 3rd OA - Wissembourg Hillclimb;
- 1968, 1st OA - Abreschwiller Hillclimb;
- 1968, 2nd OA - Arry Hillclimb;
- 1968, 2nd OA - Ballon Alsace Hillclimb;
- 1968, dnf - Sewen Lac Alfeld Hillclimb;
- 1968, 3rd OA - Hautes Vosges Hillclimb; 

 904-041 
 was then sold to a Mr. Lutz. Interestingly, Mr. Petitjean told us that 
 the dealer who sold his car, switched its paperwork with that of another 
 904.
In 1971 the registration“6775 AW 93”appeared in the TDF 
 with Cachia. In 2003 Cacchia told me that he bought his car from Poirot 
 (904 100) ? Later 904-041 was acquired by Klaus-Otto Raker. Raker, a 
 Doctor from Lemgo, Germany, has been a very active historic racer and 
 rally participant. His 550 Spyder and stainless-steel bodied 718 RSK, 
 have been fixtures on the European historic scene. Unfortunately, 904-041 
 has been rarely seen during his ownership. He appears to retain 904-041 
 to this day.
More recently, 904-041 may have been sold to Friedrich Dauphin, to add 
 to his growing collection of Alfa, Ferrari and Porsche racing cars. 
 The 904 that he has acquired has been completely restored and has been 
 entered in vintage races, driven on occasion by Walter Rohrl.
2003 Marcel Petitjean told me that the chassis plate between 904030 
 and 904041 had been changed and that the real 904030 is today 904041. 
 904-042 Originally 
 delivered to Robert Roseta of Portland, Oregon. Though variously reported 
 as a Pacific Cars Northwest and a Riviera Motors entry, it was raced 
 by Mike Eyerly to the following results:
- May 10, 1964, wore # 64, 5th OA - Pacific Raceways USRRC GT race;
- May 10, 1964, wore # 64, 7th OA - Pacific Raceways USRRC Sports race;
The car&apos;s next owner was Wade Carter, a Porsche dealer from Seattle, 
 Washington. Continuing 904-042&apos;s Pacific Raceways history, Carter used 
 the car at August 1st 1965 running of the USRRC event held at this venue. 
 There, Carter brought the car to a 16th place finish. Wade Carter has 
 long been a well-known name among Porschephiles in the Pacific Northwest. 
 Always cheery and warm, Mr. Carter was to become a fixture at the Monterey 
 Historic Races, with his 906. Unfortunately, Mr. Carter passed away 
 tragically in 2001 when a helicopter that he was testing for possible 
 purchase crashed. 
 In 
 1967, 904-042 was acquired by Bruce Munch, a resident of Glendale, California. 
 He may have acquired the car from a gentleman named Ronzle or vice versa.
From California, 904-042 moved north to Kalamazoo, Michigan, owned by 
 Richard Radt. Mr. Radt advertised the car for sale in 1972, offering 
 it for the then princely sum of $ 8200. 

 The 
 next owner was Maitland Combs of Birmingham, Michigan. He acquired the 
 car around 1973. In the 1980&apos;s, 904-042 found its way to Jeffrey Keiner 
 in Florida. 

 A 
 serious collector who has owned a 550, 906 and 910, Mr. Keiner raced 
 the car in a number of vintage events and maintained it in a race-worthy 
 condition. Under Keiner&apos;s ownership, 904-042 appeared at vintage races 
 painted red with distinctively silver rocker and rear panels. 

 During 
 Keiner&apos;s ownership it appeared in the April 1992 issue of Sports Car 
 International. Track tested by Mark Gillies, he observed that,&quot;All 
 the major controls are light: the clutch and brakes need soft inputs, 
 the steering is glorious, and if the gearchange is a bit rubbery, it&apos;s 
 still light and swift - provided that you&apos;re firm and deft.&quot;It 
 was sold to a Californian in 1992. Since, it has been shown at the 2001 
 Palos Verdes Concours in Los Angeles. 
 904-043 Sold 
 to Brumos. 1964 : 12 Hours Sebring - Jack Ryan/Bill Bencker 31 OA. 1965 
 : 2000 km Daytona - Jack Ryan/Bill Bencker 9 OA 3 cl. 1965 : 12 Hours 
 Sebring - Jack Ryan/Ted Tidwell 28 OA. Sold to RBM Motors, sold to Ryan. 
 911 Engine, Sold to Bangert. 1973 : sold to Stinchcomb who is an eye 
 physician. he painted the car in silver. 904-044 Sold 
 to Prinoth Italy&quot;NN R 22&quot;, sold to Berger. 1968 : sold to 
 Gunnarson. 904-045 Stoop 
 was the height of his fame in the English Motor racing scene. He had 
 been a works driver for Frazer Nash at Le Mans throughout the fifties, 
 having come tenth in 1954 and winning his class in 1950; and was currently 
 running a chap from the antipodes Paul&quot;Hawkeye&quot;Hawkins in 
 his privately owned Formula 1 team. (Hawkins was to emulate Ascari in 
 diving into the Monaco Harbour in Stoops&apos; Lotus 33 during that years 
 GP meeting ! 
 The 
 Aldington family were the main agents for Frazer Nash and Porsche, and 
 it was through them that he came to purchase the subject of this story; 
 904, chassis #45, on 6th March, 1964.
The introduction of the 904 was eagerly awaited by the UK Motoring public, 
 Stoops&apos; car being the first to arrive on British shores. It was delivered 
 in&quot;Irish green&quot;, the only 904 painted in this colour.
Stoop had ordered his car with a special set of ratios to suit the flowing 
 Goodwood track. With delivery only days away, and the car due to be 
 raced in a club meeting shortly after, it was found that the wrong ratios 
 had been installed. Andre Loubser who was in charge of delivery to VIP&apos;s 
 at the factory decided to make the trek down the Autobahn to Getrag 
 in nearby Ludwigsberg to acquire the appropriate gear sets. 

 After 
 pleading his case to the Managing Director, he was accompanied to the 
 shop floor where a Lathe operator was summoned to make the appropriate 
 parts for Stoops car. In less than three hours, according to Loubsers&apos; 
 own account in&quot;911 and Porsche world&quot;, he was delivering 
 the precious cargo back to Stuttgart. 

 &quot;Two 
 days later my boss, Erich Hirsch called me into his office and said:&quot;Gott in Himmel, Herr Loubser, what have you done this time?&quot;I was often in hot water for when logic dictated that problems had to 
 be solved unconventionally that was more often than not the route I 
 took.
Hirsch had heard about the gearbox saga, of course, and was most upset 
 about what I&apos;d done. First of all, there was a rigidly defined pecking 
 order in German commerce.…and young employees simply didn&apos;t knock 
 on the door of a Managing Director of a large organization such as Getrag. 
 Second all deliveries from Getrag had to be booked into the stores (from 
 where they would later be booked out again) and I had had the nerve 
 to bypass the system. 

 I 
 patiently explained that there was no time for the normal rules to be 
 followed, and that if Stoops&apos; car had not appeared at Goodwood, it would 
 have caused Porsche no end of embarrassment. When I asked Hirsch what 
 would have happened if I had not taken action, he replied,&quot;You 
 would also have been in trouble!&quot; 

 Stoop 
 campaigned his 904 enthusiastically: at the 1964 Grand Prix d&apos;Europe 
 meeting at Brands Hatch he followed home an Elan triumvirate of Peter 
 Proctor, Sir John Whitmore and Jackie Oliver. At the August, 1964 Goodwood 
 Tourist Trophy meeting, in the supporting race for two litre cars, Stoop 
 took the lead early, but Mike Spence in the Chequered Flag Lotus Elan 
 got by him on lap five, and stayed there to win, with Mike De Udy in 
 another 904, third. 

 During 
 the war Squadron leaders Tony Gaze and Richard Stoop would often be 
 seen tearing around the perimeter track at Goodwood, during their off 
 hours from Westhampnett Airbase; and it was indeed Gaze and Stoop post-war 
 that had convinced the Earl of Richmond that Goodwood was most suited 
 to regular motor racing events. 

 Stoops&apos; 
 moment of glory came at Snetterton during the prestigious 100-mile event, 
 named for the famed&quot;handicapped&quot;Lister driver, Archie Scott 
 Brown. Here Stoop claimed the two and a half litre lap record, won his 
 class and kept Peter Clarke in a Ferrari GTO at bay, finishing a credible 
 fifth outright.,Stoop also campaigned the car in Europe, notably in 
 the European mountain Championship at Rossfeld in June, and Freiburg 
 (where Edgar Barth had won in the 718. 

 Stoop 
 was killed in his Jaguar road car, and from his estate, 904 number 45 
 passed to an extensive Porsche collection, in Pennsylvania, where it 
 kept company with some of Stuttgarts&apos; finest and most exotic offspring. 
 Now, the 904 is now with its 3rd owner, here in Australia, the home 
 of Stoops&apos; mate Gaze and about five miles from where a young boy called 
 Hawkins used to man the Petrol bowsers whilst dreaming of racing cars 
 in Europe 
 904-046 Originally 
 delivered to Bernhard Rayers of Bonn, Germany. Mr. Rayers must have 
 been a fairly important person as he ran the car with Factory-supported 
 drivers in 1964. In particular, he obtained the following results with 
 904-046: 
 - 
 1964, wore # 72, with Herbie Mueller, DNF - Targa Florio;
- 1964, with Antonio Pucci, 30th OA - Nurburgring 1000 KM; 

 In 
 the 1960&apos;s, the car made its way to the US. By the late 1960&apos;s, it was 
 owned by Edward J. Ver Schneider of Syracuse, New York. Whether he was 
 the first American owner is not known. What we do know is that he had 
 the car for sale for $ 6800 in 1970. 

 He 
 sold the car to Dan Rowzie of Alexandria, Virginia, who used the car 
 on the road. From Rowzie, 904-046 passed to Miles Collier in the 1980&apos;s. 
 For a time, the car was shown in the Collier Museum in Naples, Florida, 
 next to the ex-Briggs Cunningham 904-018. Unfortunately, the collection 
 was closed to the public in the 1990&apos;s. But Mr. Collier continues to 
 own the car.
 
 904-047 Sold 
 to de Montaign France, Soisbault. 1966 : sold to Yves Martin. 1966 : 
 Rallye Lorraine DNF. Destroyed by fire. 1998 : the papers were sold 
 to Dechaumel who from nothing constructed a complet 904 replica copying 
 the car Pibarot“904 033”. 904-048 Sonauto 
 France - Sold to Simon who raced it, 911 engine. Sold to Park USA. Silver/Orange. 904-049 Originally delivered to Jean-Claude Mosnier of Lyon, France. Though 
 entered to be co-driven with Andre de Cortanze at Le Mans in 1964, 904-049 
 did not start the race. Sold to Dechaumel who raced it in hillclimbs 
 and rallyes. The car was imported into the US in the 1960&apos;s. 1975 : 
 Haney bought the car from National city without engine and restored 
 with a 6 cylinders. 1984 Advertise by Nelson. 1986 Advertise by Haney 
 who sold it to the stock brocker in San Francisco. 904-049 then appeared 
 at the Monte Carlo auctions in 1990, apparently selling at the latter 
 to Jose Segimon of Spain. Segimon then had the car restored by the Factory. 
 He advertised 904-049 for sale in UK in 1996 but, as far as we know, 
 he stills owns the car. 904-050 Originally 
 supplied with a Webasto gas heater, 904-050 was first sold to Jim Hall 
 (of Chaparral fame) and Hap Sharp, both of Midland, Texas. It is possible 
 that this is the car that Ronnie Hissom and Hap Sharp ran at the Sebring 
 12 Hrs in 1964, wearing # 40, but failed to finish. 
 Why 
 Hall and Sharp bought the car has been subject to speculation. In Jim 
 Pasha&apos;s December 1995 Porsche Panorama article, he states that: 

 &quot;It 
 is suspected that the car was purchased to satisfy the curiosity of 
 a major car manufacturer Mr. Hall was doing engineering studies for. 
 What he would have found was that the car had more frontal lift than 
 desired and that the enclosed body had an excellent (for 1964) drag 
 coefficient of about .32 in real-life.&quot;

From Hall and Sharp, 904-050 was sold to Burdette Martin, also in the 
 US. Mr. Martin was ACCUS official representing the US to the FIA. 

 Its 
 current owner, Leonard Turner, of Atlanta, Georgia, acquired 904-050 
 in 1968. Mr. Turner and his wife raced and showed the car for many years. 
 By all accounts, it remains one of the most original and unmolested 
 904s extant. It has fewer than 20,000 miles, still runs on its original 
 tires, and has never been repainted. 
 904-051 Originally 
 sold to Dr. David Lane of Ft. Lauderdale, Florida. Under his ownership 
 it appeared in the following events : 
 - 
 November 29, 1964, wore #47, 10th - Nassau Tourist Trophy;
- December 4, 1964, wore #47, 13th - Nassau Governor&apos;s Trophy;
- December 6, 1964, wore #47, 33rd - Nassau Trophy;
- 1965 : 2000 km Daytona - David Lane/Robert Stoddard 16 OA.
- 1966, with Don/Sesslar, wore #47, DNF - Daytona 24 Hours;
From Lane, the car passed in 1969 to Pete McDowell of Charlotte, North 
 Carolina. 
 904-052 Sold 
 to Coll. 1965 : Tour de Corse with Ligier“956 DQ 66”. Sold 
 to Schlesser“7041 SE 75”who raced it. Sold to Parot and 
 sold to Barbaud. 1973 : sold to Barrat USA.. 2003 sold to Mr Konig (Germany) 904-053 This 
 was originally sold to Porsche Sweden. It was originally delivered with 
 5&quot;wheels with Dunlop SP tires, a webasto gas heater and Solex 
 40 pii-4 carbs with air cleaners. 904-053 was intended for a Swedish 
 rally driver, who apparently took one look at it a reneged. Its ground 
 clearance being insufficient for usage as a rally car. 
 As 
 a result, the car was sold to a Swedish engineer named Sjumesson. He 
 only used the car on the street, advertising it for sale in 1970. 

 Its 
 current and only second owner, Jim Perrin of Columbus, Ohio, acquired 
 904-053 through a broker in 1970. Another timepiece, this 904 survives 
 in completely original condition. It has never been repainted or damaged 
 in any way. Jim has been an active PCA member and brings the car out 
 on occasion. 
 904-054 Sold 
 to Günther Selbach. 1964 : 1000 Km Nürburgring - Günther 
 Selbach 17 OA. In the 70’s the car was sold to USA to Dale. 
 904-055 

 

 

 
 
 Originally 
 owned by Ben Pon. It was delivered in a bright shade of orange and with 
 black vinyl seats.
Dutch Racing Team.1964 : 1000 Km Nürburgring - Gerhard Koch/Ben 
 Pon 3 OA 1 cl. 1964 : 24 Hours Le Mans - Ben Pon/Henk van Zalinge 8 
 OA. 1964 : 12 Hours Rheims - Henk van Zalinge/David van Lennep 15 OA. 
 1964 : 3 Hours Monza - Rob Slotemaker 1 OA. 1964 : Tour de France - 
 Rob Slotemaker/David van Lennep 6 OA. 1964 : 1000 km de Paris - Rob 
 Slotemaker/David van Lennep 6 OA 1 cl. In 1965 chassis 055 was his personnal 
 car and he raced only 055, never 023, this information been supplied 
 to the author by Ben Pon. On the way to Zolder, the driver of the delivery 
 van lost control of the trailer carrying the 904, damaging those vehicles. 
 However after repair, the 904 still won the race. Engine in 023. 1965 
 : 1000 Km Nürburgring - Ben Pon/Rob Slotemaker DNS. 1965 : 500 
 Km Spa 3 OA 1 cl. 1965 : 1000 Km Monza - Ben Pon/Rob Slotemaker 4 OA 
 1 cl. 1965 : 500 Km Spa - Ben Pon 3 OA 1 cl. 1966 : Sold for 7800 $ 
 to USA. 1972 : for sale by Cumbus. 

 As 
 recounted by Jim Pasha in the December 1995 issue of Porsche Panorama, 
 Pon had said about his participation in the European Championship that:&quot;My own goal was to finish as high in the standings as possible 
 in the 904. I knew the car was not as fast as the Cobras, Ferrari GTOs 
 and the then-new Ford GT40, but I also knew the 904 would outlast many 
 of them.&quot;Subsequent to the 1965 season, 904-055 was traded towards 
 a new 906. The Factory refurbished the motor and transmission, and, 
 though it had not been seriously damaged, it was repainted silver. Sold 
 to Warren Eads. 2002 : solf to Schwartz. 
 904-056 Sold 
 to Ancez who raced it in Belgium with a strange alteration to the roof 
 as the owner,“Baron Remordu”was very tall and could not 
 fit into the car. Sold to Germany. 904-057 Originally 
 delivered to Joan Fernandez of Spain. A very active racer in his country, 
 Fernandez compiled an extensive record with 904-057: 
 1964 
 : March : Pujada en costa a Montserrat Catalunya 1st - record
April : Joan Pinyol-RACC - Circuit Montjuic Barcelona 1st - record absolut
April : Rallye Vasco-Navarro San Sebastián 2 OA
May : Pujada en costa a Montseny - RACC - European Championship Catalunya 
 1OA
June : Rallye RACE- (Vuelta a España)- European Championship 
 Spain 1st
September : Pujada Sant Feliu de Codines - Campionat Pujada en costa 
 Catalunya 1st - record
Oct. : Campionat Pujada en costa La Massana (Viladomat) Andorra 1st 
 - record
Oct. : Campionat Pujada Coll de la Botella Andorra 1st
Oct. Rallye 2 Catalunyes, Spain-France DNF
1965 : March : Rallye Falles -Campionat Spain València DNF - 
 Motor
March : Pujada a Montserrat Catalunya 1st
Abril : Rallye RACE - European Championship Spain 1st
September : Campionat Pujada en costa - La Massana Andorra 1st
October : Pujada en costa Barcelona-Andorra Barcelona-Andorra 1st
November : Rallye 2 Catalunyes Spain -France Trencament - Motor 

 Following 
 its racing career, 904-057 was imported into the US by Jonathan Wort 
 of Lebanon, New Jersey. The car was fully restored in the Midwest and 
 remains in the US to this day. 

 2003 
 : MaiI from previous owner : I spent some time digging out photos of 
 904-057 for you. The attached (mail came back, Yahoo said&quot;file 
 too big&quot;, sending seperately) photos were taken in 1982 when I 
 was offering it for sale at my dealership for $48,500. I do remember 
 it having the original motor for it&apos;s chassis at that time having been 
 rebuilt by Wellington in the late &apos;70s. It was a&quot;real&quot;car, 
 not a rebodied, built up thing, only missing it&apos;s dash pad, original 
 wheels and airbox at the time. It also had Sebring exhaust that went 
 with it. I&apos;d appreciate it if you&apos;d share whatever history you know 
 of her, as I became quite fond of it during it&apos;s tenure with me over 
 about 1 1/2 years. The car came from a former US Navy fighter pilot 
 who brought it to America from Europe and I sold it on to another American 
 ~ circa early 1983 when we were experiencing quite an economic slump 
 over here. 
 904-058 Sonauto 
 France. Sold to Roueylou who raced it with the immatriculation.“344 
 ER 11”,“6404 CS 13”. 904-059 Sold 
 to Balas. 1965 : Mont Ventoux - Balas 10 OA. 1966 : Criterium Neige 
 et Glace - Balas DNF. Destroyed in 1966. 904-060 Originally 
 sold to Albert Gwinner of Switzerland. It appears that under Mr. Gwinner&apos;s 
 ownership, 904-060 was never raced. It was apparently only used as a 
 road car.
From Switzerland, the car was brought into the US by, long-time Porsche 
 collector, John Wean, of Fox Chapel, Pennsylvannia. During his ownership, 
 904-060 was fitted with a 2.8 911 RSR motor.
Mr. Wean owned the car for at least 20 years, before it was sold through 
 Dale Miller to Ernie Spada jr of Oswego, Oregon around 1995. At that 
 time, the car was wearing fresh orange paint, included its original 
 motor along with the 2.8 and carried an asking price of $ 320,000 US. 
 It found its way to Mr. Miller as part of a lot that was traded to obtain 
 the ex-Blatzheim 908/03 # 006, that had been on display at Peter Kaus&apos; 
 Rosso Bianco collection.
Mr. Spada had the car completely restored, over a two year period, by 
 Shark Racing, of Portland, Oregon. The result was stunning and the car 
 was shown at least once at a Portland area concours, winning its class.
From Mr. Spada, the car passed to Jerry Seinfeld. Seinfeld&apos;s collection 
 was housed for a time in an airport hanger near Los Angeles. More recently, 
 it may be housed at a garage that Seinfeld has built in Manhattan. 904-061 Originally 
 delivered to a dealer in Frankfurt, Germany named Glockler. From Glockler, 
 904-061 was sold its first owner in Portugal. The story goes that after 
 being passed by a Lamborghini Muira, the Portugese gentleman abandoned 
 the 904 in a garage for many years. 
 In 
 1980, it was acquired by Mr. Touroul, a Parisien who had run a 910 at 
 Le Mans in the 1970&apos;s. In 1988, 904-061 had only 13000 kms and still 
 sported its original Signal Red paint. It was also found to be equipped 
 with a cream leather interior with special carpets and a street exhaust. 

 By 
 the late-1990&apos;s, 904-061 had been acquired by Porsche collector, Alain 
 Salat. In 2000, 904-061 was been restored by a shop in Paris. At that 
 time, the original paint was abandoned for the more common silver exterior 
 and black interior combination. 

 2002 
 : sold to Germany. 
 904-062 Sold 
 to Pierre Jaillardon,“856 CH 13”sold to Maucort. Rallye 
 du Var DNF accident, sold to Contact Garage, sold to Jose Piger as an 
 accident car without engine, gearbox, chassis plate and french papers, 
 sold to Germany where Kurek bought it (Kurek told me that he only get 
 a nude chassis - see the Kurek chapter). The new owner rebuilt the car 
 between 1975 and 1979. 1979 : sold to Bruce Canapa USA.Sold to Morse 
 1989 sold to France to Reynaud who reconstruct the 904 and changed all 
 the front of the car including the radiator and the gas tank. 1991 : 
 auction Paris, car was restored. 1993 STPO. Color Silver with 911 engine.“8261 XQ 06” 904-063 Originally 
 delivered to&quot;Lacourbe de Vost&quot;, apparently an alias for Andre 
 Lacourbe, of Courbevoie, France. He raced the car under the name,&quot;Roy 
 von Vost&quot;.
The car was very badly damaged in an accident on the 11th lap of the 
 1965 Spa 500 KM. Subsequently, it was sent back to the Factory for a 
 complete rebuild. Though its original motor and transmission survived, 
 it required a new chassis and body. At that time, it was fitted with 
 short doors and a central filler cap but it kept the original style 
 tail with the small air intakes. As a result, 904-063 turns out to be 
 somewhat of a hybrid, being comprised of body characteristics from both 
 1964 and 1965.
After its rebuild, 904-063 was raced by Lacourbe, again under the name 
 of&quot;Roy Vost&quot;. At the April 24th, 1966 running of the Coupe 
 USA at Montlhery, wearing number 15, it finished 5th overall. Since 
 that date, little of the car has changed.
In the 1970&apos;s, 904-063 reappeared in California. While owned by Bill 
 Kargas, of Santa Barbara, it was run in the 1977 Monterey Historic Races.
From Kargas, the car was sold to Jeff Cannon of Woodland Hills, California. 
 At the time it had an indicated 825 miles on the odometer. Subsequently, 
 the car was housed in a garage in Paris for 13 years. 
 In 
 the 1990&apos;s 904-063 was acquired by Martin Schroeder of Duingen, Germany. 
 At the time, 904-063 had barely more than 1000 miles on the clock and, 
 other than its Monterey Historic Race experience, has never seen any 
 serious track usage. It was totally original, at least as it left the 
 Porsche Factory for the second time. 

 904-063 
 was then acquired by Sam Yagi of Japan. Since the late 1990&apos;s, his small 
 collection had been for sale through a number of different brokers in 
 Europe and Japan. Priced at $ 500,000 US, 904-063, with its 1600 miles 
 or so, sat virtually untouched in its Japanese garage.
In 2002 904-063 was finally sold to Bill Stephens, who lives in England. 
 This car is a fascinating timepiece and deserves a good home. It also 
 would offer an interesting contrast to some of the gleaming better-than-new 
 cars that we now see, particularly in European Historic racing. 
 904-064 Originally 
 sold to Josef&quot;Sepp&quot;Greger. He raced 904-064 with great success 
 in the 1964 and 1965 European Hillclimb Championship. The following 
 is a summary of the results that he may obtained:
1964:
- June 23, 2nd OA - Mont Ventoux Hillclimb;
- July 7, 1st OA - Ratisbona Hillclimb;
- July 28, 5th OA - Cesana-Sestriere Hillclimb;
- August 11, 5th OA - Freiburg-Schauinsland Hillclimb;
- August 25, 3rd OA - Ollon-Villars Hillclimb;
- September 8, 4th OA - Gaisberg Hillclimb;
1965:
- June 13, 7th GT - Rossfeld Hillclimb;
- June 20, 1st Sport - Wasgau Hillclimb;
- July 11, 3rd GT - Trento-Bondone Hillclimb;
- July 18, DNF - Solitude GP;
- July 25, 5th GT - Cesana-Sestriere Hillclimb;
- August 8, Freiburg-Schauinsland Hillclimb;
- August 15, 2nd GT - Happurg Hillclimb;
- August 22, 1st GT - Ratisbona Hillclimb;
- August 29, 3rd GT - Ollon-Villars Hillclimb;
- September 5, 1st GT (record run) - Augusta Hillclimb;
- Sepember 19, 2nd GT - Gaisberg Hillclimb;
- September 26, 1st (record run) - Schwahische Alb Hillclimb;
- October 10, 4th GT - Innsbruck;
- October 17, 4th GT - Wien Aspern;
In addition, Greger, driving with Kooki, and with the car wearing # 
 41, 904-064 failed to finish at the May 25, 1966 running of the Monza 
 1000 KM.The car was also raced in Italy by Barbuscia.
Later, the car was acquired by Vasek Polak and delivered to his garage 
 in Hermosa Beach, California. While under Polak&apos;s ownership, 904-064 
 was fitted with a 911 motor. Though we are not aware of specific results, 
 904-064 was likely raced in California through the late 1960&apos;s.
Eventually, the car found its way to Polak&apos;s son, Vasek Polak, jr. Through 
 the years the car has been for sale. Around 2000, priced at around $ 
 200,000. It sat in Junior&apos;s garage, virtually untouched, until acquired 
 in 2001 by Steve Johns of Arizona. Subsequent to its acquisition, Steve 
 sent 904-064 to Gunnar to be freshened up and sadly repainted. 904-065 Owner 
 or brokered for sale at some time by Everett Anton Singer from whom 
 no details where firstcoming. Sold to Vincent Faiola USA sold to Gil 
 Shelton, sold to Lichtman, sold to Weldon Scrogham, sold to Peter Sererian 
 .Sold to Europe. 904-066 Originally 
 sold to Archie Walker of Milwaukee, Wisconsin. 
 From 
 Walker, 904-066 passed to Lee Sturdivant of Chicago, Illinois, who does 
 not appear to have raced the car.
Its current (and only third) owner, Henry Payne, acquired the car from 
 Sturdivant in early 1967. Shortly thereafter, he replaced the 4-Cam 
 with a 911 motor. The 4-Cam was sold to Chuck Rathman for 904-036. He 
 replaced the original tail section with a 1965-style tail. Henry has 
 run the 904 extensively. It has been used as a daily driver, for hillclimbs, 
 and vintage races, logging over 100,000 miles. It is certainly the highest 
 mileage 904 extant today and is a testament to the robustness and build 
 quality of these racecars. It stands in marked contrast to all of the 
 horror stories of rusting chassis and epoxy losing its bond.
Before its vintage race career, 904-066 ran at the following hillclimbs, 
 driven by Henry Payne :
- 1969, 1974&amp;1978, Coonskin, West Virgina, obtaining the OA record;
- 1970, 3rd OA - Chimney Rock, North Carolina;
- 1971, FIA Class Record - Chimney rock, North Carolina;
- 1971, 1972, Class Record - Bellefontaine, OH; 

 An 
 engineer, Mr. Payne continues to log many vintage race miles in this 
 very well maintained and usable car. It now shares garage space in Charleston, 
 West Virginia with 906-160, 910-001, 907-005, and 908/02-017. 
 904-067 Originally 
 sold to George Barber of Birmingham, Alabama. Previously, this pioneer 
 privateer Porsche racer, had raced a 550 RS A Spyder in the US. Now, 
 Mr. Barber continues to operate a huge farming enterprise and has a 
 motorcycle and Lotus racing car museum, open to the public, in Birmingham.
Barber and Peter Gregg took the car and raced at the 1965“12 
 Hours of Sebring”. It is said that Gregg took the car off course, 
 bent the right spindle and the car did not finish.
At some point, its original motor was replaced by a 2.0 Liter 911 motor 
 and was red.
In the 1970&apos;s, 904-067 was acquired by Al Alden, a resident of Florida. 
 2002 : The car has passed to a new owner in the US, who the same year, 
 was having the car restored. 2002 : Monterey auction. 2003 : Scottsdale 
 auction. Sadly it lost his untouched condition by being overestored. 904-068 Originally 
 sold to Bruce Jones of Macon, Georgia. By the end of 1964, 904-068 had 
 been acquired by famed (future) 911 racer, Peter Gregg. A one-time part 
 owner in Brumos Porsche, Gregg was a talented but volatile driver. He 
 cut his teeth with 904-068, gaining the following results : - November 
 29, 1964, wore #14, 12th OA - Nassau Tourist Trophy - December 4, 1964, 
 wore #14, 14th OA - Governor&apos;s Trophy (Nassau); - December 6, 1964, 
 wore #14, 22nd OA - Nassau Trophy - April 11, 1965, DNF - Pensacola 
 USRRC - May 23, 1965, DNF - Bridgehampton USRRC (Vanderbilt Cup) - November 
 28, 1965, 2nd OA - Nassau Tourist Trophy - December 5, 1965, 11th OA 
 - Nassau Trophy. The car was sold in 1966 to Bill Lichtman from the 
 Southeast of the US. Unfortunately, he lost his life in a tragic accident 
 at an SCCA race in Savannah, Georgia. Subsequently, the parts sat for 
 close to 25 years, without its center-section (that was lost in accident). 
 More recently the parts of 904068 were acquired by Scot Michael Robottom.In 
 2002, the car was being completely build by a shop in Florida, and after 
 joins his superb ex-Rodriguez brothers RSK, s/n 718020. 904-069 Originally delivered to Heinz Schiller. A serious European competitor, 
 Schiller acquired 904-069.
Schiller also owned 904 039 and from the photo we didn’t find 
 any silver car racing with Schiller.
Subsequent to the 1964 season, 904-069 was sold to a gentleman named 
 Chalut of Genf, Switzerland. The only competitive entry that we are 
 aware of is at the 1965 Ollon-Villars Hillclimb in Switzerland. There, 
 Chalut was classified 80th OA. From Switzerland, 904-069 was sold to 
 Cordell Bahn of Seattle, Washington. Mr. Bahn used the car at the Monterey 
 Historic Races on a few occasions. In 1985, Mr. Bahn sold the car to 
 Robert Heacox. Sold to Bracht who had a restoration undertaken by Trigaux 
 in Belgium. Subsequent to its restoration, 904-069 appeared in a 1992 
 issue of Automobiles Classiques, a glossy, French classic car magazine.
Our understanding is that 904-069 was damaged in a road accident. The 
 car was then apparently completely rebuilt by Feustel in Germany, possibly 
 requiring a new chassis and body at the time. Around 1997, 904-069 was 
 acquired by Irvine Laidlaw a Scotsman, now living in Monaco. The 904 
 is one of a few cars, including 250 SWB and 6CM Maseratis, that he races 
 seriously in European vintage events. Mr. Laidlaw has built an empire 
 in organizing trade shows and consulting but does not consider himself 
 to be a car collector. He has cars that he is interested in using and 
 professes that he will sell a car once he loses interest in racing it. 
 Notwithstanding whatever happened to the car in the mid-1990&apos;s, 904-069 
 is now, a vintage racing 904. It is maintained by Phil Stainton. 2002 
 Tour Auto, I saw that there was no chassis number added on the rear 
 chassis. 904-070 Sold 
 to Handler, Japan. Suzuka Grand Prix in 1964 and has been reproduced 
 in kit (plastic model) form. 904-071 Sold 
 to AFN, England. Sold to De Udy. Raced by David Piper. 904-072 Sold 
 to Carel Godin De Beaufort. Venezuela.who“leased the car to Van 
 Lennep who crashed it in his first race. As the car was not properly 
 insured, this caused many problems for De Beaufort. 904-073 
 Sold 
 to Pierre Martin France. Sold to Allemany who raced it at the 1966 Tour 
 de Corse 1970 : Sold to a person living in Cannes and repaint&quot;Gulf 
 Colour&quot;1989 : sold to Germany to Scheider and restored end of 
 1993. Rumors says that during the restoration a complete car was built 
 and the chassis number 904 073 was put on the new car. 1994 : accident 
 at a milage of 1002 kilometers. The 904 was hit sidewards at the left 
 back wheel. Left and right hand chassis deformed, steering stub axle 
 deformed. 2001 : same damaged condition.
Rumours says that the original chassis and parts of the body which were 
 supposedly destroyed were sold to Belgium with the chassis number 904 
 016 which doesn’t exist any more. 
 904-074 Sold 
 to Giacomo Moioli alias“Noris”who raced it a lot in Hillclimbs.Car 
 was accidented and the chassis body was replaced by the factory with 
 a central filler cap. 1966 sold to Alberto Luti in Italy who also raced 
 it. 904-075 Sold 
 to Jacques Rey. Marokko. 1964 : Targa Florio Jacques Rey/Jean-Pierre 
 Hanrioud 14 OA. 1964 : Tour de France Jacques Rey/Jean-Pierre Hanrioud 
 DNF. 904-076 Though 
 there is little to say about this particular 904, it, nonetheless, has 
 a fascinating history. Its original owner, Nick Begovich, California, 
 still had this car as of the writing of this book ! 
 It 
 has never been raced and has not been restored. 
 904-077 Originally 
 delivered to Italy, the car was acquired through Ernst Prinoth. It was 
 one of very few 904&apos;s that were privately raced in Italy. One must admire 
 the courage of an Italian running a Porsche in Italy against the Alfas 
 and Ferraris of the time. The first owner entered the car in the May 
 13, 1964 running of the Coppa del Cimino, wearing # 252. 904-077 was 
 then sold to another Italian racer named Maestrini. He entered the car 
 in the following races:
- June 6, 1965, wore # 104, driven by Maestrini and Fabri, 8th OA&amp;1st 2 Liter GT - Mugello;
- June 20, 1965, wore # 366, driven by Maestrini, 1st - Camucia Cortona 
 ;
- November 4, 1965, 2nd 2 Liter GT - Shell Trophy at Vallelunga ;
- November 14, 1965, driven by Maestrini, 2nd 2 Liter GT - Viterbo Poggio 
 Nibbio ;
The car was acquired by another Italian, a gentleman named Benelli, 
 in 1985. In 1996, 904-077 was by its current owner, Romeo Balli, and 
 it continues to reside in Italy. It is quite original condition, having 
 only been refreshed and repainted. Mr. Balli occasionally exercises 
 the car and enters it in vintage events periodically.
2002 : Italy. 904-078 Originally 
 acquired by Andrea Vianini, an Italian who was living in Buenos Aires, 
 Argentina, to compete in European road races. The car was kept in Italy. 
 With Bruno Deserti and wearing number 94, it failed to finish the 1964 
 Targa Florio as a result of an accident. The car was apparently sent 
 to the Factory for repairs. Shortly thereafter, and again with Deserti, 
 it finished a respectable 10th overall at the Nurburgring 1000 KM. 
 904-078 
 stayed in Italy, owned by Vianini, into the early 1970&apos;s, used only 
 in minor events. Around 1973, it was&quot;found&quot;by Michael Lederman, 
 a New Yorker who had lived in Italy, for Ernst Benzien of Stratford, 
 Connecticut. Mr. Benzien, while in university in the mid-1960&apos;s, had 
 worked for Lake Underwood, who co-drove Cunningham&apos;s 904 at Sebring 
 in 1964. It was then that he made a mental note,&quot;I&apos;ve got to own 
 one of those one day.&quot;He picked up 904-078 at the docks in New 
 Jersey and drove the car home. His only glitch was that it stalled crossing 
 the George Washington bridge. Certainly an excusable event for a little, 
 unmuffled racecar making its first trip to the big city. Thereafter, 
 it was to be road registered in Connecticut. 

 The 
 car was (and is) very original, having kept its original motor and transmission. 
 It sported Simca-style vent windows that had been added by Vianini. 
 It had a Le Mans night light and a lock to control adding oil or fuel, 
 suggesting that it was set up to run at Le Mans. Also, it had round, 
 below-the-nose fog-lights. Its rough post-Targa Florio&quot;weekend 
 fix&quot;(as Ernst calls it) was quite evident and, as a result, was 
 cleaned up in the 1980&apos;s, along with the car being repainted. Otherwise, 
 it remains as last raced, now having only 8000 miles on the odometer. 

 Notwithstanding 
 its limited restoration, it is in beautiful condition. It was shown 
 at the Louis Vuitton Concours in New York City and won its class over 
 a Ferrari GTO, which seems appropriate. More recently, it was brought 
 to the Porsche racing car reunion at Lime Rock, organized by Brian Redman, 
 in 2001. Another of the select group of very original 904&apos;s that have 
 stayed with a long-term owner, in this case 30 years in the hands of 
 its second owner. 904-078 could not have found a more appropriate owner 
 or home to live out its retirement. A great 904 that, hopefully, will 
 avoid the fate of being concours restored. 
 904-079 
 Sold 
 to Scuderia Filipinetti. 1964 : 1000 Km Nürburgring Herbert Müller/AndréKnörr 6 OA . Hill Climb - Rossfeld AndréKnörr 16 OA 
 . 1964 : 24 Hours Le Mans Herbert Müller/Claude Sage 11 OA. 1964 
 : 12 Hours Reims Herbert Müller/AndréKnörr 12 OA. 
 Hill Climb - Freiburg AndréKnörr 8 OA. Hill Climb - Sierra 
 Montagna AndréKnörr 7 OA 3 cl. Rear body work modified. 
 904-080 Originally 
 sold to Gianni Bulgari of Rome, Italy, supplied with a Webasto gas heater. 
 Driven by Bulgari and Maurizio Grana, wearing number 78, 904-080 failed 
 to finish at the 1964 Targa Florio. The car was registered for the 1964 
 running of the Nurburgring 1000 KM but did not start. 
 From 
 Italy, it was sold to Sam Posey of Sharon, Connecticut in 1966. Now 
 a respected automotive writer and commentator for the Speed Network, 
 Posey graduated from Formula Vee to Sports Car Racing with 904-080. 
 From there, he graduated to Trans-Am racers. 

 Posey 
 adapted the car for tighter US circuits through obtaining bigger brakes. 
 During his ownership, the gas heater was removed and the battery was 
 relocated to the passenger side of the interior. With 904-080 he obtained 
 the following results:
- 1966, # 20, with Harry Theodoracopulos&amp;Jim Haynes 11th-Daytona 
 24 Hrs;
- April 1966, DNF-VIR SCCA National;
- 1966, 21st-Bridgehampton USRRC;
- 1966, with Ray Caldwell, 1st-Watkins Glen 500 (6 Hr race); 

 In 
 a feature on the car in Gmund number 6 Gilbert and Susanne Meyer recount 
 how Caldwell had to stop on the rainy Watkins Glen back straight to 
 figure out how to turn on the windshield wipers!

After the 1966 season, Posey sold the car to Alex Dearborn of Marblehead, 
 Mass. He sold the 4-cam motor to Bob Bailey and replaced it with a 2.0 
 L 911 motor. He added heating, some soundproofing, a 356 fuel tank and 
 a ski rack and used it on the road, including for trips to ski in Vermont. 
 In 1968, he pretty much gave up on the car and it sat outside rotting 
 for two years. 

 In 
 1970, Gilbert Meyer, of Boston, Mass. acquired 904-080. The car was 
 comprehensively restored over a 2 and 1/2 year period and won the Judge&apos;s 
 Choice award at the 1974 Porsche Parade at Pocono, Pennsylvania. 

 Later, 
 904-080 was sold on to Europe, where it stays to this day. 
 904-081 Sold 
 to Andre Potier.“2000 DC 59”1966 : Rallye Picardie DNF, 
 destroyed by fire. 904-082 Sold 
 to Leopolo Barbora Caracas Venuzuela. Driven by Natalini. Said to be 
 destroyed. 904-083 1964 
 :“8537 QD 75”. 3/1965 : Barbier“8202 DG 59”. 
 1965 : Coupe des Alpes, center filler cap car. Sold to Valentin Aldy. 
 France, sold to Cyr Febbraio“71 LH 83”. 1971 : Sold to 
 Germany. 1998 : Bubetz (Munich) sold to Schemel who had the car restored 
 by his friend Bergermann 904-084 
 Sold 
 to Clemens Belgium. 1964 : 500 Km Spa Emile-Claude Clemens. 1964 : 1000 
 Km Nürburgring Marcel van Bierbeek/Emile-Claude Clemens DNF. Blue. 
 Sold to Jean Pierre Gaban, big road accident on his way to Rallye Mont 
 Blanc, 1967 sold to Van Der Schrick who sold it in France 1968 : Sold 
 to USA to Tom Elerding, California. Sold to Kirby. 1980 : sold to Ron 
 Hugues. 2000 Restored 

 Mail 
 from owner : I purchased the car, 904-084, in February 1974 from O.E. 
 Pennington who lived in Lake Mary, Florida (near Orlando). I was a resident 
 of San Jose, CA at that time. The car when bought has already been converted 
 to a six cylinder engine and I was never able to determine exactly when 
 and where that change took place. It was an early 911 2.0 liter motor 
 that was pretty tired. Over time, I replaced it with a 2.7 Carrera, 
 with about 280 hp. I took the car completely apart and did a rebuild 
 of most mechanical parts, as well as a detailing of the undercarriage, 
 etc. The paint and interior were touched up, but it was basically in 
 good condition. I used the car in time trails&amp;some autocrosses 
 throughout Northern California over several years and also took it to 
 the 1975 Porsche Parade in Seattle, WA. At that time, I was very active 
 in the Golden Gate Region of PCA, and there were two other 904&apos;s owned 
 by region members. Harvey&amp;Linda Smith had either # 032 or #033, 
 and Bob Davidson had a car numbered in the low 100&apos;s. It had a factory 
 installed 911 motor. All 3 of us participated in the &apos;75 Parade I menti 
 ned above, and were entered in the Concours. It rained hard that day, 
 so the cars were crammed under som grandstands at a horse race track. 
 It was a mess! the car. I sold it in late &apos;76-early &apos;77. 
 904-085 Handler. 
 England, sold to David Hall USA. 904-086 Originally sold to Lee Cutler of Jacksonville, Florida. He brought it 
 to Nassau in the Bahamas for 1964 Speed Week. There, he finished 11th 
 in the Tourist Trophy, 12th in the Governor&apos;s Trophy, and 27th in the 
 Nassau Trophy, always wearing number 55, and was 1st OA at the Five 
 Laps. Porsche Parade.
For the 1965 season, 904-086 was driven for Cutler by Charlie Kolb. 
 Paired with Roger Heftler, Kolb drove it to 5th overall at the Daytona 
 2000 KM in 1965 and later, that same year, he drove it alone to an 8th 
 overall at the USRRC race run at Pensacola, Florida.
Charlie Kolb, who was about to turn 80 as of the writing of this book,
is still an active racer, competing with his Chevron B8 in vintage races. 
 A very funny, generous, and modest man, Kolb raced everything from a 
 Maserati 300S in the 1950&apos;s to Bill Harrah and Luigi Chinetti-supported 
 Ferrari&apos;s and Factory Porsches in the 1960&apos;s. He was among the quickest 
 of the 904 drivers in the mid-1960s. He recounted a story to me about 
 when he sold his RSK to a German living in the Bahamas. In 1965, he 
 made the trip over to the Bahamas to drive a Factory Bergspyder in the 
 Nassau Speed Week. Having negotiated a sale of his RSK to a Bahamian 
 resident, he brought the over. The new owner was to drive the car in 
 Speed Week races but was seriously outpaced by most of his competitors 
 in practice, including the 904 of Peter Gregg.
So the unhappy RSK owner complained to Charlie. Well, he said to Kolb, 
 I&apos;ve bought your car for $ 5500 and I don&apos;t have a chance, and Gregg 
 wants to sell me his 904 for $ 7500, and he&apos;s up front. Well, as racers 
 are apt to do, Charlie had already spent his $ 5500 on another racecar. 
 So Charlie made the German-Bahamian an offer. He would race the RSK 
 against Gregg and others in an all-Porsche race and, if he placed anywhere 
 other than first, he&apos;d take the car back and return the money.
As Charlie lined the aging RSK on the grid with the other Porsches, 
 the 904 drivers, including his buddies Peter Gregg and George Drolsom 
 ridiculed him. But, sure enough, Charlie did win. And since no one updated 
 the race entry list, later, at the awards banquet, a slightly embarrassed 
 inexperienced and new RSK owner was called to accept his trophy. When 
 he noted to Charlie that he in fact deserved the trophy, Charlie, ever 
 the diplomatic gentleman, said&quot;no, I have enough trophies, it&apos;s 
 yours.&quot;And, sure enough, once he had gotten up the German-Bahamian 
 could be certain of at least one thing, he did in fact now own Charlie&apos;s 
 RSK.
904-086 then passed through a few more owners, including Bob Watkins, 
 before it was disassembled in the early 1970&apos;s. In 1973, its motor was 
 rebuilt with 3-dot camshafts with interchangeable lobes and other modern 
 modifications. It was said to produce 198 DIN HP at that time, which 
 would have given a first-generation six-cylinder a serious run for its 
 money. 
 It 
 was acquired in the mid-1970&apos;s by Californian, Ron Armour, who had the 
 car restored. At that time, six colors were stripped to reach the bare 
 body. It was painted red for its new owner. Armour was responsible for 
 a number of videos, released in the mid-1980&apos;s, that covered Porsche 
 racing cars. 904-086 appeared in the 904 video.
Armour sold the car to Howard Meister of Newport Beach, California in 
 1977/8. It appeared in a Road&amp;Track Salon in July of 1978. 

 In 
 the 1980&apos;s, 904-086 followed the stream of cars that crossed the Pacific 
 over to Japan. There, it appeared at a number of vintage meets, including 
 the Monte Miglia. The car was offered for sale in 2001.
From Japan, the car was sold to a dealer in France, where it has been 
 repainted its original Champagne yellow and now sports an asking price 
 of $ 440,000. It was on display in the pits at the Le Mans Classic in 
 September of 2002 
 904-087 Originally 
 sold to Chris Cord of Beverly Hills, California. Though Mr. Cord eventually 
 became a successful professional racer, it does not appear that he ever 
 drove 904-087 in competition.
Instead, this car became part of Otto Zipper&apos;s Precision Motor Cars 
 team. It was raced extensively by Scooter Patrick, including to the 
 following results (may be):
- 1965, 14th-Pacific Raceways USRRC;
- 1965, 9th-Continental Divide USRRC;
- 1966, 9th-Las Vegas USRRC; 
 In 
 the late 1960&apos;s, 904-087 was acquired by Dick Barbour and was raced. 
 From Barbour it passed to Jim Weickgenant of Oceanside, California around 
 1970. He had it entered in the 1971 ARRC races run at Road Atlanta but 
 did not start : accident. Under his ownership, it ran in vintage races, 
 including the 1982 Monterey Historic Races, where Porsche was the featured 
 marque. 1984 : Sold by Weick Genant. The car was sold to Larry Menser 
 around 1987. Living a short distance from Laguna Seca, Mr. Menser added 
 to 904-087&apos;s continuous west coast history by running it in the Monterey 
 Historic Races, first in 1988 and regularly thereafter.
More recently, 904-087 has left Californian ownership for the first 
 time. In 2001 she was sold to Australian trucking magnate, Lindsay Fox. 
 The car now lives amongst a huge collection in Melbourne, which includes 
 a large stash of 300 SLs and, more notably, a 550 RS and an RSK. 
 904-088 1967 
 : destroyed. 1992 : Rumours says that Feustel bought the 904 papers 
 from M. Hardy and built a complete new car using his own chassis and 
 body. 1997 : Rumours says that Feustel has used the chassis/body of 
 this new car to replace the 904 104 chassis/body and he reconstructed 
 a new 904 088 ? 1999 : Auction London, the car was withdrawn from the 
 sale due to an unsatisfactory provenance. 904-089 Originally 
 sold to Horst Herold of Wiesbaden, Germany. From him it passed to a 
 succession of two German owners including M. Leuze who raced it.
From Germany, it was sold to Mike Robbins of Indiana, in the US. Mr. 
 Robbins raced the car fairly extensively, and obtained the following 
 results:
- 1967, ? - Daytona SCCA Runoffs ;
- 1968, ? - Road America June Sprints ;
- July 28, 1968, with Jack Cooper, DNF (transmission problems) - USRRC 
 Road America 500 ;
- ? - IRP ;
- ? - Blackhawk Farms ;
- ? - Nelson Ledges ;
The car is now back in Germany, in the enthusiastic hands of Klaus-Dieter 
 Frers, who vintage races the car fairly consistently. 904-089 has been 
 restored and is kept in race-worthy condition. 904-090 Sold 
 to Francisco Godia Sales Spain. 1967 : sold to Reynaud“133 RE 
 06”who raced it. 1971: raced by Jeff Klein in SCCA. Still owned 
 by Rudi Klein. 2001 : for sale need restoration as car was sitting 20 
 years in backyard. 2002 : sold. 904-091 Sold 
 to Poac USA. 1965 : 24 Hours Le Mans - Gerhard Koch/Anton Fischhaber 
 5 OA 1 cl. 1966 : 24 Hours Daytona - Günther Klass/Udo Schütz 
 8 OA 2 cl. 1966 : 12 Hours Sebring - George Follmer/Peter Gregg 7 OA 
 1cl. Sold to James Green. 1969 : Accident flipped at Watkins Glen. Sold 
 to Neuman. 2001 Sold to Switzerland and then the car was restored changing 
 the gas tank, the plexiglass, and the seats. 904-092 Originally 
 delivered to Carel Godin de Beaufort of the Netherlands.
From de Beaufort, 904-092 passed to F. English Ltd., a Ford dealership 
 located in the UK. In August of 1965, the car was sold to Patrick Godfrey, 
 who raced it in the UK. In February of 1967, 904-092 was sold to Kenneth 
 Luscome, who only kept the car for a short time before selling it to 
 Alain de Cadanet and John MacKay, also in the UK. During their ownership, 
 the car was raced as follows: May 20, 1967, de Cadanet 15th-Martini 
 Trophy at Silverstone; 
 In 
 the late 1960&apos;s, the car passed to Charles Sayer, and stayed in the 
 UK. Mr. Sayer&apos;s intention was to race the car but it was not competitive 
 enough for him.
In 1970, 904-092 crossed the Atlantic, being imported into the US and 
 finding a new owner in Michigan. From Michigan, it was sold to Bud Fagan 
 of Gainsville, FL in the 1970&apos;s.
By the late 1970&apos;s, real estate heir and magnate, Yoshiho Matsuda of 
 Tokyo and Hakone, was accumulating Porsche racecars for a Museum that 
 he would eventually open in Hakone in the 1980&apos;s, The Porsche Museum 
 of Japan. His collection was to become the most complete private Porsche 
 racecar hoard in the world, amassing a 550, 550A, RS61, 1600 GTL Abarth, 
 906, 910, 908-02 and 917K.
During his ownership a photographic book entitled&quot;Porsche 904 
 GTS&quot;, was produced by Matsuda, highlighting 904-092 but without 
 his early history which was unknown until today.
By the late 1990&apos;s, Matsuda decided to sell all of his Porsches and 
 concentrate on his four Ferrari GTOs. 

 His 
 collection was sold, mainly, through Symbolic Motors. 904-092 was offered 
 through RM and appeared at their Amelia Island and Monterey Auctions 
 in 2000, selling at the latter for $ 240 000. 2003 Restored in Silver 
 and for sale by Mark Leonard USA.The author has the original english 
 title for this car from the 60’s. 
 904-093 Originally 
 sold to Ross Bagdosarian of Beverly Hills, California. This car was 
 to be used as part of the Otto Zipper Precision Motors racing team in 
 1965. It was raced (may be) in the following events:
- March 27, 1965, wearing # 41, Scooter Patrick&amp;Dave Jordan, 10th 
 OA - Sebring 12 Hrs ; - May 2, 1965, wore # 33, Dave Jordan or Jim Adams, 
 4th OA - Riverside USRRC; - May 9, 1965, wore # 31, Dave Jordan, 4th 
 OA - Laguna USRRC GT ; August 1, 1965, Dave Jordan, 15th OA - Pacific 
 Raceways USRRC ; August 15, 1965, Dave Jordan, 11th OA - Continental 
 Divide USRRC. 
 The 
 car was then sold to Brent Doell and Gerry Gregory, who ran a racing 
 team out of Palos Verdes, California. For Doell/Gregory Racing, 904-093 
 was one of two 904&apos;s raced in Southern California by Bob Kirby through 
 to the late 1960&apos;s. The car was offered for sale in 1969. From Doell/Gregory, 
 904-093 was sold to Russell Thurber of Manhattan Beach, California. 
 Thurber apparently did not race the car and he had it for sale in late 
 1970 for $7200. By then, though, the car had become seriously raceworn. 
 The car then crossed the country over to Macon, Georgia, where it was 
 to be owned by an attorney named Bruce Jones. From Jones, the car passed 
 to Dr. Jim Griffin of Birmingham, Alabama. Jim describes the transaction 
 as being kind of frightening, involving a hotel room meeting, some goons, 
 and the transfer of 5000 hard-earned dollars. Luckily, as he remembers 
 it, he left with 904-093.
Once he got the car home, Jim realized that the car needed some serious 
 work before it would be presentable. Towards this end, he purchased 
 a new body from Stoddard in Ohio. To his surprise, the body was delivered 
 in a very flat box. This just could not be right, he thought at the 
 time. But a quick call to Stoddard&apos;s proved that there was no mistake. 
 He was told that these bodies required extensive bending before they 
 could be bonded! He put it all together and, in the end, the car was 
 beautiful.Griffin then sold the car to Charlie Morekis, a Volkswagen 
 and Porsche garage owner from Fort Walton Beach, Florida. Morekis used 
 the car often, entering it vintage races in the 1980&apos;s. He sold 904-093 
 in the early 1990&apos;s. 
 904-094 Sold 
 to Ricketts Motor for 7 425 $. 1964 17th August sold to Otto Zipper. 
 1964 31th August, sold to Jane O’neall.1966 17th June sold to 
 Advanced Production Service (the famous Georges Lucas). 1966 7th Sept. 
 Sold to Bruce Smith. 1967 4th March sold to Harrison Haggard. Sold to 
 Mazzota. 2003 : in Japan. The author has all the original invoices from 
 all the previous owners. 904-095 Sold 
 to Sonauto. 1964 : 12 Hours Reims - Annie Soisbault/Claude Dubois 13 
 OA. 1966 sold to Balas. 1967 : Criterium Neige et Glace. Sold to Freisinger, 
 sold to Webb USA, who in 1985 sold it to H.A Sessions.1996 sold to Mr 
 Jenkins who had the engine restored by Andial. 904-096 Originally 
 delivered to Robert Rhodes of Fresno, California. During Rhodes&apos; ownership 
 it was raced only once. Milt Minter, who would go on to race 917-10s 
 in the Can-Am Championship, was loaned the car for a race at Candlestick 
 Park in San Francisco in 1964. Though Minter finished a commendable 
 2nd, the car was slightly damaged and drowned Rhodes&apos; interest in racing 
 his prized possession.
Rhodes then sold 904-096 to George Thwing of La Jolla, California. Mr. 
 Thwing ran it in SCCA events, and, eventually, had its 4-cam replaced 
 with a 2.0 L, 6-cylinder motor. He advertised the 4-Cam for sale around 
 1970, representing it as having a&quot;stage 3 case and Le Mans Kit.&quot;During his ownership, Thwing was known to exercise the car on the Pacific 
 coast near San Diego. 
 Its 
 next owner was Harry Isaacs of Beverly Hills, California who bought 
 it in 1968.
Martin Konig, who acquired 904-096 in 1989, brought the car to the United 
 Kingdom subsequent to a complete restoration by Nate Cantwell&apos;s Connecticut 
 shop. At that time, its ruby red paint was changed to silver. During 
 Konig&apos;s ownership, 904-096 had been photographed for magazines and had 
 been shown at a few car meets. 

 More 
 recently, 904-096 has joined the growing collection of Mr. Laureys in 
 Belgium. There, it joins an Alfa TZ1, a 33.2 Daytona, and a Stradale. 
 904-097 Sold 
 to AFN England, sold to Morris who raced it in England and Italy, sold 
 to Butler USA. 1993 : bought by M. Jung from MR Sportwagen Switzerland. 
 1994 : Restoration done at the factory of Ruf Automobile for his customer 
 M. Jung. 904-098 Sold 
 to Brandage USA, sold to Tidwell, sold to Herrington.

Mail from Herrington : I owned 098 for a number of years, late &apos;60s 
 to early &apos;80s. I used it as a street car, though I took it to one PCA 
 driving event, (at Marlboro, RIP) where I found that what they said 
 about the car was true-corners like a go-kart, but when it lets go, 
 it&apos;s done180 degrees before you know it&apos;s loose. It was a really great 
 car on the windy hilly roads of northern Virginia, not so great in the 
 concrete jungles of southern California. 904-099 Apparently 
 built as a road car, 904-099 was first owned by Clyde McNeil of Thomas, 
 Oklahoma. He acquired the car through a dealership named Hahn Porsche. 
 Through 
 the actor Robert Redford, the car was then sold to Harry Cohn of Columbia 
 Pictures and moved to Beverly Hills, California. 

 Its 
 third (and current) owner, is Robert Serra of Kansas City, Kansas. He 
 acquired 904-099 in 1975. The car has never been damaged and is now 
 pristine. Most recently, it was shown at the Porsche Club of America 
 Annual Meet at Mt. Tremblant in 1999 and at the 2001 PCA Meet. 
 904-100 &quot;SLS 
 D 905”. Sold To Franz Jung Germany. Originally delivered to Christian 
 Poirot of France. Mr. Poirot would become a loyal Porsche competition 
 car customer, progressing through 906s, 910s and 908s. Wearing number 
 62, 904-100 was driven by Poirot and Rolf Stommelen at the 1965 running 
 of the Le Mans 24 Hrs. Unfortunately, its participation was short-lived, 
 retiring with a broken gearbox early in the second hour of the race.
In 2003 : Cachia told me that he bought his car from Poirot but on the 
 registration paper the car of Cachia appeared to be 904 041.
The car was sold to an amateur racer in California, who raced it successfully 
 on the West Coast for a few years. From there it ended up in Bethesda, 
 Maryland, in the hands of Jim Meehan. 
 Meehan 
 then sold it Dick Barbour, who was living in San Diego. Barbour also 
 owned 904-087 around that time, so it is difficult to be certain whether 
 he raced 904-100. What is certain, though, is that he advertised the 
 car for sale between 1969 and 1972, in a package that included three 
 motors, a spare tail section and various other parts. 

 Jim 
 Derich, another Californian, purchased the car from Barbour in the early 
 1970&apos;s. The car was silver and in restored condition at that time. He 
 ran 904-100 at the 2nd running of the Monterey Historic Races in 1975. 

 After 
 the Poirot accident in 1964 the car was replaced with a new chassis 
 with central filler cap (look the photo in the races result). Now the 
 car is with a right passenger filler cap who is not correct. Something 
 seems strange as a center filler cap does not became a right passenger 
 filler cap without some manipulation !
In 1988 it came to the sympathetic hands of Gilbert Amoroso. For him, 
 the car was completely stripped and fully restored over a three year 
 period. 904-100 was painted black at that time. It received the Road&amp;Track award at the 1991 Newport Beach Concours. He offered the 
 car for sale in 1993 for $425,000. 

 904-100 
 then passed to Jim Barrington of Stinson Beach, California. The car 
 now has three Gmund Coupes for stable-mates. Most recently, it was shown 
 at the Porsche Club of America&apos;s 2000 Annual Meet. 

 
 
 904-101 Sold 
 to Werner Brendel. 1964 : Tour de France Klass/Wütherich 40 OA. 
 Sold to Allen Hilmer. Accident in Long Beach highway crash. 1985 : sold 
 to Kerry Morse. 202 : we believe that only the chassis exists today. 904-102 Sold 
 to Rolf Stommelen 1965 Hill Climb - Rossfeld Rolf Stommelen 6 OA 3 cl. 
 1965 Hill Climb - Freiburg .Rolf Stommelen 7 OA. 1965 Hill Climb - Ollon 
 Villars Rolf Stommelen 5 OA 2 cl.1966 Hill Climb - Sierra Montagna Rolf 
 Stommelen DNF. Sold to Joe Pfister, sold to Bob Bergstrom Japan, sold 
 to Mike Szabo,sold to Dick Lovell, sold to Kato Kenichi 904-103 Sold 
 to Dennis Aase, sold to Hilmer. Destroyed 904-104 Sold 
 to Eddy Meert Belgium. 1964 : 500 Km Spa Meert. 1964 : Tour de France 
 Meert 6 OA. 1967 : sold to Dutoit“7491 DW 59”. 1970 : sold 
 to Consten“241 BD 92”with 6 cylinders 2400 cc. 1995 : 
 STPO France. 1997 : rumours say that the car was restored by Feustel 
 who replaced the rusty chassis and body. Original chassis/body was sold 
 with another number. 904-105 Sold 
 to Heini Walter. Look also 904033. 904-106 24 
 Hours Le Mans Robert Buchet / Guy Ligier 7 OA (but registration show“821 FK 86”who belong to 904-021). The author has the Le 
 Mans registration which confirm 904 106 as car entered. 904-107 Sold 
 to John Fergus USA, sold to Carl Armstrong, sold to Reilly. Central 
 filler gas tank. Engine p99088 Silver. 2001 : in USA Completly restored 
 and for sale in USA in 2002. 904-108 Sold 
 to Schultz.1964 : Tour de France - Robert Buchet /Herbert Linge 3 OA. 
 1 cl.1965 : 12 Hours Sebring - Joe Buzzetta/Ben Pon 6 OA 2 cl. 1965 
 : Targa Florio - Andrea Vianini DNF accident. 2001 : Germany. 904-109 Built 
 from spares by Vasek Polak sold to Stephen Watkins, sold to Mazzotta, 
 sold to David Sablan,sold to Sailors. 2001 Hirsch USA 904-113 1968 
 : Kurek bought some destroyed parts and in 1984 built a new car using 
 his chassis and body. 1988 : Sold to Canada to Boyd. 2002 : for sale 
 in Japan with a 6 cylinders engine. 904-115 1968 
 Kurek bought destroyed parts and in 1980 built a new car using his own 
 chassis and body. 1983 sold to Mr Resnick USA. Sold to Japan. 904-119 2002 
 : construction of a 904 replica with parts. 904-126 Built 
 from parts with 2000 cc 6 cylinders. 1986 Paul Resnick who own a Porsche 
 dismantling emporium in Yonkers sold to Steve Sailors, sold to Ken Maytag 
 1997 for sale in Germany for 140 000 euros (replica car ).
	</body>
</document>
