<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000732" url="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/photo-safe-by-my-eyes-only/id322556928?mt=8" time="2012-07-12-16:05" support="5" score="0.01832363044770914" bingtitle="App Store - Photo Safe by My Eyes Only™" webtitle="App Store - Photo Safe by My Eyes Only™">
			<query id="000919" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000916" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000937" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="000933" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000934" bing-rank="60"/>
	<description>Opening the iTunes Store. If iTunes doesn&apos;t ... want published on the internet if you leave your phone at a fast food restaurant ... long passwords using characters and numbers ...</description>
	<body>
		Apple Store Mac iPod iPhone iPad iTunes Support 
 
 

 What’s New What is iTunes What’s on iTunes iTunes Charts How To 
 Opening the iTunes Store. If iTunes doesn&apos;t open, click the iTunes application icon in your Dock or on your Windows desktop. Progress Indicator iTunes 
iTunes is the world&apos;s easiest way to organize and add to your digital media collection.

We are unable to find iTunes on your computer. To buy and download Photo Safe by My Eyes Only™ by Software Ops LLC, get iTunes now.
 
Already have iTunes? Click I Have iTunes to open it now.
 iTunes for Mac + PC 
Photo Safe by My Eyes Only™

By Software Ops LLC
 View More By This Developer 
Open iTunes to buy and download apps.
 
Description

Photo Safe by My Eyes Only™ is an iOS app that will protect your private photos from prying eyes. All the photos are fully encrypted and completely password protected with photo transfer to web browser or other iOS device over WiFi.

You Need this App If...
You have pictures you want to keep safe, secure and password protected
You are a private person and don’t want your family photos viewed by strangers if they steal your iOS device
You want to use your new iPhones to take close ups of all your credit cards and IDs
You want to use your camera to take close ups of all your credit cards and IDs
You are a spy and want to take photos of secret documents
You have compromising photos of your lover you don’t want published on the internet if you leave your phone at a fast food restaurant
You have compromising photos of yourself you don’t want published on the internet if you leave your phone at a fast food restaurant
You have photos that you don’t want your better half to see
You have photos you don’t want your parents to see


Advanced Features
256 bit encryption of all photos
- Password protected with long passwords using characters and numbers
- Import Photos from Photos App, Camera Roll, directly from a camera
NEW WiFi import/export using any web browser, iOS device to iOS device running Photo Safe
- NEW Bluetooth transfers for devices running iOS 4.0 or better and running Photo Safe
- Create personalized folders
- 16X full sized photo zoom
- Copy and Paste photos from other apps
- Copy and Paste into Message App, (Note: you have to paste the photo that is in the past buffer)
- Send photos in emails

UI and Usability Features
Blazing decryption performance on iPad and iPhone 4 and new iPods; don’t forget that before photos can be displayed they are decrypted.
Retina Display support
- Muti-touch photo browsing, swipe, pinch, tap, double tap, two finger tap
NEW look and feel throughout the app

Encryption so Strong, it Needed U.S. Government Approval for Export
256 bit AES encryption to protect your photos. The encrypted information is protected by a password.

Full Data Wipe and Password Reset
If somebody tries to access your private photos stored in My Eyes Only Photo and enters the wrong password six times, all your photos will be deleted and the password will be reset.

Advanced Password Features
With My Eyes Only Photo, like My Eyes Only(tm), forgetting your password doesn’t mean you can’t get access to the application. A password hint feature is provided to help the user remember their password. It also has a configurable password recovery question and answer that allows users to select their own private question and answer to help the gain access to their photos.


NOTE: To access photos from the Apple Photos app requires that Location Services be turned on. This is a requirement from Apple to ensure your privacy is protected. Photo Safe doesn&apos;t use the location information, but it still needs Location Services activated to import the photos from the Photos Library.
 Software Ops LLC Web Site Photo Safe by My Eyes Only™ Support 
What&apos;s New in Version 2.1.10

- This update attempts to prevent future decryption errors after adding new photos. It will not fix existing errors. We believe the issue is with iOS 5.x encryption routines and we are waiting on Apple to address the issue.
 
iPhone Screenshots
 
Customer Reviews
 
 Password is not safe           
 by
 
 JerryLam1984 
The password used for encrypting/decrypting the photos in this app gets stored on your phone and can be recovered using computer forensics tools. It does encrypt the pictures, but with the password this easy to find, it makes the encryption pointless. This app is only going to protect your photos from an inexperienced user plugging away at your phone. It offers no protection from the experts.
 
 Disappointing.           
 by
 
 RBennett2040 
Useful tool and appealling interface, but the follow up has been awful. The promised ability to re-arrange the order of the photos never came. Without it, I can&apos;t recommend this app.
 
 Good not great           
 by
 
 Emil Andrew 
Works well with pics from the phone but crashes with larger files.
 
Customers Also Bought
 
 Photogene for iPad Photo&amp;Video View In iTunes 
 
 Camera for iPad Photo&amp;Video View In iTunes 
 
 CAMERA-A Photo&amp;Video View In iTunes 
 
 ImageTouch HD Photo&amp;Video View In iTunes 
 
 ArtStudio for iPad - draw, paint and edit photo Photo&amp;Video View In iTunes 
 View In iTunes 
 $2.99 Category: Photo&amp;Video Updated: Jan 25, 2012 Version: 2.1.10 Size: 2.4 MB Language: English Seller: Joe Michels © Software Ops LLC 
 Rated 4+ 
 Requirements: Compatible with iPhone, iPod touch, and iPad.Requires iOS 4.0 or later.
 
Customer Ratings
 Current Version:           41 Ratings All Versions:           534 Ratings 
More iPhone Apps by Software Ops LLC

 
 ID Lock™ View In iTunes 
 
 My Eyes Only Lite™ View In iTunes 
 
 My Eyes Only™ Classic View In iTunes 
 
 InstaContact™ View In iTunes 
 
 
Become a fan of the iTunes and App Store pages on Facebook for exclusive offers, the inside scoop on new apps and more.
 
 Home iTunes 
 
iTunes

 Download iTunes 10 What is iTunes? What’s on iTunes iTunes Charts A-Z Features How Tos 
 
More iTunes

 Digital Music Basics iTunes Ping AirPlay iTunes Gifts iPod + iTunes Support Accessibility 
 
Partner Programs

 Partner as a Company Partner as a Content Provider Join the Affiliate Program Linking Tools iTunes LP and iTunes Extras App Store Volume Purchase 
 
iTunes Store

 Browse iTunes Store Browse App Store Buy Music Now Buy iTunes Gift Cards Redeem iTunes Gift Cards iTunes Corporate Sales Free Single of the Week Inside iTunes 
 
Shop the Apple Online Store (1-800-MY-APPLE), visit an Apple Retail Store , or find a reseller .

 Apple Info Site Map Hot News RSS Feeds Contact Us 
 
Copyright © 2011 Apple Inc. All rights reserved.

 Terms of Use Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
