<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000032" url="http://www.city-data.com/forum/tampa-bay/249382-what-does-mc-donalds-fast-food.html" time="2012-07-12-15:13" support="2" score="0.009760046665431846" bingtitle="What does Mc Donalds/fast food resturants pay? (Tampa: leases ..." webtitle="What does Mc Donalds/fast food resturants pay? (Tampa: leases, consignment) - Tampa - St. Petersburg - Clearwater -  City-Data Forum">
			<query id="001034" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="001035" bing-rank="2"/>
	<description>What does Mc Donalds/fast food resturants pay? Anyone know what the starting pay is for places like Mc D&apos;s/Burger King ...</description>
	<body>
		City-Data Forum &gt; U.S. Forums &gt; Florida &gt; Tampa Bay What does Mc Donalds/fast food resturants pay? (Tampa: leases, consignment) 
 
 User Name Remember Me Password 
 
 
 Register Today&apos;s Posts Search 
 

 Tampa Bay Tampa - St. Petersburg - Clearwater 

 
 Search Forums Show Threads   Show Posts Advanced Search Search Blogs Advanced Search 
 
 Go to Page... 
 Welcome to City-Data.com forum! Make sure to register - it&apos;s free and very quick! You have to register before you can post and participate in our discussions with 1 million other registered members. User profiles and some forums can only be seen by registered members. After you create your free account you will be able to customize many options, you will have the full access to over 15,000 posts/day about local topics and you will see fewer ads. 
 
 Jump to a detailed profile or search
site with 
 Search Forums   ( Advanced ) 
 Business Search - 14 Million verified businesses 
 Search for:  near:  
 
 
 
 Page 1 of 2 1 2 &gt; 
 
 
 
   02-03-2008, 07:25 PM 
 Superbecky79 Senior Member   201 posts, read 475,069 times Reputation: 69 
 What does Mc Donalds/fast food resturants pay? Anyone know what the starting pay is for places like Mc D&apos;s/Burger King/ Target....?

Friend is thinking of moving here and as she is 60 years old she does not want to relocate and not be able to find ANYTHING for work....and a fast food joint would be a last resort but she wants to make sure that it would support a single woman!

Anyone??? 
 
 
 
 
   02-04-2008, 03:15 AM 
 stpeteguy Senior Member   482 posts, read 759,935 times Reputation: 259 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Superbecky79 Anyone know what the starting pay is for places like Mc D&apos;s/Burger King/ Target....?

Friend is thinking of moving here and as she is 60 years old she does not want to relocate and not be able to find ANYTHING for work....and a fast food joint would be a last resort but she wants to make sure that it would support a single woman!

Anyone??? 
 Well those places are always hiring, and most actually pay a buck or two over minimum wage. So i&apos;d say $7 to $8 per hour. 
 
   02-04-2008, 07:16 AM 
 jessiesma Senior Member   849 posts, read 1,813,648 times Reputation: 155 
 is this a serious question Assuming it is, first of all, she won&apos;t even get that level job without being here. Second she probably won&apos;t get hired because of her age, but no way will it support her. FL has added about a $1 to the Fed. minimum wage it&apos;s around $6.75 that should tell you something about the cost of living here. She wouldn&apos;t get much more than that and to live a barely decent life one needs minimum $10/ hr. Those jobs are rare to say the least and demand your life&apos;s blood. She will be pushed to her physical limit and then some. Two things are happening on that level of employment in this area.
First, a lot of places are hiring seniors as seasonal workers during&quot;snowbird&quot;season. Some of these people have the same job up north when they&apos;re there.
Second, we are seeing a lot of&quot;developmentally&quot;disabled folk doing these jobs which is great but they will work for minimum because they are subsidized and the business is subsidized also for hiring them.
Oh, there&apos;s a third. The immigrant population both legal and illegal is large so you have a third group willing to work for very little money because the entire family will share expenses in order to save enough for a nice house and education for the kids.
I&apos;m 61 and married. I am also disabled and it&apos;s tough. I wouldn&apos;t do it. McD&apos;s isn&apos;t a last resort. It&apos;s no resort. If the Op&apos;s friend can come here for a few weeks to look for a job, that&apos;s what she needs to do. Does she not have experience and skills? If she comes she needs to use the Op&apos;s address and phone as a local address.
 

 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Superbecky79 Anyone know what the starting pay is for places like Mc D&apos;s/Burger King/ Target....?

Friend is thinking of moving here and as she is 60 years old she does not want to relocate and not be able to find ANYTHING for work....and a fast food joint would be a last resort but she wants to make sure that it would support a single woman!

Anyone??? 
 
 
   02-04-2008, 07:01 PM 
 Superbecky79 Senior Member   201 posts, read 475,069 times Reputation: 69 
 Well, the fact is she has applied to transfer with her current company. But she would be doing a different job(and she would only move here with that position secured.)
She is more worried about the&quot;what if&quot;that job does not pan out and she just spent a lot of money to move here, then signed a lease and now would have to live here for a few months before moving back cross country.
She grew up poor, so she does worry about the&quot;what ifs!&quot;

She in no way wants to work at a Mc D&apos;s, but if she lost her job then she wanted to know if she could at least pay her bills for a few months before moving back home. She does not want to blow her savings. 
 
   02-05-2008, 05:40 AM 
 Keeper  of dark secrets Status: &quot;hooray.. rain today&quot; (set 1 day ago)   Location: foothills of the Appalachians 12,329 posts, read 14,515,793 times Blog Entries: 1 Reputation: 7694
	</body>
</document>
