<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000899" url="http://www.articlesbase.com/alternative-medicine-articles/increase-your-sperm-count-motility-and-improve-morphology-with-ayurvedic-medicine-3887502.html" time="2012-07-12-16:15" support="3" score="0.003461113642562098" bingtitle="Increase your sperm count, motility and improve morphology with ..." webtitle="Increase your sperm count, motility and improve morphology with ayurvedic medicine">
			<query id="001436" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001421" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="001435" bing-rank="92"/>
	<description>... very broad minded, and yet there is no change in ... energy drink, or high calorie snack from a fast food restaurant ... researches are concentrated on the same line ...</description>
	<body>
		Free Online Articles Directory 
 Why Submit Articles? Top Authors Top Articles FAQ AB Answers 

 Publish Article 
 
 Login Login via Register 

 Hello My Home Sign Out 
 Email 
 Password 
 Remember me?
 Lost Password? 
 Home Page &gt; Health &gt; Alternative Medicine &gt; Increase your sperm count, motility and improve morphology with ayurvedic medicine 
Increase your sperm count, motility and improve morphology with ayurvedic medicine
 Posted: Dec 21, 2010 |Comments: 0 | Views: 384 | 
Today man has achieved tremendous progress in every aspect. Society has become very broad minded, and yet there is no change in the biased approach with the couples without child. A sincere effort is made by Admark Herbals Limited to help some of those couples through OLIGOHerbal Capsule .

Approximately 15% couples attempting their first pregnancy meet with failure. Most authorities define these patients as infertile if they have been unable to achieve a pregnancy after one year of unprotected intercourse. The fact is, among 60% of all couples experiencing infertility, a male factor is involved. In approximately 40 % of cases subfertility is found in the male alone and in another 20% both male and female are abnormal. Barring some physical defects, low sperm count (Oligospermia) and poor sperm quality is responsible for male infertility in more than 90% of cases. Out of these in about 30% to 40% the cause is unexplained, and in the rest of the cases critical illness, malnutrition, genetic abnormalities, pollution, and also side effects of some medicines, hormones and chemicals are responsible. (In short, it is not the number but the quality of the sperm that is important in fertility).

Several studies in different countries have led to the conclusion that there has been a large-scale decrease in sperm count and quality of sperm in last 50 years. And scientists studying the decrease in sperm count claim that human males will be infertile by next 50 years, if the current trend is maintained.
 
 THE ANSWER TO ALL THE PROBLEMS-OLIGO Herbal Capsule 

Benefits of OLIGO Herbal Capsule :

Cures Oligospermia

Increases semen quality and quantity

Stimulates speedy production of sperm and increases sperm count

Makes sperm healthier and strong

Increases sperm motility

Increases sperm fertility and life

Cures abnormalities of sperm

Note :

Dose: For males only two capsules a day compulsorily to be taken with 200 ml. milk

Average period of treatment is about 8 to 15 months

OLIGO Herbal Capsules works as per basic constitution and nature of the person

The medicine is not tested on patient with AZOOSPERMIA , so the result on Azoospermia is not known

 OLIGO Herbal Capsule, challenge to modern science. 

In view of modern medical science, the production of sperm in male body is very complex mechanism, which involves various organs, glands and hormones secreted from the glands. Not only this, but the whole system should function harmoniously. Sperm takes 74 days to produce and mature and therefore there is often a 4 to 6 months delay between treatment of the male and resulting changes in the sperm. If we make the statement in other way – according to modern science it improves sperm count before 74 days.

 OLIGO Herbal Capsules start increasing sperm count within 45 days. 

OLIGO Herbal is not only meant for patients of OLIGOSPERMIA but is a tonic for all human males.

It is concluded from many studies that each succeeding generation of human species is born with diminished physical and mental strengths compared to their ancestors. Among others, the main reason is the characteristic of genes acquired in heredity. The genes are basically transmitted only through sperm, so the quality of sperm is very important in this factor.

With OLIGO Herbal Capsules, reverses the diminution in physical and mental strengths to ensure strong and healthy generations.

Male infertility is a broad and complex subject, this information is intended for only a very general introduction of a very common concern like low sperm count, low motility, weak sperm and abnormal shapes of sperms – for which Oligo Herbal Capsules give very best results. We at Admark Herbals Limited strongly encourage you to find a specialist to fully evaluate your particular situation so that you can better understand the cause of your problem as well as the potential treatment.
 Retrieved from &quot; http://www.articlesbase.com/alternative-medicine-articles/increase-your-sperm-count-motility-and-improve-morphology-with-ayurvedic-medicine-3887502.html &quot; Sanjay Antala - About the Author: 


 
Questions and Answers
 Ask our experts your Alternative Medicine related questions here... Ask 200  Characters left 
 
 Dear Sir, my age is 35 and my wife age is 31. We got married 5 years ago. We checked at clinic. My wife is ok. I have no sperm count. I want to increase my sperm count.Could you give me advise please? 
 
 Does weed increase your sperm count ? 
 
 How to increase my sperm count and what foods to take? 
 
 Rate this Article 5 1 2 3 4 5 vote(s) 4 vote(s) Feedback Print Re-Publish Source:   http://www.articlesbase.com/alternative-medicine-articles/increase-your-sperm-count-motility-and-improve-morphology-with-ayurvedic-medicine-3887502.html 
Article Tags:

 increase sperm count 
 , 
 increase sperm motility 
 , 
 improve sperm morphology with natural medicine 
 , 
 silajit 
 , 
 ashwagandha 
 , 
 satavari 
 , 
 rudanti 
 , 
 zinc 
 , 
 boitite 
 , 
 iron 
 
 
Latest Alternative Medicine Articles
 
More from Sanjay Antala
 
 
 Knowledge is Freedom; Homeopathy is Knowledge: It Answers the Who&apos;s, What&apos;s, When&apos;s, Where&apos;s, Why&apos;s and How&apos;s of Chronic 
 
It was the sinus infections, her doctor told her. The sinus infections never cleared, even with antibiotics; now the infected material went into her lungs and was causing lung problems. The treatments: live with it and take medical drugs. But Kit thought otherwise. She didn&apos;t believe she was doomed to suffer with two chronic diseases for the rest of her life. Kit sought homeopathic care to answer her questions and to heal.
 By: Ronda Behnke ND, CHomP l Health &gt; Alternative Medicine l Jul 10, 2012 
 Is Thai Massage the Same As Yoga? 
 
The similarities and differences between traditional Thai massage and yoga, and an introduction to real Thai yoga or Ruesri Datton.
 By: R. Siam l Health &gt; Alternative Medicine l Jul 06, 2012 
 Advantages of Using Resistance Bands 
 
For beginners, there is simply no alternative to these bands. Besides, if one is opting for complex moves these are great to use. Finally everything boils down to the purchase price.
 By: pubarticle0 l Health &gt; Alternative Medicine l Jul 06, 2012 
 Conventional Facet of Cardiovascular Translational Research 
 
Scientific research shows that heart problems are one of the main reasons for death among people. Medical research facilities happen to be quite aggressive in conducting research to take a look deeper into heart ailments and probe the important changes of heart failure; development and experimentation with new heart scan imaging; diagnostic modality such as molecular analysis; and, prevention and treatments for heart diseases.
 By: Terry Dancer l Health &gt; Alternative Medicine l Jul 05, 2012 
 Detoxification In A Nutshell 
 
The human organism is not in a passive state. It runs the activities of filtration and evacuation of the residues and toxins. The organism is the best cleanser, able to eliminate a high quantity of toxins that harm the inner equilibrium.
 By: Katie Adams l Health &gt; Alternative Medicine l Jul 05, 2012 
 Anemia – a common world problem 
 
Anemia is one of the most common ailments. It can be explained as the decline of red blood cells also known as hemoglobin in the blood.
 By: Sanjay Antala l Health &gt; Alternative Medicine l Feb 23, 2011 
 Admark Herbals Limited – Research oriented ayurvedic manufacturer 
 
Admark Herbals Limited, Dhoraji, India is an ayurvedic medicine manufacturer offering wide range of ayurvedic medicines for health which include herbal medicine for AIDS, hypertension, heart ailment, anemia, diabetes, weight loss, anti-depressant, anti-malaria etc.
 By: Sanjay Antala l Health &gt; Alternative Medicine l Jan 01, 2011 l Views: 132 
 Have You Been Diagnosed with Diabetes? 
 
If you&apos;ve been told you have diabetes, you join 16 Million Americans who have been diagnosed with the disease. Without proper care and treatment, diabetes can lead to life threatening complications. The good news is, there is a lot you can do to prevent diabetes from getting worse.
 By: Sanjay Antala l Health &gt; Alternative Medicine l Dec 30, 2010 
 Are you loosing hair? 
 
We all loose hair daily. The problem comes when it is not restored. Sanjivani Fort is a unique blend of rare ayurvedic herbs and it may be the answer to stop hair loss and prevent balding!
 By: Sanjay Antala l Beauty &gt; Hair l Dec 24, 2010 
 Is Diabetes a disease of pancrease 
 
All over the world, Adult Onset Diabetes is considered as disease of Pancreas. In which Pancreas either stops producing Insulin or produces insufficient Insulin or Insulin is not of standard quality. This is view of modern science about diabetes and all researches are concentrated on the same line. The modern science failed to find effective remedy to cure Diabetes, the main reason they are working on wrong path and ultimately never reach the goal. We at Admark considered Adult Onset Diabete
 By: Sanjay Antala l Health &gt; Diseases and Conditions l Dec 21, 2010 
Discuss this Article
 Author Navigation 
 My Home Publish Article View/Edit Articles View/Edit Q&amp;A; Edit your Account Manage Authors Statistics Page Article Widget 

 My Home Edit your Account Update Profile View/Edit Q&amp;A; Publish Article 
 Author Box Sanjay Antala has 6 articles online Contact Author Subscribe to RSS Print article Send to friend Re-Publish article Articles Categories All Categories Advertising Arts&amp;Entertainment Automotive Beauty Business Careers Computers Education Finance Food and Beverage Health Hobbies Home and Family Home Improvement Internet Law Marketing News and Society Relationships Self Improvement Shopping Spirituality Sports and Fitness Technology Travel Writing Health Acne Allergies Alternative Medicine Anti Aging Cancer Dental Care Disabilities Diseases and Conditions Hair Loss Hearing Medical Tourism Medicine Men&apos;s Health Mental Health Nutrition Plastic Surgeries Quit Smoking Sleep Supplements&amp;Vitamins Vision Wellness Women&apos;s Health Need Help? 
 Contact Us FAQ Submit Articles Editorial Guidelines Blog 
 Site Links 
 Recent Articles Top Authors Top Articles Find Articles Site Map Mobile Version 
 Webmasters 
 RSS Builder RSS 
 Business Info 
 Advertising 
 Use of this web site constitutes acceptance of the Terms Of Use and Privacy Policy | User published content is licensed under a Creative Commons License .
 Copyright © 2005-2012 Free Articles by ArticlesBase.com, All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
