<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000949" url="http://philadelphia.ebayclassifieds.com/food-beverage-hospitality/?catId=100047" time="2012-07-12-16:19" support="1" score="0.001367585764022479" bingtitle="Philadelphia Food &amp; Bev, Hospitality Job | eBay Classifieds ..." webtitle="Philadelphia  FoodBev, Hospitality Job | eBay Classifieds (Kijiji) - Page 1">
			<query id="000694" bing-rank="150"/>
	<description>Cars &amp; vehicles (2521) Community ... JOB ID: PA20202 Job Title: Cashier Company: Job Chit ... fast-food job because we re not an average fast-food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Free, Friendly, Local 
 Create your FREE Ad 
 What In All Categories For sale Pets Housing Cars&amp;vehicles Community Jobs Accounting&amp;finance Administrative&amp;office Architecture&amp;engineering Biotech, R&amp;D;,&amp;science Business&amp;management Construction&amp;trades Customer service Education&amp;training Food/beverage&amp;hospitality General labor Graphic&amp;web design Human resources IT&amp;software development Legal Marketing&amp;PR Medical&amp;healthcare Real estate Retail&amp;wholesale Sales&amp;biz dev Salon, spa,&amp;fitness Transportation TV&amp;film Writing&amp;editing Everything else Resumes Services Where Search 
 Philadelphia Change default location... 
 
 
 eBay Classifieds  »  Jobs  »  Food/beverage&amp;hospitality » 
 1-50 
 of 147 ads
 
 in 

 Popular searches in Food/beverage&amp;hospitality: hotel ,  dietary ,  cashier View as: Categories 
 All Categories  (15383) 
 For sale  (4506) Pets  (3328) Housing  (2401) Cars&amp;vehicles  (2834) Community  (147) Jobs  (1654) 
 Accounting&amp;finance  (100) Administrative&amp;office  (51) Architecture&amp;engineering  (60) Biotech, R&amp;D;,&amp;science  (92) Business&amp;management  (30) Construction&amp;trades  (49) Customer service  (30) Education&amp;training  (35) Food/beverage&amp;hospitality  (147) General labor  (46) Graphic&amp;web design  (14) Human resources  (26) IT&amp;software development  (99) Legal  (19) Marketing&amp;PR  (28) Medical&amp;healthcare  (432) Real estate  (31) Retail&amp;wholesale  (68) Sales&amp;biz dev  (117) Salon, spa,&amp;fitness  (18) Transportation  (62) TV&amp;film  (20) Everything else  (76) 
 Resumes  (19) Services  (494) 
 
   
   

 
 Restaurant Assistant Manager - Growing Company 
 
There’s no place like our restaurants. That’s because we aim to have all of our guests feel like they&apos;re at home. With hundreds of stores across the ...
 
Jul 11 - 
 
 
 Bensalem
 
 Front of the House Restaurant Manager 
 
As customers have discovered new tastes to satisfy their cravings, we’ve been able to adapt to provide them. For the past decade, we’ve been mixing the ...
 
Jul 11 - 
 
 
 Plymouth Meeting
 
 Restaurant Manager - Growing Concept 
 
We don’t just hire managers, we hire personalities. Some restaurants are really concerned about image, no tattoos, no piercings, boring hair colors…we look ...
 
Jul 11 - 
 
 
 Willow Grove
 
 Hooters Girl 
 
The Hooters of Bensalem (3620 Street Rd.) is accepting applications for the position of Hooters Girl.  The Hooters Girl is the essence of the ...
 
Jul 11 - 
 
 
 Bensalem
 
 Hooters Girl 
 
The Hooters of King of Prussia (240 N. Gulph Rd) is accepting applications for the position of Hooters Girl.  The Hooters Girl is the essence of the ...
 
Jul 11 - 
 
 
 King of Prussia
 
 Housekeeper-Lead - Princeton Marriott at Forrestal (12000UKL) 
 
Are you ready to explore new challenges?

At Marriott we can help make it happen – with opportunities for building new skills, ...
 
Jul 11 - 
 
 
 Princeton
 
 Server; Wait Staff 
 
WAIT STAFF
Exclusive Private Community in Princeton, NJ has several Full and Part time wait staff positions available. Prior experience helpful, but ...
 
Jul 10 - 
 
 
 Princeton
 
 Housekeeper - Marriott (12000V9M,12000V9S,12000V9R,12000V9U) 
 
Are you ready to explore new challenges?

At Marriott we can help make it happen – with opportunities for building new skills, co-workers who share your ...
 
Jul 10 - 
 
 
 Philadelphia
 
 Assistant General Manager needed for full service restaurant 
 
Assistant General Manager needed in Moorsetown, NJ for a strong corporate casual dining concept. 

Qualifications: 
Minimum of 2 years GM or AGM ...
 
Jul 10 - 
 
 
 Moorestown
 
 Help Wanted (561 Montolooking Rd, Brick) 
 
Help Wanted

Experience Grill/Short Order Cook

Early morning start
Weekends a must
Potential Management position

Apply between hours of 1-3pm Monday ...
 
Jul 10 - 
 
 
 Brick
 
 Station Attendant - Philadelphia Airport Marriott (12000VFX) 
 
Are you ready to explore new challenges?

At Marriott we can help make it happen – with opportunities for building new skills, ...
 
Jul 10 - 
 
 
 Philadelphia
 
 Housekeeper - Philadelphia Airport Marriott (12000VNF) 
 
Are you ready to explore new challenges?

At Marriott we can help make it happen – with opportunities for building new skills, ...
 
Jul 10 - 
 
 
 Philadelphia
 
 Restaurant GM&apos;s----Hiring Immediately!! QSR Oppty! LOTS OF GROWTH!! 
 
START A NEW JOB WITHIN A WEEK!!!!!!!

 Fast Food Managers!!

 Growth oriented, established and HIGHLY reputable Fast Food franchises looking ...
 
Jul 9 - 
 
 
 Riverside
 
 Full Service Restaurant Managers 
 
I am looking for experienced restaurant managers for solid and stable companies throughout the entire Philadelphia region.

Previous recent restaurant ...
 
Jul 9 - 
 
 
 Philadelphia
 
 Attendant-Laundry - Courtyard Mt. Laurel (12000VFP) 
 
Are you ready to explore new challenges?

At Marriott we can help make it happen – with opportunities for building new skills, ...
 
Jul 9 - 
 
 
 Mount Laurel
 
 Housekeeper - Philadelphia Marriott Downtown (12000V9O) 
 
Are you ready to explore new challenges?

At Marriott we can help make it happen – with opportunities for building new skills, ...
 
Jul 9 - 
 
 
 Philadelphia
 
 Restaurant Manager - Quick Service 
 
For close to 30 years, we&apos;ve become synonymous with getting customers to start their day on the right foot. Whether it&apos;s one of our delicious breakfast ...
 
Jul 8 - 
 
 
 Philadelphia
 
 Restaurant General Manager - Several Needs 
 
We are one of the most recognizable names in all of Hospitality. For the past few decades, we have expanded across the globe, and have even more plans for ...
 
Jul 8 - 
 
 
 Philadelphia
 
 Restaurant Manager - Several Needs 
 
We are one of the most recognizable names in all of Hospitality. For the past few decades, we have expanded across the globe, and have even more plans for ...
 
Jul 8 - 
 
 
 Philadelphia
 
 Restaurant Management needed - New Store Opening 
 
As soon as our guests taste the food we have to offer, they&apos;ll be hooked! Our motto now has been the same as it was when we first opened our doors over ...
 
Jul 8 - 
 
 
 Royersford
 
 Assistant Operations Manager (Job#12000V2O) 
 
With more than 300 managed properties worldwide (including conference centers) our flagship brand, Marriott Hotels&amp;Resorts celebrates the drive, focus, ...
 
Jul 6 - 
 
 
 Philadelphia
 
 Bistro Svr-Refreshing Bus PM - Courtyard Mt. Laurel (12000VFM) 
 
Are you ready to explore new challenges?

At Marriott we can help make it happen – with opportunities for building new skills, ...
 
Jul 6 - 
 
 
 Mount Laurel
 
 Food Demonstrator $12hr 
 
Triple Point is currently hiring Food Demonstrators to represent our clients’ products at a major Supermarket chain.

Duties:
Share information about the ...
 
Jul 6 - 
 
 
 Norristown
 
 Director of Operations 
 
We are one of the most recognizable names in all of Hospitality. For the past few decades, we have expanded across the globe, and have even more plans for ...
 
Jul 5 - 
 
 
 Philadelphia
 
 Food Service workers needed! 
 
Masonic Villages of Pennsylvania at Lafayette Hill is currently seeking candidates for Food Service Positions: Servers and Dietary Workers
 
**Most ...
 
Jul 5 - 
 
 
 Lafayette Hill
 
 Cook&apos;s Helpers and Kitchen Utility Workers needed! 
 
Masonic Villages of Pennsylvania at Lafayette Hill is currently seeking candidates for Food Service Positions: Kitchen Utility Workers and Cook&apos;s ...
 
Jul 5 - 
 
 
 Lafayette Hill
 
 Housekeeper - Courtyard Philadelphia Airport (12000ULR) 
 
Are you ready to explore new challenges?

At Marriott we can help make it happen – with opportunities for building new skills, ...
 
Jul 5 - 
 
 
 Philadelphia
 
 UPSCALE STEAKHOUSE EXECUTIVE CHEF 
 
UPSCALE FINE DINING RESTAURANT COMPANY
EXCELLENT SALARY BONUS AND 401K!
AWARD WINNING UPSCALE GROWTH CONCEPT ...
 
Jul 5 - 
 
 
 Philadelphia
 
 Restaurant GM&apos;s---Fast Food (HIRING NOW) PROVEN FAST FOOD GM&apos;S APPLY!! 
 
START A NEW JOB WITHIN A WEEK!!!!!!!

 Fast Food Managers!!

 Growth oriented, established and HIGHLY reputable Fast Food franchises looking ...
 
Jul 2 - 
 
 
 Riverside
 
 Dietary Worker wanted! 
 
Masonic Villages of Pennsylvania at Lafayette Hill is currently seeking candidates for Food Services. We are currently hiring for a full time Dietary ...
 
Jun 29 - 
 
 
 Lafayette Hill
 
 Guest Service Representative - Residence Inn (12000UHQ) 
 
Are you ready to explore new challenges?

At Marriott we can help make it happen – with opportunities for building new skills, ...
 
Jun 29 - 
 
 
 Cranbury
 
 ASM is looking to hire Demonstrators - multiple locations - PA 
 
Advantage Sales and Marketing, currently has a number of immediate openings throughout the local area. We are looking for outgoing and energetic individuals ...
 
Jun 28 - 
 
 
 Doylestown
 
 Restaurant General Manager - Growing Concept 
 
We are a growing restaurant company that achieves superior financial results by consistently exceeding our guests&apos;expectations. As we continue to grow, our ...
 
Jun 28 - 
 
 
 Princeton
 
 Restaurant Manager - Immediate Opportunity 
 
Year after year we&apos;re ranked by consumers as one of America’s Top 10 highest-rated chains. How come? It might have to do with the quality of food we ...
 
Jun 28 - 
 
 
 Voorhees
 
 Sous Chef 
 
The aim of our restaurants is to create a unique dining experience every time a customer walks through our doors. We offer diverse choices for our guests to ...
 
Jun 28 - 
 
 
 Marlton
 
 Restaurant Manager - Immediate Opportunity 
 
For over half a century, we&apos;ve served American classics to people across the country. We&apos;re annually ranked among the best family dining chains in the ...
 
Jun 28 - 
 
 
 Trenton
 
 Restaurant Manager - New Opportunity 
 
You might know us from our presence in the region. You might not know that we are one of the best chains to work for in the restaurant industry. We ...
 
Jun 28 - 
 
 
 Princeton
 
 Cook - Courtyard Philadelphia Downtown (12000TW3) 
 
Are you ready to explore new challenges?

At Marriott we can help make it happen – with opportunities for building new skills, ...
 
Jun 28 - 
 
 
 Philadelphia
 
 Restaurant General Manager - Quick Service 
 
For the past 40 years, we’ve been setting the bar for outstanding customer service and abundant growth in the fast casual industry. With over a thousand ...
 
Jun 28 - 
 
 
 Cherry Hill
 
 Server-Room Service - Philadelphia Marriott Downtown (12000U3B) 
 
Are you ready to explore new challenges?

At Marriott we can help make it happen – with opportunities for building new skills, ...
 
Jun 27 - 
 
 
 Philadelphia
 
 Birthday Party Host 
 
Looking for an Exciting, Part-time opportunity to work in a fun, fast-paced environment? Look No Further! The Brunswick Corporation has over 165 years of ...
 
Jun 25 - 
 
 
 Lakewood
 
 Looking for candidates with culinary and cooking skills! 
 
Masonic Villages of Pennsylvania at Lafayette Hill is currently seeking candidates for the Food Service Position: Kitchen Utility Worker.
 
Kitchen ...
 
Jun 25 - 
 
 
 Lafayette Hill
 
 Bravo Pizza In-House Server/Delivery Driver (9 West Ridge Pike Rofo) 
 
Job Description:
This position will be responsible for delivering orders to customers who place orders by telephone for delivery. 

When there are no ...
 
Jun 25 - 
 
 
 Royersford
 
 Hotel Director of Sales and Marketing 
 
Director of Sales&amp;Marketing needed for historic, downtown Philadelphia hotel, rich in local tradition. Major renovation to begin 3rd quarter will move ...
 
Jun 22 - 
 
 
 Philadelphia
 
 Housekeeper - Residence Inn Cranbury South Brunswick (12000SIZ) 
 
Are you ready to explore new challenges?

At Marriott we can help make it happen – with opportunities for building new skills, ...
 
Jun 21 - 
 
 
 Cranbury
 
 Guest Service Representative - Courtyard (12000T7D) 
 
Are you ready to explore new challenges?

At Marriott we can help make it happen – with opportunities for building new skills, ...
 
Jun 21 - 
 
 
 Wayne
 
 Hiring Now Rock Star GM&apos;s / MGRs/ Kitchen Mgrs 
 
Interviewing and HIRING MANAGERS NOW!!!!!!
 
 If you enjoy working in a fun, high-energy environment with a growing company where the game is ...
 
Jun 21 - 
 
 
 Philadelphia
 
 Restaurant Assistant Managers 
 
Restaurant Managers--Upscale Trendy Bar and Grill Managers
 Managers with experience from concepts that serve  Fresh Food Menus
 
 Job ...
 
Jun 20 - 
 
 
 Philadelphia
 
 Guest Service Representative - Marriott Hotels(12000TBC) 
 
Are you ready to explore new challenges?

At Marriott we can help make it happen – with opportunities for building new skills, ...
 
Jun 20 - 
 
 
 Philadelphia
 
 Supervisor-Restaurant - Marriott Hotels (12000SN4) 
 
Are you ready to explore new challenges?

At Marriott we can help make it happen -- with opportunities for building new skills, ...
 
Jun 19 - 
 
 
 Princeton
 
 
 1 2 3 
 

   eBay Classifieds offers a number of food/beverage&amp;hospitality job listings in Philadelphia, such as housekeeping jobs, hotel management positions, part-time chef jobs, cleaner jobs, food product ambassador jobs, food services assistant positions and environmental services associate jobs. Perhaps you are looking to do catering services for wedding and anniversary events in your local area. When you find a suitable job, send in a cover letter and a resume along with any additional documents or information that you feel may be of use. You can do so by clicking on the reply button on the ad page, or additionally you can phone the advertiser if a number is provided. Help About Blog Mobile Apps Privacy Policy Terms of Use Contact Us Popular Items Twitter Facebook YouTube 
Copyright © 2012 eBay International AG
	</body>
</document>
