<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000314" url="http://whimsicaltimes.wordpress.com/" time="2012-07-12-15:30" support="1" score="0.0015007221983343029" bingtitle="Whimsical Times" webtitle="Whimsical Times">
			<query id="001227" bing-rank="217"/>
	<description>what the....LOL Bohan wanted to throw my scarf ... The kitchen also looked a lot like a fast food restaurant of ... The storage area is hidden somewhere behind ...</description>
	<body>
		Whimsical Times To remember past memories, present fun, and future dreams 
 
 Home About 
 
Latest
 
 End of Michaelmas ~ 
 
Wow, so term has finally ended, and I have got to say that it totally took me by surprise–8 weeks is seriously just waaaaayyy too short for one term XD  I’ve been busy finalizing our Europe trip plans and also packing all my stuff up because I have to move out of my room so College can rent it out for admission interviews as well as conference or other function attendees =\  Yes, it’s been a very hectic final week of term, and almost none of it academic related XP

On that note, I had another race–the Novice Fairbairns Cup on Thursday Dec 2.  First and Third NW1 ended up getting 22nd out of 50 or so entries, which wasn’t great considering the NW1 crew from last year got 4th, but I guess it’s more motivation for us to train harder to race next term =P  The senior crews were supposed to race on Dec 3, but because it’s been soooo cold the past few days, severe ice on the upper stretches of the river caused them to cancel the race (in fact, our novice race course was also shortened because of ice).  Even though they didn’t cancel the novice race due to the weather, it was still the coldest I’ve ever been while rowing, and my feathering hand got owned–I don’t think I’ve ever felt so much pain in my hands before x__X To officially end my last day in Cambridge for Michaelmas term, I went to Fairbairns Dinner, a fancy 3 course meal with bread, wine, and tea with the boat club.  The senior members said it was kind of strange this year because they didn’t race before the dinner, but it was still a lot of fun =)

So yeah, couple rowing/racing and packing, the end of term definitely did not feel like the freedom I usually feel when a semester ends at MIT =P  Still, I’m super psyched to go to Morocco tomorrow morning…err I guess it will be later this morning now (XD)…I will finally be warm for a week!!!  Sooo looking forward to non sub-zero temperatures again (yes, I mean in Celcius =P)  After Morocco, it’s an immediate switch to our Europe winter trip, so I will definitely not be writing much for the next month or so, but expect a lot of pictures and stories from the trips once mid-January comes around!

Until then!!! =)

 
 
 Posted by whimsicaltimes  |  December 4, 2010 | Categories: Uncategorized | Leave A Comment» 
 
 Clare Novice Regatta 
 
Nov 27 ~

Today was my first boat race ever!!!  Since we needed to be at the boathouse at 8:20am, I got up at 7 to make sure I had ample time to eat breakfast and dress warmly.  I thought it was going to be freezing cold so I ended up wearing tights + MIT sweatpants, two thin long sleeved shirts under my First and Third t-shirt all under a Northface fleece jacket and finally a peacoat, two pairs of gloves, and my Trinity wool scarf =P  Needless to say, I overdressed a bit, but always better to be safe than sorry right? Hahaha.

The brisk walk over to the boathouse was gorgeous – it was cold enough this morning that there was a light layer of snow covering everything, and as I was up so early, I even saw the layer completely untouched in some places ^___^  Yup, that was really cool…the first snow in Cambridge is so much earlier than in Boston!!!
 
Trinity Great Court with the first snow this season!!!!
 
At the boathouse, I warmed up on the ergs with some of the girls that were there already, and then we got our boat Peter Brandt out when the entire crew + cox + coaches turned up.  By this time, some of us were starting to get a bit nervous…we actually haven’t rowed together in this group of 8 at all before the race (while on the other hand we heard that our opponent today – Wolfson College – had been rowing with the same crew since the beginning of term x__X), and we were using racing blades (called cleavers) instead of the training blades for the first time as a crew today.  Hahaha – our coaches kept telling us over and over again that they taught us in novice term how to row properly, not how to race, so we should just try our best =)
 
Peter Brandt in the river - look at the snow on the bank!!! XD
 
A little about the race today – it is a side-by-side knockout race.  Basically, two boats line up next to each other at the start point, and whoever reaches the end first wins that round and moves on.  The losers get to go home =P

So off we went!  We actually had to row quite a distance to get to the start of the race course, which was basically the furthest we have ever gone up the river on a training outing before, so at first we just went at a good pace up the river.  Then we had to stop and wait a bit at our marshalling point, during which it started to snow!!!  Omg!  Snow while we had to race didn’t sound like the most appealing thought to me, but luckily it was just a light snow and it stopped shortly after it started…phew =P  Anyway after we chilled at the marshal point for who knows how long, it was finally time to row the final stretch up the river to the start point!!!
 
Moored along the banks at the marshal point. Yup, that&apos;s my forehead...semi-failed attempt at taking the picture by myself XD But, it started snowing!!! (there are snowflakes in my hair! XP)
 
“Wolfson, First and Third, attention! Go!”  Three short strokes, 5 powerful strokes winding up to the full slide, then 10 high pressure strokes before settling down to a good racing pace.  That’s what is called the
“racing start”, when you try to explode from the starting line with a strong start.  Unfortunately for us, we’ve only practiced racing starts since the beginning of the week, so we were a bit uncoordinated, and although I was staring straight ahead, I could tell out of the corner of my eye that Wolfson had gone past after awhile.  Ahhh well…we could still hear our coaches yelling from the banks so we continued to row hard =P  About halfway through the course, I could tell that everyone was getting a bit tired – as the stroke, I could really feel it when we start getting out of sync, and it got to the point where my slide/recovery went only half the distance it should’ve gone XD  Still, even though we lost, overall it was a good race and now I can finally say I’ve been in a rowing race before! =D  Hehehehe.  And the weather actually became really nice after our race – the sun was coming up and I wasn’t even cold since we were rowing so hard (I took off my peacoat at the boathouse, and then ended up taking off my scarf, gloves, and jacket as well right before the race started)!  Since we lost, we immediately rowed back down the river to our boathouse, and by the time we got out, I was aptly tired from rowing up and down the river at a faster pace than normal, not to mention racing down one stretch of the river =P  Luckily for me, I didn’t get wet at all, but some of the girls behind me were pretty drenched from the furious rowing during the race XP  I guess it’s nice to be at the back of the boat ^___^
 
Crew pic (plus cox =P)...hahah sorry there were two cameras so not everyone is looking at this one
 
So yup, that was it for my first race!  We’re actually racing again next Thurs and Friday in Novice and Senior Fairbairns, the biggest race of the first term – for FaT, traditionally novice women’s 1 (NW1) crew –which is us =P – rows as women’s 2 (W2) for the Senior Fairbairns race x___X  Apparently the senior racing course is 4.5 km!!!  We’ve never even rowed that distance in a regular outing, let alone race that distance x___X  To do final training for Fairbairns, we also have outings, tomorrow, Mon, Tues, and Wed.  Adding on to the two races means I will be rowing everyday for a week….hahhah I’ve never trained for a sport so much before XP  Lol…next week will be very very interesting =P

 
 
 Posted by whimsicaltimes  |  November 27, 2010 | Categories: Uncategorized | Leave A Comment» 
 
 Mid-November Fun =) 
 
Ok, finally updating!  Hahah sorry for the inactivity…A simple breakdown of what has been going on is basically – lectures/practicals/supervisions, rowing, and formals =P  Hahahaha yup.  I’ll just skip the first one and talk about rowing and formals XD

 Rowing: 

We finally learned and started to practice feathering which is where you rotate the blade 90 degrees towards you so that the flat of the blade is parallel with the water’s surface when the blade is out of the water, and then square the blade (rotate 90 degrees back – what you normally think of when you think of rowing with oars =P) when the blade is in the water.  As stroke, my blade extends out to my right, so I am supposed to use my inner hand (right hand) to do the feathering by rotating my wrist back and forth, which turns out to be a lot more tiring than I expected XD  Hahaha.  Still, it was nice to progress a little further in our rowing technique; in addition to feathering, we practiced balancing the boat by sitting up straight and trying to minimize side-to-side wobbling movements while stroking.  In one outing where we were in a 4 again because not enough people were available, we managed to balance the boat so well that we could row all 4 blades squared without feeling like the boat was going to completely tip over XD  Yeah…I can tell we’re definitely improving, which is a really cool feeling =)  A week before Clare Novice Regatta (see other entry), we started practicing racing starts as well, and even had two practice erg sessions – which were super exhausting.  In the first erg session, we erged for two 15 min periods (which is actually not that much at all, but they kind of just dumped it on us out of the blue&gt;__&lt;) and in the second session, we practiced racing starts and 500 meter sprints 4 times x______X  Now that was painful….especially since before we have always been just rowing at an easy pace, and all of a sudden they’re telling us to push really hard XP  Hahaha gotta get back in shape soon….=P

 Formals: 

I’ve upped my formal count by so many since the last report!  Lols, here is the latest count:

Trinity (x4)
Churchill
Gonville and Caius
Murray Edwards
St. John’s
Emmanuel
Queens’
 
Murray Edwards formal with ABACUS
 
Trinity/St. John&apos;s international students&apos;swap (at John&apos;s)
 
 
 
Formal at Emma! Thanks Bohan! =P Lols...Stephie and I were both wearing glasses...XD
 
Summary?  Seven colleges, 10 formals XP  Will be 11 by next week as I have a Christmas formal dinner at Trinity tomorrow =P  Hehehe, not bad, but I definitely want to cover more colleges next term!!! =P

 

 Last couple major events of note: 

We went to London again on the 20 th !!!!  Reason?  David Chen was here!!!  Hahaha he flew over to tour a company that has given him a job offer, and was free on Saturday so he asked us if we could come to London, and of course we said yes (along with Bohan and Steph) =P  The weather was definitely not as nice as our first London trip, and we had to leave later in the day because Stephie had supervision that ended at 11am, but obviously it was still a lot of fun to go to London.  This time, we were smart and headed straight to Chinatown for a delicious lunch after meeting David at his amazingly pretty/fancy hotel XD, and then took him to see the Parliament buildings/Big Ben.  In the evening, we wandered over to Oxford Street, which felt very much like NYC with the multitude of shops, plus there were Christmas holiday light decorations all the way down the street ^____^  Overall it was an easygoing day – we didn’t plan anything in advance so we weren’t rushing to go anywhere, and it was awesome to catch up with someone from MIT =)
 
^____^ Hi David!!!
 
It was Thanksgiving the past Thursday!  Lol, sadly enough, the British don’t celebrate thanksgiving so we didn’t have a nice four day weekend like everyone back home is enjoying right now (on the flip side, our term ends next week so I guess it wouldn’t make sense to have a break now….XD).  Fortunately for us, the Cambridge/American alumni club hosts an annual Thanksgiving lunch to celebrate the holiday and try to make us feel a little more at home for Thanksgiving, which was really nice.  It was a fancy lunch in the University Centre building, and we were served a main course meal of slices of turkey with bacon-wrapped sausage and vegetables, dessert that consisted of a slice each of pumpkin, apple, and pecan pies, and wine =P  They also gave everyone a free Cambridge University crest pin, which I thought was really neat XD  Hehehe we got to see a few other CME people too, which is always nice ^___^
 
Thanksgiving Lunch =)
 
I think that just about sums everything up – I might’ve missed a few things, and forgot some details here and there, but hey, if I can’t remember them, they couldn’t have been that important right? XD

Can’t believe end of the term is coming up so soon!!  We have to figure out the last bit of reservations for our winter break trip (sooooo excited!!!) and pack as well!!  Ahhhhhhh x__X  Lol hopefully it won’t be too hectic next week XD
 
 Posted by whimsicaltimes  |  November 27, 2010 | Categories: Uncategorized | Leave A Comment» 
 
 London in 12 hours =D 
 
Nov 7 ~

I woke up at 7:30am today to get ready for our first day-trip out of Cambridge in London!!! =D  I left Trinity early because I wanted to wander around town for a bit and take some more pictures before meeting up with Stephie and Bohan in front of Emma at 8:45am. We then walked to the train station (which was around 20 min away) and met Steph RIGHT in time to catch our 9:20am train (we were literally waiting at the platform for Bohan to get his tea at 9:17am XD talk about a close call =P).  Unfortunately because we were so late to get on the train, there were no more seats available, so we stood the entire 45 min to London x__X  But hey, I somehow got tickets for the four of us for 8 pounds each ROUNDTRIP, so who’s to complain if we have to stand instead of sit…lol.  Steph had also bought some plums, and Stephie got croissants at the station, so we munched on a small breakfast as the countryside zoomed by past us ^___^

 
 
Train station at Cambridge
 
It was so sunny in the morning!!! =D We were scared for awhile that it might rain today XD
 
All too soon, we arrived at King’s Cross Station!!!  The first thing we wanted to do obviously was find Platform 9 ¾, but couldn’t find it and didn’t want to keep wasting time trying, so we decided to just look harder at night when we were heading back to Cambridge…hehehehe.  So off we went!

First stop on the Underground (the equivalent of the T in Boston) – Westminster.  Right when we exited the subway station, we saw Big Ben!  It was just like in V for Vendetta except that they were doing some maintenance construction on the Parliament building right next to it, which spoiled the scene somewhat XD  Still, it was a beautiful sunny day at the moment, so we all got our cameras out and started snapping away…I think we all played the roles of tourists very well today XP  Continuing on, we walked across the bridge so we could see Parliament and Big Ben from the other side of the river, and we also got a nice view of the London Eye.  Going even further, we walked past Westminster Abbey, which was sadly closed to visitors due to worship service today, but the outside façade of the building was still impressive enough.  They were also commemorating WWII sacrifices by putting the red poppy on little wooden fences on the grass outside forming plots dedicated to different groups of people who fought in the war.

 

 

 

 
 
Parliament from across the river
 
London Eye
 
the sky was really pretty XD
 
Westminster Abbey
 
 

 

 
 
they&apos;re wearing gowns like at Cambridge!!!! =P
 
12 noon!
 
Next, we walked along Whitehall (a street with a bunch of government/parliament buildings) heading towards Trafalgar Square.  Before we reached the Square, we stopped by the entrance to a museum where two guards were sitting virtually motionless atop two beautiful black horses.  A bunch of tourists were fascinated and kept running up to the horse+guard and taking pictures, which was funny because there was a sign behind them warning that the horses might kick or bite XD  Anyway, we FINALLY reached Trafalgar Square afterwards, and I got super excited because we saw the monument in V for Vendetta that the people all dressed like V walked past before reaching the soldiers near the end of the movie ^___^  Sooooo cool!!!  The monument was on a tall pedestal of stone and we all really wanted to go up, but it was a little tall and the stone slippery so Bohan had to help us a bit XD  But we made it!  Stephie and Bohan also wanted to climb up another stone pedestal with a huge brass lion on it so they could sit on its paws =P

 
 
This was in the movie!!! Except...there were no vehicles, it was nighttime, and everyone there had masks and black cloaks =P
 
Trafalgar Square, behind the monument
 
After wandering around the Square for a bit, we all decided that we were getting pretty hungry, so we started scouting for a place to eat lunch at.  Steph and I ended up going into this one nice looking pub called The Lord Moon of The Mall….LOL.  And it turned out to be another Spoons (a pub really close to Emma in Cambridge that we go to for the curry night on Thursdays =P), so we decided to eat here since it was cheaper than all the other places around the Square.  Steph 2 and Bohan all got fish and chips, and I ordered Sunday Pork Roast, which came with Yorkshire Pudding (more like a flaky pastry crust thing instead of really pudding…no idea how the British named this thing…), potatoes, steamed broccoli and carrots, and peas…a nice and filling lunch =)

MOVING ON!  We walked down a nice long straight stretch of road known as The Mall, which connects Trafalgar Square with…Buckingham Palace, home of the Queen!!!  Because we were literally taking forever at each of our stops, I jokingly imposed a rule that no stopping is allowed until we get to Buckingham Palace, which resulted in some blurry pictures as we all tried to still take pictures while walking XP  It was a really nice walk though – the sun which had disappeared behind some clouds came back out again, and the trees lining the street were all yellow, making it feel very bright and warm even though it was actually pretty cold XD  hahaha.  The Palace itself was at the end of the street behind another monument with gold-gilded gates keeping the tourists at bay =P  Again, with the sun out, it was a really impressive and beautiful sight, and to think…this is where royalty lives!!!!  The scrollwork on the gates were really intricate, and if you got close enough to peer through the gates, you could see solitary guards standing motionless in front of more doors past the main gate and a large square behind the gate before you actually reach the palace building XD  Random fun fact:  apparently to qualify to be a part of the Queen’s royal guards, one has to have served in the army for at least 22 years…and this is just for ceremony!!! X___X

 
 
entrance to The Mall from Trafalgar Sqaure
 
Steph was really happy when she saw all the dead leaves on the ground ^___^
 
The Mall
 
Statue in front of Buckingham Palace
 
 

 
 
Gate leading to the Buckingham Palace front plaza
 
the Palace
 
decoration on the front gates...
 
LOOK AT MY PRO SKILLS!!! I took this picture on the first try! =D
 
After Buckingham Palace, we walked back down The Mall, but turned before hitting Trafalgar Square again to reach Piccadilly!  (Another aside: I kept updating Steph 2 and Bohan on the streets that have an equivalent property in the British version of Monopoly – Piccadilly is a yellow property, Bond St. and Oxford St. (both of which we didn’t get to see today) are green properties, Trafalgar Square is a red property, and Pall Mall is a pink property =P)  This street resembled New York City the most to me as it was soo crowded, with large-screen advertisements and billboards everywhere =)  We wanted to have afternoon tea in London, so we found a small café (Café Nero) and sad down for some milk tea for Bohan and Steph, and hot chocolate for Stephie and me.  It was so nice to take a break after walking so much (even though we did technically sit down for lunch too…but still XD)…plus it was warm inside – I wanted to just sit longer and relax but we still had so many more places to see!!!
 
a Pizza Hut restaurant we passed by...they&apos;re sooo fancy here! O__O
 
 

 
 
A fancy cafe we passed...wanted to try it out for afternoon tea until we found out it was 14 pounds a person x___x But the cakes do look sooo delicious!
 
Hot chocolate...with WHIPPED CREAM and belgium chocolates on top!!!! MMMMMMMMM
 
Next stop – Tate Modern.  The building was originally a warehouse of sorts, but they converted it to have several exhibits dedicated to modern art.  After wandering through the rooms in the museum, I’ve come to the conclusion that I can’t really appreciate modern art XD  I was extremely confused at most of the pieces in the museum, and completely baffled at what they were trying to represent…it might also have been because I was starting to get tired and a room full of large paintings with pale stripes just didn’t really seem that special to me…XP  There were some pieces that were pretty interesting, but on the whole, I didn’t enjoy the museum all that much =P

 

 
 
A taste of what was in the museum...
 
Those are birds...and arrows...and a sketched city skyline outline....
 
what the....LOL Bohan wanted to throw my scarf in the pile x__X
 
now this was cool! a flower sculpture made from some kind of thin metal...
 
Tower Bridge was the next place on our itinerary – we could either take the subway from the Tate, or walk along the river.  We decided to walk…which my foot which was starting to hurt slightly from an old TKD injury was not too happy with, but the night scenery was beautiful along the river.  Especially when we finally spotted the Tower Bridge, which was aglow with lights…it was soooo pretty!!!! =)  For dinner, we ate at a restaurant called Strada which overlooked the river + Tower Bridge–we shared a rosemary and garlic pizza bread appetizer, and then we each got a pasta dish.  The total bill came out to be around 50 pounds (x___X) but the food was good and the restaurant had a nice ambiance ^___^  hahahahaha…the portion sizes weren’t that large though (as expected as we are in the UK after all…), and I think our waiter was surprised when we were all almost done when he came to ask us how the food was =P
 
St. Paul&apos;s Cathedral (as seen from the Tate Modern) at night...little camera does funny things with the colors but it looks pretty neat like that =P
 
little camera gets super grainy at night...&gt;__&lt;Tower Bridge in the background!
 
Tower Bridge! Yay! This pic turned out well =D
 
Strada =D
 
At this point in time, we were all pretty exhausted and briefly considered taking an earlier train home.  But Stephie convinced us to check out Chinatown, which we did, and good thing too!  We all tried a delicious Pork Bun and got boba milk tea!!!!  We could’ve each gotten like…8-9 buns for the price of our dinner, and probably have enjoyed it more too XD  Oh well…the thought of food and a warm restaurant was just too tempting while we were in the Tower Bridge area =P  Next time though, we’re definitely coming back to Chinatown for food first XP

Finally after a long long long day filled with walking, we headed back to King’s Cross.  Since it was still a bit early, we attempted to seek out the ever-elusive Platform 9 ¾ again…After vainly searching for awhile, Bohan finally decided to just ask a worker at the Station – “Excuse me sir, where’s Platform 9 ¾?” LOL.  Sounds like it came right out of the Harry Potter movie =P  The worker laughed good-naturedly and directed us to where it was….tada!!!  At last!  It was so exciting that we all had to pose with the trolley halfway immersed in the wall, and then do a self-timer group picture in front of the sign ^___^  tehehehehe.  On the way to our actual platform, we decided that we should all get together to have a Harry Potter movie marathon before watching Part I of the 7 th movie coming out soon!!! =P
 
Platform 9 3/4!!!! (self-timer =P)
 
12 hours later…our train back to Cambridge departed from King’s Cross Station.  Today was such a wonderful fun-filled day – a taste of what our Europe trip this winter will be like no doubt!  Only thing is, my foot was really killing me by this time so I definitely need to get a brace before I run around Europe like today for a month =P  A quick 45 min later, we were back in Cambridge, and 30 min after that, I had walked safely home and am happily lounging on my couch =P

More pictures will be posted on Facebook (also check Stephie’s fb as she took a lot with the D40 while I had the little point-and-shoot, and the night ones turn out much better on that camera than our little camera =P).

And so ends our London trip =)  Good night!
 
 Posted by whimsicaltimes  |  November 8, 2010 | Categories: Uncategorized | 1 Comment» 
 
 Tea + Rowing 
 
Nov 6 ~

Today, I experienced my first official British afternoon tea event – with the MIT Club of Great Britain at Sidney-Sussex College.  It was pretty fun – obviously tea was served, along with an assortment of cakes and desserts =P  We also got to talk to some MIT alums who are at Cambridge right now and as always, it was fun comparing and contrasting the two schools as well as the two countries XD

Today was also my worst rowing outing yet – even the beautiful weather could not make me enjoy it in the least bit.  I guess it was a combination of a very inexperienced novice cox and some rowers who didn’t know how to stabilize the boat; essentially we had to keep stopping because the boat would get too close to the banks, and when it was finally my turn to row, most of the time I couldn’t get my blade out of the water because the boat was tilting too much to the stroke side x__X  Sigh…maybe I should try to be less critical of novices but it is hard after having such a nice outing on Thursday XP  Here are some pictures I took on my way to the boathouse…
 
St. John&apos;s College entrance (on the left)...resembles Trinity&apos;s Great Gate a lot =P
 
 

 

 

 
 
The exact same view as last night (Guy Fawkes Night)...except in the afternoon - the fireworks were launched just behind those two short trees on the other side of the river (taken from the balcony of Trinity First and Third Boathouse)
 
Dinner was at Dojo again with Stephie, Bohan, Stephen, and Arsen and Stephie and I shared a curry udon dish this time that was really yummy ^___^  Then we all went home and worked….hahah but it’s ok because tomorrow we’re going to London!!!! Yaaaaaayyyyy!!!!!!
 
 Posted by whimsicaltimes  |  November 8, 2010 | Categories: Uncategorized | Leave A Comment» 
 
 Remember remember the 5th of November! 
 
Nov 5 ~

Hahaha it feels so cool to type November 5 th out especially since I’m in England right now =P In terms of classes, the day went horribly as for some reason I was feeling especially tired and found it really hard to stay awake and focused.  It might also have been because we changed profs in two out of my three classes, and the new profs were not as exciting and enthusiastic as the previous ones XD  On the other hand, lunch was good as we went to the Chinese take-out restaurant yet again…I think we’ve seriously become regulars at that place now – the woman who takes orders can recognize us already and even suggested that we call in advance to place our order so we wouldn’t have to wait for our food to be prepared =P  Definitely something that we will try out next week as it will give us more time to go to Emma to eat and relax in a warm cozy room before Path practicals on Wednesdays and Fridays XP

Popularized by the movie V for Vendetta, Nov 5 is actually a holiday in the UK (Guy Fawkes Day), and to celebrate it, Cambridge hosted a Fair, fireworks show, and bonfire on Midsummer’s Common.  Trinity First and Third also had their annual Nov 5 boathouse party, where they served mulled wine (red wine heated with orange slices in it), beer, tomato and basil soup, and toasties (white sandwich bread with cheese and deli ham grilled on one of those Panini press things…).  The wine was actually pretty good since the orange flavoring masked most of the strong bitter taste, and the toasties were also surprisingly tasty despite being so simply made =P  At 7:30pm, the fireworks started, and I ended up watching it from the front of the boathouse as the balcony was already really full.  The location was amazing!  Our boathouse is literally directly across the river (which isn’t very wide) from where they were launching the fireworks…During the 4 th of July fireworks display in Boston last year, I had thought that sitting on the esplanade across the river from the Prudential tower was incredible enough as the fireworks were shot from a barge in the middle of the Charles River around that area, but I was even closer to the launch point tonight!  So close in fact, that I had to crane my neck back during most of the show to see them explode in the sky =P  Yeah, that was really cool except for the fact that it was windy and rainy and I ran outside when the show started in short sleeves without my jacket so it was pretty cold XD  And although the location was a lot better tonight than in Boston, the July 4 th firework show was overall a lot more impressive especially with the Boston skyline as a backdrop and the Boston Pops concert projected by huge speakers =P

 
 
Look at how close I was!!! =) Although there was a river separating us =P
 
The balcony of Trinity First and Third&apos;s boathouse
 
Novice rowers! =) Helen&apos;s (on right) Trinity-colored umbrella was sooo big!!! And we were all really wet XD
 
After getting aptly wet, I went back to Trinity to change clothes with Stephie before grabbing some juice and a banoffee pie I bought at Sainsbury’s earlier and heading off to Emma to watch V for Vendetta with Steph and Bohan!!!  After a 3 rd viewing, it is still one of my most favorite movies ever, and it was even more exciting this time as we noted down the places we saw in the movie as places we would see when we go to London! =D  Also, the banoffee pie was absolutely delicious despite being premade and it was also only 3 pounds!!!  The slice I got at Pizza Express awhile back was less than a quarter of the size of this one and also over 4 pounds O__O  Yay for a great movie – it made the walk back to Trinity afterwards totally worth it ^___^

Side note:  I had the pleasure of seeing the very confused expressions of two of my friends today as they found out that I have a twin =P
 
 Posted by whimsicaltimes  |  November 6, 2010 | Categories: Uncategorized | Leave A Comment» 
 
 Random thoughts =P 
 
1.  You get a LOT of professors here for each class, and I really mean A LOT!  At MIT, I had at most two profs teaching a class a semester (like orgo and 7.013)…here, BMB class alone has 12 profs for the year….O_______O  It’s a little strange having to adjust to a new teaching style, new lecture notes, and slightly new material every few lectures or so since I feel like they don’t really transition well from one lecturer to the next…

2.  I just realized I have gone a month at school without referring to my classes with numbers O__O  It’s BMB, Path, or Pharm all the time, as opposed to 7.02, 7.03, 7.05 and 21F.039/Japanese Pop Culture like spring semester sophomore year =P  Heheheh I miss my numbers XD

3.  You’re not allowed to bring food or drinks into lecture halls…WHAT?!?!  At MIT, EVERYONE has a cup of coffee with them for an early morning class…how do you stay awake without coffee&gt;__&lt;LOL

4.  People in Britain say“keen”instead of“interested”or“excited”.  As in,“the novices this year are so keen [about rowing]!!!”=P  Funny no?

5.  I can to Cambridge thinking that I wouldn’t see Stephie a lot–I mean, makes sense since we’re in different Colleges and you’re supposed to be closest to the people in your own College.  Turns out, we see each other EVERYDAY–during the week because we have classes every day together, and during the weekends because…well…we’re always hanging out with Bohan and Steph =D  And we are still as paranoid as ever about what each other is doing at every moment of the day–most of our gchat messages or texts to each other are“WHAT ARE YOU DOING???!?!”or“WHERE ARE YOU?!?!?!”….or something like that XP  HAHAHAHHAHAHA….fail…..

6.  A car blasting“Dynamite”just went past my window on Trinity Street XD  lol
 
 Posted by whimsicaltimes  |  November 5, 2010 | Categories: Uncategorized | 6 Comments» 
 
 Mostly about food…and rowing =D 
 
Another multi-day update:

Nov 1 ~

Hahahaha I really don’t think I remember much about today except that I had brown bread ice cream for dinner, which I’ve been told by multiple people is the best flavor of ice cream at Trinity.  Unfortunately for me, I was still very much sick on Monday especially with my stuffy nose, so I couldn’t properly taste it…but it seemed interesting enough =)  It was like a vanilla ice cream base with brown bread crumbs inside except the crumbs were a bit crispy…it made for a very unique texture for the ice cream =D

Nov 2 ~

We went to Selwyn for dinner today!!!  My first time eating at Selwyn, which was pretty nice =D  The kitchen also looked a lot like a fast food restaurant of sorts – it was painted bright red and yellow, and had servers in matching uniforms + colors, and some signs on the walls stating the menu =P  Tonight, the main course was spaghetti with meatballs, which didn’t sound or look that appetizing, but turned out to be pretty yummy!

After dinner, Bohan, Stephie, and I went to Magdalene (pronounced Maudlin…no idea why XD) for a CUFAS Fireworks Safety training which ended up repeating some of the techniques we learned at a previous session, but I guess the boringness was somewhat mitigated by the unbelievably cute kitten pictures the presenter put in his slideshow (yeah…kinda strange, but omg they were sooooo cute XP).  Yup, that’s basically it for today – kind of funny how I have so much free time on Tuesday (since I only have practicals from 2-5pm and we normally get out at 4ish….) and yet I somehow don’t really get anything done….

Nov 3 ~

Pharm lecture today was on obesity, and to my utmost surprise, our new lecturer is American!!!  Hahaha not that I have anything against the British accent (I still believe that we Americans sound very crude compared to the British…anyone with a British accent automatically gets like an elegant and refined status XD), but it was really nice and comforting in a way to hear a non-British-accented lecture – made me feel more at home =)  The only downside was we didn’t have handouts for the class, and the presentation slides weren’t going to be posted, so Stephie and I were furiously trying to copy down notes the entire time – even tag-teaming it (we each copied half of a slide), we still missed some of the material….x__X  They lecture so fast!!!!

At night, I went to Hall with Max for dinner and met Hilmy there (I swear because of Max, the majority of Trinity fresher’s I know/am around are medics…lol and they are so much more hardcore than I am XD).  During dinner (because they are medics and I am a medic wanna-be which in Hilmy’s book means I’m a medic XP), we talked about what we did/learned in classes today, and Hilmy launched into another discussion about how Americans are so much more obese than the British because of our portion sizes..LOL.  They also tried to convince me to stay another year at Cambridge (after this one) and so finish my last year here instead of at MIT, but that will never happen =P  Highlight of the dinner though, was actually walking to and from Hall – because the temporary kitchens (those ugly green building things at the Hall corner of Great Court) are FINALLY being dismantled and taken away, the normal walkway to Hall was blocked off, so we sneakily walked over a stretch of Great Court grass under cover of darkness…mwahahahahah XD  The sad thing is, I actually felt bad about breaking the rules and stepping on gras…NOW WHY WOULD I FEEL GUILTY ABOUT STEPPING ON GRASS?!?!?!  Sounds pretty ridiculous huh…? =P

On another note…I can’t wait until they open up the new kitchens!!!  I took a sneak peak at it and it looks so sparkling clean and white and new and AAHHHHH it won’t officially open til next term -________-

Nov 4 ~

Rowing this morning – at 7am!!! X___X UGH you know it’s waaaay too early to be up with people in California are awake when you go to sleep AND when you wake up the next morning.  Amazingly, it was warm outside, even at 6:45am when I left Trinity to walk to the boathouse, and it was actually pretty refreshing to be up so early while the sky was still getting bright =)  As usual, I’m one of the first ones there, but luckily all the other rowers except one showed up within 15 min past 7am (good job guys!), so with our experienced rower coach, we made 8 even with the one no-show…phew.  Since we had an experienced cox again (who also happens to be one of our lower boat captains), we very efficiently got the boat out of the boathouse and were one of the first ones to push off from the banks, exactly at 7:30am.  So much for me boasting that Trinity has not made us go on a 7am outing before…that’s going to change now with daylight savings making it dark outside BEFORE 5PM!!!! SAAAAAADDDD x__X

Anyway, there were sooo many boats out on the river this early in the morning (the reason why our LBCs continuously tell us to be available during the afternoons when the river is less crowded&gt;__&lt;) so our rowing efficiency was actually pretty low – every few strokes, we’d have to stop the boat to let another College push off the banks.  However, we did get in some nice and even stern 6 and bow 6 rowing going on – rowing with 6 people feels just as smooth as with 4 people now, which is great! =D  Maybe spending so much more time in the coastal IVs is finally paying off….Our cox even decided that we should give a go at rowing with all 8 at the same time (aka no one sitting the boat) – it was pretty cool since this was only the 2 nd VIII outing I’ve been in and already we’re trying to go all 8 rowing.  However, because again the river was really crowded, we didn’t get really far before we had to stop and switch back to rowing in 6’s (since we’re much smoother rowing 6’s and it isn’t polite to hold up boats behind us XD).  As stroke again, I had to pay particular attention to maintaining a good rhythm for the people behind me to follow, which ended up being a bit hard today since the wind was really strong, and my blade kept getting caught in the water during the finish because the boat would wobble when we were rowing all 8.  Still, I think our coaches were pretty happy with us today, which is always a good sign ^__^

The rest of the day was spent in BMB practical, where we did a 2.5 hr-long session on bioinformatics (basically using a computer to analyze sequencing data), during which I could not seem to stay awake XD  It was also the last supervision with my current Path supervisor as we will be switching to the person we were supposed to originally have next week (pro: it will be at Trinity so I can go home earlier =D, con: apparently this supervisor will rip your essays apart x__X *scared*).  My current supervisor is soo nice too!!  He told all of us that if during the course of revising we feel like we need extra supervision sessions with him to just let him know personally and not go through College since that will be too much of a hassle XD

Lunch at Dojo, a Japanese noodle restaurant place that also has Taiwanese, Singaporean, Malaysian, and Thai-style noodle and rice dishes =D  Absolutely delicious and decently price for the size (Stephie and I shared)…sigh I love Asian food XD

Dinner at Spoons (omg 5.99 pounds for curry, rice, naan bread, poppadums with mango chutney,  and a large mug of delicious hot chocolate with whipped cream…mmmmmmm ^___^) and then work at Emma before coming home tonight =)  I even finished typing my essay =P so all in all, a fairly productive day =D

NOT TO MENTION:  we finally started booking and seriously looking into transportations and accommodations for our Europe trip this week – as in I seriously spent virtually all of Tues and Wed night planning instead of working x__X  Luckily I didn’t have much work to do this week anyways, and I finished typing my essay all today, so now I just have to copy it over on paper and draw some accompanying diagrams XD  Planning this trip is hard…especially trying to compare prices and arrange dates so that you can get the cheapest deals while still maintaining decent quality of living/traveling XP  Hopefully everything turns out well – most important is to have fun with friends right? ^__^
 
 Posted by whimsicaltimes  |  November 5, 2010 | Categories: Uncategorized | 1 Comment» 
 
 What a week!! =P 
 
Whew I’m finally writing again after an entire week!  Here’s a breakdown of what happened the past 7 days…(hopefully I remembered everything XD):

10/25 ~

Monday!  Normally I wouldn’t be so excited about starting a new week of classes but today I get to row – again!  Day 3 out of 4 in a row…lol.  It was also an absolutely gorgeous day to go rowing – the sun was out, the river was calm, and most importantly, there were virtually no other boats out!  I think I saw maybe 1 full 8 out on the river, a couple of one and two-people scullers (have two blades per person instead of just one), and a small barge – and that’s about it! O___O  It was amazing!  We basically had the river to ourselves ^__^  After my outing, I raced back to Trinity to get ready for my Pharm supervision, only to find out that my supervisor was so sick she had to cancel the supervision today – hooray (for me, not her XP)!!!!!!  I actually got to relax a bit after rowing instead of trekking all the way to the Pharm department which is a good 15-20 min away.  The only bad thing is that it meant I had to make up this supervision on Saturday morning, but at the moment, it was totally worth it =P

After my evening BMB supervision, I get a text saying that Steph 2 (Yiwen, your idea is brilliant XP), Bohan, and Stephen were meeting at The Anchor (a pub right outside Queens’) and so I went to go join them.  Instead of staying there though, because it was so crowded we decided to leave and wander around town until we finally ended up at The Cow (another pub =P) where everyone except Stephie and me got something to eat.  And I think that just about brought me to all the major pubs in the town except a couple….tehehehe XD

10/26 ~

Rowing, again!  Today was my first early morning outing ever, and it wasn’t even that early to be honest – I just had to be at the boathouse at 8am (Steph 2 and Bohan have all had legit early early morning outings).  The weather was not that great today – pretty windy which made it fairly hard to steer and it started to lightly rain near the 2 nd half of our outing, so I experienced getting wet on the river yet again =\  Even better, our cox decides to have all four of us row at the same time today, which seemed like a terrible idea to me the entire time we were doing it.  There’s a reason why we only row in pairs in the fours – the stability provided by the pair not rowing is irreplaceable…as soon as we lost the two blades “sitting” the boat, we started tilting everywhere.  It was quite a scary experience, especially since I literally felt like we were going to capsize on multiple occasions, but we were told to just keep rowing.  It was even harder for me because as stroke I was the one setting the rhythm for everyone, so even when my blade got “caught” in the water (which was quite often since we were tipping so much), I had to resist the sudden pressure and just push through it, and that ended up getting a bit uncomfortable after awhile…We somehow made it in sync for a few strokes though – I totally appreciate the impact of using a pair to stabilize the boat now x__X  (And here I was wanting them to let all four of us row together….)

At first, I was kind of sad that this would be my last outing for the week, until I got an email later saying that they really wanted to get an VIII out on Saturday at a time when I was free!!!  So of course I leapt at the chance to sign up for one of the remaining 4 spots =P  Really excited about Sat now… Steph 2 and Bohan have all started rowing in VIIIs, so I’m the last one (Trinity’s boat club believes in taking a longer time to teach their novices the correct technique for rowing, which is easier done in smaller boats =P).

At night, I went over to Queens’ for dinner because Stephie had sent me an email with a link to their menu that week and the dinner tonight sounded pretty good – except we both got really mad at the cashier since I got charged a cover fee again (we were hoping to bypass it since it was only me this time…)!!!!  Grrrrr I’m not eating at Queens’ anymore until we can figure out this cover charge problem…1.2 pounds per meal per guest actually starts to add up pretty quickly….

10/27 ~

Today was such a double-edged sword day – as in it was awesome because so many cool things were going on today, but I also started feeling really sick (I swear Stephie gave her illness to me like she always does x___X).  I had this bone-deep weariness weighing me down the whole day and felt like I could’ve crashed at any time, but surprisingly, I was able to stay completely awake through all three lectures PLUS Path practical, something that I don’t think I’ve quite managed before XP  Who knew…maybe being sick has its virtues =P  Highlight of the class was Pharm lecture, when the Professor who was telling us about the insulin pathway said this at breakneck speed: “So insulin activates its receptor, which activates IRS-1, which activates Type I PI3-kinase, which phosphorylates PI4,5P 2 to PI3,4,5P 3 , which activates PDK-1, which then activates PKB, which inactivates GSK-3, which inactivates glycogen synthase, thus stimulating glycogen synthesis.  I could say that even faster after a couple of beers.”  ROFL.

For lunch, Bohan took Stephie and me to a new place called Gourmet Burger Kitchen (I always think of CPK XD) where we had delicious hamburgers!!!  There was a time not too long ago when I refused to eat hamburgers, but now I actually find myself missing them XP  And the burgers were so good that we decided to come back here again tomorrow during our lunch break from BMB practical (though still not as amazing as Pour House) =P  LOLs  It wasn’t even too expensive because Bohan had a card where you can get a 40% discount Sun-Thurs, plus I think Stephie and I just need to reconcile ourselves with the fact that everything in the UK is expensive and we can save our stomachs a lot of pain (ie by being hungry) if we’d just accept that fact XD

Anyway, the fun started after practical when Stephie and I headed over to a place called The Shop for our first studio shoot session with the photography society (henceforth known as PhoCUS).  At first, I was a bit grumpy about signing up to do this right after classes because I wanted nothing more than to go to my room and sleep, but I’m really happy I came – it was soooo cool!!!!  The lesson for today was to play with a single light source using fancy lighting equipment (black/white studio shoot umbrellas, a soft box, etc) and we had the entire hour to try out different angles of lighting.  The only unfortunate thing was that the society member in charge split Stephie and I up, and Stephie took our camera, so I don’t have any of the original pictures that my group took with me right now (I’m working on getting them from the girl whose camera we used though!).  Anyway, I put up some of my favorites (sorry for the bad quality – got them off of her picasa album…remember this was a shoot playing with light =P).  I’m really looking forward to more studio shoot sessions now…I think we’ll get to use two light sources at the next one, and the goal for the term (or maybe year…I forgot what the guy said XD) is to be in charge of our own shoot with hair/makeup assistants, a real model, and a lighting assistant =P  I mean, HOW COOL IS THAT?!?!?!  Not that I’m anywhere close to being good enough for that yet XP
 
Elona - I asked her to flip her hair and captured this shot =P The white light is from the softbox.
 
Elona and Parin - softbox lighting from the side.
 
soft box lighting from the top =D
 
Soon after, it was time to go to HK Fusion (the really yummy Chinese food restaurant we ate at earlier) for an ABACUS dinner + karaoke event.  The restaurant was conveniently located right across from St. John’s main entrance (aka really close to Trinity =P), so in no time, I was enjoying a most delicious dinner buffet =D  Food was sooooooo gooood!!!!!!  Hall food is acceptable after repeated exposure until you get a taste of legit Asian food again (yeah, you know…in which the rice is actually cooked properly…) XD  Here is the menu for the night:

1. Authentic aromatic crispy duck + pancakes + sweet hoisin sauce.
2. Crunchy deep-fried seaweed (v)
3. Roast crispy belly of prime pork
4. Fish fillet ladled in sweetcorn sauce
5. Beautiful Ma po tofu (v)
6. Traditional savoury chicken satay
7. Classic stir-fried beef infused with spices and black bean sauce
8. Marinated King prawns lightly tossed in salt and pepper
9. Sweet and sour succulent pork balls–Hong Kong style
10. House Special Ho Fun
11. (mix and match) Mixed vegetable in szechuan sauce (v)
12. (mix and match) Chinese vegetable (pak choi) chop suey (v)
13. Steamed rice (v)
14. Special fried rice
15. Plain fried noodles (v)

The first item was especially tasty – it’s usually eaten as a starter dish where you take a piece of thin tortilla-like pancake and you add duck meat, thinly shredded cucumbers and green onions, and sweet hoisin sauce, and then wrap the whole thing up like a burrito ^____^  Sigh…Stephie and I seriously talked about going home home just so we could eat good food again =P  After dinner, we watched some of the members sing to Lady Gaga (XD) and then headed over to Cindies!!!  Too bad Stephie was being lame and didn’t join because she had to wake up early to row tomorrow, but this makes the 5 th club in three weeks that I’ve been to (which is 5 more than the past 20 years of my life XP).  And thus ends my Wednesday.  Only at Cambridge will people be able to convince me to go to a club at 11pm, and succeed in doing so =P

10/28 ~

Luckily for me, BMB practicals don’t start until 11am, so I was able to sleep in for a bit =P  Even better, the practical was fairly quick today, so we were out by 2:30pm, at which point Bohan, Stephie, and I decide to go to Grafton center because Stephie and I have never been there before (a shopping area approx 5 min away from the back gate of Emma =P).  Grafton has a really cool store called Argos there, which is literally just a small store with 3 stations: 1) look through a HUGE catalogue of all the items in their warehouse (imagine a Cosco with all of its items plus hundreds more in catalogued book form) and enter in the product numbers of the items you want, 2) pay for the items at the cashier desk, and 3) pick up your items from another counter.  The storage area is hidden somewhere behind/underneath the store front area, so all you see are the requested items popping out of a hatch/conveyer belt and voila!  You have your purchase =P  Bohan got some ping pong balls because Steph 2 have been mentioning that they wanted to play beer pong (or at least a version of it XD)….

For dinner, I had ICE CREAM!!!!  Vanilla with chocolate syrup this time, and still absolutely heaven =)  I don’t understand how Trinity makes its ice cream…UPDATE!  There’s ice cream TWICE for dinner next week! O___O  Hahhaa, after my most satisfying dinner, I went to Emma for another study party.  It really is so much nicer to work with other people at the same time….**misses MIT a lot**

10/29 ~

FRIDAY!!!  Again, I wasn’t looking forward to another long day as I was still not feeling any better from my sickness (I now also had a stuffy nose to add to my incessant cough), but somehow I managed to plough through it (though not with quite the same level of attentiveness as Wed =P).

Nothing interesting happened until the evening, when I had a family dinner with my two College siblings.  We had Domino’s pizza as everyone still had a billion vouchers from Fresher’s Fair, and Matt had bought smoothie drinks from Sainsbury’s earlier, which were really really good!!!  After munching on pizza (I think I had five slices because they were really just so small…a medium here is NOT a medium…lol), we decided to play a game of Monopoly (it was British version too – aka the property spaces were all changed to British streets and railroad stations like Oxford Street, Trafalgar Square, Mayfair, King’s Cross Station =P)!  Oh boy, I had not played this game in so long, and accordingly, I got completely owned x__X  I really don’t understand how my luck could be so bad – I definitely was unable to collect my 200 pounds most of the times I passed GO because 1) I landed on the Income Tax space which is a flat 200 pound fee in this version, 2) I landed on one of the first two property spaces that Matt had built hotels on really early in the game (making them 250 and 450 pounds respectively for rent…x__X),  or 3) I landed on the chance space around the GO space and ended up going to jail instead of “passing” GO.  EPIC FAIL.  Matt and JJ ended up feeling so sorry for me that they would tell me to pay less for rent when I landed on one of their property spaces, though not like that helped me much XD  The game got really interesting when I finally relented and traded properties with both of them so that everyone could get a monopoly.  By this time, Matt had enough money to GIVE me 2000 pounds, AND still have enough to build a hotel directly on each of the three yellow properties, making them OVER 1000 pounds for rent EACH!  *dies*  Still, even though I had the worst luck ever, it was really fun to play the game again, and hang out with my two siblings =D

Before going to bed, I practiced the song that we were going to practice at Chinese Orchestra (CUCOS) rehearsal tomorrow for over an hour – it felt really good to play the erhu again after so long (CUCOS lent me a spare erhu) and I just really like this song XD

10/30 ~

As I mentioned earlier, my makeup supervision got scheduled for this morning at 11am, so I ended up waking up at around 9 to study a bit for it and somehow forgot to eat breakfast in the process, so I was pretty hungry by the time I arrived at the Pharm department.  Turns out though, my supervisor had cookies and pineapple slices prepared for us as an apology for rescheduling us, so I had fruit for the first time in like, FOREVER!  It’s expensive to eat fruit here…XD

Anyway, after supervision and lunch, it was time for our VIII outing!!!  FINALLY!  I was so pumped up as I biked over to the boathouse – only to find 2 other rowers there when I showed up x___X  Man was I frustrated…how can people not show up when this was going to be the first VIII outing we’ve had???  Luckily for me, two other rowers showed up (though like 15 min late -___-), and we had 3 senior rowers who kindly agreed to row with us so we could still go out on the river today =)  It was AMAZING!!!  The VIII is so smooth compared to the Coastal IVs and even though we were rowing 4 at a time (and maybe 6 at a time at one point) instead of the full 8 (thankfully everyone else was stabilizing/sitting the boat), we were still zooming through the water =P  I was stroke again (they really need to give me a chance to row somewhere else otherwise I’m going to get used to setting my own rhythm…lol) which was really cool today because I could totally feel the difference from when the middle four were rowing to when the bow four were rowing (bow four had two experienced rowers) =)  And, lucky me again….the weather was really nice!!!  I’ve had really good luck with nice weather for the most part – it’s normally really warm out when I’m on the river ^___^  I also saw Steph in her boat as they were docking at Selwyn’s boathouse! =)  Hope we’ll get a lot more VIII outings next week – totally beats the IVs and obviously the tubs =P

After rowing, I biked back to Trinity, picked up my erhu, and headed over to Clare College where the rehearsal was at.  Hahaha omg, Chinese overload for the week – the conductor (who is very good at conducting) spoke Mandarin the entire time; luckily for us, he is from Taiwan so he speaks normally (in our opinion, normal is without the typical mainland Chinese “accent”…don’t know what it’s called in English XD).  Anyway, overall, the practice was really fun, and it was great to hear the entire orchestra plus percussion instruments piece together the song to match the recording, but it was also pretty tiring as the rehearsal is 4 hours long (I skipped the first hour because of rowing, but 3 hour rehearsal is still super long x__X).  Also, the spare erhu isn’t very good – I miss my erhu back home XD  And although Stephie and I both really enjoy playing with the orchestra, we might end up not actually continuing as it literally is a huge time sink in the middle of every Saturday…we’ll see XP

At night, we ate dinner at Emma, and then played beer pong without the beer =P  In other words, Bohan rearranged his room a bit so we had a long shelf sitting on top of his dresser to act as a long table, and a 6 cup triangle on both ends (because 10 cups wouldn’t fit =P).  And, we just took turns tossing ping pong balls into the cups for “practice”.  Lols, Steph 2 and Bohan ended up challenging each other to a couple of matches, which got pretty intense =P  After, they all went to the Queens’ Halloween party, and I went home to get some work done, despite Stephie trying to convince me to go with them by saying it would be the only Halloween party at Cambridge opportunity I would ever get XD  (Good thing I didn’t end up going because Stephie later said that it wasn’t that good =P)  I did drop by Sainsbury’s first to get some juice and got quite a scare when I saw two girls in Victorian dresses with some bloodlike substance all over their faces and necks x___X  Some people have such interesting Halloween costume ideas…  Later in the night, I had a surprise visit from Stephen who got me Trailer of Life fries (yuuuummmy!!!!!) as he was walking back to Churchill (waaay North) from a basketball game at the gym (waaaay South) and passed by town =D  And so I went to sleep with my tummy happily full ^___^

10/31 ~

Ugh today was kind of fail.  Woke up early to go to a First Aid Society (CUFAS) training session at 9am, only it turned out that it was one that Stephie and I had already attended a couple of weeks ago…so after sitting through an hour of repeated material, we finally had a break during which I explained the mix-up to the trainer who very nicely told us we could just come back at 12pm then for the 2 nd half of the training (so we just went to Queens’ since it was closer and studied).  X___X  We totally could’ve slept in today…On the flip side, the 2 nd training session ended really early – before 2:30pm when it was originally planned to end at 4:00pm, so Stephie and I decided to go to the Chinese take-out place all the way south on Lensfield Road because we really liked the Pineapple Pork fried rice I got on Friday XD

Fail #2…it was closed x__X  And it’s a pretty long walk to get there&gt;___&lt;So instead, we went to the restaurant next door, quickly bought something to eat, and then made a spur of the moment decision to crash Bohan’s room at Emma to eat since it was conveniently on the way home for both of us and we were really hungry by this time =P

After our late lunch, I went home and got a lot of studying done (all caught up with lectures now =D), and then, it was time for our Caius Formal!!!  Hahaha, why Caius?  Basically, we randomly met up with a Ollie, a CME ’10 who did TKD at MIT last year and is a 4 th year medical student now =D, at an earlier CUFAS meeting where he told us he’d invite us to a formal sometime, which turned out to be tonight =D  Caius was nice because you could just wear casual clothes and then put your gown over it XP  Now I’ve been to three formals – Churchill, Trinity, and Caius!  Hoping to get it up to over 10 by the end of the year…XD  Once dinner was over, we chilled for a bit at the bar and just had fun talking about the differences between MIT and Cambridge ^__^  There was also a 2 nd year medic at Caius who started talking to Ollie about how to apply to MIT and coincidently since we were there as well, we got bombarded with questions about the whole CME program XP
 
Caius Formal with Ollie! =D
 
Yup that’s about it!  Wow, I knew this was going to take a long time and probably not get to go to sleep early today because of it….should try harder to blog more regularly next week XD
 
 Posted by whimsicaltimes  |  November 1, 2010 | Categories: Uncategorized | 1 Comment» 
 
 Rowing (again) + Emma study party =D 
 
Oct 24 ~

OMG I’m so sore today XD  Especially my back but also a little in my arms too =P  But today was actually a warm day to go rowing AND the river was calm as well!!!  Brilliant ^__^  Haha, I was stroke again today because I was the most experienced out of our group of 4 rowers, which is awesome because I get to set the pace again =P  It’s kind of funny – I’ve already been out on a coastal IV 4-5 times after tubbing 3 times, whereas one of the girls had only tubbed once before and this was her first coastal IV outing XD  I’m definitely spending too much time at the boathouse but rowing is literally sooo much fun!!!  (Steph, Stephie and I had a long conversation last night about how much we all love rowing =P)  Today’s outing was shorter though because apparently there was a fishing competition going on in a section of the river that we normally row past, so we couldn’t go as far…although granted I’m not sure we would’ve made it that far anyways today XD  Hence, while I was sore from rowing yesterday and the previous Wednesday, today was not very intense =P  After my rowing session, I was supposed to cox for the next novice outing, but only two of the girls showed up!!!!  Omg, I waited over an hour (because we ended our rowing session early and one of the two girls came late) for nothing, which was frustrating…They ended up just going out in a tub with the coach as the cox, so I just walked home fuming XP  Hahaha, I think I’m just going to give up trying out coxing and stick with rowing, which I think I would enjoy a lot more anyways =P

That took up the good part of my afternoon, and all too soon, it was dinner time – which I had with Stephie and Steph today because I tempted them with Trinity pineapple and coconut ice cream!!!  I’m now at 4 for 4 for eating in Hall when there’s ice cream – tiramisu, pralines, butterscotch, and pineapple coconut ^___^  I’ve already scouted out the menus for next week too – I think we’re having vanilla ice cream with chocolate syrup on Thursday night….HAHAHAH XD

And now, back at Emma for a study party again with unlimited access to wifi (the more important part =P – it’s so nice to be able to open your laptop and automatically connect to the wireless internet here…we are SO SPOILED at MIT XD).  We just finished a Domino’s ham and pineapple pizza too, using one of the millions of coupons we got from Fresher’s Fair way back when =P

And so the weekend ends and a new week begins…

On a completely different note – MIT won the first ECTC tournament of the year yesterday!!!  WOOT!  Apparently it was a major win too – over Brown (2 nd ) and Cornell (3 rd – gasp! =P).  Hahaha makes me nostalgic…although my first MIT tournament ended pretty badly (huge swollen right hand and injured right foot from naively agreeing to spar a heavyweight x__X).  Still, I wish I had been there to compete and cheer on the rest of the team XD
 
 Posted by whimsicaltimes  |  October 24, 2010 | Categories: Uncategorized | 3 Comments» 
 «Older Entries 
Recent Posts

 End of Michaelmas ~ Clare Novice Regatta Mid-November Fun =) London in 12 hours =D Tea + Rowing 
 
Archives

 December 2010  (1) November 2010  (8) October 2010  (27) August 2010  (10) July 2010  (11) 
 
 
 
 July 2012 M T W T F S S «Dec       1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31   
 
 Blog at WordPress.com . | Theme: Modularity Lite by Graph Paper Press .
 Follow 
 Follow“Whimsical Times” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
