<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000831" url="http://www.reviewstream.com/reviews/?p=45431" time="2012-07-12-16:12" support="3" score="0.00456285216147957" bingtitle="KFC Cunupia Trinidad review - REVIEW STREAM: write review - get paid" webtitle="KFC Cunupia Trinidad review">
			<query id="000978" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="000226" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000973" bing-rank="185"/>
	<description>I opted to wait but the rest of my order was served ... one food on the menu makes KFC my favorite fast food restaurant ... food is destroying the quality I&apos;ve come to expect ...</description>
	<body>
		Reviews » Restaurants » KFC Cunupia Trinidad 
 
KFC Cunupia Trinidad
 Monroe Road, Cunupia, Trinidad 

 



 by RJR 
 TRUSTWORTHY 
 No matter where you go you usually get hungry if you aren’t returning home early. Today I went out to run some errands and ran a little late. I decided I’d buy something to eat because I was already getting hungry. I decided on Kentucky Fried Chicken and decided I would buy a box at the Montrose Junction Kentucky Fried Chicken outlet. But I was quite a distance away and then it hit me. I had never bought Kentucky Fried Chicken at the Monroe Road outlet located closer to where I was in Cunupia.

The Kentucky Fried Chicken outlet in Monroe Road looks pretty small on the outside but I was very surprised when I entered. It was spacious, had lots of seating available and the overall design (some of which can be seen from the outside) of the inside of this Kentucky Fried Chicken was welcoming and very neatly done.

There wasn’t too large a crowd or long a queue although it was during the lunch hour period. The service is pretty fast there and the staff is very friendly and willing to serve you, unlike some other Kentucky Fried Chicken outlet cashiers I have encountered before.

The pace (how quickly I was served) is generally good. They were out of buttermilk biscuits so I was told I may need to wait a couple of minutes if I wanted them. I opted to wait but the rest of my order was served up in the meantime at a nice fast pace.

As soon as the buttermilk biscuits were done they were handed to me promptly with no delay. They also served up some good pieces of fried chicken which had no yellow fat under the skin which really is a bit of a turn off when I am eating fried chicken.

I found the french fries to be very small and that also made it seem like it had less in the package as well. The french fries were crunchy and soft yet enjoyable though. The buttermilk biscuits were definitely smaller than usual but the mashed potatoes were delicious.

Overall, the Kentucky Fried Chicken outlet located at Monroe Road in Cunupia turned out to be better than I thought. I will definitely give it points for the clean, spacious and overall welcoming surrounding as well as the good staff they hired but I will take away a couple of point for the biscuits and fries.

Everything tasted delicious though and I would definitely buy at this Kentucky Fried Chicken outlet again if I am in the area.

Rating: 8
 
 
 
 
 
 

 
 Share your thoughts. Ask. Reply. Your opinion is valuable. 
 


 
 
 
 
 
 
 Related reviews : 

 
 +1 
 KFC Gulf City Mall South Trinidad 
 I haven&apos;t been to Gulf City for a while but I had this weird craving for Kentucky Fried Chicken when lunch time came around and I was already hungry before I got there! I told my boyfriend that we should go have lunch first and I&apos;m in the mood ...

 
     
 Kentucky Fried Chicken, Maastricht, The Netherlands 
 I did not see any other Kentucky Fried Chicken in this town. The town is quite big if I compared with other cities around it. But there is only one Kentucky Fried Chicken in this city. 

And this Kentucky Fried Chicken is located exactly in the city center of ...

 
 +1 
 KFC Manchester TN 
 Kentucky fried chicken is a chain fast food restaurant that specializes in chicken foods. They offer various buckets of chicken done different ways, chicken sandwiches, chicken salads, and various other chicken foods. We go to Kentucky Fried Chicken when we need to get food fast and lots of ...

 
     
 Kentucky Fried Chicken, Lenoke, AR 
 I walked into the Kentucky Fried Chicken in Lonoke, AR, and the first thing I noticed how utterly filthy and dirty it was. It as so slick on the floor that I felt like I was going to fall over. It was disgusting in there, the service ...

 
     
 KFC Gravy 
 I go to a fastfood on a daily basis for a few months now. Because I am employed in a call center. And as a customer I am fond of ordering fried chicken. What I always take note of is the taste of gravy sauce. I have ...

 
 +1 
 Kentucky Fried Chicken 2-Piece Drumstick&amp;Thigh with Drink Special 
 Kentucky Fried Chicken, like most fast food establishments these days, are always offering new combinations and specials to try and lure consumers to their place. One of the current lures is the KFC 2-Piece Drumstick&amp;Thigh Special.

Here is what you get for a Kentucky Fried Chicken 2-Piece ...

 
     
 KFC Wendesbury 
 Kentucky Fried Chicken in Wendesbury is where we go for a bite to eat after we have been round Ikea just of Junction nine of the M Five motorway. This particular Kentucky is always a good place to go.

The building itself is large and has both and upstairs ...

 
     
 KFC Trincity Mall Trinidad 
 I have had Fried Chicken at this Kentucky Fried Chicken Outlet a couple times before but never took into account about their actual customer service, speed of service etc. till this weekend just gone by.

My boyfriend and I was going to the movies and we already got a late ...

 
 +1 
 Kentucy Fried Chicken Beaver Dam WI 
 The Kentucky Fried Chicken in Beaver Dam isn&apos;t very large and isn&apos;t even in the best location (next to a half-abandoned mall) but, when I&apos;m looking for a quick meal, it&apos;s definitely on top of my list.
Unlike the other &quot;fast&quot; food places around town, I usually have my food ...

 
     
 KFC Trincity Trinidad 
 Now I know I have reviewed a Kentucky Fried Chicken branch located in Trincity Mall before. But there are two in this mall. Each conveniently situated on whatever floor you happen to be on. In my last review I talked about the Kentucky Fried Chicken outlet on Level 1 ...

 
     
 KFC Food: Popcorn Chicken 
 I&apos;ve always been a fan of Kentucky Fried Chicken (KFC) but one food on the menu makes KFC my favorite fast food restaurant there is and that food is popcorn chicken, it is my favorite KFC food on the menu. I like it because it is boneless (unlike Chicken ...

 
     
 KFC Beaver Dam WI 
 More and more, I&apos;m beginning to think this movement toward providing healthier food is destroying the quality I&apos;ve come to expect from my favorite fast food restaurants.



Kentucky Fried Chicken here in Beaver Dam is a perfect example of this. Because they are more expensive than many of the other ...

 
 +1 
 Tokyo Kentucky Fried Chicken 
 For a western tourist, it is allways interesting to be at Tokyo, Japan, taking the &quot;light&quot; japanese food. But sometimes, We miss our country&apos;s food.
In this situation, after a week in Tokyo, I wondered about to eat something less &quot;light&quot; than the japanese food.
I would like to eat something ...

 
 +1 
 Royal Castle Fried Chicken 
 I like to try foods from different places and one of our local fast food chains is a restaurant named Royal Castle. Now admittedly I haven&apos;t eaten Royal Castle in the longest time. Royal Castle is essentially a local version of the worldwide popular Kentucky Fried Chicken outlets.

Well, one ...

 
     
 Kentucky Fried Chicken“Boneless Wings”(tv ad) 
 ...

 
 
 
 
 The review was published as it&apos;s written by reviewer in August, 2008. The reviewer certified that no compensation of any kind was received from the reviewed item producer, trademark owner or any other institution, related with the reviewed item. 
 The site is not responsible for the mistakes made. 72708454310331/k2311a0827/8.27.08
	</body>
</document>
