<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000864" url="http://www.canadianbusiness.com/article/77838--atm-provider-directcash-to-purchase-australian-at-company-customers-limited" time="2012-07-12-16:13" support="1" score="0.0005998323877168552" bingtitle="ATM provider DirectCash to purchase Australian AT&lt; company ..." webtitle="ATM provider DirectCash to purchase Australian AT&lt;company Customers Limited | CanadianBusiness.com">
			<query id="000806" bing-rank="177"/>
	<description>Portage Place shopping centre added to Ontario properties ... Singapore &apos;very concerned&apos; about inflation rate near 5 per ... Recent Articles Tim Hortons&apos; new coffee cup: why the ...</description>
	<body>
		Canadian Business Network
 
 News&amp;Analysis Small Business Personal Finance Politics International 
 
 Connect Login Register 
 Subscribe:  Magazine Newsletters Read Magazine 
 My Portfolio / Discussions / Multimedia 
 
 Home News&amp;Markets News&amp;Markets 
 Recent Articles Former German state gov, Morgan Stanley executive investigated in power company sale Clinton to meet with Myanmar&apos;s president as US eases sanctions Struggling carmaker Peugeot-Citroen slashing 8,000 jobs in France, closing iconic plant China&apos;s slowdown spreads pain despite stimulus as companies struggle with plunging sales South Korea&apos;s central bank unexpectedly lowers key interest rate to fend off external risks ADB cuts growth forecast for developing Asia amid eurozone crisis, sluggish US recovery 

 Topics Daily News Headlines Stocks, Bonds, Commodities Joe Castaldo&apos;s Blog 

 Industries Energy Financial Consumer Goods 
 More from News&amp;Markets Blogs&amp;Analysis Blogs&amp;Analysis 
 Recent Articles Game consoles are regressing technologically Ken Block takes on San Francisco in Gymkhana Five How can boards tie ethical conduct to executive compensation? Social networking&apos;s hidden ethical value Robot legs give paraplegics new hope 

 Our Authors Larry MacDonald Chris MacDonald Jacqueline Nelson Jeff Beer Peter Nowak Richard Branson James Cowan Samson Okalow ALL AUTHORS 
 More from Blogs&amp;Analysis Strategy Strategy 
 Recent Articles Molson Coors fights for share of shrinking beer market Premium-casual restaurant chains Earls, Cactus Club expand beyond west How to retire debt-free: 5 things you should do now Japan&apos;s Skytree now tallest tower in the world SNC Lavalin’s missing millions mess: is Ben Aïssa responsible? Skipping vacation time is a potential disaster 

 Topics Corporate Social Responsibility Blogs Daily News Headlines Sales and Marketing Blog 
 More from Strategy Technology Technology 
 Recent Articles RIM attempts turnaround PC sales fall by 6 pct to 11 pct in US during 2Q PC sales fall by 6 pct to 11 pct in US during 2Q Groupon&apos;s stock hits lowest level since IPO Group spends $6 a name to get charters on ballot 

 Topics Technology Blog RIM Energy Industry Samson Okalow&apos;s Blog Jeff Beer&apos;s Blog 
 More from Technology Investing Investing 
 Recent Articles Michael O&apos;Higgins&apos;s &apos;Absolute Return&apos; strategy tries to beat the market SNC Lavalin’s missing millions mess: is Ben Aïssa responsible? Real estate as an inflation hedge Adobe changes business model to cloud-based subscription CEO Poll: Should stock options be abolished? India&apos;s slowing growth not a worry in the long run 

 Topics Investing Blog Financial Daily News Headlines Real Estate Larry MacDonald&apos;s Blog Thomas Watsons&apos; Blog 
 More from Investing Lifestyle Lifestyle 
 Recent Articles How much do you need to retire well? Premium-casual restaurant chains Earls, Cactus Club expand beyond west How to retire debt-free: 5 things you should do now Travel: Tree-house hotels that span the globe Skipping vacation time is a potential disaster The Unfair Trade 

 Topics Election 2011 Daily News Headlines Performance blog Consumer Insight Blog Sales and Marketing Blog EIC Steve Maich&apos;s Blog 
 More from Lifestyle Lists&amp;Rankings Lists&amp;Rankings 
 Lists&amp;Rankings Investor 500 Rich 100 Portraits In Leadership Puck Money Canada&apos;s Richest Neighbourhoods MBA Guide 2012 TSX Venture 50 Outlook 2012 Best Jobs 2012 
 More from Lists&amp;Rankings 
 Hot Topics: 
 Canadian Business now on iPad RRSP Rich 100 Survival Guide Canadian Success Stories Stock Quotes More Topics 
 Print Text: A A Topics  News&amp;Markets 
ATM provider DirectCash to purchase Australian AT&lt;company Customers Limited
 By The Canadian Press | April 02, 2012 Chat Email 
 
CALGARY - ATM provider DirectCash Payments Inc. (TSX:DCI) has struck a deal to acquire a similar Australian company called Customers Limited for about $179 million.

Calgary-based DirectCash Payments will $1.27 per share for the company in cash and the deal is expected to close in the third quarter.

DirectCash has about 7,900 ATM’s in Canada and some other countries, but that number will grow to about 14,200 once the deal is completed.

The transaction, which has been approved by the DirectCash board, will add about $129 million in revenue to the company’s balance sheet.

DirectCash says the deal will make it one of the top ATM providers in the world with operations in Canada, Australia, New Zealand, Mexico, the U.K. and the United States.

&quot;We are very excited about this acquisition as it gives us a significant ATM market presence in Australia,” said DirectCash president and CEO Jeffrey Smith.

”We are excited to have the opportunity to add the Customers business to our operations, and continue to build our presence internationally.”
 Print Text: A A Topics  News&amp;Markets Comments Comment Anonymously Login to Comment 
 User name: User email: Your email will not be displayed Title: Comment Share to Facebook 
 
 Cancel Sort Newest Oldest Agreed Loading comments - please wait... 1 of 1 Back Next Subscribe 
 
 Newsletter Twitter Facebook Podcast Mobile RSS 
 
 Newsletter Twitter Facebook Podcast Mobile RSS
	</body>
</document>
