<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000823" url="http://www.junkdrawerblog.com/2008/06/my-big-fat-head.html" time="2012-07-12-16:11" support="2" score="0.004149281239436074" bingtitle="The Junk Drawer » My Big Fat Head" webtitle="The Junk DrawerMy Big Fat Head">
			<query id="001226" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="001038" bing-rank="143"/>
	<description>She wrote about her experience working in a fast-food restaurant ... She went over to men’s uniform boxes and pulled ... Surprised she didn’t throw a tablecloth over it.</description>
	<body>
		The Junk Drawer 
 Fresh and delicious stories about anything that amuses me, confuses me, or makes me blow a gasket. Take a look around the drawer. Just leave everything where you found it. 
 Home About Greatest Hits Advertise Contact Windy the Plastic Bag 
 
 My Big Fat Head 
 contests , embarrassing June 26th, 2008 
 Back in November, I laughed through a post by one of my favorite bloggers, Cardiogirl . She wrote about her experience working in a fast-food restaurant as a teenager and how she had to wear a hat as part of her uniform. 

 Only one problem. She says,“I hate wearing hats. I do not have a hat face. I do not have a hat head. I don’t look good in hats and I will gladly let my ears succumb to frostbite in the midst of winter.” 

 I dropped her a comment that I didn’t have a hat head either, which made wearing a ridiculous cowboy hat as part of my restaurant uniform all the more humiliating. 

 I told her about my goofy hat and vowed to search high and low for the one picture in existence showing me in the uniform, complete with hat, in all its splendor. 

 Cardiogirl, this one’s for you! 

 

 Big Fat Head, Circa 1982 

 Here’s the thing about the hat and my big, fat head . This hat was issued to me on the day of my orientation. The manager pulled out a few hats for me to try on and none of them fit. None of the women’s hats fit. God bless her, she was so nice to me. 

 Kathy, it doesn’t seem that any of these fit. Let’s try some others. 

 She went over to men’s uniform boxes and pulled out a gigundo hat that would fit only me and Charlie Brown. 

 Here, try this one. 

 Practically sobbing, I tried on the hat and it fit. Sorta. I knew in my heart I could probably have worn an even larger one, but I decided to make do with the one I was given. There was no way I was going to try on anything larger or I’d have to quit the job I hadn’t even started yet. 

 But here’s the confusing thing. You know damn well that when I sat down to write this, I had to measure my head to know once and for all how fat it is. 

 It’s not! 

 According to several sources, the average circumference of a woman’s head is 22.5 inches. Mine is slightly over average, at 23 inches . I have to say I was really surprised. Only two things could explain why I had to wear a men’s hat as a teen. One, my head was larger in 1982 and shrank since then, or two, my head is so seriously misshapen that it just won’t wear a hat very well. I’m going with #2. 

 Now here’s a little contest for you : If anyone—family members excluded—can name the restaurant I worked at based on the above picture, I’ll send you a Junk Drawer magnet . It might be tough because I believe the restaurant went out of business sometime in the mid-90s and may have been located only on the East Coast, United States. 

 Let’s make it two contests! Women only. Go measure your head and whoever has the fattest head gets a prize, too. Of course, you may not want to admit your achievement, but if nothing else, you’ll have my sympathies. No lying just to get a magnet. I have it on good authority they’re becoming collector’s items. 
 Stumble it! 
68 Responses to“My Big Fat Head”

 Jaffer Says:
 June 26th, 2008 at 6:59 pm 
Wow ! Is that really you in the picture ? You look so different (to me anyways) compared to the previous ones you shared

 
 Tim Says:
 June 26th, 2008 at 8:04 pm 
It doesn’t look like you had any wicked 80′s hair going on in the picture. I know a lot of eighties dos would require a much larger hat to account for the massive amount of curls / fan.
 Babs - beetle Says:
 June 26th, 2008 at 8:18 pm 
The hat does look a tad small :O) I can’t find my tape measure, so here I am at 2am with a metal retractable rule wrapped round my head. What kind of fool am I? I think it was 22.5 but I will do it again when I find a proper tape measure.

 Babs–beetle’s last blog post.. Just a dream? 
 DrowseyMonkey Says:
 June 26th, 2008 at 8:22 pm 
Did you miss my giant freak head post? LOL My head is 23.5 inches, and birds fly into it. And no…no hat fits me so I get it, LOL.

 http://drowseymonkey.blogspot.com/2008/05/my-giant-freak-head.html 

 DrowseyMonkey’s last blog post.. Ooohh…Sparkly, Kind of 
 The Mom Says:
 June 26th, 2008 at 9:02 pm 
Bob’s Big Boy?

My big fat head is 22.25 inches. *blush*

 The Mom’s last blog post.. A Thousand Words Thursday 
 FerdC Says:
 June 26th, 2008 at 9:27 pm 
At first I was going to say your big fat head is okay, because you must have more brains than anyone else!

But then you said your head is actually normal sized, just misshapen. Saying you must have misshapen brains is not very nice, though, so I won’t say it.

Kathy, I think the picture is adorable! (That’s not a guy word. Don’t tell anyone, okay?) And I think it is SO COOL, and brave, to show flashbacks from your past. No way in hell I’d show you mine.

I’m guessing the Ponderosa restaurant.

 FerdC’s last blog post.. Linky Love 
 Shadowsrider Says:
 June 26th, 2008 at 9:50 pm 
Ponderosa is my guess too, but there was also a Bonanza restaurant when I was a kid. Both had the western theme uniforms. I’m with you on the odd shape head. Mine is very oval, I can never get hats to stay on, even supersized ones.

 Shadowsrider’s last blog post.. Comfort Food 
 Ulquiorra Says:
 June 26th, 2008 at 10:18 pm 
Hats are always way to warm around the ears for me to bear when it’s not snowing.

And why is the second contest only for women? They’re more likely to lie…although those are the kind of lies that would take them farther from winning…

 Ulquiorra’s last blog post.. What Modern People do For Entertainment 
 Mama O Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 1:06 am 
Oh fun! I thought for sure I’d win the fat head prize, and I love winning. However, it is not to be. 21.5 How about a magnet if you’re a pin head?
 cardiogirl Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 4:09 am 
You are one dedicated blogger, Kathy! I remember being so jacked about seeing that picture, and then…well, I forgot about it (cringes). But this is totally awesome! LOVE that picture.

And I had to whip out my tape measure. Initially I got 23.5 inches and I thought NOOOOO!!! I actually took my ponytail out and remeasured (pulling that mofo as tight as I possibly could) and I ended up with 23.

I guess our noggins are extra large to stash the extra brains, right?

 cardiogirl’s last blog post.. The book of questions, Volume 1 
 Kathy Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 4:46 am 
Jaffer—Hmmm, is that good or bad? I think the oldest age I’ve been in any other picture I’ve posted was 12. So stuff happened between pre-teen and 17. You know, stuff .

Tim—Oh, there was wicked hair going on. It’s just smashed under the hat. I’ll have to dig out some big hair photos for you, in the years I straightened my curly hair. It’s not a good move and the pictures will prove that.

Babs—Further proof we are soul sisters. I did the same thing! It kind of hurt. Glad I later found a soft tape in my sewing kit. That won’t send you to the ER.

DrowseyMonkey— I’m a walking candy apple! Just read your story and I’m sorry, but that’s gold! I haven’t had a bird fly into my giant head yet, but I should be so lucky to be in your good company if it does!

The Mom—Nope. Not Bob’s Big Boy. Congrats on the slightly under average noggin.

FerdC—That’s OK. If I’m going to post about my big fat head, I’m just asking for it. The reason I have no problem posting these pictures is because they can’t possibly hurt me now. In fact, it’s kind of like therapy. Facing your past“head”-on is good for the soul. Nope, not Ponderosa.

Shadowsrider—Nope, both wrong. I wish I could wear a baseball cap sometimes. Put a ponytail through the hole in the back. Nothin’doin’. My hair is too thick and I’d have to smash it on and then I’d have big head, flat head. Not an attractive look.

Ulquiorra—I’m assuming most men would have larger heads than women. Am I wrong? Go ahead and measure! Post back with your size.

Mama O—Hmmm, maybe I should have added“smallest head wins a prize.”But then non-freak-head people get everything in life already, right?

cardiogirl—Thank you for inspiring this post! I had to pull the tape tight, too. My hair is so thick, surely it adds an inch! Yes, I like to believe our extra inch allows for more brain. Whether I’m making good use of it is another matter.
 Babs - beetle Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 6:01 am 
Well, my nice weight watchers (not that I have ever been to weight watchers) tape measure has vanished. I had to resort to a paper one out of an emergency kit. My head is officially 22″but still, hats look awful on me. The last time I had a hat face was when I was a teenager ;O)

 Babs–beetle’s last blog post.. Just a dream? 
 Lee Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 6:28 am 
I bet you work at Roy Roger’s Restaurant! Or else the uniforms were very similar.

Seeing that picture brings to mind a song that’s being played on country stations right now:
 HOTTIE ! She’s a Hottie !!! Got a smokin’little body !
String bikini and a barbed-wire tat
 She’s a rockin’that cowboy hat! 
HOTTIE ! She’s a Hottie !!! and just a little bit naughty !
Ki yi diggy diggy, Ki yi diggy diggy, yey HEY hey HEY 
 BabaBooey Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 7:01 am 
My question is, who of you and your siblings, who was the one who had to change the channel on the TV?
 BigNerd Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 7:06 am 
1) Va-Va-Va-VOOM!
2) Restaurant: The Red Barn
3) Favorite Line:“…pulled out a gigundo hat that would fit only me and Charlie Brown.”
4) No one has a bigger head than Ted Kennedy.
5) Is that a /console/ T.V.? The kind you had to get up to change the channel? UHF Rawkz.
6) Bonus #6: Can I buy a Top Spot? Hehehe.

 BigNerd’s last blog post.. WordPress: Strong May Numbers 
 Jules Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 7:06 am 
22.15! I thought I would be bigger too.
My guess is“The magic time machine”?

 Jules’s last blog post.. Dogs swimming video 
 Bucky Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 7:10 am 
I wouldn’t have a clue about the restaurant. But I do know that that is one big head small hat!

 Bucky’s last blog post.. Death And Taxes 
 Bucky Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 7:11 am 
(big head was supposed to have a strike through it. I guess that doesn’t work in your comments…)

I lose.

 Bucky’s last blog post.. Death And Taxes 
 Kathy Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 7:13 am 
 WE HAVE A WINNER! Lee got the restaurant right. It was Roy Rogers. To make my experience there that much more miserable, when you manned the drive-thru, this is how you had to address the customers:

At the menu board:“Howdy, pardner! May I take your order please?”
When they finished placing their order:“Pull around to the window and round‘er up!”

I’m dead serious.
 JD at I Do Things Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 7:14 am 
May I suggest a third reason why the hats didn’t fit? The restaurant took sadistic pleasure in stocking only children’s hats and making their employees feel so bad about themselves that they were cowed into working for meager wages and wouldn’t dare complain about anything. That’s my guess. That there looks like a toy hat, and your head does NOT look big (your chest, however . . . that’s definitely not a man’s shirt!)

Ahem! Anyway, I was surprised to find that my head is only 22 inches. I thought it was pretty big, considering my moon face. I think Drowsey Monkey’s in the lead?

 JD at I Do Things’s last blog post.. I Lived with a Rat so you don’t have to 
 Babs - beetle Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 7:21 am 
Well Drowsey Monkey has birds dive bomb her head. She deserves to be the winner!

 Babs–beetle’s last blog post.. Stones in my life. 
 Ulquiorra Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 8:26 am 
Haha…All men aren’t bigheads, as you might think.

I measure in at 22.5 in. Wait…that’s the average circumference of a woman’s head?

 Ulquiorra’s last blog post.. QDOS–A Soundframe For Better Sound 
 damon Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 9:01 am 
Sounde like an acute case of Mr. Potato Head syndrome.
None of his hats fit him either.;)

 damon’s last blog post.. Ugly Is Only Skin Deep 
 Jeff Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 9:32 am 
You didn’t have a big head, you had a little body. You also had one butt ugly couch.

 Jeff’s last blog post.. Summer’s Here 
 Regan Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 9:33 am 
Maryland friend chicken? I know my mom worked there….

Maybe some country resturant? KFC?
 Maureen Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 9:41 am 
60! (cm) or 23 and 3/8ths inches for you Americans.. I measured around the forehead, where a hat usually sits…so I think that’s how to measure.

Yea, I AM appalled. Thanks for pointing out more of my deformities, K. Now I know why I always had to wear men’s hats too…especially when I had my‘fro in the 70′s….

 Maureen’s last blog post.. Letting My Imagination Run Away 
 Lisa Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 9:43 am 
Roy Rogers?

Anyhow…maybe it wasn’t your head that was big, but your hair?

My mom always says her head is huge, but really it is her hair. She says she doesn’t have a hat head either, but I swear…her hair is poofy. That has to be it.
 Canucklehead Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 9:59 am 
All I can assure you, without the benefit of a tape measure is that my giant melow would make yours look like a pea by comparion. I like hats, although I don’t wear them very often–let’s just say that I’m glad baseball hats come with those adjustable things on the back. (The last and final one has been a friend to me on more then one occasion.
 The Success Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 10:01 am 
You have nice blog
Cool and simple
Success For You

The Success

 The Success’s last blog post.. Success with Blowfish Shoes 
 Daisy the Curly Cat Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 10:03 am 
I think my Mommie has a pinhead because hers measures 21.5″Or maybe she measured wrong; are you supposed to measure around the pointy end?

 Daisy the Curly Cat’s last blog post.. Fashion Friday: I am the cat’s meow… 
 Ulquiorra Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 10:19 am 
I dunno, I did it around my forehead and the back of it.

 Ulquiorra’s last blog post.. QDOS–A Soundframe For Better Sound 
 Zip n Tizzy Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 10:23 am 
Oooh, got here too late to guess, but I’m patting myself on the back for guessing Roy Roger’s. It’s kind of like playing jeopardy at home…no chance to win, but still a thrill to play along!

Wanted to post anyway to say“Great Picture!”

 Zip n Tizzy’s last blog post.. I’ll cry if I want to! 
 sue Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 10:40 am 
Darn I’m too late for the contest. I was going to guess“The Big Fat-Head Restaurant”.

 sue’s last blog post.. Bathtub Gangsta Wardrobe Malfunction 
 Jolene Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 11:23 am 
LOL, I don’t look good in hats either. I don’t have a big head or anything, they just simply don’t suit me. I wish I could wear them, I’ll try one on every once in a while and the hubby just laughs at me, so back on the shelf it goes. I want so badly to wear a cowboy hat, we live in a“western”city, but nope, so far I have looked ridiculous in every one I’ve tried.

The second job I ever had was at a place called Bullwinkle’s, they don’t exist anymore(not here anyway), they were like Chuck E Cheese. Anyway, our uniform there was a Mountie suit(as in a look alike to the RCMP..Royal Canadian Mounted Police)…I’m sure you’ve seen our Mounties uniforms…black pants, red jacket and brown hat. So yes, I had to wear the brown Mountie hat and incredibly itchy Mountie jacket.

 Jolene’s last blog post.. I Finally Joined! 
 Bruce Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 11:31 am 
I count my lucky stars that I never had to work in a resturant as a teenager. The closest I ever came was Pizza Delivery Boy…..and we were rebels of the night.

 Bruce’s last blog post.. Essential Cinema–34 
 Jenn Thorson Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 1:31 pm 
My theory, Kathy, is that you do not in fact have a big head, but you had 80s hair. See 80s hair would account for the inability to wear a hat.

PS- I recall being unable to SEE due to the stupid loose cowboy hat I had had to wear in band. These hats were ginormous. We would go into parade rest and become visually impaired. So don’t feel bad. Too small hats are where it’s at. 

 Jenn Thorson’s last blog post.. What I learned from Bugs Bunny 
 Joe Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 1:50 pm 
I only can find one of those wooden yardsticks that fold in 3 sections. It doesn’t go all the way around, so apparently my head is more than 36 inches. 

 Joe’s last blog post.. Malevolent Monkeys of Miami 
 Poetikat Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 2:06 pm 
I was going to say“Ponderosa”. We had those in Southern Ontario and I’m thinking they were an American franchise.

Wow, it’s amazing how your uniform complements the decor! Did you choose the job for that reason? The shirt gives you a nice voluptuous look as well.

I worked for Mother’s Pizza for a couple of weeks, until I burned my arm on an oven door. I couldn’t get the smell of chopped onions out of my nostrils for days.

Kat

 Poetikat’s last blog post.. Movie Memories (from the cobwebs of my brain) 
 Shieldmaiden96 Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 3:16 pm 
I had a tour of a Roy Rogers as a class trip in third grade. Before we reflect on how sad that was, I have to admit I was TOTALLY STOKED. Because we got to GO BEHIND THE COUNTER AND EVERYTHING.

When I was little my mom worked at a restaurant on Rt 1 in Media called the Longhorn Ranch. Her uniform consisted of a hat, a western shirt with fringe, a miniskirt with fringe, and cowboy boots. And twin sidearm cap guns that she had to fire off when it was someone’s birthday. On reflection it was kind of stripper-y but at five I just found it awesome.

 Shieldmaiden96′s last blog post.. Whatever you do…don’t mention the war…. 
 ann of the shampoo bag Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 3:36 pm 
Kathy, did that tv even work? I think it was just a giant plant stand.
 Kathy Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 3:59 pm 
Babs—Well, at least you had hat face as a teen. I think it’s clear I didn’t. I love all this head-measuring going on!

Lee—I’ll email you for your postal address and send you a magnet. Congratulations on your winning entry! BTW, I call myself a hottie every day. And then I laugh my ass off.

BabaBooey—I don’t even think that TV worked for the few years prior. Isn’t that what everyone does with old TVs? Use them as tables and put plants on them?

BigNerd—OK, I have to confess. I originally typed Ted Kennedy instead of Charlie Brown, but felt bad because poor Ted is going through a trying time of it. So I had to think of the next biggest head I know. People keep buying Top Spots, but I want to take it down since I got my payment. Please don’t buy!

Jules—Awesome head measurement! I hated that uniform like you wouldn’t believe. Of course, I’d kill to fit in it now.

Bucky—Ha! It does look a little tiny on that fat head, doesn’t it?

JD at I Do Things—Funny! Yes, let’s say they were children’s hats, shall we? Aren’t you glad to know you have a smaller than average head? You’ll never have to wonder if it’ll fit through doors and stuff.

Babs—Yes, I think DrowseyMonkey gets a magnet even if the doesn’t officially have the fattest head. For that bird slam, she deserves to be showered with gifts.

Ulquiorra—OK, I tried Googling the average size of a man’s head and got some unsavory results. I’m not going back there again. Let’s just say you’re average, OK?

damon—Yeah, but his are super tiny! Just call me Mrs. Potato Head!

Jeff—What? You don’t like plaid couches? At least it wasn’t rainbow plaid.

Regan—I never understood how Maryland Fried Chicken stayed in business all these years or how they can say they sell“food.”Their mashed potatoes get pumped out of an ice cream machine for God’s sake. I don’t know how your mom could stand working there.

Maureen—Awesome! But sorry, it looks like you just missed Drowsey’s number. I loved your fro! I remember when you posted that pic. Priceless.

Lisa—Yes, it’s Roy Rogers (announced previously in the comments—Lee won). Hair poof was definitely part of my hat problem. But it didn’t account for all of my troubles. I really think it’s the shape of my head.

Canucklehead—See, even a baseball cap with the adjuster thing on the back won’t help me. If I put one on, it keeps riding up. We’d have to have a“melon-off”to compare who’s worse.

The Success—Thanks, but how big is your noggin?

Daisy the Curly Cat—Oh, boy. I laughed my bit fat head off when I read your comment, Daisy. Tell your Mommie that pin heads are special, too.“The pointy end…”Oh, that’s funny.

Ulquiorra—I did mine right in the middle of my forehead and around back, pulled tight to eliminate hair poof.

Zip n Tizzy—Congrats, even though you were late to the party. Thanks for stopping by. Love your screen name!

sue—The restaurant where they have head rests in all the booths for everybody’s fat heads!

Jolene—I’m sorry you don’t have a good hat head, but you are clearly in good company! I’m thinking your uniform was way worse than mine. Plus it sounds hot as hell. Sorry for that.

Bruce—And you got to make tips!

Jenn Thorson—True. Hair played a big part in my inability to wear it well. Ugh. A cowboy had with a band uniform? You must have been uncomfortable the whole time. Hopefully you played a light instrument. Pity the tuba player.

Joe—Hilarious! That’d put you in the Charlie Brown head category. Sorry.

Poetikat—I can’t explain the decor. A bit of“Behind the Times Chic.”Oh, yeah. My uniform always smelled like grease and french fries. You think you want to smell food all the time, but not if it follows you everywhere. Too much of a good thing.

Shieldmaiden96—The first time you go behind the counter is the most fun, seeing how things work. But then you realize how things work and you get a little disgusted. At least it did for me. Good Lord! Your mom really had it goin’on, didn’t she? She wore cowboy boots, too, I’m sure. What a vision!

ann of the shampoo bag—No. I think it died in the late 70s and mom saw it as a coffee table in its next life. Surprised she didn’t throw a tablecloth over it. Looks like hell, doesn’t it?
 Asuka_Aki Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 4:02 pm 
Hi, I have the same problem with hats and sunglasses. I also checked and my head is only half a cm larger than the average…So Why are average women hats and glasses so damb small, see kid size! I measure 5 feet 10 inches and i gusees everythings big on my body!

 Asuka_Aki’s last blog post.. My trip to New York 
 Regan Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 4:16 pm 
Mashed potatoes in an ice cream machine? Oh, wow.

I feel so bad for your job. And mom’s too. You look absolutly miserable in that picture. I don’t think those resturants payed you enough.
 KFJ Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 5:04 pm 
Golden Corral, maybe????

Not gonna measure my head, pretty sure mine is abnormally small……of course most of it is dominant brain!!!

 KFJ’s last blog post.. ’80’s Fix Wednesday 
 Daniel Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 7:47 pm 
I’m a little late to the game here but my guess was Roy Rogers but I see someone more timely beat me to it.
 Kathy Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 8:00 pm 
Regan—Swear to God. You pulled up the handle and mashed potatoes oozed out. Ask your Mom about it. No fast-food job pays enough. I think it’s to make you realize the value of a college education.

KFJ—Ooo! Never heard of that one, but nope. It was Roy Rogers and Lee guessed it. Oh, now you made me curious. Measure it, woman!

Daniel—That’s the trouble with these contests. Everybody’s in a different time zone and the answers come in any time. But way to go! Good‘ol Roys. I have such a craving for a bacon cheeseburger. Not a fan of the roast beef, but ooo, them burgers!
 Kathy Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 8:53 pm 
Asuka_Aki (sorry you got caught in my filter)–I have trouble with sunglasses, as well. The pair I have now is so narrow, I have to watch that I don’t poke myself in the eye putting them on. I swear, they weren’t kid glasses! What’s up with that?
 The Success Says:
 June 27th, 2008 at 11:19 pm 
Dear Kathy
I have been registered for your TOPSPOT, but I didn’t see my site there. My transaction via paypal
thanks

 The Success’s last blog post.. Success with Blowfish Shoes 
 Libertine Says:
 June 28th, 2008 at 12:03 am 
When I was on the police force, I wore a size 7 3/8 hat, which I think is 23 inches.

Don’t feel bad about your head size—who wants an f’in pinhead anyway?

 Libertine’s last blog post.. How Fundamentalists View Movie Characters 
 Lauren Says:
 June 28th, 2008 at 5:27 am 
Well there is NO way I can win the fat head part of your contest. I have one of the smallest heads you can imagine and I am bracing myself for the jokes coming my way. I do make up for it with my hair…as Drowsey often points out.

 Lauren’s last blog post.. Carrie’s Friday Foto Finish Fiesta 
 Swubird Says:
 June 28th, 2008 at 10:05 am 
Hooters!

 Swubird’s last blog post.. CREEP IN THE BIJOU THEATER 
 Kathy Says:
 June 28th, 2008 at 4:06 pm 
The Success—Thank you for the Top Spots contribution. I do see your link there.

Libertine—I’m always comparing myself to normal, as you probably know. Maybe I need a“head”shrink.

Lauren—I have the doubly bad problem. Big head, big hair. The 80s were my decade.

Swubird—If they were in existence in the early 80s, might I have stood a chance? Don’t answer that.
 Nodins Nest Says:
 June 28th, 2008 at 7:44 pm 
I remember that restaurant and that is a very handsome outfit, I’ve certainly seen worse!

 Nodins Nest’s last blog post.. First Shapes Handmade Book 
 Kathy Says:
 June 28th, 2008 at 7:49 pm 
Nodins Nest—Oooo! I just love your Gravatar! So pretty! Without the stupid cowboy hat, it wouldn’t have been so bad. But, yes, I suppose there were worse. But geez, to wear that for minimum wage? It was like every day was a Halloween party.
 brooke regans friend Says:
 June 29th, 2008 at 5:55 pm 
i did some research and its the red barn
my head circumfrance is…6 and a half of toilet paper sheet
you figure it out
 brooke regans friend Says:
 June 29th, 2008 at 6:00 pm 
oops i guessed to late
 Callie Says:
 June 30th, 2008 at 8:40 am 
Ha ha Ha, your post crack me up. Found you thru Entrecard. I will be subscribing to your feed. Thanks for the laughs. Loved your post up above about the toilet cleaning and such.
 Kathy Says:
 June 30th, 2008 at 5:09 pm 
brooke—I love that you used the next best thing to a tape measure! I don’t know what that translates to, but I’m guessing you don’t have as fat a head as me!

Callie—Welcome aboard! I’ve been finding some great new blogs via EC, as well. I’m glad you stumbled over here and subscribed. Good to have you.
 Dan Says:
 July 13th, 2008 at 11:33 pm 
Big fat head.. come on now really.. it’s not that big at all 
 Kathy Says:
 July 14th, 2008 at 3:52 am 
Dan—Ah, gee, thanks! But how come I had to wear a man’s hat? Something is definitely wrong with my cranium.
 Samuel Barns Says:
 September 12th, 2008 at 4:34 pm 
Its really a shame the uniforms that companies make their employees wear. It seems a lot of companies have realized that if the employees feel good in the uniforms their performance should be enhanced by it.
My guess is The Golden Coral.
 Kathy Says:
 September 13th, 2008 at 3:47 pm 
Samuel Barns—I remember going to this particular restaurant when it first opened, thinking I felt sorry for the workers who had to wear such stupid outfits. And then I applied there 6 months later. (It was a Roy Rogers.)
 sabags Says:
 October 12th, 2008 at 4:31 am 
Well I just want to say the hat looks funny on your head.Sorry, I am not judging you.But I don’t have a hat head too.I look like a monk with those stupid hats~
 Kathy Says:
 October 13th, 2008 at 4:39 pm 
sabags—Yes, it does look funny. Like if I leaned over it would fall right off. I’ve resigned myself to the fact that I do not have a hat head and I’m OK with it. Glad to have you in the No Hats for Me Club.
 Cardiogirl: 19% body fat 100% fun»If you’re not into pina coladas but you do like robbing banks, I’ve got just the thing for you Says:
 January 22nd, 2009 at 6:33 am 
[...] to Kathy of The Junk Drawer who is a Sister in Solidarity when it comes to super-sized craniums. I really thought we were going to have the same size head, Kathy. But yours is 23 inches. I measured twice. Hair in a ponytail, hair down. I pulled that mofo as [...]
 Ian Says:
 January 23rd, 2009 at 2:31 pm 
Sorry for the extremely late in the day post. Your head is definitely not so big.
In an effort to make large headed people feel better if they are down about their mega noggins,here is a true story i hope wil lighten the load for you.
I played baseball in Australia when i was younger and one young fellow on our team had such an outsized head that somebody found an adult sized motorcycle helmet for him with all the lining ripped out to encase his collossal cranium.
As an adult this would be embarrassing enough but as we were all eleven years old at the time our huge headed team mate came in for some serious taunting.
 Kathy Says:
 January 24th, 2009 at 6:36 pm 
Ian—I laughed my ass off at your story. Oh, but I do feel bad for that large-noggin’d kid. Maybe his body grew into his head?
 Anna Says:
 October 3rd, 2009 at 9:03 am 
Really wonderful piece of information and I appreciate it that you share something humorous and reader can relate to this, very funny, good one, cant wait to read more..
 
 
 
Keep Up With Me
 

 
Dig Through the Drawer
 Select Month June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 
Categories

 art Bacon Bizarre Blogging cats Childhood computing contests embarrassing food Fun language literary Short stories Stuff I don&apos;t hate Stuff I hate Stupid things I do suburbia tech support Travel What&apos;s That? Windy work 
 
Get Junk Drawer on Kindle
 
 
 
Kathy Frederick

 
 
Recent Posts

 They Heard Me Coming a Mile Away Mug Shots Good Deed Gone Wrong Weird Guy in the Men’s Room What This Curly Top Girl Learned by Having Straight Hair for 36 Hours I Hate This Commercial With the White Hot Intensity of a Thousand Suns Love Note How an Angry Cat Makes Demands Wanted: SWF With Tech Support Skills Dude, Where’s My Car? 
 
Sponsoring Friends
 
Junk Drawer Sponsors
 
 Junk Removal 
 Oxyelite 
 Rockin Body 
 Orkin commercial 
 
Grab Some Junk!
	</body>
</document>
