<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000404" url="http://ca.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20110406154047AAc8rDM" time="2012-07-12-15:39" support="4" score="0.004122608075718498" bingtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - What would you do if McDonalds wouldnt ..." webtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - What would you do if McDonalds wouldnt serve...your kind?">
			<query id="000068" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000086" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000082" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000087" bing-rank="165"/>
	<description>... and the secruity guard told the cashier not ... lever/button which is on the same dispenser as the soda. ... When was the last time you ate at a fast food restaurant?</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Canada Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog (USA) 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Other - Dining Out &gt; Resolved Question 
 BALLIN. :D Member since: April 23, 2009 Total points: 107 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
What would you do if McDonalds wouldnt serve...your kind?
 I went to McDonalds and the secruity guard told the cashier not to serve me.. So i asked why and she said because....and then i said is it because im Muslim? ( I KNOW that came at of nowhere, but i just wanted to ask, to make sure it&apos;s true...) and she said no its becausee im a theif. And because i put soda in the water cup. ( I HAVE NEVER DONE THAT!!!) i said you most be mistaken me for someelse because i never did it. And then she sais no, it was you. Like she was sooo sure of it! So i left. I know its not because im muslim...what should i do? 
 1 year ago Report Abuse 
 by WallyZ Member since: May 08, 2007 Total points: 96,506 (Level 7) Badge Image: 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 &gt;she said no its becausee im a [thief]...
&lt;because she thinks you are a republican?????

You did not mention it but do you normally drink water instead of soda?
You should insist that they call a manager so you can speak with him/her. Calmly and politely state your case with the manager. Point out that the guard could not have seen you specifically put soda in unless she had been standing there and observed that you did not press the little water lever/button which is on the same dispenser as the soda. The guard&apos;s job is to observe and report, the most the guard could do is to catch you in the act and report it to the manager. Then it is up to the manager whether to ban you or not. z 
 Edited 1 year ago Report Abuse 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: ;) 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; What would you do if… &quot;was originally asked in Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (5)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Lizzy Member since: November 17, 2008 Total points: 1,223 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 take this as a lesson...so mcdonalds doesnt serve&quot;your kind&quot;go to somewhere else! if mcdonald&apos;s wanted your patronage badly enough they wouldnt care who you were, i say, rule out mcdonalds go to another fast food chain, and im totally sorry for what happened to you, that really stinks. :( 
 1 year ago Report Abuse 
 by Jason C Member since: June 21, 2009 Total points: 4,015 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Unfortunately, it&apos;s not a right for a particular business to serve you. I would simply not patronize that particular McDonald&apos;s in the future. 
 1 year ago Report Abuse 
 by readupmo... Member since: March 06, 2009 Total points: 13,354 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Find a McDonalds that does not have a security guard. 
 1 year ago Report Abuse 
 by m3xican princ3ss Member since: February 02, 2011 Total points: 352 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 U should of said ok i want proof it was me, speak to da manager and thrn sue their *** after they seen it wasnt you. 
 1 year ago Report Abuse 
 by Victoria Member since: March 30, 2011 Total points: 969 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Its probably that location. I&apos;ve seen fully clothed Muslims be served all the time 
 1 year ago Report Abuse 
 
 
Discover Questions in Other - Dining Out 

 Why do I get food poisoning from fast food places? My boss serves up old out of date food , what to do ? What do you usually get at Panera? Where to buy good cheesecake thats NOT from Cheesecake Factory? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Canada Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Canada Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines
	</body>
</document>
