<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000419" url="http://www.lakeforest-ca.patch.com/listings/wienerschnitzel-33" time="2012-07-12-15:40" support="1" score="0.0015100182987467228" bingtitle="Wienerschnitzel - Lake Forest, CA Patch" webtitle="Wienerschnitzel - Lake Forest, CA Patch">
			<query id="001062" bing-rank="216"/>
	<description>Wienerschnitzel is a fast-food restaurant that offers premium hot dogs and sausages. Its menu includes hot dogs ... Payments accepted: American Express, Cash, Debit Card ...</description>
	<body>
		patching...   
Editor Sarah de Crescenzo sarah.decrescenzo@patch.com 
 
 
 60° Current weather TODAY | 60°F Partly cloudy. Patchy fog in the morning. Highs 74 to 79 near the coast to 88 to 93 inland. Light winds. 
 Hourly Detailed Radar 
 FRI 93° 65° SAT 91° 63° SUN 88° 60° MON 88° 58° TUE 87° 59° WED 84° --°   
 Admin 

 

 Patch Newsletter Nearby 
 Mission Viejo Patch Rancho Santa Margarita Patch Aliso Viejo Patch Laguna Niguel Patch Laguna Beach Patch San Juan Capistrano Patch Newport Beach-Corona del Mar Patch San Clemente Patch 
 See more 

 Join Sign In 

 
 Profile Account Newsletters Log Out 
 
 
 Home News Browse News 
 Arts Business Elections Government Obituaries Opinion Police&amp;Fire School News Sports 

 2012 Summer Reading Guide House&amp;Home Public Safety Readers&apos; Choice Lake Forest 2012 Summer Guide Announcements Local Voices 
 Events Browse Events 
 Art&amp;Entertainment Awareness Charitable Classes&amp;Lectures Fairs&amp;Festivals Family Food&amp;Drink Garage Sales Government Graduation 

 Music Organizations Outdoor Patch&apos;s House&amp;Home Religious School Events Sports&amp;Recreation Theater Wedding 
 Directory Browse Directory 
 Readers&apos; Choice 2012 Arts&amp;Entertainment Automotive&amp;Boating Community Resources Food&amp;Dining Government Health Nightlife 

 Real Estate Schools Services Shopping Sports&amp;Fitness Travel&amp;Transportation Hometown Partners Restaurant Reviews 
 Commute Pics&amp;Clips » 
 Jobs Volunteer 
 
 Breaking: Pastor Convicted of Molesting 5 Young Boys From His Congregation» Welcome back, Patch Blogger! Make Patch better! Take our survey:   OK | Sorry, maybe next time 
 (survey will open in a new window) 
 
 Food&amp;Dining , Restaurants 
 
 
Wienerschnitzel
 Rate this business 
 20652 Lake Forest Dr Lake Forest , CA 92630 | Get Directions » 

 949-583-1508 

 www.​wienerschnitzel.​com 
 33.662541 -117.667282 primary 
 Wienerschnitzel 
 20652 Lake Forest Dr, Lake Forest, CA 949-583-1508 /listings/wienerschnitzel-33 1593034 /locations/1950065 
 Email Send to Phone Print   Tweet 
 ‹ Back to Listing   new   Embed | Share       context Photos (5) 
Photos
 Credit 0Alex Gonzales Credit 0Alex Gonzales Credit 0Alex Gonzales Credit 0Alex Gonzales Credit 0Alex Gonzales Upload Photos | Search Patch Archive http://lakeforest-ca.patch.com/listings/wienerschnitzel-33/media_attachments/edit?upload_started=1342045482 asset[new_asset_attachment_attributes][to_id] 1593034 asset[new_asset_attachment_attributes][to_type] Listing listing[new_asset_attachment_attributes][user_id] new_asset_attachment_attributes 

Do you own or manage this location? Claim it! 
Wienerschnitzel is a fast-food restaurant that offers premium hot dogs and sausages. Its menu includes hot dogs, chili dogs, burgers and chili-cheese fries. You can choose between single servings of meat or try one of the combos that add value to your meal. For dessert, you can try an cream cone or Freezes, featuring the Nutter Butter. This location has a large interior with plenty of seating for customers.
 
 Hours: Mon-Fri, 7am - 10pm; Sat, Sun, 9am - 10pm Handicap Accessible: Yes Founding Date: 1961 Payments accepted: American Express, Cash, Debit Card, Discover, MasterCard, Visa Products: Burgers, fries, hot dogs, shakes General services: Eat-in, Take-out Menu link: www.​wienerschnitzel.​com/​menu_wienerschnitzel.​php Specialties: Hot dogs, sausages ATM: No Parking: Free lot Private events: No Cuisine: American, Burgers, Polish What dish is most representative of the restaurant?: Chili-cheese dog Price level: $ Reservations: Not accepted Number of tables: 25 Features: Dinner, Kids&apos; Menu, Lunch Atmosphere: Fun, Late-night, Singles scene Dress code: Casual 
 
At This Location


 
 Add an event here 
 
Rate This Business
 [[&quot;validates_presence_of&quot;,{&quot;message&quot;:&quot;Psst \u2014 you still need to enter text for your review.&quot;}],[&quot;validates_length_of&quot;,{&quot;too_long&quot;:&quot;Easy there, Tolstoy. Your review cannot exceed 1500 characters.&quot;,&quot;maximum&quot;:1500,&quot;allow_blank&quot;:true}]] 
 
 
Reviews
     small_zoom false false 33.6335 -117.727 33.6674 -117.661 
See More on Patch

 The Wine Artist Power-FUL 
     
Most Popular listings

 Scooter Zone Lake Forest City Hall&amp;Community Center Santiago De Compostela Church Green Earth Coffee Monkey Business Gymnastics 
 
Advertise

Advertise on Patch and reach potential customers in your backyard and beyond. Click here for more information.
 Learn more » 
 
Volunteer

If you want to help local causes, or your cause needs local help, your next click should be right here.
 Learn more » 
 
Contribute

 Send us news tips Put an event on the calendar Announce something to everyone 
 
Patch Info

 About Us Jobs Advertise About Our Ads Terms of Use Privacy Policy - UPDATED 
 
Get in Touch

 Go Patch! Help Contact Us Patch Blog 
 
Patch Initiatives

 PatchU 
 
Goodies

 Patch Newsletter Widgets 
 Copyright © 2012 Patch. All Rights Reserved. 
Send to Phone
 Close 
 Phone number 

 Carrier Select a Carrier Alltel Ameritech AT&amp;T Bell Atlantic Bellsouth Mobility BlueSkyFrog Boost Mobile Cellular South Comcast PCS Cricket kajeet Metro PCS Powertel PSC Wireless Qwest Southern Link Sprint PCS Suncom T-Mobile Telus Mobility Tracfone Verizon Wireless Virgin Mobile 

Message preview
 Wienerschnitzel
20652 Lake Forest Dr
949-583-1508
http://patch.com/L-pwks 
Patch will never charge you for sending text messages. However,
existing SMS charges (if any) by your carrier will still apply.

 Cancel 
 Terms of Service Privacy Policy 
 
 
Claim this Listing
 Close View your listing 
Hi! We&apos;re glad we found you. Let&apos;s confirm a few details before we get started.
 What&apos;s your name? [[&quot;validates_presence_of&quot;,{&quot;message&quot;:&quot;Please tell us your full name.&quot;}]] What&apos;s your role at this organization? [[&quot;validates_presence_of&quot;,{&quot;message&quot;:&quot;Please tell us about your role with this organization&quot;}],[&quot;validates_length_of&quot;,{&quot;too_long&quot;:&quot;Your note is too long! Your note cannot exceed 1024 characters.&quot;,&quot;maximum&quot;:1024,&quot;allow_blank&quot;:true}]] What&apos;s your phone number? [[&quot;validates_presence_of&quot;,{&quot;message&quot;:&quot;Please tell us your daytime phone number.&quot;}],[&quot;validates_format_of&quot;,{&quot;message&quot;:&quot;We can&apos;t understand the phone number you entered. Please try entering the numbers like this: 212-555-1212.&quot;,&quot;with&quot;:[&quot;^\\d?[^\\d]{0,2}(\\d{3})?[^\\d]{0,2}\\d{3}[^\\d]?\\d{4}|Unknown$&quot;,&quot;&quot;],&quot;allow_blank&quot;:true}]] Are you authorized to represent this organization? Tell us why. [[&quot;validates_presence_of&quot;,{&quot;message&quot;:&quot;Please tell us about your relationship to this listing.&quot;}],[&quot;validates_length_of&quot;,{&quot;too_long&quot;:&quot;Word limit exceeded! Your explanation cannot exceed 1024 characters.&quot;,&quot;maximum&quot;:1024,&quot;allow_blank&quot;:true}]] 
 If you are not authorized to represent this organization, you may be subject to legal action. 
 Cancel Close 
Get Patched In

Lake Forest news, events, and deals sent to you daily and breaking news as it happens. See more options 
 
You’re now signed up!
 
 Terms of Service Privacy Policy 
 Close 
 Send us a news tip

Enter your tip here and it will be sent straight to
 Sarah de Crescenzo, Copy Editor Joan Fantazia, and Editor Paige Austin,
Lake Forest Patch&apos;s (incredibly grateful)
editors.
 Your name: [[&quot;validates_presence_of&quot;,{&quot;message&quot;:&quot;Please enter your name&quot;}]] Your email address: [[&quot;validates_presence_of&quot;,{&quot;message&quot;:&quot;Please enter your email address.&quot;}],[&quot;validates_format_of&quot;,{&quot;with&quot;:[&quot;^([^@\\s]+)@((?:[-a-z0-9]+\\.)+[a-z]{2,})$&quot;,&quot;i&quot;],&quot;message&quot;:&quot;Email address is not formatted properly.&quot;}]] Your suggestion: [[&quot;validates_presence_of&quot;,{&quot;message&quot;:&quot;Please include a suggestion.&quot;}]] Send me a copy Cancel
	</body>
</document>
