<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000243" url="http://lotgk.wordpress.com/2009/09/30/elephant-ear-restaurant/" time="2012-07-12-15:26" support="3" score="0.005201129894751754" bingtitle="Elephant Ear Restaurant « Grassy Knoll Institute" webtitle="Elephant Ear RestaurantGrassy Knoll Institute">
			<query id="000947" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="001009" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="56"/>
	<description>... one time..Also, we are NOT a fast food restaurant ... About calling ahead for your order. That’s a great idea. I asked the cashier when I was picking up my order ...</description>
	<body>
		Grassy Knoll Institute 

Home Of The 99 Cent Conspiracy Theory
 
 Home About Us Aliens April Fools Day Conspiracy FAQ’s Holidays Inner Sanctum Nuns Random Shots 
 
 
Category Archives
 April Fools Days 
 Blue Plate Special 
 Christmas Holidays 
 Conspiracy Theories 
 Geneva On The Lake 
 Giant Aliens 
 Growing Up Catholic 
 Halloween Dark Zone 
 Inner Sanctum 
 Logos Of LOTGK 
 Lost Secrets Revealed 
 Post Cards Edge 
 Psychic Predictions 2012 
 Random Shots 
 Record Albums 
 Sci-Fi Sexy Sirens 
 St. Patrick&apos;s Day 
 Thought Screen Helmet 
 Video Vault 
 Viking Thunder 
 
Conspiracy Theories
 
 
Kennedy Assassination, Flu Shot Virus, Big Foot, Lochness Monster, Beatles Hoax, Michael Jackson, Princess Diana, Moon landing, and many more.
 Conspiracy Archives 
 
Blue Plate Special
 
 
We visit all the &quot;Greasy Spoon&quot; restaurants around the country rating each experience. Featuring Las Vegas, Chicago, San Francisco, Gatlinburg, Houston, New York, Youngstown.
 Blue Plate Special 
 
Giant Alien Invasion
 
 
Sexy Giant Aliens are roaming the Earth plotting to enslave humanity. View photographic proof Giant Aliens have already infiltrated the population.
 Giant Alien Invasion 
 
Growing Up Catholic
 
 
1960&apos;s Catholic grade school with mean Nuns as teachers was a recipe of pure Hell. I knew my mission in life the day I pulled Sister Ann Teresa’s habit off her head. I had to know what secret treasures lay hidden beneath.
 Growing Up Catholic 
 
Sci-Fi Sexy Sirens
 
 
We pay homage to the sexy actresses and their cleavage who starred in science fiction movies and television series.

 Sci-Fi Sexy Sirens 
 
Thought Screen Helmet
 
 
The Thought Screen Helmet is the only defense against alien abduction. It disrupts the telepathic link between wearer and alien to eliminate contact.
 Thought Screen Helmet 
 
Find The Logo
 
 
The LOTGK logo can be found all over the world. Even on a sexy girls ass.
 Find The Logo 
 
Inner Sanctum
 
 
Humorous personal life stories of the past, present, and future from a 50 plus year old who has seen everything. Almost!
 Inner Sanctum 
 
Random Shots
 
 
Random tidbits of worthy news and photographs that don’t quite fit into any of the Grassy Knoll Institutes categories.
 Random Shots 
 
Postcards Edge
 
 
Sometimes a picture is worth a thousands words. If they were only worth money!
 Postcards Edge 
 
Viking Thunder
 
 
Rantings of a mad die hard Viking fan. No purple colored glasses for this fan.
 Viking thunder Rant 
 
Classic Vinyl Records
 
 
Classic vinyl record albums rescued from my basement. See what you have been missing.
 Classic Vinyl Records 
 
Geneva On The Lake
 
 
Once a thriving vacation resort and young adult get-a-way spot, has succumbed to erosion. From the once beautiful beach to the town and businesses that dot the once vibrant strip.
 Geneva On The Lake 
 
Video Vault
 
 
Brutal clips of faces of death, reckless driving, experiments documented, grass growing, public hangings, live executions, and clips of UFO’s flying above.
 Video Vault 
 
Worldly Visitors
 
 
 Email Subscription 
 
Enter your email address to subscribe to this blog and receive notifications of new posts by email.

Join 52 other followers

 

 
 
Mission Statement
 Grassy Knoll Institute. Home of the 99 cent conspiracy theory. We keep overhead and expenses low to provide more affordable and better tasting conspiracy theories for our readers. Hurry, supplies are limited at these prices. And quit calling me Shirley. 
Stats: Blah Blah Blah

 3,583,765 Satisfied Surfers Since 10/06/2007 
 
Grassy Knoll Tags
 abc lost adrian peterson aliens april fools April Fools Day Blue Plate Special boobs brad childress Conspiracy dharma entertainment fast food food funny gatlinburg Giant Aliens giants grassy knoll halloween halloween costumes hanso holidays humor Inner Sanctum ireland irish john kennedy jokes lost Lost Secrets lost theories lotgk lunch minnesota vikings nfl ohio post cards postcards random restaurants sexy vikings virtual reality youngstown youngstown restaurants 
Time Travel
 Select Month June 2012 (2) May 2012 (4) April 2012 (18) March 2012 (20) February 2012 (7) January 2012 (9) December 2011 (11) November 2011 (4) October 2011 (37) September 2011 (13) August 2011 (8) July 2011 (8) June 2011 (18) May 2011 (23) April 2011 (18) March 2011 (25) February 2011 (8) January 2011 (15) December 2010 (9) November 2010 (4) October 2010 (46) September 2010 (10) August 2010 (12) July 2010 (13) June 2010 (9) May 2010 (11) April 2010 (36) March 2010 (26) February 2010 (14) January 2010 (16) December 2009 (22) November 2009 (17) October 2009 (45) September 2009 (16) August 2009 (17) July 2009 (16) June 2009 (13) May 2009 (15) April 2009 (42) March 2009 (28) February 2009 (22) January 2009 (22) December 2008 (15) November 2008 (24) October 2008 (52) September 2008 (31) August 2008 (32) July 2008 (28) June 2008 (18) May 2008 (22) April 2008 (38) March 2008 (37) February 2008 (29) January 2008 (40) December 2007 (199) November 2007 (212) October 2007 (264) September 2007 (8) August 2007 (4) July 2007 (2) June 2007 (5) May 2007 (5) April 2007 (25) March 2007 (20) February 2007 (4) January 2007 (2) December 2006 (6) November 2006 (6) October 2006 (10) September 2006 (5) August 2006 (4) June 2006 (2) May 2006 (6) April 2006 (19) March 2006 (4) February 2006 (4) January 2006 (3) December 2005 (1) November 2005 (4) October 2005 (2) September 2005 (1) April 2005 (28) January 2005 (2) December 2004 (2) November 2004 (3) October 2004 (8) September 2004 (4) 
 
 
50 Psychic Predictions
 
 
For 2012: See who lives, who dies, who gets married, who gets divorced, who goes to jail, Natural disasters, and everything else under the sun.
 2012 Psychic Predictions 
 
Kris Williams Big Secret
 
 
TAPS ghost hunter investigator Kris Williams has been teasing the Twitterverse with a big secret she has. Our investigative team dug it up.
 Kris Williams Big Secret 
 
Hotel Conneaut Haunt
 
 
Click for the entire investigation conducted October 3rd, 2008 of video evidence of iconic Ghost Elizabeth.
 Hotel Conneaut Investigation 
Recent Comments

 marliio (@marliio) on Princess Diana Attending Willi… LOTGK on 50 Bold Predictions For 2012 B… LOTGK on 50 Bold Predictions For 2012 B… LOTGK on 50 Bold Predictions For 2012 B… LOTGK on 50 Bold Predictions For 2012 B… 
 
Kennedy Conspiracy
 
 
 November 22nd, 1963, President John F. Kennedy was assassinated in Dealey Plaza in front of thousands of spectators. Read the complete JFK conspiracy chronicles here.

 JFK Conspiracy Chronicles 
 
Princess Diana Is Alive
 
 
Evidence Princess Diana fabricated her own death to end her connection with the royal family.
 Princess Diana To Attend Royal Wedding 
 
April Fools Day Archives
 
 
 As usual we celebrate our feast day with cutting edge news that no one else delivers. Just like pizza. Click the link button below (Me) to read the archives. 
 
 
RSS And Twitter Follow
 RSS Twitter 
 
Top O The Mornin’To Ya
 
 
 St. Patrick&apos;s Day, more than Guinness beer and lucky Leprechauns. Check out our sexy red headed women in green, Irish humor, folklore, and other blarney.
 St. Patrick&apos;s Day Lore 
Natalie Wood is Alive
 
 
 One of Hollywood’s intriguing mysteries re-surfaced as a photo of actress Natalie Wood taken four years after her death in 1985, was posted on the Net.

 Natalie Wood Alive 
 
Halloween Dark Zone
 
 
 Creepy video, ghostly tales, plenty of sexy women in adult Halloween costumes, haunted house critiques, pranks, scary movie lists, even a “Live” electrocution. You never know what&apos;s lurking in the shadows. 
 
 
Christmas Time Is Here
 
 
Merry Christmas and Happy Holidays. All Christmas related posts from the Grassy Knoll Institute with plenty of mistletoe.
 Christmas Time Is Here 
 
ABC Lost Sequel
 
 
A new four part series that picks up from the series finale, during the church scene. Real answers to the critical questions with a very plausible endgame scenario is explored. If you miss Lost,

 Read More Here... 
 
The Book Of LOTGK
 
 
My first offering is a 26 chapter expose of my experience working in a warehouse in 1980. The strange and bizarre were considered the norm. I titled this book, My Office Has A Window. 
Grassy Knoll Categories

 April Fools Day (151) Blue Plate Special (235) Christmas (44) Conspiracy (96) Geneva (37) Giant Aliens (153) Growing Up Catholic (33) Halloween Dark Zone (209) Inner Sanctum (83) Lost Secrets (148) Lotgk Logo (53) Office Window (26) Postcards Edge (122) President Kennedy (76) Pyschic Predictions (5) Quirks (9) Random Shots (164) Sci-Fi Sexy Sirens (43) St. Patricks Day (85) Stump The Neener (11) Thought Screen (44) Video Vault (70) Viking Thunder (147) Vinyl Album Art (33) 
 
Current Hot Stories

 Ghost Hunters Kris Williams Big Secret Revealed 2007 Sexy Halloween Show Models Ireland&apos;s Sexy Ginger (Red Heads) Real Reason Grant Wilson Left Ghost Hunters Natalie Wood Found Alive 
 
Meta

 Register Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.com 
 
Grassy Knoll Institute
 
Powered By A Really Good Tasting Corned Beef Sandwich.
1995-2012
 __________________________ 
 « Jack Kennedy Kicks Back In Shades And The Devil’s Eyes » 
Elephant Ear Restaurant

Posted by LOTGK on September 30, 2009
 
Fair Food Without The Fair
 
It’s the end of September and the local and state fairs are now just a recent memory. Some wishing they would have bought that giant Elephant Ear or hot sausage sandwich smothered in peppers and onions.

As if my prayers had a direct hot line to the big guy, a new restaurant popped up in my old town called the Elephant Ear. The menu was simple and ingenious. All your fair food favorites.

We pulled in and the place was packed. There was one parking spot left out of about 25 in the lot. It must be good if the place is packed right?
 
Fair Corn Dogs
 
The layout was simple. A small sit down area with a few booths and tables, maybe seating for 25-30 people. An order and pickup counter on the left side. We waited in line for our turn. We waited about 5 minutes to place our order. After we placed our order, it took almost 20 minutes for our order to come up. That is why the place was packed. The food preparation was very slow. We noticed that everyone sitting at the tables and booths were waiting for orders.

Finally, our number was called and I retrieved our order. Of course I had to order a corn dog. It was standard fare, (Fair) and standard size. It was cooked well and tasted good. I have to say, it tasted just like the Canfield Fair corn dogs. And at $2.75 it better.
 
Cheeseburger&amp;Fair Fries
 
The second part of my artery clogging dinner was a cheeseburger and original“Fair”french fries. The cheeseburger was nothing special, no outstanding qualities. The bun was a little beat up, and it looked like it was just tossed in the container. It was well cooked, the cheese melted, the beef adequate quality.

The fries, on the other hand, were not“Fair”quality. In fact, they were pretty horrendous. Perhaps if they were cooked properly, they would have tasted better. They had the texture of fat spaghetti strings. They were soggy, wet, greasy, and well, terrible. The cost was $6 dollars for the combo which was reasonable if the fries were edible.

So, the service was terrible, the food below average, and the price adequate. However, I have to commend the owners for the unique idea of Fair food without all the stinky animals and smelly pumpkins and rotting hay. Since the restaurant was still new, I have decided to give them one more chance to redeem themselves. With that…..

The Grassy Knoll Institute scores 2.5 out of 5 shots and is on the fence about recommending Elephant Ear Restaurant for dinner.

 

 Back To Blue Plate Special Archives 

 LURKING ON THE GRASSY KNOLL 
 
Share this:
 
 
 
This entry was posted on September 30, 2009 at 9:35 pm and is filed under Blue Plate Special .
 Tagged: blue plate , canfield fair , corn dogs , elephant ear , fair fries , grassy knoll , lotgk , sausage sandwich , youngstown , youngstown restaurants . You can follow any responses to this entry through the RSS 2.0 feed.

 You can leave a response , or trackback from your own site.
 
17 Responses to“Elephant Ear Restaurant”

 
 Max Jackl said 
 October 1, 2009 at 9:14 am 
To bad they couldn’t get the process down correct. the concept is brilliant. Wish I had thought of it.
 Reply 
 
 LOTGK said 
 October 1, 2009 at 11:52 pm 
That is my thought process. The restaurant was new, and maybe they have it down now. I will report back soon.
 Reply 
 
 Gumby said 
 October 1, 2009 at 9:59 am 
I’m not impressed dude. Looks like something I can buy at the super walmart. Just saying!
 Reply 
 
 LOTGK said 
 October 1, 2009 at 11:55 pm 
Well, maybe not super Wal-Mart, but yea, standard type fare food. We shall see how they stack up in the near future.
 Reply 
 
 Anti-christ said 
 October 1, 2009 at 12:02 pm 
The fries aren’t fit to eat in Hell.
 Reply 
 
 LOTGK said 
 October 1, 2009 at 11:57 pm 
Agreed, soggy, and the fries were wet. Yes, wet. Hard to describe them as anything else.
 Reply 
 
 Moominboy said 
 October 1, 2009 at 3:40 pm 
Those fries doesn’t look good at all. I can probably make better ones. And I can’t stand my own food…
 Reply 
 
 LOTGK said 
 October 1, 2009 at 11:59 pm 
I know you can make better ones. I seriously think they were rushed and did not cook them fully. Usually, you want your fries, hot, not soggy and wet, and a little crunchy.
 Reply 
 
 Moominboy said 
 October 2, 2009 at 1:06 pm 
I’m one of those people that burn ramen noodles, you know….
 Reply 
 
 LOTGK said 
 October 2, 2009 at 1:46 pm 
I can relate to that.
 Reply 
 
 
 
 Shannon said 
 October 11, 2009 at 9:31 pm 
HI, I am the owner of The Elephant Ear. I am sorry that you did not have a good experience with your fries. I do admit that the fries I see in the picture above do indeed look soggy. I also noticed that your food must have also been a“to go”order because of the styrofoam container. When the fries sit in this container, at any restaurant, they do tend to become soggy because of the steam. When eaten fresh our fries are golden brown and crispy and fair quality. Also, the wait time of 20 minutes is due to the fact that at times we are extrememly busy…again, we are a small restaurant with only a limited amount of space for equipment….we can only cook so much food at one time..Also, we are NOT a fast food restaurant..just like a sit down restaurant, we cook your food as it is ordered. We use FRESH beef patties and when they are ordered we cook them. I do not like the idea of having food sit around in a steamer all day, unfortunatley we live in a rush rush society and me wanting to have“fresh”food is backfiring on me.
However, I do encourage you to give us a second chance….my name is Shannon and I will cook your meal for you if you come and I am there.
I also encourage you to try something a little more unique than a cheeseburger. I am stuck somewhere in the middle between a fast food and a true sit down restaurant and there is only so much I can do with a cheeseburger to make it intersting as well as keep the cost down…so, I decided to spend the money on FRESH patties. The Elephant Burger is our more elaborate burger. The“Big Mac”of The Elephant Ear, so to speak.
We also offer call ahead ordering which drastically reduces the wait time.
Also, I would suggest eating your meal there as well….fries are very tempermental and are best eaten as fresh as possible. Being stuck inside the styrofoam box didn’t help at all.
Lastly, I will definitely print this article out for my employees. I appreciate your honesty and the oppurtunity to hear constructive feedback that challenges me to make my restaurant a better place to eat.
 Reply 
 
 LOTGK said 
 October 11, 2009 at 10:43 pm 
Shannon, I appreciate you reading and commenting on my Blue Plate Special section. In kind, let me add,…

I call them as I see them. In a nutshell, the fries were not cooked, perhaps your employee’s were hurried and didn’t keep the fryer on the full cycle. Placing them in the take out container did not make them that way. They were not cooked long enough. I have purchased many an order of fries in take out containers and most stand up to the short travel time to my destination. In your case, it was literally three minutes.

About the 20 minute wait, yes, I understand that, and I stated such in my critique. I even offered an excuse for you thinking your restaurant was new, new employees, and perhaps all the bugs weren’t worked out. I have no problem waiting for good tasting food. However, I do mind waiting for uncooked bad tasting food.

About calling ahead for your order. That’s a great idea. I asked the cashier when I was picking up my order for a take out menu. She said they didn’t have any. So much for calling ahead huh?

And, the cheeseburger doesn’t have to be fancy or interesting, just well cooked and edible, which it was. Nothing fancy, just standard fair cheesebueger.

Shannon, I do appreciate your offer to personally cook my meal when I visit, but that would sway the critique. I promised I would return, and I will. Would would you recommend that is good?
 Reply 
 
 Shannon said 
 October 11, 2009 at 11:59 pm 
I will take your word on the fries, and I totally agree with. When I am there I am very adamant about the fries being hot, crispy and golden. I honestly agree that the fries in the picture are less than stellar.
I would definatley reccomend the elephant hoagie or the slaw dog, but if you are not into coleslaw then the elephant burger is a great choice…..and of course an elephant ear!!!

Running out of menus was infact a problem. I honestly couldn’t believe how many we go through. We recently implemented website address cards (which features our full menu) for those times when we run out.

I do hope your return and have a far better experience. I really do value feedback, good or bad, because both encourage me in some way to do better. Happy Eating:)
 Reply 
 Angus said 
 June 22, 2010 at 4:31 am 
I moved from my home town of Youngstown four years ago to come to Nashville. I am not sure where the elephant ear is, but from what I can tell, it looks like it is in where the laundromat and hallowells meat market was. Is that right? Next time I come for a visit, I am going there.
 Reply 
 
 LOTGK said 
 June 23, 2010 at 8:16 am 
Angus, yes, that is exactly where it is. And as promised, I will be re-visiting the Elephant Ear later this summer to re-evaluate the restaurant.
 Reply 
 
 Dianna said 
 June 29, 2010 at 11:29 pm 
Just FYI, I came across an auction notice for the restaurant equipment in the Elephant Ear, says the facility is closing on June 30th 2010,
 Reply 
 
 LOTGK said 
 June 29, 2010 at 11:58 pm 
I don’t know about that.
 Reply 
 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (Address never made public) Name Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 

 Notify me of new posts via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 « Jack Kennedy Kicks Back In Shades And The Devil’s Eyes »   Blog at WordPress.com . | Theme: Customized Andreas09 by Andreas Viklund . Follow 
 Follow“Grassy Knoll Institute” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



Join 52 other followers

 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com Send to Email Address Your Name Your Email Address Cancel Post was not sent - check your email addresses! Email check failed, please try again Sorry, your blog cannot share posts by email.
	</body>
</document>
