<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000359" url="http://kepongtalk.blogspot.com/2009_06_01_archive.html" time="2012-07-12-15:34" support="9" score="0.01683253300513798" bingtitle="Everything about Kepong: June 2009" webtitle="Everything about Kepong: June 2009">
			<query id="000733" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000923" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="001488" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="001143" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000703" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="001236" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="001173" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="001300" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000891" bing-rank="230"/>
	<description>We caught a number of movies this way including ... playing and I was still looking for a place to sit. ... I remember dining in that fast food restaurant. I also remember ...</description>
	<body>
		skip to main | skip to sidebar 
 Monday, June 29, 2009 
 
 Ho Sin @ Taman Bukit Maluri 
 

 Last weekend, my family&amp;I went out for dinner. We went to this restaurant that is famous for“ho sin”(meaning fish from the river). Kok Heng (國興) is located at Taman Bukit Maluri (nearby the famous Tuck Kee Restaurant). They operate from 11am to 10pm. If you wanted to try some ho sin but don’t want to go too far from town, you can try this outlet. They serve lots of ho sin. And they also serve good fish head mihun (魚頭米) .
 
They will serve soup of the day each time you“ngai song sik fan”(order rice and dishes). Best part is that it is FOC.
 
 


We ordered a ginger sauce steam fish (姜茸蒸金鳳魚), stir-fried vegi, pai kuat wong (排骨王) and sei dai tin wong (四大天王).

We are disappointed as the steam fish is not up to the usual standard that night :( The tauke nia chatted with us when we almost finished our meal. We complained the fish not so good and she tasted the fish herself. And she told us we should tell her earlier so that she can replace with another fish. She gave us a small discount when we pay the bill.

The pai kuat wong is very nice. The meat is tender inside and crispy outside. Well marinated with all the favour nicely absorb by the meat. Thumbs up!
 Posted by Megan at 4:59 PM No comments: Labels: Kepong Food 
 Meals On Wheels 
 I feel sorry for the kids nowadays. It&apos;s a rare sight now to see ice-cream sellers on motocycles peddling their treats around neighbourhoods. Back when I was a kid, there used to be ice-creams sellers on bicycles and a bell. Every kid then knows that the ice-cream man is coming when they hear the oh-so-familiar rhythmic &apos;ting-ting-ting&apos; of the bell.

So what has this to do with Kepong? Well, I&apos;m gonna relate my experience with these special type of peddlars that used to ply their trade around Kepong.

Growing up in Kepong, I have come across quite a number of different people selling their wares door-to-door on a bicycle or motorcycle or even a small lorry. They will use either the road in front or the back lane and people will come out of their houses to buy.

There are those ice-cream sellers that I mentioned earlier. They usually come on a bicycle and travel down the road in front of our houses. To signal their arrival, they used a bell. Later on, the bicycles were replaced with motorcycles and the last time I&apos;ve seen one of these peddlars, they were using vans and played a soundtrack using loudspeakers to advertise their wares. I dunno but I feel that the bell was more effective in announcing their wares. It had a more intimate feel. You hear the &apos;ting-ting-ting&apos; and a smile will cross your face and you know that the ice-cream uncle is here. Those soundtrack playing vans just gets on my nerves. After the tenth time you hear the same jingle being repeated you just wanna rip out that tape or CD and smash it to bits!

Then there&apos;s the laksa seller that comes on a bike with a modified sidecar. He sells fishball mee and laksa and cooks the noodles right on his bike. I used to buy his fishball mee and I always ordered the &apos;large&apos; size! He will come around 11am and he plys the backlane. To announce his arrival he will call out, &quot;Ching Tong Laksa My Fun Mean!&quot; in Cantonese in a loud voice.

For variety, you can also opt to buy &quot;Wan Tan Mee&quot; from another peddlar. This uncle plied the route for the longest time! He was one of the first to appear and one of the last to leave the scene. He used to come on a bicycle (with sidecar of course) in the early days but changed to a motocycle later on. He also came around 11am and this uncle is also a Kepong resident. In my memory, he sold one of the best &quot;Wan Tan Mee&quot; I&apos;ve ever eaten even up till today. To buy the noodles, you will need to supply your own plate or bowl. Of course that wasn&apos;t a problem as they were just outside your house doorsteps!

Besides these, I recalled at least 2 aunties on bicycles selling &apos;kuih&apos; in the mornings. Then there were a couple of drinks vendor selling soya bean, &quot;tau foo fah&quot; and &quot;cincau&quot;. One was a lady and another was a guy. Direct competitors these two were. They had bad blood with each other as I can remember one time the guy literally chased the lady out of the neighbourhood on his bike with all their wares clanging. That particular day, I reckoned that both did not have good business as they were more intent on the chase than making sales!

In the early days, there was also a &quot;Yau Yu Vung Choy&quot; or Sotong and Kangkung snack seller that came in the afternoon. He was also one of the pioneers but he disappeared from the scene rather early. He came on a bicycle.

Apart from these ready to eat food sellers, there were also vegetables sellers that came in their small lorries laden with all sorts of vegetables and ocassionally even some fish. There was also one mobile pork seller. He came on a bike with a large metal box mounted behind. He carried a wooden board on which he would slice and dice his meat to his customers&apos; request. Oh yes he carried those large meat cleavers with him in the box. He even had a metal sharpening rod in there! Ocassionally you could see him sharpening the cleaver before cutting the meat. I guess if you saw a guy sharpening a meat cleaver outside your back door nowadays you would scream blue murder and call in the SWAT team! Those days were a lot simpler and more peaceful.

Those sellers were a bunch of colourful characters! The pork seller was a friendly chap. So was the laksa seller. The &quot;wan tan mee&quot; seller always had a serious demeanour on his face like he hated his job but he would never turn down a sale. Most of them were chatty and they contributed generously to the neighbourhood grapevine! Along with their wares they also peddle some red hot gossips! If you don&apos;t want the whole neighbourhood knowing that you just went for a matchmaking session that ended badly, don&apos;t ever mention it in front of these chatty bunch! Haha!

Sadly, these unique kind of mobile vendors disappeared over time. Now, the closest thing you can find to them is the Indian bread sellers on their bikes and even these are fast going the way of the dinosaurs! Posted by alphaKKC at 3:15 PM No comments: Labels: alphaKKC , Kepong Nostalgia 
 Thursday, June 25, 2009 
 
 Cinema, Cinema, Cinema 
 A couple of posts back, I talked about the Kentucky Fried Chicken outlet in Kepong Baru. There I mentioned an abandoned cinema. This post I am going to talk about that cinema plus another one in Kepong. Yup! The good old days... or so they seem. You tend to want to remember the good things rather than the bad things... hehehehe.

When I was growing up there has never been any cinemas in Kepong Baru. To catch a movie you&apos;ll have to go downtown to KL. When I was in primary school going to the cinema often means following my aunt to work! Reason being that my aunt used to work in a cinema as a ticket seller. So we would follow her to work and she would &apos;sneak&apos; us into the cinema hall in between her shifts. We caught a number of movies this way including &apos;Superman : The Movie&apos;.

Coming back to the topic, Kepong Baru never had any cinemas until I was in secondary school. Then they opened not one but 2 cinemas! They were called the Pavilion Kepong and Odeon Kepong and they were both about 2 kilometres apart. Pavilion Kepong was the one opposite the Kentucky Fried Chicken outlet.

Boy! Were we excited about that development! Finally, being able to catch movies right in your own neighbourhood. I never really did find out why they opened 2 cinemas there but I had a theory that they planned to show English movies only at the Pavilion and Chinese movies only at the Odeon.

To get to Pavilion, we used to just walk. To get to Odeon, we would take the red coloured Selangor bus - those big buses like the Rapid KL buses today - and pay about 20 cents&apos; fare to get to the Odeon&apos;s front steps. Then we could enjoy whatever movies were playing.

The cinemas were never very popular. Even at the peak of their glory, They never had crowds like those cinemas in KL. Probability of getting seats were very high except on Chinese New Year. They were a great boon for us for we hardly travel downtown to KL much due to our limited budget but I guess the crowd was just too little to sustain operations.

I remember that I caught quite a few movies in those 2 cinemas. I remember one time when I caught Alien 3 at the Pavilion Kepong. By the time I bought the tickets and entered the hall, the movie had already started. You know what they say, the nearer you are to a place, the later you will be getting there! So there was the movie already playing and I was still looking for a place to sit. At the time, they didn&apos;t even bother to give you a seat number as the crowd had dwindled to such a low number that it was free seating!

What happened next would be forever burned into my mind! As you know the Alien films were predominantly dark and most scenes were dark and gloomy in nature. That was the case as I looked for a seat that fateful day. So with my eyes locked onto the screen, I randomly chose a seat and tried to sit down. I said tried because I did not know that the seat was already occupied! It wasn&apos;t until the occupant of the seat I have chosen pushed me away that I knew the seat was not empty! Imagine my embarassment! I quickly mumbled an apology and moved to another place.

It was then I both thanked and cursed the darkness in the cinema hall. Cursed it because it caused me to almost sit on another movie goer. Thanked it because it hid my face from the guy/girl I almost sat on! Honestly I still don&apos;t know if it was a guy or girl in that seat on that day! So, to that guy or gal - if you happen to be reading this blog - please accept my sincere apology. It was an honest mistake!

The rest of the movie played on uneventfully after that but I can still recall that moment. I was alone that day fortunately. Yes, I occasionally go to the movies alone and I still do so to this very day. While that memory will be permanent, the cinema did not share the same fate. Not long after, the Pavilion closed down. The Odeon survived a bit longer but eventually also closed down. The Pavilion had a brief revival after its first closure but the second coming also suffered the same fate and it close down a short while after its second opening.

After its second closing, the Pavilion remained abandoned till this day. The cinema building is in a sorry state today. Everything looks so run down, dirty and old. It&apos;s only legacy was the car park that still served its purposed long after the cinema went out of business and now I hear a couple of stalls is open there.

The Odeon&apos;s site had a better fate. After is closed, the site was renovated and turned into a restaurant cum karaoke lounge cum designer coffee outlet. The Tai Thong restaurant opened a branch there, occupying the ground floor. The first floor was turned into a Star Karaoke outlet and for a while there was a Gloria Jeans Coffee outlet there.

It seems that Kepong folks do not like drinking gourmet coffee and the Gloria Jeans Coffee went bust after a while. The Tai Thong and the karaoke is still in operations last time I checked. After the closure of the cinemas, Kepong Baru is left without any cinemas once again. All that&apos;s left is the memories and the buildings that once housed them. But still when I am old and gray, their brief existence will give me the opportunity to boast to my grandkids that their grandpa once lived in a neighbourhood that had 2 cinemas! Posted by alphaKKC at 3:26 PM 2 comments: Labels: alphaKKC , Kepong Nostalgia 
 Monday, June 22, 2009 
 
 The Flyover 
 There is one flyover in Taman Kepong. It connects Taman Kepong with Taman Maluri Kepong. There&apos;s no river to cross. Instead this flyover jumps a railway track that used to keep Taman Kepong separate from Taman Maluri Kepong. Still have no idea where this flyover is? It&apos;s just a short distance away from the Kepong Komuter station.

For me, this flyover came a little too late. About 20 years too late. When I was in secondary school, I had a friend living in Taman Maluri Kepong. His house was literally just behind the railway tracks. My house was just a short distance away from the current Kepong Komuter station. So, as the bird flies the distance is not great. Just about a 20 minutes walk away. There was no direct link road, however, in those days. The road on the Taman Kepong side ended before the railway tracks and there was only a foot path across the tracks (illegal of course) and onto a dusty path that cut through some bushes before you emerge onto a tarred road on the Maluri side.

It was even difficult trying to get across on a bicycle - not to mention dangerous as the railway track is in use. So my friend and I used to wish that someone would build a flyover across the railway tracks and how it would be so much easier to visit each other then.

We waited and wished and waited and wished and waited... until my friend moved out to another place in Bandar Sri Damansara. No flyover. Then I moved out of Kepong to Puchong and what do you know, the flyover materialized! I was struck at the irony of the whole thing. When we wanted it, it never did appear and once we were no longer staying there, it came into being.

Anyway, I am grateful for the flyover as I use it quite often nowadays. Every weekend to be exact when I send my daughter to her grandparents&apos; house. I turn in from the LDP and whiz pass Desa Parkcity and on to the Telekom exchange building and then up and over the flyover and I&apos;m there at my parent&apos;s place.

I remember back then the road ended at the Telekom exchange building. It was the only building up the small hill and beyond that - where Desa Parkcity is now - was a piece of empty land and overgrown with bushes - hardly accessible. We used to go up that hill in the evening just to catch the breeze there and my brother and I used to cycle up the hill and roll down it on our bikes.

There were hardly any cars using that road then and we had the place all to ourselves and others that go there just for a walk. It was a popular place for older folks who hiked up the hill as excercise in the mornings and evenings. I had no idea that it could link to the LDP but back then there was no LDP either. I remember the first time I travelled down Jalan Damansara (before it became LDP) at night. It was quite an eerie experience which I shall keep for some future post. Posted by alphaKKC at 1:34 PM No comments: Labels: alphaKKC , Kepong Nostalgia , Taman Kepong 
 Sunday, June 21, 2009 
 
 Durian Street’s Indian Rojak 
 If you are staying around Kepong, I’m sure you know the Rojak seller at Jalan Mengastua or more commonly known as the Durian Street, Kepong Baru. My personal opinion, his rojak is the best around Kepong. Yummy!

For the information of those not too familiar with Kepong, this street is named Durian Street is because there are plenty of Durian on sales (and almost for all year round). Of course, during Durian seasons, there are even more Durians available. You can choose to have take away for dine in at the Durian stores. Yes, there are dine-in services available! The seller will actually open the Durians you choose, give you proper place to sit down and enjoy the fruits. No worries about your hand after eating the Durians, they also provide water for you to wash them. Cool, rite?
 
 This is the famous Durian Street of Kepong Baru. If are not too familiar with Kepong, just ask around the people there where’s Durian Street, I’m sure most people are able to show you the way.
 
Ok, back to the Indian Rojak / Mamak Rojak or Pasembur, whatever you like to term it. This Indian man is selling his rojak at one of the Durian store along the Durian Street. Don’t ask me the name of his rojak store. I have no idea at all. He ain’t have any name display there.
 
 See, so many people queuing up for his Rojak. 

Queue at his store is a common sight. He operates from 1pm onwards and usually at about 3pm or 4pm his rojak already sold out. So if you want to buy his rojak, best come around 2pm.

What’s inside the Rojak? Ok, here’s a photo of what I brought yesterday. It contains, coconut fritters, fried bean curd (tofu), pawn fritters, hard boiled eggs, cucumber, bean sprout and turnip (“sa got”) and sotong (is optional). And the best part of his rojak is the gravy, not too spicy with nice aroma of peanut.

 This is the amount of 1 pack. RM 3 per pack without the sotong.
 
 
 Oh…the yummy rojak&amp;it’s gravy. Sorry, too eager to eat it until all the photos I took is blurred. This is the best I can get. 

You can choose to take away or dine-in as well. There’s also a chendol seller beside his store. So you can have the spicy rojak and enjoy the cooling chendol.



 Posted by Megan at 10:00 AM No comments: Labels: Kepong Food 
 Friday, June 19, 2009 
 
 Perfect Daddy Challenge @ BREM Mall, Kepong 
 
Kepong BREM Mall is having a“Perfect Daddy”challenge on this Sunday 21 June 2009. It starts at 2pm, concourse area of BREM Mall.

What will these perfect dads do? They will be judged on doing 3 parts of challenges–catwalk&amp;self introduction, talent showcase and doing household chores. Top winner will walk away with RM 800 cash vouchers, RM 1500 worth of white gold diamond bracelet and a trophy.

The best part is there’s no registration fee required. Interested to enroll yourself or your daddy to the challenge? Entry forms are available from the information counter of BREM mall or call the organiser at 03-6250 4422.
 
 For map, please logon to http://www.bremholding.com/kepong2.html Posted by Megan at 4:00 PM No comments: Labels: Kepong Activities 
 Thursday, June 18, 2009 
 
 OR-JU Korean Restaurant 
 Tired of having the normal food for lunch and dinner, maybe you want to try this outlet. This restaurant is run by Korean. They offer variety of Korean noodle, Korean rice and ala-cart Korean dishes. If you don’t think that’s enough, they also serve sushi, tempuras and some other Japanese food.

I’m not tight budget lately, so I decided to try out their set lunch. They offer 6 types of set lunch, all price at RM 7.90 per set (excluding 5% service charge). All the set come with green tea, rice/noodle, tempura, kimchi and soup (noodle set are without soup).


 

I’ve ordered the mixed vegi rice set. The rice is served together with few types of vegi, and they put some gravy inside the rice. A separate chili sauce is prepared to add and mix with the rice. If you like something light and less oily, this can be a good choice. 

My friend ordered the roasted chicken rice set. Well, I think stirred fried chicken would be a more appropriate name. Quite tasty I would say.

They also serve a kind of ginger brew tea like drink after your meal. And the best part is that it is FOC.

I would say the food is okay and the price is reasonable.

 Location: No 66, Jalan Metro Perdana Barat 3, Taman Usahawan, Kepong 52100 Kuala Lumpur.


 Posted by Megan at 3:37 PM No comments: Labels: Kepong Food 
 Tuesday, June 16, 2009 
 
 Fast Food and Shopping Way Back Then 
 When I was a little kid, Kepong was a quiet little town. It is not happening at all. There&apos;s some schools and residential areas, some shops for commercial areas and that&apos;s all.

There was an open market where the vendors sells their vegetables and other sundry goods. There was also and indoor market but for some reason, the indoor market - located nearer to the old Kepong town center along Jalan Kepong - was not so popular. The new market is located at the &apos;new&apos; Kepong town center called Kepong Baru.

So that was pretty much it. The ladies of the house go to the market to shop and get their neccessities and then go back home. There was little else left to do. Then out of the blue a 3-storey complex was built near the Kepong Baru market and a brand spanking new shopping emporium was opened. If I remember correctly it was called the Yuyi Supermarket and it housed - surprise, surprise! - a supermarket!

The supermarket took the entire ground floor selling everything from toilet cleaning solutions to frozen meat. The second floor was occupied by the anchor tenant as well and harboured a departmental store selling clothes. The third floor had smaller retail lots that housed other entrepreneurs&apos; businesses. The only shoplot that I recalled up in the 3rd floor was a shoe store because we occasionally shopped there to get new shoes.

3 whole storeys of modern shopping paradise! Wow! Kepong is rocking, I tell ya! Well, that&apos;s how I felt at least. Now we could &apos;hang out&apos; at the supermarket - well, until our parents finished shopping, at least. It wasn&apos;t a very big building actually. Just about the size of a cinema hall back then but it was a modern shopping facility.

If memory served me correctly, not long after this Yuyi Supermarket opened, the first fast food outlet in Kepong opened just down the street at a corner shoplot. Wowzer! Now we&apos;re getting modernized! It was a Kentucky Fried Chicken outlet. Yup! They weren&apos;t all that lazy back then. They spelled out the whole words of the name, not just KFC like now. I betcha some kids nowadays don&apos;t even know what KFC stands for.

The Kentucky Fried Chicken was labelled as a &apos;Family Restaurant&apos; and a proper restaurant it was. You went in and sat down at a table and the waiters or waitresses will come over and took your order. Of course all you could order was Fried Chicken and the like but they took your order. Not like now you had to queue up at the counter and tell the kid at the cash register what you wanted.

After you have ordered, they will set the plates for you - yes, real plates. Not those paper box-like thing they pass off as plates nowadays. Laid out the forks and knives and then bring you your chicken and soft drinks. Then you can dine in air-conditioned comfort.

I remember dining in that fast food restaurant. I also remember that the bun and the mashed patatoes were much, much better than they are now. Now the bun is flat, hard and tasteless. Back then it used to be fluffy and had a sweet aromatic taste. The mashed patatoes then also tasted more natural rather than the processed taste that you get now. The chickens were also served in bigger sized portions. Seems like the fast food outlets now supersized their prices but shrunk the portions, taste and have done away with service totally!

Eating at the Kentucky Fried Chicken was an expensive affair so we did not dine there often but we did pass by the outlet each time we went to the market. Each time we walked past we would peer into the restaurant longingly.

The restaurant then went through several facelifts and have now evolved into one of the modern KFC outlets. It is still there now. At least it was still there the last time I checked but I seldom dine there anymore. And the Yuyi supermarket? It has changed management several times. From Yuyi to the Emporium and it was once a Parkson Ria for some time. Now I think it is unoccupied but the building is still there - right opposite the equally abandoned cinema hall. What cinema hall, you ask? That&apos;s a story for the next post! Posted by alphaKKC at 11:13 AM 2 comments: Labels: alphaKKC , Kepong Nostalgia 
 Wednesday, June 10, 2009 
 
 New Parking Fee @ Jusco, Metro Prima 
 I think most Kepongese know how popular is Jusco, Metro Prima. Cars queuing in and out from Jusco, Metro Prima car park used to be normal sight on Saturday/ Sunday or Public Holiday.

I guess Kepongese simply love to shop around Metro Prima. It is the number one choice for many to enjoy free air-cond on a normal hot non-working day with family. Do some window shopping, have some free reading at the Popular bookstore, settle your bill at the most crowded POS Office I known of, or even watch a movie at the cinema. Ah…it is simply the best and nearest hang-out place to be. And the best part is all Jusco members are entitled for free parking at the building. It is just hard to have free parking access in the city nowadays. Thus, sometimes it can be quite hard to find a parking in this building.

Recently, the management must have find out that most people come here for window shop and they unable to yield any profit from these shoppers. So they post a new parking rate.

No more RM 1 per entry for non J-Card member and no more unlimited free parking for J-Card member. The new rates are as below.

Non-J Card Member FREE for the 1st hour. And exceeding the 1st hour RM 1 will be charged.

J-Card Member. FREE for the 1st 2 hours. And exceeding the 1st 2 hours RM 1 will be charged.

So movie goers, no more free parking at Metro Prima…
I am so sad, coz I am one of those who enjoyed these privileges…
Oh I missed those days… Posted by Megan at 3:01 PM No comments: Labels: Kepong Movements 
 Tuesday, June 9, 2009 
 
 Jacob&apos;s Walk Of Life - 21 June 2009 
 Actually I&apos;m new to Kepong.....my friend, Megan invited me to be a contributor to this Everything About Kepong. Well, as I&apos;ve said I&apos;m new to Kepong as I just started to learn more about Kepong in the past few years. The most frequent visited place in Kepong would be Jusco Kepong. 

Anyway, to kick-start my blog, I would like to invite all the Kepong folks to participate in Jacob&apos;s Walk of Life on 21 June 2009 at Taman Metropolitan Kepong. To know more, just click to www.jacobs.com.my &amp;register yourself. Thinking of having a healthier lifestyle, come join me at Walk Of Life event... it&apos;s just around your neighbourhood.

I, myself have not been to Taman Metropolitan Kepong so I would like to take this opportunity to visit this place. I heard many people went there for kite-flying. Gotta check out myself.

See you there&amp;live a healthier lifestyle. Posted by Wild Orchids - Ling at 9:08 PM 1 comment: 
 Saturday, June 6, 2009 
 
 Kindergarten Daze 
 Wokeh! More Kepong Nostalgia! This time I take you to the place where I was introduced to education - Kindergarten! 
 In my last post, I said that I wasn&apos;t even in kindergarten when we first moved to Kepong. Well, that was not for long. My parents got us (my sis and I) registered to a kindergarten nearby. How nearby? Well, all we had to do was walk to the end of our block and cross a street and we are there. The kindergarten was actually a bungalow house that was converted. 
 For the life of me I cannot remember what the kindergarten&apos;s name was. I guess I wasn&apos;t paying much attention, hehehehe! Anyway, we got registered and we had to go for classes. It was then I got the first taste of a question that would hound me for the rest of my school days all the way to secondary school. What was the question? It was, &quot;Are you and your sister twins?&quot; 
 The answer, &quot;No! We&apos;re not twins.&quot; After that the other question would follow, &quot;Then how come both of you are in the same class?&quot; Then I would explain, &quot;My sis in born in January. I was born in November. So same year but not twins.&quot; 
 There was another kindergarten nearby - it was actually a church. It was another 100 or so meters away. A catholic church to be exact and an unmistakable landmark in Kepong. If any of you lived in Kepong, you probably would know the &apos;church at the round-about&apos; in Taman Kepong. That&apos;s the church I&apos;m referring to. 
 Didn&apos;t know why we were not registered there and didn&apos;t care either. Hey, kids care not for decisions made by adults, no? 
 I could not remember the first day at kindergarten. Mom said that I cried when first left alone in class. Of course my parents were just outside the classroom but I can&apos;t seem to recall any of that happening. I guess I probably did cry - I was kinda a crybaby then. 
 So what did I remember about kindergarten? I remember that mom would walk us there in the morning and after classes ended, we would wait for mom to come and walk us back. I also recalled my favourite time in kindergarten - recess! Yes! Recess! That&apos;s when we get food and we get to play in the garden! There were see-saws and a slide if I remember correctly. I loved it when they served Milo during recess! It&apos;s my favourite drink! 
 We learnt to sing and write our names and count to 10 maybe. The days were a blur now. Not much I can remember but I can still remember that they served Milo and other drinks in plastic cups and most of the cups were green in colour! Don&apos;t ask me why but that&apos;s what I can still remember. The days in kindergarten zipped by and soon I found myself in primary school, but that&apos;s a story for another day.  
 The kindergarten is no longer there now. It closed up long, long ago for reasons unknown. Some family is living there in the lot now. The church is still there although the round-about is also gone. Now there&apos;s a crossroad with traffic lights where the round-about used to be. Things have changed. Now, there&apos;s so many cars zipping by the street where my old kindergarten used to be, that often there will be a traffic jam leading to the traffic lights. Back then, the road is almost deserted with an occasional car passing by every now and then. 
 I remember that I used to enjoy the walks to and from kindergarten. We get to cross the road and then walk almost all the way to the end of our block. It felt like an adventure! Yup! Those were the good old days!  Posted by alphaKKC at 11:51 PM No comments: Labels: alphaKKC , Kepong Nostalgia , Taman Kepong 
 Friday, June 5, 2009 
 
 “Go Green, Live Green”Green Day Celebration 2009 @ FRIM 
 
It’s weekend again. Nothing on the list but shopping? Boring…

Why not drop by to FRIM, Kepong this Sunday for The Star’s 2009 Green Day Celebration with the theme of“Go Green, Live Green”.

Here’s the info about the event:-

Venue: F.R.I.M, Kepong (Never heard of F.R.I.M? Is Forest Research Institute Malaysia)
Date: 7 June 2009, Sunday
Time: 8pm–3pm
Admission: FREE
Parking: Very limited. If you don’t mind can park outside the FRIM and take a nature walk. Breathe in some good fresh air.





 What’s ON? 
· Recycle your old Handphone complete with batteries&amp;related accessories. Every phone recycled is entitled to an adoption of tree planted in your name at Lombok Indonesia. You can view it at Google Earth. Cool!! Courtesy of Nokia.
· Nature Walk on FRIM Keruing Trail . Session: 11am-12noon&amp;2pm-3pm. Only open to 20 people per session. 1st come 1st serve. Courtesy of Malaysian Nature Society
· Guided Nature Trail&amp;Canopy Walk . Session: 9am, 10.30am&amp;12noon Courtesy of FRIM
· Tree Climbing Demonstration . Session: 10am, 11am&amp;12.30pm (Gee... I used to know how to climb a tree... )
· Sand Art activities for kids. Courtesy of Bonuslink
·Recycle for a FREE Revive . 1st 200 people only. Courtesy of Permanis.
· Energy Saving Bulbs Give Away . Courtesy of Philips&amp;The Star.
· Signatures collection in support of turtle campaign by WWF.
·If you can’t live without shopping . Never mind, their will be some sales on here.

For the conveniences of those haven’t been to FRIM. I attached a MAP to FRIM.
 



Have fun folks!!


 Posted by Megan at 4:09 PM No comments: Labels: Activities 
 Kepong in My Mind 
 So, I have been invited to contribute to the Kepong Talk Blog. Well, I guess I meet the minimum requirements. I have spent a few decades living there though I won&apos;t say how many! So I&apos;ll be writing some about it. Here&apos;s the first entry:

Kepong - a name that didn&apos;t ring any bells for me until I realise that I am going to be living there! Didn&apos;t even know where it was but then I was just a little tyke back then. When I said little tyke, I meant little tyke as in I wasn&apos;t even in kindergarten back then!

The earliest memory of Kepong in my mind that I can recall is when my dad brought us - meaning my mom, my elder sis and me - to see our new house. We&apos;ll be moving to this place called Kepong. When we reached our new house, the place was still very much a construction site. The house was newly finished. The road was not even tarred, just gravel and the place was just rows and rows of newly constructed houses and ours happened to be the one dad parked his car out front.

When we went inside the house the most vivid memory I had was how the house made echoes whenever you spoke! So we (my sis and I) tore through the house and shouted in each room and giggled when the echoes came back. How easy to please us when we were young!

That was about all I could recall about the first impression of the house in Kepong. Soon after that we moved in. I remembered that we were one of the first few occupants to move into that neighbourhood. So early that the electricity was not even hooked up yet! When evening came we had this big lantern - some sort of gas lantern if I am not mistaken - to light up the house. It boggles my mind now on how we slept without any air-cond or fans during the night!

It was in that house that we stayed throughout my primary and secondary school years. The neighbourhood grew up with us. Back then people used to say things like, &quot;Kepong?! Wah! So far away ar, you stay?&quot; or &quot;Kepong? That&apos;s like in the middle of the jungle!&quot; I guess it was newly opened area and new housing estates back then but when you&apos;re a kid, you didn&apos;t care about these things.

After the neighbourhood came alive a little with more families, the only row of shoplots that was a stone&apos;s throw away from my house became occupied. I didn&apos;t know which shop opened first but I recalled one of them was a sundry shop run by a Chinese family. That shop became one of the places where I would frequent throughout the years. Mom sent us to buy stuff and sometimes we went there to buy stuff like sweets and ice-cream for ourselves. I also recalled the the owner of the shop used to go on a bike to each house and ask whether we needed anything. He would take down the orders and have them delivered to you later in the day! He would keep tabs and billed us periodically. Talk about service! I never learned his name. Not even today do I know his name! We called him &apos;Chap For Lau&apos; which means &apos;Sundry Shop Guy&apos; in Hakka and that was his name for me till today.

The power lines were hooked up eventually and we finally had flourescent lights to illuminate our house at night. Boy, were we happy on that first night we switched on the lights! Man, those flourescent lights were much brighter than the lantern and the best part was they were white! The lantern had a yellow light and it cast such a dull glow. After that day, the lantern went into storage but it would still serve us ocassionally when the power went out. During those days, power outtage were much more common.

Those were some of the earliest memory I had about Kepong. Nothing much about the actual town but hey I was just a kid! In case you&apos;re wondering which residential area I am referring to it&apos;s Taman Kepong!

Stay tuned for more nostalgia in the next posts!!


Now for some shameless self advertisement:

 Do visit http://xqsitely.multiply.com to see some of my works on wedding photography as well as personal portraiture. 
 I am a freelance photographer and can be contacted for wedding shoots. 
 Email : chong_kk@yahoo.com Posted by alphaKKC at 1:52 PM 1 comment: Labels: alphaKKC , Kepong Nostalgia , Taman Kepong 
 3 New H1NI cases detected in Malaysia 
 Today when I flipped the newspaper and I saw that there were 3 new cases of H1N1 detected in Malaysia.

One student coming back from the states on MH 091 on the 1 June.
Another 2 were German tourist arrived from Singapore on AirAsia AK702 on 3 June.

The health ministry is tracking those on these 2 flights to prevent local transmission of the virus. They ask corporation for those in contact with the 3 patients to contact them on 03-881 0200 / 03-881 0300.
Keep our free from Influenza A H1N1 threats!! Posted by Megan at 11:48 AM No comments: Labels: community service 
 Thursday, June 4, 2009 
 
 Welcome to Kepong Talk 
 Kepong. What does this word means to you? To many people it is merely a name of a place. Yet to me, it means much more than this.

I’m living here since I was born. To me, Kepong is my home and my kampong. Here I have my family&amp;friends around. Many people may say Kepong is a“ulu”place, but to me it is an“awesome”place where I grow up. I am proud to be a Kepongese!

I love Kepong, and this is the reason I start this“Kepong Talk”blog. My purpose is to talk everything about Kepong. The food, the people, the activities, the travel, the history and geography (although I am not too old, but I’m willing to share as many as I know and as many as I can dig) of Kepong.

Welcome to Kepong Talk and I urge you to join me in the blog and share your view about Kepong. And if you happened to know any Kepongese (no matter existing, ex or future ones), ask them to logon to Kepong Talk. And for people who love Kepong for whatever reasons, I also welcome you to be part of Kepong Talk. Posted by Megan at 6:01 PM No comments: Labels: General Newer Posts Home Subscribe to: Posts (Atom) 
 Everything about Kepong 
 
 
 
Subscribe To
 Posts Atom Posts All Comments Atom All Comments 
Blog Archive
 
 ▼  2009 (32) 
 ►  November (1) 
 Keep up the good work 
 

 ►  October (4) 
 More Food&amp;Travel Blog Bak Kut Teh Promo Another 99 Speedmart at Kepong It’s only RM 2 
 

 ►  September (2) 
 Pica-chu! Eat that Pokemon! Kepong Yong Tou Foo Is delicious!! 
 

 ►  August (2) 
 MJ Contest Yummy Cendol 
 

 ►  July (8) 
 Bakery/ Café/ Chill Out Place Baking Class for home bakers List for Schools in Kepong Kepong School Days Welcome announcements and blogs on Kepong Power Distruption @ Kepong Pos Office Branches Jalan Damansara - Before It Became LDP 
 

 ▼  June (15) 
 Ho Sin @ Taman Bukit Maluri Meals On Wheels Cinema, Cinema, Cinema The Flyover Durian Street’s Indian Rojak Perfect Daddy Challenge @ BREM Mall, Kepong OR-JU Korean Restaurant Fast Food and Shopping Way Back Then New Parking Fee @ Jusco, Metro Prima Jacob&apos;s Walk Of Life - 21 June 2009 Kindergarten Daze “Go Green, Live Green”Green Day Celebration 2009 ... Kepong in My Mind 3 New H1NI cases detected in Malaysia Welcome to Kepong Talk 
 
 
 
Labels
 
 Activities (1) alphaKKC (8) Announcements (3) community service (1) General (4) Kepong Activities (2) Kepong Food (9) Kepong Movements (1) Kepong Nostalgia (8) Taman Kepong (3) 
 
Contributors
 
 alphaKKC Megan Wild Orchids - Ling 
 
Blogs I like...
 
 A Life Less Extraordinary Cassie&apos;s Journal Pt. 4 3 days ago kennysia.com Club Med Phuket 4 days ago Lifestyle Designers The Majestic Mount Bromo of Java, Indonesia 7 months ago Luan Bai Y.E.S is back!! 2 years ago Tony Fernandes CEO Blog We didn&apos;t start the fire 3 days ago 
 
Followers
 
BlogCatalog
	</body>
</document>
