<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000374" url="http://faithfulprovisions.com/2011/12/20/giveaway-enter-to-win-a-chick-fil-a-prize-pack/" time="2012-07-12-15:34" support="1" score="0.0015186847917383573" bingtitle="Giveaway: Enter to Win a Chick-fil-A Prize Pack — Faithful ..." webtitle="Giveaway: Enter to Win a Chick-fil-A Prize Pack — Faithful Provisions">
			<query id="000284" bing-rank="202"/>
	<description>Be sure to enter a separate comment for each method ... fries and better toys (books!) than any other fast food restaurant! ... My Food Column</description>
	<body>
		Home About 
 About Video Story 
 Contact 
 Contact Advertising Media Speaking 
 My Book 
 
Founded on Luke 12:24, Faithful Provisions is dedicated to showing individuals and families how to save money by encouraging, equipping and empowering… [read more] 
 
 Start Here 
 Subscribe to Faithful Provisions Menu Planning Stockpiling Couponing Navigating the Store Budgeting and Planning FAQ Store Policies 
 Deals Coupons 
 Coupon Database Printable Coupons 
 Coupons.com Printables RedPlum Coupons SmartSource Coupons Coupon Network Target Store Coupons 
 All You Magazine Coupon Lingo Cellfire Loadable Coupons Organic&amp;Natural Coupons Publix Coupons Sunday Coupon Preview 
 Store Deals Summer Links 
 Recipes with Strawberries How to Freeze Strawberries Free Kids’Summer Movies Free Kids’Bowling Free Kids’Summer Reading Programs Find A MOPS Group What to Buy When: July 
 Resources 
 Devotionals Categories Popular Series 
 Budgeting Series What to Buy When Every Month of the Year Healthy Living Series Kids’Free Educational Resources Simply Saving Series 
 FREE Downloads Freebies 
 Birthday Freebies Kids Freebies 
 Giveaways 
 Enter Giveaways Giveaway Linky List 
 My Community Photo Deals Frugal Map Q&amp;A Submission Form 
 In the Kitchen 
 Weekly Meal Plans Kelly’s Recipe Box Kelly’s Kitchen Tips Ingredient-Based Recipe Index Recipe Shopping List The Ingredient Exchange 
 
 
Giveaway: Chick-fil-A Cow Watch Prize Pack
 
by Kelly on December 20, 2011 · 119 comments Share Tweet 119 Comments 

 
 Please note: This Giveaway is now closed. The winner is listed HERE . 

 
My kids LOVE these new Chick-fil-A cow watches! And because I’m thinking your kids will love them too, I have a special giveaway for you today. TODAY ONLY, you can enter to win a Chick-fil-A Prize Pack which consists of: Five Cow Watches and Two Chick-fil-A Plush Cows!

How would you like to win? See all the details below.

In case you don’t win, Chick-fil-A cow watches are now available in Chick-fil-A kid’s meals. Check with your local Chick-fil-A restaurant for availability.

FAITHFUL PROVISIONS GIVEAWAY DETAILS

Chick-fil-A is offering one Chick-fil-A prize package to one randomly selected winner. The winner will be announced on Wednesday, December 21, 2011.

 Faithful Provisions Giveaway Disclosure: Chick-fil-A sponsored this giveaway by providing me with one Chick-fil-A prize package to give away to one randomly selected winner. For more information about Faithful Provisions, please read my Disclosure Policy . 

====================

 HOW TO ENTER…. 

 *One entry per person per method of entry per day. Be sure to enter a separate comment for each method of entry (one comment for Facebook, one comment for Twitter, etc.). This way you have a higher chance of winning. 

**4 Entries per Person per Day

1. COMMENT : Leave a comment telling me your favorite Chick-fil-A menu item ! 

2. NEWSLETTER SIGN-UP : Subscribe to my Email Newsletter – even if you already receive it, add an entry as a comment below!

3. TWITTER : Follow Faithful Provisions and Chick-fil-A .

4. FACEBOOK : Follow Faithful Provisions and Chick-fil-A .

====================

 GIVEAWAY ENDS TODAY, TUESDAY, December 20th, AT 11:59 pm CST. The winner will be drawn using Random.org . The winner will be notified via email and the name will be posted on Wednesday, December 14, 2011. 
 Click here
to LIKE us
on Facebook 
Related Posts :
	</body>
</document>
