<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000875" url="http://www.doorsixteen.com/2011/06/24/cold-brewed-coffee-love/" time="2012-07-12-16:14" support="1" score="0.0007001139633723046" bingtitle="Cold-brewed coffee love. | Door Sixteen" webtitle="Cold-brewed coffee love. | Door Sixteen">
			<query id="001245" bing-rank="123"/>
	<description>Yes, I do have at least a cup (“a cup” = one container of ... m wasting any as good coffee is not throw away ... mine are the supersize cups from a fast food restaurant).</description>
	<body>
		Jun 24, 2011 Food + Drink Share this post 
 Facebook Twitter Digg StumbleUpon Del.icio.us 
 91 comments 
Cold-brewed coffee love.

 

It’s no secret that coffee is one of my great loves, but it may surprise you to know that I don’t actually drink that much of it. Yes, I do have at least a cup (“a cup”= one container of finite size, not necessarily measuring 8oz) of it a day—sometimes two—but it’s not as though I’m guzzling it constantly or anything. I do think of coffee as a real pleasure, not just for the perkifying aspects of the caffeine it contains, but also the routine of preparing the coffee. The daily ritual. And it tastes darned good, too, provided it’s made right.

From around mid-May until mid-September, 95% of the coffee I drink is iced. While some people like to enjoy a cold beer when the air turns sultry, I prefer to sip on cold coffee (through a straw, please—bendy if at all possible). Sometimes I buy one on the go, but most of the time I make my own. Until recently, I’ve always followed a basic set of instructions: Brew a pot of coffee using double the amount of beans as you would for hot coffee, let cool, and serve over ice (or coffee cubes , if I’m getting fancy).

For the past few years, though, I’ve been hearing a lot of yammering about using a cold-brewing method for making coffee (most notably this New York Times article , Smitten Kitchen’s recipe , and the many accolades for the Toddy system ). I tried it out a couple of times using a pitcher, a jar, and a strainer as depicted on Smitten Kitchen, but I honestly found the whole operation kind of unwieldy and messy…and the end result wasn’t fabulous enough to warrant the effort. So I went back to hot-brewing/cooling.

Enter the Bean Iced Coffee Maker from Bodum , previously seen on my“it list” . I’m a sucker for just about anything Bodum makes (beyond the classic French press everyone has, they also make an awesome toaster and the most practical laundry bag I’ve ever owned), so when I saw that they’d introduced a press specifically geared toward making iced coffee, my curiosity was piqued.

(Four paragraphs in and I haven’t even started the“review”yet. This is why it takes me so long to write posts!)

What, may you ask, makes this new press different from a regular French press for hot coffee? Well, for starters, the size. The largest hot coffee press Bodum makes is 34oz, but the cold-brew press has a 51oz capacity. That’s a pretty huge difference! There are also two lids included—one without a plunger in top so the whole thing can fit nicely in the fridge pre-plunge while the coffee is brewing. Both lids make an airtight seal so the cold coffee will keep fresh for days (no, really, it does!). And it looks cute, which is always nice.

Let’s get to the important part now: HOW DOES THE COFFEE TASTE? Friends, cold-brewed coffee, when done right, tastes awesome . Strong without being bitter, rich and full and caramel-y and with no aftertaste whatsoever. It’s like what you always imagine coffee is going to taste like with none of the disappointment.

The only real con when it comes to cold-brewing is that it does have to be done in advance. The grinds have to sit for at least 12 hours before pressing (we wait a full 24 hours because that works with our schedule—we usually only have coffee at home in the mornings), so it’s not like you can whip up a pitcher of coffee on a whim. Granted, you do wind up with several days’worth of coffee at the end of the process, but it’s something to keep in mind. Also, I’ve never found washing French presses to be much fun…but it’s not so bad if it isn’t every morning.

I should also note that the coffee that cold-brewing produces is, at least in theory, concentrated. You can, therefore, be able to add water to it in your glass to create a beverage of exactly the strength you like. The reason I say“in theory”, though, is that apparently Evan and I are deranged freaks because we just drink the concentrate straight up—or at least straight up with some ice cubes and soy creamer. What can I say, we like strong coffee.

I can’t say that I’m likely to use cold-brewing as a substitute for regular drip coffee during colder months (I’m happy with my Cuisinart , and the thought of having to reheat cold coffee in the morning—before having consumed said coffee—is just too much for me to comprehend), but for iced coffee it really is a no-brainer.

And on that note, I’m heading off for the fridge now to pour myself a glass. Fortunately, we have a whole box of bendy straws on-hand.

 

 Here’s the method I use for cold-brewing in my Bodum press : 

• Measure 12 level scoops (scoop included) of medium/course-ground coffee into the pitcher
• Fill pitcher halfway with filtered water; stir until saturated using a wooden spoon
• Fill pitcher to 1/2″from the top, put lid on
• Stick in fridge for 12-24 hours; press

That’s it!
 91 comments Leave a comment 
 Lara June 24, 2011 8:32 am 
 
Thanks for the review! Your recipe doesn’t seem nearly as strong as the NYT’s, which calls for 1 pound of coffee for 10 cups of water–a pretty pricey experiment and also maybe why you like yours straight. I’ve been trying it with almond milk lately, pretty tasty!

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 9:04 am
 

I’m actually considering doing a test-run with more coffee in the mix to see if I can get it to the point of being TOO strong so we’d have to dilute it. It would be great if I could get one pitcher of coffee to last us the whole work-week!
 Katie June 24, 2011 8:32 am 
 
Ok, you’ve got me craving iced coffee at 10.30pm in winter (I’m in Australia). Haha! I really need to try cold pressed coffee ASAP! I keep hearing how wonderful it is.Oh and I hear ya about the bendy straws!

[ Reply ]
 Krysta June 24, 2011 8:43 am 
 
Great review! I have only just begun making my own coffee in the mornings at all, and have never even attempted to make iced coffee, but this sounds easy and delicious.

Is there a type of coffee/bean that you highly recommend?

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 8:51 am
 

I’m kind of all over the place lately with different kinds of coffee. For years we were Illy devotees, but we’ve been branching out and trying stuff from smaller, localized roasters. My most recent infatuation is the Cowboy Blend from Ristretto Roasters in Portland . My friend Jen sent me a bag, I think it might be the best coffee I’ve had in my life! (A bit inconvenient for a New Yorker, though.)

Depending on where in the country you live, I’d suggest asking coffee-drinking friends if there are any local roasters that they really like! If you have an independent shop that you frequent, there’s a good chance they sell their beans, too.
 Sarah @ Knit York City June 24, 2011 8:57 am 
 
What a great review! I haven’t been able to find a cold-brew system that’s as affordable as the Bodum one so I’m definitely going to consider it. Now I just need to convince myself that having an electric kettle, Aero Press, and espresso machine are more than enough beverage appliances for two people that generally only drink coffee at home on the weekends so I don’t go out and buy this right now.

I mean, I have a ton of adorable Ikea bendy straws, so it’s super tempting!

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 9:18 am
 

A few years ago IKEA had black bendy straws!!! I wish I’d stocked up, because they were way more stylish than the standard-issue white/striped ones I have now.
 Alex June 24, 2011 8:58 am 
 
Ooh that looks interesting. I’ve never got on with French presses at all, I use a stovetop la Moka (a Bialetti caffettiera). I blame my Italian mother for indoctrination into strong espresso at an early age. I like the ritual of it’s preparation and how easy it is to clean. Plus I like the finer grind of an espresso coffee like Lavazza or Union Coffee. But I am intrigued by the cold coffee press…I wonder if they do it in the UK? Thanks Anna!

[ Reply ]
 Liz / Jun 24, 2011 / 12:17 pm
 

I’ve seen it on their uk website–[...]–and plan to order one next week!
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 12:27 pm
 

Liz, there was a link in your comment to an article about the Daily Mail—I assume it was an accident, so I removed it. ;)
 Liz / Jun 24, 2011 / 4:49 am
 

Yes, thank you. I was having a useless day and must have got confused. This is the link I meant to post (and thank you again for correcting my error).

 http://www.bodum.com/gb/en-us/shop/detail/K11081-01/ 

(I double checked this so it if some random Guardian link I’m abandoning the internet as I’m clearly not intelligent enough to use it.)
 Shelley June 24, 2011 9:04 am 
 
Hi Anna. I appreciate your blog and it’s wide variety of posts.
I love my bodum coffee and do drink it hot all summer long. But I do generally use any left overs for cold coffee the next day. Then I never feel that I’m wasting any as good coffee is not throw away cheap.

Do you use a regular bodum french press at all for hot coffee?? If so you might be interested in a little sweater I make to keep your second cup piping hot…..you can check it out here: http://www.etsy.com/people/feltneeds 

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 9:07 am
 

Shelley, no, I don’t like to use a French press for hot coffee. I find cleaning a French press too cumbersome to deal with on a daily basis. I’m very happy with our Cuisinart drip machine during the cooler months. It takes far less preparatory effort on the part of the un-caffeinated. :)
 Shelley / Jun 24, 2011 / 9:19 am
 

I have gotten over the ick factor of cleaning the bodum. All the grinds go in the garden and account for some pretty nice blossoms right about now. But, I hear you about cleaning. Though, I just can’t help myself…every time I see a naked bodum, I want to put a sweater on it.
 Kathy June 24, 2011 9:31 am 
 
I have been waiting for this post since you mentioned writing it on twitter! Sounds so good that we may just have to go out and buy the cold-press! Thanks for breaking it down so nicely!

[ Reply ]
 Amy June 24, 2011 9:44 am 
 
I bought this in green because I saw it on your list a while back. I agree it makes the best iced coffee I’ve ever had. My partner and I think it almost tastes like chocolate milk when you add half and half. We also don’t water ours down. The only problem I had was trying to figure out how to get the lid on and off but I finally got the hang of it. It was worth every penny.

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 9:58 am
 

Amy, my tweets about the lid (back when I first bought the press) were pretty funny!! I just COULD NOT get the lid off (I was struggling for hours), and I thought I was going to have to return the press!! And then I found out that you have to do do a 1/4-turn to the left because there are little tabs that fit through slots inside. OOPS. Haha. Fortunately now that I know how to do it, it’s easy. I just wish there were instructions on the box explaining how to get the lid off, because BOY was it a struggle. :D
 Amy / Jun 24, 2011 / 10:19 am
 

The instructions are lacking, to say the least. It also helps to have the plunger up. I was sure I would break it.
 Cara / Jun 24, 2011 / 1:08 pm
 

THANK YOU for this post. I have been struggling with mine for 20 minutes when my six year old walks in and asks what is wrong. I tell her I can’t figure out how to get the lid off!! Her reply…?“Google it!”BLESS YOU!! And dang that quarter turn and lack of instructions!! LOL! Thanks for the boost. I’m on my way to happy iced coffee drinking!
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 1:13 pm
 

HAH! Oh, Cara—I was sooooooo in that exact same position when I got mine. I was ready to take hammer to it!! Your six-year-old is smart. :D
 Jenny N. June 24, 2011 9:54 am 
 
12-24 hours?! I’m not sure I can do that because one of the things I love most about my mornings is the sound of grinding coffee (then the smell!) and the spoon clinking against the coffee cup when stirring in sugar. It’s one of those meditative things that’s enjoyable before work. But, now you got me in the mood for some iced coffee. So I may stick some ice cubes in tomorrow morning’s cup. :)

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 9:59 am
 

Yeah, the downside with cold-brew is that you don’t get the smell. The TASTE is worth it, though. It’s completely different!
 Miss A June 24, 2011 10:03 am 
 
Why you gotta make me want iced coffee this bad! I just feel like throwing out the entire pot of hot coffee I just brewed!

[ Reply ]
 karen anne June 24, 2011 10:19 am 
 
I’ve been going through toasters trying to find one that really toasts well–and evenly! You mentioned the Bodum toaster and I love the way they look and the great colors–but do you think it is the toaster I’ve been searching for??? Are you happy with yours? Thanks!

p.s. Iced coffee to sip on the porch in honor of my southern grandma is a MUST–she always had to have her iced coffee with copious amounts of heavy cream and sugar! We just finished our porch so I’ve been thinking about her a lot lately- http://studioatlillehus.blogspot.com/2011/06/94-let-summer-begin.html 

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 10:31 am
 

We are definitely happy with the Bodum toaster! I take toast seriously, so I understand concerns about evenness and such. :)

I will say, though, that it’s not my perfect toaster. That would be the Dualit. We have one at the house (purchased with wedding gift money years ago), and it’s phenomenal. It doesn’t have a pop-up function, though, and it does require pre-heating…so it’s really best for situations where you’ll be toasting several rounds of bread (if you have guest over, say, or if you’re toasting a couple of bagels) and are able to monitor the toaster to prevent burning.

The Bodum toaster has the convenience factor in place, though—it pops up, it heats up instantly, etc. I can’t speak to its longevity since we’ve only had it for a year and a half, but for“casual”toasting needs, it’s been great. :)
 Anabela June 24, 2011 10:25 am 
 
Oh man, I think I’m sold. I love the idea of having a pot of cold coffee ready to go, and for some reason I rarely have ice cubes around which makes making iced coffee at home a little difficult! I recently got some stainless steel straws that are just perfect for this. Thanks, Anna!

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 10:33 am
 

Stainless steel straws! Neat. I’ll have to look into that. I used to have glass straws that broke (rather horrifyingly, since I didn’t notice there were shards of glass in my drink!!), but I love the idea of a reusable straw that’s more durable.
 Anabela / Jun 24, 2011 / 11:19 am
 

Ahhh! I got mine at West Elm but I’ve seen them on Amazon for pretty cheap (4 for $10). I always felt bad throwing away straws every day, but I love straws! The steel ones get cold in an iced drink or smoothie too, which is pretty refreshing.
 Sarah June 24, 2011 10:33 am 
 
When is saw the bodum’s cold brew press on your It List, I immediately bought it for my boyfriend’s birthday. I started cold brewing coffee two summers ago (like you thanks to Smitten Kitchen’s recipe) and it was always a pain using a coffee filter and strainer method…LOVE the bodum. So I guess the point of my comment is to say thanks for finding it and putting it on your it list.

[ Reply ]
 libby June 24, 2011 10:35 am 
 
i might have to snag one of these. i just made some cold brewed coffee for the first time this week. i used cheap cafe bustelo espresso and strained it—made a big mess in my kitchen, but it was very good. i drink the concentrate straight up, too. as my grandpa said after a great, strong cup of coffee:“let’s paint the house!”

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 10:42 am
 

Grandpa sounds like my kind of guy! :D

p.s. I think Cafe Bustelo coffee is delicious!! And cheap. And the can is cute!
 Amy June 24, 2011 11:30 am 
 
I have the Bean too! I haven’t quite gotten the hang of it yet though (and yes, there was a learning curve with the lid! ha). I need to try again though, because iced coffee is ALL I want to drink in the summer. Maybe I’m not using enough grounds? Or too many? Or my ice cubes tasted funny? I don’t know, but I need to get it down. Having a ready-to-go pot of cold coffee in the fridge just sounds too good.

Also I agree about the concentrate thing- I’ve never diluted it! Just a bit of soymilk or creamer.

[ Reply ]
 katie June 24, 2011 11:45 am 
 
hi hi!
thanks for the info! I actually currently own a toddy and find the results to be lacking. a little too watery for my taste. are these new cold presses from bodum different from any regular french press? i’m curious if its worth the investment if i already own a french press.

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 11:49 am
 

Katie, check paragraph #5 (the one where I actually start the review, hahah…it begins with“What, may you ask…”). I explained the difference there. :)
 katie / Jun 24, 2011 / 1:46 pm
 

Sorry Anna, can I blame my new mommy brain? Thanks a bunch!
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 1:49 pm
 

:D Absolutely, Katie! You can also blame the fact that I rambled on waaaaay longer than I really should have before I got to the important stuff. ;)
 cajeta June 24, 2011 11:59 am 
 
I’ve never had good cold coffee (always tastes weak to me—and weak coffee is worse than no coffee!) so thanks for the review. This might even be a great way to make homemade coffee ice cream!

[ Reply ]
 holly June 24, 2011 12:38 pm 
 
i just got this at my bridal shower! i love it. ive only made one batch so far, i think i needed to put more grounds in because it was a little weak.

[ Reply ]
 Lindsay June 24, 2011 12:40 pm 
 
I recently read this and I’m interested in trying it.

 http://tmagazine.blogs.nytimes.com/2011/06/10/ristretto-on-the-rocks/?ref=dining 

I love the design of the Chemex, though I don’t have one…yet.
This is pretty much how I make hot coffee. I have a ceramic filter and I filter hot water through into a mason jar. I love the ease of clean up. Paper filter goes into the compost and ceramic filter and jar into the dishwasher. Now, I just have to try the method of brewing it over ice. I’ll report back after the weekend!

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 12:51 pm
 

That’s how most people make iced coffee, I think (not necessarily with a Chemex), but the taste is completely different. I personally prefer the flavor of cold-brewed, but double-strength over ice is definitely good if you’re short on time!
 Amy / Jun 24, 2011 / 9:37 pm
 

Thanks for posting that! My current favorite is hot espresso over ice, so maybe this would be more up my alley than cold brew. (Though it’s probably just that I’m doing it wrong!) In any case, I’ll have to try it. And do report back! :)
 mommy June 24, 2011 12:45 pm 
 
Do you think I can convert Bernie who is a coffee lover, but doesn’t like iced coffee? I can’t wait to try this regardless.

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 12:49 pm
 

Oh, just drink it all yourself. :)
 Eva June 24, 2011 12:47 pm 
 
Just wanted to say thanks for turning me on to this awesome press! I bought one (in purple) when you posted the link on twitter a while back and I am in LOVE. A gigantic THANK YOU to you!!

I’ve been throwing in a few extra scoops of coffee so that it doesn’t taste all watery once the ice melts (plus, like you noted, it makes the pot last longer so I’m not making a new one every day).

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 12:52 pm
 

How many scoops are you using, Eva? I do think I want to start making it stronger/diluting to extend the time between brews!
 Eva / Jun 24, 2011 / 3:05 pm
 

I did 16 scoops in my most recent batch and it was good according to my tasters, but if you drink it straight up I would guess you prefer your coffee a little stronger than me so 18 might be better for you!
 Brenda June 24, 2011 1:05 pm 
 
I bought a Toddy last year and am in love with it. I brew one pound of French Roast coffee (coarse ground) at a time and it makes a big batch of“concentrate”. I use it straight up and add a bunch of milk. It tastes like a coffee milk shake to me. Doesn’t need any sugar and is so creamy and yummy. I’ll have to try it with soy milk sometime.

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 1:12 pm
 

I’m glad I’m not the only nut using the concentrate straight! :D
 tallin June 24, 2011 1:51 pm 
 
mmm iced coffee. my blasphemous method is to dissolve a teaspoon of instant coffee with just a splash of hot water and then pour cold water or soy milk over it. classy, i know. but it works well, especially at the office!

and as long as you’re reviewing…can I ask you how you’ve liked your clarisonic brush? i’ve been thinking about getting one for ages!

[ Reply ]
 Liza June 24, 2011 2:25 pm 
 
I have an unrelated question. Well related, but more to your Poketo organizer post than to the cold-brewed coffee. Though they go hand in hand in the mornings. Have you come across a decent, large wall calendar? One that leaves space for making notes? I love the Pentagram typeface one but no space . . . and I feel like you may own a Stendig (sp?) but also no space . . . Sorry for the randomness.

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 2:26 pm
 

I have a Stendig calendar in my apartment kitchen, but I don’t write on it. I’ve never looked for a wall calendar to write on, because I need something that goes with me when I leave—sorry!
 Katherine June 24, 2011 3:08 pm 
 
I’ve been using Toddy for five or six years now and I love it straight up, on the rocks, or with some bovine lactic fluid. I do not dilute it with water. I can’t imagine living in the desert and not drinking the cold-brew.

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 3:11 pm
 

“Bovine lactic fluid”made me crack up, Katherine!! It took me a minute…:D
 Alison June 24, 2011 3:36 pm 
 
Making coffee is such a ritual for me. In fact, I don’t even drink it anymore but still make it every morning for my man. Interesting that you mention this!

[ Reply ]
 kellie June 24, 2011 3:36 pm 
 
I love this post. Especially since I happened to be sitting here drinking my iced coffee with a bendy straw while reading it :)

[ Reply ]
 Martina June 24, 2011 4:45 pm 
 
Iced coffee doesn’t really feature here in Dublin with our weather! With the rain teeming down and a“fresh”12.5 degrees temp outside all I want is a hot cuppa! Just thinking of you as I am watching Morrissey live at Glastonbury (on TV!). Have a great weekend :)

[ Reply ]
 Becca B June 24, 2011 5:49 pm 
 
I didn’t know this existed! I’ve been using my Chemex or stove top espresso maker for all of these years, but have never been able to make a fantastic iced coffee. I can’t wait to find/get on of these, thanks for the review!

[ Reply ]
 Oliver June 24, 2011 7:16 pm 
 
Just ordered an orange one (dutch soccer fan) from Amazon. Can’t wait to try it out. I’d prefer not to know the amount of money I’ve spent on $5 iced coffee drinks from Stumptown every summer.

THX Anna!

[ Reply ]
 alexandra @ work and tumble June 25, 2011 7:53 pm 
 
Any suggestions on the best way to sweeten cold-brewed coffee? I’m sort of suspicious of those Starbucks-y syrups–but would regular granulated sugar dissolve at all? I’m not sure I could handle concentrated coffee without a least a touch of sweet.

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 8:03 pm
 

I find I don’t really need any sugar in cold-brewed coffee because it really has no bitterness whatsoever. Evan does like some sugar in his, and he just uses course raw sugar. No, it doesn’t dissolve completely, but it’s okay. (Sugar substitutes like Splenda dissolve easily, but I gave those up completely almost 2 years ago.)

What you could do, though, is make up a small batch of simple syrup , which will dissolve instantly. You can buy it pre-made, of course, but it’s so easy to make that you may as well do it yourself.
 alexandra @ work and tumble / Jun 24, 2011 / 8:50 pm
 

Great! I didn’t realize simple syrup was just sugar and water! Thanks, Anna.
 kimberly June 25, 2011 10:44 pm 
 
i like iced coffee (pretty much) everyday year-round and recently bought this lovely little invention–best $40 i’ve spent in a while. i love it! my husband and i were admittedly at each other’s throats trying to get the lid off. no marriage has ever ended though over iced coffee (as far as i know…).

i also use these ikea straws (not all black–which i would love–but better than those supermarket striped ones): http://www.ikea.com/us/en/catalog/products/10132458 

[ Reply ]
 Frau Haselmayer June 26, 2011 12:27 am 
 
Your post makes me want to have some iced coffee NOW even though I do not even like coffee at all!

But after reading this including all the comments I really think I could like coffee this way (it’s mostly the bitterness that I dislike). I will defininitely try it!

[ Reply ]
 Pam June 27, 2011 11:08 pm 
 
When you say‘none of the disappointment’could i dare hope to interpret that as‘the coffee will taste like coffee smells instead of like it usually tastes’? I am not a coffee drinker now, just a smeller, for that reason, but your review has me intrigued.

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 11:10 pm
 

Yes! That’s exactly what I mean! The best coffee does indeed taste as good as it smells.
 andrea June 28, 2011 12:58 am 
 
There is a very good coffee place in the town of Hudson called Strongtree, right across from the train station. Fair trade, organic, roast-their-own coffee. If I lived on the Hudson River I think I would get my coffee there. (www.strongtreecoffee.com)

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 6:10 am
 

Thanks, Andrea! I’ll see if they sell through any retailers near us. The town of Hudson is actually almost two hours away from Newburgh.
 Michelle June 28, 2011 5:13 pm 
 
I have been cold brewing in a regular Bodum Press (8 cup Young Press) for a couple of years now&amp;I love it! I was just going to stick with that until you mentioned how big the Bean Press is…I always seem to run out by Friday&amp;can never manage to schedule the next batch accurately. Fast forward to the weekend after your post&amp;I happened upon an orange Bean Press for 50% off at Target! Yea! Now I’m set for coffee thru the weekend.

Lately I’ve been adding the coffee concentrate to a AM banana chocolate smoothie (my homemade version of a $bucks Vivanno). For iced coffee, I’ve been using chocolate hazelnut milk. I also LOVE mixing sweetened condensed milk (1-2 tbsp) w/a big glass of the concentrate for a weekend morning treat. It’s like drinking ice cream.

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 5:36 pm
 

Oooooh, all of that sounds REALLY good!!! Noted. (Also, 50% off at Target? Cool!)
 maggie June 28, 2011 6:08 pm 
 
Ooh. I passed by a coffee shop I’m not usually near while running errands a few weeks ago and decided to go inside and get my usual iced tall Americano. The barista suggested I try their new cold brewed coffee instead. It was so good! But seemed pretty strong to me. In any case, I’ve been meaning to try it at home. Love the idea of having a week’s worth in the fridge. I usually rely on either purchased coffee or the bad office coffee on weekdays because I’m always running late.

[ Reply ]
 Pablo June 30, 2011 5:32 am 
 
I’m also a coffee lover!! =D

[ Reply ]
 Mae July 1, 2011 3:44 pm 
 
Ok, you got me. I’m entertaining the thought of buying one lol.

[ Reply ]
 jja July 3, 2011 1:34 pm 
 
I love this posting! I love coffee, and Bodum too, so I guess I really have to try this. Ice coffe during the summer is great, we just have to get some summer in germany.
I also adore strong coffee, actually start my morning only with one espresso and one more in the afternoon.

[ Reply ]
 Stephanie July 3, 2011 4:32 pm 
 
I bought a cheap french press from IKEA and I think I’m going to attempt to make this cold brew in it today! Otherwise I’ve hardly used it, my boyfriend makes a pot in the morning with our trusty ol’Mr.Coffee machine. It sounds so good though with a little cream and simple syrup to sweeten it up…

[ Reply ]
 Sophia July 5, 2011 9:06 am 
 
thank you for this post! i’ve been looking for a good way to make delicious iced coffee (coffee=my favorite ritual of the day, totally), so I may give this a try. Just wondering–can you tell me what you do to get photographs like the one of the coffee? If I’ve miss your explanation somewhere, sorry–but I do love all your photographs and have been playing around with my camera to try to get similar results…with zero luck…thanks!

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 9:54 am
 

I don’t really do anything special when I take photos, I don’t think! I have a very basic point&amp;shoot camera (it’s a Panasonic Lumix, about 3 years old). I think the key is really just to make sure the lighting is good. I do have a very heavy hand when it comes to post-camera work, though, and I will do any number of things in Photoshop to achieve the look I want—whether it’s just simple retouching or altering the color and tones completely. Lately I’ve been pulling the white levels down a lot to make the images look a little“flatter”. All of this is mostly the disguise the fact that I’m not very good at the actual photography part of taking photographs. ;)

Of course, all of this is separate from the Instagram photos that I take with my iPhone. I don’t do anything to those images—there are snazzy filters built in to the app, and I just let them do their thing.
 Sophia / Jun 24, 2011 / 10:23 am
 

thanks! i’ve heard about adjusting white levels so I may give that a shot…:)
 Layla July 5, 2011 1:40 pm 
 
Ahh! I’m de-lurking to tell you how wonderful this review was–I will definitely be buying this soon. Also wanted to mention that Crate&amp;Barrel, of all places, has the iced coffee press for $29.95…best deal I’vee seen! But sadly only in off-white, and I’m still daydreaming about the green one. Oh well. Thought I’d at least pass the deal on to your lovely readership.

 http://www.crateandbarrel.com/kitchen-and-food/coffee-makers/bodum-iced-coffee-press/s165738 

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 1:54 pm
 

I considered buying white, but I was worried it would get coffee stains!
 gbl July 17, 2011 1:39 pm 
 
Really, all the Bodum coffee presses are cold-coffee presses. By the time the coffee sits in the Bodum coffee press for the recommended three to four minutes, it is cold.

Add“sludgy”

Cold sludgy coffee. It takes some marketing to push that on people, but somehow, Bodum has succeeded.

Your kidney’s don’t thank you.

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 1:59 pm
 

I have not had any problems with my Bodum cold press producing anything remotely“sludgy”. Have you actually used one?

And are you making a case against coffee completely with that comment about“kidney’s”[sic]? That reminds me of the Groucho Marx joke about small portions of terrible food—sounds like you’re out for defeat, however you can get it.
 Kari July 19, 2011 7:39 pm 
 
Just received my Orange Bean in the mail and can’t wait to enjoy some ice cold coffee tomorrow morning (although I should probably wait until Thursday.) Just trying to decide how many scoops…leaning toward 16 right now.

[ Reply ]
 Katie July 24, 2011 8:50 pm 
 
Hi,

I know I’m posting this comment quite a bit after you originally posted this but I recently bought the Bodum cold press when I realized how much money I was spending buying iced coffee…but I have a stupid question…after you brew and press the coffee do you leave the pitcher in the fridge with the grounds at the bottom for the next few days while you are finishing off the rest of the coffee? Does it keep okay?

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 8:07 am
 

Hi Katie, yes, iced coffee will keep in the fridge for at least a week as long as it’s kept in an airtight container (like this press!).
 Jennie August 2, 2011 12:39 pm 
 
Well, I am sure glad I came back and re-read this post! After all of the rave reviews, I was so excited to use my cold coffee press (I LOOOOVE iced coffee). I was then wondering why it was so weak and bitter…I’ve been using only 6 scoops of coffee! My mind translated ounces to cups when I read the directions. *sigh* Now, I can’t wait to do it the CORRECT way!

Have you had any issues with the press lid leaking when you pour? Mine dribbles and I wonder if I just don’t have it on right.

I swear, I’m not normally this incompetent.

[ Reply ]
 Anna @ D16 / Jun 24, 2011 / 12:51 pm
 

Hah! Oh dear, yes, 6 scoops is definitely NOT enough. Once you try it with double that amount, I promise you’ll be in iced coffee heaven. :)

And no, I haven’t had any issues with leaking/dribbling. In fact, my husband was just commenting the other day on how drip-proof the lid is! You do have to make sure everything is aligned, though. There are little tabs on the side of the lid that fit into slots in the top of the vessel, and then twist into a channel (clockwise). The pour spout should be centered in the middle of a curve on the front of the vessel when everything is correctly twisted into place, and there shouldn’t be any gaps around the edges. Aside from being less messy, you want to make sure you have an airtight seal!
 Jennie / Jun 24, 2011 / 2:08 pm
 

Yep, 12 scoops made all the difference! Delicious!

Also, I found a nick in my rubber seal. I guess I’ll have to send it back for an exchange…or move the nick to the back of the lid so it can’t leak, since I’m not sure if I can part with this now.
 Lindsay Széchényi August 4, 2011 7:12 pm 
 
YUM! I’ve been using a regular Bodum french press to brew iced coffee since you mentioned it on Twitter a while back. I accidentally knocked it over and broke it though a few weeks ago :( so I’ve been torturing myself since then (no iced coffee for me) and now I’m REALLY looking forward to getting the Bean :) Thanks for the review.

[ Reply ]
 jay September 28, 2011 8:45 am 
 
i like iced coffee,Ah, cold brewed coffee! It’s my summer staple. I make it in a homemade contraption, and keep in the fridge for days in a sealed container. No change in flavour at all! My contraption is 2 huge plastic cups that fit inside of each other (mine are the supersize cups from a fast food restaurant). Poke holes in the bottom of one of the cups with a push pin, so the bottom of the cup is perforated like an asterisk. Nest it in the other cup. Put the grounds&amp;water in the inside cup, steep, and elevate the inside cup over the outside cup (I use a piece of cardboard with a hole cut out, and drain.

[ Reply ]
 Dennis March 11, 2012 10:27 pm 
 
I just picked this up as I had busted my other bodum press, and drink my coffee cold all the time. Especially being im in Tampa, but even when I was in Connecticut I wouldnt drink it hot unless it was that windy kind of cold which is just terrible. I wanted to say thanks because the instructions leave much to be desired lol. I wasn’t entirely sure what“overnight”meant since usually warm brewing with a press it’s important to know the amount of time to brew. I tossed some coffee into it tonight and will get to see what this thing can do. Btw I couldnt get that top open either lol. Even after twisting it the thing wasnt coming off without a fight.

[ Reply ]
 Tiffanie March 22, 2012 10:59 pm 
 
Perfect timing for me. My husband is a hand-drip fanatic, we’ve got so much gear here we could BE a Blue Bottle outlet. I miss the days when I could easily have a cup of coffee at the ready, ESPECIALLY an iced coffee, which I definitely only crave on the rare warm days here. We will have exactly 2 1/2 warm days in May, I will be sure to get this contraption by then and try your method of preparation first. Do update if you find a way to stretch it a week (so sacrilegious in this house, but sounds so nice to make it once and have it around, a luxury, really). Thanks for the kick in the pants on this, I’ve been meaning to figure this one out. :)

[ Reply ]
 
 Your comment 
 

 

 
 Comment 

 
 
 Click to cancel reply 
 Door Sixteen is a hate-free, drama-free, spam-free, ad-free zone.
Wanna be startin&apos; somethin&apos;? Beat it. 
 Want a little picture to show up next to your comments? Go get a Gravatar ! 
 
Here
 
 About Me My Instagrams FAQ RSS Feed 
 
There
 
 Twitter Facebook I Design Stuff 
 
Archives By Month
 Select Month June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 June 2007 
Archives By Category
 
 Art + Design Blogs + Tweets Food + Drink Four Legs Friends + Family Go Ask Anna Greed Handmade Health Inspiration Music + Movies + Books Nerdstalgia New York City Newburgh Scavenged The Apartment / Brooklyn The Apartment / Manhattan The House / Newburgh To-Do Vanity + Wearables Work 
 
 

 

 
 ©2007–2011 Anna Dorfman. All Rights Reserved. 
 All photographs, written content and design are the sole property of the site owner unless otherwise indicated.
 Content may not be added to Facebook, Tumblr, Pinterest or any other social networking sites without permission. 
Please see the FAQ page for additional information.
	</body>
</document>
