<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000392" url="http://www.menuism.com/restaurants/kfc-kentucky-fried-chicken-columbia-325415" time="2012-07-12-15:38" support="13" score="0.02379760109590485" bingtitle="KFC - Kentucky Fried Chicken - Reviews &amp; Menu - 7351 Garners Ferry ..." webtitle="KFC - Kentucky Fried Chicken - Reviews&amp;Menu - 7351 Garners Ferry Rd, Columbia 29209">
			<query id="001040" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000561" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="000915" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000221" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="000538" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="001481" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000910" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="001476" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000226" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000852" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000284" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="001035" bing-rank="91"/>
	<description>Had to wait for another person to order and pay to get my change. Watched the new trainee make my order ... I have never been treated more poorly by any fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Menuism - Restaurant and dish reviews 
 Explore Restaurant Reviews&amp;Menus 
 Restaurants Near Me Make Online Reservations Order Delivery&amp;Takeout Restaurant Week Directory Popular Cities Popular Chains What&apos;s Menu ism ? Monthly Review Contest 
 Remember Personal Dining Journal 
 My Favorites My Try List My Photos Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 
 Learn Foodie Education Blog 
 Food Primers Exclusive Interviews 
 
 FIND AROUND GO 
 Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 

 Not a member? To save, rate, and share reviews, sign up! Already a member? Log in (OpenID) Connect with Facebook 
 
 larger map / directions 

 KFC - Kentucky Fried Chicken Menu 

 KFC - Kentucky Fried Chicken Locations 
 
 - Pages - The Restaurant Map/Directions Dishes/Menu Images 
 Columbia Restaurants » American » KFC - Kentucky Fried Chicken Share | 
KFC - Kentucky Fried Chicken
 
 1.0 star rating           
  1.0 rating over 2 reviews 
 (803) 783-1219 

 7351 Garners Ferry Rd ( ) 

 Columbia , SC 29209 

 View Nearby Businesses» 
 Send to Phone Email Listing Print Listing   
 View Menu Website Read Reviews (2) View Map/Directions 
 
 Information From the Restaurant Offers 
 
 Description:  KFC - Kentucky Fried Chicken is a American and Chicken restaurant where most Menuism users came for a family meal and paid between $25 and $50 . Tags: American, Chicken, Cheap Eats, Family Style, Kid Friendly, Delivery, and Good For Kids Stats: 
 192 dishes entered by diners at KFC - Kentucky Fried Chicken 
 Tips: 
 Call ahead to place your picnic orders and you&apos;ll avoid the inevitable weekend wait time. 
 
 
Nothing yet.
 
 Do you own KFC - Kentucky Fried Chicken? Contact us to connect with your diners. 
 
 Suggest Corrections/Menu 
 
Reviews for KFC - Kentucky Fried Chicken
 Write a review 
 2 reviews First reviewed by akjustice2219 
 
 1 helpful votes over 1 review 
 akjustice2219 
 1 Restaurant Review +1 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 KFC - Kentucky Fried Chicken akjustice2219 
 October 28, 2010 
 1.0 
 1.0 star rating           
 +1 0 +1 1 Votes   
Two Strikes, Three? You&apos;re out.‎ - ‎ -...
 
Two Strikes, Three? You’re out.‎–‎–2010-10-28
I had been to this location and had a terrible experience and called with my complaint. Manager Elaine talked to me and invited me back to have dinner on her. I decided one evening to go back and Elaine was not there. So instead of trying to talk to another about her offer of a free meal, I ordered and paid. From the start it was a disaster. Closed the register before giving me my change. Had to wait for another person to order and pay to get my change. Watched the new trainee make my order which was not what I had ordered. The order was up on the monitor, and instead of the manager on duty supervising his staff, he was having Pizza delivered in to him behind the counter. (Should have been an indication to me that the food would be bad, if their own people will not eat there) Well, I spoke up when my order was packed and said, I think you made the wrong stuff. Another person then looked over the order and at the actual meal, and yep, it was wrong. She said“Oh well just make him two more of the smaller sandwiches and he can have four of those instead of the larger one”. I said, I just wanted what I ordered. Well, then a cook from behind the line talking to the girl that delivered the Pizza to the manager on duty says,“Yes, let’s get this man’s order scraight! We need to make his order right!”, and started behind the line still talking to the other,“Let’s get this man’s order right, now!”Well, this was condisending to me and I spoke up, Did he think this was a joke, was it funny. (Still no Manager on duty, must have been busy with that Pizza). Finally the manager on duty come up and says,“We do make mistakes sir!”Well this is the second time they made a mistake on me, and after I was invited back my the store manager Elaine, it was just as bad or worse as the time I complained before. Finally received my food, but during all the time I had been waiting, still no one offered me a drink, or anything to calm me down from confronting my wrong order and having to wait again for the food to be prepared. The previous time, the Store Manger Elaine told me that they all know they should ask if I’d like something to drink while I wait. I left my business card and asked that the store manager Elaine call me. The next day, I waited all day and decided to call the store myself. I asked for Elaine and then asked if my card had even been given to her. At least the card was passed along in her message book, but she stated she was busy all day and did not have the chance to look at her messages listed in the book. We talked again about the poor experience I had and she appoligized. She asked me to come back and see her when she on duty. I told her No! The quality should be the same whether she’s there or not. So, now I have to see whose working to get good service and good food! I think not. We I ate my Honey Bar-B-Q sandwich, it was dry, too strong on the sauce, and it was like the product had been on the steam line for the whole day. Not Good. I will not give them my money for a third time to be disappointed again.

By the way, the survey on the back of the reciept will not allow you to call in from the same number more than one time in six weeks or so. So when I tried to call that number to complain, it kicked me out of the system, and did not take my complaint. Now that’s good customer service, I was upset and should have been able to leave my comments even though they did not want me to enter their giveaway again. I also went online and left my complaint for the customer service survey online and asked that I be contacted. Never got contacted. KFC should change their slogan, instead of :&quot;So G-double O-G good! It should be:“So try us till we get it right! sucker!”

I cannot believe the franchise owners and such are not concerned enough to make sure their restaurants are operating with quality and standards. I hope one of them will call me to answer my complaint.
 
Dishes I tried:
 
HONEY BBQ SANDWICH
 
 1.0 star rating           
 
I had been to this location and had a terrible experience and called with my complaint. Manager Elaine talked to me and invited me back to have dinner on her. I decided one evening to go back and Elaine was not there. So instead of trying to talk to another about her offer of a free meal, I ordered and paid. From the start it was a disaster. Closed the register before giving me my change. Had to wait for another person to order and pay to get my change. Watched the new trainee make my order which was not what I had ordered. The order was up on the monitor, and instead of the manager on duty supervising his staff, he was having Pizza delivered in to him behind the counter. (Should have been an indication to me that the food would be bad, if their own people will not eat there) Well, I spoke up when my order was packed and said, I think you made the wrong stuff. Another person then looked over the order and at the actual meal, and yep, it was wrong. She said“Oh well just make him two more of the smaller sandwiches and he can have four of those instead of the larger one”. I said, I just wanted what I ordered. Well, then a cook from behind the line talking to the girl that delivered the Pizza to the manager on duty says,“Yes, let’s get this man’s order scraight! We need to make his order right!”, and started behind the line still talking to the other,“Let’s get this man’s order right, now!”Well, this was condisending to me and I spoke up, Did he think this was a joke, was it funny. (Still no Manager on duty, must have been busy with that Pizza). Finally the manager on duty come up and says,“We do make mistakes sir!”Well this is the second time they made a mistake on me, and after I was invited back my the store manager Elaine, it was just as bad or worse as the time I complained before. Finally received my food, but during all the time I had been waiting, still no one offered me a drink, or anything to calm me down from confronting my wrong order and having to wait again for the food to be prepared. The previous time, the Store Manger Elaine told me that they all know they should ask if I’d like something to drink while I wait. I left my business card and asked that the store manager Elaine call me. The next day, I waited all day and decided to call the store myself. I asked for Elaine and then asked if my card had even been given to her. At least the card was passed along in her message book, but she stated she was busy all day and did not have the chance to look at her messages listed in the book. We talked again about the poor experience I had and she appoligized. She asked me to come back and see her when she on duty. I told her No! The quality should be the same whether she’s there or not. So, now I have to see whose working to get good service and good food! I think not. We I ate my Honey Bar-B-Q sandwich, it was dry, too strong on the sauce, and it was like the product had been on the steam line for the whole day. Not Good. I will not give them my money for a third time to be disappointed again.

By the way, the survey on the back of the reciept will not allow you to call in from the same number more than one time in six weeks or so. So when I tried to call that number to complain, it kicked me out of the system, and did not take my complaint. Now that’s good customer service, I was upset and should have been able to leave my comments even though they did not want me to enter their giveaway again. I also went online and left my complaint for the customer service survey online and asked that I be contacted. Never got contacted. KFC should change their slogan, instead of :&quot;So G-double O-G good! It should be:“So try us till we get it right! sucker!”

I cannot believe the franchise owners and such are not concerned enough to make sure their restaurants are operating with quality and standards. I hope one of them will call me to answer my complaint.
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply Samantha S 
 from Insider Pages 
 
September 24, 2009
 
 1 star rating           
 
KFC on Garners Ferry
 
I have never been treated more poorly by any fast food restaurant. It&apos;s somewhat hard to believe that one can have such a horrible experience in such a short amount of time. We were annoyed before we even made it to the drive thru line…

 read full review» 
 Read 1 reviews on Citysearch» 
Best Dishes at KFC - Kentucky Fried Chicken

These dishes from the KFC - Kentucky Fried Chicken menu are contributed by Menuism users directly, 
 as part of a restaurant review, or as part of an image upload.
 
MASHED POTATO BOWL
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
23. 10Pc. Family Meal (legs and thighs)
 
 5.0 star rating           
 
10 PC (Feeds 5)
 
 4.0 star rating           
 View all dishes 
 Title Max Comfort Inn&amp;Suites Ft.Jackson Maingate La Quinta Inn Columbia - Maingate/Ft. Jackson Holiday Inn Express Hotel&amp;Suites Columbia-Fort Jackson Lowe&apos;s Lowe&apos;s Quality Inn&amp;Suites Ft. Jackson Maingate Country Inn&amp;Suites Columbia Sleep Inn Near Ft. Jackson Greenlawn Memorial Park&amp;Funeral Home 
 KFC - Kentucky Fried Chicken is located near the cities of West Columbia, Forest Acres, Cayce, Steubenville, and Oak Grove. People found this by searching for: Dead Girl Found On Garners Ferry Rd, Kentucky Fried Chicken Menu Columbia Sc, Talktokfc Survey, What Are Kfc&apos;s Service Ratings On Garners Ferry, Talk To Kfc Survey, Kfc Menu Price On Garner Ferry Rd In Columbia Sc, What Time Does Kfc Close In Columbia, and Columbia Sc Kentucky Fried Chicken Franchises. Write a Review Add to Try List Add to Favorites Suggest Corrections Upload Pics 
Featured in Columbia
 
 4.0 star rating           
 Longhorn Steakhouse 
 5.0 star rating           
 Hampton Street Vineyard 
 5.0 star rating           
 Yamato Japanese Steak House 
 4.16667 star rating           
 Longhorn Steakhouse 
 5.0 star rating           
 Big T Bar-BQ 
 4.0 star rating           
 The Pizza Palace Restaurant 
 3.5 star rating           
 FATZ 
 5.0 star rating           
 Travinia Italian Kitchen Northeast 
 5.0 star rating           
 Carolina Deli 
 5.0 star rating           
 Pearlz Oyster Bar 
 Upload Pics Photos
 
 See All 50 
 
Nearby Restaurants
 Pizza Hut Somethin Fishy Somethin Fishy Incorporated Thaikingdom Cafe Sebi 
Link to KFC - Kentucky Fried Chicken
 
Copy the link below and paste onto your website or blog to display badge.

 Copy 
 
 Follow Menuism around the web Find us on Facebook Follow us on Twitter Find us on Google+ 
 
 Learn More
 Advertise About
Advertise
FAQ
Privacy
Terms of Use 
 Take Action
 Link to Menuism / Badges and Widgets 
 Browse
 Restaurant Week Restaurant Locations Popular Cities Sitemap 
 
 ©2006 - 2012 Delta Beans, LLC
 Contact Menuism 

Some Images and Data provided by Citysearch .
	</body>
</document>
