<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000294" url="http://whatwasthatone.livejournal.com/4422582.html" time="2012-07-12-15:29" support="2" score="0.002889738256287626" bingtitle="whatwasthatone: Con artist show - What was that one?!" webtitle="whatwasthatone: Con artist show">
			<query id="001220" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="001216" bing-rank="79"/>
	<description>... is him digging through a fast-food restaurant&apos;s trash can for a receipt and bringing it back in and telling the guy behind the counter ... I keep wondering if there was ...</description>
	<body>
		Upload a Userpic 
 Home Create an account Explore 
 Search by Interest Search by School Ratings Community Directory Feeds Question of the Day FRNK Radio 
 Shop 
 Gift Paid Account Virtual Gifts Domains RF Merchandise 
 LJ Extras 
 Mobile LJ Talk Downloads 
 
 
 Mogwai_toejam ( akktri ) wrote in whatwasthatone ,
 2011 - 06 - 09 18:38:00 
 
 Previous Memorize Share Next 
 
Con artist show
 There was a reality show where a guy hired a special effects crew in order to fake stuff and get free things from businesses.
It was weird. I can&apos;t remember what it was called.
He&apos;d get free meals and free services by faking stuff like bad service, pest control problems, etc.
On the whole he spent more than he really got out of it, but what was the title of that show? 
 
 Post a new comment 
Error



Anonymous comments are disabled in this journal
 
 We will log you in after post We will log you in after post We will log you in after post We will log you in after post We will log you in after post Anonymously 
 switch 
 LiveJournal Facebook Twitter OpenId Google MailRu VKontakte Anonymously 
 
 Insert Bold Insert Italic Insert Underline Insert Strikethrough Insert Link Insert LJ User 

 Insert Photo Insert Video 

 Spell check 
 
Your reply will be screened

Your IP address will be recorded  
 Post a new comment   Help 4 comments 
 
 Post a new comment 4 comments 
 
 
About

 Contact Advertise Jobs Site News More... 
 
Help

 Support / FAQs Safety Tips 

Get Involved

 Volunteer Developers 
 
Legal

 Terms of Service Privacy Policy Copyright Abuse Policy 

LJ Labs

 LJ Aqua More... 
 
Store

 Upgrade Account Virtual Gifts Merchandise More... 
 
 Change language: English English (UK) Deutsch Dansk español Français Italiano Русский Українська Беларуская 日本語 Português Esperanto עברית Nederlands Magyar Gaeilge íslenska suomi Ελληνικά Norsk bokmål Svenska polski 简体中文 Latviešu Türkçe Bahasa Melayu हिन्दी Português Brasileiro 繁體中文 Lietuvių Norsk nynorsk 
 Current version : v.93.6 
 »View Full Sitemap 
 
 Copyright©1999 LiveJournal, Inc. All rights reserved. 
 Username: Create an Account 
 Forgot your login or password? 
 
 OpenID Google Mail.Ru VKontakte 
 Password: Remember Me English•Español•Deutsch•Русский…
	</body>
</document>
