<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000697" url="http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/755417" time="2012-07-12-15:59" support="1" score="0.002517555673600914" bingtitle="2010: Your year in food - General Chowhounding Topics - Chowhound" webtitle="2010: Your year in food - General Topics - Chowhound">
			<query id="000315" bing-rank="71"/>
	<description>So I guess my food highlight for 2010 was that I know ... nondescript animal protein on a Styrofoam tray. ... * Only ate at one fast food restaurant this year and it was during a ...</description>
	<body>
		Log in / Sign Up Entire Site 
 Entire Site Chowhound Recipes Stories Video 
 CHOW 
 Follow @CHOW videos 
 All Videos Supertaster CHOW Tips You&apos;re Doing It All Wrong My Go-To Obsessives The Easiest Way 
 recipes 
 All Recipes Quick&amp;Easy Fun DIY Projects Main Dishes Sweets Recipe Slideshows 
 Blogs 
 CHOW Daily Best of Chowhound 
 chowhound discussions 
 All Boards Home Cooking Manhattan San Francisco Bay Area Los Angeles Area Philadelphia Greater Boston Area Southern New England Ontario (including Toronto) B.C. (including Vancouver) 
 
 HOME &gt; Chowhound &gt; General Topics Save This Board &gt; 
 Email Print 
 
2010: Your year in food
 
What was new and noteworthy for you foodwise this year? For me...

My first banh mi:
 http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/638293#5516227 

Ice cream at Robb&apos;s Farm (Glastonbury, CT)--goat tracks and dirty barn shoes!
 http://sites.google.com/site/robbsfarm2/ 

Picking cherries for the first time and making tipsy cherries:
 http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/736115#5936602 

The lavender martini (yes, cocktail, not a real martini, got it)--killer on an especially hot summer day at Esca (Middletown, CT) and fun to replicate at home

Finding a new favorite farm stand - Berruti&apos;s (G&apos;bury, CT) - where I couldn&apos;t get enough of Montauk corn, native cauliflower, lettuce and tomatoes, white peaches, Mutsu apples, and I looked forward to swapping recipe ideas with&quot;my farm stand guy&quot;...now they&apos;re selling Christmas trees. I miss them already...

Making new gelato recipes--my two favorites were pignoli cookie and chocolate

Cevapi--it was new on me!
 http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/731587#5884080 

Discovering fantastic pizza in freakin&apos; Sheboygan, Wisconsin of all places! Ever have bresaola on a pizza? A M A Z I N G! I flew to what (to me) felt like the middle of nowhere, and found myself working within walking distance of so many great restaurants, it was a good thing I did a lot of walking getting to and from all of that food! YOU ROCK, STEFANO! Second video on the left explains what makes it sooooooooooooooooooo special.
 http://www.ilritrovopizza.com/video.html 

EVERYTHING I ate at Margaux (Sheboygan, WI):
 http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/397288?tag=main_body;topic-397288 

Beer, butter &apos;n onion brats from Miesfeld&apos;s (Sheboygan, WI):
 http://www.miesfelds.com/ 

Buffalo roasted cauliflower!
 http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/6928... 

Duck and beef bresaola appetizer on my b&apos;day at Luce, my favorite hometown restaurant

Starting a food blog and finally making the top 9 on Foodbuzz (just this month!)!

How about you?
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By kattyeyes on Dec 23, 2010 06:54 PM 
Updated on Jan 4, 2011

 32 Replies 
 
 
Hmm, let&apos;s see.

Dining-wise:

o I had Ethiopian food for the first time and it was one of the best new experiences.

o I had a hot half smoke in DC (same as Ethiopian above)

o Again in DC, thanks to Veggo, had great Maryland crab (cakes and soup) at Legal Seafoods. It&apos;s a chain and gets no respect but it was great. The shellfish wine flight didn&apos;t hurt.

o Basically all the food in DC and the farmers markets. My first trip there but not my last, for sure.

o Amazing Sichuan food with Alan Barnes in the major &apos;burbs of Sacramento.

o Rediscovering the Inner Richmond district in SF, specifically Clement St. You could spend a month there and not repeat.

o Lunch at El Dorado Kitchen in Sonoma. See picture below. Amazing.

That seems to be enough dining-wise.

Cooking:

o Well, I made xiao long bao/ soup dumplings (also see picture) for the first time. They were good, not very good and not great, but credible.

o I&apos;ve gotten MUCH more into Mexican food once I discovered a great Latino market in Reno. When you can buy freshly made corn tortillas, chorizo, etc. it expands your boundaries.

o Thanks to Sam, I made chicken stock from feet and backs and it&apos;s amazing.

o Speaking of Sam, he influences so many things I cook and eat. Thanks, buddy.

o Bought a new range with an induction cooktop. Just wow. Can&apos;t imagine not having it.

o Started using cast iron alot more. My main skillet almost looks like a mirror.

o Ooh, almost forgot. I bought a little upright freezer (maybe 4&apos; tall and 2&apos; wide). Not only can I buy things when they&apos;re on special but I can keep the fridge one WAY better organized.

I realize that I could go on and on but I&apos;ll stop here - for now :) A great Chow year. Life is good.
   
 Permalink | Reply 
 By c oliver on Dec 23, 2010 07:36 PM 

 
This was my year of getting intimately re-acquainted with huitlacoche from corn stalk to table, and sharing my experiences here. I still have a good stash in the freezer, so I will chronicle successes and misfires into 2011 as I shamelessly grovel for new ideas for its use.
Also this year, a friend from Uruguay turned me on to sweetbreads, and I&apos;m busy catching up on lost years. Grilled over mesquite with chimichurri they are killer.
Finally, I have failed miserably at attempts to curb my addiction to stone crabs. I gorged on them daily earlier in the year in Belize, and I have a monster claw for snacking tomorrow that is 9 inches. Santa was good.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Veggo on Dec 24, 2010 03:30 PM 

 
Raising my own chicken, slaughtering it, skinning it, cooking it and eating it.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By ipsedixit on Dec 24, 2010 06:38 PM 
 re: ipsedixit 
Oh wow. I&apos;m so impressed. How did it taste and feel? I hope wonderful.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By c oliver on Dec 24, 2010 06:56 PM 
 re: c oliver 
Highly recommended.

Read about it here: http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/707713 
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By ipsedixit on Dec 24, 2010 07:00 PM 
 re: ipsedixit 
I saw my first poultry slaughtered yesterday for Christmas tamales. I may become a vegetarian.

At the least, I&apos;ll never trust the woman who raises those chickens again. They wait for her every morning and she talks to them. She picked them up and twisted their necks in a motion that looked like a carress or patting the head.

They were then hung by a string while she slit their throats to drain the blood. One of the ducks had not died and as she ran the knife across its neck she said&quot;tranquillo&quot;in the same tone she uses with the children and dog when she wants to calm them down.

I guess it was more humane than what goes on at Foster Farms ... but still.

I think that the taste of home-raised poultry is highly over rated. The tamales were fine, but if I didn&apos;t know how they were raised, I don&apos;t think the taste is significantly better than something from a market.

The lesson was to question anyone who is nice to me and feeds me for no particular reason
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By rworange on Dec 24, 2010 07:48 PM 
 re: rworange 
I love this. Good lesson.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Glencora on Dec 25, 2010 10:06 AM 

 re: rworange 
Chicken tamales is not the best vehicle to appreciate the subtleties of homegrown chickens.

I think if you take issue with the slaughter of chickens, then you&apos;d probably have issues with just about the slaughter of any animal bred for human consumption.

I see vegetarianism in your future ...
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By ipsedixit on Dec 25, 2010 10:15 AM 
 re: ipsedixit 
Sounds like the woman slaughters her animals with the least amount of fear for the animal. I congratulate her for that.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By c oliver on Dec 25, 2010 10:19 AM 
 re: c oliver 
We also raise and process our own chickens and ducks. Who, by the way, if kept properly are not dirty filthy animals. Our hens are for eggs and the roos and drakes get eaten. The birds do taste &apos;gamier&apos; than store raised birds because store raised birds are bred to be processed at 8 weeks (cornish cross breed) and ours are heritage breeds processed at 24 weeks.

So I guess my food highlight for 2010 was that I know where my food comes from and how to get it humanely from yard to table. And I didn&apos;t become a vegetarian in the process. :-)
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By rosepoint on Dec 27, 2010 05:05 AM 
 re: rosepoint 
The taste varies wildly and it really doesn&apos;t have anything to do with at what point the poultry is killed. So you might have gamey birds while others might not be.

Seriously, I&apos;ve eaten A LOT of home-raised poultry from my own back yard and those of others this year. I&apos;ve lost my reverance and awe for the terms like &apos;naturally-raised&quot;. Yes, they are better than being shot thru with chemicals and cooped up. But flavor-wise, it is not a big factor.

It is no different than buying an organic apple or a conventionally grown one. I&apos;ve had some tastesless organic versions and some tasty conventionaly grown produce.

You&apos;d have to go thru a lot of work to learn breed, feed and other stuff. When I return home, all I&apos;m going for at the farmers market or meat market will be who sells the best tasting chickens.

The only constant I&apos;ve found is that a really old bird will be tough ... the reason for those long-stewed dishes in many countries. Even a tough, old bird can be made tasty in the right hands.

As to dirty, even parakeets are dirty. By that I meant that it takes a whole lot of work to keep the poultry yard and chickens looking tidy.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By rworange on Dec 27, 2010 06:19 AM 



 re: ipsedixit 
I&apos;ve had nothing but home-raised poultry this year both from my backyard and the backyards of others.

In fact, &apos;farm-raised&apos; is a not considered a good thing here. Menus feature galinos criollas (sp) ... home-raised.

It is no different nor more sublime than what you would buy in a supermarket. The poultry I&apos;ve had has ranged from exquisite to tough and tasteless. It is a matter of breed, feed, age and a lot of other factors ... including the talent of the person cooking said bird.

I just wanted to offer another perspective to&quot;:highly recommended&quot;. It is so trendy these days in the US to raise your own poultry. Anyone contemplating this ... should contemplate more.

The result may not be any better than what is in the market ... just as someone who is not an accomplished baker would be better off buying a superlative artisan baked good.

If I had to kill my own chicken, I would become a vegetarian. Chickens, and especially ducks, are nasty, dirty, gratingly noisy, canabalistic and stupid creatures. The term&quot;bird-brained&quot;doesn&apos;t come from nowhere.

Home-raised poutlry is a fact of life in Guatemala. Many people don&apos;t have the money or luxury to buy from the markets ... if they did, they would. I have a hard time getting across the concept that people in the US pay big money for chickens raised naturally.

And yes, I&apos;m a city girl. My family thinks it is funny every time I sit down to a poultry dinner,and before starting to eat, look at the plate and say&quot;Vaya con Dios, pollo&quot;&quot;A Dios pato&quot;Gracias.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By rworange on Dec 25, 2010 11:34 AM 
 re: c oliver 
No, even in my rural area the supermarkets sell chickens. Wal-marts local stores, Paiz and Dispensa Familiar, sell Tyson chickens and Butterball turkeys.

However, it is rare that someone without a piece of land attached to the house doesn&apos;t have poutlry. Even the super rich relatives in Guatemala City have poultry ... btw that&apos;s where I had the equisite chicken They have a person whose only job it is is to care for the birds. The cages are spotless. The feed is well thought out .. .and hilariously enough they insist their chickens eat NO grubs or insects ... something that is a big selling point in the US .. the chickens running around eating insects and such.

However, you can&apos;t argue with results. That was the best chicken I&apos;ve ever had. They also have a fabulous cook. Until that chicken, the most memorable chicken dish I ever had was at Chez Panisse maybe 15 years ago. .

So, I guess the rich relatives chicken is my most memorable and tasty dish of 2010.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By rworange on Dec 25, 2010 12:16 PM 



 re: rworange 
Killing animals is never pretty. And what you saw sounds to me like a very humane and fairly inoffensive slaughter.

IMO it&apos;s better to look the ethical (and aesthetic) implications of eating other living creatures straight in the eye. Then we can make informed decisions about whether to remain omnivores or become vegetarians. It&apos;s cowardly to pretend that meat is just nondescript animal protein on a Styrofoam tray.

Frankly, I think it would be a good thing if people had to see where there meat comes from. There&apos;d be more vegetarians, and those who choose to eat meat would be far less tolerant of abusive practices.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By alanbarnes on Dec 27, 2010 08:22 PM 

 re: rworange 
I wish everyone could slaughter their chickens in the way you described above.
I know a lot of people raising their own chickens, pigs, lambs, etc. and when the time comes to kill,it does not always go so smoothly.
It is an art, and that woman should be commended.
As far as the difference in taste, sustainable animal husbandry is also about giving the animal a better life, not simply whether you notice the subtleties of the meat in a tamale.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By rabaja on Jan 4, 2011 12:52 PM 
 re: rabaja 
75% of North Americans live in urban areas, so what may be a pleasant wish may not be practical or lawful for most.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Veggo on Jan 4, 2011 01:02 PM 
 re: Veggo 
I wasn&apos;t really speaking to that. I was just commenting that a lot of people who can legally raise their own animals for slaughter do not always do it as well as the woman rwOrange was lucky enough to meet.
It&apos;s takes practice and a knowing hand.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By rabaja on Jan 4, 2011 02:51 PM 
 re: rabaja 
Gotcha. It&apos;s beyond my experience, but i&apos;ll clean the fish...
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Veggo on Jan 4, 2011 03:30 PM 

 re: rabaja 
I was just commenting that a lot of people who can legally raise their own animals for slaughter do not always do it as well as the woman rwOrange was lucky enough to meet.
It&apos;s takes practice and a knowing hand.
________________________

I&apos;ll ditto that sentiment.

Having slaughtered my own chicken I can attest to the fact that the first time is nothing but a bloody mess (figuratively, not literally) ... something that would make the Saw movies seem like a Disney production.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By ipsedixit on Jan 4, 2011 05:08 PM 

 re: rabaja 
The details with photos here ... from live duck to tamal.

Christmas Tamales Rojos Guatemaltecos – Or never trust anyone who feeds you for no apparent reason …
 http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/757104 

Direct link to all photos
 http://www.flickr.com/photos/7685047@N02/sets/72157625721860250/detail/ 

After all that work ... which involved raising all that poultry from hatchlings ... I wish I could say those tamales were one of my top tastes of 2010, but they weren&apos;t.

The best tamal I had and one of the best tastes of 2010 was a street tamal negro that cost $1.25 and took me one minute to buy.
 http://www.flickr.com/photos/7685047@... 

It is sort of ironic, I think. Everyone is always chasing authenticity and naturally raised. I don&apos;t think you can get more authentic or natural than those tamales rojos .. and while the taste was fine, the only truly memorable thing was the experience.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By rworange on Jan 4, 2011 07:48 PM 




 
 
 
 
 
A good one, starting with a trip to Paris and London (and enjoying the food more in London, dynamite dinners at the Harwood Arms and Bentley&apos;s - oh the Cornish oysters and Dover sole, ditto lunch at Hibiscus - this time we didn&apos;t go high end in Paris, the food was great but not killingly so).
Best dinner in NY: In August at The Modern restaurant - exciting and delicious food in a beautiful room at a window table, impeccable Martini and service.
Worst dinner in NY: In September at Le Périgord - boring and overpriced food in a shabby restaurant that has decidedly seen better days.
Happiest circumstance: The continuing growth and broadening of the Chinese cuisines available in NYC. Now let&apos;s go for a Shaanxi and a Xinjiang place please, and a real Beijing roast duck restaurant...and a Mongolian BBQ like the Aristocrat in Taipei of yore.
Biggest challenge: Overcoming my new kitchen&apos;s wonky oven (it works, but has its little ways).
Proudest accomplishment: The Gateau St-Honoré I made at souschef&apos;s urging.
Obstacle overcome: Pie pastry, finally cracked with the CI recipe scrupulously followed.
Best confection consumed: A Jacques Bellanger milk chocolate and marcona almond bar, the chocolate unbelievably complex and the bar crammed with so many almonds it seemed to burst apart in my mouth. A gift from a sweet friend who knows me very well.
Runner-up: The caramelized hazelnuts in chocolate just received from another friend that are what M&amp;Ms;should aspire to be when they grow up.
Very thankful for the circumstances we find ourselves in, with all the opportunites available.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By buttertart on Dec 25, 2010 07:08 AM 

 
Participating in summer and winter CSA&apos;s
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By shaebones on Dec 25, 2010 10:46 PM 

 
In 2010 I fell in love with live chickens all over again. We raised chickens, ducks, geese, pigs, cows, sheep and horses on the farm when we were kids, all of which we ate except for the horses (and the kids). My brother now has the farm and he has started the process again, with his own chickens and rabbits. What a pleasure it was to see his extremely happy chickens tugging at worms, clucking contentedly; gathering warm eggs every morning, etc. Although butchery is not a joy to watch he did it humanely and quickly. His happy poultry tastes so wonderful. If we were allowed to do it I would happily raise chickens in our back yard in town. I love the connection of raising and eating your own animals - always have.

Discovered I don&apos;t love sea urchin as I was hoping to!

Had my usual annual fill of white truffles in Istria. Delectable.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By chefathome on Dec 27, 2010 12:02 PM 

 
Great Thread

* Discovering the Pacific Northwest Cuisine - Seattle - Portland - Eating at Tom Douglas&apos; Dahlia, Pacific NW Oysters comparing them to the ones down here in Florida in the gulf.

* Pike Place Market - Seattle

* Scratching off two restaurants that I have been to that Tony B. has gone to on No Reservations - I know kinda stalkerish, lol. Voodoo Doughnut and Salumi

* Touring the Brewery of Rogue Ales and getting a wonderful wine and history lesson from Mr. Paul at Shallon Winery in Oregon.

* Enjoying my first Pho and Banh Mi in the Vi-Mi district in Orlando at Pho 88.

* Drinking and Eating around the world at Epcot - not really all that foodie but a hell of a great time.

* Enjoying the best cuban sandwich and cuban espresso I&apos;ve ever had in Miami

* Having the misfortune of not being able to order oysters because of the lack of quantity due to the oil leak in the gulf.

* Helping my husband in his food and beer endeavors - Smoking meats, cheese, leg of lamb, pulled pork, sea bass, salmon and brewing Indian Pale Ales.

* Had fun introducing a friend from Maine to gator and other Florida cuisine.

* Ate nuetella for the first time ever and loved it.

* Ate Sea Urchin for the first time and enjoyed it, but my husband did not. lol.

* Honed some baking skills.

* had a calamari tasting at the house to figure out which calamari recipe we liked the best. The asian spicy recipe won.

* Made a huge effort to eat local.

* Only ate at one fast food restaurant this year and it was during a road trip where I had no other options. :)
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Sandwich_Sister on Dec 27, 2010 12:41 PM 
 re: Sandwich_Sister 
Congratulations on discovering the Pacific NW cuisine.

When I moved to this country I worked (as a chef) for several years in New York, Nashville, Miami, Hawaii, and finally Los Angeles for the rest of my career. I thought I knew the foods of&quot;America&quot;- it wasn&apos;t until I retired and moved to WA that I discovered a whole new and exciting cuisine that if I had only known would have made this area my home. The diversity of fresh local indigenous ingredients is superb - so congratulations on your find.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By RetiredChef on Jan 4, 2011 09:09 AM 
 re: RetiredChef 
Thanks, It was a totally surprise I mean I knew I was going there to taste some food, but I didn&apos;t know how amazing it was going to be.

I really can&apos;t wait to go back.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Sandwich_Sister on Jan 4, 2011 09:37 AM 

 
 
 
How could I forget olive harvesting in Italy? Very interesting. We were able to bring back some extremely fresh, young and grassy olive oil.

Crushing grapes in Italy, too, at a small vineyard.&quot;Helping&quot;(I use the term loosely) in the wine process.

Although I&apos;ve gardened my whole life this year was the year for tomatoes. They were well over 7 feet tall (average here about 2-3 feet). Not so unusual for some of you except my gardening zone is zone 1 (meaning 87 frost-free days annually). Four plants produced over 600 tomatoes! If it didn&apos;t freeze so hard so early there would have been tons more - hundreds of blossoms. The raised beds are placed strategically in a major suntrap with our white house as a backdrop, surrounded by crushed gravel, which also holds in heat.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By chefathome on Dec 27, 2010 01:12 PM 

 
A pretty good year which I’ve just about managed to narrow down to a single monthly selection

Calderata Manchego at Don Quijote, Los Cristianos, Tenerife in January

“Deep fried jam sandwich with Carnation milk ice cream” at 60 Hope Street, Liverpool, in February

The mullet in the tasting menu at Fraiche, Oxton, in March.

Sticky toffee pudding at Sharrow Bay Hotel, Ulverston in April

Shish taouk at Palmyra, Richmond in May.

Nihari lamb at Moti Mahal, London in June

Salamagundi at the Sportsman, Seasalter in July (although it was nearly edged by by the lightly boiled duck egg with eel soldiers at Eddie Gilberts, in Ramsgate on the same trip)

Jelly of quail at a 60th birthday celebration dinner at the Fat Duck, Bray in August

The whole mezze at Mezodopolian, Yeroskipou, Cyprus in September

Gujarati vegetarian food (the whole lunch) at Prashad, Bradford in October

Fish&amp;chips at Fosters, Didsbury in November.

Dry meat curry at Tayyabs, London, in December
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Harters on Dec 28, 2010 05:16 AM 
 re: Harters 
Show off ;)
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By shaebones on Dec 28, 2010 07:23 AM 

 re: Harters 
I want that jam sandwich please.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By buttertart on Dec 28, 2010 07:59 AM 

 
 
Congrats on the blog, kattyeyes!

On my own blog I just did a roundup of my top 10 savory dishes, top 5 desserts, and top 5 cocktails I had this year...but all in Colorado since my blog is Denver-dining oriented.

But you&apos;re asking what was new for us; since I&apos;m a food writer, those experiences are getting rarer, but going to Chile for the first (I hope not only) time helped:

CHORRILLANA! Basically Chilean loaded fries, with beef and eggs. I&apos;m vaguely obsessed with it and think everybody else should be too.

Pebre. Wonderful Chilean salsa. It does taste different than Mexican types but I can&apos;t put my finger on why...greener, it seems, but not with tomatillo...

Merquen. Chilean spice powder with smoked dried chilies, cumin, coriander.

My first experience with Dongbei cuisine, swooning over black eggs and tofu. Also love all the cold spicy dishes—sliced beef, seaweed, cucumber...but I&apos;d had versions of those before...

 http://www.ruthtobias.com/denveater 
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By tatamagouche on Dec 29, 2010 06:49 AM 
 re: tatamagouche 
&quot;An Essay On Austin Texas Food In 2010: From Odd Duck To Hoffbrau and Everything In Between&quot;

I did the google above and encountered a huge helping of food reviews on the Austin dining scene in 2010.

Lots of good eating from Thai to ancient steakhouses, Mexican meat markets to Vietnamese sandwich joints.

The food trailer scene is exploding with over 1100 carts in operation.

We&apos;ve got it good out here in the Lone Star state these days.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By scrumptiouschef on Dec 29, 2010 10:22 PM 

 
 
 «Back to the General Topics Board Back to the Top | Reply to original post 
Discussions You Might Also Like...
 How many people buy supermarket chicken and meat? (305 replies) 1 Please tell me why/if large-scale industrially produced (feed lot) meat is better/as good as local pasture-raised. (123 replies) 2 No flavor in the taste of meats, pork, poultry (6 replies) 3 Can&apos;t find what you&apos;re looking for? Start your own discussion now . 
 Most Recent Discussions 
 
Thursday, July 12, 2012 replies 
 
 58 

 Lamb - should it be gamey or... 

10 minutes ago
 
 249 

 what foods does your city have... 

12 minutes ago
 
 5 

 What to buy at an asian market... 

31 minutes ago
 
 5 

 Unrefrigerated Cheeses Left... 

about 1 hour ago
 
 91 

 Party Foods: Which ones are... 

about 1 hour ago
 
 0 

 Looking for decent packaged... 

about 2 hours ago
 
 Videos 
 How to Make an Easy Margarita 
 Recipe Slideshows 

 Healthy Chicken Recipes See All 25 Recipes» 
 
 »Videos » How to Make an Easy Margarita » Supertaster Daily: Taco Bell&apos;s Cantina Bell Menu » Supertaster Daily: The Seattle-Style Hot Dog » How to Tell How Much Propane Is Left for Your Gas Grill » NY CHOW Report: Bud Light–Battered Fish Po&apos; Boy at Motorboat&amp;the Big Banana » Supertaster Daily: Whole Grain Beefaroni 
 
 »Recipes » Road Trip Munchies » French-y Picnic Recipes for Bastille Day » Cold Dishes for Hot Weather » Pine Cone Punch » Homemade Chocolate Graham Cracker S&apos;mores » Blue Cheese and Chive Compound Butter 
 
 »Blogs » The Diss, Updated: Calling Asian Food&quot;Hipster&quot; » Anyone in the Bay Area Still Making Mandarin Pressed Duck? » Amazing Espresso in Orange County » Boston Lobster Rolls: Chowhound Lists » Yopparai, an Izakaya Speakeasy on the Lower East Side » Must-Try Adobo Sandwich at Redwood Empire Farmers&apos; Market 
 
 »Discussion » Has KFC&apos;s chicken pot pie changed? (thread begun April 2012) » Tom Douglas restaurants? » Min Ghung Asian Bistro, Glastonbury » Confused about cutting boards » The Rebel House - Boca Raton » Lamb - should it be gamey or not? 
 
 About/Contact CHOW | Feedback 
 FOLLOW CHOW 
 facebook twitter google plus pinterest youTube rss 
 CBS Cares | CBS Films | CBS Radio | CBS.com | CBSInteractive | CBSNews.com | CBSSports.com | CHOW | Clicker | CNET | College Network | Find Articles | GameSpot | Help.com | Last.fm | MaxPreps | Metacritic.com | Moneywatch | mySimon | Radio.com | Search.com | Shopper.com | Showtime | SmartPlanet | TechRepublic | The Insider | TV.com | UrbanBaby.com | ZDNet 
CBS Entertainment | About CBS Interactive | Jobs | Advertise 

©2012 CBS Interactive Inc. All rights reserved. | Privacy Policy | Ad Choice | Terms of Use 
 X 
Log In
 USERNAME / EMAIL PASSWORD Remember me Join CHOW | Forgot your password? X 
Sign Up
 USERNAME EMAIL PASSWORD CONFIRM PASSWORD 
Choose Newsletters

 CHOW Announcements CHOW Partner Offers Recipe of the Day CHOW Latest Stories Weekly Recipes 
 THE DIGEST - The best of Chowhound 
 San Francisco Bay Area New York City Los Angeles Area Home Cooking Boston 
 Username is public and once confirmed, is unchangeable. By clicking the SIGN UP button, you agree to CHOW&apos;s terms of use and have read and understand our privacy policy . Share with your friends X 
 TO: FROM: MESSAGE: 
 Share &quot;2010: Your year in food&quot;
	</body>
</document>
