<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000187" url="http://www.meriyatrra.com/business_1/all/page/358.html" time="2012-07-12-15:22" support="8" score="0.018700998448009817" bingtitle="in Travel Business Listing | Meriyatrra.com" webtitle="in  Travel Business Listing | Meriyatrra.com">
			<query id="000033" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="000051" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000048" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000058" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000042" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="000469" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="000493" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000043" bing-rank="38"/>
	<description>Tikka Hut Fast Food Restaurant Food, Mangalore, karnataka, India Shop No.23,Muda Market ... Opp Mega Mall, BIG Bazar,Near 5 Spice Resturant,Andheri West,Mumbai - 400053</description>
	<body>
		Welcome Guest 
New User? Register | Login 
 
 Home Blog My Blogs Read all Blogs Write new Blog Ask Question My Questions Read all Questions Ask New Questions Destinations Discover new Destination Places List All Travel Places Discover new Travel Place Events List All Events List All Festivals Publish new event for free Photos My Photos Album View all Photos Add new Photo Videos My Videos Most Viewed Videos Top Rated Videos View all Videos Add new Video Polls Favorite Guidebook Series Most Romantic Place Better way of Traveling Honeymoon holiday choice. Best site for flight tickets Best holiday option in India??? Place do you generally like to visit during holidays? Mobile Photos View all Holidays International Holidays Domestic Holidays Add Holidays Business listing Hotels Restaurants Resort Shops Tour Operators Travel Agents Bed&amp;Breakfast Pub Nightclub / Discotheque Movie Theater Cafeteria Water Park Theme Park Bowling Alley Billiards Casino List all business List your business for free 
 
 Want to list your business? 

 List your Business for free 
 
 Recent Business 
 Casa de Goa Resort 
Goa, India

 Sagara Beach Resorts 
Kovalam, India

 Pagoda Resort 
Alappuzha (Alleppey), India

 Michaels Inn 
Thekkady, India

 Tea Castle Resort 
Munnar, India

 Riviera De Goa Resort 
Goa, India

 Casablanca Beach Resort 
Goa, India

 Sinclairs Bay View 
Port Blair, India

 JCT Houseboat 
Alappuzha (Alleppey), India

 Blackberry Hills 
Munnar, India
 Recent Comments Unknown column &apos;s.status&apos; in &apos;where clause&apos;
	</body>
</document>
