<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000940" url="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/ency/patientinstructions/000211.htm" time="2012-07-12-16:18" support="2" score="0.004345348728334965" bingtitle="Cholesterol - what to ask your doctor : MedlinePlus Medical ..." webtitle="Cholesterol - what to ask your doctor : MedlinePlus Medical Encyclopedia">
			<query id="000221" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000721" bing-rank="50"/>
	<description>Can I ever go to a fast-food restaurant again? Do I need to limit how much salt I use? Can I use other spices to make my food taste good? Is it okay to drink any ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip navigation A service of the U.S. National Library of Medicine 
 National Institutes of Health Home About MedlinePlus Site Map FAQs Contact Us Search MedlinePlus 
 Health Topics Drugs&amp;Supplements Videos&amp;Cool Tools 

 ESPAÑOL 
 
Cholesterol - what to ask your doctor
 To use the sharing features on this page, please enable JavaScript. 
Your body needs cholesterol to work properly. When you have extra cholesterol in your blood, it builds up inside the walls of your arteries (blood vessels), including the ones that go to your heart. This buildup is called plaque.

Plaque narrows your arteries and slows or stops the blood flow. This can cause a heart attack , stroke , or other serious heart disease .

Below are some questions you may want to ask your doctor or nurse to help you take care of your cholesterol.
 
Questions

What is my cholesterol level? What should my cholesterol level be?

 What are HDL (&quot;good&quot;) cholesterol and LDL (&quot;bad&quot;) cholesterol? Does my cholesterol need to be better? How often should I have my cholesterol checked? 

What medicines am I taking to treat high cholesterol?

 Do they have any side effects? What should I do if I miss a dose? Are there foods, other medicines, vitamins, or herbal supplements that may change how well my cholesterol medicines work? 

What is a heart-healthy diet?

 What are low-fat foods? What types of fat are okay for me to eat? How can I read a food label to know how much fat there is? Is it ever okay to eat something that is not heart healthy? What are some ways to eat healthy when I go to a restaurant? Can I ever go to a fast-food restaurant again? Do I need to limit how much salt I use? Can I use other spices to make my food taste good? Is it okay to drink any alcohol? 

What can I do to stop smoking?

Should I start an exercise program?

 Is it safe for me to exercise on my own? Where should I exercise, inside or outside? Which activities are better to start with? Are there activities or exercises that are not safe for me? Can I exercise most days? How long and how hard can I exercise? What symptoms may I need to watch out for? 

Alternate Names

Hyperlipidemia - what to ask your doctor; What to ask your doctor about cholesterol

Update Date: 11/21/2010

Updated by: David C. Dugdale, III, MD, Professor of Medicine, Division of General Medicine, Department of Medicine, University of Washington School of Medicine. Also reviewed by David Zieve, MD, MHA, Medical Director, A.D.A.M. Health Solutions, Ebix, Inc.
 Browse the Encyclopedia 
 MedlinePlus Topics 
 
 Cholesterol 
 
 Read More 
 
 Cholesterol and triglyceride test Familial hypercholesterolemia Heart attack High blood cholesterol levels 
 
 Patient Instructions 
 
 Being active when you have heart disease Butter, margarine, and cooking oils Cholesterol and lifestyle Cholesterol - drug treatment Diabetes - preventing heart attack and stroke Dietary fats explained 
 
A.D.A.M., Inc. is accredited by URAC, also known as the American Accreditation HealthCare Commission (www.urac.org). URAC&apos;s accreditation program is an independent audit to verify that A.D.A.M. follows rigorous standards of quality and accountability. A.D.A.M. is among the first to achieve this important distinction for online health information and services. Learn more about A.D.A.M.&apos;s editorial policy , editorial process and privacy policy . A.D.A.M. is also a founding member of Hi-Ethics and subscribes to the principles of the Health on the Net Foundation (www.hon.ch).

The information provided herein should not be used during any medical emergency or for the diagnosis or treatment of any medical condition. A licensed physician should be consulted for diagnosis and treatment of any and all medical conditions. Call 911 for all medical emergencies. Links to other sites are provided for information only -- they do not constitute endorsements of those other sites. Copyright 1997-2012, A.D.A.M., Inc. Duplication for commercial use must be authorized in writing by ADAM Health Solutions.
 
 Mobile version Get email updates Subscribe to RSS Follow us on Twitter 

 Disclaimers Copyright Privacy Accessibility Quality Guidelines Viewers&amp;Players 
 U.S. National Library of Medicine 8600 Rockville Pike, Bethesda, MD 20894 U.S. Department of Health and Human Services National Institutes of Health 
 Page last updated: 28 June 2012
	</body>
</document>
