<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000981" url="http://veganite.hubpages.com/hub/Recycling-Alamogordo-New-Mexico" time="2012-07-12-16:21" support="6" score="0.0031266506600038484" bingtitle="Recycling Alamogordo, New Mexico" webtitle="Recycling Alamogordo, New Mexico">
			<query id="000445" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="001513" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="000384" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000714" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000039" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="000697" bing-rank="26"/>
	<description>... the Sacramento Mountains with just about every fast food ... for their rebate program where they will pick up ... Several businesses in town have small receptacles for you ...</description>
	<body>
		HubPages 
 explore 
 topics hubs answers forums 
 sign in join now 
 flag 
 Explore  » Politics and Social Issues (50,117) » Environment and Green Issues (2,642) » Recycling Issues (199) 
 by veganite 
38 Followers 
Recycling Alamogordo, New Mexico
 See all 6 photos Recycling center in Alamogordo, NM. See all 6 photos Reclaimed water sign in Alameda Park. See all 6 photos Tire enforcement along ditch. See all 6 photos Habitat For Humanity ReStore. See all 6 photos One of the many Thrift Stores in town. See all 6 photos Solar trashcan in front of City Hall. The panel is on top. 
Many towns and cities across the United States of America and even the world are making efforts to set up recycling programs not only for their citizens but for themselves. If you live in one of these places, you are familiar with green bins, blue bins, and bins of every shape, color, and size designed to sort and contain anything from newspapers to aluminum cans to those pesky plastic grocery bags. But that may be the extent of recycling offered in your neck of the woods and that’s a shame because recycling is extremely important in conserving resources and reducing waste. This waste ends up in land fills and land fills are filling up.

I’ve lived in many cities in my life but no city I have lived in has done more to create recycling opportunities than Alamogordo, New Mexico. Not only does the city itself participate in recycling but its citizens have continued the effort.

To drive through Alamogordo, you wouldn’t think that the city is on the recycling bandwagon. It’s a major hub for commerce for the surrounding area of south central New Mexico. The city lines the west side of the Sacramento Mountains with just about every fast food restaurant, motel chain, and home improvement store known to man. But live in Alamogordo for a while and you’ll see that the city has an environmental conscience like using old tires to stabilize ditches throughout town and reclaimed water to irrigate its numerous parks and landscapes.

The most obvious effort to encourage recycling are the receptacles the city provides to the public for cardboard, aluminum cans, and newspaper which are almost always overflowing. Drive out to the transfer station partnered with the New Mexico Recycling Coalition and you can drop off plastic, glass, aluminum, scrap metal, appliances, car batteries, oil, antifreeze, tires, and yard waste for recycling. But if you don’t want to donate your metal items for recycling and opt to sell them, there are numerous scrap yards in the area more than willing to give you top dollar. Don’t want to drive out to the transfer station? You can drop off car batteries and oil for recycling at auto parts stores like AutoZone.




Have a non running car you can’t take to a scrap yard? Donate it to Heritage for the Blind. They will haul it away for you for free and give you a vacation voucher. Have an old working refrigerator or freezer you want to replace with a new energy efficient one? Contact PNM, the electric company, for their rebate program where they will pick up that old fridge for free and pay you $30. Don’t know what to do with those plastic grocery bags? Take them to WalMart and drop them off in their plastic recycling bin. Have an old pair of eyeglasses you can no longer use? Several businesses in town have small receptacles for you to donate them to Lions Club International. Have too many dead electric tool batteries? Lowes and Home Depot have bins for you to drop those off for recycling. Did your compact florescent lightbulb finally burn out and you don’t know what to do with it since you shouldn’t put it in the trash? Lowes has a bin for you to drop those off. Doing some spring cleaning and need to get rid of stuff? There are numerous thrift stores in the city for you to donate your old items and some like Goodwill, Salvation Army, and Animal Mission are charitable. Would you rather make some money off that stuff instead of donating? Log on to hollomanyardsales.com (a local area website), craigslist.com, or freecycle.org where you can post a classified advertisement for free. Remodeling your home and have good household items you need to get rid of? The Habitat for Humanity ReStore will gladly accept your donations. They sell these items at a discounted price to other people who are remodeling and they use the money to build houses for qualified low income families. Tired of tripping over that pile of magazines? The city library has a table in the lobby where you can place them for other people to read. There&apos;s even a solar trashcan in front of City Hall.

And for the animals, Animal Village NM just outside of the city is a nonprofit no kill shelter saving animals from death row and finding them forever homes.

In Alamogordo, there’s almost no reason to throw anything away. The city and its citizens have truly come together whether they really know it or not to do their part in preserving the environment and conserving resources. I know there are many other cities out there that are just as active with recycling if not more so than Alamogordo. But, Alamogordo is where I live and it makes me feel good to know that I have all of these recycling opportunities and I can be part of the collective effort.
 
 Reusing and Recycling (Help the Environment) Amazon Price: $2.73
List Price: $5.99 McGraw-Hill Recycling Handbook, 2nd Edition Amazon Price: $77.72
List Price: $120.00 Recycling (a short story) Amazon Price: $0.99
 Reduce, Reuse, Recycle: An Easy Household Guide (Chelsea Green Guides) Amazon Price: $1.12
List Price: $7.95 Cash For Your Trash: Scrap Recycling in America Amazon Price: $21.78
List Price: $23.95 
 
This Hub was last updated on January 30, 2012
 
You can help the HubPages community highlight top quality content by ranking this article up or down.
 Useful   • Funny   • Awesome   • Beautiful   • Interesting  {1} Discover More Hubs Freegle Re-use Group, Cardiff, Wales 5 Ways to Recycle Old Jeans How to Preserve our Natural Resources, Reduce Our Dependence on Fossil Fuels,... How to Save the Environment - Recycling, Reusing, Composting The Paper Recycling Process Green Living - Creative Recycling Tips and Tricks 
 Loading... Comments 0 comments 

No comments yet.
 Submit a Comment New comments are not being accepted on this Hub at this time. Like This Hub? 
Over 50 Million people discover HubPages every month.
 HubPages 
 about us blog advertise faq link to this page copyright 

Copyright©2012 HubPages Inc. and respective owners. All rights reserved.

Other product and company names shown may be trademarks of their respective owners.

HubPages ® is a registered Service Mark of HubPages, Inc.

 terms of use privacy policy (0.76 sec) HubPages Business 
 working
	</body>
</document>
