<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000952" url="http://www.insiderpages.com/b/3715357986/jordans-furniture-inc-natick" time="2012-07-12-16:19" support="1" score="0.0003585176835177319" bingtitle="Jordan&apos;s Furniture Inc - Natick - Insider Pages - Restaurant ..." webtitle="Jordan&apos;s Furniture - Natick">
			<query id="000924" bing-rank="36"/>
	<description>WHAT HAPPENED TO THIS STORE!!!!! I have been ... of the chairs had tape residue on the fabric seat. ... to me plus i just love it.They got a big fast food restaurant in ...</description>
	<body>
		join sign in 
 Find Near Browse Categories 
recommendations that matter most 
 Health&amp;Medical Home&amp;Garden Hair&amp;Beauty Auto
 Services Pets follow us Advertise With Us 
 Natick, MA &gt; Furniture Stores &gt; Beds &gt;Jordan&apos;s Furniture 

 

 

 

 
Jordan&apos;s Furniture
 ★★☆☆☆ 18 Reviews Write a Review 
508-424-0088
 1 Underprice Way (Route 9) Natick , MA 01760 www.jordans.com 
Quality Designer Furniture
 
 Add Photo Edit Business 
 
About Jordan&apos;s Furniture
 Categories 
 Furniture Stores Beds 
 Details 
 Mattress Stores 
 Hours Monday: 10:00 AM - 10:00 PM
Tuesday: 10:00 AM - 10:00 PM
Wednesday: 10:00 AM - 10:00 PM
Thursday: 10:00 AM - 10:00 PM
Friday: 10:00 AM - 10:00 PM
Saturday: 10:00 AM - 10:00 PM
Sunday: 11:00 AM - 07:00 PM 
Home&amp;Garden
 More choices in Natick: 
 Mattress Giant 
309 Moody St Waltham, MA
 
 Mattress Giant 
100 Worcester Rd Framingham, MA
 
More about Jordan&apos;s Furniture

Stroll our recreation of Bourbon Street, New Orleans, see 110,000 square feet of quality designer furniture, see an IMAX movie or enjoy a meal from Kelly&apos;s Roast Beef at our Natick location.
 
 Reviews 
 
Insider Pages Reviews for Jordan&apos;s Furniture

Have experience with this business? Write a Review. 
 ★☆☆☆☆ Sofas from the warehouse have mice inside them 
 Jen H. 1 Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 
So I purchased a leather reclining sectional online from Jordans, paid for it cash (2100) had it delivered. The sofa looked great in the living room however I laid down on it and heard noices coming from the inside of it. What do ya know... a nest of FIELD MICE. I never jumped up so fast in my life. Apparently their warehouse is loaded with them. I do not recomend buying anything from Jordans. Bernie and Phyls...Here I Come!
 March 11, 2011 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★★★☆☆ mistake rectified by them 
 claire g. 3 Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 
had a big problem w an item not arriving on time,but after alot of fuss on my part, they bent over backwards to help out
 December 21, 2010 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★☆☆☆☆ Elliot What Happened to this Store? 
 Joanne F. 1 Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 
WHAT HAPPENED TO THIS STORE!!!!! I have been purchasing furniture from Jordans since they started in Waltham and up till they moved into the Natick store. I always was very satisfied with my furniture.
I recently purchased a new living room set and it is crap, such poor quality, nothing like what I sat on in the show room.
Trying to deal with the customer service people is very frustrating. One customer service person (Megan) told me if I dont like the furniture I can sell it on Craigs list.

Elliot whats going on????????????

I strongly recommend NOT buying from Jordans.
 December 10, 2010 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★★★☆☆ ms. 
 mammyo Y. 3 Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 
I had good luck with them buying a couch, rug and kitchen table all at different times. but these reviews are scarey! I think their prices are very high, but the furniture is very nice. But they def should stop bragging about being cheap. NOw, the one thing that does drive me crazy is that the salespeople are always so snooty looking. The all walk around with their noses up in the air and look like you are bothering them when you ask a simple question, like youre some little peon!! every one of them (*natick)
 December 09, 2010 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★☆☆☆☆ your time is not important to them unless they can make some money on it. 
 timmy m. 1 Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 
God help anyone looking for quality .
I have had 5 end tables delivered and they have all been defective in one way or another .I have lost 3 days labor as a result of there delivery scedual ( 10am - 2 pm ).After all the junk they kept delivering , there best sugestion was to try again . This place is a freakin joke !!! Talking to a customer rep is like speaking to a robot .GOOD LUCK ! Read the reviews before shopping .The bad ones are true and the ones that are good are from employees .one star given because one was required to post this review . anyone giving more than one star is drinking way too much cool-aid .
 October 27, 2010 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★☆☆☆☆ Don&apos;t shop at Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 ann g. 1 Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 
Disaster is all I can say about my experience with Jordan&apos;s Furniture. The high end mattress I bought from them has totally fallen apart in 7 months time. They send out these mattress inspectors to check it out and the report comes back saying the mattress is not defective even though my 130 pound body sinks into the mattress about 7 inches deep when I put my body weight onto it. I demand another inspection and this time the mattress is measuring defective but now they blame it on the foundation which was found to be&quot;free from defects&quot;in the first inspections three weeks earlier. They are all a bunch of clowns out to rip off the consumer. Sooner or later it will catch up with them. Just stay away from Jordan&apos;s!!!
 September 13, 2010 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★☆☆☆☆ Rude and obnoxious 
 Frank R. 1 Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 
I wanted to get a desk. I called and asked them if they had it. They said yes, it was in stock. I went there to pick it up they said it has to be shipped from their warehouse. Then they argued with me that I should get their delivery. Over 100 $ for a 250 $ item! Then they told me they are used to making sales of thousands of dollars and did not really want to waste time with my 250 $ purchase. That is when I left and gave up on them.
 September 13, 2010 
 Report Abuse 

1 out of 1 people found this review helpful.

Was this review helpful to you?
 ★☆☆☆☆ STAY AWAY FROM JORDANS 
 Kelly S. 1 Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 
First let me say anyone who has given a good review must have only gone for food and games! The customer service is the worst I have ever encountered. I am on the phone with them weekly. Waiting 4 months for desk so we have a living room full of boxes. We finally got a coffee table it was damaged. They sent another the top wont shut its all warped! They send repair guy I wait around all day each time he says nope warped they will send another! You will have to wait around for the Third coffee table this is 4 days of my life I will not get back! they don&apos;t care!You pay high price and get worse quality than BOBS! I have talked with 4 managers and written to ELIOT the owner that never responded to my 3 page letter of problems. They don&apos;t care. We were stupid to open the 12 month interest free DON&apos;T DO IT! The bank will not send statements I have called 2x to have address changed. My husband is an Attorney I just bothered him a work to o something about the HSBC bank. They want to charge us late fees. ITS CRIMINAL they wont send out statements. Its one thing after another. STAY AWAY FROM JORDANS. They have done nothing to compensate us for all the problems! They just keep sanding broken furniture and cards in the mail saying desk delayed another month!! It and a huge shopper ask my husband. I will never ever shop there again. enjoy the RIDES and food. They do that to distract you with their gimmicks from their horrible service!
 September 13, 2010 
 Report Abuse 

1 out of 1 people found this review helpful.

Was this review helpful to you?
 ★☆☆☆☆ Horrible customer service 
 Jane B. 1 Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 
I bought a $1200 kitchen table in January and was told there would be a few weeks delay. Well it is mid May and it only just arrived. I had to call them to find out what was going on and all they could say was it is my choice if I want to cancel the order. They really did not care. I will never shop at Jordans again. They do not care about what their customers value.
 September 13, 2010 
 Report Abuse 

1 out of 1 people found this review helpful.

Was this review helpful to you?
 ★★☆☆☆ Where is my furniture?!? 
Anonymous 2 Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 
Jordans has a huge selection, great products and in-store staff was very helpful. Well, we were told we&apos;d have our couches in 4-6 weeks from the date we ordered it. It&apos;s now been 8 weeks and still no couches. I called and was told it will probably be another 3-4 weeks (due to some issue with the fabric)before they get the couches into their warehouse to ship, which means it will be another week at least, before it arrives to us (so. maine). Same thing with our bedroom set. We were told we&apos;d have it early July, but early July came and went and we heard nothing. So I called and was told it would be an additional month before our furniture would arrive. What a let down. New house and no furniture. Very disappointed! We had much better luck with Bernie and Phyls!
 September 13, 2010 
 Report Abuse 

1 out of 1 people found this review helpful.

Was this review helpful to you?
 ★☆☆☆☆ Bad Furniture, Overpriced, Bad Service 
Anonymous 1 Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 
Bought a leather sofa and loveseat. $2600 for each - hardly an&quot;underprice&quot;but OK if the quality is there. It isn&apos;t. Six months in the cushions are compacted and sagging, and the frame is shot. The service technician came in the last 2 minutes of a 3-hour window and said they would add additional framing but it&apos;s obvious when you look at the inside of the sofa that it was simply not constructed well and the additional framing will be a temporary fix. Now have to wait for another 3 hours on a Saturday for pick-up, and wreck another day after that for delivery of repaired sofa.

This is a FURNITURE STORE. Who cares about entertainment, MOM, food, or fountains? Never again.
 September 13, 2010 
 Report Abuse 

1 out of 1 people found this review helpful.

Was this review helpful to you?
 ★★★★★ Fun atmosphere 
 Kyra T. | Insider Expert
| Rank: 2,285 5 Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 
I&apos;ve never been to Jordans to actually buy anything, but I&apos;ve been there to see what the hype was about. It&apos;s a very entertaining place to go, the iMax is great, although always packed, and even the food isn&apos;t bad.
 January 21, 2008 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★☆☆☆☆ Jordans Furniture - Best of Boston, yeah, but not recently 
 Al Z. 1 Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 
Want to have a heartbreaking customer service experience? Want to see a store do nothing that matches its hype and marketing?

Buy some furniture at this store and watch the joy of your purchase get sucked from you and your family.

After years (more than 20 years) of buying furniture at Jordan&apos;s I have taken the prudent path of becoming an ex-customer.

Good quality furniture (while it is in the store) and helpful sales staff (until you write the check) and then there are the delivery people (whose motto should be&quot;Ascendo tuum&quot;or up yours.

Why do people who choose to work in customer service, do so when they hate people so much - Jordans hired all of them
 November 22, 2006 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★☆☆☆☆ Gone are the days of the Customer is always right..... 
 amy f. 1 Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 
Jordan&apos;s isn&apos;t what it used to be and I think Barry&amp;Elliot would be appalled. The customer is always right is no longer part of their ethics....We purchased a kitchen set including 8 chairs on June 16th. When the furniture was delivered on July 1st, one of the chairs had tape residue on the fabric seat. I called the Company that day&amp;even offered to bring the chair to the store to exchange it. I was told by Eric, the head of customer service, that I wasn&apos;t entitled to a new chair, I had to schedule an appointment for a service call&amp;the company would send a rep out to try&amp;clean it. He was very unhelpful in scheduling this, refusing to give me a time frame unless it was the day before the appointment. I explained that I can&apos;t take time off from work to wait all day for this, as I would need to give them a time frame of when I would be in. The earliest they could schedule me was 14 days after the delivery. I went to the store the next business day&amp;attempted to speak to the office. I was told by a rep. named Sylvia that there&apos;s nothing she can do as I didn&apos;t purchase the fabric protection plan. I tried to explain that the chair came damaged, it was nothing I did. There apparently was no one there that could help me and she put me on the phone with a customer service rep, who turned out to be Eric, the man I spoke to on the 1st. Eric was unbelievably rude to me. I tried to explain that I only have 7 days to return the chair, according to their policy, and I wanted the &apos;cleaning&apos; to take place before that so I could see if it would work or if I was going to return it. He said&quot;I&apos;ve already explained this to you&quot;...and went on to patronize me. I spent a lot of money in that store on this kitchen set as well as an entire bedroom set and feel that this company could be more helpful to their clients. They refused to accommodate me and are forcing me to keep damaged merchandise until it&apos;s convenient for them to service it. I&apos;m not interested in a refurbished chair, I want a new one as that is what I purchased. I have never been spoken to like Eric spoke to me, he has no concept of customer service, and I am shocked that this is how their reps are allowed to handle problems created by their warehouse. I&apos;m sure this multi million dollar company is able to exchange a $75 chair in order to keep a customer.
 July 05, 2006 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★★★★★ Jordan&apos;s Furniture Review 
 Jade L. | Insider Expert
| Rank: 10,635 5 Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 
This is beyond a furniture store! They have a HUGE selection of furniture and great quality and price, but they also have an IMAX movie theatre right inside the building. It has a concession stand and everything. Great blockbuster hits, a few at a time and great prices. Even 3D movies. Would highly recommend.
 November 30, 2005 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★★★★★ A Furniture Store and Disneyland! 
 Richard L. | Insider Expert
| Rank: 10,847 5 Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 
The Jordans Furniture store on the Natick/Framingham line is perhaps the most entertaining furniture store on the planet. They sell excellent furniture, not always at prices as low as some discount furniture stores, but the price is right for the quality they offer. Not only do they sell furniture, but they do so in a Disneyland type atmosphere. You walk into the store and find yourself on Bourbon Street. A sales person hands you Mardi Gras beads as you walk down Bourbon Street admiring the three-story building facades. Many of the&quot;shops&quot;on Bourbon Street sell furniture, of course, but there is also a roast beef shop, a dessert streetcar, a virtual reality entertainment experience, a full large-screen IMAX theater, and an animated musical review featuring animatronics every half hour. I sometimes go here even when I don&apos;t want furniture!

PROS: Furniture store entertainment at its finest, quality furniture
CONS: None
 November 27, 2005 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★★★★★ best quality,excellent prices and beutiful furniture. 
 ZIA K. | Insider Expert
| Rank: 11,847 5 Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 
Jordans Furniture is located on top of hill in a very center of heart location in Natick just a few seconds from big natick mall.I just love there furniture.I just ordered some new couches for my living room which they will deliver in 2 weeks.They have 4 locations but i go to natick as that is the 1 accesible to me plus i just love it.They got a big fast food restaurant in there and i have to mention with alot of joy about there big imax theature.O i just love it.In last december i got a very nice dinning table set and this year for christmas i ordered new couches with there great quality and best prices you just cant go wrong.They also offer there own financing with 1 year no interst to make it easy on your pockets.
 November 23, 2005 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★★★★★ Fabulous selection, great service, fun locations 
 J G. | Insider Expert
| Rank: 5,598 5 Jordan&apos;s Furniture 
 
If you haven&apos;t been to Jordan&apos;s Furniture, you have to check it out! This Natick location has a huge parking lot and is decorated in a mardi gras theme. There are individual rooms that look like store fronts which are separated based upon the rooms in your house. There is a huge selection of items of all different price ranges. There are loads of salespeople around but none of them will bother you until you are ready to make a purchase.

Delivery from Jordan&apos;s is professional and on time. They will take anything back that doesn&apos;t fit in your room and you won&apos;t be charged. Overall, this is the best furniture store I&apos;ve ever been to!

PROS: Great selection, service and locations!
CONS: None
 July 26, 2005 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 Write a Review Get Map&amp;Directions 
Modify or Try Another Search For:
 
Beds - Natick, MA
 Find Near Home | About Us | FAQ | Blog | Help/Contact Us | Feedback | Store Finder | Doctor Finder | Sitemap | Privacy Policy (updated) | Terms &amp; Conditions ©2004–2012 Insider Pages. All rights reserved. Partner Sites: MyAutismTeam | Ask Answers | Ask Kids | Life123 | Citysearch | MerchantCircle | Urbanspoon
	</body>
</document>
