<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000082" url="http://www.freebase.com/view/en/johnnys_charcoal_broiled_hamburgers" time="2012-07-12-15:16" support="1" score="0.002828849517228336" bingtitle="Johnny&apos;s Charcoal Broiled Hamburgers facts - Freebase" webtitle="Johnny&apos;s Charcoal Broiled Hamburgers facts - Freebase">
			<query id="001168" bing-rank="184"/>
	<description>We can tell you that Johnny&apos;s Charcoal Broiled Hamburgers is a… …Restaurant ... The chain was solely a Mexican fast-food restaurant until 1998, when many locations were co ...</description>
	<body>
		Start typing to get some suggestions 
 Data Schema Apps Docs 
 Sign In or Sign Up 





 
Johnny&apos;s Charcoal Broiled Hamburgers
 Johnny&apos;s Charcoal Broiled Hamburgers, or simply, &quot;Johnny&apos;s Hamburgers&quot;, is an eatery located in Scarborough, Toronto, at Victoria Park and Sheppard Ave. It is locally famous for its charcoal broiled hamburgers which are considered one of the city&apos;s two best, famous for its economical prices, and infamous for its choice of glaring orange and white checkers decor and its choice to not serve lettuce. On its back walls are numerous retro Coca-Cola po... More 
Johnny&apos;s Charcoal Broiled Hamburgers, or simply, &quot;Johnny&apos;s Hamburgers&quot;, is an eatery located in Scarborough, Toronto, at Victoria Park and Sheppard Ave. It is locally famous for its charcoal broiled hamburgers which are considered one of the city&apos;s two best, famous for its economical prices, and infamous for its choice of glaring orange and white checkers decor and its choice to not serve lettuce. On its back walls are numerous retro Coca-Cola posters and signs. On its side wall is an assortment of taped-up newspaper clippings mentioning the restaurant.
The burgers come in a brown paper bag alongside a single napkin. If you order fries and a drink, their &quot;combo&quot; is served on a cardboard tray. There is no seating inside other than the bench where people wait for their number to be called up. The bench itself spans the entire length of the restaurant. Outside there are old wooden picnic tables on tiny patches of grass with the occasional large oil-barrel trashcan where pigeons often...
 Less Read article at Wikipedia 
Also known as:

 Johnny&apos;s Charcoal Broiled Hamburgers, Toronto 
 
We can tell you that Johnny&apos;s Charcoal Broiled Hamburgers is a

  Restaurant  Organization Location 

If you know more about Johnny&apos;s Charcoal Broiled Hamburgers , you can add more facts here» 
 
Similar topics in Freebase

 
 21 Club 
 The 21 Club, often simply 21, is a restaurant and former prohibition-era speakeasy, located at 21 West 52nd Street in New York City.
The Bar Room includes a restaurant, a lounge and, as the name implies, a bar. The walls and ceiling of the Bar Room are covered with antique toys and sports... 
 241 Pizza 
 241 Pizza is a Canadian franchise chain of pizza restaurants. There are 62 locations across Ontario, particularly in The Greater Toronto Area. There are also locations in Manitoba and Saskatchewan. 241 Pizza competes heavily in the Greater Toronto Area with other pizza chains such as Pizza Pizza,... 
 Al tazaj 
 Al Tazaj is a chicken BBQ Arabic restaurant which started and is based in Saudi Arabia, but has since expanded to many countries in the Middle East.
The first AL TAZAJ restaurant proudly opened its doors in the holy city of Makkah in 1989. The idea started by Shaikh Abdul Rahman Fakieh who owns... 
 Al&apos;s Breakfast 
 Al&apos;s Breakfast is reportedly the narrowest restaurant in the city of Minneapolis, at a width of ten feet (3.0 m). Al&apos;s Breakfast (Dinkytown Branch) is crammed into a former alleyway between two much larger buildings and is located in the city&apos;s Dinkytown neighborhood near the University of... 
 Albert&apos;s Real Jamaican Foods 
 Albert&apos;s Real Jamaican Foods is a restaurant at 542 St. Clair Avenue West at the corner of Vaughan Road in Toronto, Ontario, Canada. It was founded by Albert Wiggan, a recipient of the Harry Jerome Award.
One of fifteen children, Albert&apos;s mother taught him how to cook from a young age. At the age... 
 Amber 
 Overseen by Culinary Director Richard Ekkebus, two-star Michelin restaurant Amber presents modern French cuisine. Using only the finest and freshest ingredients sourced from all parts of the world. Chef Ekkebus crafts distinctive new flavours with innovative presentations to create unique dishes... 
 Amigos/Kings Classic 
 Amigos/Kings Classic is a small Nebraska-based fast-food chain that serves Mexican and American foods. The restaurant was founded as Amigos in Lincoln, Nebraska in 1980. The chain was solely a Mexican fast-food restaurant until 1998, when many locations were co-branded with A&amp;W; Restaurants. After... 
 Anchor Bar 
 Anchor Bar is a restaurant located in Buffalo, New York which was the birthplace of spicy chicken wings, known outside the Buffalo area as Buffalo wings. The restaurant was initially established in 1935. Teressa Bellissimo is credited with the creation of the dish when she deep-fried some wings and... 
 Anna&apos;s Taqueria 
 Anna&apos;s Taqueria is a chain of fast-service Mexican-fusion restaurants in the Boston area.
Anna&apos;s is modeled after U.S. West Coast style Mexican cuisine, specifically the Mission-style or San Francisco burrito. Its menu offers only four core items: burritos, tacos, quesadillas and Mexican plates,... 
 Antoine&apos;s 
 Antoine&apos;s is a Louisiana Creole cuisine restaurant located at 713 rue St. Louis (St. Louis Street) in the French Quarter of New Orleans, Louisiana. It has the distinction of being the oldest family run restaurant in the United States, having been established in 1840 by Antoine Alciatore. A New... 
 
These people have edited this topic:

 Freebase Experts 
spencermountain

 Member Since: Jun 15, 2008 Contributions: 224,744 Facts 
 
maxim75

 Member Since: Mar 8, 2010 Contributions: 1,069,623 Facts 
 
 Edit this topic Last edited Feb 13, 2012 See all topic history» 
Elsewhere on the web

 Wikipedia Wikipedia 
 Edit and Show details 
Add or delete facts, download data in JSON or RDF formats, and explore topic metadata.
 
What is Freebase?

Freebase is a huge collection of facts, built by people like you. 
 Freebase connects facts in ways other sites can&apos;t, 
 giving you new ways to explore millions of subjects.
 You can help improve it! 
 
Flag this Topic

Why do you want to flag this topic?

 Label as possibly offensive Delete from Freebase Merge with another topic Split into multiple topics 
 
Freebase data is free for use under the CC-BY license .
 Learn more about Freebase licensing and attribution» 
 
The original description for Johnny&apos;s Charcoal Broiled Hamburgers was automatically generated from Wikipedia.org licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License .
 1 
 ©2012  
 Page History RDF Feedback Attribution Policy Terms of Service About Us Jobs Freebase Blog 
 Freebase contains information on: 
 Arts&amp;Entertainment Commons Products&amp;Services Science&amp;Technology Society Special Interests Sports System Time&amp;Space Transportation 
 Dev Tools Refresh cache | Query Editor | Normal view | Explore | Explore2 | Admin view | View transaction log | Suggest transaction log | Client transaction log | hide (F8) | debug-level none error all TID(s): Controller: 0.753 s Template: 0.034 s Cost: br=12.0, cc=1.149, cdbr=1.0, ch=5.0, cm=16.0, cm+h=21.0, cr=21.0, cs=19.0, cw=16.0, dr=16300.0, dt=1.623, dw=0.0, gqr=0.0, in=7955.0, ir=485.0, iw=0.0, lh=1.0, lm=0.0, lr=1.0, mcs=0.008, mcu=0.396, mr=18.0, nivcsw=249.0, nreqs=40.0, nvcsw=92.0, oublock=648.0, pf=0.0, pr=0.0, stime=0.034, te=0.069, tf=0.237, tg=0.209, tm=0.665, tr=0.055, ts=0.0, tu=0.053, utime=1.108, va=22093.0
	</body>
</document>
