<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000508" url="http://www.fool.com/Features/1996/sp0527b.htm" time="2012-07-12-15:46" support="3" score="0.0033810509600292766" bingtitle="FOOLWIRE: Valuation Principles &amp; Practice" webtitle="FOOLWIRE: Valuation PrinciplesPractice">
			<query id="000264" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000266" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="000989" bing-rank="150"/>
	<description>... through pages of stock tables in order to ferret ... PSR in conjunction with the P/E in order to confirm ... out of ten people forced to name a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Valuation: Principles&amp;Practice 
 How to Read a
 Balance Sheet 
 Introduction To Valuations 
 Earnings-Based Valuations 
 The Fool Ratio 
 Revenues-Based Valuations 
 Cash Flow-Based Valuations 
 Equity-Based Valuations 
 Yield-Based Valuations 
 Member-Based Valuations 
 The Motley Fool&apos;s Online Peg/Ypeg
 Calculator 
 So just how do you value the shares of a company? Based on
 earnings, revenues, cash-flow. . . or something else entirely? Or do you
 simply apply multiple valuations in order to discern what the fair price
 for a share of stock might be? In this series of informative articles by
 MF Templar, Fools get a chance to learn lots of potential ways to value a
 company&apos;s shares, as well as helpful methods to determine whether or not
 a stock is undervalued right now. 
[The Second article in this series can now be found in the
 &quot; Fools&amp;Their Money &quot; area as All About &quot;Liquid&quot; .]
 Transmitted: 5/26/96 Introduction To Valuation 
Valuation is the first step toward intelligent investing. When an investor
 attempts to determine the worth of her shares based on the fundamentals,
 she can make informed decisions about what stocks to buy or sell. Without
 fundamental value, one is set adrift in a sea of random short-term price
 movements and gut feelings.
For years, the financial establishment has promoted the specious notion that
 valuation should be reserved for experts. Supposedly, only sell-side brokerage
 analysts have the requisite experience and intestinal fortitude to go out
 into the churning, swirling market and predict future prices. Valuation,
 however, is no abstruse science that can only be practiced by MBAs and CFAs.
 Requiring only basic math skills and diligence, any Fool can determine values
 with the best of them.
Before you can value a share of stock, you have to have some notion of what
 a share of stock is. A share of stock is not some magical creation that ebbs
 and flows like the tide; rather, it is the concrete representation of ownership
 in a publicly traded company. If XYZ Corp. has one million shares of stock
 outstanding and you hold a single, solitary share, that means you own a millionth
 of the company.
Why would someone want to pay you for your millionth? There are quite a few
 reasons, actually. There is always going to be someone else who wants that
 millionth of the ownership because they want a millionth of the votes at
 a shareholder meeting. Although small by itself, if you amass that millionth
 and about five hundred thousand of its friends, you suddenly have a controlling
 interest in the company and can make it do all sorts of things, like pay
 fat dividends or merge with your company.
Companies buy shares in other companies for all sorts of reason. Whether
 it be an outright takeover, in which a company buys all the shares, or a
 joint venture, in which the company typically buys enough of another company
 to earn a seat on the board of directors, the stock is always on sale. The
 price of a stock translates into the price of the company, on sale for seven
 and a half hours a day, five days a week. It is this information that allows
 other companies, public or private, to make intelligent business decisions
 with clear and concise information about what another company&apos;s shares might
 cost them.
The share of stock is a stand-in for a share in the company&apos;s revenues, earnings,
 cash flow, shareholder&apos;s equity -- you name it, the whole enchilada. For
 the individual investor, however, this normally means just worrying about
 what portion of all of those numbers you can get in dividends. The share
 of ownership entitles you to a share of all dividends in perpetuity. Even
 if the company&apos;s stock does not currently have a dividend yield, there always
 remains the possibility that at some point in the future there could be some
 sort of dividend.
Finally, a company can simply repurchase its own shares using its excess
 cash, rather than paying out dividends to shareholders. This effectively
 drives up the stock price by providing a buyer as well as improving earnings
 per share (EPS) comparisons by decreasing the number of shares outstanding.
 Mature, cash-flow positive companies tend to be much more liberal in this
 day and age with share repurchases as opposed to dividends, simply because
 dividends to shareholders get taxed twice.
This series of articles will take you through the major methods for valuing
 companies. The main categories of valuation I will elucidate are valuations
 based on earnings, revenues, cash flow, equity, dividends and subscribers.
 Finally, I will sum this all up in a conclusion that positions these valuations
 in the broader context of fundamental analysis and gives you a sense of how
 to apply these in your own investment efforts.
 Randy Befumo (MF Templar), a Fool 
 Transmitted March 3, 1997 Earnings-Based Valuations 
 EARNINGS PER SHARE AND THE P/E RATIO 
The most common way to value a company is to use its earnings. Earnings,
 also called net income or net profit, is the money that is left over after
 a company pays all of its bills. To allow for apples-to-apples comparisons,
 most people who look at earnings measure them according to earnings per
 share (EPS) .
You arrive at the earnings per share by simply dividing the dollar amount
 of the earnings a company reports by the number of shares it currently has
 outstanding. Thus, if XYZ Corp. has one million shares outstanding and has
 earned one million dollars in the past 12 months, it has a trailing EPS of
 $1.00. (The reason it is called a trailing EPS is because it looks at the
 last four quarters reported -- the quarters that trail behind the most recent
 quarter reported.) $1,000,000
 -------------- = $1.00 in earnings per share (EPS)
 1,000,000 shares 
The earnings per share alone means absolutely nothing, though. To look at
 a company&apos;s earnings relative to its price, most investors employ the price/earnings (P/E) ratio . The P/E ratio takes the stock price and
 divides it by the last four quarters&apos; worth of earnings. For instance, if,
 in our example above, XYZ Corp. was currently trading at $15 a share, it
 would have a P/E of 15. $15 share price
--------------------------- = 15 P/E
$1.00 in trailing EPS 
 IS THE P/E THE HOLY GRAIL? 
There is a large population of individual investors who stop their entire
 analysis of a company after they figure out the trailing P/E ratio. With
 no regard to any other form of valuation, this group of unFoolish investors
 blindly plunge ahead armed with this one ratio, purposefully ignoring the
 vagaries of equity analysis. Popularized by Ben Graham (who used a number
 of other techniques as well as low P/E to isolate value), the P/E has been
 oversimplified by those who only look at this number. Such investors look
 for &quot;low P/E&quot; stocks. These are companies that have a very low price relative
 to their trailing earnings.
Also called a &quot;multiple&quot;, the P/E is most often used in comparison with the
 current rate of growth in earnings per share. The Foolish assumption is that
 for a growth company, in a fairly valued situation the price/earnings ratio
 is about equal to the rate of EPS growth.
In our example of XYZ Corp., for instance, we find out that XYZ Corp. grew
 its earnings per share at a 13% over the past year, suggesting that at a
 P/E of 15 the company is pretty fairly valued. Fools believe that P/E only
 makes sense for growth companies relative to the earnings growth. If a company
 has lost money in the past year or has suffered a decrease in earnings per
 share over the past twelve months, the P/E becomes less useful than other
 valuation methods we will talk about later in this series. In the end, P/E
 has to be viewed in the context of growth and cannot be simply isolated without
 taking on some significant potential for error.
 ARE LOW P/E STOCKS REALLY A BARGAIN? 
With the advent of computerized screening of stock databases, low P/E stocks
 that have been mispriced have become more and more rare. When Ben Graham
 formulated many of his principles for investing, one had to search manually
 through pages of stock tables in order to ferret out companies that had extremely
 low P/Es. Today, all you have to do is punch a few buttons on an online database
 and you have a list as long as your arm.
This screening has added efficiency to the market. When you see a low P/E
 stock these days, more often than not it deserves to have a low P/E because
 of its questionable future prospects. As intelligent investors value companies
 based on future prospects and not past performance, stocks with low P/Es
 often have dark clouds looming in the months ahead. This is not to say that
 you cannot still find some great low P/E stocks that for some reason the
 market has simple overlooked -- you still can and it happens all the time.
 Rather, you need to confirm the value in these companies by applying some
 other valuation techniques.
 THE PEG AND YPEG 
The most common Foolish applications of the P/E are the P/E and growth
 ratio (PEG) and the year-ahead P/E and growth ratio (YPEG). Rather
 than reinvent the wheel, as there is a wonderful series of articles already
 written on these very subjects in Fooldom, I will simply direct your attention
 to them and talk about them very briefly. The full article on the PEG and
 YPEG, titled &quot; The Fool Ratio ,&quot; can be found
 in the &quot; Fools&amp;Their Money &quot; area.
The PEG simply takes the annualized rate of growth out to the furthest estimate
 and compares this with the current stock price. Since it is future growth
 that makes a company valuable to both an acquirer and a shareholder seeking
 either dividends or free cash flow to fund stock buybacks, this makes some
 degree of intuitive sense. Only looking at the trailing P/E is kind of like
 driving while looking out the rearview mirror.
If a company is expected to grow at 10% a year over the next two years and
 has a P/E of 10, it will have a PEG of 1.0. P/E of 10
---------------------- = 1.0 PEG
10% EPS growth 
A PEG of 1.0 suggests that a company is fairly valued. If the company in
 the above example only had a P/E of five but was expected to grow at 10%
 a year, it would have a PEG of 0.5 -- implying that it is selling for one
 half (50%) of its fair value. If the company had a P/E of 20 and expected
 growth of 10% a year, it would have a PEG of 2.0, worth double what it should
 be according to the assumption that the P/E should equal the EPS rate of
 growth.
While the PEG is most often used for growth companies, the YPEG is best suited
 for valuing larger, more-established ones. The YPEG uses the same assumptions
 as the PEG but looks at different numbers. As most earnings estimate services
 provide estimated 5-year growth rates, these are simply taken as an indication
 of the fair multiple for a company&apos;s stock going forward. Thus, if the current
 P/E is 10 but analysts expect the company to grow at 20% over the next five
 years, the YPEG is equal to 0.5 and the stock looks cheap according to this
 metric. As always, one must view the PEG and YPEG in the context of other
 measures of value and not consider them as magic money machines.
 MULTIPLES 
Although the PEG and YPEG are helpful, they both operate on the assumption
 that the P/E should equal the EPS rate of growth. Unfortunately, in the real
 world, this is not always the case. Thus, many simply look at estimated earnings
 and estimate what fair multiple someone might pay for the stock. For example,
 if XYZ Corp. has historically traded at about 10 times earnings and is currently
 down to 7 times earnings because it missed estimates one quarter, it would
 be reasonable to buy the stock with the expectation that it will return to
 its historic 10 times multiple if the missed quarter was only a short-term
 anomaly.
When you project fair multiples for a company based on forward earnings
 estimates, you start to make a heck of a lot of assumptions about what is
 going to happen in the future. Although one can do enough research to make
 the risk of being wrong as marginal as possible, it will always still exist.
 Should one of your assumptions turn out to be incorrect, the stock will probably
 not go where you expect it to go. That said, most of the other investors
 and companies out there are using this same approach, making their own
 assumptions as well, so, in the worst-case scenario, at least you won&apos;t be
 alone.
A modification to the multiple approach is to determine the relationship
 between the company&apos;s P/E and the average P/E of the S&amp;P 500. If XYZ
 Corp. has historically traded at 150% of the S&amp;P 500 and the S&amp;P
 is currently at 10, many investors believe that XYZ Corp. should eventually
 hit a fair P/E of 15, assuming that nothing changes. This historical relationship
 requires some sophisticated databases and spreadsheets to figure out and
 is not widely used by individual investors, although many professional money
 managers often use this approach.
 Randy Befumo (MF Templar), a Fool 
 Transmitted March 3, 1997 The Fool
 Ratio Revenue-Based Valuations 
 VALUATION: THE PRICE/SALES RATIO 
Every time a company sells a customer something, it is generating revenues.
 Revenues are the sales generated by a company for peddling goods or services.
 Whether or not a company has made money in the last year, there are always
 revenues. Even companies that may be temporarily losing money, have earnings
 depressed due to short-term circumstances (like product development or higher
 taxes), or are relatively new in a high-growth industry are often valued
 off of their revenues and not their earnings. Revenue-based valuations are
 achieved using the price/sales ratio, often simply abbreviated PSR.
The price/sales ratio takes the current market capitalization of a company
 and divides it by the last 12 months trailing revenues. The market capitalization
 is the current market value of a company, arrived at by multiplying the current
 share price times the shares outstanding. This is the current price at which
 the market is valuing the company. For instance, if our example company XYZ
 Corp. has ten million shares outstanding, priced at $10 a share, then the
 market capitalization is $100 million.
Some investors are even more conservative and add the current long-term debt
 of the company to the total current market value of its stock to get the
 market capitalization. The logic here is that if you were to acquire the
 company, you would acquire its debt as well, effectively paying that much
 more. This avoids comparing PSRs between two companies where one has taken
 out enormous debt that it has used to boast sales and one that has lower
 sales but has not added any nasty debt either.
 Market Capitalization = (Shares Outstanding * Current Share Price) + Current
 Long-term Debt 
The next step in calculating the PSR is to add up the revenues from the last
 four quarters and divide this number into the market capitalization. Say
 XYZ Corp. had $200 million in sales over the last four quarters and currently
 has no long-term debt. The PSR would be: (1,000,000 shares * $10/share) + $0 debt
PSR = ------------------------------------------------------- = 0.5
$20 million revenues 
The PSR is a measurement that companies often consider when making an
 acquisition. If you have ever heard of a deal being done based on a certain
 &quot;multiple of sales,&quot; you have seen the PSR in use. As this is a perfectly
 legitimate way for a company to value an acquisition, many simply expropriate
 it for the stock market and use it to value a company as an ongoing concern.
 USES OF THE PSR 
As with the PEG and the YPEG, the lower the PSR, the better. Ken Fisher,
 who is most famous for using the PSR to value stocks, looks for companies
 with PSRs below 1.0 in order to find value stocks that the market might currently
 be overlooking. This is the most common application of the PSR and is actually
 a pretty good indicator of value, according to the work that James O&apos;Shaughnessey
 has done with S&amp;P&apos;s CompuStat database.
The PSR is also a valuable tool to use when a company has not made money
 in the last year. Unless the corporation is going out of business, the PSR
 can tell you whether or not the concern&apos;s sales are being valued at a discount
 to its peers. If XYZ Corp. lost money in the past year, but has a PSR of
 0.50 when many companies in the same industry have PSRs of 2.0 or higher,
 you can assume that, if it can turn itself around and start making money
 again, it will have a substantial upside as it increases that PSR to be more
 in line with its peers. There are some years during recessions, for example,
 when none of the auto companies make money. Does this mean they are all worthless
 and there is no way to compare them? Nope, not at all. You just need to use
 the PSR instead of the P/E to measure how much you are paying for a dollar
 of sales instead of a dollar of earnings.
Another common use of the PSR is to compare companies in the same line of
 business with each other, using the PSR in conjunction with the P/E in order
 to confirm value. If a company has a low P/E but a high PSR, it can warn
 an investor that there are potentially some one-time gains in the last four
 quarters that are pumping up earnings per share. Finally, new companies in
 hot industries are often priced based on multiples of revenues and not multiples
 of earnings.
 Randy Befumo (MF Templar), a Fool 
 Transmitted March 3, 1997 Cash Flow-Based Valuation 
 CASH-FLOW (EBITDA)&amp;NON-CASH CHARGES 
Despite the fact that most individual investors are completely ignorant of cash flow , it is probably the most common measurement for valuing
 public and private companies used by investment bankers. Cash flow is literally
 the cash that flows through a company during the course of a quarter or the
 year after taking out all fixed expenses. Cash flow is normally defined as earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization (EBITDA). 
Why look at earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization?
 Interest income and expense, as well as taxes, are all tossed aside because
 cash flow is designed to focus on the operating business and not secondary
 costs or profits. Taxes especially depend on the vagaries of the laws in
 a given year and actually can cause dramatic fluctuations in earnings power.
 For instance, CYBEROPTICS (Nasdaq: CYBE) enjoyed a 15% tax rate in
 1996, but in 1997 that rate will more than double. This situation overstates
 CyberOptics&apos; current earnings and understates its forward earnings, masking
 the company&apos;s real operating situation. Thus, a canny analyst would use the
 growth rate of earnings before interest and taxes (EBIT) instead of
 net income in order to evaluate the company&apos;s growth. EBIT is also adjusted
 for any one-time charges or benefits.
As for depreciation and amortization , these are called non-cash charges , as the company is not actually spending any money
 on them. Rather, depreciation is an accounting convention for tax purposes
 that allows companies to get a break on capital expenditures as plant and
 equipment ages and becomes less useful. Amortization normally comes in when
 a company acquires another company at a premium to its shareholder&apos;s equity
 -- a number that it account for on its balance sheet as goodwill and is forced
 to amortize over a set period of time, according to generally accepted accounting
 principles (GAAP). When looking at a company&apos;s operating cash flow, it makes
 sense to toss aside accounting conventions that might mask cash strength.
 WHEN AND HOW TO USE CASH FLOW 
Cash flow is most commonly used to value industries that involve tremendous
 up-front capital expenditures and companies that have large amortization
 burdens. Cable TV companies like TIME-WARNER (NYSE: TWX) and TELECOMMUNICATIONS INC. (Nasdaq: TCOMA) have reported negative earnings
 for years due to the huge capital expense of building their cable networks,
 even though their cash flow has actually grown. This is because huge depreciation
 and amortization charges have masked their ability to generate cash.
 Sophisticated buyers of these properties use cash flow as one way of pricing
 an acquisition, thus it makes sense for investors to use it as well.
The most common valuation application of EBITDA, the discounted cash
 flow , is a rather complicated spreadsheet exercise that defies simple
 explanation. Economic Value Added (EVA) is another sophisticated
 modification of cash flow that looks at the cost of capital and the incremental
 return above that cost as a way of separating businesses that truly generate
 cash from ones that just eat it up. The most straightforward way for an
 individual investor to use cash flow is to understand how cash flow multiples
 work.
In a private or public market acquisition, the price-to-cash flow multiple
 is normally in the 6.0 to 7.0 range. When this multiple reaches the 8.0 to
 9.0 range, the acquisition is normally considered to be expensive. Some counsel
 selling companies when their cash flow multiple extends beyond 10.0. In a
 leveraged buyout (LBO), the buyer normally tries not to pay more than 5.0
 times cash flow because so much of the acquisition is funded by debt. A LBO
 also looks to pay back all the cash used for the buyout within six years,
 have an EBITDA of 2.0 or more times the interest payments, and have total
 debt of only 4.5 to 5.0 times the EBITDA.
Investors interested in going to the next level with EBITDA and looking at
 discounted cash flow or EVA are encouraged to check out the bookstore or the library. Since companies
 making acquisitions use these methods, it makes sense for investors to
 familiarize themselves with the logic behind them as this might enable a
 Foolish investor to spot a bargain before someone else.
 Randy Befumo (MF Templar), a Fool 
 Transmitted March 10, 1997 Equity-Based Valuations 
 WHAT IS EQUITY? 
 Equity is a fancy way of referring to what is actually there. Whether
 it&apos;s tangible things like cash, current assets, working capital and shareholder&apos;s
 equity, or intangible qualities like management or brand name, equity is
 everything that a company has if it were to suddenly stop selling products
 and stop making money tomorrow.
Traditionally, investors who rely on buying companies with a substantial
 amount of equity to back up their value are a paranoid lot who are looking
 to be able to collect something in liquidation. However, as the TV-dominated
 mass-consumer age has helped intangibles like brand names create powerful
 moats around a core business, contemporary investors have begun to push the
 boundaries of equity by emphasizing qualities that have no tangible or concrete
 value, but are absolutely vital to the company as an ongoing concern.
 THE BALANCE SHEET: CASH&amp;WORKING CAPITAL 
Like to buy a dollar of assets for a dollar in market value? Ben Graham did.
 He developed one of the premier screens for ferreting out companies with
 more cash on hand than their current market value. First, Graham would look
 at a company&apos;s cash and equivalents and short-term investments. Dividing
 this number by the number of shares outstanding gives a quick measure that
 tells you how much of the current share price consists of just the cash that
 the company has on hand. Buying a company with a lot of cash can yield a
 lot of benefits -- cash can fund product development and strategic acquisitions
 and can pay high-caliber executives. Even a company that might seem to have
 limited future prospects can offer tremendous promise if it has enough cash
 on hand.
Another measure of value is a company&apos;s current working capital relative
 to its market capitalization. Working capital is what is left after you subtract
 a company&apos;s current liabilities from its current assets .
 Working capital represents the funds that a company has ready access to for
 use in conducting its everyday business. If you buy a company for close to
 its working capital, you have essentially bought a dollar of assets for a
 dollar of stock price -- not a bad deal, either. Just as cash funds all sorts
 of good things, so does working capital.
 SHAREHOLDER&apos;S EQUITY&amp;BOOK VALUE 
 Shareholder&apos;s equity is an accounting convention that includes a company&apos;s
 liquid assets like cash, hard assets like real estate, as well as retained
 earnings. This is an overall measure of how much liquidation value a company
 has if all of its assets were sold off -- whether those assets are office
 buildings, desks, old T-shirts in inventory or replacement vacuum tubes for
 ENIAC systems.
Shareholder equity helps you value a company when you use it to figure out book value . Book value is literally the value of a company that can
 be found on the accounting ledger. To calculate book value per share, take
 a company&apos;s shareholder&apos;s equity and divide it by the current number of shares
 outstanding. If you then take the stock&apos;s current price and divide by the
 current book value, you have the price-to-book ratio .
Book value is a relatively straightforward concept. The closer to book value
 you can buy something at, the better it is. Book value is actually somewhat
 skeptically viewed in this day and age, since most companies have latitude
 in valuing their inventory, as well as inflation or deflation of real estate
 depending on what tax consequences the company is trying to avoid. However,
 with financial companies like banks, consumer loan concerns, brokerages and
 credit card companies, the book value is extremely relevant. For instance,
 in the banking industry, takeovers are often priced based on book value,
 with banks or savings&amp;loans being taken over at multiples of between
 1.7 to 2.0 times book value.
Another use of shareholder&apos;s equity is to determine return on equity ,
 or ROE. Return on equity is a measure of how much in earnings a company generates
 in four quarters compared to its shareholder&apos;s equity. It is measured as
 a percentage. For instance, if XYZ Corp. made a million dollars in the past
 year and has a shareholder&apos;s equity of ten million, then the ROE is 10%.
 Some use ROE as a screen to find companies that can generate large profits
 with little in the way of capital investment. COCA-COLA (NYSE: KO) ,
 for instance, does not require constant spending to upgrade equipment --
 the syrup-making process does not regularly move ahead by technological leaps
 and bounds. In fact, high ROE companies are so attractive to some investors
 that they will take the ROE and average it with the expected earnings growth
 in order to figure out a fair multiple. This is why a pharmaceutical company
 like MERCK (NYSE: MRK) can grow at 10% or so every year but consistently
 trade at 20 times earnings or more.
 INTANGIBLES 
Brand is the most intangible element to a company, but quite possibly the
 one most important to a company&apos;s ability as an ongoing concern. If every
 single MCDONALD&apos;S (NYSE: MCD) restaurant were to suddenly disappear
 tomorrow, the company could simply go out and get a few loans and be built
 back up into a world power within a few months. What is it about McDonald&apos;s
 that would allow it to do this? It is McDonald&apos;s presence in our collective
 minds -- the fact that nine out of ten people forced to name a fast food
 restaurant would name McDonald&apos;s without hesitating. The company has a well-known
 brand and this adds tremendous economic value despite the fact that it cannot
 be quantified.
Some investors are preoccupied by brands, particularly brands emerging in
 industries that have traditionally been without them. The genius of INTEL (Nasdaq: INTC) and MICROSOFT (Nasdaq: MSFT) is that they
 have built their company names into brands that give them an incredible edge
 over their competition. A brand is also transferable to other products --
 the reason Microsoft can contemplate becoming a power in online banking,
 for instance, is because it already has incredible brand equity in applications
 and operating systems. It is as simple as Reese&apos;s Peanut Butter cups transferring
 their brand onto Reese&apos;s Pieces, creating a new product that requires minimum
 advertising to build up.
The real trick with brands, though, is that it takes at least competent
 management to unlock the value. If a brand is forced to suffer through
 incompetence, such as AMERICAN EXPRESS (NYSE: AXP) in the early 1990s
 or Coca-Cola in the early 1980s, then many can become skeptical about the
 value of the brand, leading them to doubt whether or not the brand value
 remains intact. The major buying opportunities for brands ironically comes
 when people stop believing in them for a few moments, forgetting that brands
 normally survive even the most difficult of short-term traumas.
Intangibles can also sometimes mean that a company&apos;s shares can trade at
 a premium to its growth rate. Thus a company with fat profit margins, a dominant
 market share, consistent estimate-beating performance or a debt-free balance
 sheet can trade at a slightly higher multiple than its growth rate would
 otherwise suggest. Although intangibles are difficult to quantify, it does
 not mean that they do not have a tremendous power over a company&apos;s share
 price. The only problem with a company that has a lot of intangible assets
 is that one danger sign can make the premium completely disappear.
 THE PIECEMEAL COMPANY 
Finally, a company can sometimes be worth more divided up rather than all
 in one piece. This can happen because there is a hidden asset that most people
 are not aware of, like land purchased in the 1980s that has been kept on
 the books at cost despite dramatic appreciation of the land around it, or
 simply because a diversified company does not produce any synergies. SEARS (NYSE: S) , DEAN WITTER DISCOVER (NYSE: DWD) and ALLSTATE (NYSE: ALL) are all worth a heck of a lot more broken apart
 as separate companies than they ever were when they were all together. Keeping
 an eye out for a company that can be broken into parts worth more than the
 whole makes sense, especially in this day and age when so many 1970s
 conglomerates are crumbling into their component parts.
-Randy Befumo (MF Templar)
 T ransmitted March 5, 1997 Yield-Based Valuation 
 VALUATIONS BASED ON YIELD 
A dividend yield is the percentage of a company&apos;s stock price that
 it pays out as dividends over the course of a year. For example, if a company
 pays $1.00 in dividends per quarter and it is trading at $100, it has a dividend
 yield of 4%. Four quarters of $1 is $4, and this divided by $100 is 4%.
Yield has a curious effect on a company. Many income-oriented investors start
 to pour into a company&apos;s stock when the yield hits a magical level. The
 historical performance of the Dow Dividend Approach supports the general conclusion buttressed by Jim O&apos;Shaugnessey&apos;s work
 that shows that a portfolio made up of large capitalization, above-average
 yielding stocks outperforms the market over time.
Some, like Geraldine Weiss, actually invest in stocks based on what yield
 they should have. Weiss measures the average historical yield and counsels
 investing in a company&apos;s shares when the yield hits the edge of the undervalued
 band. For instance, if a company has historically yielded 2.5% and is currently
 paying $4 in dividends, the stock should trade in the $160 range. Anyone
 interested in learning more about Weiss&apos;s yield-oriented valuation approach
 should check out Dividends Don&apos;t Lie . The simplest way to take advantage
 of stocks that are undervalued based on their yield is to use the Dow Dividend
 Approach, which you can learn more about in the
 &quot; Fool&apos;s School &quot; area.
 Randy Befumo (MF Templar), a Fool 
 Transmitted March 10, 1997 Member-Based Valuations 
Sometimes a company can be valued based on its subscribers or its customer
 accounts. Subscriber-based valuations are most common in media and
 communication companies that generate regular, monthly income -- like cellular,
 cable TV and online companies. Often, in a subscriber-based valuation, analysts
 will calculate the average revenues per subscriber over their lifetime and
 then figure the value for the entire company based on this approach. If AMERICA ONLINE (NYSE: AOL) has six million members and each sticks
 around, on average, for 30 months, spending an average of $20 a month, the
 company is worth 6 million times $20 times 30 or $3.6 billion. This sort
 of valuation is also used for cable TV companies and cellular phone companies.
 For instance, Continental Cablevision was bought out for $2000 a subscriber.
Another way a company can be valued on members is based on accounts. In the
 healthcare informatics industry, companies are routinely acquired based on
 the value of their existing accounts. These acquisitions often completely
 ignore the past earnings or revenues of the company, instead focusing on
 what additional revenue could be conceivably generated from these new accounts.
 Although member-based valuations seem rather confusing, their exact mechanics
 are unique to each industry. Studying the history of the last few major
 acquisitions can tell an inquisitive investor how the member model has worked
 in past mergers and can suggest how it might work in the future.
 Randy Befumo (MF Templar), a Fool 
 Transmitted March 10, 1997 Copyright©1996, The Motley Fool 
All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
