<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000091" url="http://www.good.is/post/picture-show-visions-of-fast-food/" time="2012-07-12-15:17" support="10" score="0.028543690939745976" bingtitle="Picture Show: Visions of Fast Food - - GOOD" webtitle="Picture Show: Visions of Fast Food -  - GOOD">
			<query id="001118" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000365" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="001191" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="000052" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="001526" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000458" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000055" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="001380" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000898" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000397" bing-rank="125"/>
	<description>In the short time since fast food chains have become ... He adds, &quot;I may eat it on a lower frequency now.&quot; ... 4 Financial Fitness Task 8: Digitize Your Receipts ...</description>
	<body>
		News The Magazine Finder Maker 
 
 GOOD 


 
 News 
 Politics Education Environment Cities Transportation 
 Business 
 Spin Economy Social Enterprise Your Money 
 Culture 
 Books Film&amp;TV Music Art Media 
 Design 
 Architecture Graphic Design Creativity Diy 
 Lifestyle 
 Food Sex&amp;Relationships Health Spending 
 Technology 
 Social Media Gadgets Apps 
 Infographics Videos Projects 
 
Picture Show: Visions of Fast Food
 Previous Article Next Article 
 GOOD 
 hard at work Jon Feinstein 
 Photographer, Curator. 
 See Gallery 
 September 16, 2009 • 9:30 am PDT + comments 
 

 In the short time since fast food chains have become part of our national (and global) culture, a number of burger shops have begotten some truly iconic–and insalubrious-food items, the mass production and marketing of which is utterly astounding. However, when removed from their brightly colored wrappers and shot against a stark, clinical background, as in the case of Jon Feinstein &apos;s photographic series, &quot; Fast Food ,&quot; the archetypal snacks and sandwiches take on a decidedly unsettling quality.

&quot;There&apos;s this weird relationship that we as Americans have with fast food,&quot; says Feinstein, who titled each image with the given item&apos;s fat content, in grams. &quot;I made a project where the food mostly looks disgusting, yet some of it is still strangely enticing-probably because the branding is so embedded in our psyches.&quot; He adds, &quot;I may eat it on a lower frequency now.&quot;

What follows is a selection from Jon Feinstein&apos;s &quot;Fast Food.&quot;



 
&quot;2.25 Grams&quot;


 
&quot;2.6 Grams&quot;


 
&quot;4 Grams&quot;


 
&quot;8 Grams&quot;


 
&quot;9 Grams&quot;


 
&quot;11 Grams&quot;


 
&quot;12 Grams&quot;


 
&quot;14 Grams&quot;


 
&quot;17 Grams&quot;


 
&quot;18 Grams&quot;


 
&quot;21 Grams&quot;


 
&quot;26 Grams&quot;


 
&quot;29 Grams&quot;


 
&quot;30 Grams&quot;


 
&quot;39 Grams&quot;


 
&quot;42 Grams&quot;


 To preserve the experience of seeing these foods removed from their branding, the names were not printed below each photo. For those who are interested, the food items shown are, in descending order, as follows: Chicken McNugget (McDonald&apos;s), Chicken Tender (Burger King), Chicken Ring (White Castle), Chicken Wing (KFC), Plain Hamburger (Burger King), Plain Hamburger (White Castle), Cheeseburger (Burger King), Filet-O-Fish ( Burger King McDonald&apos;s), Fried Chicken Breast (KFC), Southern Chicken Sandwich (McDonald&apos;s), Big Mac (McDonald&apos;s), Pepperoni Personal Pan Pizza (Pizza Hut Express), Whopper (Burger King), and Angus Third Pounder Deluxe with Bacon (McDonald&apos;s). 

–
Are you a photographer with a project you would like to share with the GOOD community? Send a brief description and a few sample images (or a link) to photo [at] goodinc [dot] com, and we&apos;ll take a look. If we like it, it might end up as one of our Picture Shows. We look forward to your submissions.

 

 Posted in Design , Picture Show 
More GOOD stuff
 
 Picture Show: You Are What You Eat 
 
 Picture Show: The Garden 
 
 Picture Show: Urban Chickens 
 See Comments Popular Most Discussed Recent 
 1 Most Americans Believe College Is a Right (So What&apos;s the Hangup in Congress?) 2 Making a More Empathetic MBA In the Mumbai Slums 3 Do We Need a &apos;Bar Exam&apos; For Teachers? 4 Oakland Getting First Urban Network of CO2 Sensors 5 Do It Yourself: Submit Your Projects #30DaysofGOOD 
 
 1 Why Supporting Your Local Library Is the Ultimate Homage to Ray Bradbury 2 How to Start an Urban Farm in a Post-Industrial City 3 Young People Are Driving Less—And Not Just Because They&apos;re Broke 4 Is the Certificate the New College Degree? 5 Mobilize.org: Making Civic Engagement a Priority for Millennials 
 
 1 Intermission: San Diego Fireworks FAIL All At Once 2 Recycled Amusement: A Ugandan Playground of Water Bottles 3 Do It Yourself: Get Some Tools #30DaysofGOOD 4 GOOD Ideas for Cities: Uniting Cultural Institutions 5 Do 5-Year-Olds Really Need Career Testing? 
 
Get the Daily GOOD

One good thing a day.
 
Good Elsewhere

 Facebook Youtube Twitter Tumblr 
 
Good Magazine
 
Join GOOD+ and get the magazine.
 SUBSCRIBE 
 Sponsored by University of Phoenix Related posts

 
 Design 
 
 Picture Show: Google This 

Taking our ubiquitous searches to the physical world
The Brazilian Italian artist Filippo Minelli wrote to us about his interest in &quot;exploring...
 by GOOD 
 Design 
 
 Picture Show: Mathieu Young&apos;s &quot;Walkabout&quot; 

A photographer embarks on a long walk across Los Angeles.
Fascinated by the social and cultural diversity of Los Angeles, I embarked on a four...
 by GOOD , Mathieu Young 
 Design 
 
 Picture Show: Guantanamo Bay 

 For nearly three years, Christopher Sims made phone calls and sent letters to various military personnel in order to gain access to the military...
 by GOOD , Christopher Sims 
 
 
 Picture Show: Mayors Across America 

The photographer Ed Morris describes the bicycle as &quot;the perfect vehicle for traveling across the country,&quot; and the mayor as the &quot;perfect...
 by GOOD , Ed Morris 
 Design 
 
 Picture Show: American Faith 

 The word faith often refers to a belief in something not based on proof. From that perspective, the idea of attempting to photograph it would...
 by GOOD , Christopher Churchill 
 Design 
 
 Picture Show: Daughters of Job 

 In the early 1990s, when the photographer Alison Malone was a young girl, she was a member of a private society know as Job&apos;s Daughters, an...
 by GOOD 
 
 
 Picture Show: No Lifeguard on Duty 

 J. Bennett Fitts traveled some 20,000 miles to produce &quot;No Lifeguard on Duty,&quot; an investigation of America&apos;s forgotten roadside motels. These...
 by GOOD , J. Bennett Fitts 
 Design 
 
 Picture Show: At the Truck Stop 

 Before creating his quietly intimate series &quot;Truck Drivers,&quot; the photographer Jon Bakos hadn&apos;t spent a lot of time in truck stops. Of course,...
 by GOOD , Jon Bakos 
 
 
 Picture Show: Palimpsesto Urbano: Mexico City 

 If Mexico City is a book, then it&apos;s one that&apos;s constantly being rewritten. For the photographer Brian Rosa the city is in a constant state of...
 by GOOD , Brian Rosa 
 Design 
 
 Picture Show: A Quiet Heaven in Vrindavan, India 

 The Indian village of Vrindavan is believed by many Hindus to be the physical manifestation of ‘heaven&apos; as well as the place in which the... 
 by GOOD , Shane Lavalette 
 
 
 Picture Show: The Harvest 

 The ongoing battle between medical marijuana advocates and law enforcement has begotten some tricky legality, which has lead to all sorts of...
 by GOOD , Mathieu Young 
 
 
 Picture Show: Crash Tests 

 Crash test dummies, or anthropomorphic test devices, are replications of human forms and weight distributions, used to study potential human...
 by GOOD , Charles Negre 
 
 
 Picture Show: Museology Revisited 

 When Richard Ross&apos;s visual exploration of natural history museums, Museology , was published by Aperture in 1989, its hallmark was a series of...
 by GOOD , Richard Ross 
 
 
 The Year in Picture Shows 

 One year ago, we launched a weekly series called the Picture Show with a simple goal: to offer visual explorations of the world through individual...
 by GOOD 
 Design 
 
 Picture Show: Iraq in the Mojave 

 Army soldiers prepare to role-play insurgents during the Medical Trauma Lane. The green straps are part of a complex &quot;laser tag&quot; system worn... 
 by GOOD 
 Design 
 
 Picture Show: Waiting for the End of the World 

 Self-preservation is something that most humans take quite seriously, and that a few take to extremes. Faced with the real or imagined threat of...
 by GOOD , Richard Ross 
 
 
 Picture Show: Four Days in Dubai 

 Dubai can seem more like a mirage than any place on Earth-even in the shade, it&apos;s marvelously bright. Whether the city is the most precious gem in...
 by GOOD , Dustin Aksland 
 Design 
 
 Picture Show: Kitintale Skate Park in Uganda 

Yann Gross&apos;s &quot;Kintintale Skates,&quot; offers a glimpse at the first skate park in East Africa. Located in the a working class suburb of Kampala,...
 by GOOD 
 Design 
 
 Picture Show: At Home on the Road in Australia 

 In Australia, as in the United States, the idea of keeping house in a mobile home carries no shortage of negative stigma. There&apos;s a default...
 by GOOD 
 
 
 Picture Show: Free Again 

 Crime and punishment. Rehabilitation and reform. Correctional facilities. We use these phrases when we talk about prison, but the distance between...
 by GOOD 
 
 GOOD 

©GOOD Worldwide, LLC.

For people who give a damn.
 Join 
Hubs

 News Business Culture Design Lifestyle Technology 
 
Features

 Infographics Videos Slideshows Projects Get the magazine Manage subscription Current issue Online Store 
 
Company

 About Contact Support Advertise GOOD/Corps Jobs Privacy Terms 
 
Connect

 Twitter Facebook Tumblr YouTube RSS 
 
 Magazine / Check Out the Current Issue Finder / A Collection of What&apos;s Good Now Maker / Make Good Things Happen
	</body>
</document>
