<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000328" url="http://forum.lowyat.net/topic/1131628/all" time="2012-07-12-15:31" support="6" score="0.006516222917069317" bingtitle="USPS Priority Mail International - Lowyat.NET - Insanely Addictive ..." webtitle="USPS Priority Mail International">
			<query id="001390" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="001197" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="001201" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="000272" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="001386" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="000789" bing-rank="214"/>
	<description>Just wondering if the person gave me the tracking number or the receipt reference number cos ... It was near 5 pm actually. Phew!! It was quite tiring running around from one ...</description>
	<body>
		Lowyat.NET   Lowyat.NET Rules and Regulations 

 FAQ Help Search Members Calendar 
 
 Welcome Guest ( Log In | Register )
   Lowyat.NET  -&gt;  Trade Zone  -&gt;  Trade Zone Resource Centre 
   
 
 Outline ·[ Standard ]· Linear+ 

   USPS Priority Mail International , Delivery Time&amp;Kastam
 Share on | Track this topic | Email this topic | Print this topic 
 doli_pargorsi Aug 15 2009, 11:35 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #1 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 9

Joined: Jul 2009


 

 
 
 Hi!

I&apos;m a newbie from PJ&amp;need some advices about my trade below:

I bought one eBay item from US -- costs around US$700 (incld. shipping).
On 03/08/2009 seller shipped it via USPS Priority Mail International (PMI) with extra service&quot;insurance&quot;(considering the$), but it would be without tracking). Shipping ref. no. CP64xxxxxx7US. According to him, it should be arrives in 6 to 10 days.

Until yesterday 14/08/2009 I have not received it yet. So I checked the USPS website, but it says&quot;There is no record of this item&quot;.

My Q are:
1. About the USPS PMI, usually how long it takes to Malaysia? For my case it is more than 2 weeks now. Is that normal?
2. I worry it got&quot;kena tahan kastam&quot;because of the$$$. Until now I haven&apos;t received any call or letter from Pos Malaysia or Kastam yet. So what I should do? Should I call Pos Malaysia first?

Thank you in advance for sharing experience&amp;answering. 
 
 
 
 Crazy.SoT.Gila Aug 15 2009, 11:41 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #2 

ilovekyx
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 1,681

Joined: Sep 2005
From: Oil Town


 

 
 
 Number of days in delivery usually refers to business day. In this case, the 10th day would be the coming Monday. 

 karasawamk2 Aug 16 2009, 12:39 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #3 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 180

Joined: Jan 2007
From: USJ 9, Subang Jaya


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(doli_pargorsi@Aug 15 2009, 11:35 PM) Hi!

I&apos;m a newbie from PJ&amp;need some advices about my trade below:

I bought one eBay item from US -- costs around US$700 (incld. shipping).
On 03/08/2009 seller shipped it via USPS Priority Mail International (PMI) with extra service&quot;insurance&quot;(considering the$), but it would be without tracking). Shipping ref. no. CP64xxxxxx7US. According to him, it should be arrives in 6 to 10 days.

Until yesterday 14/08/2009 I have not received it yet. So I checked the USPS website, but it says&quot;There is no record of this item&quot;.

My Q are:
1. About the USPS PMI, usually how long it takes to Malaysia? For my case it is more than 2 weeks now. Is that normal?
2. I worry it got&quot;kena tahan kastam&quot;because of the$$$. Until now I haven&apos;t received any call or letter from Pos Malaysia or Kastam yet. So what I should do? Should I call Pos Malaysia first?

Thank you in advance for sharing experience&amp;answering.
 I now this is personal but what item u ordering in ebay? 

 Shizuru Aug 16 2009, 12:45 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #4 

Newbie
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 3,574

Joined: May 2006


 

 
 
 2 weeks is normal. Should wait 7-14 working days and this exclude kastam processing which normally take 2-3 working days and pos Malaysia delivery time. If USPS Priority Mail International with insurance should be like registered post right? The processing should be faster if EMS. 

 doli_pargorsi Aug 16 2009, 10:28 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #5 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 9

Joined: Jul 2009


 

 
 
 It is just an used watch.

 This post has been edited by doli_pargorsi : Aug 18 2009, 11:25 PM 

 annariana Aug 17 2009, 11:28 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #6 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 195

Joined: Apr 2009
From: Berkeley, JB, Akita, Dublin, home~


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(doli_pargorsi@Aug 15 2009, 11:35 PM) Hi!

I&apos;m a newbie from PJ&amp;need some advices about my trade below:

I bought one eBay item from US -- costs around US$700 (incld. shipping).
On 03/08/2009 seller shipped it via USPS Priority Mail International (PMI) with extra service&quot;insurance&quot;(considering the$), but it would be without tracking). Shipping ref. no. CP64xxxxxx7US. According to him, it should be arrives in 6 to 10 days.

Until yesterday 14/08/2009 I have not received it yet. So I checked the USPS website, but it says&quot;There is no record of this item&quot;.

My Q are:
1. About the USPS PMI, usually how long it takes to Malaysia? For my case it is more than 2 weeks now. Is that normal?
2. I worry it got&quot;kena tahan kastam&quot;because of the$$$. Until now I haven&apos;t received any call or letter from Pos Malaysia or Kastam yet. So what I should do? Should I call Pos Malaysia first?

Thank you in advance for sharing experience&amp;answering.
 hi there,

USPS priority international DOES NOT provide tracking. as far as i knew, only USPS express mail provides tracking for their stuff the number u get must be the customs reference number. 

 dream-painter Aug 17 2009, 10:30 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #7 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 51

Joined: Jan 2009


 
 
 Parcel from US takes time (if you are not using the express method), around 14-21 days normally.

Sometime even more than 30 days when it is stuck at the Customs 

 

 ilovevs Aug 18 2009, 05:37 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #8 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 18

Joined: Mar 2008


 

 
 
 Hi,

USPS Priority Mail do provide tracking number and you can check it at their website. normally items can reach here around 10 -14 days. you can also call the Pos Malaysia in KLIA and check whether u parcel has arrives.

 

 gizmo_pony Aug 18 2009, 10:15 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #9 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 451

Joined: Jun 2005


 

 
 
 USPS Priority Mail don&apos;t provide tracking no. unless the sender pay more for this additional service.

It is included in case of USPS Express Mail.

Correct me if I&apos;m wrong. I got this info from my friend in US.

 

 doli_pargorsi Aug 18 2009, 11:11 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #10 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 9

Joined: Jul 2009


 

 
 
 Yes, gizmo_pony. Your comment is the same as what my US seller said. He says prefer insure it than tracking.


BTW, thanks you all guys for the comments.


I wonder why my previous trades from Germany using Deutsche Post&amp;cheaper shipmpent, just took only 7&amp;11 days. 

 This post has been edited by doli_pargorsi : Aug 18 2009, 11:39 PM 

 nimrod2 Aug 19 2009, 03:45 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #11 

the imba one
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 2,489

Joined: Jan 2006
From: UrbanSubangJaya


 
 

 
 
 
i guess depends on the courier company. maybe they ship less stuff to malaysia.

i find UPS and royal mail from UK very reliable and fast.
i&apos;ve shipped stuff from UK twice. and both reach to my house within 3 days.
 

 svage98 Aug 19 2009, 04:56 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #12 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 344

Joined: Oct 2007
From: Nilai/Putrajaya/Bangi


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(doli_pargorsi@Aug 15 2009, 11:35 PM) Hi!

I&apos;m a newbie from PJ&amp;need some advices about my trade below:

I bought one eBay item from US -- costs around US$700 (incld. shipping).
On 03/08/2009 seller shipped it via USPS Priority Mail International (PMI) with extra service&quot;insurance&quot;(considering the$), but it would be without tracking). Shipping ref. no. CP64xxxxxx7US. According to him, it should be arrives in 6 to 10 days.

Until yesterday 14/08/2009 I have not received it yet. So I checked the USPS website, but it says&quot;There is no record of this item&quot;.

My Q are:
1. About the USPS PMI, usually how long it takes to Malaysia? For my case it is more than 2 weeks now. Is that normal?
2. I worry it got&quot;kena tahan kastam&quot;because of the$$$. Until now I haven&apos;t received any call or letter from Pos Malaysia or Kastam yet. So what I should do? Should I call Pos Malaysia first?

Thank you in advance for sharing experience&amp;answering.
 What shipping method you using? First Class International, Priority International or Express International?Item which cost RM500 and above including shipping will likely get held with customs but if you do not received any letter from customs yet then that means your stuff haven&apos;t arrived yet in Malaysia.

 Added on August 19, 2009, 5:03 pm QUOTE(gizmo_pony@Aug 18 2009, 10:15 PM) USPS Priority Mail don&apos;t provide tracking no. unless the sender pay more for this additional service.

It is included in case of USPS Express Mail.

Correct me if I&apos;m wrong. I got this info from my friend in US.
 Yup...you are correct there bro. One can insist on tracking for USPS Priority Mail but at an additional cost...same as insurance. The CP64xxxxxx7US is in fact not tracking but the declaration form used for shipping the item.

 This post has been edited by svage98 : Aug 19 2009, 05:03 PM 

 doli_pargorsi Aug 19 2009, 09:02 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #13 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 9

Joined: Jul 2009


 

 
 
 Good news, I received the goods today. 

Found that it had been held at Malaysia Custom since 12/08/2009 until 18/08/2008.

Custom had opened the packing, but luckily nothing missing. They released it without any problem nor duty.

Yes, now I know the C64xxxxxx7US is the US custom reference number (I think the US seller forgot to mention it too).

Case is resolved now. I hope my experience will be useful for other forum members. 

 jas Oct 1 2009, 12:28 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #14 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 13

Joined: Apr 2007


 
 
 QUOTE(doli_pargorsi@Aug 19 2009, 09:02 PM) Good news, I received the goods today. :hyper:

Found that it had been held at Malaysia Custom since 12/08/2009 until 18/08/2008.

Custom had opened the packing, but luckily nothing missing. They released it without any problem nor duty.

Yes, now I know the C64xxxxxx7US is the US custom reference number (I think the US seller forgot to mention it too).

Case is resolved now. I hope my experience will be useful for other forum members.
 Hi there, I&apos;m also facing the same experience and hope that someone here can advice.

I bought an item of ebay and shipper sent it thru USPS priority international mail.
I have a number though not sure its its tracking or customs - CQ33 530X XXXU S

I did go to the USPS site to checked and it tells me this

Detailed Results:

International Dispatch, September 28, 2009, 6:41 am, ISC CHICAGO IL (USPS)
Arrival
Acceptance, September 26, 2009, 10:19 am, FRESNO, TX 77545
Electronic Shipping Info Received, September 26, 2009


does this means that its a tracking number?

can I conclude
that the item left the US port on 28 Sept. ?
arrive by now and with customs?
how long before it reaches me or customs to contact me?

Tried checking with POS. no luck!

 

 star*bug Oct 1 2009, 06:56 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #15 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 37

Joined: Mar 2009


 
 
 hi dear, i just got my parcel from usa thru priority mail, well the item was sent on 17 september and i get it today on 1st of october. so it not necessary take 6-10 days, could be more cuz it kena tahan at malaysia custom.

and priority mail do provide tracking number my dear, in fact, once the seller send the product, the priority mail service will email u to verify your address and stuff, together with your item location, they will update u where your item is at the moment, very efficient and it made me feel secure.



 

 svage98 Oct 1 2009, 10:15 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #16 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 344

Joined: Oct 2007
From: Nilai/Putrajaya/Bangi


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(star*bug@Oct 1 2009, 06:56 PM) hi dear, i just got my parcel from usa thru priority mail, well the item was sent on 17 september and i get it today on 1st of october. so it not necessary take 6-10 days, could be more cuz it kena tahan at malaysia custom.

and priority mail do provide tracking number my dear, in fact, once the seller send the product, the priority mail service will email u to verify your address and stuff, together with your item location, they will update u where your item is at the moment, very efficient and it made me feel secure.
 Priority international does not include tracking or insurance. You&apos;re seller must have included the tracking (meaning he purchase tracking without charging you additional cost). Both tracking and insurance can be purchase for priority international shipping at an additional price. Normally US seller will just quote without tracking&amp;insurance. Because if you purchase them both the price will be about the same as shipping via express mail.

If item got held by customs...you will get a letter within 3-4 days of item held. Letter is sent via poslaju.

 Added on October 1, 2009, 10:34 pm QUOTE(jas@Oct 1 2009, 12:28 PM) Hi there, I&apos;m also facing the same experience and hope that someone here can advice.

I bought an item of ebay and shipper sent it thru USPS priority international mail.
I have a number though not sure its its tracking or customs - CQ33 530X XXXU S

I did go to the USPS site to checked and it tells me this

Detailed Results:

International Dispatch, September 28, 2009, 6:41 am, ISC CHICAGO IL (USPS)
Arrival
Acceptance, September 26, 2009, 10:19 am, FRESNO, TX 77545
Electronic Shipping Info Received, September 26, 2009
does this means that its a tracking number?

can I conclude
that the item left the US port on 28 Sept. ?
arrive by now and with customs?
how long before it reaches me or customs to contact me?

Tried checking with POS. no luck!
 Priority international mail can take up to 2 weeks to reach here...in some cases 3 weeks. Did your seller said the shipping include tracking or not? If you are not sure better ask. If your seller did include tracking in the shipping then you view the tracking at UPSP website. You can also track the item at pos malaysia website as soon it reach Malaysia. If you see nothing there then it haven&apos;t reach yet. For me I give it about 2 weeks the most and then usually I can view the delivery status at pos malaysia website.



 This post has been edited by svage98 : Oct 1 2009, 10:34 PM 

 DeinanCF Oct 20 2009, 10:21 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #17 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 27

Joined: May 2009
From: Subang Jaya


 
 
 I&apos;m waiting for an item to come from US using USPS as well.

Just wondering if the person gave me the tracking number or the receipt reference number cos it&apos;s so damn long.

I specifically asked that there be tracking number and insured.(Probably First Class Priority Mail with insurance?)

1USPSRxxYxxxxxxxxxxxx

the&apos;x&apos;being numbers.

It&apos;s been 2 weeks since it was sent out(6 oct), and the person has not replied my emails regarding the tracking number. But it&apos;s through paypal so I&apos;m not worried, yet.

Anyway, what is Priority Mail referred as here?

 This post has been edited by DeinanCF : Oct 20 2009, 10:25 AM 

 doli_pargorsi Oct 29 2009, 10:00 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #18 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 9

Joined: Jul 2009


 

 
 
 Usually the tracking number is 13 characters.

you may get the info from:
 http://www.usps.com/shipping/trackandconfi...trackandconfirm 

 svage98 Oct 30 2009, 01:53 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #19 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 344

Joined: Oct 2007
From: Nilai/Putrajaya/Bangi


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(DeinanCF@Oct 20 2009, 10:21 AM) I&apos;m waiting for an item to come from US using USPS as well.

Just wondering if the person gave me the tracking number or the receipt reference number cos it&apos;s so damn long.

I specifically asked that there be tracking number and insured.(Probably First Class Priority Mail with insurance?)

1USPSRxxYxxxxxxxxxxxx

the&apos;x&apos;being numbers.

It&apos;s been 2 weeks since it was sent out(6 oct), and the person has not replied my emails regarding the tracking number. But it&apos;s through paypal so I&apos;m not worried, yet.

Anyway, what is Priority Mail referred as here?
 Is considered as parcel mail...which usually can be checked at e-parcel tracking system in pos malaysia website. However...it will only appear if it has entered Malaysia (meaning check in with customs).

Express mail is poslaju so you can check at poslaju tracking 

 doli_pargorsi Oct 31 2009, 10:40 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #20 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 9

Joined: Jul 2009


 

 
 
 QUOTE(svage98@Oct 30 2009, 01:53 PM) Is considered as parcel mail...which usually can be checked at e-parcel tracking system in pos malaysia website. However...it will only appear if it has entered Malaysia (meaning check in with customs).

Express mail is poslaju so you can check at poslaju tracking 
 Hi svage98!

Good to hear that, but I don&apos;t know about it ... interested. Could you explain more? By example maybe ...

I have been waiting for a small parcel from Victoria, AU. It was sent on 05/10/09 via Australia Post-AIRMAIL (insured). The seller gave me the Custom article (form CP74 number). I have checked the reference no. in AU Post&amp;also POS Malaysia web, but no result.
===
never mind. [last week I called them to check my parcel] This morning 02/11/09 I received call from Pos Malaysia today to collect my parcel. 

 This post has been edited by doli_pargorsi : Nov 3 2009, 12:07 AM 

 AskarPerang Nov 3 2009, 10:19 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #21 

~tUPaI...~
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 5,671

Joined: Aug 2007
From: Outer Space


 
 

 
 
 Hi, i would like to know how long is the delivery time from US to Malaysia if i&apos;m using US express mail international? 

 DeinanCF Nov 6 2009, 07:32 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #22 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 27

Joined: May 2009
From: Subang Jaya


 
 
 My last shipment from US took 2 weeks.

My previous shipment was CVxxxxxxxxUS. Was left with a pos laju slip in mail box and only the receiver stated can claim it and no representative allowed.Dunno express or priority mail but it was definitely insured(mentioned by the pos laju master himself).
---------------------------------------------------------------------------
This new one till now haven&apos;t received.

tracking no(?): 1USPSR73Yxxxxxxxxxxxx(x - numbers)
(WTF tracking number??)

I can only speculate that 1USPSR73Yetc is a receipt number and not tracking number.

Anyway, I&apos;ve still got 15 days from a paypal claim. TS was not responsive at all. Of 5 emails only replied once, only to say that it&apos;s in customs, but which customs? US or Malaysia? and that was 2 weeks ago, then no reply again. TS also never mentioned what type of shipping service used. zzz



I received customs letter and got a parcel earlier today, but it&apos;s not from US.

 This post has been edited by DeinanCF : Nov 6 2009, 07:39 PM 

 AskarPerang Nov 6 2009, 10:19 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #23 

~tUPaI...~
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 5,671

Joined: Aug 2007
From: Outer Space


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(AskarPerang@Nov 3 2009, 10:19 PM) Hi, i would like to know how long is the delivery time from US to Malaysia if i&apos;m using US express mail international?
 So anyone know the answer to this question? 

 doli_pargorsi Nov 8 2009, 12:08 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #24 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 9

Joined: Jul 2009


 

 
 
 I never try Express Mail Int&apos;l&apos;coz more expensive, but more reliable (with tracking).
The delivery time depends on volume/ weight of your parcel.

It should be faster than the other two (PMI/ FCMI). Refer this link:
 http://www.usps.com/international/sendpackages.htm 

Sharing my experience with USPS:

USPS First-Class Mail Int&apos;l, FCMI
no tracking number
1 small parcel (weight&lt;0.5 kg)
Total = 6 working days, as follow:
* sent from San Marino, California on 28/08/09
* released by Kastam on 03/09/09
* received on 09/09/09


USPS Priority Mail Int&apos;l, PMI
also small parcel
Total = 12 working days, as follow:
* sent from US on 15/09/09
* released by Kastam on 24/09/09
* received on 05/10/09

 This post has been edited by doli_pargorsi : Nov 8 2009, 12:10 AM 

 ayu Nov 8 2009, 07:03 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #25 

~Great Seller~Excellent service~
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 1,172

Joined: Jul 2006
From: KLANG TELOK PULAI


 
 

 
 
 i bought almost 2K USD from us country with using the USPS..it is no problem at all. Very fast to delivery!!
1week can reach edi . 

 deadfish Dec 8 2009, 10:23 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #26 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 81

Joined: Nov 2006


 

 
 
 QUOTE(AskarPerang@Nov 6 2009, 10:19 PM) So anyone know the answer to this question?  
 I received my Express Mail Intl package from USPS in one week flat...
Tracking was accurate until it reached Msia... then it was silent for 3 days and then boom suddenly reached my house! 

 debbierowe Dec 8 2009, 02:05 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #27 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 300

Joined: May 2009


 


 
 
 bought perfume... a rare french perfume invented in year 1962, not selling in almost every country except US and France...

sending from NY ... x-my fingers... it will reach safe and sounds, if not mistaken they have used as cheap as possible... either Priority Mail® International
or
First-Class Mail® International... this is the consequences of using that damn coupon for&quot;free delivery&quot;

costum open those stuff??? what if they like my stuff and decided to keep it... those m0r0ns? XD 

 shindy Dec 21 2009, 07:48 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #28 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 8

Joined: Dec 2008


 

 
 
 hi , if using the Priority Mail international , got any tax or charger whn arrived malaysia? 

 zzzzzzzzzzzy Dec 22 2009, 10:31 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #29 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 67

Joined: Aug 2008


 
 
 QUOTE(doli_pargorsi@Nov 8 2009, 12:08 AM) USPS First-Class Mail Int&apos;l, FCMI
no tracking number
1 small parcel (weight&lt;0.5 kg)
Total = 6 working days, as follow:
 * sent from San Marino, California on 28/08/09
 * released by Kastam on 03/09/09
 * received on 09/09/09

 just wanna get some feedback, is it really safe to use first class shipping thou it has no tracking number?
I just won a shoe off ebay and is deciding whether to use First Class mail$27 or Priority mail$36... 

 Moogle Stiltzkin Dec 23 2009, 08:42 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #30 

Look at all my stars!!
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 2,206

Joined: Jan 2003


 
 
 Currently it is the sixth day but still no word if my shipping arrived. Tracking sucks.

I think priority mail international by DHL was way better because tracking was very detailed and it arrived in 5-6 days flat to my doorstep.

I paid a bit more for USPS priority mail international for a separate order and the tracking i paid for is bollox and not worth the asking price. Also not as fast as DHL. 

 Mun_ Dec 23 2009, 10:55 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #31 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 89

Joined: Jun 2009
From: ~:HomeSweetHome:~


 

 
 
 QUOTE(zzzzzzzzzzzy@Dec 22 2009, 10:31 PM) just wanna get some feedback, is it really safe to use first class shipping thou it has no tracking number?
I just won a shoe off ebay and is deciding whether to use First Class mail$27 or Priority mail$36...
 As long as you made your payment by Paypal , either one is safe .
( If you&apos;re not received your parcel after 7 days ,can file a Dispute to Paypal - Max:45 days )

If with Tracking no:, you can see your parcel every Single Move at the Screen 

and if Without Tracking no: ,it is something like&apos;Blind Wait&apos; 

 zzzzzzzzzzzy Dec 23 2009, 04:12 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #32 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 67

Joined: Aug 2008


 
 
 ^
thanks alot mun, i&apos;ll be waiting for the postman then =D 

 Moogle Stiltzkin Dec 26 2009, 01:54 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #33 

Look at all my stars!!
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 2,206

Joined: Jan 2003


 
 
 QUOTE(Mun_@Dec 23 2009, 10:55 AM) As long as you made your payment by Paypal , either one is safe .
( If you&apos;re not received your parcel after 7 days ,can file a Dispute to Paypal - Max:45 days )

If with Tracking no:, you can see your parcel every Single Move at the Screen 

and if Without Tracking no: ,it is something like&apos;Blind Wait&apos; 
 USPS tracking is shit. Ok for example this is mine.


 QUOTE Your item cleared customs in MALAYSIA at 11:00 AM on December 25, 2009. Information, if available, is updated periodically throughout the day. Please check again later.

Out of Foreign Customs, December 25, 2009, 11:00 am, MALAYSIA


Into Foreign Customs, December 25, 2009, 10:59 am, MALAYSIA

Arrived Abroad, December 25, 2009, 9:26 am, MALAYSIA

International Dispatch, December 20, 2009, 10:17 pm, ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)


Arrival
Shipment Accepted; December 18, 2009, 4:24 pm, PALM BAY, FL 32905
Electronic Shipping Info Received, December 18, 2009 

They only update only after it had happened, in some instances 1-2 days after x_x; See how there is a big gap between 20 and 25. Where is the tracking for that???

Compared to DHL, DHL informed me all movements no exception. So seriously USPS suX BOLLOX 

Also tracking says out of foreign customs, but when i checked with Poslaju who apparently is the local shipper for USPS in Malaysia, they informed me it&apos;s still at customs and will take 3-4 days. Is the tracker lying or is poslaju lying? 

 This post has been edited by Moogle Stiltzkin : Dec 26 2009, 01:57 PM 

 AskarPerang Dec 27 2009, 07:51 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #34 

~tUPaI...~
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 5,671

Joined: Aug 2007
From: Outer Space


 
 

 
 
 I bought something for my friend. Shipment using Express Mail International®.
Took 7 days to reach.

Here is the tracking:
 http://trkcnfrm1.smi.usps.com/PTSInternetW...m=EC665744786US 


The details:
 QUOTE Bullet Delivered Abroad, December 22, 2009, 10:04 am, MALAYSIA
Bullet Out of Foreign Customs, December 21, 2009, 6:50 pm, MALAYSIA
Bullet Into Foreign Customs, December 21, 2009, 5:33 pm, MALAYSIA
Bullet Arrived Abroad, December 21, 2009, 4:25 pm, MALAYSIA
Bullet International Dispatch, December 16, 2009, 7:10 pm, ISC CHICAGO IL (USPS)
Bullet Arrival
Bullet Electronic Shipping Info Received, December 16, 2009
Bullet Processed through Sort Facility, December 15, 2009, 8:23 pm, NORTH HOUSTON, TX 77315 

 debbierowe Jan 4 2010, 08:39 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #35 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 300

Joined: May 2009


 


 
 
 QUOTE(debbierowe@Dec 8 2009, 02:05 PM) bought perfume... a rare french perfume invented in year 1962, not selling in almost every country except US and France...

sending from NY ... x-my fingers... it will reach safe and sounds, if not mistaken they have used as cheap as possible... either Priority Mail® International
or
First-Class Mail® International... this is the consequences of using that damn coupon for&quot;free delivery&quot;

costum open those stuff??? what if they like my stuff and decided to keep it... those m0r0ns? XD
 USPS Priority Mail International - (package)
package sent 8 Dec 2009
package arrived 30 Dec 2009

good ol 23 days exculde malaysia public holiday, 15 days if public holiday not counted...

but very happy no tax on my perfume.. 

 owikh84 Jan 17 2010, 08:38 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #36 

i7 Clan
 
 Overclocker&apos;s United 

Group: Elite
Posts: 6,074

Joined: Nov 2007
From: Butterworth, PG / Machang, Kelantan


 

 
 
 I bought a a pair of shoes recently.

 USPS Priority Mail 

Label/Receipt Number: CQXXXXXXXXUS
Class: Priority Mail International Parcels
Service(s): International Parcels
Status: Attempted Delivery Abroad

We attempted to deliver your item in MALAYSIA at 8:22 PM on January 16, 2010.

Attempted Delivery Abroad, January 16, 2010, 8:22 pm, MALAYSIA
Attempted Delivery Abroad, January 16, 2010, 3:53 pm, MALAYSIA
Attempted Delivery Abroad, January 16, 2010, 9:20 am, MALAYSIA
Out of Foreign Customs, January 15, 2010, 2:49 pm, MALAYSIA
Into Foreign Customs, January 13, 2010, 6:40 pm, MALAYSIA
Arrived Abroad, January 13, 2010, 4:10 pm, MALAYSIA
International Dispatch, January 05, 2010, 4:35 pm, ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)
Arrival
Electronic Shipping Info Received, January 04, 2010
 

 ArtcoreWarlock Jan 21 2010, 05:43 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #37 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 101

Joined: Dec 2008


 

 
 
 Hi Everybody,

i planning to sell item in ebay. does anybody here have experience shipping item to international from k.l?..what service do you use?

thanks in advance 

 zzzzzzzzzzzy Jan 24 2010, 12:59 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #38 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 67

Joined: Aug 2008


 
 
 Bought a shoe off ebay and my first experience of using First Class Mail International. It has no tracking but I was surprise that it only took 7 days to reach my house.
Much faster compared to my previous Express Priority Mail

Class: First-Class Mail International
-Sent from COLUMBUS, OH, 16 Jan
-Released from kastam 21 Jan
-Received 23 Jan 

 kukarchoon Jan 30 2010, 12:18 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #39 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 110

Joined: Nov 2006


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(ArtcoreWarlock@Jan 21 2010, 05:43 PM) Hi Everybody,

i planning to sell item in ebay. does anybody here have experience shipping item to international from k.l?..what service do you use?

thanks in advance
 Last time i sent a parcel from KL to china using registered mail(pos daftar), the parcel just dropped to receiver&apos;s door without notice the receiver. However, it does provide tracking number, and it&apos;s alot cheaper than other post service. 

 siewsphone Mar 20 2010, 07:46 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #40 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 188

Joined: Mar 2005


 
 
 Do I need to sign for the USPS Priority Mail with Insure? My house always empty on weekdays. 

 Ryan19 May 3 2010, 05:50 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #41 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 32

Joined: Aug 2008


 
 
 Recently, I bought a MX Air Mouse receiver from Ebay seller from L.A.
Label/Receipt Number: LNXXXXXXXXU S
Class: First-Class Mail International
Service(s): International Letter
Status: Electronic Shipping Info Received

The U.S. Postal Service was electronically notified by the shipper on April 30, 2010 to expect your package for mailing. This does not indicate receipt by the USPS or the actual mailing date. Delivery status information will be provided if / when available. Information, if available, is updated periodically throughout the day. Please check again later.

*X-Finger, hope arrive around 1-2 week, since it&apos;s just a small receiver.

Received info:


Shipment Activity Location Date&amp;Time
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Electronic Shipping DIAMOND BAR CA 91765 04/30/10 12:10am
Info Received
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Roughly, when will I receive it? As he posted in a letter form. As the receiver is small less than 1kg.

Currently, received message from ebay seller. Noted he send it thru First Class Mail (letter)

Package sent out on 4/29
Please allow 14-21 business days for international delivery. Sat. and Sunday excluded.
It should be there shortly.
Thank you and have a nice day
Customer Service
Linda H.

After 2-3 weeks, I&apos;ll report here again.

 This post has been edited by Ryan19 : May 4 2010, 09:09 AM 

 hkspower May 6 2010, 11:23 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #42 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 240

Joined: Jan 2003
From: 工口


 

 
 
 Label/Receipt Number: CJU S
Class: Priority Mail International Parcels
Service(s): International Parcels
Status: Attempted Delivery Abroad

We attempted to deliver your item in GREAT BRITAIN at 10:47 AM on May 6, 2010.

Detailed Results:

Bullet Attempted Delivery Abroad, May 06, 2010, 10:47 am, GREAT BRITAIN
Bullet Into Foreign Customs, May 03, 2010, 12:10 pm, MALAYSIA
Bullet Arrival at Transit Office From Exchange, May 03, 2010, 8:23 am, MALAYSIA
Bullet International Dispatch, April 26, 2010, 6:31 pm, ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)
Bullet Arrival
Bullet Arrival
Bullet Arrival at Unit, April 21, 2010, 4:46 am, CUMMING, GA 30041
Bullet Acceptance, April 16, 2010, 12:16 pm, CUMMING, GA 30041
Bullet Electronic Shipping Info Received, April 16, 2010


 wtf!this is epic! 

 corallinkz May 7 2010, 04:35 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #43 

Regular
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 1,227

Joined: Feb 2006
From: 192.168.1.1


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(hkspower@May 6 2010, 11:23 PM) Label/Receipt Number: CJU S
Class: Priority Mail International Parcels
Service(s): International Parcels
Status: Attempted Delivery Abroad

We attempted to deliver your item in GREAT BRITAIN at 10:47 AM on May 6, 2010.

 Detailed Results:

Bullet Attempted Delivery Abroad, May 06, 2010, 10:47 am, GREAT BRITAIN
Bullet Into Foreign Customs, May 03, 2010, 12:10 pm, MALAYSIA
Bullet Arrival at Transit Office From Exchange, May 03, 2010, 8:23 am, MALAYSIA
Bullet International Dispatch, April 26, 2010, 6:31 pm, ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)
Bullet Arrival
Bullet Arrival
Bullet Arrival at Unit, April 21, 2010, 4:46 am, CUMMING, GA 30041
Bullet Acceptance, April 16, 2010, 12:16 pm, CUMMING, GA 30041
Bullet Electronic Shipping Info Received, April 16, 2010
  wtf!this is epic!  
 from US--&gt;malaysia---&gt;great britian? 

 soundsyst64 May 7 2010, 07:14 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #44 

I&apos;m No-Longer-Noobs
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 3,229

Joined: Jul 2005
From: In /hardware/

 

 
 
 QUOTE(Ryan19@May 3 2010, 05:50 PM) Received info:
Shipment Activity    Location               Date&amp;Time
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Electronic Shipping   DIAMOND BAR CA 91765         04/30/10 12:10am
Info Received
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Roughly, when will I receive it? As he posted in a letter form. As the receiver is small less than 1kg.

Currently, received message from ebay seller. Noted he send it thru First Class Mail (letter)

Package sent out on 4/29
Please allow 14-21 business days for international delivery. Sat. and Sunday excluded.
It should be there shortly.
Thank you and have a nice day
Customer Service
Linda H.

After 2-3 weeks, I&apos;ll report here again.
 Since it&apos;s registered mail (when reach to malaysia), it&apos;ll take at least more than 3 weeks. 

 uncle wong Aug 9 2010, 10:44 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #45 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 26

Joined: Dec 2008


 
 
 I got 2 parcel from USA .
Both ship using USPS Priority Mail International ( No insurance added ) ( No tracking number )

 

 

 Received 1 of my small parcel today from US using USPS Priority Mail International ( No insurance added ) ( No tracking number )
Ship from US 01 August . Received 11 August . 

 This post has been edited by uncle wong : Aug 11 2010, 10:35 PM 

 hkspower Aug 10 2010, 02:41 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #46 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 240

Joined: Jan 2003
From: 工口


 

 
 
 only parcel got tracking 

 chamyk2311 Aug 20 2010, 09:40 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #47 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 127

Joined: Dec 2008
From: Sandakan


 
 
 I bought something from US. Ship from 03 August 2010 and still havent received. Hope will arrived by this week. With the status given, is that means my package has passed the custom?



 Attached thumbnail(s) 
 

 shawnspunxx Aug 21 2010, 05:56 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #48 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 24

Joined: Nov 2008


 
 
 QUOTE(chamyk2311@Aug 20 2010, 09:40 AM) I bought something from US. Ship from 03 August 2010 and still havent received. Hope will arrived by this week. With the status given, is that means my package has passed the custom?
 so have you received it? 

 limhongwoon Aug 21 2010, 06:50 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #49 

Intel Certified - COre I7
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 2,723

Joined: Oct 2007
From: Penang


 

 
 
 It take 2 weeks of time ? 

 chamyk2311 Aug 22 2010, 12:39 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #50 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 127

Joined: Dec 2008
From: Sandakan


 
 
 QUOTE(shawnspunxx@Aug 21 2010, 05:56 AM) so have you received it?
 no, not yet 

 ilovevs Aug 24 2010, 10:30 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #51 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 18

Joined: Mar 2008


 

 
 
 QUOTE(chamyk2311@Aug 20 2010, 09:40 AM) I bought something from US. Ship from 03 August 2010 and still havent received. Hope will arrived by this week. With the status given, is that means my package has passed the custom?
 yup, this status shows already passed custom. normally, you should get your item within this week. 

 davinlicious Aug 24 2010, 11:48 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #52 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 267

Joined: Apr 2009
From: peace garden


 
 

 
 
 what item u buy? 

 mhaniff_11 Aug 25 2010, 12:20 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #53 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 121

Joined: Nov 2009


 

 
 
 How long does USPS express mail take to arrive to my doorsteps? 

 shawnspunxx Aug 25 2010, 10:46 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #54 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 24

Joined: Nov 2008


 
 
 QUOTE(mhaniff_11@Aug 25 2010, 12:20 AM) How long does USPS express mail take to arrive to my doorsteps?
 8 to 10 days. 

 leroy87 Aug 26 2010, 02:06 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #55 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 326

Joined: May 2007
From: Melaka Maju Jaya


 
 

 
 
 if your barang gets stucked at customs, will the kastam send u letter saying barang ada ditahan or somthing? or not how u wan to know its stuck there or either the seller scam u? 

 nekko_chan Aug 26 2010, 07:06 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #56 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 4

Joined: Mar 2009


 
 
 Hi,

Just want to share my experience with you guys. 

I bought some lip balms from US. The seller sent the parcel on the 16th of August 2010 but USPS only shipped it on the 21st of August 2010. It arrived at KLIA Pos on the 25th.

Here are the tracking details on my parcel:

 Class: Priority Mail International Parcels
Service(s): International Parcels
Status: Delivered Abroad

Your item was delivered in MALAYSIA at 4:59 pm on August 26, 2010.

Detailed Results:

Delivered Abroad, August 26, 2010, 4:59 pm, MALAYSIA
Out of Foreign Customs, August 26, 2010, 3:31 pm, MALAYSIA
Into Foreign Customs, August 25, 2010, 5:25 pm, MALAYSIA
Arrived Abroad, August 25, 2010, 4:18 pm, MALAYSIA
International Dispatch, August 21, 2010, 4:49 am, ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)
Arrival
Electronic Shipping Info Received, August 16, 2010 

The parcel was detained by Malaysia Customs on the 25th. I called KLIA&apos;s Pusat Mel&amp;Courier Pos Malaysia ( 03-8787 2020 ) after 2 pm today to ask about my parcel and was given a number and the choice to collect the parcel myself or to wait for the letter from Pos Malaysia on Monday. So I decided to go to KLIA&apos;s Pos (it&apos;s a big Pos Malaysia building next to LCCT Terminal) to collect it myself.

First I had to report at room no 2 to get the Pos Malaysia&apos;s letter and a slip with the number of my parcel on it. Then I was directed to counter no 1 to get the parcel. Upon receiving the parcel, I had to submit my visitor&apos;s pass to the counter.

Then I had to go to counter no 5 to open the parcel in front of a custom officer. Here I was asked to declare how many items are in the parcel. He then told me to go to counter no 3 because cosmetic products must be cleared by Pharmaceutical Dept. Then the lady at counter no 3 told me that my items had to be declared first so I was directed back to room no 2 to get some declaration forms (costs RM18). The wait for the forms is quite long (almost 20-30 minutes) so patience is a must here.

Then, after finally receiving the forms, I was directed back to counter no 5 where the officer checked the papers and told me to go to counter no 3 again. The lady at counter no 3 told me to go to Pharmaceutical Dept (which is a building located across the road from Pos Malaysia&apos;s building, so you guys have to drive to go there).

At the Pharmaceutical Dept&apos;s building, I had to go to level 5 and submit my form at the counter there. The lady checked my form and asked for a sample of the product. After scrutinizing the product, she returned it to me. Then she told me that for cosmetic products (in my case lip balms/lipsticks type), they only permit 3 tubes per import as they deemed it to be enough for a month&apos;s usage. To import more than that we need to have a permit. So I was let off with a pink letter of warning. Then she directed me to go to level 3 to get my form photostated (cost me 20 cents) and then back again at level 5 to submit the photostated form to her.

She cleared my forms and then, I was directed back to Pos Malaysia so I went directly to counter no 5 and the custom officer checked the papers and then he directed me to counter no 4. The officer at counter no 4 checked my papers and keyed in some data in the computer, scribbled something on my papers and asked to look at a sample product. Then finally, I was directed back to go to counter no 1 to get my visitor&apos;s pass and the parcel was cleared!No tax needed!And the time of release was NOT 3.31 pm. It was near 5 pm actually.

Phew!!It was quite tiring running around from one counter to another and even going to another building. I guess maybe next time I&apos;ll opt to appoint Pos Malaysia to settle and send the parcel to me instead.


Hope this information is useful to you guys. 

 This post has been edited by nekko_chan : Aug 26 2010, 08:14 PM 

 mhaniff_11 Aug 26 2010, 10:41 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #57 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 121

Joined: Nov 2009


 

 
 
 QUOTE(nekko_chan@Aug 26 2010, 08:06 PM) 

Then I had to go to counter no 5 to open the parcel in front of a custom officer. Here I was asked to declare how many items are in the parcel.
 If my parcel is under gift,and then i have to open the parcel in front of custom officer right?but if they found out there&apos;s a bill of my item,will the item will be taxtable?

 This post has been edited by mhaniff_11 : Aug 26 2010, 10:42 PM 

 nekko_chan Aug 27 2010, 09:06 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #58 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 4

Joined: Mar 2009


 
 
 QUOTE(mhaniff_11@Aug 26 2010, 10:41 PM) If my parcel is under gift,and then i have to open the parcel in front of custom officer right?but if they found out there&apos;s a bill of my item,will the item will be taxtable?
 Yup. I guess every parcel yang kena tahan must be opened in front of the custom officer.

About your item being taxable or vice versa, I think it depends on what the item in your parcel is. For instance in my case, the custom officer put my lip balms under cosmetic products&apos;code that is non-dutiable (and I think luck played a part too because I read somewhere in this thread or some other thread that it depends on the value of the items we imported, if more than certain amount, we&apos;ll be taxed for sure).

But electronic goods definitely will be taxed because there was this one guy before me got taxed 10% from the amount of his stuff.

 This post has been edited by nekko_chan : Aug 27 2010, 09:07 AM 

 limhongwoon Aug 27 2010, 03:05 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #59 

Intel Certified - COre I7
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 2,723

Joined: Oct 2007
From: Penang


 

 
 
 Ebay seller tell that there are no USPS shipping with tracking number and Insurance available to here . 

 mhaniff_11 Aug 27 2010, 05:47 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #60 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 121

Joined: Nov 2009


 

 
 
 my item is declare under warranty repair..how about it?do i need to pay tax too? 

 nekko_chan Aug 30 2010, 09:08 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #61 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 4

Joined: Mar 2009


 
 
 I&apos;m not sure whether my parcel was insured or not but the sender from US did use Priority Mail International Parcel and she gave me a tracking number for it. The whole process is realllly slow though. I am a newbie in this importing stuff and that was my first buy from US. 

I wonder how all those sellers in forums having shopping sprees for cosmetic products from US are importing their goods? And how can we obtain the permit to import cosmetic products in the future? I tried going to the bpfk website but it was not that informative or clear. 

 7thsky Aug 30 2010, 10:30 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #62 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 180

Joined: Dec 2007


 
 
 yes i second that - it&apos;s slow depending on your luck. Mine took 16 days to arrive [USPS International Mail Priority].. that&apos;s the range time given anyway. FedEx took 4 days - of course the cost is a different matter!.. cheers! 

 leftycall9 Aug 30 2010, 05:28 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #63 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 8

Joined: Jun 2010


 
 
 hello everyone,

In my case,I bought a bottle of Mc Cormick brand pure vanilla extract last 31st July.item was shipped on 2nd August from Miami,US via USPS Priority Mail International with custom form number as tracking no. When I checked with USPS website it says :

Label/Receipt Number: LJxxxxxxxUS
Class: Priority Mail International Parcels
Service(s): International Letter
Status: Electronic Shipping Info Received

The U.S. Postal Service was electronically notified by the shipper on August 02, 2010 to expect your package for mailing. This does not indicate receipt by the USPS or the actual mailing date. Delivery status information will be provided if / when available. Information, if available, is updated periodically throughout the day. Please check again later.



Until today I keep receiving this electronic confirmation info,no updates.It was frustrating too since tracking number starts with LJ/LC are not traceable in Malaysia.If I knew earlier I should use more expensive postage even for 1Ib item.

I already contacted the seller about my item not received and she said usually when it comes to international shipping for foods and medical stuff US customs are very slow doing their job.they have to carefully inspects the labels,ingredients and exporting permits/licences of these things before release them for international shipping.

It&apos;s nearly 4 weeks now I haven&apos;t received any call/letter from Malaysia Customs nor Post Malaysia.Last week I went to my local post office,Sibu Sarawak asking about my parcel they said not arrived yet and just be patient. IF my item is being detained or ditahan by Customs,how long does their letter take to arrive to your home to inform you about your parcel? If they send it using normal post Malaysia it could take 2-3 weeks to arrive at my hometown here,Sibu Sarawak. sigh.... 

I also emailed Malaysia Customs regarding taxing of my Mc Cormick vanilla extract. In their reply they said vanilla extract are allowed for importing and not taxable here.However I need to get approval letter or some sort of kelulusan from Ministry of Health.
So my question is,how to get the approval from MOH? As I live in Sarawak this can be big hassle to get the form and submit other documentations in KLIA unless it can be done by post.If you have bought any kind of food (snacks,candy,coffee,tea,food flavourings) from online before,how to get the approval from MOH to release them from customs?

This pure vanilla extract is a gift for my mother she loves baking I want her to get a good taste of real vanilla at least once in her lifetime. Here in Sarawak for baking we are stuck with synthetic vanilla essence Star brand and many locally manufactured.God knows what they made with once I put a teaspoon in and my French toast tasted like eggy cough syrup!

 

 kca Aug 31 2010, 01:58 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #64 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 68

Joined: Jun 2006
From: Selangor, Malaysia


 
 
 how to track priority mail with CPxxxxxx after item reach msia? thanks 

 mhaniff_11 Aug 31 2010, 11:39 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #65 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 121

Joined: Nov 2009


 

 
 
 I just receive my item yesterday..i went to kastam and pick up my item there.. 

 juniorkirk Sep 1 2010, 12:50 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #66 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 31

Joined: Oct 2006


 
 
 QUOTE(kca@Aug 31 2010, 01:58 PM) how to track priority mail with CPxxxxxx after item reach msia? thanks
 poslaju 

 hmloo Sep 4 2010, 01:41 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #67 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 12

Joined: Feb 2010


 
 
 Have purchased a men wrist watch from US website with tracking no. RE xxx xxx xxx US since 25th August 2010 via USPS registered mail. I cannot track on USPS either Pos Malaysia there is no record, seller telling me cannot track USPS online but do call Pos Malaysia for tracking!Do yours know how many days from US to Malaysia? 

 charkuoi Sep 6 2010, 07:21 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #68 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 24

Joined: Apr 2010
From: Land Below The Breeze..


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(mhaniff_11@Aug 31 2010, 11:39 PM) I just receive my item yesterday..i went to kastam and pick up my item there..
 so.. how long u have 2 wait b4 u received ur item r? do u have any letter dat telling u 2 pick up ur item?

i&apos;ve waited more than 1 month for my item dat i purchased from ebay. until now still i didn&apos;t received it. just so u know, i buy 2 item from that sites. total for both of the item is less than rm200
 

 leroy87 Sep 17 2010, 11:36 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #69 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 326

Joined: May 2007
From: Melaka Maju Jaya


 
 

 
 
 how to check the label reciept number for
CJxxxxUS if it alrady stated Out of Foreign customs in the USPS tracking?
Pos laju stil canot track.. 

 beguiler Sep 27 2010, 01:26 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #70 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 145

Joined: Oct 2009


 
 
 is it a must to go kastam there to open my parcel? or i can appoint pos laju to do so?
damn troublesome to go to kastam kernel
hate to see those useless leech too

my item start with CV

 This post has been edited by beguiler : Sep 27 2010, 01:27 PM 

 KenYoung Sep 29 2010, 03:13 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #71 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 170

Joined: Sep 2008


 

 
 
 QUOTE(leroy87@Sep 17 2010, 11:36 AM) how to check the label reciept number for
CJxxxxUS if it alrady stated Out of Foreign customs in the USPS tracking?
Pos laju stil canot track..
 Did you get item at the end? 

 Prevail Sep 29 2010, 11:15 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #72 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 169

Joined: Sep 2010


 
 
 QUOTE(KenYoung@Sep 29 2010, 03:13 AM) Did you get item at the end?
 my case similar too..usps website already stated out of foreign custom clearance since yesterday morning 10am but i still cant track in poslaju today
our government postal service really such a bull..so slow..
 

 MissEndearing Oct 19 2010, 11:09 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #73 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 32

Joined: Oct 2009
From: PJ


 

 
 
 QUOTE Label/Receipt Number:
Class: Priority Mail International Parcels
Service(s): International Parcels
Status: Arrived Abroad

Your item arrived in MALAYSIA at 8:57 am on October 19, 2010. Information, if available, is updated periodically throughout the day. Please check again later.

  Enter Label/Receipt Number.

 Detailed Results:

Arrived Abroad, October 19, 2010, 8:57 am, MALAYSIA
International Dispatch, October 15, 2010, 9:42 pm, ISC LOS ANGELES CA (USPS)
Arrival
Electronic Shipping Info Received, October 14, 2010 Hope i will be receiving it soon =) wohoo 

 Added on October 20, 2010, 8:52 am I wanted to hand collect my parcel so i called pos laju. I am very disapointed with Pos Laju Customer service.

I called 4 times yesterday and 2 times this morning:-

1. First call, the representative told me the parcels are not in the system.
2. 2nd call immediately after i hang up, the representative told me the parcel is on the way to the Post Station from KLIA. She ask me to call back 2 hours time to check which station my parcel will be @ so they can arrange for me to pick up.
3. 3rd call 2 hours later, Parcel not in system.
4. 4th call immediately, my parcel have not reached any post station, ask to call back next day 8.30am.

5. 5th call @ 830am, the rep. again said my parcel is not traceable and not recorded in system.
6. 6th call immediately after 5th, the rep say my parcel is still in KLIA.

What kinda service is this?!

 This post has been edited by MissEndearing : Oct 20 2010, 08:52 AM 

 paull98 Dec 8 2010, 02:27 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #74 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 21

Joined: Dec 2010
From: Sibu, Sarawak


 

 
 
 Class: Priority Mail International
Service(s): International Letter
Status: Processed through Sort Facility

Your item was processed through and left our MINNEAPOLIS, MN 55413 facility on December 01, 2010. The item is currently in transit to the destination. Information, if available, is updated periodically throughout the day. Please check again later.



Track and Confirm

Enter Label/Receipt Number.

Enter Label / Receipt Number.




Detailed Results:

Bullet Processed through Sort Facility, December 01, 2010, 12:46 am, MINNEAPOLIS, MN 55413
Bullet Acceptance, November 30, 2010, 3:40 pm, SAINT PAUL, MN 55121
Bullet Electronic Shipping Info Received, November 29, 2010
Notification Options


Guys does this means my item is out of US or still not dispatch? Arghhh 

 msdevious Dec 8 2010, 08:39 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #75 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 30

Joined: Aug 2010


 
 
 ^Means it&apos;s in transit. Usually takes about 3-5 days to arrive in Malaysia.

 This post has been edited by msdevious : Dec 8 2010, 08:39 PM 

 paull98 Dec 8 2010, 08:56 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #76 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 21

Joined: Dec 2010
From: Sibu, Sarawak


 

 
 
 QUOTE(msdevious@Dec 8 2010, 08:39 PM) ^Means it&apos;s in transit. Usually takes about 3-5 days to arrive in Malaysia.
 If you notice, it has been 6 days since it&apos;s been dispatched (1st DEC) so it was obviously exceeded the usual 3-5days transit time 

 msdevious Dec 8 2010, 09:18 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #77 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 30

Joined: Aug 2010


 
 
 OK, I didn&apos;t notice the&quot;International Letter&quot;part. Forget what I said. It might take longer. For parcels, usually 3-5 days.
Also, your item hasn&apos;t left USA yet. After processed through sort facility, you will see something like this:

International Dispatch, December 04, 2010, 5:31 pm, ISC SAN FRANCISCO (USPS)
Arrival
Electronic Shipping Info Received, December 04, 2010
Processed through Sort Facility, December 03, 2010, 5:41 pm, SEATTLE, WA 98168
Acceptance, December 03, 2010, 9:50 am, SEATTLE, WA 98109

 This post has been edited by msdevious : Dec 8 2010, 09:20 PM 

 soundsyst64 Dec 8 2010, 09:39 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #78 

I&apos;m No-Longer-Noobs
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 3,229

Joined: Jul 2005
From: In /hardware/

 

 
 
 priority mail international is not an express service. It still take about 2 weeks to arrive, like First-Class Mail International. The only difference is priority mail international have tracking number.

if want express service, use Express mail international, but of course it&apos;ll cost you more.

 

 svage98 Dec 8 2010, 10:39 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #79 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 344

Joined: Oct 2007
From: Nilai/Putrajaya/Bangi


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(paull98@Dec 8 2010, 08:56 PM) If you notice, it has been 6 days since it&apos;s been dispatched (1st DEC) so it was obviously exceeded the usual 3-5days transit time
 As stated above...priority mail is not EMS so it is totally impossible that it will arrive here in Malaysia within 3-5 days. That would be Express Mail. Priority mail usually takes 2-3 weeks...but during holiday rush like Christmas sometimes mails can be a bit slower than expected 

 This post has been edited by svage98 : Dec 8 2010, 10:39 PM 

 paull98 Dec 9 2010, 12:52 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #80 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 21

Joined: Dec 2010
From: Sibu, Sarawak


 

 
 
 Your item was processed through and left our MINNEAPOLIS, MN 55413 facility on December 01, 2010. The item is currently in transit to the destination . Information, if available, is updated periodically throughout the day. Please check again later.



The highlighted sentence really confused me now, it can be explained as either in transit to another sorting center or to Malaysia. If it is out of US it should be International dispatch following by a date just like what msdevious showed us.

The official website of USPS stated that Express and Priority Mail International only takes 6-10 days. varies by country for First Class International, That was why i chose to use Priority because it takes about the same time compare to Express but cheaper.

 This post has been edited by paull98 : Dec 9 2010, 01:03 AM 

 msdevious Dec 9 2010, 02:25 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #81 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 30

Joined: Aug 2010


 
 
 QUOTE(svage98@Dec 8 2010, 10:39 PM) As stated above...priority mail is not EMS so it is totally impossible that it will arrive here in Malaysia within 3-5 days. I was responding to the transit time between USA and Malaysia. I&apos;ve used both Priority and Express, not much difference. 

For example, one of my Priority Item tracking:
 CODE Arrived Abroad, November 08, 2010, 5:49 pm, MALAYSIA
International Dispatch, November 04, 2010, 8:53 am, ISC CHICAGO IL(USPS) 

compared with my Express item:
 CODE Arrived Abroad, December 08, 2010, 3:59 pm, MALAYSIA
International Dispatch, December 04, 2010, 5:31 pm, ISC SAN FRANCISCO(USPS) 

Both takes four days to arrive in Malaysia. 

In Paul&apos;s case, I believe the item is still in transit to the final destination before International Dispatch and might be slower because it&apos;s in the&quot;Letter&quot;class? Not sure though. Mine are both parcels. And since it&apos;s near Christmas time, I expect many people would be sending Xmas cards so that might cause some delay too. 

 paull98 Dec 9 2010, 04:57 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #82 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 21

Joined: Dec 2010
From: Sibu, Sarawak


 

 
 
 QUOTE(msdevious@Dec 9 2010, 02:25 AM) I was responding to the transit time between USA and Malaysia. I&apos;ve used both Priority and Express, not much difference. 

For example, one of my Priority Item tracking:
 CODE Arrived Abroad, November 08, 2010, 5:49 pm, MALAYSIA
International Dispatch, November 04, 2010, 8:53 am, ISC CHICAGO IL(USPS) 

compared with my Express item:
 CODE Arrived Abroad, December 08, 2010, 3:59 pm, MALAYSIA
International Dispatch, December 04, 2010, 5:31 pm, ISC SAN FRANCISCO(USPS) 

Both takes four days to arrive in Malaysia. 

In Paul&apos;s case, I believe the item is still in transit to the final destination before International Dispatch and might be slower because it&apos;s in the&quot;Letter&quot;class? Not sure though. Mine are both parcels. And since it&apos;s near Christmas time, I expect many people would be sending Xmas cards so that might cause some delay too.
 msdevious, thanks a lot for showing me the previous delivery detail you have with USPS i must say it is very useful for those who are seeking for references. After your last post regarding the transit i have the same feeling it is still in the US so i emailed the seller to check but he claimed that the items has been dispatched and out of US since 1st Dec.

He further explained that Everything seems to be delayed because of the christmas season but i should be seeing it pretty soon. Normally when the package leaves foreign customs is the next time that it is scanned and it normally takes about 6-10 days in foreign customs.

I don&apos;t trust him! 

 

 hkspower Dec 9 2010, 10:59 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #83 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 240

Joined: Jan 2003
From: 工口


 

 
 
 2 week is the standard time for delivery 

 bakrul Dec 10 2010, 08:55 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #84 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 23

Joined: Apr 2010


 
 
 Detailed Results:

Delivered Abroad, December 08, 2010, 1:54 pm, MALAYSIA
Attempted Delivery Abroad, December 07, 2010, 9:38 am, MALAYSIA
Out of Foreign Customs, December 04, 2010, 10:29 am, MALAYSIA
Into Foreign Customs, December 04, 2010, 9:43 am, MALAYSIA
Arrived Abroad, December 04, 2010, 9:42 am, MALAYSIA
International Dispatch, November 28, 2010, 11:13 am, ISC SAN FRANCISCO (USPS)
Arrival
Electronic Shipping Info Received, November 24, 2010
Acceptance, November 24, 2010, 3:34 pm, DONALD, OR 97020


just want 2 share 

 svage98 Dec 10 2010, 10:17 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #85 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 344

Joined: Oct 2007
From: Nilai/Putrajaya/Bangi


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(paull98@Dec 9 2010, 12:52 AM) Your item was processed through and left our MINNEAPOLIS, MN 55413 facility on December 01, 2010. The item is currently in transit to the destination . Information, if available, is updated periodically throughout the day. Please check again later.
The highlighted sentence really confused me now, it can be explained as either in transit to another sorting center or to Malaysia. If it is out of US it should be International dispatch following by a date just like what msdevious showed us.

The official website of USPS stated that Express and Priority Mail International only takes 6-10 days. varies by country for First Class International, That was why i chose to use Priority because it takes about the same time compare to Express but cheaper.
 The official website state Express Mail takes 3-5 days while Priority Mail takes 6-10 days...both not the same http://www.usps.com/international/sendpackages.htm 

 paull98 Dec 10 2010, 01:48 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #86 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 21

Joined: Dec 2010
From: Sibu, Sarawak


 

 
 
 QUOTE(bakrul@Dec 10 2010, 08:55 AM) Detailed Results:

Delivered Abroad, December 08, 2010, 1:54 pm, MALAYSIA
Attempted Delivery Abroad, December 07, 2010, 9:38 am, MALAYSIA
Out of Foreign Customs, December 04, 2010, 10:29 am, MALAYSIA
Into Foreign Customs, December 04, 2010, 9:43 am, MALAYSIA
Arrived Abroad, December 04, 2010, 9:42 am, MALAYSIA
International Dispatch, November 28, 2010, 11:13 am, ISC SAN FRANCISCO (USPS)
Arrival
Electronic Shipping Info Received, November 24, 2010
Acceptance, November 24, 2010, 3:34 pm, DONALD, OR 97020
just want 2 share
 Nice bakrul, you got your shipment in exactly 10 days, today is the 10th days for mine and i see nothing even in the tracking i don&apos;t see the international dispatch status. I think the seller conned me!

My USPS update stopped on 1st Dec till now, were yours updated frequently during the transit? i mean do you get new status every times it got to a different location or was it being updated at once after u received ur shipment?

 This post has been edited by paull98 : Dec 10 2010, 02:00 PM 

 pureen Dec 10 2010, 04:15 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #87 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 1

Joined: Jun 2010


 
 
 I lost 5 parcels, bought from ebay (all in aug-sept). they give tracking no but once out from us cannot trace it anymore. 2 seller refund but the rest its ok.. they r not mine

I read somewhere there are few cases of stolen parcel in klia.. now i stop from spending overseas.. 

 paull98 Dec 12 2010, 12:25 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #88 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 21

Joined: Dec 2010
From: Sibu, Sarawak


 

 
 
 QUOTE(pureen@Dec 10 2010, 04:15 PM) I lost 5 parcels, bought from ebay (all in aug-sept). they give tracking no but once out from us cannot trace it anymore. 2 seller refund but the rest its ok.. they r not mine

I read somewhere there are few cases of stolen parcel in klia.. now i stop from spending overseas..
 bad bad bad news for me.. 

 Added on December 17, 2010, 10:59 pm QUOTE(hkspower@Dec 9 2010, 10:59 PM) 2 week is the standard time for delivery
 3 weeks by now and my tracking status stay unchanged, out of US but no where to be seen. Even my snail mail without register from HK has arrived which i bought at the same time, guess USPS priority international wasn&apos;t that reliable after all. Maybe it is the seller who conned me..

 Added on December 26, 2010, 12:28 pm Merry Xmas everyone!Guess i lost my Xmas present this time, my parcel is still no where to be seen and USPS got it sent out on 01 Dec so i assume it is lost.

Anybody experience a lost parcel or letter from USPS? Mine is USPS priority mail international.

 This post has been edited by paull98 : Dec 26 2010, 12:28 PM 

 KronenZerg Dec 28 2010, 01:49 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #89 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 209

Joined: Nov 2006


 
 
 Just to let everybody know, i ordered my stuff from US on 22-Dec10. It was shipped on 23-Dec and arrived in Customs on 26Dec.
It was cleared on 28-Dec AM and i received the parcel on 28-Dec PM. Luckily no taxes since my stuff was ard RM600.

However, my order shipment was through Express International mail (Based on the website international shipping)
So, it is quite efficient and timely manner. 

Just be patient ....

 

 paull98 Dec 29 2010, 12:15 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #90 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 21

Joined: Dec 2010
From: Sibu, Sarawak


 

 
 
 QUOTE(KronenZerg@Dec 28 2010, 01:49 PM) Just to let everybody know, i ordered my stuff from US on 22-Dec10. It was shipped on 23-Dec and arrived in Customs on 26Dec.
It was cleared on 28-Dec AM and i received the parcel on 28-Dec PM. Luckily no taxes since my stuff was ard RM600.

However, my order shipment was through Express International mail (Based on the website international shipping)
So, it is quite efficient and timely manner.  

Just be patient ....
 Glad that you received your Xmas present in such a short period, did you receive your package through Pos Laju service instead of Pos Msia? If you don&apos;t mind would you pm me your tracking number so i can find out what service it uses when it arrive Msia because all the Tracking starting with L is handle by Pos Msia whereby starting with C and E are handle by Pos Laju.
 

 KronenZerg Dec 29 2010, 11:20 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #91 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 209

Joined: Nov 2006


 
 
 QUOTE(paull98@Dec 29 2010, 12:15 AM) Glad that you received your Xmas present in such a short period, did you receive your package through Pos Laju service instead of Pos Msia? If you don&apos;t mind would you pm me your tracking number so i can find out what service it uses when it arrive Msia because all the Tracking starting with L is handle by Pos Msia whereby starting with C and E are handle by Pos Laju.
 My parcel was delivered via Pos Laju cos mine was Express Mail Shipment.
Correction on the tracking ... out from custom 28-Dec AM and received in the same day, 5hrs later.

See the initial infront .. which stated&quot;EC&quot;



 Attached thumbnail(s) 
 

 nad Jan 1 2011, 06:20 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #92 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 1

Joined: Feb 2008


 
 
 QUOTE(paull98@Dec 29 2010, 12:15 AM) Glad that you received your Xmas present in such a short period, did you receive your package through Pos Laju service instead of Pos Msia? If you don&apos;t mind would you pm me your tracking number so i can find out what service it uses when it arrive Msia because all the Tracking starting with L is handle by Pos Msia whereby starting with C and E are handle by Pos Laju.
 Hi,

Just to share my experienced when you are buying stuffs from US and shipping using USPS

1) When the shipping label given (so call&apos;tracking #&apos;) begin with the letters&apos;LC&apos;/&apos;LJ&apos;, you can only track them until port of departure in US. (use USPS tracking on-line web)

2) When the shipping label given (so call&apos;tracking #&apos;) begin with the letters&apos;CP&apos;/&apos;CQ&apos;, you can only track them until to you door step. Once the item
arrived in Malaysia, you need to use&apos;Pos laju&apos;tracking at the website or if your item was held by the custom, they will inform you ( no experience before) or you can call pos malaysia.

Therefore, if you want to track your stuff on-line up to door step, please advise your seller to provide tracking # with starting letter&quot;C&quot;NOT letter&quot;L&quot;. Better pay for the tracking #
starts with letter&quot;C&quot;.

OR

You can use trusted group&apos;spree&apos;buying from US that provided from member in the forum.

Please advise if I&apos;m wrong on the above information.

Thanks 

 Prince J Jan 1 2011, 08:04 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #93 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 203

Joined: May 2010
From: Johor - Kluang


 

 
 
 Hey there,

Just want to ask if I am planning to buy Iphone 3gs lcd replacement part from US, will it get taxes?? Which mail shall I use?
The item is just$23.

Too expensive to buy here, almost double the price.
 

 pukakayama Jan 3 2011, 12:25 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #94 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 2

Joined: Jan 2011


 
 
 Hi,
i purchase a phone from ebay US and below is the shipping detail.i tried to call klia custom and klia post office, all given the same answer unable to check the item location. refer to the seller, USPS replied item have been arrived in Malaysia. any idea who should i refer to?any contact number?Appreciate your help.


Label/Receipt Number: LJ60 3869 874U S
Service(s): International Letter
Status: Processed through Sort Facility

Your item was processed through and left our CHICAGO, IL 60688 facility on October 09, 2010. The item is currently in transit to the destination. No further information is available for this item. 

 Sylverphyre Jan 7 2011, 04:14 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #95 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 2

Joined: Dec 2009


 
 
 Hey, just wondering if this means my package is stuck in customs?

Into Foreign Customs, January 06, 2011, 8:33 pm, MALAYSIA
Out of Foreign Customs, January 06, 2011, 6:54 pm, MALAYSIA
Into Foreign Customs, January 06, 2011, 4:22 pm, MALAYSIA
Arrived Abroad, January 06, 2011, 4:21 pm, MALAYSIA

Wondering how come&quot;Into Foreign Customs&quot;popped again after&quot;Out of Foreign Customs&quot;...

Really hoped to get my package by the weekend... SIGH... 

 georgelimsk Jan 11 2011, 04:54 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #96 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 305

Joined: Sep 2008


 
 
 wat this means? will pos laju send me a letter inform me to collect the parcel if im not at home on the time of delivery.

Detailed Results:

Attempted Delivery Abroad, January 10, 2011, 11:14 am, MALAYSIA
Out of Foreign Customs, January 10, 2011, 10:34 am, MALAYSIA
Into Foreign Customs, January 06, 2011, 4:12 pm, MALAYSIA
Arrived Abroad, January 06, 2011, 4:11 pm, MALAYSIA
International Dispatch, December 24, 2010, 10:03 am, FOREIGN CENTERJERSEY CITY NJ 099
Arrival
Electronic Shipping Info Received, December 23, 2010

btw i bought similar items from germany with DHL

05.01.11 11:24 Hours DE The instruction data for this shipment have been provided by the sender to DHL electronically
05.01.11 13:28 Hours -- The shipment has been picked up
05.01.11 18:16 Hours Bielefeld, DE The international shipment has been processed in the parcel center of origin
06.01.11 05:50 Hours Saulheim, DE The international shipment has been processed in the export parcel center
07.01.11 12:28 Hours IPZ-Ffm, DE The shipment is being transported to the destination country
11.01.11 09:28 Hours MY The shipment has arrived in the destination country
11.01.11 09:29 Hours MY The shipment has been delivered to customs in the destination countr

USPS really suck compare to DHL. worse is partner with pos malaysia.

 This post has been edited by georgelimsk : Jan 11 2011, 04:57 PM 

 Strawberry&lt;3 Jan 11 2011, 05:13 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #97 

www.ai-syoping.com
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 1,586

Joined: Sep 2009
From: Ai Syoping


 

 
 
 QUOTE(georgelimsk@Jan 11 2011, 04:54 PM) wat this means? will pos laju send me a letter inform me to collect the parcel if im not at home on the time of delivery.

Detailed Results:
 
 Attempted Delivery Abroad , January 10, 2011, 11:14 am, MALAYSIA
Out of Foreign Customs, January 10, 2011, 10:34 am, MALAYSIA
Into Foreign Customs, January 06, 2011, 4:12 pm, MALAYSIA
Arrived Abroad, January 06, 2011, 4:11 pm, MALAYSIA
International Dispatch, December 24, 2010, 10:03 am, FOREIGN CENTERJERSEY CITY NJ 099
Arrival
Electronic Shipping Info Received, December 23, 2010

btw i bought similar items from germany with DHL

05.01.11 11:24 Hours DE The instruction data for this shipment have been provided by the sender to DHL electronically 
05.01.11 13:28 Hours -- The shipment has been picked up 
05.01.11 18:16 Hours Bielefeld, DE The international shipment has been processed in the parcel center of origin 
06.01.11 05:50 Hours Saulheim, DE The international shipment has been processed in the export parcel center 
07.01.11 12:28 Hours IPZ-Ffm, DE The shipment is being transported to the destination country 
11.01.11 09:28 Hours MY The shipment has arrived in the destination country 
11.01.11 09:29 Hours MY The shipment has been delivered to customs in the destination countr

USPS really suck compare to DHL. worse is partner with pos malaysia.
 Yes, they will leave a card/letter for u to go to collect the parcel at pos office or u can call them to re-attempt the next day. 

 georgelimsk Jan 11 2011, 05:58 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #98 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 305

Joined: Sep 2008


 
 
 hm...im in kl now...i called home...my mom said apa pun tarak...=( 

 Strawberry&lt;3 Jan 11 2011, 06:02 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #99 

www.ai-syoping.com
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 1,586

Joined: Sep 2009
From: Ai Syoping


 

 
 
 QUOTE(georgelimsk@Jan 11 2011, 05:58 PM) hm...im in kl now...i called home...my mom said apa pun tarak...=(
 maybe they didn&apos;t attempt or tomorrow only receive th eletter.. but to be sure better call them to ask 

 georgelimsk Jan 13 2011, 11:48 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #100 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 305

Joined: Sep 2008


 
 
 i have received my stuff...just happened that my mom was opening the gate they were there...=) 

 mydaus Jan 13 2011, 10:33 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #101 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 1

Joined: Apr 2009


 

 
 
 my experience buying @ eBay from US, mail by U.S. Postal Service.

Payment made on 4th Jan 2011.

Shipping details
Mailing date: Jan 5, 2011
Shipper: U.S. Postal Service
Tracking number: LJxxxxxxxxxUS
Service type: Priority Mail International®
Shipping Status: Shipped

Item received on the 13th Jan 2010.

The tracking number is useless, info not up to date via their website... 

 msdevious Jan 14 2011, 02:46 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #102 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 30

Joined: Aug 2010


 
 
 ^Anything starting with LJ... can&apos;t be tracked.
Priority Mail International and Express Mail International starting with C... and E... can. 

 bakrul Jan 14 2011, 07:28 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #103 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 23

Joined: Apr 2010


 
 
 QUOTE(mydaus@Jan 13 2011, 10:33 PM) my experience buying @ eBay from US, mail by U.S. Postal Service.

Payment made on 4th Jan 2011.

Shipping details
Mailing date: Jan 5, 2011
Shipper: U.S. Postal Service
Tracking number: LJxxxxxxxxxUS
Service type: Priority Mail International®
Shipping Status: Shipped

Item received on the 13th Jan 2010.

The tracking number is useless, info not up to date via their website...
 even r service type is Priority Mail international but it look like it a flat rate priority and LJ can be track as shipping status only.at least we know that order had been shipped out just wait patiently. 

 Shazzac Jan 19 2011, 03:43 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #104 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 345

Joined: Jul 2006


 

 
 
 For me, usually:

USPS First Class Mail - from California to Shah Alam - will take min 10 days to max 14 days. Never more than that. Anything that came out from any ulu cities, will take double the time. Usually east coast will go through main in Florida and west coast will go through main in California.

USPS Priority Mail - usually 10 days will reach, never more.

Actually can say that it&apos;s quite fast dy.

Once I bought something from China - took a damn 5 weeks to reach. WTH? 

 I&lt;3LYN Jan 20 2011, 12:43 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #105 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 492

Joined: Sep 2009
From: Sri Petaling


 

 
 
 I lost a gift worth RM200+ with USPS Priority Mail International..... it has been almost 2 months... it has never arrive... 

 +h0m@s.. Jan 25 2011, 01:41 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #106 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 236

Joined: Sep 2008


 

 
 
 LNXXXXXXXXXUS

can i know what does this mean?? the seller said this is the tracking number but in usps website and pos laju website both got no record wo.. can i know what happened?? 

 Enigmatic Jan 25 2011, 02:15 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #107 

I will do it, just because I can. Problem?
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 2,652

Joined: Jan 2005
From: Nowhere Everywhere Status: Banned


 

 
 
 QUOTE(+h0m@s..@Jan 25 2011, 01:41 AM) LNXXXXXXXXXUS

can i know what does this mean?? the seller said this is the tracking number but in usps website and pos laju website both got no record wo.. can i know what happened??
 First Class Mail International, not trackable. 

 This post has been edited by Enigmatic : Jan 25 2011, 02:15 AM 

 december88 Jan 25 2011, 07:00 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #108 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 401

Joined: Nov 2007
From: KL


 

 
 
 QUOTE(Shazzac@Jan 19 2011, 03:43 PM) Once I bought something from China - took a damn 5 weeks to reach. WTH?
 It&apos;s confirm by sea instead of air mail.

 QUOTE(I&lt;3LYN@Jan 20 2011, 12:43 PM) I lost a gift worth RM200+ with USPS Priority Mail International..... it has been almost 2 months... it has never arrive...
 Request for post office to track your stuff.
Ask your seller to initiate this.
Sure it takes time, but since you already come to terms with this, I say give it a go.
Never know what surprise awaits you one day when the postman brings you lost item back. 

 neilisa Feb 24 2011, 11:11 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #109 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 3

Joined: Oct 2009


 
 
 Hi guys,

I need some help from you about usps first class mail.

I&apos;ve ordered few items from US before via usps first class mail and receive it safely not more than 2 weeks.

This is my 1st experience about parcel didn&apos;t reach me. Since 19 Jan 2011 the seller post the item until now I didn&apos;t get my parcel. It&apos;s 3 set of phone casing worth RM300.

I&apos;ve contact the seller and ask about my item. He said he&apos;ll call the post office and after 2 days he said the parcel hung up at Malaysian custom, just give them a call and give your name and address they will process it for clearing.

This morning I called Kastam Pos Malaysia KLIA. No answer from 8.30am until 10.40am, the officer pick up my call and I ask her about my case. And she answer it rudely that&quot;no tracking number no talk, name and address not accepted and please confirm that my parcel really held by kastam.&quot;

I&apos;ve waited almost a month and no letter from kastam or pos malaysia about my parcel being held.


How do you know if the parcel held by kastam because the usps first class mail don&apos;t have tracking number?


 

 Jenglot Mar 2 2011, 05:28 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #110 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 226

Joined: Jan 2003
From: Kuala Lumpur


 

 
 
 Hai,

how you guys check USPS tracking in poslaju website..Its under which service? e-Parcel,Pos Express,PosDaftar??

Order something from ebay.seller ship using First-Class Mail International
now already 3 weeks..

check from USPS website:

Label/Receipt Number: LJ0xxxxxxxxUS
Class: First-Class Mail International
Service(s): International Letter
Status: Processed through Sort Facility

Detailed Results:

Processed through Sort Facility, February 09, 2011, 9:35 pm, MINNEAPOLIS, MN 55413
Acceptance, February 09, 2011, 3:36 pm, MAPLE PLAIN, MN 55359
Electronic Shipping Info Received, February 09, 2011


try to check with pos malaysia customer service, the lady told me, anything start with L cannot be trace. 

 HeavenDust Mar 23 2011, 08:31 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #111 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 4

Joined: Feb 2009


 

 
 
 Hey guys,
I&apos;m a prolific online buyer (Ebay and Etsy are my usual haunts) and from my experiences USPS First Class Mail is the cheapest, non-trackable, non-insured mailing option possible. Your chance with Pos Malaysia is 50-50. USPS Priority Mail is a step up: you get a tracking number with limited tracking, and no insurance. Having said that, this is very important: Just because you think you used USPS Priority Mail International as your shipping method, that doesn&apos;t mean you&apos;re safe. Some sellers tell you they use Priority Mail but ship using First Class instead. Some use Priority and give you tracking numbers that start with&quot;L&quot;like&quot;LN&quot;or&quot;LJ&quot;- these are NOT TRACKABLE IN MALAYSIA!Malaysia will treat these as normal mail, and it has no guarantee of reaching you, making your chances 50-50 as well. It is no different from First Class Mail.

However, I&apos;ve recently bought a bag and it was also shipped via Priority Mail Parcel, and the tracking number starts with&quot;C&quot;. In my experience, USPS Express Mail tracking number also begins with&quot;C&quot;, and they&apos;re much better in terms of tracking and your chances of getting them. I say chances, because our Pos Malaysia are just a bunch of nincompoop monkeys with sticky fingers. In 2010 alone I&quot;lost&quot;about 20 parcels from various sellers out of... oh, 40-50. That&apos;s a very HIGH percentage.

So, my advice to everyone is this: If the item is highly valued, very important to you and you want it to reach you safely - either use courier services like UPS (not to be confused with USPS), DHL or FedEx. Or, if you want to be cost effective use USPS Express Mail, and make sure there&apos;s insurance. I no longer use First Class or even Priority now unless the tracking number starts with&quot;C&quot;. And of course, use Express Mail. Trust me, your sanity and peace of mind are worth the hefty price tag.

Get your tracking number from the seller, and go to usps.com to track your items. If you see&quot;Into Foreign Customs&quot;for a long time with it not moving, chances are it&apos;s being held and you should check to see what&apos;s holding it up. I haven&apos;t tried this personally, just part of the information I&apos;d gathered researching about lost parcels and other people&apos;s experiences.

HTH!

 Added on March 23, 2011, 8:35 pm QUOTE(Jenglot@Mar 2 2011, 05:28 PM) Hai,

how you guys check USPS tracking in poslaju website..Its under which service? e-Parcel,Pos Express,PosDaftar??

Order something from ebay.seller ship using  First-Class Mail International
now already 3 weeks..

check from USPS website:

Label/Receipt Number: LJ0xxxxxxxxUS
Class: First-Class Mail International
Service(s): International Letter
Status: Processed through Sort Facility

Detailed Results:

Processed through Sort Facility, February 09, 2011, 9:35 pm, MINNEAPOLIS, MN 55413
Acceptance, February 09, 2011, 3:36 pm, MAPLE PLAIN, MN 55359
Electronic Shipping Info Received, February 09, 2011
try to check with pos malaysia customer service, the lady told me, anything start with L cannot be trace.
 USPS First Class Mail is not trackable. Your tracking number starting with&quot;L&quot;which is in your case,&quot;LJ&quot;, will be treated as normal mail and takes roughly 3-4 weeks to arrive. You won&apos;t be able to check it on our local pos malaysia website either, I&apos;ve tried. Good luck to you.

 This post has been edited by HeavenDust : Mar 23 2011, 08:39 PM 

 Jenglot Mar 24 2011, 05:11 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #112 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 226

Joined: Jan 2003
From: Kuala Lumpur


 

 
 
 My experience using Priority Mail...

 Tracking Via Pos Malaysia.. Item arrive in KLIA on 21st...received Kastam letter on 23rd..Today go and collect my parcel and pay tax + documentation fee

 Tracking via USPS. a bit more info compare to Pos Malaysia..

So far quite satisfy with the time. Still waiting for another parcel. The seller ship using USPS First-Class Mail International. Almost 2 month..no news.. 

 hkspower Mar 24 2011, 07:15 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #113 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 240

Joined: Jan 2003
From: 工口


 

 
 
 f*** normal airmail, 3rd time a row nothing came

Dec9 lost feb 22,24 still nowhere 2 b seen
 

 Magnum7997 Mar 25 2011, 01:11 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #114 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 5

Joined: Mar 2010


 
 
 After 1 month, still stuck on California my parcel. There goes RM 600+ worth of stuff. 

 HeavenDust Mar 26 2011, 06:43 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #115 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 4

Joined: Feb 2009


 

 
 
 Finally found the answer... damn the stupid USPS site for being so confusing!

OK, here&apos;s the breakdown:
USPS Priority Mail are divided into many types. This page illustrates best what I&apos;m describing. Most sellers will use small Flat Rate boxes, and on that page, it&apos;s the 4th item under Priority Mail International Options. THESE ARE NOT TRACKABLE. If you click the small question mark next to it they will say so too. These options&apos;tracking numbers will start with L, and treated as normal mail in Malaysia.

 QUOTE Priority Mail International Small Flat Rate Box, is a Letter-post service.
Tracking is not available for the Priority Mail International Small Flat Rate Box, but is an available added service for Priority Mail International Medium or Large Flat Rate Boxes. 

However, you can request the seller to use the first option (the one that starts at$32) because it&apos;ll be treated as *parcel* in Malaysia, and hence, I believe will be handled by Poslaju.

This one:
Priority Mail® International
Max. length 42&quot;, max. length plus girth combined 79&quot;

I believe the tracking number for this option will start with C.

Confusing, right? And they&apos;re both USPS Priority International!Sama saja, only one is letter, one is parcel. Once they end up in Malaysia, they will be handled differently. What a hassle!Why don&apos;t Poslaju just handle every Priority mail?

I&apos;ll try this out and see if it&apos;s really the case.

 This post has been edited by HeavenDust : Mar 26 2011, 06:44 PM 

 cybersim2 Mar 30 2011, 04:43 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #116 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 310

Joined: Aug 2006
From: CatCity


 

 
 
 I lost a few items shipped using USPS First Mail International. Thank god I have no problem receiving every items shipped using USPS Priority Mail International. I guess a lot items end up in our Msian CusXXX / PosXXX officer house 

 Christopher7 Apr 10 2011, 02:28 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #117 

Stay Hungry, Stay Foolish
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 884

Joined: Feb 2009


 

 
 
 Hi May I know how long it takes for&apos;UPS Mail Innovations&apos;to ship to Malaysia? Thanks. 

 illuminarias Apr 11 2011, 05:53 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #118 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 26

Joined: Nov 2010
From: Tropicana


 

 
 
 I&apos;d like to know how long it&apos;ll take First-Class Mail International to ship to malaysia. Mine is insured and has the tracking code starting with LC.
 

 hokuan Apr 15 2011, 09:22 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #119 

Regular
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 1,306

Joined: Nov 2006


 
 

 
 
 I&apos;m waiting for my parcel and when I check today, the status is as shown in the attachment.

There are two&quot;Into Foreign Custom&quot;, usually only one and the other would be out of custom within hours. But now already one day, and status still like this.
Is my item being held?

 Attached thumbnail(s) 
 

 Anhero Apr 25 2011, 08:25 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #120 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 9

Joined: Oct 2008


 

 
 
 Hi I&apos;ve ordered a package from US through ebay
After reading this thread I checked both the USPS and Poslaju site with the tracking number i was given. (luckily it started with C).
This is what I got

This is from the USPS site
 

And this is from the Poslaju site
 

Just want to double confirm. This means Poslaju won&apos;t deliver it to my house and I&apos;ll have to go to PPL Batu Caves to collect it right? And lets say I want Poslaju to deliver to my doorstep, what should I do? 

 zeannjian Apr 25 2011, 08:33 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #121 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 6

Joined: Mar 2010


 

 
 
 Hi,

I order an iPad2 and my friend ship it back to me via USPS.

So far still at international dispatch.

Will it go through kastam by any luck?

Worth USD700 tho..

I&apos;m so worry right now.

Thanks. 

 Anhero Apr 25 2011, 08:44 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #122 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 9

Joined: Oct 2008


 

 
 
 From what I read in this thread and a few others, electronic items usually get held at customs and there will be a ~10% (from a few pages back in this thread, can&apos;t really confirm the percentage) tax on it 

 zeannjian Apr 26 2011, 07:59 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #123 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 6

Joined: Mar 2010


 

 
 
 Detailed Results:

Out of Foreign Customs, April 26, 2011, 12:21 am, MALAYSIA
Into Foreign Customs, April 25, 2011, 11:35 pm, MALAYSIA
Arrived Abroad, April 25, 2011, 11:34 pm, MALAYSIA
International Dispatch, April 22, 2011, 9:51 pm, ISC CHICAGO IL (USPS)
Arrival
Processed through Sort Facility, April 21, 2011, 6:22 pm, OMAHA, NE 68110
Processed through Sort Facility, April 21, 2011, 5:36 pm, LINCOLN, NE 68501
Acceptance, April 21, 2011, 11:11 am, LINCOLN, NE 68588


To all the awesome Bro here.

Is this means it already out of the custom and clear?

 Added on April 26, 2011, 8:03 am And just wanna ask.

I have seen some other forumer here received their iPad without any distruption.

Is it that kastam won&apos;t care so much about Apple product?

I saw iPod touch, iPad, iPhone....

is these product tax exempted from Malaysia?

 Added on April 26, 2011, 10:23 am QUOTE(zeannjian@Apr 25 2011, 08:33 PM) Hi, 

I order an iPad2 and my friend ship it back to me via USPS.

So far still at international dispatch.

Will it go through kastam by any luck?

Worth USD700 tho..

I&apos;m so worry right now.

Thanks.
 Hi guys,

thank you much for the info.

Just wanna inform that my iPad have reach Msia safe and smooth.
Lucky get thru kastam.

Thanks!

 This post has been edited by zeannjian : Apr 26 2011, 10:23 AM 

 madeleine_1406 Apr 27 2011, 02:48 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #124 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 191

Joined: Nov 2008
From: los angeles,US,france,asia


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(zeannjian@Apr 25 2011, 03:59 PM) Detailed Results:
 
Out of Foreign Customs, April 26, 2011, 12:21 am, MALAYSIA
Into Foreign Customs, April 25, 2011, 11:35 pm, MALAYSIA
Arrived Abroad, April 25, 2011, 11:34 pm, MALAYSIA
International Dispatch, April 22, 2011, 9:51 pm, ISC CHICAGO IL (USPS)
Arrival
Processed through Sort Facility, April 21, 2011, 6:22 pm, OMAHA, NE 68110
Processed through Sort Facility, April 21, 2011, 5:36 pm, LINCOLN, NE 68501
Acceptance, April 21, 2011, 11:11 am, LINCOLN, NE 68588
To all the awesome Bro here.

Is this means it already out of the custom and clear?

 Added on April 26, 2011, 8:03 am And just wanna ask.

I have seen some other forumer here received their iPad without any distruption.

Is it that kastam won&apos;t care so much about Apple product?

I saw iPod touch, iPad, iPhone....

is these product tax exempted from Malaysia?

 Added on April 26, 2011, 10:23 am 
Hi guys,

thank you much for the info.

Just wanna inform that my iPad have reach Msia safe and smooth.
Lucky get thru kastam.

Thanks!
 wow...its so great to heard tht its pass kastam yeh:)
btw,so u can use ur ipad 2 at msia now without jailbreak??
 

 mrbs84 May 18 2011, 07:29 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #125 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 170

Joined: Jun 2008
From: Unsure


 
 

 
 
 I&apos;m a frequent buyer/seller to US, wanna share some of my experience with you guys.

USPS Priority is not the fastest way as it&apos;s stated on their web, it said 6-10 days but in fact it will take more than 2 weeks to arrive here in malaysia.

Usually i will go for First Class, more cheaper and it&apos;s takes the same time period with Priority Mail.

But, international shipping is really depend on your luck. Sometimes i got First Class arrive within 7 days and same with Priority.

And USPS have the cheapest and the slowest way which is via International Ground. I have 3 parcel from US sending with that service (which is the seller fault). And it will takes 1-3 month.. My suggestion never ever use that service if you buying from the states, unless you&apos;re really patient.

The fastest country delivered in malaysia on my experience is France, UK, Sweden, Australia, Taiwan&amp;Hong Kong. 

 AoiSatan May 22 2011, 11:11 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #126 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 6

Joined: Jan 2008


 
 
 Hi guys, so i just bought a guitar from ebay and there was a tracking number provided. it was CP8xxxxxxx1US. It was shipped on 17th May. and the status has been in acceptance for at least 4 working days.

Class: Priority Mail International Parcels
Service(s): International Parcels
Status: Acceptance

Your item was accepted at 2:48 pm on May 17, 2011 in LYMAN, SC 29365. Information, if available, is updated periodically throughout the day. Please check again later.

is this normal?? im kinda scared now 

 adhoc May 23 2011, 01:28 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #127 

5 Star Trader
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 1,040

Joined: Jan 2009
From: Klang, Selangor


 
 


 
 
 QUOTE(AoiSatan@May 22 2011, 11:11 PM) Hi guys, so i just bought a guitar from ebay and there was a tracking number provided. it was CP8xxxxxxx1US. It was shipped on 17th May. and the status has been in acceptance for at least 4 working days.

Class: Priority Mail International Parcels
Service(s): International Parcels
Status: Acceptance

Your item was accepted at 2:48 pm on May 17, 2011 in LYMAN, SC 29365. Information, if available, is updated periodically throughout the day. Please check again later.

is this normal?? im kinda scared now     
 What i understand is Priority Mail International Parcels dont have tracking no. The no. provided to you is custom reference no. Correct me if i&apos;m wrong 

 sKyWiR3pT3lTd May 23 2011, 04:23 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #128 

Welcome Brendan Rodgers!
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 6,002

Joined: Feb 2010
From: Anfield Road


 
 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(adhoc@May 23 2011, 01:28 AM) What i understand is Priority Mail International Parcels dont have tracking no. The no. provided to you is custom reference no. Correct me if i&apos;m wrong 
 USPS Priority Mail International does have tracking numbers. But they would not show any information once it leaves the country (US). Priority Mail usually takes less than 10 days. Most of my ebay purchases uses USPS Priority Mail International..arrives quicker than i thought.. 

 AoiSatan May 23 2011, 07:09 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #129 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 6

Joined: Jan 2008


 
 
 QUOTE(sKyWiR3pT3lTd@May 23 2011, 04:23 AM) USPS Priority Mail International does have tracking numbers. But they would not show any information once it leaves the country (US). Priority Mail usually takes less than 10 days. Most of my ebay purchases uses USPS Priority Mail International..arrives quicker than i thought..
 So does that mean it will say when it arrives here in malaysia?? 

 hkspower May 24 2011, 03:22 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #130 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 240

Joined: Jan 2003
From: 工口


 

 
 
 wait 4 2 week 

 adhoc May 24 2011, 03:33 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #131 

5 Star Trader
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 1,040

Joined: Jan 2009
From: Klang, Selangor


 
 


 
 
 QUOTE(sKyWiR3pT3lTd@May 23 2011, 04:23 AM) USPS Priority Mail International does have tracking numbers. But they would not show any information once it leaves the country (US). Priority Mail usually takes less than 10 days. Most of my ebay purchases uses USPS Priority Mail International..arrives quicker than i thought..
 Ohh...thanks for info 

 madeleine_1406 May 28 2011, 04:12 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #132 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 191

Joined: Nov 2008
From: los angeles,US,france,asia


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(sKyWiR3pT3lTd@May 22 2011, 12:23 PM) USPS Priority Mail International does have tracking numbers. But they would not show any information once it leaves the country (US). Priority Mail usually takes less than 10 days. Most of my ebay purchases uses USPS Priority Mail International..arrives quicker than i thought..
 yup exactly....indeed ebay is safe even if the parcel is loss,we can claim for refund back...awesome right!! 

 longman07 Jun 15 2011, 10:25 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #133 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 22

Joined: Mar 2007


 

 
 
 i bought harmony one from amazon on 26.01 (only rm70 cheaper from local seller, just to try since this was my 1st online experience buying from abroad). They shipped using DHL on 27.01 and i self collect at dhl office on 31.01, damn fast... no tax somemore...

 try my luck to purchase 3 pairs of levi&apos;s from US. They left US on 12th June with USPS Priority and luckily the tracking no. starts from CPxxxxxxUS.

And still waiting. But what i read from you guys, i have faith that they will arrive my doorstep by end of this month. Hope customs will release them without tax.

-------------------------

yes. they arrived via poslaju on monday 20thjune. no tax. 

 This post has been edited by longman07 : Jun 22 2011, 09:20 AM 

 macgeorge Jun 23 2011, 11:58 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #134 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 3

Joined: Jun 2010


 
 
 Hi, anyone experienced late delivery by USPS EMI recently?

My item was posted on 14/6/2011 from CA USA seems still not reaching Malaysia yet, at this moment. Informed the sender, and he called USPS, and the answer given was wait for another few more days.....


 

 This post has been edited by macgeorge : Jun 23 2011, 03:10 PM 

 longman07 Jun 24 2011, 09:07 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #135 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 22

Joined: Mar 2007


 

 
 
 QUOTE(macgeorge@Jun 23 2011, 11:58 AM) Hi, anyone experienced late delivery by USPS EMI recently?

My item was posted on 14/6/2011 from CA USA seems still not reaching Malaysia yet, at this moment. Informed the sender, and he called USPS, and the answer given was wait for another few more days.....
 
 u should give them at least 2 weeks. expect them to arrive next week (at least 28th). if not, then only u should scream. in my case above, i gave them 2 weeks to arrive (i.e. end of this month). but it still arrived in 9 days. it was a bonus to me ... (just my 2 cents) 

 sKyWiR3pT3lTd Jun 25 2011, 12:21 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #136 

Welcome Brendan Rodgers!
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 6,002

Joined: Feb 2010
From: Anfield Road


 
 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(madeleine_1406@May 28 2011, 04:12 PM) yup exactly....indeed ebay is safe even if the parcel is loss,we can claim for refund back...awesome right!!
 Correct 

 QUOTE(adhoc@May 24 2011, 03:33 AM) Ohh...thanks for info 
 Welcome 

 QUOTE(AoiSatan@May 23 2011, 07:09 AM) So does that mean it will say when it arrives here in malaysia??
 Nope, you will not have the arrival estimation but usually USPS First Class International arrives in 14 days or less 

 macgeorge Jun 25 2011, 07:45 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #137 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 3

Joined: Jun 2010


 
 
 QUOTE(longman07@Jun 24 2011, 09:07 AM) u should give them at least 2 weeks. expect them to arrive next week (at least 28th). if not, then only u should scream. in my case above, i gave them 2 weeks to arrive (i.e. end of this month). but it still arrived in 9 days. it was a bonus to me ... (just my 2 cents)
 Hi, for information, I&apos;ve received mine on 24th June 2011.

My past experience: Priority Mail - 12 days / Express Mail - 6 days&amp;10 days&amp;this time 11 days. FedEx - 6 days

Anyway thanks for answering. 

 This post has been edited by macgeorge : Jun 25 2011, 02:59 PM 

 poisonspice Jul 7 2011, 09:56 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #138 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 1

Joined: Jul 2011


 
 
 Hi, just thought of sharing my past experience for my Ebay purchases and sent via USPS priority mail.

my 1st purchase reached me within 5 business days after it was shipped - approx. RM450. SUPER EFFICIENT 

2nd purchase - after 10 days, never reached me. And i found out that it was pneding custom clearance. The bag was about USD250 including shipping. Due to that, i had incurred another RM50 for appointing poslaju to do the custom clearance on my behalf since i didnt have the time to go all the way to Sepang to redeem my goods. And additional tax of RM80. So instead of paying RM800 for the bag, the whole cost me RM930 

last 2 weeks, i made my 3rd attempt, also shipped via USPS priority mail. It&apos;s been 8 business days, and the tracking status still state&quot;processed thru LA bla bla bla&quot;, and i was getting worried. But when i checked the status this morning, it states that custom has been cleared *fingers crossed*

Therefore, i gathered that:
1) if your purchases is more than RM500 - likely to subject to witholding by custom - therefore, likely to subject to tax.
2) you have to inform the seller that do not include the shipping cost to the goods value; otherwise, when it reaches Msia, the custom will tax you based on everything.
3) alternatively, inform the seller to put a lower value than the actual price of the goods that you are paying; disclaimer: provided the seller is willing to help you la... 

 longman07 Jul 8 2011, 03:37 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #139 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 22

Joined: Mar 2007


 

 
 
 QUOTE(poisonspice@Jul 7 2011, 09:56 AM) 

Therefore, i gathered that:
1) if your purchases is more than RM500 - likely to subject to witholding by custom - therefore, likely to subject to tax.
2) you have to inform the seller that do not include the shipping cost to the goods value; otherwise, when it reaches Msia, the custom will tax you based on everything.
3) alternatively, inform the seller to put a lower value than the actual price of the goods that you are paying; disclaimer: provided the seller is willing to help you la...
 thanks for your observation... it&apos;ll help much... but sometimes, i think it would also on one&apos;s luck... i purchased harmony remote control about rm6++ from amazon... no tax... 

 jessand Jul 11 2011, 06:58 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #140 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 27

Joined: Sep 2008


 

 
 
 Hi,

I bought an item from US as well. I purchased since 13june 2011. Till now i did not received anything. I&apos;ve been keep contacting with the seller and so far the seller responded plus always keep me updated.
My tracking number also start with LJ*****US. What should i do now? Pos Malaysia cannot track too. haihhhh 

 longman07 Jul 12 2011, 09:00 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #141 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 22

Joined: Mar 2007


 

 
 
 QUOTE(jessand@Jul 11 2011, 06:58 PM) Hi,

I bought an item from US as well. I purchased since 13june 2011. Till now i did not received anything. I&apos;ve been keep contacting with the seller and so far the seller responded plus always keep me updated.
My tracking number also start with LJ*****US. What should i do now? Pos Malaysia cannot track too. haihhhh
 one month already... unless usps use bike.... did u check with USPS website?... maybe pending clearance at our customs department... 

 magnifizio Jul 13 2011, 05:12 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #142 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 193

Joined: Sep 2007


 

 
 
 QUOTE(jessand@Jul 11 2011, 06:58 PM) Hi,

I bought an item from US as well. I purchased since 13june 2011. Till now i did not received anything. I&apos;ve been keep contacting with the seller and so far the seller responded plus always keep me updated.
My tracking number also start with LJ*****US. What should i do now? Pos Malaysia cannot track too. haihhhh
 i have the exact same experience

below are my shipment details:

Label/Receipt Number: LJ** **** ***U S
Class: Priority Mail International Parcels
Service(s): International Letter
Status: Processed through Sort Facility
Your item was processed through and left our OPA LOCKA, FL 33054 facility on June 14, 2011 at 7:47 pm. The item is currently in transit to the destination. Information, if available, is updated periodically throughout the day. Please check again later.
Detailed Results:

Processed through Sort Facility, June 14, 2011, 7:47 pm, OPA LOCKA, FL 33054
Electronic Shipping Info Received, June 15, 2011

i bought a pair of sunglasses worth usd70
i tried calling poslaju and also USPS

poslaju&apos;s reply: label id is not tracking no. hence they cant track my parcel.

USPS&apos;s reply:&quot;we will get back to you within 24hours&quot;that was 3 days ago.

anyone can help offer a solution please?
perhaps the parcel is still stuck in custom?
if so, how can i contact custom department?
PLEASE...HELP...
anyone with a past experience? 

 sugen Jul 14 2011, 08:45 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #143 

Regular
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 1,127

Joined: Jul 2007


 

 
 
 I purchased iphone4 water proof casing from the states worth USD80 that ships today 14/7 via UPSP with tracking number started with LJ XXXXX. After reading all the post here. I am a bit worry now, this is my fist time purchase from USA. Hope my goods arrive safely. 

 rayanne Jul 15 2011, 11:03 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #144 

Getting Started
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 192

Joined: Jul 2005
From: Spree Collection @Puchong/Bangsar


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(sugen@Jul 14 2011, 08:45 PM) I purchased iphone4 water proof casing from the states worth USD80 that ships today 14/7 via UPSP with tracking number started with LJ XXXXX. After reading all the post here. I am a bit worry now, this is my fist time purchase from USA. Hope my goods arrive safely.
 waterproof casing worth usd80 !!
perhaps you can track it first, dont worry too early.. 

 Mclaren Jul 15 2011, 11:48 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #145 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 206

Joined: Oct 2006


 
 
 QUOTE(sugen@Jul 14 2011, 08:45 PM) I purchased iphone4 water proof casing from the states worth USD80 that ships today 14/7 via UPSP with tracking number started with LJ XXXXX. After reading all the post here. I am a bit worry now, this is my fist time purchase from USA. Hope my goods arrive safely.
 it should be fine...as i got my parcel via UPSP in a week 

 sugen Jul 20 2011, 02:45 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #146 

Regular
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 1,127

Joined: Jul 2007


 

 
 
 yahoo!!It arrives today 20/7.. The item was shipped from San Diego on 14/7.. Postman do a door to door delivery...This is the 1st time i purchase directly from USA.. What a good experience..

 QUOTE(rayanne@Jul 15 2011, 11:03 AM) waterproof casing worth usd80 !!
perhaps you can track it first, dont worry too early..
 This post has been edited by sugen : Jul 20 2011, 02:48 PM 

 gadgetfreq Jul 22 2011, 04:56 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #147 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 20

Joined: Mar 2006


 

 
 
 You all are very lucky... mine&apos;s is already 30 days.. its just 10 pcs of Hot Wheels&amp;Matchbox car. Theres goes RM100+ down to drain... Thank you Malaysia... 

 steventan85 Jul 27 2011, 10:55 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #148 

Look at all my stars!!
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 4,247

Joined: Jan 2006


 
 
 QUOTE(gadgetfreq@Jul 22 2011, 04:56 PM) You all are very lucky... mine&apos;s is already 30 days.. its just 10 pcs of Hot Wheels&amp;Matchbox car. Theres goes RM100+ down to drain... Thank you Malaysia...
 u can check with USPS and if ur getting Priority mail or Express mail international, there is USD100 insurance with it... 

 towsuan Aug 3 2011, 04:51 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #149 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 20

Joined: Aug 2007


 
 
 QUOTE(sugen@Jul 20 2011, 04:45 PM) yahoo!!It arrives today 20/7.. The item was shipped from San Diego on 14/7.. Postman do a door to door delivery...This is the 1st time i purchase directly from USA.. What a good experience..
 Just want to ask, the postman is from POSLAJU orr the normal motorbike postman? Thanks.. 

 onscreen Aug 17 2011, 11:03 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #150 

On my way
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 521

Joined: Jan 2003
From: Kay Jay, PeeJey, Celangor


 

 
 
 QUOTE(poisonspice@Jul 7 2011, 09:56 AM) Therefore, i gathered that:
1) if your purchases is more than RM500 - likely to subject to witholding by custom - therefore, likely to subject to tax.
2) you have to inform the seller that do not include the shipping cost to the goods value; otherwise, when it reaches Msia, the custom will tax you based on everything.
3) alternatively, inform the seller to put a lower value than the actual price of the goods that you are paying; disclaimer: provided the seller is willing to help you la...
 1. Anything higher than RM500 will lead to higher chance for inspection but WILL not be likely to subject to tax based on the item description. If they still insist on charging tax or any duty fees, you can do the honor to slap them back with the tariff codes of imported goods and usually that do the job 

2. Usually reliable sellers will do a breakdown on the total amount for easier process. You have to inform the seller to do a breakdown between the shipping charges and the actual item value AS well as a clear description of the item if clarifying it as gift isnt an option.

3. Works flawless. 

 svage98 Aug 17 2011, 11:07 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #151 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 344

Joined: Oct 2007
From: Nilai/Putrajaya/Bangi


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(towsuan@Aug 3 2011, 04:51 PM) Just want to ask, the postman is from POSLAJU orr the normal motorbike postman? Thanks..
 Most likely package was shipped via courier or express mail since the delivery time is so short. So I guess postman is from poslaju.

 Added on August 17, 2011, 11:23 am QUOTE(gadgetfreq@Jul 22 2011, 04:56 PM) You all are very lucky... mine&apos;s is already 30 days.. its just 10 pcs of Hot Wheels&amp;Matchbox car. Theres goes RM100+ down to drain... Thank you Malaysia...
 If you used Priority Mail International or Express Mail International is shouldn&apos;t take one month. Did you use First Class Mail/ International Standard shipping? If you did that could take some time getting to Malaysia. I&apos;ve had cases where items I bought from ebay took 2-3 months to arrive. Worse case I get where my items don&apos;t reach at all maybe got lost somewhere since normal mail cannot track.

 Added on August 17, 2011, 11:30 am QUOTE(magnifizio@Jul 13 2011, 05:12 PM) i have the exact same experience

below are my shipment details:

Label/Receipt Number: LJ** **** ***U S
Class: Priority Mail International Parcels
Service(s): International Letter
Status: Processed through Sort Facility
Your item was processed through and left our OPA LOCKA, FL 33054 facility on June 14, 2011 at 7:47 pm. The item is currently in transit to the destination. Information, if available, is updated periodically throughout the day. Please check again later.
Detailed Results:

Processed through Sort Facility, June 14, 2011, 7:47 pm, OPA LOCKA, FL 33054
Electronic Shipping Info Received, June 15, 2011

i bought a pair of sunglasses worth usd70
i tried calling poslaju and also USPS

poslaju&apos;s reply: label id is not tracking no. hence they cant track my parcel.

USPS&apos;s reply:&quot;we will get back to you within 24hours&quot;that was 3 days ago.

anyone can help offer a solution please?
perhaps the parcel is still stuck in custom?
if so, how can i contact custom department?
PLEASE...HELP...
anyone with a past experience?
 If the item arrive at Malaysia it should appear under e-parcel tracking at Pos Malaysia Website and then poslaju tracking only after your parcel has cleared with the customs. Tracking updates should also be available at USPS website. Try calling Pos Malaysia customer service about your tracking.

 This post has been edited by svage98 : Aug 19 2011, 08:32 PM 

 Nidz Aug 19 2011, 04:12 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #152 

Don&apos;t Be Average!!
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 1,194

Joined: Dec 2006
From: Subang Jaya, Selangor


 

 
 
 This is my experience:

16/5 - ordered USD100 worth of items from SGPStore. shipped using First-Class Mail International (no tracking)

after 1 month, still didnt receive.

enquire with the seller, they say its out of their reach because USPS cannot track, and they cannot be held liable. but they offer me to re-ship the items but i hav to bear the shipping cost. this time, i chose express mail. another USD34, but with tracking.

this time, the item arrive at my place ngam2 one week after ship from usa.....

after this, i&apos;ll always use tracked parcel for items more than USD50. better pay abit than ur item lost. not all seller can re-ship the item for u 2nd time 

 nill Sep 3 2011, 08:43 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #153 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 9

Joined: May 2010


 

 
 
 YOUR LABEL NUMBER: CJ***0*4***US
SERVICE: Priority Mail International Parcels

STATUS OF YOUR ITEM: DATE&amp;TIME: LOCATION:

Customs clearance September 05, 2011, 4:22 pm MALAYSIA
processing complete
Customs Clearance September 05, 2011, 8:52 am MALAYSIA
Processed Through Sort Facility September 05, 2011, 8:51 am MALAYSIA
Processed Through Sort Facility August 29, 2011, 1:01 am ISC CHICAGO IL (USPS)
Arrived at Sort Facility August 29, 2011, 1:00 am ISC CHICAGO IL (USPS)
Electronic Shipping Info Received August 26, 2011
Shipment Accepted August 26, 2011, 4:31 pm PLANO, TX 75074

FEATURES: International Parcels

The status of Track&amp;Confirm has not changed since 29th August until 3rd of September. Should i contact the seller? Is this normal? I have seen other users post which shows that it takes one day to switch status to international dispatch in one day.

 QUOTE zeannjian [Apr 26 2011, 07:59 AM]:


Detailed Results:

Out of Foreign Customs, April 26, 2011, 12:21 am, MALAYSIA
Into Foreign Customs, April 25, 2011, 11:35 pm, MALAYSIA
Arrived Abroad, April 25, 2011, 11:34 pm, MALAYSIA
International Dispatch, April 22, 2011, 9:51 pm, ISC CHICAGO IL (USPS)
Arrival
Processed through Sort Facility, April 21, 2011, 6:22 pm, OMAHA, NE 68110
Processed through Sort Facility, April 21, 2011, 5:36 pm, LINCOLN, NE 68501
Acceptance, April 21, 2011, 11:11 am, LINCOLN, NE 68588 Is it because of the holiday in Malaysia or the event of Hurricane Irene affecting US?


Edit: I just received my parcel today at 10+ am. 

 This post has been edited by nill : Sep 8 2011, 10:17 PM 

 gblaura Sep 4 2011, 09:44 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #154 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 2

Joined: Oct 2007


 
 
 Mine one more worst im waiting my parcel nearly 2 months of period..still not arrive yet~~ below are the status and this package is worth about USD1,7xx.xx 

Label/Receipt Number: EC70 xxxx xxUS
Class: Express Mail International®
Status: Processed Through Sort Facility

Your item was processed through our ISC MIAMI FL (USPS) facility on July 06, 2011 at 9:42 am. The item is currently in transit to the destination.

Detailed Results:

Processed Through Sort Facility, July 06, 2011, 9:42 am, ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)
Arrived at Sort Facility, July 06, 2011, 9:41 am, ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)
Processed through Sort Facility, July 05, 2011, 7:50 pm, MIAMI, FL 33152
Acceptance, July 05, 2011, 2:58 pm, POMPANO BEACH, FL 33076
Electronic Shipping Info Received, July 05, 2011

and i have another package too send on 25th August~ is about 10 days already, still in the same status~~~ i was so scare...it will have the same problem like the previous package ~~, hope my luck are not so bad~~~~ 

Label/Receipt Number: EC97 xxxxxxxUS
Class: Express Mail International®
Status: Processed Through Sort Facility

Your item was processed through our ISC MIAMI FL (USPS) facility on August 25, 2011 at 10:18 pm. The item is currently in transit to the destination.

Detailed Results:

Processed Through Sort Facility, August 25, 2011, 10:18 pm, ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)
Arrived at Sort Facility, August 25, 2011, 10:17 pm, ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)
Processed through Sort Facility, August 25, 2011, 4:25 pm, MIAMI, FL 33152
Acceptance, August 25, 2011, 12:25 pm, POMPANO BEACH, FL 33076
Electronic Shipping Info Received, August 24, 2011

 This post has been edited by gblaura : Sep 4 2011, 09:48 PM 

 nill Sep 4 2011, 10:30 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #155 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 9

Joined: May 2010


 

 
 
 Your shipment indeed needs more attention.
Did you contact your seller or check with the customs officers?
or read here:
 http://pages.ebay.com/help/sell/cancel-tra...on-process.html 

 This post has been edited by nill : Sep 4 2011, 10:35 PM 

 gblaura Sep 4 2011, 10:38 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #156 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 2

Joined: Oct 2007


 
 
 i have already contact to the seller, but as she say because i didn&apos;t buy the insurance, so i can&apos;t file a claim from USPS....=( 

 SkyBlue99 Sep 5 2011, 05:22 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #157 

Look at all their stars!!Not Mine!!
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 1,948

Joined: Feb 2009
From: Kuala Lumpur


 

 
 
 My seller used First Class as well for the first shipment. I was against it but they wanted to use it so no choice, after 2 months item still not yet arrived. Contacted seller and they sent another batch of stock which arrived in 3 days But overall USPS have yet found the missing parcel. Usually takes more than 3 weeks as what I was told by seller 

 nill Sep 5 2011, 11:17 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #158 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 9

Joined: May 2010


 

 
 
 QUOTE(madeleine_1406@May 28 2011, 04:12 PM) yup exactly....indeed ebay is safe even if the parcel is loss,we can claim for refund back...awesome right!!
 is this true? do you have a specific case to share? 

 ckyned Sep 8 2011, 08:19 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #159 

~Trial&amp;Error~
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 592

Joined: May 2008
From: Earth


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(nill@Sep 3 2011, 08:43 PM) YOUR LABEL NUMBER: CJ***0*4***US                   
SERVICE:          Priority Mail International Parcels

STATUS OF YOUR ITEM: DATE&amp;TIME: LOCATION:

Customs clearance    September 05, 2011, 4:22 pm MALAYSIA
processing complete
Customs Clearance            September 05, 2011, 8:52 am MALAYSIA
Processed Through Sort Facility   September 05, 2011, 8:51 am MALAYSIA
Processed Through Sort Facility   August 29, 2011, 1:01 am   ISC CHICAGO IL (USPS)
                 Arrived at Sort Facility          August 29, 2011, 1:00 am    ISC CHICAGO IL (USPS)
                 Electronic Shipping Info Received  August 26, 2011
                 Shipment Accepted            August 26, 2011, 4:31 pm    PLANO, TX 75074

FEATURES:         International Parcels

The status of Track&amp;Confirm has not changed since 29th August until 3rd of September. Should i contact the seller? Is this normal? I have seen other users post which shows that it takes one day to switch status to international dispatch in one day.
Is it because of the holiday in Malaysia or the event of Hurricane Irene affecting US?
Edit: I just received my parcel today at 10+ am. 
 Customs clearance September 05, 2011, 4:22 pm MALAYSIA
processing complete&lt;-- @nill: this is the last update from USPS? then what r the procedure u been through&amp;what is your item? mine is electronic one. mine got stucked @&quot;Customs Clearance&quot;maybe waiting tomorrow? 

 nill Sep 8 2011, 10:19 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #160 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 9

Joined: May 2010


 

 
 
 YOUR LABEL NUMBER: CJ***0*4***US
SERVICE: Priority Mail International Parcels

STATUS OF YOUR ITEM: DATE&amp;TIME: LOCATION:

Delivered September 07, 2011, 10:27 am MALAYSIA
Attempted Delivery September 07, 2011, 9:00 am MALAYSIA
- Scheduled for
another
delivery
attempt today
Customs clearance September 05, 2011, 4:22 pm MALAYSIA
processing complete
Customs Clearance September 05, 2011, 8:52 am MALAYSIA
Processed Through Sort Facility September 05, 2011, 8:51 am MALAYSIA
Processed Through Sort Facility August 29, 2011, 1:01 am ISC CHICAGO IL (USPS)
Arrived at Sort Facility August 29, 2011, 1:00 am ISC CHICAGO IL (USPS)
Electronic Shipping Info Received August 26, 2011
Shipment Accepted August 26, 2011, 4:31 pm PLANO, TX 75074

FEATURES: International Parcels

at pos malaysia 


E-Parcel Tracking result

Item No: CJ***0*4***US

1. 5 September 2011 8:51:05 AM PMK KLIA, MALAYSIA RECEIVED ITEM FROM UNITED STATES
2. 7 September 2011 9:00:53 AM PDC Shah Alam OUT FOR DELIVERY
3. 7 September 2011 10:27:56 AM PDC Shah Alam DELIVERED

The website updated at pos malaysia updated a day after but usps updated at the same date the parcel is received by me.

 

My item is labelled as gift and cost below RM300 [2 sets of board game weigh less than 5lb]. I only have to receive my parcel. The Immigration didn&apos;t call me. Good luck to you. If everything goes right, wait for two working days.

 This post has been edited by nill : Sep 8 2011, 10:32 PM 

 ckyned Sep 8 2011, 11:24 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #161 

~Trial&amp;Error~
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 592

Joined: May 2008
From: Earth


 
 

 
 
 @nill: alright, thanks for the info&amp;the wish. ;-)
i think my parcel is arround ~4kg&amp;I ask the reseller to put it as RMA item&amp;lower the price label. BTW, no extra charge from Poslaju? I heard had to pay them RM50 as we appointed them as agent to collect/deliver the item.

8 September 2011 8:13:24 AM PMK KLIA, MALAYSIA RECEIVED ITEM FROM UNITED STATES
&lt;-- got in the system now. ^^ 

 nill Sep 9 2011, 10:16 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #162 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 9

Joined: May 2010


 

 
 
 you have to wait until saturday or monday. at least pos malaysia have update your item status.

 This post has been edited by nill : Sep 9 2011, 10:19 AM 

 ckyned Sep 9 2011, 03:59 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #163 

~Trial&amp;Error~
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 592

Joined: May 2008
From: Earth


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(nill@Sep 9 2011, 10:16 AM) you have to wait until saturday or monday. at least pos malaysia have update your item status.
 repeating my question,&quot;BTW, no extra charge from Poslaju? I heard had to pay them RM50 as we appointed them as agent to collect/deliver the item.&quot; 

 nill Sep 9 2011, 04:17 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #164 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 9

Joined: May 2010


 

 
 
 i don&apos;t know.. that was my first online order, my goods are non-electronic and it is below RM300.

Sorry that i can&apos;t help.

Edit:

I didn&apos;t get any extra charge. If your item got stuck in customs, they will call or send you a letter. If Pos Malaysia settles any problem regarding customs for you, you might be charged RM50&lt;&lt; Anyone able to clarify this? Since your buyer label it as RMA, maybe there is no extra charge at all.

^ Did you get your shipment?

 This post has been edited by nill : Sep 10 2011, 08:57 PM 

 DjKenji Sep 27 2011, 09:02 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #165 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 414

Joined: Sep 2006
From: Klang&gt;Melbourne&gt;OUG&gt;PJ


 
 

 
 
 This is unbeliever with USPS Express mail international from US to Malaysia

 

take a look Today is 27th September, No news from poslauju. Tmr morning will call up KILA custom to check-out.

 Added on September 28, 2011, 12:17 am QUOTE(gblaura@Sep 4 2011, 09:44 PM) Mine one more worst im waiting my parcel nearly 2 months of period..still not arrive yet~~ below are the status and this package is worth about USD1,7xx.xx    

Label/Receipt Number: EC70 xxxx xxUS
Class: Express Mail International®
Status: Processed Through Sort Facility

Your item was processed through our ISC MIAMI FL (USPS) facility on July 06, 2011 at 9:42 am. The item is currently in transit to the destination.

Detailed Results:
 
Processed Through Sort Facility, July 06, 2011, 9:42 am, ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)
Arrived at Sort Facility, July 06, 2011, 9:41 am, ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)
Processed through Sort Facility, July 05, 2011, 7:50 pm, MIAMI, FL 33152
Acceptance, July 05, 2011, 2:58 pm, POMPANO BEACH, FL 33076
Electronic Shipping Info Received, July 05, 2011

and i have another package too send on 25th August~ is about 10 days already, still in the same status~~~ i was so scare...it will have the same problem like the previous package ~~, hope my luck are not so bad~~~~   

Label/Receipt Number: EC97 xxxxxxxUS
Class: Express Mail International®
Status: Processed Through Sort Facility

Your item was processed through our ISC MIAMI FL (USPS) facility on August 25, 2011 at 10:18 pm. The item is currently in transit to the destination.

Detailed Results:
 
Processed Through Sort Facility, August 25, 2011, 10:18 pm, ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)
Arrived at Sort Facility, August 25, 2011, 10:17 pm, ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)
Processed through Sort Facility, August 25, 2011, 4:25 pm, MIAMI, FL 33152
Acceptance, August 25, 2011, 12:25 pm, POMPANO BEACH, FL 33076
Electronic Shipping Info Received, August 24, 2011
 after 20days+ do u have any news update?

Some problem says the USPS trace and confirm will delay update states for 1~2 weeks time.

 This post has been edited by DjKenji : Sep 28 2011, 12:17 AM 

 hako Sep 29 2011, 08:53 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #166 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 245

Joined: Apr 2009
From: Malaysia


 

 
 
 Hi, I bought something online. Shipped using USPS priority mail international. no tracking provided.

the store(barnes&amp;noble) say should arrive in 15 working days,

but now already 1 month+. I asked at my post office they say no tracking code so cannot find my parcel.

any idea what to do?

 This post has been edited by hako : Sep 29 2011, 08:54 PM 

 Desteoh Oct 1 2011, 02:38 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #167 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 4

Joined: Apr 2011
From: New York City


 

 
 
 for ur information.. USPS Priority Mail do NOT provide tracking number ...
on once is out of USA noway u can track the parcel...

only reg mail provided tracking # is better to used DHL.. or UPS. Or fedex... but it may cost more...

 Added on October 1, 2011, 2:39 pm for ur information.. USPS Priority Mail do NOT provide tracking number ...
on once is out of USA noway u can track the parcel...

only reg mail provided tracking # is better to used DHL.. or UPS. Or fedex... but it may cost more...



 This post has been edited by Desteoh : Oct 1 2011, 02:39 PM 

 hako Oct 2 2011, 09:58 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #168 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 245

Joined: Apr 2009
From: Malaysia


 

 
 
 QUOTE(Desteoh@Oct 1 2011, 02:38 PM) for ur information.. USPS Priority Mail do NOT provide tracking number ...
on once is out of USA noway u can track the parcel...

only reg mail provided tracking # is better to used DHL.. or UPS. Or fedex... but it may cost more...

 Added on October 1, 2011, 2:39 pm for ur information.. USPS Priority Mail do NOT provide tracking number ...
on once is out of USA noway u can track the parcel...

only reg mail provided tracking # is better to used DHL.. or UPS. Or fedex... but it may cost more...
 Yeah. Went to post office to check whether they receive my package or not,more than a month packages still not delivered, but due to no tracking code, they cannot do anything. 

They try to find by address/name also cannot find anything.

looks like my packages gone already. 

 Gustav Gabrielson Oct 4 2011, 05:09 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #169 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 2

Joined: Oct 2011


 
 
 QUOTE(Desteoh@Oct 1 2011, 02:38 PM) for ur information.. USPS Priority Mail do NOT provide tracking number ...
on once is out of USA noway u can track the parcel...

only reg mail provided tracking # is better to used DHL.. or UPS. Or fedex... but it may cost more...

 Added on October 1, 2011, 2:39 pm for ur information.. USPS Priority Mail do NOT provide tracking number ...
on once is out of USA noway u can track the parcel...

only reg mail provided tracking # is better to used DHL.. or UPS. Or fedex... but it may cost more...
 USPS provides tracking number if you pay them extra fee. Please go to the USPS website for more details (it may be complicated but not like the POSlaju site) 

I have received shipments from friends and they come with the tracking number.


 

 longman07 Oct 5 2011, 10:25 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #170 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 22

Joined: Mar 2007


 

 
 
 QUOTE Desteoh Posted Oct 1 2011, 02:38 PM
 for ur information.. USPS Priority Mail do NOT provide tracking number ...
on once is out of USA noway u can track the parcel...

only reg mail provided tracking # is better to used DHL.. or UPS. Or fedex... but it may cost more... 

i think usps priority mail international do provide tracking number. or the problem came in with the seller. i have 2 experiences with usps priority. and they arrived within a week. eg.

 

 This post has been edited by longman07 : Oct 5 2011, 10:28 AM 

 billytattertons Oct 16 2011, 02:14 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #171 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 112

Joined: Jun 2011


 
 
 I have just received one parcel from my sis thru USPS international priority mail and she didn&apos;t pay for tracking so once it&apos;s out of US, basically i can&apos;t track the parcel.

I tried emailing poslaju and the reply i&apos;ve got is that my parcel is delivered into malaysia as normal mail without tracking so they don&apos;t have the tracking info for my parcel, i.e. they don&apos;t know where is my parcel.

anyway, got the parcel safe and sound. 

 hkspower Oct 16 2011, 11:31 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #172 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 240

Joined: Jan 2003
From: 工口


 

 
 
 good 4 u, usually normal mail w/o tracking always lost for me 

 billytattertons Oct 17 2011, 12:57 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #173 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 112

Joined: Jun 2011


 
 
 ya, i was kinda worried that it might get lost. since it&apos;s without tracking. luckily the parcel arrived. guess the safest way is to have tracking. 

 mars1069 Oct 22 2011, 07:01 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #174 

Regular
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 1,685

Joined: Aug 2008


 
 
 QUOTE(longman07@Oct 5 2011, 10:25 AM) i think usps priority mail international do provide tracking number. or the problem came in with the seller. i have 2 experiences with usps priority. and they arrived within a week. eg.

 
 &quot;address not available, item returned to sender。。。&quot;sounds scary coz sender in US, means the item will be sending back to US? hope they write my address correctly on the item 

 billytattertons Oct 25 2011, 06:10 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #175 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 112

Joined: Jun 2011


 
 
 try sending an email to them asking for further details or clarification... 

 heavenly91 Oct 26 2011, 07:20 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #176 

Challenge my statement with facts. Not fabricated fact.
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 895

Joined: Apr 2010
From: Subang Jaya


 
 

 
 
 the usps website and pos malaysia did not update my parcel status.

 I received my parcel on the 10th of October 2011.
 
USPS Priority Mail International Parcels Track&amp;Confirm:

 USPS Track&amp;Confirm Link 

YOUR LABEL NUMBER: CJ***5*6***US
SERVICE: Priority Mail International Parcels

STATUS OF YOUR ITEM:
DATE&amp;TIME: LOCATION:

 Customs clearance processing complete 
October 06, 2011, 10:26 am MALAYSIA

 Customs Clearance 
October 06, 2011, 7:46 am MALAYSIA

 Processed Through Sort Facility 
October 06, 2011, 7:46 am MALAYSIA

 Processed Through Sort Facility 
October 02, 2011, 6:12 pm ISC CHICAGO IL (USPS)

 Arrived at Sort Facility 
October 02, 2011, 6:11 pm ISC CHICAGO IL (USPS)

 Acceptance 
September 30, 2011, 5:31 pm FENTON, MO 63026

 Electronic Shipping Info Received 
September 30, 2011

FEATURES: International Parcels

 Pos Malaysia Webpage 

E-Parcel Tracking result

Item No: CJ***0*4***US

1. 6 October 2011 7:46:39 AM PMK KLIA, MALAYSIA RECEIVED ITEM FROM UNITED STATES

USPS and Pos Malaysia did not update their website yet...

 I believe all the blame goes to Pos Malaysia. Last time i was the one who received the parcel. Maybe i didn&apos;t signed for this parcel, therefore they never update the parcel status.

 This post has been edited by heavenly91 : Oct 26 2011, 07:23 PM 

 ripburger Oct 27 2011, 10:34 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #177 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 3

Joined: Jul 2007


 

 
 
 QUOTE(heavenly91@Oct 26 2011, 07:20 PM) the usps website and pos malaysia did not update my parcel status.

 I received my parcel on the 10th of October 2011.
 
USPS Priority Mail International Parcels Track&amp;Confirm:

 USPS Track&amp;Confirm Link 

YOUR LABEL NUMBER: CJ***5*6***US
SERVICE: Priority Mail International Parcels

STATUS OF YOUR ITEM:
DATE&amp;TIME: LOCATION:

 Customs clearance processing complete 
October 06, 2011, 10:26 am MALAYSIA

 Customs Clearance 
October 06, 2011, 7:46 am MALAYSIA

 Processed Through Sort Facility 
October 06, 2011, 7:46 am MALAYSIA

 Processed Through Sort Facility 
October 02, 2011, 6:12 pm ISC CHICAGO IL (USPS)

 Arrived at Sort Facility 
October 02, 2011, 6:11 pm ISC CHICAGO IL (USPS)

 Acceptance 
September 30, 2011, 5:31 pm FENTON, MO 63026

 Electronic Shipping Info Received 
September 30, 2011

FEATURES: International Parcels

 Pos Malaysia Webpage 

E-Parcel Tracking result

Item No: CJ***0*4***US

1. 6 October 2011 7:46:39 AM PMK KLIA, MALAYSIA RECEIVED ITEM FROM UNITED STATES

USPS and Pos Malaysia did not update their website yet...

 I believe all the blame goes to Pos Malaysia. Last time i was the one who received the parcel. Maybe i didn&apos;t signed for this parcel, therefore they never update the parcel status.
 hmm, why is the tracking number different for both the USPS and POS E-PARCEL tracking?

 Added on October 27, 2011, 10:53 am Label Number : CJxxxxxxxxxUS
Service : Priority Mail International Parcels
Features : International Parcels

Status of Your Item:

Processed Through Sort Facility October 06 , 2011, 2:46 pm ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)

Arrived at Sort Facility October 06, 2011, 2:46 pm ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)

Shipment Accepted October 04 , 2011, 3:20 pm ATLANTA, GA 30304

Electronic Shipping Info Received October 04 , 2011


23 days and still no updates from both USPS and POS E-PARCEL web track



 



 This post has been edited by ripburger : Oct 27 2011, 10:53 AM 

 sHawTY Oct 27 2011, 11:04 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #178 

Signature Violation Hunter
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 6,979

Joined: Jul 2005

 

 
 
 QUOTE(ripburger@Oct 27 2011, 10:34 AM) 23 days and still no updates from both USPS and POS E-PARCEL web track Have you tried calling Pos Malaysia Helpline?
1300-300-300

 This post has been edited by sHawTY : Oct 27 2011, 11:04 AM 

 ripburger Oct 27 2011, 05:00 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #179 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 3

Joined: Jul 2007


 

 
 
 QUOTE(sHawTY@Oct 27 2011, 11:04 AM) Have you tried calling Pos Malaysia Helpline?
1300-300-300
 hmm not yet, but saw some of our lyn buddies saying that contacting the POS KLIA is more appropriate (03-87872020)
ill give them a call tmr.
i just received my stuff via USPS FIRST CLASS within a week, so i guess there is a problem with my priority mail parcel, but i doubt that my parcel will be held by customs since the seller declared the item value at only ~USD65 without shipping.

btw thanks for ur help, sHawTY 

 billytattertons Oct 28 2011, 12:12 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #180 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 112

Joined: Jun 2011


 
 
 QUOTE(ripburger@Oct 27 2011, 05:00 PM) hmm not yet, but saw some of our lyn buddies saying that contacting the POS KLIA is more appropriate (03-87872020)
ill give them a call tmr.
i just received my stuff via USPS FIRST CLASS within a week, so i guess there is a problem with my priority mail parcel, but i doubt that my parcel will be held by customs since the seller declared the item value at only ~USD65 without shipping.

btw thanks for ur help, sHawTY 
 Calling them will be faster but u can try emailing them at care@pos.com.my

I tried once to email them about my USPS parcel without tracking and this is what they replied:

 QUOTE Dear Billy,

We thank you for your e-mail which we received on 02/10/2011.

According to the reference number given LCXXXXXXXXXUS, we would like to inform that the tracking said mail was sent to Malaysia as an ordinary mail, hence, once the item entered to Malaysia, we will treat it as normal mail. Tracking number for the item only can be used in USPS track and trace which mean the First-Class Mail International is only valid for local delivery area.

We appreciate your continuous support and patience. Please feel free to call us at our PosLine number at 1 300 300 300 or 0327279100 Our Customer Service Consultant will glad to assist you at anytime from 8:30 am to 8:00 pm, Monday to Friday and 8:30 am to 5:00 pm on Saturday (except for 1st Saturday of the month and Public Holiday) or e-mail us at care@pos.com.my

Thank you.

Yours sincerely,
SERYIA SINAS
ESCALATION&amp;RESOLUTION
CUSTOMER CARE DEPARTMENT
Pos Malaysia Berhad (22990-M)
Level 6, Dayabumi Complex 50670 Kuala Lumpur
 hope this helps. 

 This post has been edited by billytattertons : Oct 28 2011, 12:13 AM 

 ripburger Oct 28 2011, 10:06 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #181 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 3

Joined: Jul 2007


 

 
 
 QUOTE(billytattertons@Oct 28 2011, 12:12 AM) Calling them will be faster but u can try emailing them at care@pos.com.my

I tried once to email them about my USPS parcel without tracking and this is what they replied:
hope this helps.  
 Hi there Billy,
thanks for the info.
i called pos at 1300-300-300 today and was told that my parcel has not reached Malaysia yet, no record from customs also.
so i guess i have to continue waiting.
this is weird since its already 3 weeks+ and still not dispatched yet?

 

 billytattertons Oct 30 2011, 05:48 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #182 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 112

Joined: Jun 2011


 
 
 QUOTE(ripburger@Oct 28 2011, 10:06 AM) Hi there Billy,
thanks for the info.
i called pos at 1300-300-300 today and was told that my parcel has not reached Malaysia yet, no record from customs also.
so i guess i have to continue waiting.
this is weird since its already 3 weeks+ and still not dispatched yet?

 
 You are welcome. 
If pos Malaysia is correct, maybe u can try to call/send email to USPS customer service to ask about your parcel. Provide them your tracking number and maybe they can provide some valuable info about ur parcel.

Just a piece of my thought. 

 nill Nov 27 2011, 12:43 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #183 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 9

Joined: May 2010


 

 
 
 i need to confirm, will there be taxes if i order boardgames from US worth USD$140.61?

 This post has been edited by nill : Nov 27 2011, 12:44 PM 

 billytattertons Nov 29 2011, 11:39 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #184 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 112

Joined: Jun 2011


 
 
 QUOTE(nill@Nov 27 2011, 12:43 PM) i need to confirm, will there be taxes if i order boardgames from US worth USD$140.61?
 Think you are asking in the wrong post. but u can check the tax from here: http://tariff.customs.gov.my/ 

 nill Nov 30 2011, 12:26 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #185 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 9

Joined: May 2010


 

 
 
 QUOTE(billytattertons@Nov 29 2011, 11:39 PM) Think you are asking in the wrong post. but u can check the tax from here: http://tariff.customs.gov.my/ 
 Thanks. 

 ripburger Nov 30 2011, 09:09 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #186 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 3

Joined: Jul 2007


 

 
 
 QUOTE(billytattertons@Oct 30 2011, 05:48 PM) You are welcome.  
If pos Malaysia is correct, maybe u can try to call/send email to USPS customer service to ask about your parcel. Provide them your tracking number and maybe they can provide some valuable info about ur parcel.

Just a piece of my thought.
 unfortunately, I highly suspect that my parcel is gone, got refunded.
i purchased another one and this time its USPS Express, hope everything is good this time
its very nice of u for helping me, thanks again! 

 billytattertons Nov 30 2011, 08:11 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #187 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 112

Joined: Jun 2011


 
 
 QUOTE(ripburger@Nov 30 2011, 09:09 AM) unfortunately, I highly suspect that my parcel is gone, got refunded.
i purchased another one and this time its USPS Express, hope everything is good this time
its very nice of u for helping me, thanks again!
 You are welcome. Hope things go smoothly for you this time. 

 Kintey Nov 30 2011, 09:35 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #188 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 4

Joined: Jul 2009


 
 
 Ah, trying to buy Warhammer 40k Battleforce from US, but after reading all the USPS (i only have USPS First Class Mail International as an option atm) problems, im like feeling FUUUUUUUU customs ._.

But the stuff is below Rm350, shouldnt be taxed i presume?
Feel so sedih if my barang kena tahan at custom =.= 

 ripburger Jan 6 2012, 01:27 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #189 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 3

Joined: Jul 2007


 

 
 
 QUOTE(billytattertons@Nov 30 2011, 08:11 PM) You are welcome. Hope things go smoothly for you this time. 
 at last i got my item safely on my hands after waiting for 3 months plus. This time via USPS Express, everything goes smoothly until it was handled by poslaju. According to poslaju track, it was delivered to an unknown person near my area!can you believe that? such simple work and yet they could made an error, i mean, come on, how could a person see home address wrongly?! Guess i ran into some badluck.
anyway everything is good now!I hope my words could help some of our fellow lyners
thanks again Billy for ur help! 
 

 rogershah Mar 5 2012, 10:30 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #190 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 8

Joined: Oct 2008


 

 
 
 hi guys,

I have a question about my parcel from the US.


Label/Receipt Number: CQxxxxxxxx S
Class: Priority Mail International Parcels
Service(s): International Parcels
Status: Customs Clearance

Your item is being processed by customs in MALAYSIA at 9:24 am on March 02, 2012.


Detailed Results:

Customs Clearance, March 02, 2012, 9:24 am, MALAYSIA
Processed Through Sort Facility, March 02, 2012, 9:23 am, MALAYSIA
Processed Through Sort Facility, February 28, 2012, 11:55 am, FOREIGN CENTERJERSEY CITY NJ 099
Arrived at Sort Facility, February 28, 2012, 11:53 am, FOREIGN CENTERJERSEY CITY NJ 099
Processed through USPS Sort Facility, February 25, 2012, 5:40 am, KEARNY, NJ 07032
Depart USPS Sort Facility, February 25, 2012, KEARNY, NJ 07032
Processed at USPS Origin Sort Facility, February 24, 2012, 10:07 pm, KEARNY, NJ 07032
Accepted at USPS Origin Sort Facility, February 24, 2012, 8:52 pm, STONY POINT, NY 10980
Electronic Shipping Info Received, February 23, 2012


It says that my parcel has gone into custom clearance, but I thought that usually they clear the parcel within a few hours on the sameday... but somehow still no update... is it being held up?

any ideas? 

 electronicfly Mar 5 2012, 11:45 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #191 

Getting Started
 
 Trade Zone 

Group: Moderator
Posts: 100

Joined: Nov 2007
From: Selangor


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(rogershah@Mar 5 2012, 10:30 AM) hi guys,

I have a question about my parcel from the US.

 
Label/Receipt Number: CQxxxxxxxx S
Class: Priority Mail International Parcels
Service(s): International Parcels
Status: Customs Clearance

Your item is being processed by customs in MALAYSIA at 9:24 am on March 02, 2012.
  

 Detailed Results:

Customs Clearance, March 02, 2012, 9:24 am, MALAYSIA
Processed Through Sort Facility, March 02, 2012, 9:23 am, MALAYSIA
Processed Through Sort Facility, February 28, 2012, 11:55 am, FOREIGN CENTERJERSEY CITY NJ 099
Arrived at Sort Facility, February 28, 2012, 11:53 am, FOREIGN CENTERJERSEY CITY NJ 099
Processed through USPS Sort Facility, February 25, 2012, 5:40 am, KEARNY, NJ 07032
Depart USPS Sort Facility, February 25, 2012, KEARNY, NJ 07032
Processed at USPS Origin Sort Facility, February 24, 2012, 10:07 pm, KEARNY, NJ 07032
Accepted at USPS Origin Sort Facility, February 24, 2012, 8:52 pm, STONY POINT, NY 10980
Electronic Shipping Info Received, February 23, 2012
It says that my parcel has gone into custom clearance, but I thought that usually they clear the parcel within a few hours on the sameday... but somehow still no update... is it being held up?

any ideas?
 I suggest just chill for a while. Your parcel reached Customs on a Friday = half day, then 1st Sat of the month + Sunday = no work. They don&apos;t always clear parcels that fast also, for me it&apos;s usually 3 working days at least =/ 

 rogershah Mar 5 2012, 01:58 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #192 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 8

Joined: Oct 2008


 

 
 
 QUOTE(electronicfly@Mar 5 2012, 11:45 AM) I suggest just chill for a while. Your parcel reached Customs on a Friday = half day, then 1st Sat of the month + Sunday = no work. They don&apos;t always clear parcels that fast also, for me it&apos;s usually 3 working days at least =/
 I see, thanks. 

 aindejeje Mar 7 2012, 07:20 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #193 

EDA MASTER
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 811

Joined: Jul 2007


 
 
 Anyone can help me:
LJ63419XXXXUS (USPS Priority Flat Rate Padded Envelope)
Acceptance
February 13, 2012, 3:32 pm
HIALEAH, FL 33002
International Letter
Electronic Shipping Info Received
February 13, 2012

Ship 13/2/2012
Up till now, the small padded envelope still not arrived.
Call poslaju, 1300300300 - answer: not trackable.
Call 03-22632616 - she said not in the system, even in klia, still not reach Malaysia. Anyway who know the number is belong to what department?

Is the any contact number that helps?

 This post has been edited by aindejeje : Mar 7 2012, 07:22 PM 

 electronicfly Mar 7 2012, 07:35 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #194 

Getting Started
 
 Trade Zone 

Group: Moderator
Posts: 100

Joined: Nov 2007
From: Selangor


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(aindejeje@Mar 7 2012, 07:20 PM) Anyone can help me:
LJ63419XXXXUS (USPS Priority Flat Rate Padded Envelope)
Acceptance
February 13, 2012, 3:32 pm
HIALEAH, FL 33002
International Letter
Electronic Shipping Info Received
February 13, 2012

Ship 13/2/2012
Up till now, the small padded envelope still not arrived.
Call poslaju, 1300300300 - answer: not trackable.
Call 03-22632616 - she said not in the system, even in klia, still not reach Malaysia. Anyway who know the number is belong to what department?

Is the any contact number that helps?
 Electronic Shipping Info Received&lt;-- this is the info given by sender to USPS through their online self-printing shipping notice thingymabob.

I&apos;ve no clue whether HIALEAH, FL 33002 is one of the exit points, but I doubt it is since the the shipping notice thingy was created on that day itself, and there wasn&apos;t an update that item has been picked up.

There&apos;s a chance that your parcel is still stuck in US, so best to contact USPS or the sender to help. Sad part is that USPS Priority = trackable only within US, so if it&apos;s hilang-ed if/when it reached Malaysia, then there&apos;s no way to track. 

 aindejeje Mar 11 2012, 12:14 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #195 

EDA MASTER
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 811

Joined: Jul 2007


 
 
 QUOTE(electronicfly@Mar 7 2012, 07:35 PM) Electronic Shipping Info Received&lt;-- this is the info given by sender to USPS through their online self-printing shipping notice thingymabob.

I&apos;ve no clue whether HIALEAH, FL 33002 is one of the exit points, but I doubt it is since the the shipping notice thingy was created on that day itself, and there wasn&apos;t an update that item has been picked up.

There&apos;s a chance that your parcel is still stuck in US, so best to contact USPS or the sender to help. Sad part is that USPS Priority = trackable only within US, so if it&apos;s hilang-ed if/when it reached Malaysia, then there&apos;s no way to track.
 I already checked with USPS, they said my item is not trackable.
Which post office shall I refer to if my item is stuck at the post office? Is it normal post office, or special post office that handle parcel? 

 electronicfly Mar 11 2012, 12:08 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #196 

Getting Started
 
 Trade Zone 

Group: Moderator
Posts: 100

Joined: Nov 2007
From: Selangor


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(aindejeje@Mar 11 2012, 12:14 AM) I already checked with USPS, they said my item is not trackable.
Which post office shall I refer to if my item is stuck at the post office? Is it normal post office, or special post office that handle parcel?
 did you ask them specifically about tracking within US? Should be can one lo, I&apos;ve had one that can before =/

Try calling the post office by LCCT that handles the Customs stuff. 

 adambomb Mar 12 2012, 12:39 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #197 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 18

Joined: Jan 2010
From: Kuala Lumpur


 

 
 
 hello everyone, i still haven&apos;t received my package by USPS Priority Mail International, its almost a month now, kinda disappointing to keep waiting

CJ208111396US
Priority Mail International Parcels
Processed Through Sort Facility
March 06, 2012, 6:21 am
FOREIGN CENTERJERSEY CITY NJ 099
International Parcels
Arrived at Sort Facility
March 06, 2012, 6:16 am
FOREIGN CENTERJERSEY CITY NJ 099
Depart USPS Sort Facility
February 21, 2012
KEARNY, NJ 07032
Processed through USPS Sort Facility
February 21, 2012, 7:24 am
KEARNY, NJ 07032
Electronic Shipping Info Received
February 18, 2012
Processed at USPS Origin Sort Facility
February 18, 2012, 12:23 am
NASHUA, NH 03063
Accepted at USPS Origin Sort Facility
February 17, 2012, 11:08 pm
SALEM, NH 03079

Is this normal? 

 bakrul Mar 12 2012, 07:44 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #198 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 23

Joined: Apr 2010


 
 
 QUOTE(adambomb@Mar 12 2012, 12:39 AM) hello everyone, i still haven&apos;t received my package by USPS Priority Mail International, its almost a month now, kinda disappointing to keep waiting

CJ208111396US
Priority Mail International Parcels
Processed Through Sort Facility
March 06, 2012, 6:21 am
FOREIGN CENTERJERSEY CITY NJ 099
International Parcels
Arrived at Sort Facility
March 06, 2012, 6:16 am
FOREIGN CENTERJERSEY CITY NJ 099
Depart USPS Sort Facility
February 21, 2012
KEARNY, NJ 07032
Processed through USPS Sort Facility
February 21, 2012, 7:24 am
KEARNY, NJ 07032
Electronic Shipping Info Received
February 18, 2012
Processed at USPS Origin Sort Facility
February 18, 2012, 12:23 am
NASHUA, NH 03063
Accepted at USPS Origin Sort Facility
February 17, 2012, 11:08 pm
SALEM, NH 03079

Is this normal?
 pls call posmalaysia, u can ask status of the tracking no.
 

 electronicfly Mar 12 2012, 09:59 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #199 

Getting Started
 
 Trade Zone 

Group: Moderator
Posts: 100

Joined: Nov 2007
From: Selangor


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(adambomb@Mar 12 2012, 12:39 AM) hello everyone, i still haven&apos;t received my package by USPS Priority Mail International, its almost a month now, kinda disappointing to keep waiting

CJ208111396US
Priority Mail International Parcels
Processed Through Sort Facility
March 06, 2012, 6:21 am
FOREIGN CENTERJERSEY CITY NJ 099
International Parcels
Arrived at Sort Facility
March 06, 2012, 6:16 am
FOREIGN CENTERJERSEY CITY NJ 099
Depart USPS Sort Facility
February 21, 2012
KEARNY, NJ 07032
Processed through USPS Sort Facility
February 21, 2012, 7:24 am
KEARNY, NJ 07032
Electronic Shipping Info Received
February 18, 2012
Processed at USPS Origin Sort Facility
February 18, 2012, 12:23 am
NASHUA, NH 03063
Accepted at USPS Origin Sort Facility
February 17, 2012, 11:08 pm
SALEM, NH 03079

Is this normal?
 It&apos;s still in US as of 6th March. I don&apos;t know why it took them about 2 weeks to travel 400+km though -.-&quot;

Processed Through Sort Facility March 06, 2012, 6:21 am FOREIGN CENTERJERSEY CITY NJ 099 

 Starscream666 Mar 12 2012, 10:49 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #200 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 57

Joined: Jul 2007


 

 
 
 this thread should be a sticky, theres quite a few sifu&apos;s here already lol
am i allowed to ask noob question? i tried google and stuff like that cant get concrete answer la

for USPS express mail normally how long does it take to reach MY anyway? 

 electronicfly Mar 12 2012, 11:13 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #201 

Getting Started
 
 Trade Zone 

Group: Moderator
Posts: 100

Joined: Nov 2007
From: Selangor


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(Starscream666@Mar 12 2012, 10:49 AM) this thread should be a sticky, theres quite a few sifu&apos;s here already lol
am i allowed to ask noob question? i tried google and stuff like that cant get concrete answer la

for USPS express mail normally how long does it take to reach MY anyway?
 Search on the USPS website ma. 3-5 days
 https://www.usps.com/ship/service-chart.htm 

 Starscream666 Mar 12 2012, 01:09 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #202 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 57

Joined: Jul 2007


 

 
 
 i am a lousy seacher, once again thank you for assisting a noobazoid 

 stinky Mar 12 2012, 06:39 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #203 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 274

Joined: Feb 2005


 

 
 
 Oh No....my parcel has been detained by Pos M&apos;sia Kastam at KLIA.

I dont understand why, it&apos;s just a camera bag, 0.5kg, 1 unit, USD130 (less than RM500).......why why why?

 

 adambomb Mar 12 2012, 08:25 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #204 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 18

Joined: Jan 2010
From: Kuala Lumpur


 

 
 
 QUOTE(bakrul@Mar 12 2012, 07:44 AM) pls call posmalaysia, u can ask status of the tracking no.
 i already email pos malaysia, surprisingly the response was fast
the package just cleared malaysian customs today 

 Added on March 12, 2012, 8:26 pm QUOTE(electronicfly@Mar 12 2012, 09:59 AM) It&apos;s still in US as of 6th March. I don&apos;t know why it took them about 2 weeks to travel 400+km though -.-&quot;

Processed Through Sort Facility       March 06, 2012, 6:21 am       FOREIGN CENTERJERSEY CITY NJ 099
 yeah. funny that it got stuck in US for quite some time sigh

 This post has been edited by adambomb : Mar 12 2012, 08:26 PM 

 billytattertons Mar 13 2012, 12:51 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #205 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 112

Joined: Jun 2011


 
 
 QUOTE(adambomb@Mar 12 2012, 08:25 PM) i already email pos malaysia, surprisingly the response was fast
the package just cleared malaysian customs today  i agree with u. 
emailed them once and i find them helpful. 

 aindejeje Mar 17 2012, 05:03 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #206 

EDA MASTER
 

Group: Senior Member
Posts: 811

Joined: Jul 2007


 
 
 QUOTE(electronicfly@Mar 11 2012, 12:08 PM) did you ask them specifically about tracking within US? Should be can one lo, I&apos;ve had one that can before =/

Try calling the post office by LCCT that handles the Customs stuff.
 I called them (03-8777XXXX), but they also said it is not trackable. zzzz.
I email USPS with my tracking number LJXXXXXXXXXUS (small padded envelope), same reply: not trackable.
Damn service with tracking number but not trackable. 

 mfa97 Mar 21 2012, 02:37 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #207 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 24

Joined: May 2008
From: Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia


 

 
 
 Sharing experience with forumers.. my package using USPS Express Mail International service arrived in 8 days, could have been 6 days but I was not in office on Saturday.

 Attached thumbnail(s) 
 

 nuttyking91 Mar 29 2012, 01:18 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #208 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 165

Joined: Nov 2011
From: Penang, Malaysia


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(mfa97@Mar 21 2012, 02:37 PM) Sharing experience with forumers.. my package using USPS Express Mail International service arrived in 8 days, could have been 6 days but I was not in office on Saturday.
 great info here. I should roughly know when will my parcel arrive. was sent on tuesday using USPS express mail. hope everything goes smoothly. 

 svage98 Mar 29 2012, 09:15 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #209 

Casual
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 344

Joined: Oct 2007
From: Nilai/Putrajaya/Bangi


 
 

 
 
 Express Mail should reach Malaysia within 7 days but the problem is usually with our Kustam which our package could get held for a few days or a week or two depending on them&gt;.&gt;

 This post has been edited by svage98 : Mar 29 2012, 09:16 AM 

 nuttyking91 Apr 2 2012, 07:51 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #210 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 165

Joined: Nov 2011
From: Penang, Malaysia


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(svage98@Mar 29 2012, 09:15 AM) Express Mail should reach Malaysia within 7 days but the problem is usually with our Kustam which our package could get held for a few days or a week or two depending on them&gt;.&gt;
 can i now use local tracking to track my parcel already? since has reached malaysian borders. which tracking to use? poslaju or pos malaysia? 

Customs Clearance


April 02, 2012, 10:44 am


MALAYSIA


Proof of Delivery




Processed Through Sort Facility


April 02, 2012, 10:43 am


MALAYSIA





Processed Through Sort Facility


March 28, 2012, 4:52 pm


ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)





Arrived at Sort Facility


March 28, 2012, 4:51 pm


ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)





Depart USPS Sort Facility


March 27, 2012


BIRMINGHAM, AL 35203





Processed through USPS Sort Facility


March 27, 2012, 7:35 pm


BIRMINGHAM, AL 35203





Dispatched to Sort Facility


March 27, 2012, 5:22 pm


BIRMINGHAM, AL 35209





Acceptance


March 27, 2012, 4:46 pm


BIRMINGHAM, AL 35209
 

 billytattertons Apr 2 2012, 09:55 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #211 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 112

Joined: Jun 2011


 
 
 if u r using priority mail, then u can track it using pos malaysia website - parcel. 

 nuttyking91 Apr 3 2012, 02:11 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #212 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 165

Joined: Nov 2011
From: Penang, Malaysia


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(billytattertons@Apr 2 2012, 09:55 PM) if u r using priority mail, then u can track it using pos malaysia website - parcel.
 using express mail. cannot see my parcel in poslaju or pos malaysia. Is it beacouse my place doesn&apos;t have tracking system? 

 billytattertons Apr 3 2012, 05:56 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #213 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 112

Joined: Jun 2011


 
 
 QUOTE(nuttyking91@Apr 3 2012, 02:11 PM) using express mail. cannot see my parcel in poslaju or pos malaysia. Is it beacouse my place doesn&apos;t have tracking system?
 not really sure about express mail. sorry about that. ur item is normal mail or parcel? which category have u tried to track?
i believe every PPL/pos malaysia office will have tracking system.

 

 nuttyking91 Apr 3 2012, 08:01 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #214 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 165

Joined: Nov 2011
From: Penang, Malaysia


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(billytattertons@Apr 3 2012, 05:56 PM) not really sure about express mail. sorry about that. ur item is normal mail or parcel? which category have u tried to track?
i believe every PPL/pos malaysia office will have tracking system.
 a very small parcel. sunglasses. the last time i post a parcel to Kampar also wothout tracking. the sender gave me the tracking number, but even after i received it, there&apos;s still no records in the online tracking system. so i assume Kampar doesn&apos;t have a tracking system, so they don&apos;t even bother to scan when it was first posted. customs have released it on monday 10+ am yesterday. hopefully i can get it by tmr? 

 billytattertons Apr 3 2012, 11:22 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #215 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 112

Joined: Jun 2011


 
 
 QUOTE(nuttyking91@Apr 3 2012, 08:01 PM) a very small parcel. sunglasses.  the last time i post a parcel to Kampar also wothout tracking. the sender gave me the tracking number, but even after i received it, there&apos;s still no records in the online tracking system. so i assume Kampar doesn&apos;t have a tracking system, so they don&apos;t even bother to scan when it was first posted. customs have released it on monday 10+ am yesterday. hopefully i can get it by tmr?
 You could be right. Had similar experiences like you, only that i&apos;m the sender.
Should be getting it by tomorrow. (unless PPL ppl decided to take another day) 

 nuttyking91 Apr 4 2012, 01:00 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #216 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 165

Joined: Nov 2011
From: Penang, Malaysia


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(billytattertons@Apr 3 2012, 11:22 PM) You could be right. Had similar experiences like you, only that i&apos;m the sender.
Should be getting it by tomorrow. (unless PPL ppl decided to take another day)
 is it possible that it is detained in customs? perhaps i want to call in there. I see those successful ones have custom clearance processing completed. mine don&apos;t have. sunglasses is untaxable though.

Customs Clearance
April 02, 2012, 10:44 am
MALAYSIA

Processed Through Sort Facility
April 02, 2012, 10:43 am
MALAYSIA

Processed Through Sort Facility
March 28, 2012, 4:52 pm
ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)

Arrived at Sort Facility
March 28, 2012, 4:51 pm
ISC MIAMI FL (USPS)

Depart USPS Sort Facility
March 27, 2012
BIRMINGHAM, AL 35203

Processed through USPS Sort Facility
March 27, 2012, 7:35 pm
BIRMINGHAM, AL 35203

Dispatched to Sort Facility
March 27, 2012, 5:22 pm
BIRMINGHAM, AL 35209

Acceptance
March 27, 2012, 4:46 pm
BIRMINGHAM, AL 35209

 This post has been edited by nuttyking91 : Apr 4 2012, 01:03 AM 

 billytattertons Apr 4 2012, 01:17 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #217 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 112

Joined: Jun 2011


 
 
 QUOTE(nuttyking91@Apr 4 2012, 01:00 AM) is it possible that it is detained in customs? perhaps i want to call in there. I see those successful ones have custom clearance processing completed. mine don&apos;t have.  sunglasses is untaxable though. there&apos;s this possibility, since the tracking system doesn&apos;t show processing completed.
my priority mail parcels usually have another column showing custom clearance processing completed after the custom clearance.

sunglasses is non-taxable stuff but if the price&gt;rm500 (including shipping), they might tax u...

better call them up to ask. 

 nuttyking91 Apr 4 2012, 01:25 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #218 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 165

Joined: Nov 2011
From: Penang, Malaysia


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(billytattertons@Apr 4 2012, 01:17 AM) there&apos;s this possibility, since the tracking system doesn&apos;t show processing completed.
my priority mail parcels usually have another column showing custom clearance processing completed after the custom clearance.

sunglasses is non-taxable stuff but if the price&gt;rm500 (including shipping), they might tax u...

better call them up to ask.
 I will call them later in the morning then I wonder how much will they charge me. only a student, hopefully can deal with them if they really held my stuffs. It&apos;s just around USD166 plus shipping, slightly over though. I don&apos;t know how much my sender declare the item worth. 

 billytattertons Apr 4 2012, 01:30 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #219 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 112

Joined: Jun 2011


 
 
 QUOTE(nuttyking91@Apr 4 2012, 01:25 AM) I will call them later in the morning then  I wonder how much will they charge me. only a student, hopefully can deal with them if they really held my stuffs. It&apos;s just around USD166 plus shipping, slightly over though. I don&apos;t know how much my sender declare the item worth.
 try to nego with them if they really charge. Best of luck to you 2ml! 

 nuttyking91 Apr 4 2012, 12:59 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #220 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 165

Joined: Nov 2011
From: Penang, Malaysia


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(billytattertons@Apr 4 2012, 01:30 AM) try to nego with them if they really charge. Best of luck to you 2ml!
 called up one by one from pos klia to pos ipoh. currently on the way to tapah. hopefully no tax. if got tax means usually ifter clearing from klia means no tax? strangely no tracking update for USPS after custom clearance. 

 bakrul Apr 4 2012, 02:25 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #221 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 23

Joined: Apr 2010


 
 
 QUOTE(nuttyking91@Apr 4 2012, 12:59 PM) called up one by one from pos klia to pos ipoh. currently on the way to tapah. hopefully no tax.  if got tax means    usually ifter clearing from klia means no tax? strangely no tracking update for USPS after custom clearance.
 yup....once item released from KLIA that mean no tax.USPS will not update the system after custom clearance but will updated it when u received the item 

 nuttyking91 Apr 4 2012, 07:44 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #222 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 165

Joined: Nov 2011
From: Penang, Malaysia


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(bakrul@Apr 4 2012, 02:25 PM) yup....once item released from KLIA that mean no tax.USPS will not update the system after custom clearance but will updated it when u received the item
 hopefully will receive my stuff tomorrow afternoon 

 Added on April 5, 2012, 12:39 pm QUOTE(nuttyking91@Apr 4 2012, 07:44 PM) hopefully will receive my stuff tomorrow afternoon  
 received my item!no tax!the seller declare it cheap cheap.!delivery time for USPS express mail, roughly a week. 

 This post has been edited by nuttyking91 : Apr 5 2012, 12:39 PM 

 kentkoh Apr 26 2012, 12:39 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #223 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 159

Joined: Sep 2008


 

 
 
 i just bought an item from ebay cost me USD300 on 17th April.

the latest up date for my tracking number is only 21st April saying
&quot;Processed Through Sort Facility&quot;

what does it mean? it mean 10days from the item been shipped out.

but still in&quot;Processed Through Sort Facility&quot;?? 

 bakrul Apr 26 2012, 02:57 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #224 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 23

Joined: Apr 2010


 
 
 QUOTE(kentkoh@Apr 26 2012, 12:39 PM) i just bought an item from ebay cost me USD300 on 17th April.

the latest up date for my tracking number is only 21st April saying
&quot;Processed Through Sort Facility&quot;

what does it mean? it mean 10days from the item been shipped out.

but still in&quot;Processed Through Sort Facility&quot;??
 what type of shipping the seller used? 

 billytattertons Apr 26 2012, 04:59 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #225 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 112

Joined: Jun 2011


 
 
 QUOTE(kentkoh@Apr 26 2012, 12:39 PM) i just bought an item from ebay cost me USD300 on 17th April.

the latest up date for my tracking number is only 21st April saying
&quot;Processed Through Sort Facility&quot;

what does it mean? it mean 10days from the item been shipped out.

but still in&quot;Processed Through Sort Facility&quot;??
 from ur description, sounds like ur item is without tracking. then shud be first class intl mail.
if it&apos;s without tracking (usually starts with LC ends with US), then ur tracking ends at Processed through sort facility. 

 Dar1en Apr 28 2012, 05:02 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #226 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 30

Joined: Mar 2012


 

 
 
 First-Class Mail International

Processed through USPS Sort Facility

April 13, 2012, 11:57 pm

JAMAICA, NY 11430

why so long? -___- 

 Latios Apr 29 2012, 05:38 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #227 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 90

Joined: May 2008
From: Lawas, Sarawak


 

 
 
 QUOTE(Dar1en@Apr 28 2012, 05:02 PM) First-Class Mail International

Processed through USPS Sort Facility

April 13, 2012, 11:57 pm

JAMAICA, NY 11430

why so long? -___-
 This is because First class Mail International is not traceable. It is just a reference that your item is sent. Only traceable mails are Priority Mail International, Registered Mail, and Express Mail International. 

 kentkoh May 1 2012, 02:21 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #228 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 159

Joined: Sep 2008


 

 
 
 
 2 times customs clearance. And do u think my stuff will be detained by customs. My item worth RM1000 but dunno how much seller declare. 



Customs Clearance


April 30, 2012, 2:23 pm


MALAYSIA







Customs Clearance


April 30, 2012, 10:19 am


MALAYSIA




 

 HongLJ May 1 2012, 07:32 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #229 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 0

Joined: Apr 2012


 
 
 Guys i need your help!I bought a box of headphones on the 3rd of march and shipped it using USPS First Class International Mail but it never arrived. So by the 45th day i started a dispute on ebay and now filed a claim, but paypal is slow in resolving this case. Now i have another 2 items that never arrived, other stuff that i bought and ship using USPS First Class usually arrive within 2 weeks but not this 3 stuff. I noticed that this 2 of this 3 things were large parcels, i was wondering weather is it possible that it actually arrived, but the postman can&apos;t fit the box into the mailbox of my apartment, so he just left it there? Or are they supposed to leave a note by my door or mailbox? Up until now i have not received any letters or notes by either the customs or the post office for me to go retrieve my item. And all my items was less than USD100 of value, so it wouldn&apos;t be possible that the custom detained it. Any experience or suggestions guys? 

 bakrul May 1 2012, 10:57 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #230 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 23

Joined: Apr 2010


 
 
 QUOTE(HongLJ@May 1 2012, 07:32 PM) Guys i need your help!I bought a box of headphones on the 3rd of march and shipped it using USPS First Class International Mail but it never arrived. So by the 45th day i started a dispute on ebay and now filed a claim, but paypal is slow in resolving this case. Now i have another 2 items that never arrived, other stuff that i bought and ship using USPS First Class usually arrive within 2 weeks but not this 3 stuff. I noticed that this 2 of this 3 things were large parcels, i was wondering weather is it possible that it actually arrived, but the postman can&apos;t fit the box into the mailbox of my apartment, so he just left it there? Or are they supposed to leave a note by my door or mailbox? Up until now i have not received any letters or notes by either the customs or the post office for me to go retrieve my item. And all my items was less than USD100 of value, so it wouldn&apos;t be possible that the custom detained it. Any experience or suggestions guys?
 Since ur shipment are not trackable is very difficult to solve.r u staying in apartment...coz if item too big mr.postman will leave where he think posible 4 u/other ppl to see the parcel.just be patient..let paypal handle it 4 u.u will get ur money back 

 rikusai May 9 2012, 09:49 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #231 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 17

Joined: May 2008
From: KL


 

 
 
 help!anyone know whats the process of my parcel now?

LOS ANGELES, CA, USA
Saturday, May 5, 2012 8:47 AM
PROCESSED THROUGH USPS SORT FACILITY
ANAHEIM, CA, USA
Saturday, May 5, 2012
DEPART USPS SORT FACILITY
Friday, May 4, 2012 7:24 PM
PROCESSED THROUGH USPS SORT FACILITY
CORONA, CA, USA
Friday, May 4, 2012 6:23 PM
DISPATCHED TO SORT FACILITY

it seems that the sort facility at Anaheim only took a day and my parcel was sent to LA. but its been like 4 days and no updates at all. My tracking number stars with CQXXXXXXXXXXUS. 

 keeluen May 9 2012, 10:27 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #232 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 5

Joined: Jun 2008


 

 
 
 it should be arriving in malaysia soon.
my case : used priority mail only.. ship out 24th april. reached kastam on 2nd may, finally from pos malaysia on 7th may.
so roughly estimation of time is there for your reference..
 

 rikusai May 9 2012, 11:55 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #233 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 17

Joined: May 2008
From: KL


 

 
 
 QUOTE(keeluen@May 9 2012, 10:27 AM) it should be arriving in malaysia soon.
my case : used priority mail only.. ship out 24th april. reached kastam on 2nd may, finally from pos malaysia on 7th may.
so roughly estimation of time is there for your reference..
 but the information stops at LA. I&apos;m taking Anaheim for an example. at Anaheim it tells me that the parcel has departed the sort facility and ended up at LA sort facility. Shouldn&apos;t it give me another information stating that its departing LA USPS sort facility to the LA airport or something? 

 Kenneth Thien May 13 2012, 06:35 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #234 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 7

Joined: Sep 2009


 

 
 
 QUOTE(doli_pargorsi@Aug 19 2009, 09:02 PM) Good news, I received the goods today. 

Found that it had been held at Malaysia Custom since 12/08/2009 until 18/08/2008.

Custom had opened the packing, but luckily nothing missing. They released it without any problem nor duty.

Yes, now I know the C64xxxxxx7US is the US custom reference number (I think the US seller forgot to mention it too).

Case is resolved now. I hope my experience will be useful for other forum members.
 Bro, how do u know was stuck in custom? I&apos;m still waiting my item till now since 17th April 2012.

I&apos;m very kan cheong with it le...

 Added on May 13, 2012, 7:23 pm QUOTE(rikusai@May 9 2012, 09:49 AM) help!anyone know whats the process of my parcel now?

LOS ANGELES, CA, USA
Saturday, May 5, 2012 8:47 AM
PROCESSED THROUGH USPS SORT FACILITY
ANAHEIM, CA, USA
Saturday, May 5, 2012
DEPART USPS SORT FACILITY
Friday, May 4, 2012 7:24 PM
PROCESSED THROUGH USPS SORT FACILITY
CORONA, CA, USA
Friday, May 4, 2012 6:23 PM
DISPATCHED TO SORT FACILITY

it seems that the sort facility at Anaheim only took a day and my parcel was sent to LA. but its been like 4 days and no updates at all. My tracking number stars with CQXXXXXXXXXXUS.
 How you can get it so details ?

Mine is just told me electronic receive from USPS only, it&apos;s been 3weeks le...

Please help...

 This post has been edited by Kenneth Thien : May 13 2012, 07:23 PM 

 rikusai May 14 2012, 01:14 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #235 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 17

Joined: May 2008
From: KL


 

 
 
 QUOTE(Kenneth Thien@May 13 2012, 06:35 PM) Added on May 13, 2012, 7:23 pm 
How you can get it so details ?

Mine is just told me electronic receive from USPS only, it&apos;s been 3weeks le...

Please help...
 Did the seller provide a tracking no? Mine starts with CQXXXXXXXXXUS so mine is trackable tilll it reaches my door step, i think.

If urs starts with LJ, then urs cant be tracked and probably already reached Malaysia base on the date of order.

Either u can try calling poslaju if your tracking starts with C and inquire or contact the seller to see whats the hold up. But if start with L, dont bother calling poslaju cuz they will tell u thats normal mail and not parcel. But still try contacting the seller for advice

 This post has been edited by rikusai : May 14 2012, 01:15 PM 

 pearllypearl May 30 2012, 08:02 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #236 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 1

Joined: Jul 2008


 
 
 mine is even worse. i&apos;ve been waiting for nearly 2months haven&apos;t get my item. contacted the seller, seller asked me to track the parcel by myself (as if i never tracked before..). Then i emailed USPS, no feedback. But I haven&apos;t check with PosLaju yet.
My tracking details as below... . How to resolve?!

LJ9xxxxxxxx US
 »Click to show Spoiler - click again to hide...« First-Class Mail International
Processed through USPS Sort Facility - April 04, 2012, 11:23 pm - LOS ANGELES, CA 90009

International Letter

Electronic Shipping Info Received - April 04, 2012

Dispatched to Sort Facility - April 03, 2012, 5:48 pm - NEWHALL, CA 91321

Acceptance - April 03, 2012, 2:35 pm
 

 penpal_my May 30 2012, 08:26 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #237 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 13

Joined: Nov 2006


 

 
 
 QUOTE(pearllypearl@May 30 2012, 08:02 AM) mine is even worse. i&apos;ve been waiting for nearly 2months haven&apos;t get my item. contacted the seller, seller asked me to track the parcel by myself (as if i never tracked before..). Then i emailed USPS, no feedback. But I haven&apos;t check with PosLaju yet.
My tracking details as below... . How to resolve?!

LJ9xxxxxxxx US
 »Click to show Spoiler - click again to hide...« First-Class Mail International
Processed through USPS Sort Facility - April 04, 2012, 11:23 pm - LOS ANGELES, CA 90009

International Letter

Electronic Shipping Info Received -  April 04, 2012

Dispatched to Sort Facility - April 03, 2012, 5:48 pm - NEWHALL, CA 91321

Acceptance -  April 03, 2012, 2:35 pm
 
 i also still did not received my parcels using First Class Mail. Now nearly 2 months...i just open the cases. dont know whether i can get the money back since it is not the seller fault. Can paypal refund my money with case like this? 

 This post has been edited by penpal_my : May 30 2012, 08:27 AM 

 bakrul May 30 2012, 08:27 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #238 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 23

Joined: Apr 2010


 
 
 QUOTE(pearllypearl@May 30 2012, 08:02 AM) mine is even worse. i&apos;ve been waiting for nearly 2months haven&apos;t get my item. contacted the seller, seller asked me to track the parcel by myself (as if i never tracked before..). Then i emailed USPS, no feedback. But I haven&apos;t check with PosLaju yet.
My tracking details as below... . How to resolve?!

LJ9xxxxxxxx US
 »Click to show Spoiler - click again to hide...« First-Class Mail International
Processed through USPS Sort Facility - April 04, 2012, 11:23 pm - LOS ANGELES, CA 90009 

International Letter

Electronic Shipping Info Received - April 04, 2012

Dispatched to Sort Facility - April 03, 2012, 5:48 pm - NEWHALL, CA 91321 
 
Acceptance - April 03, 2012, 2:35 pm
 
 i assume that ur parcel is missing.if u bought thru ebay just open a dispute and get a refund.ur tracking no. only show that the seller send the item and it&apos;s lost. 

 kowjobin May 31 2012, 01:06 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #239 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 0

Joined: May 2009


 
 
 What is tat mean by attempted delivery abroad?
I didnt received it till 2day.. wher should i call to noe where is my packages?

Express Mail International®
Attempted Delivery Abroad
May 22, 2012, 10:02 am
MALAYSIA
Proof of Delivery
Attempted Delivery Abroad
May 21, 2012, 7:42 am
MALAYSIA
Customs clearance processing complete
May 20, 2012, 1:00 am
MALAYSIA
Customs Clearance
May 19, 2012, 11:33 pm
MALAYSIA 

 bakrul May 31 2012, 08:20 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #240 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 23

Joined: Apr 2010


 
 
 QUOTE(kowjobin@May 31 2012, 01:06 AM) What is tat mean by attempted delivery abroad?
I didnt received it till 2day.. wher should i call to noe where is my packages?

Express Mail International®
Attempted Delivery Abroad
May 22, 2012, 10:02 am
MALAYSIA
Proof of Delivery
Attempted Delivery Abroad
May 21, 2012, 7:42 am
MALAYSIA
Customs clearance processing complete
May 20, 2012, 1:00 am
MALAYSIA
Customs Clearance
May 19, 2012, 11:33 pm
MALAYSIA
 just call posmalaysia and give them the tracking no.they know the status of your item 

 pearllypearl Jun 6 2012, 08:15 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #241 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 1

Joined: Jul 2008


 
 
 QUOTE(bakrul@May 30 2012, 08:27 AM) i assume that ur parcel is missing.if u bought thru ebay just open a dispute and get a refund.ur tracking no. only show that the seller send the item and it&apos;s lost.
 mine is actually a redemption of a deal which i bought from those group saving websites.
anyway, i&apos;ve reported the case to that website and they&apos;ve contacted the seller as well to resend the item from US again.
POS Malaysia is reaaaaaally very disappointing! 

 kyo6813013 Jul 3 2012, 04:32 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #242 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 14

Joined: Jan 2008


 
 

 
 
 Anyone know&quot;Addressee not available - Addressee advised to pick up the item&quot;word this tracking? anyone know the meaning my item in post office?
 

 billytattertons Jul 3 2012, 04:40 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #243 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 112

Joined: Jun 2011


 
 
 QUOTE(kyo6813013@Jul 3 2012, 04:32 PM) Anyone know&quot;Addressee not available - Addressee advised to pick up the item&quot;word this tracking? anyone know the meaning my item in post office?
 yes, this means that your item is with the post office ppl. 

 kyo6813013 Jul 3 2012, 04:56 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #244 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 14

Joined: Jan 2008


 
 

 
 
 QUOTE(billytattertons@Jul 3 2012, 04:40 PM) yes, this means that your item is with the post office ppl.
 So, me need going post office collect item?or waiting
someone delivery to me? 

 billytattertons Jul 3 2012, 07:27 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #245 

Getting Started
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 112

Joined: Jun 2011


 
 
 QUOTE(kyo6813013@Jul 3 2012, 04:56 PM) So, me need going post office collect item?or waiting
someone delivery to me?
 U have to head over to poslaju centre that holds ur item to collect.
Poslaju only offers 2nd delivery to poslaju items, dun think priority mail is included. 

 blossom0909 Jul 4 2012, 09:38 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #246 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 0

Joined: Jul 2011


 

 
 
 I bought some skincare products from US recently and they were shipped out by seller 2 weeks ago with first class mail international and tracking number starting with LN*********US. Current tracking status shows&quot;Depart USPS Sort Facility - LOS ANGELES, CA 90009&quot;. Should I be worrying about it now? how do I know whether they&apos;ve arrived in Msia? Pls advice any1.
 

 bakrul Jul 5 2012, 07:40 AM Show posts by this member only | Post #247 

New Member
 

Group: Junior Member
Posts: 23

Joined: Apr 2010


 
 
 QUOTE(blossom0909@Jul 4 2012, 09:38 PM) I bought some skincare products from US recently and they were shipped out by seller 2 weeks ago with first class mail international and tracking number starting with LN*********US. Current tracking status shows&quot;Depart USPS Sort Facility - LOS ANGELES, CA 90009&quot;. Should I be worrying about it now? how do I know whether they&apos;ve arrived in Msia? Pls advice any1.
 First Class Mail International do not offer tracking outside from US.it just the info that seller had send the item out.just wait the Mr Posman drop it in your mail box. 

 blossom0909 Jul 7 2012, 09:14 PM Show posts by this member only | Post #248 

New Member
 

Group: New Member
Posts: 0

Joined: Jul 2011


 

 
 
 thanks. received a note from pos malaysia yesterday. 2 weeks is pretty fast i mean for this normal mail. 
 «Next Oldest · Trade Zone Resource Centre · Next Newest»   
 0 new posts since last visit! Read latest posts or hide this alert 
 
 
   Close Topic Options Track this topic 
 Receive email notification when a reply has been made to this topic and you are not active on the board. 

 Subscribe to this forum 
 Receive email notification when a new topic is posted in this forum and you are not active on the board. 

 Download / Print this Topic 
 Download this topic in different formats or view a printer friendly version. Forum Home Search Help Front Desk   |-- Announcements   |-- Main Site/Forum Feedback and Helpdesk   |---- Accepted Feature Requests   |-- Events and Gatherings Computers   |-- Essential Reviews and Guides   |-- Technical Support   |-- Hardware   |---- Hardware Questions&amp;Answers   |-- Software   |---- Latest Updates   |---- Windows 7   |---- Windows Vista   |---- Internet Related   |---- Multimedia   |---- Security&amp;Privacy   |-- Overclockers United   |---- Cooling and Hard-modding   |---- Lowyat.NET Overclocking Database   |-- Gamers Hideout   |---- Diablo III   |---- World of Warcraft   |---- Counterstrike   |---- Online Gaming   |------ Warhammer Online: Age of Reckoning   |---- Warcraft 3   |---- Sports Games   |---- Battlefield Series   |---- Competitive Gaming   |---- Call of Duty   |---- StarCraft   |---- Gamers Hideout Garage Sales   |-- Desktop Customization   |-- Casings and Modifications   |---- Worklogs   |-- Price&amp;Dealers Guide   |---- Gamer&apos;s Hideout Sdn. Bhd.   |---- Compuzone   |---- Cycom Sales&amp;Service   |---- Inter-Asia (Edifier Speakers)   |---- Gadget Zone   |---- Winchance   |---- JACtech Advance Computer Services   |---- TECH Computer Workshop Special Interest   |-- Apple Byte   |---- iPhone   |---- iPod Bar   |---- iPad   |-- Mobile Computing   |---- Notebook Specific Discussion   |-- Mobile Phones and PDAs   |---- Windows Phone   |------ Windows Phone Handset-Specific Discussion   |---- Symbian   |------ Symbian Phone-Specific Discussion   |---- Standard OS and Others   |------ Standard OS and other Specific Discussion   |---- Blackberry   |---- Android   |-- Photography, Digital Imaging&amp;Video   |---- Showcase   |-- Consoles Couch   |---- Playstation   |---- Xbox   |---- Nintendo   |---- Consoles Couch Garage Sales   |-- Networks and Broadband   |---- Broadband User-2-User   |---- Getting Broadband   |---- Networking Tech Support   |-- Codemasters   |-- Linux&amp;Open Source Software   |-- Arts&amp;Designs   |-- Blogmasters&amp;Webmasters   |---- LYN Bloggers   |-- Home Entertainment   |---- Audiophiles   |-- Musicians Roundtable Discussions   |-- Real World Issues   |-- Finance, Business and Investment House   |---- Stock Exchange   |---- Credit Cards, Debit Cards and Loyalty Cards   |-- Property Talk   |---- Home Renovations and Interior Design   |-- Education Essentials   |---- PhD School   |-- Jobs&amp;Careers   |---- Job Market Trends by JobStreet.com   |-- Pregnancy&amp;Parenting   |-- Health&amp;Fitness   |---- Member Workout Journals   |---- Bodybuilding&amp;Strength Training Lifestyle   |-- Kopitiam   |---- Serious Kopitiam   |---- Jokes Heaven   |---- Chat-Free Kopitiam   |---- Chat and Group Discussion Only   |---- The Museum Of Kopitiam   |-- Cupid&apos;s Corner   |-- The Fast&amp;The Furious   |---- ICE   |---- Technical Talk   |-- Pets Wonderland   |-- Movies&amp;Music   |---- Galeries de Celebrites   |-- Anime Shrine   |-- The Sports Channel   |-- Football Lounge   |-- Hobbies, Collectibles and Model Kits   |---- LYN Book Club   |-- Travel&amp;Living   |-- Food&amp;Flavours   |-- Girl&apos;s Club   |---- Cosmetics   |---- GC Garage Sales   |-- Trends + Fashion   |-- Men&apos;s Style&amp;Fashion LYN Community Projects   |-- Folding@Malaysia   |-- LYN Charity Foundation   |-- LYN T-Shirt Design Competition 2011 Classifieds   |-- Job Enlistments   |-- Properties   |-- Services Noticeboard Trade Zone   |-- Garage Sales   |---- Full Systems, CPU, Motherboards, Casings, PSUs   |---- Display Cards&amp;Monitors   |---- Memory&amp;Drives   |---- Mobile Phones and Related Accessories   |---- Networking Related Items   |---- Notebooks&amp;Tablets   |---- Music Players and Audio Related Accessories   |---- Games   |---- Cameras&amp;Photography   |------ Digital SLRs&amp;Lenses   |------ Compacts&amp;Prosumers   |------ Photography Accessories   |---- Blu-ray / HD-DVD / DVD   |-- LYN Street Mart   |---- Automotive Garage   |---- Stuff For The Ladies   |---- Stuff for the Lads   |---- Food Market   |---- Hobbies&amp;Collectibles   |---- Pet Store   |---- Home Electronics&amp;Homewares   |---- Musical Instruments   |-- Bulk Orders   |---- Memory, Drives&amp;Media   |-- Trade Zone Resource Centre   |-- Trade Zone Helpdesk&amp;Dispute Resolution Corner   |-- Lowyat.NET Official Merchandise   
 
 
 
 Switch to: | Lo-Fi Version 0.3140sec   7.36   7queries   GZIP Disabled
Time is now: 12th July 2012 - 09:31 PM 
 All Rights Reserved 2003-2012 Vijandren Ramadass (~unite against racism~) Powered by Invision Power Board (Trial)©2012  IPS, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
