<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000125" url="http://notalwaysright.com/page/15" time="2012-07-12-15:19" support="1" score="0.001494745040476621" bingtitle="Funny &amp; Stupid Customer Stories – Not Always Right" webtitle="FunnyStupid Customer StoriesNot Always Right">
			<query id="000737" bing-rank="114"/>
	<description>Fast Food, Restaurant | Melbourne, Australia | Extra Stupid ... Me: “I am sorry, sir, I am unable to take cash through the phone. I will either need a credit card number ...</description>
	<body>
		Add Your Quote!  |  About/FAQ   Contact  |  Top   Random   Hall of Fame  |  Extras  |  Store Featured Story: 
 Never Say No To La Novia (1,831 thumbs up) FOR SALE: 
 The YAM Network (Auction ends Thursday, July 12, 2012!) 
 Avoid This Customer Like The Plague 
 Pet Store | Edinburgh, Scotland, UK | Bizarre , Pets&amp;Animals 
 (I work in a large pet supply store which also sells pet rodents and rabbits. My job includes offering advice and info to those who want to buy a pet.) 

 Customer: “Excuse me, are these a kind of hamster?”

 Me: “No sir, those are rats.”

 Customer: “Wild rats?! Are you sure they’re not a kind of long-tailed hamster?”

 Me: “They’re definitely rats. They’re not wild; they’re domestic. They’re also known as‘fancy rats’.”

 Customer: “Okay, so do they carry the plague, too?”

 (I’m used to this question. It’s always been asked jokingly, so I chuckle.) 

 Me: “Nope, no plague. Rats are very clean pets and are actually cleaner than your average pet dog or cat.”

 Customer: “I don’t want disease in my house. Are you sure these aren’t carrying plague?”

 (I realise he is totally serious.) 

 Me: “I assure you, these rats are perfectly safe to own.”

 Customer: “I don’t believe you! How do you know?”

 Me: “I actually own several rats and they make really lovely pets. They’re very clever and affectionate.”

 (Suddenly, he becomes very agitated and backs away from me. He covers his mouth by lifting his t-shirt over it, simultaneously revealing an obscene and racist tattoo on his stomach.) 

 Me: “Sir, I need you to lower your shirt please…right now.”

 Customer: *loudly so everyone in the store can hear* “She has plague rats in her house! Stay away from her! Oh my God, what the f*** is wrong with you?! Do you want people to get ill?! I’ll kick your a** in for trying to make me ill!”

 (At this point, two burly male colleagues of mine come running from other aisles to help. They make the customer put his shirt back down and try to escort him out of the shop, but he struggles like mad in his bid to‘warn’everyone. They have trouble restraining him, despite their height and strength.) 

 Customer: “She’s diseased for God’s sake! She has plague rats!”

 (One of my coworkers who has been escorting him out decides he’s had enough and speaks up.) 

 Male Coworker #1: “I keep rats too, mate. Now, get out in case I give you the plague too! Don’t come back, either—the plague might be in the air!”

 (At this, the customer freezes and then bolts screaming from the shop. The other customers applaud my coworkers, I get an extra 10 minute break and three nice people gave homes to pairs of rats after wanting to find out more about them!) 
 ( 1,323 Thumbs Up!) 
 In Plain Site 
 Bank | Montreal, QC, Canada | Technology 
 Caller: “Your website sucks. I can’t even get last month’s statement!”

 Me: “I’d be more than happy to help, sir. You can definitely obtain last month’s statement.”

 Caller: “No, I can’t! I looked everywhere. Your website is the worst bank website I’ve ever seen!”

 Me: “I’ll show you exactly where you need to go, sir. You can obtain last month’s statement by—”

 Caller: “Even [other bank] and [another bank] have better websites than you! This is absolutely ridiculous!”

 Me: “Like I said, sir, we do have last month’s statement on our website. You can even see your statement from years ago.”

 Caller: “No, you can’t! Your website sucks! You should have last month’s statement!”

 Me: “If you can humour me, sir, please log in.”

 Caller: “Fine, I’ve logged in. You see?! I don’t see last month’s statement anywhere!”

 Me: “So you’re currently on the home page, sir?”

 Caller: “Yes!”

 Me: “Okay, now please click on“Last Statement”, which is right in the middle of the page.”

 Caller: *clicks the link and stays totally silent* 

 Me: “Did you need help looking up anything else?”

 Caller: “Your website still sucks!”
 ( 1,085 Thumbs Up!) 
 My Butter Half 
 Movie Theater | Minnesota, USA | Food&amp;Drink , Love/Romance , Top 
 (A couple approaches me at the movie theater’s concession stand.) 

 Me: “Hi, what can I—”

 Customer: “Give me a green tea.”

 Me: “Sorry, we don’t have green tea.”

 Customer: “ARE YOU KIDDING ME?! Well, fine! What DO you have?”

 (I point right behind me where all our sodas are clearly listed.) 

 Customer: “Well, FINE! Give me a Diet Coke, then.”

 Customer Husband: “…And a large popcorn, please!”

 Me: “Sure! That all?”

 Customer Husband: “Yep!”

 Me: “Cool. You guys want butter on the popcorn?”

 Customer Husband: *giant smile* “Ye—”

 Customer: “Of course not! Unlike you, I have a figure to maintain! I can’t have BUTTER on my popcorn! Really, are you an idiot?!”

 (I go to get them their popcorn, but I purposely put way too much butter in the bucket and shovel a thin layer of popcorn on top to hide the butter.) 

 Me: “Here you go!”

 Customer: “Well, finally!”

 Customer Husband: *whispers as his wife turns away* “Butter?”

 Me: “Yes, sir.”

 (The guy hands me a five dollar bill. To this day, my coworkers and I refer to him as‘Butter Man.’) 
 ( 1,778 Thumbs Up!) 
 Dislike Father, Dislike Son 
 Candy Shop | Missouri, USA | Bigotry , Children , Parents , Top 
 (A lady walks in with her 11-year-old son. He is being very mouthy to her, mouthy to her friend that is with them. He even glares at me when I tell him he can not eat of our bulk candy bins. They finally come up to the counter to pay for their candy, but he is still saying horrible things to his mother. She is looking very upset by this point.) 

 Me: “Did you find everything okay?”

 Customer’s Son: “Shut up!”

 Me: “You know, if my son talked to me that way—”

 Customer’s Son: “You’d what, b****?”

 Me: “I’d probably hogtie him and throw him into his room.”

 Customer: *laughs* 

 Customer’s Son: “B****, you wouldn’t be standing!”

 Me: *laughing* “Oh? How you figure that?”

 Customer’s Son: “Because you’re a woman, and women are weak.”

 Customer: *to her son* “Oh my God, are you serious?! You are NOT visiting your father anymore!”

 Customer’s Son: *to me* “Now get me an Icee, b****.”

 Me: “Oh, I don’t know. I’m not sure my weak woman’s hands can make it for you!”

 Customer: *laughing, to me* “Thank you!” *to her son* “Now, let’s go. I’m not buying you anything!”

 Me: “Have a nice day!”

 Customer’s Son: *flips me off* 

 Customer: *smacks him* 
 ( 1,670 Thumbs Up!) 
 Contextual Innuendos 
 Pharmacy | Salt Lake City, UT, USA | Rude&amp;Risque 
 (I’m at work on a Saturday with a clerk and a pharmacist. I notice the clerk speaking with an elderly woman out front but don’t think much of it. A few minutes later, the clerk comes back with a strange expression on her face and tells me I have to go help the woman.) 

 Me: “What can I help you with?”

 Customer: “I’m looking for a vibrator.”

 Me: “A…vibrator?”

 Customer: “Yes. I had one, but I used it too much and it wore out.”

 Me: “I don’t think we have anything like that. Where did you buy the first one?”

 Customer: “At another pharmacy, but I want one with a long handle so it can reach better.”

 (At this point I’m biting the inside of my cheek in an effort not to laugh.) 

 Me: “What kind of vibrator are you looking for, exactly?”

 Customer: “You know! One of those that rub your feet!”

 Me: “OH! Sorry, we don’t have anything like that.”
 ( 939 Thumbs Up!) 
 Must Have Been The Funny Farm 
 Farm Supply Store | Nanaimo, BC, Canada | Crazy Requests , Food&amp;Drink , Pets&amp;Animals 
 (Note: I work in a farm supply store. In addition to selling the usual stuff like equipment, animal feed, and seed, it also sells chickens and chicks.) 

 Customer: “Where are your nugget chickens?”

 Me: “…Pardon?”

 Customer: “Your NUGGET chickens!”

 Me: “I’m afraid I’m not understanding what you are looking for. Are you wanting to purchase chicks, or perhaps full grown chickens?”

 Customer: “No, no, no! You know, the chickens that lay nuggets!”

 Me: *puzzled expression* 

 Customer: “CHICKEN NUGGET CHICKENS, for crying out loud! I promised my son I’d get him one! He loves chicken nuggets!”

 Me: “Ma’am, chicken nuggets are not laid by chickens. Chickens lay eggs. Nuggets are small pieces of chicken that have been breaded and baked or fried.”

 Customer: “I’ll have you know, Missy, I grew up on a farm and I know what I’m talking about! Nevermind, I’ll just try the store in the next town. You’re worthless!”
 ( 1,391 Thumbs Up!) 
 Bottom-Rung Bozos 
 Gift Shop | Florida, USA | Physical , Top 
 (This takes place in a small, mom-and-pop gift store. Note: I am about 7 months pregnant when this takes place.) 

 Customer: “Hey you, girl! I need one of those games at the top of the shelf.”

 Me: “Sure, no problem, sir. Just give me a moment to finish up here and I’ll grab it.”

 Customer: “Well, hurry up!”

 (The customer continues to mutter about me being useless. I go to grab the ladder when my coworker, who happens to be the owner’s son, sees this.) 

 Coworker: *to me* “Oh hey…you don’t need to be on that ladder. I got it.”

 Customer: *to coworker* “What?! No, I asked her. Let her do it!”

 Coworker: “Sir, it’s not safe for her to be up there right now.”

 Customer: “YOU SHOULDN’T BE ACCOMMODATING TO FATTIES!”

 (Note: the customer himself is extremely large.) 

 Coworker: “Sir, she’s pregnant, not fat.”

 Customer: “Stupid b**** is just fat! You shouldn’t accommodate fatties! She’s just a fat b****! Make her do her job! STOP ACCOMMODATING THE FATTIES!”

 Me: “Sir, I’m seven months pregnant, not fat, and if you continue to use vulgar language, I will have to ask you to leave.”

 Customer: “You stupid b****! Do your d*** job, you stupid fat a**!”

 Me: “I’m refusing you service. Please leave.”

 Customer: “YOU CAN’T DO THAT! GET THAT D*** GAME! I PAY YOUR SALARY!”

 (The owner, who has overheard the entire exchange, comes over.) 

 Owner: “Sir, you shouldn’t be carrying on and calling people fatties…especially pregnant women.”

 Customer: “F*** YOU! I WANT TO TALK TO YOUR MANAGER!”

 Owner: “I’ll do you one better: I own this store, and if I see you in my store again, I will have you arrested for trespassing. Oh…and NO, you don’t pay her salary: I do, and I plan to give her a big raise after this.”

 Customer: “SCREW YOU! You can’t talk to me this way. I’m a paying customer!”

 Coworker: “Hey buddy, you just blow in from stupid town? You haven’t bought anything.”

 Customer: “DON’T ACCOMMODATE FATTIES!”

 (In his anger, he knocks down a rack of merchandise over and hauls out of the store as fast as he can.) 

 Coworker: “I’m going to call the police…”

 (The customer was arrested less than a block away, and I got a raise.) 
 ( 2,479 Thumbs Up!) 
 When Intelligences Cancel Out, Part 2 
 Retail | Lawrence, KS, USA | At The Checkout , Extra Stupid 
 (I work as a cashier. At the checkout, the display on the cash back screen shows the amounts. Underneath is a large“No Cash Back”button, and below that in the corner is a small“Cancel”button.) 

 Me: “Your total is $25.88.”

 Customer: “This will be debit.” *swipes card* “Oh, I hit the‘Cancel’button.”

 Me: “That’s okay. You’ll need to swipe it again.”

 Customer: “I don’t get why you can’t make this clearer! I don’t want cash back.”

 Me: “Then you need to hit the button that says‘No Cash Back’, not the‘Cancel’button.”

 Customer: “That’s just dumb! Why don’t you make a button that just says‘Cancel’if you don’t want cash back?!”

 Related:
 When Intelligences Cancel Out 
 ( 560 Thumbs Up!) Page 15/819 First « ... 13 14 15 16 17 ... » Last 
 
19,758
Fans 
5,025
Followers 
10,881
Subscribers 
 
Navigate
 Announcements At The Checkout Awesome Customers Bigotry Bizarre Body Problems Bookstore Canada Children Coffee Shop Comics Comics Single Crazy Requests Criminal/Illegal Extra Stupid Extras Food&amp;Drink Funny Names Geeks Rule Geography Health&amp;Sickness History Holidays Home Improvement Hotels&amp;Lodging Language&amp;Words Liars&amp;Scammers Love/Romance Married Customers Math&amp;Science Money Issues Movie Theater Musical Mayhem Old Comics One-Liners Parents Pets&amp;Animals Physical Politics Religion Roundups RSS-Announce Rude&amp;Risque Students Technology Theme Time Top Tourists/Travel Uncategorized Underaged Xcluded View by Job 911 Airline Airport Animal Shelter Announcements Apartment Complex Aquarium Arcade Art Gallery Artist Auto Mechanic Auto Parts Baby Store Bail Bonds Bakery Bank Bar Beach Beauty Salon Blood Bank Boat Rental Bookstore Bowling Alley Bridal Store Buffet Bus Cable Company Cafe Call Center Camera Shop Camera Store Camp Candy Shop Car Dealership Card Shop Car Rental Car Wash Cash Advance Casino Catering Cellphone Store Charity Check Cashing Chemist Child Care Chocolate Shop Church Clinic Clothing Store Coffee Shop College Comic Book Store comic store Computer Lab Computer Repair Computer Store Concert Hall Concession Stand Construction Contractor Convenience Store Copy Shop Costume Shop Country Club Craft Store Cruise Ship Customer Service Dance Studio Daycare Day Spa Deli Dentist Department Store DMV Doctor Dog Daycare Dog Kennel Dollar Store Donut Shop Drug Store Drugstore Dry Cleaner Electronics Repair electronics store EMT Fabric Store Farm Farmer&apos;s Market Fast Food Fencing Club Ferry Fish Store Flea Market flooring company Florist Flower Shop Frozen Yogurt Shop Furniture Store Garden Store Gas Station Gift Shop Golf Course Government Graphic Design Grocery Grocery Store Gun Store Gym Hair Salon Hardware Store Help Desk Highway Patrol home home furnishings home furnishings store home improvement Home Security Hospital Hotel Ice Cream Shop Ice Cream Store Insurance Internet Cafe Investment Firm ISP Jewelry Store Key Shop Landscaper Laundromat Law Firm Lawn Care Lemonade Stand library lifeguard Lingerie Store Liquor Store Locksmith Mall Marina Marine Biologist Massage Medical Office Military Miscellaneous Morgue Mortgage Company Movie Theater Museum Music Festival Music Store newspaper Non-Profit Nursing Home Office Office Supply Store Online Store Optometrist Outdoor Supply Store Paintball Field Paramedic Park Parking Lot Party Planner Party Store Party Supply Store Pawn Shop Pest control Pet Groomer Pet Hotel Pet Store Pharmacy Phone Company Photo Lab Pizza Pizza Delivery Pizza Place Plant Nursery Plumber Police Polling Station Pool Pool Maintenance Pool Supply Porn Billing Portrait Studio Post Office Power Company Print Shop Private School Property Management Publishing Radio Station Real Estate Recording Studio Record Store repair shop Resort Restaurant Retail Retirement Home Roadside assistance Sales Sandwich Shop School Security Self Storage Shipping Company Shoe Store Sign Installer Ski Resort Smoke Shop Smoothie Shop Snack Bar Software Company Souvenir Store Sporting Goods Store Summer Camp Supermarket Tanning Salon Tattoo Parlor Taxi Tax Preparer Tea Shop Tech Support Telemarketing theater Theatre Theme Park Thrift Store Ticket Sales Tire Center Tour Tour Guide Tourist Attraction Toy Store Train Station Travel Agency Travel Store Tree Nursery Tutor TV Studio University Vet Video Editor Video Game Store Video Rental Video Rental Store Video Store Vitamin Store Water Park Web Design Well Driller Wine Store Zombies Zoo View by Month July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 
Not Always Sites

 Not Always Romantic Not Always Related Not Always Working 
Friends

 The Awesomer Passive Aggressive Notes Retail Hell 

Archives
 
 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 
 
Most Viewed Stories

 Why Barkeeps Should Rule The World 19680 views Scamming In Plain Sight 16122 views Coming To A Theater Near You: Gangsta Ushers 15501 views Choose Your Battles 14458 views Don’t Mess With The Candyland Gang 14054 views Fighting Fire With Fire 9230 views The Road To Yell(ing) Is Paved With Good Intentions 6899 views Human Watching 5000 views For My Next Trick… 4111 views Who Needs Enemies When You’ve Got Bricks 2982 views 
 

 
Not Always Right Poll
Sorry, there are no polls available at the moment. 

 
 
 
About Not Always Right

Not Always Right features funny&amp;stupid customer stories that show the customer is NOT always right! More... 

 About/FAQ 
 Press 
 Contact 
 Term of Use 
 Privacy Policy 
 Send Us An Extras/FB/Twitter Tip 
 Link To Us 
 Apps 

Copyright 2007-2012 NotAlwaysRight.com 
Subscribe&amp;Follow

 Facebook 
 Twitter 
 RSS 
 Email Subscription 


Network Sites

 Not Always Romantic 
 Not Always Related 
 Not Always Working 

 IYAMLOL 
 IYAMCHEAP 
 IYAMYOURS 
 IYAMBAD 
 IYAMHEALTHY 
June 2012 Top Referrers


 Passive Aggressive Notes Etiquette Hell Retail Hell Underground Consumerist STFU Parents Customers Suck! You Are Not A Photographer Funny Junk The Mary Sue Tech Comedy 

 Join Our Top Referrer Program!
	</body>
</document>
