<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000640" url="http://www.freebase.com/view/en/bryant-lake_bowl" time="2012-07-12-15:56" support="1" score="0.0002458650247791541" bingtitle="Bryant-Lake Bowl facts - Freebase" webtitle="Bryant-Lake Bowl facts - Freebase">
			<query id="001269" bing-rank="210"/>
	<description>... is a bowling alley, restaurant, bar, and 85-seat ... The chain was solely a Mexican fast-food restaurant until 1998 ... The chain is known for its breakfast selection and ...</description>
	<body>
		Start typing to get some suggestions 
 Data Schema Apps Docs 
 Sign In or Sign Up 





 
Bryant-Lake Bowl
 Bryant-Lake Bowl, locally nicknamed BLB, is a bowling alley, restaurant, bar, and 85-seat theatre in the Uptown neighborhood of Minneapolis, Minnesota. The theatre is a venue for cabaret and wide variety of other stage productions. It is a host of the annual Minnesota Fringe Festival.
Bryant-Lake Bowl hosted the signing ceremony for the law making Minneapolis restaurants and bars free of tobacco smoke. 
Bryant-Lake Bowl, locally nicknamed BLB, is a bowling alley, restaurant, bar, and 85-seat theatre in the Uptown neighborhood of Minneapolis, Minnesota. The theatre is a venue for cabaret and wide variety of other stage productions. It is a host of the annual Minnesota Fringe Festival.
Bryant-Lake Bowl hosted the signing ceremony for the law making Minneapolis restaurants and bars free of tobacco smoke.
 Less Read article at Wikipedia 
 Building Occupant 
 
Buildings occupied:

 Bryant Lake Bowl 
 top↑ 
We can also tell you Bryant-Lake Bowl is a

  Restaurant  Employer 

If you know more about Bryant-Lake Bowl , you can add more facts here» 
 
These people have edited this topic:

 
darin

 Member Since: Nov 30, 2006 Contributions: 6,967 Facts 
 
 Edit this topic Last edited Jul 5, 2012 See all topic history» 
Bryant-Lake Bowl elsewhere on the web

 Wikipedia Wikipedia 
 Edit and Show details 
Add or delete facts, download data in JSON or RDF formats, and explore topic metadata.
 
What is Freebase?

Freebase is a huge collection of facts, built by people like you. 
 Freebase connects facts in ways other sites can&apos;t, 
 giving you new ways to explore millions of subjects.
 You can help improve it! 
 
Flag this Topic

Why do you want to flag this topic?

 Label as possibly offensive Delete from Freebase Merge with another topic Split into multiple topics 
 
Freebase data is free for use under the CC-BY license .
 Learn more about Freebase licensing and attribution» 
 
The original description for Bryant-Lake Bowl was automatically generated from Wikipedia.org licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License .
 1 
 ©2012  
 Page History RDF Feedback Attribution Policy Terms of Service About Us Jobs Freebase Blog 
 Freebase contains information on: 
 Arts&amp;Entertainment Commons Products&amp;Services Science&amp;Technology Society Special Interests Sports System Time&amp;Space Transportation 
 Dev Tools Refresh cache | Query Editor | Normal view | Explore | Explore2 | Admin view | View transaction log | Suggest transaction log | Client transaction log | hide (F8) | debug-level none error all TID(s): Controller: 1.767 s Template: 0.050 s Cost: br=2.0, cc=1.15, ch=3.0, cm=15.0, cm+h=18.0, cr=18.0, cs=18.0, cw=15.0, dr=11479.0, dt=2.796, dw=0.0, gqr=0.0, in=6965.0, ir=489.0, iw=0.0, lh=2.0, lm=0.0, lr=2.0, mcs=0.001, mcu=0.326, mr=17.0, nivcsw=186.0, nreqs=37.0, nvcsw=102.0, oublock=600.0, pf=0.0, pr=0.0, stime=0.015, te=0.07, tf=0.416, tg=0.402, tm=0.841, tr=0.042, ts=0.0, tu=0.038, utime=1.127, va=14033.0
	</body>
</document>
