<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000588" url="http://bellmore.patch.com/topics/Arby%2527s" time="2012-07-12-15:52" support="1" score="0.0003319312058333714" bingtitle="Arby&apos;s - Bellmore, NY Patch" webtitle="Arby&apos;s - Bellmore, NY Patch">
			<query id="000798" bing-rank="160"/>
	<description>... as to allow vehicles to readily enter and exit the ... several revisions, including: Hearings for the fast food restaurant ... variances for: The next hearing will take place at ...</description>
	<body>
		patching...   
Editor Danielle De Souza danielle.desouza@patch.com 
 
 
 83° Current weather TODAY | 83°F Mostly sunny. Highs in the mid 80s. Northeast winds around 5 mph...becoming south this afternoon. 
 Hourly Detailed Radar 
 FRI 86° 70° SAT 86° 72° SUN 87° 74° MON 89° 73° TUE 89° 74° WED 89° --°   
 Admin 

 

 Patch Newsletter Nearby 
 Merrick Patch Wantagh-Seaford Patch East Meadow Patch Levittown Patch Massapequa Patch Malverne-West Hempstead-Lynbrook Patch Rockville Centre Patch Farmingdale Patch 
 See more 

 Join Sign In 

 
 Profile Account Newsletters Log Out 
 
 
 Home News Browse News 
 Arts Business Elections Government Obituaries Opinion Police&amp;Fire School News Sports Bellmore School Vote 2012 

 House&amp;Home Long Island Summer Guide North Bellmore School Closure Readers&apos; Choice 2012 Summer Guide Announcements Local Voices 
 Events Browse Events 
 Art&amp;Entertainment Awareness Charitable Classes&amp;Lectures Fairs&amp;Festivals Family Food&amp;Drink Garage Sales Government Graduation 

 Music Organizations Outdoor Patch&apos;s House&amp;Home Religious School Events Sports&amp;Recreation Theater Valentine&apos;s Day Guide Wedding 
 Directory Browse Directory 
 Readers&apos; Choice 2012 Arts&amp;Entertainment Automotive&amp;Boating Community Resources Food&amp;Dining Government Health Nightlife 

 Real Estate Schools Services Shopping Sports&amp;Fitness Travel&amp;Transportation Hometown Partners Restaurant Reviews 
 Commute Pics&amp;Clips More Stuff 
 Jobs Volunteer 
 
 Update: Want to get Bellmore Patch in your inbox daily? Click here and sign up for our newsletters.» Welcome back, Patch Blogger! Make Patch better! Take our survey:   OK | Sorry, maybe next time 
 (survey will open in a new window) 
Arby&apos;s
 
Browse By

 
Related Topics

 Fast Food Hearing White Castle Bellmore Preservation Group Bellmore Town Of Hempstead Zoning Board Building Department Denied Patch Question Proposal 
 
Trending Topics

 Community Swimming Bellmore Schools Girls Basketball Basketball Mill Pond Park Gifts Gregg Allman Awards 
 
 
Tuesday, October 25, 2011
 
 Patch Question: Arby&apos;s in Bellmore 

Sound off on the daily hot topic.
 
 THE NEIGHBORHOOD FILES Danielle De Souza Tuesday, October 25, 2011 
 
Arby&apos;s opened in Bellmore a few weeks ago after much debate and concern. Residents who live near the franchise were concerned with traffic, late drive-thru hours, noise, early morning food deliveries and more. But, after many meetings and discussions, the owner and the community were able to come to agreements on how the eatery would be run. How do you feel about Arby&apos;s opening in Bellmore? Do you live near the restaurant? If so, do you feel it is a disturbance to you and your family? Do you think it would be good for the community? Or are you not concerned about it at all? Tell us in the comment section below.

   1 Comment Photos (1) 
 
 Charles Cottitta 

 3:18 pm on Tuesday, October 25, 2011 

Arby&apos;s the fast food establishment as a good corporate citizen is still to be seen. Financially speaking, Bellmore and locale is the beneficary of another tax revenue stream.   more › 
 
 Arby&apos;s Opens to Mixed Reviews in Bellmore 

Fast food chain is first of its kind for Bellmore.
 
 THE NEIGHBORHOOD FILES Danielle De Souza Tuesday, October 25, 2011 
 
After a series of community meetings and concessions, Arby&apos;s opened on Sunrise Highway about two weeks ago. The main civic group involved said they came to agreements that they felt were beneficial to both the community and the eatery. Matthew Walden of the Bellmore Preservation Group said that Arby&apos;s owner, Thomas J. Clarke, his lawyer, William Bonesso, his architect and members of the community all worked together.&quot;The Arby&apos;s really worked with the community,&quot;Walden said. Bonesso said that after many discussions, Arby&apos;s made some changes to the original plans for the franchise:&quot;I think that it was a satisfactory agreement that the community and the owner came up with,&quot;Bonesso said. However residents who reside behind the fast food …
 
In this Article:
 
 Bellmore Preservation Group Reviews Arby&apos;s Application , Zoning Board Sets Conditions for Arby&apos;s Application Approval , and 7-Eleven 
 
 Photos (3) 
 
Thursday, August 19, 2010
 
 Zoning Board Sets Conditions for Arby&apos;s Application Approval 

Fast food franchise granted several variances that are subject to several conditions set by the Hempstead Town BZA.
 
 GOVERNMENT Jaime Sumersille Thursday, August 19, 2010 
 
The Hempstead Town Zoning Board granted the Arby&apos;s application subject to the following conditions: 1. The door situated on the rear (south side) of the Arby&apos;s building shall not be used for deliveries of any kind. 2. No deliveries to the subject premises shall occur before 7 a.m. 3. The hours of operation for the restaurant and drive-thru shall be as follows: Restaurant: 6 a.m. to 10 p.m. Drive-thru: Sunday though Wednesday – 6 a.m. to 11 p.m. Thursday through Saturday – 6 a.m. to midnight; 4. The premises shall be landscaped and professionally irrigated in accordance with the landscaping depicted on the site plan prepared by Rosenbaum Design Group, originally dated Sept. 25, 2009, last revised Jan. 20, 2010. Said landscaping and …
 
In this Article:
 
 Town Zoning Board Approves Bellmore Arby&apos;s Application 
 
   1 Comment Photos (2) Videos (1) 
 40.66947 -73.52416 
 Zoning Board Sets Conditions for Arby&apos;s Application Approval 
 Bellmore Ave&amp;Sunrise Hwy, Bellmore, NY /articles/zoning-board-sets-conditions-for-arbys-application-approval /locations/1700696 
 Thomas 

 4:16 pm on Saturday, October 8, 2011 

&quot;10. The subject drive-thru facility shall be so maintained as to allow vehicles to readily enter and exit the subject site, with no straddling of the abutting sidewalk by vehicles or backing up of vehicles onto the abutting public street, whereby traffic flow thereon would be interfered with.&quot;Drive-Thru backs out onto Sunrise Highway multiple cars deep. Only a matter of time before a major …   more › 
 
 Town Zoning Board Approves Bellmore Arby&apos;s Application 

Working with nearby residents to address concerns pays off for franchise owner.
 
 GOVERNMENT Jaime Sumersille Thursday, August 19, 2010 
 
The Hempstead Town Zoning Board recently approved an application for an Arby&apos;s restaurant on Sunrise Highway in Bellmore. The approved site plan included several revisions, including: Hearings for the fast food restaurant were adjourned several times to allow Arby&apos;s franchise owner Thomas Clarke and his attorney William Bonesso to meet with nearby residents and the Bellmore Preservation Group. After several community meetings, Clarke agreed to make changes regarding landscaping, parking, an order board and hours of operation.&quot;The Bellmore Preservation Group is very happy that our meetings with Tom Clarke and Mr. Bonesso covered the concern of the residents,&quot;Eileen Casazza, Bellmore Preservation Group member said. The restaurant portion …

 Photos (2) 
 40.66947 -73.52416 
 Town Zoning Board Approves Bellmore Arby&apos;s Application 
 Bellmore Ave&amp;Sunrise Hwy, Bellmore, NY /articles/town-zoning-board-approves-bellmore-arbys-application /locations/1697066 
Thursday, July 29, 2010
 
 VIDEO: Zoning Board Holds Hearing on Proposed Arby&apos;s 


 
 GOVERNMENT Jaime Sumersille Thursday, July 29, 2010 
 


 Videos (1) 
 40.705802 -73.619928 
 VIDEO: Zoning Board Holds Hearing on Proposed Arby&apos;s 
 Town of Hempstead Building&amp;Zoning Department 1 Washington St, Hempstead, NY /articles/video-zoning-board-holds-hearing-on-proposed-arbys 148500 /locations/1578121 
Wednesday, July 28, 2010
 
 Hempstead Zoning Board Hears Case for Proposed Arby&apos;s 

Franchise owner agrees to almost all conditions requested by neighbors.
 
 GOVERNMENT Jaime Sumersille Wednesday, July 28, 2010 
 
Attorneys for an Arby&apos;s franchise owner finally made their case before the Hempstead Town Zoning Board Wednesday afternoon after three adjournments. The adjournments were requested so that franchisee Thomas Clarke and his team could meet with members of the Bellmore Preservation Group and other nearby residents.&quot;The applicant has made a lot of accommodations,&quot;attorney William F. Bonesso, Esq. said to the board in regard to the proposed fast food restaurant at the old Speedy&apos;s Muffler location. The latest site plan submitted by Clarke&apos;s team includes several building plan revisions: Bonesso also had to request a variance for less parking spaces than required by code. His argument was that the board should look at the drive-thru on the …
 
In this Article:
 
 Abco Art and Nassau County Legislator David Denenberg 
 
 Photos (14) 
 40.705802 -73.619928 
 Hempstead Zoning Board Hears Case for Proposed Arby&apos;s 
 Town of Hempstead Building&amp;Zoning Department 1 Washington St, Hempstead, NY /articles/hempstead-town-zoning-board-hears-case-for-proposed-arbys 148500 /locations/1571796 40.66941 -73.52412 
 Hempstead Zoning Board Hears Case for Proposed Arby&apos;s 
 Sunrise Hwy&amp;Bellmore Ave, Bellmore, NY Old Speedy Muffler Location - approx 150 feet east of Bellmore Avenue /articles/hempstead-town-zoning-board-hears-case-for-proposed-arbys /locations/1571797 
Tuesday, July 27, 2010
 
 Town BZA Hearing for Proposed Arby&apos;s Set for Wednesday 

After building plan changes and community outreach, franchise owner will bring his variance requests before the board.
 
 GOVERNMENT Jaime Sumersille Tuesday, July 27, 2010 
 
After three adjournments, meetings with surrounding neighbors and site plan revisions, an Arby&apos;s franchise owner will finally go before the Hempstead Town Board of Zoning and Appeals Wednesday at noon. William F. Bonesso, Esq. is representing the applicant, Thomas J. Clarke. He is proposing a fast food restaurant, with drive-thru, on Sunrise Highway (at the old Speedy Muffler location.) Clarke, is seeking variances for: Members of the Bellmore Preservation Group, of which Clarke and his staff worked closely with regarding this proposal, are also expected to attend the hearing. They requested earlier closing evening hours and later morning delivery hours - all of which Clarke agreed to. A variance request for special exception to use part …
 
In this Article:
 
 Bellmore Preservation Group Reviews Arby&apos;s Application 
 
 Photos (2) 
 40.66941 -73.52412 
 Town BZA Hearing for Proposed Arby&apos;s Set for Wednesday 
 Sunrise Hwy&amp;Bellmore Ave, Bellmore, NY Old Speedy Muffler Location - approx 150 feet east of Bellmore Avenue /articles/town-bza-hearing-for-proposed-arbys-set-for-wednesday /locations/1570476 40.705802 -73.619928 
 Town BZA Hearing for Proposed Arby&apos;s Set for Wednesday 
 Town of Hempstead Building&amp;Zoning Department 1 Washington St, Hempstead, NY /articles/town-bza-hearing-for-proposed-arbys-set-for-wednesday 148500 /locations/1570477 
Wednesday, June 30, 2010
 
 Bellmore Preservation Group Reviews Arby&apos;s Application 

Residents discuss site plan changes for fast food restaurant proposal with franchise owner.
 
 BUSINESS Jaime Sumersille Wednesday, June 30, 2010 
 
An Arby&apos;s franchise owner, his architect and lawyer met with the Bellmore Preservation Group last night to discuss the fast food restaurant&apos;s proposed building plans. The proposed 3,900 sq. ft. building would be located just east of Sunrise Highway and Bellmore Avenue. It would be two stories high, with 17&apos; being the tallest height, have seating for 66 people and 27 parking spots. The applicant, Thomas J. Clarke, his attorney William F. Bonesso, Esq. and architect Dennis Flynn of Rosebaum Design Group addressed every single concern raised by residents in previous meetings. Legislator Dave Denenberg, upon the request of several residents in attendance, pushed for earlier drive-thru hours. Originally, the drive-thru was slated to be …
 
In this Article:
 
 Another Hearing Date Change for Proposed Arby&apos;s , Nassau County Legislator David Denenberg , King Kullen , and 2 more › 
 
   1 Comment Photos (9) Videos (1) 
 40.66941 -73.52412 
 Bellmore Preservation Group Reviews Arby&apos;s Application 
 Sunrise Hwy&amp;Bellmore Ave, Bellmore, NY Old Speedy Muffler Location - approx 150 feet east of Bellmore Avenue /articles/bellmore-preservation-group-goes-over-arbys-application /locations/1571616 
 Patrick Ingegno 

 5:28 pm on Tuesday, July 19, 2011 

Ummm Ummmm, I can&apos;t wait to have a delicious roast beef sandwich.. Let&apos;s grow up! This is going to be on a major highway, Sunrise Hgwy, when you bought a home within&quot;spittin&quot;distance of this road you have to KNOW that there was going to be business going on there...without the businesses our legislature will want to raise our property taxes, again! why don&apos;t we just close ALL of the businesses …   more › 
 
Tuesday, June 29, 2010
 
 Another Hearing Date Change for Proposed Arby&apos;s 

Hempstead Town BZA to review variance requests on July 14.
 
 GOVERNMENT Jaime Sumersille Tuesday, June 29, 2010 
 
After two postponements already, the hearing involving eight zoning variance requests from a proposed Arby&apos;s franchise will likely be adjourned again tomorrow by the Hempstead Town Building&amp;Zoning board.&quot;A decision on the request will be made tomorrow,&quot;Hempstead Town Press Secretary Susan Trenkle-Pokalsky said. It was earlier this year that an Arby&apos;s franchisee submitted an application to the Hempstead Town BZA to construct a fast food restaurant on Sunrise Highway at the old Speedy Muffler location. The applicant, Thomas J. Clarke, owns several Arby&apos;s and Burger King restaurants and is being represented by William F. Bonesso, Esq. Clarke, is seeking variances for: The next hearing will take place at 3 p.m. on Wednesday, July 14. The …
 
In this Article:
 
 Town of Hempstead Building&amp;Zoning Department 
 
 Photos (2) 
 40.705802 -73.619928 
 Another Hearing Date Change for Proposed Arby&apos;s 
 Hempstead Town Hall 1 Washington St, Hempstead, NY /articles/another-hearing-date-change-for-proposed-arbys 148509 /locations/1461851 40.66941 -73.52412 
 Another Hearing Date Change for Proposed Arby&apos;s 
 Sunrise Hwy&amp;Bellmore Ave, Bellmore, NY Old Speedy Muffler Location - approx 150 feet east of Bellmore Avenue /articles/another-hearing-date-change-for-proposed-arbys /locations/1461852 
Thursday, June 3, 2010
 
 UPDATED: Bellmore White Castle Rejected 

Zoning board ruling a victory for families who fought the fast food restaurant.
 
 GOVERNMENT Jaime Sumersille Thursday, June 3, 2010 
 
Nearly 2.5 months after a Town of Hempstead Zoning hearing, hundreds of Bellmore residents finally got the answer they had been waiting and fighting for. There will be no White Castle. The board unanimously denied the application, said Susan Trenkle-Pokalsky, Hempstead&apos;s press secretary.&quot;As a community, we are ecstatic,&quot;said Matt Walden, a member of the Bellmore Preservation Group.&quot;The community came together. Everybody worked together and had their voices heard.&quot;The group is made up of about 100 families who scraped together nearly $12,000 for legal fees and other costs to fight - and ultimately defeat - the White Castle. The Bellmore Preservation Group argued that the fast food shop would lead to increase in traffic, noise, litter …
 
In this Article:
 
 Town of Hempstead Building&amp;Zoning Department 
 
 Photos (3) Videos (7) Documents (1) 
 40.66804 -73.52961 
 UPDATED: Bellmore White Castle Rejected 
 Saint Marks Ave&amp;Sunrise Hwy, Bellmore, NY /articles/toh-zoning-board-unanimously-denies-bellmore-white-castle-proposal /locations/757353 ‹ Prev 1 2 … Next › Got a Hot Tip?   
Videos
 
 
Arts

 Long Island International Film Expo Comes Back to Bellmore 
 about 13 hours ago http://o4.aolcdn.com/dims-shared/dims3/PATCH/thumbnail/132x88/crop/88x88+22+0/http://hss-prod.hss.aol.com/hss/storage/patch/a1af10fa227e7f207dffd076a831f8c2 
The Neighborhood Files

 VIDEO: Got Cupcakes? Hosts Second Annual Cupcake Eating Contest 
 3 days ago http://o3.aolcdn.com/dims-shared/dims3/PATCH/thumbnail/132x88/crop/88x88+22+0/http://hss-prod.hss.aol.com/hss/storage/patch/76c78631bc05e76508e4265d061f6085 
Graduation

 VIDEO: Kennedy High School Graduation 2012 
 16 days ago http://o4.aolcdn.com/dims-shared/dims3/PATCH/thumbnail/132x88/crop/88x88+22+0/http://hss-prod.hss.aol.com/hss/storage/patch/a58b094b48afe015a4c5eaedb2559498 
Graduation

 VIDEO: Mepham High School Graduation 2012 
 17 days ago http://o1.aolcdn.com/dims-shared/dims3/PATCH/thumbnail/156x88/crop/88x88+34+0/http://hss-prod.hss.aol.com/hss/storage/patch/d375f8bee666c8540f10d56307248538 
Health Services

 Livingston Foot Care Specialists 
 http://o2.aolcdn.com/dims-shared/dims3/PATCH/thumbnail/157x88/crop/88x88+34+0/http://hss-prod.hss.aol.com/hss/storage/patch/69ebd51cb8f243c7478818b2a3e58035 
Home Services&amp;Repairs

 Napoli Marble&amp;Granite 
 http://o3.aolcdn.com/dims-shared/dims3/PATCH/thumbnail/132x88/crop/88x88+22+0/http://hss-prod.hss.aol.com/hss/storage/patch/3c324138abc0ffa2f18548e633675bc3 
Government

 Merrick Preserve Gets Boost From Town 
 18 days ago http://o2.aolcdn.com/dims-shared/dims3/PATCH/thumbnail/132x88/crop/88x88+22+0/http://hss-prod.hss.aol.com/hss/storage/patch/abece60931de1d1927940e703971168b 
Schools

 VIDEO: Students and Faculty Say Goodbye to Gunther 
 19 days ago http://o3.aolcdn.com/dims-shared/dims3/PATCH/thumbnail/119x88/crop/88x88+15+0/http://hss-prod.hss.aol.com/hss/storage/patch/548042e2f0b257ea80ad7a0ad16ad045 
Optometrists

 Landrio&amp;Dorman O.D. 
 http://o1.aolcdn.com/dims-shared/dims3/PATCH/thumbnail/119x88/crop/88x88+16+0/http://hss-prod.hss.aol.com/hss/storage/patch/50f361e954e4fd4e948bbd2b3fcce9cd 
Summer

 Summer Reading Lists for Kids Ages 6-9 
 27 days ago http://o4.aolcdn.com/dims-shared/dims3/PATCH/thumbnail/154x88/crop/88x88+33+0/http://hss-prod.hss.aol.com/hss/storage/patch/959cda979f1fd8aa4db254549d814163 
Summer

 Summer Reading Lists for Preschoolers and Kids Ages 2-7 
 30 days ago 
     
Most Popular Articles

 Crime Nearby: Teen Arrested for Marijuana Possession, Schools Damaged &apos;Free Slurpee Day&apos; Gets Even Bigger PHOTO: Deer Sighting VIDEO: Got Cupcakes? Hosts Second Annual Cupcake Eating Contest Weekly Recap: Independence Day Run, Deer Sighting in Bellmore 
 
PSST! Want to Contribute?

 Got a hot tip on news you think everyone should know? Tell us. Just married? New baby? Make honor roll? Add an Announcement Organizing that big block party or poetry reading? Put it on the calendar! Have a great photo of your community? Add it to Your Neighborhood Gallery. http://bellmore.patch.com/articles/your-neighborhood-gallery-7a75164c/media_attachments/edit?upload_started=1342101159 asset[new_asset_attachment_attributes][to_id] 1579612 asset[new_asset_attachment_attributes][to_type] Article article[new_asset_attachment_attributes][user_id] new_asset_attachment_attributes 
 Advertisements | Add your own   
Advertise

Advertise on Patch and reach potential customers in your backyard and beyond. Click here for more information.
 Learn more » 
 
Volunteer

If you want to help local causes, or your cause needs local help, your next click should be right here.
 Learn more » 
 
Contribute

 Send us news tips Put an event on the calendar Announce something to everyone 
 
Patch Info

 About Us Jobs Advertise About Our Ads Terms of Use Privacy Policy - UPDATED 
 
Get in Touch

 Go Patch! Help Contact Us Patch Blog 
 
Patch Initiatives

 PatchU 
 
Goodies

 Patch Newsletter Widgets 
 Copyright © 2012 Patch. All Rights Reserved. 
   Uploading...
 Close Oops! There was an error with your upload, and it did not complete. Click Cancel and try again. Tip: try uploading a smaller file. Done Cancel 
   Search Patch Archive
 Close http://bellmore.patch.com/media_attachments/create asset_attachment[to_id] 1579612 asset_attachment[to_type] Article Finished Cancel search Close 
 Send us a news tip

Enter your tip here and it will be sent straight to
Editor Danielle De Souza and Cindy Springsteen,
Bellmore Patch&apos;s (incredibly grateful)
editors.
 Your name: [[&quot;validates_presence_of&quot;,{&quot;message&quot;:&quot;Please enter your name&quot;}]] Your email address: [[&quot;validates_presence_of&quot;,{&quot;message&quot;:&quot;Please enter your email address.&quot;}],[&quot;validates_format_of&quot;,{&quot;with&quot;:[&quot;^([^@\\s]+)@((?:[-a-z0-9]+\\.)+[a-z]{2,})$&quot;,&quot;i&quot;],&quot;message&quot;:&quot;Email address is not formatted properly.&quot;}]] Your suggestion: [[&quot;validates_presence_of&quot;,{&quot;message&quot;:&quot;Please include a suggestion.&quot;}]] Send me a copy Cancel Close 
Get Patched In

Bellmore news, events, and deals sent to you daily and breaking news as it happens. See more options 
 
You’re now signed up!
 
 Terms of Service Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
