<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000721" url="http://www.fark.com/comments/6923831/When-asked-why-he-was-drinking-beer-from-a-wine-glass-this-guy-didnt-know-but-he-took-a-stab-at-it" time="2012-07-12-16:04" support="2" score="0.001522892530515769" bingtitle="FARK.com: (6923831) When asked why he was drinking beer from a ..." webtitle="FARK.com:  (6923831) When asked why he was drinking beer from a wine glass, this guy didnt know, but he took a stab at it">
			<query id="000246" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="000243" bing-rank="117"/>
	<description>Last week he entered a fast food restaurant. Just ahead of him, two men got ... So you&apos;d be in the &quot;start a knife fight with a guy for drinking beer out of a wine glass ...</description>
	<body>
		It&apos;s Not News It&apos;s Fark.com Real news. Real funny Log In  |  Sign Up» Login Password Forgot password? X 
 Fark TotalFark my Fark About/FArQ Contests Store Contact Us Mobile 
 Search: Password Login Turn on javascript (or enable it for Fark) for a better user experience. If you can read this, either the style sheet didn&apos;t load or you have an older browser that doesn&apos;t support 
style sheets. Try clearing your browser cache and refreshing the page. 
 Main Sports Business Geek Entertainment Politics Video 
 

 When asked why he was drinking beer from a wine glass, this guy didn&apos;t know, but he took a stab at it    ( chicagotribune.com ) 48
 More: Scary , Naperville , stabbing   
 •       •       • 

 6502 clicks; posted to Main» on 05 Feb 2012 at 5:40 PM    |  Favorite    |   share:     more»    |     shirt it! 
 

 
 
 Share this link: 

 URL: http://fk.cm/go/6923831 Bookmark: URL: http://fk.cm/6923831 Bookmark: Article Comments close 
 48 Comments    ( +0» ) 
 Paginated (50/page) Single page Single page, reversed Normal view Change images to links Show raw HTML   Show posts from ignored users   
 View Voting Results: Smartest and Funniest   
 
 olddeegee 2012-02-05 02:27:34 PM 
 Sounds like he had a bad day. Very sad. 
   
 
 R.A.Danny 2012-02-05 03:11:03 PM 
 And they say nothing ever happens in Naperville.
I highly recommend White Tavern over the douchebag hipster bars downtown. 
   
 
 Apos 2012-02-05 04:36:38 PM 
 &quot;A man&apos;s gotta have his limitations.&quot; 

-Inspector Harry Callahan, Magnum Force 
   
 
 Daobaz 2012-02-05 05:44:13 PM 
 I think they got the point.

....


^_^ 
   
 
 sirgrim 2012-02-05 05:47:28 PM 
 Ban glasses. 
   
 
 Teen Wolf Blitzer 2012-02-05 05:52:06 PM 
 Hmm the article was very detailed, but it didn&apos;t include the.most important piece of information: why was he drinking beer out of a wine glass? 
   
 
 Cubansaltyballs 2012-02-05 05:54:34 PM 
 Teen Wolf Blitzer : Hmm the article was very detailed, but it didn&apos;t include the.most important piece of information: why was he drinking beer out of a wine glass? 

Because he&apos;s a psycho mama&apos;s boy that still lives at home with his mammy. 
   
 
 Apos 2012-02-05 05:55:28 PM 
 Teen Wolf Blitzer : Hmm the article was very detailed, but it didn&apos;t include the.most important piece of information: why was he drinking beer out of a wine glass? 


A stab at pretentiousness? 
   
 
 starlost 2012-02-05 05:55:35 PM 
 waiter/bartender who served the beer in a wine glass is an accomplice. more likely the murderer was drunk and grabbed half finished beer bottles and wine glasses from the strangers at his table and made himself a backwash cocktail.then the victim said wtf dude. 
   
 
 RoyBatty 2012-02-05 05:55:51 PM 
 Chris did get out. He enrolled in the college courses with me, and, although it was hard, he gutted it out like he always did. He went on to college and eventually became a lawyer. Last week he entered a fast food restaurant. Just ahead of him, two men got into an argument-one of them pulled a knife. Chris, who had always made the best peace, tried to break it up. He was stabbed in the throat. He died almost instantly. 
   
 
 mark12A 2012-02-05 05:58:08 PM 
 Such uncouth behavior *must * be dealt with. 
   
 
 brandnewchair 2012-02-05 06:01:02 PM 
 perhaps he ordered a goose island Matilda... they always serve that in a wine-type glass.

and i would have been damn proud of my beer and glass choice. 
   
 
 Shahab 2012-02-05 06:08:29 PM 
 Well maybe next time they won&apos;t go making fun of people for the way they drink their booze. Also, I don&apos;t want to blame the victim here, but don&apos;t try and restrain an armed man after he just demonstrated his willingness to use his weapon, from the article it sounds like the first guy got sliced on the arm then the person who died tried to restrain the Olaska guy and the Olaska guy stabbed in the chest. At that point grab your friend, let the other guy go, and call the cops. 
   
 
 Hots_Kebabs 2012-02-05 06:13:55 PM 
 once, when I was tending bar, a woman ordered a Coors Light from me, I asked her if she wanted a frosty mug, she said no but she would like a red wine glass instead. I said phhhttt I don&apos;t have any red wine glasses just some of these clear ones...what a loser 
   
 
 ScottMpls 2012-02-05 06:14:44 PM 
 Was it a dessert wine glass or a red wine glass? 
   
 
 zzrhardy 2012-02-05 06:15:24 PM 
 &quot;Why are you drinking beer out of a wine glass?&quot;

&quot;Thermodynamics&quot;.

See, it&apos;s not hard, you don&apos;t have to get all douchy or McStabby about it. 
   
 
 Christian Bale 2012-02-05 06:16:55 PM 
 Church members will try to help raise the $300,000 cash bond, the attorneys said. 

The Religion of Personal Responsibility strikes again. 
   
 
 Christian Bale 2012-02-05 06:18:05 PM 
 &quot;This is a good kid,&quot; Gulbrandsen said. 

and again. 
   
 
 hammettman 2012-02-05 06:18:20 PM 
 I always love these comments:

 &quot;This is a good kid,&quot; Gulbrandsen said 

Except for the stabbing 3 people part. 
   
 
 numbone 2012-02-05 06:21:35 PM 
 What does Miss Manners say about drinking beer from a wine glass?

Not sure but Olaska. 
   
 
 HappyStargazer 2012-02-05 06:23:20 PM 
 I always thought Mountain Dew in crystal wine glasses was the shiat. 
   
 
 Teen Wolf Blitzer 2012-02-05 06:23:49 PM 
 hammettman : I always love these comments:

&quot;This is a good kid,&quot; Gulbrandsen said

Except for the stabbing 3 people part. 

Yeah, I&apos;d say stabbing someone in the heart over a beverage dispute precludes one from being a &quot;good person&quot; but I&apos;m not a defense attorney so what do I know... 
   
 
 HappyStargazer 2012-02-05 06:25:09 PM 
 RoyBatty : Chris did get out. He enrolled in the college courses with me, and, although it was hard, he gutted it out like he always did. He went on to college and eventually became a lawyer. Last week he entered a fast food restaurant. Just ahead of him, two men got into an argument-one of them pulled a knife. Chris, who had always made the best peace, tried to break it up. He was stabbed in the throat. He died almost instantly. 

I never had any friends later on like the ones I had when I was twelve. Jesus, does anyone? 
   
 
 Danger Avoid Death 2012-02-05 06:26:45 PM 
 I&apos;ll bet he was a regular in just about every Fark beer-snob thread. Some of those can get pretty McStabby. 
   
 
 brandnewchair 2012-02-05 06:26:46 PM 
 Teen Wolf Blitzer : hammettman: I always love these comments:

&quot;This is a good kid,&quot; Gulbrandsen said

Except for the stabbing 3 people part.

Yeah, I&apos;d say stabbing someone in the heart over a beverage dispute precludes one from being a &quot;good person&quot; but I&apos;m not a defense attorney so what do I know... 

typical farker attitude...
sometimes good people stab 3 people over a beer dispute.
quit being so judgemental. 
   
 
 4seasons85! 2012-02-05 06:39:53 PM 
 Speaking of wine... I have a bottle I need to open... it&apos;s staring at me and calling my name! 
   
 
 yosluggo 2012-02-05 06:42:20 PM 
 People need to learn to shut the fark up because you never know who you are farking with. 
   
 
 Fast Thick Pants 2012-02-05 06:50:09 PM 
 Ever had one of those days when you&apos;re relaxing at a bar, sitting at a table, minding your own business, enjoying a beer... maybe you&apos;ve been there for about 15 minutes. Place starts filling up, and a group of entitled puddingheads start eying your table. They figure they&apos;ll just sit down and start annoying the hell out of you, and you&apos;ll leave. A bunch of football jocks accustomed to bullying their way into whatever they want. You hold your ground and they start making fun of you. Making fun of your drink. Idiotic, but you can feel the heat start to rise under your collar. They&apos;ve got you boxed in. They&apos;re laughing in your face, poking you in the ribs with their meaty jock fingers, howling like retarded jackals. Dammit, dammit. You&apos;re trembling with adrenaline. WHY. WON&apos;T. THEY. JUST. LEAVE. ME. ALONE....

Well, if this sounds like you, please, please, please leave your five-inch folding knife at home next time you go out drinking. Thanks! 
   
 
 Don&apos;t Troll Me Bro! 2012-02-05 07:30:25 PM 
 hammettman : I always love these comments:

&quot;This is a good kid,&quot; Gulbrandsen said

Except for the stabbing 3 people part. 

I love the &quot;good kid&quot; line. Last year we had a premeditated robbery that ended up becoming a murder here in Madison. Even the story the defense attorney gave made it sound like the murder part was planned as well. The person that masterminded it was &quot;a good kid&quot; according to parents. No, your child was a monster, and you&apos;ve failed as a parent; let that eat at you until your dying breath, you failure.

/wow, bad grammer
//too lazy to fix 
   
 
 Amos Quito 2012-02-05 07:45:08 PM 
 Mixin beer n Wine.

Oy. 
   
 
 Ebenezer Floppen Slopper 2012-02-05 08:49:58 PM 
 Naperville is slowly building a history of stabbings 
/CSB; stabber in linked article was an ex roommate 
   
 
 jaytkay 2012-02-05 09:10:07 PM 
 White people problems 
   
 
 jmsvrsn 2012-02-05 09:59:54 PM 
 
   
 
 StanTheMan 2012-02-05 10:11:47 PM 
 &quot;&quot;Obviously, this is an incredible aberration in the life of David,&quot; he told the judge as Olaska&apos;s parents and members of his church looked on.&quot; 

Not to mention, an incredible aberration in the life of his victim, i.e., death. 
   
 
 Danger Avoid Death 2012-02-05 10:31:15 PM 
 StanTheMan : &quot;&quot;Obviously, this is an incredible aberration in the life of David,&quot; he told the judge as Olaska&apos;s parents and members of his church looked on.&quot;

Not to mention, an incredible aberration in the life of his victim, i.e., death. 

Life is the leading cause of death. 
   
 
 italie 2012-02-05 11:51:25 PM 
 Naperville is as Naperville does.

//Only good things to ever come out of Naperville were Harry Kalas and that Nikki chick. 
   
 
 asscorethethird 2012-02-06 12:24:28 AM 
 Sounds like the stabee&apos;s were starting shiat and got what they deserved. In a bar and three people are starting shiat with me? This is why people (myself included) carry a knife. At the first indication of violence I probably would have done the same thing, and it freaks me out that you are all so brainwashed as to think that he is automatically a scumball. You don&apos;t know what happened!

Shahab, fast thick pants, and yosluggo you guys are all right... 
   
 
 Jeebus Saves 2012-02-06 12:40:23 AM 
 The most important piece of information is missing. What beer was the guy drinking? It might not have been a wine glass, but a tulip glass used for certain types of beers. And yes, the glass makes all the difference when drinking certain beers. Can&apos;t tell you the shiat I took when I came back with a Goose Island Juliet in a tulip glass and set down a pitcher of piss for my brother and his friends. 
   
 
 wellreadneck 2012-02-06 01:33:34 AM 
 asscorethethird : Sounds like the stabee&apos;s were starting shiat and got what they deserved. In a bar and three people are starting shiat with me? This is why people (myself included) carry a knife. At the first indication of violence I probably would have done the same thing, and it freaks me out that you are all so brainwashed as to think that he is automatically a scumball. You don&apos;t know what happened!

Shahab, fast thick pants, and yosluggo you guys are all right... 

This

Seems like these days, you&apos;re supposed to just lie down in the fetal position, wait til they eventually get tired of kicking you, then crawl away the better man. 
   
 
 foxyshadis 2012-02-06 03:58:06 AM 
 Fark double IPAs and fark pretentious wannabe winos who insist on drinking them out of a merlot glass or brandy snifter. It&apos;s a vain attempt to join in the snobbery of other snobby drinkers. Just enjoy your drink, you don&apos;t show everyone else how awesome you are for ordering the most expensive drink at the bar. 
   
 
 mjl 2012-02-06 08:23:44 AM 
 Last year I was at a conference lunch where I picked up a glass of red wine
and it took a few moments to realize that I was actually drinking coke. The expectation trumped the taste :-} 
   
 
 jaytkay 2012-02-06 09:31:19 AM 
 wellreadneck : asscorethethird: Sounds like the stabee&apos;s were starting shiat and got what they deserved. In a bar and three people are starting shiat with me? This is why people (myself included) carry a knife. At the first indication of violence I probably would have done the same thing, and it freaks me out that you are all so brainwashed as to think that he is automatically a scumball. You don&apos;t know what happened!

Shahab, fast thick pants, and yosluggo you guys are all right...

This

Seems like these days, you&apos;re supposed to just lie down in the fetal position, wait til they eventually get tired of kicking you, then crawl away the better man. 

Hell yeah!

He pokes fun at the sweater tied around your neck, you jeer at his pink popped-collar Izod .

He sneers at your beer glass, you stab him in the heart.

It&apos;s the Naperville way. 
   
 
 DRFS Rich 2012-02-06 10:12:00 AM 
 R.A.Danny - As long as we&apos;re recommending only the classiest joints, why not go all out a few blocks east and head to Miss Kitty&apos;s Saloon?

Grumpy Bulldog is pretty good, if it&apos;s still down there. Not too pretentious and a good beer selection. Quigley&apos;s pours a good pint too. 
   
 
 R.A.Danny 2012-02-06 10:22:23 AM 
 DRFS Rich : R.A.Danny - As long as we&apos;re recommending only the classiest joints, why not go all out a few blocks east and head to Miss Kitty&apos;s Saloon?

Grumpy Bulldog is pretty good, if it&apos;s still down there. Not too pretentious and a good beer selection. Quigley&apos;s pours a good pint too. 

Not enough urine on the floor.
Sersiously though, I love White&apos;s. Too many of the downtown bars are way too pretentious for me. 
   
 
 cfh 2012-02-06 10:58:09 AM 
 
   
 
 wellreadneck 2012-02-06 10:59:08 AM 
 jaytkay : wellreadneck: asscorethethird: Sounds like the stabee&apos;s were starting shiat and got what they deserved. In a bar and three people are starting shiat with me? This is why people (myself included) carry a knife. At the first indication of violence I probably would have done the same thing, and it freaks me out that you are all so brainwashed as to think that he is automatically a scumball. You don&apos;t know what happened!

Shahab, fast thick pants, and yosluggo you guys are all right...

This

Seems like these days, you&apos;re supposed to just lie down in the fetal position, wait til they eventually get tired of kicking you, then crawl away the better man.

Hell yeah!

 He pokes fun at the sweater tied around your neck, you jeer at his pink popped-collar Izod .

 He sneers at your beer glass, you stab him in the heart.

It&apos;s the Naperville way. 

In this instance, those pronouns should be plural. When faced with multiple opponents, especially drunken jocks in a bar, it&apos;s reasonable to assume that the impending confrontation won&apos;t be governed by Queensberry rules.
Misjudging the defensive capabilities of their severely outnumbered target was their mistake. Choosing a victim who didn&apos;t do things according to their plan shouldn&apos;t mean they get to reverse the roles. 
   
 
 StanTheMan 2012-02-06 04:55:22 PM 
 foxyshadis : Fark double IPAs and fark pretentious wannabe winos who insist on drinking them out of a merlot glass or brandy snifter. It&apos;s a vain attempt to join in the snobbery of other snobby drinkers. Just enjoy your drink, you don&apos;t show everyone else how awesome you are for ordering the most expensive drink at the bar. 

So you&apos;d be in the &quot;start a knife fight with a guy for drinking beer out of a wine glass&quot; then.

/Nobody drinks an IPA out of a wine glass
/You drink a Belgian out of a Belgian beer glass that sort of looks like a wine glass 
   
 
 foxyshadis 2012-02-07 02:00:28 AM 
 StanTheMan : foxyshadis: Fark double IPAs and fark pretentious wannabe winos who insist on drinking them out of a merlot glass or brandy snifter. It&apos;s a vain attempt to join in the snobbery of other snobby drinkers. Just enjoy your drink, you don&apos;t show everyone else how awesome you are for ordering the most expensive drink at the bar.

So you&apos;d be in the &quot;start a knife fight with a guy for drinking beer out of a wine glass&quot; then.

/Nobody drinks an IPA out of a wine glass
/You drink a Belgian out of a Belgian beer glass that sort of looks like a wine glass 

The only place I&apos;ve ever been served a tulip glass, if that&apos;s what you&apos;re talking about, is at a microbrewery. Most restaurants hopping on this trend are using the exact same wine glass that they serve their wine in - believe me, I&apos;ve tried it, just to see what was up. Some use brandy snifters, which at least makes sense, though I&apos;d rather have a cognac in one if I&apos;m going to fark up my sense of smell anyway. Some use those gigantic round wine glasses that hold most of a pint. Either way, it&apos;s a trend that restaurants are capitalizing on, advertising on tables and menus galore while putting a minimum effort and rarely bothering to even procure something we can&apos;t find at the damn grocery store every day.

/Start banging fist on table halfway into rant.
//Had a few already... and then some. 
   
 Displayed 48 of 48 comments 
 View Voting Results: Smartest and Funniest 
 Redisplay/refresh comments 
 
 This thread is closed to new comments. 

 Submit a Link»    Like Fark! +1 Fark! Follow @fark on Twitter Fark via RSS 
 
 Top Links Top Comments Top Submitters Press/Publicity 
 Headlines of the Week 
 All Latest Fark Forum Link Voting Sports Forum Fark Blogs Geek Forum Fark Book Entertainment Forum Fark Travel Guide Politics Forum Fark Parties Fark Party Forum Fark Chat Photoshop Forum PS/Photo Browser Farktography Forum Fark Quiz 
 From the Fark Shop : 
 
Braaains 
3DIY Mighty Wallet 
Penguin Plush 
Giant Inflatable Monster Head (Frankenstein) 
 More from the Fark Shop »  
 Stories from our partner sites: 

 
 Jackie Chan Hates the Rush Hour Movies! 
 How Apple Works 
 11 Terrifying Ventriloquist Dummies 
 One of Anime&apos;s Worst Catchphrases? 
 More news at Scribol» 

 
 Woody Guthrie: Rare Photos of an Amer... 
 The Moviegoer: In Praise of Sitting i... 
 Gene Kelly: Rare Photos 
 The Aleutians: Rare Photos From WWII&apos;... 
 More news at Life» 

 
 ESPY Awards Highlights: Pitcher Brian... 
 Britney Spears Explains Her Second&apos;X... 
 Miley Cyrus&apos;15th Tattoo Is A Quote F... 
 Charlie Sheen Lights One Up At MLB Al... 
 More news at Starpulse» 

 
 Tom Cruise&apos;s Lawyer May Sue National... 
 Police Arrest Suspect After Koretown... 
 San Bernardino To Examine Impact Of B... 
 Manhattan Beach Officer Hospitalized... 
 More news at KTLA» 

 
Also on Fark

 Main &quot;The sunglasses were never found&quot;    ( nwfdailynews.com ) »  (6 comments) Sports Jay Paterno says all his dad wanted was a thorough investigation of Jerry Sandusky and he&apos;s been fighting hard for just that these past 15 years    ( content.usatoday.com ) »  (10 comments) Business Forgot your password? Hackers at the Yahoo server have it for you    ( msnbc.msn.com ) »  (4 comments) Geek Global warming may cause stressed cows to udderly decrease milk production in certain parts of the country    ( phys.org ) »  (24 comments) Entertainment Mets&apos;R.A. Dickey demonstrates the art of throwing the knuckleball to battery mate David Letterman.&quot;I feel like I&apos;m at the circus&quot;(w/video)    ( nydailynews.com ) »  (0 comments) Politics While the media is busily covering the staged NAACP fauxtroversy, someone has actually bothered to look at Romney&apos;s financial disclosures, and he may be guilty of a felony    ( politico.com ) »  (16 comments) Video I got it, I got it, I got it, I got it, I got it, I got it, I got it, I.............ain&apos;t got it    ( liveleak.com ) »  (36 comments) 

 Fark :: Main | Sports | Business | Geek | Entertainment | Politics | Video Total Fark :: TotalFark | TF Discussion | All | Commented | Top Voted | Greenlit FArQ :: About Us | Quick Answers | FarkIt | Posting Rules | Farkisms Contests :: Photoshop | Farktography | VideoEdit | Caption Buy Fark :: Headline Shirts | Fark Book | Fark Store 

 Submit a Link» 

Copyright©1999 - 2012 Fark, Inc | Last updated: Jul 12 2012 10:04:39
 Contact Us   |   Report a bug/error msg   |   Terms of service/legal/privacy policy 
 Runtime: 0.110 sec (110 ms)
	</body>
</document>
