<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000895" url="http://www.mymysteryparty.com/mofanewyeeve.html" time="2012-07-12-16:15" support="2" score="0.0024418701133059467" bingtitle="New Years Eve Scavenger Hunt - Murder Mystery Party Games" webtitle="New Years Eve Scavenger HuntMurder Mystery Party Game">
			<query id="001259" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="001273" bing-rank="216"/>
	<description>... holding the can and next to a confused cashier. TASK 7: Make ... Purchase only 12 French fries from any fast food restaurant. ... Team selection squares : A game rule summary for 5 ...</description>
	<body>
		home contact us view cart privacy policy about us 


 
 Investigate the Site Home &gt; Games by Season &gt; New Year&apos;s Eve &gt;The Most Fantastic New Years Eve Scavenger Hunt 2012 -Instant Download Version Item# NYESCAV $19.95 
 Description 
 It is time to host the most wicked New Year&apos;s Party...EVER!! 2012 is your year to be the greatest party host of all times. So, how do you do that? Be the host of &apos;The Most Fantastic New Years Eve Scavenger Hunt!&apos;

This scavenger hunt is a fun and hilarious challenge that allows you and your guests to compete in an ultimate race against time. The party will be a huge success for a New Years Eve party as long as you and your guests relax, focus on strategy and take some hilarious &apos;picture proofs&apos; to provide lifelong memories and start 2012 with an entertaining &apos;bang.&apos; This is the instant download version of the game - no waiting! Download immediately upon purchase!

 WOULD YOU RATHER THE PROFESSIONALS AT MY MYSTERY PARTY PREPARE YOUR GAME KIT FOR YOU? Click here for the Party Ready Pack version of the game! 

 Example Tasks from the NYE Hunt: 

TASK 1: Find a street sign that has the word &apos;New&apos; as part of the name. The team members must pose like different kinds of animals while standing underneath the sign. The picture proof is the sign and the animal impersonators.

TASK 3: Go to the store and find Black Eyed Peas and then go to the cashier and ask them if the actual band (i.e. the Black Eyed Peas) is in there when you open it up. The picture proof is one team member holding the can and next to a confused cashier.

TASK 7: Make a sign that says &apos;Honk if you&apos;re going to have a great 2012!&apos; Stand on a street corner with a stop light (the safety manager should make sure it is a safe location) and hold the sign towards the cars at the light. When three cars have honked, take a picture proof of one team member holding the sign on the street corner.

TASK 17: Purchase only 12 French fries from any fast food restaurant. Sit down at a table, line 6 of them up and then weave in the other 6 fries (like a basket weave pattern) and pour 16 stripes of ketchup across them. The picture proof is one team member posing with their French fry/ ketchup creation. 
*The best weave gets an extra task point!

 Hilarious, right? Can you imagine starting the new year
with your friends being absolutely crazy like that? 

Gettin&apos; the NYE party started:

In summary, the guests will draw for teams and navigate their way in their own cars about the town to complete a list of challenging yet hilarious tasks. The team who makes it back to home base (the host&apos;s party location) with the most successfully completed tasks verified by &apos;picture proofs&apos;...wins! This is the ultimate way to kick off the new year! Start the NYE party right! After the scavenger hunt, you can all go out to dinner or have a party at your home - we promise, you will have loads to laugh about!

 SCAVENGER HUNT GAME MATERIALS INCLUDE THE FOLLOWING: 
 Complete game instructions for the host!  Team instructions - game play - final judging!    Team selection squares A game rule summary for 5 teams The scavenger hunt task list (30 tasks) for 5 teams Optional &apos;not cooperating with the Captain&apos; sheets for 5 teams The scavenger hunt judging score sheet 


 Life is one party at a time - so why not make this one your next? 
 
Accessories
 
 
 Sample Scavenger Hunt Materials 
 
 How to Host a Scavenger Hunt Party 
 
 Free, printable invitation 
 
 Alternative Version: Free, printable invitation 
 
 Contact us via email at: support@mymysteryparty.com (24/7) or by phone at 1-800-714-3951 (M-F, 10-3PM Central). Dallas, Texas USA

 
 Adult Mystery Party Games Teen Mystery Party Games Kid&apos;s Mystery Party Games Need More Characters? Party Ready Packs Games by Season Scavenger Hunt Games Party Props Game Extras Need Help Choosing a Game? FAQ Testimonials Gift Certificates Costume and Party Supplies Halloween Games Bridal Games The Author 
 home | contact us | view cart | privacy policy | about us Copyright 2007-2012 My Mystery Party All Rights Reserved.
The best site for Halloween Murder Mystery Parties and Games.
Contact us at 1-800-714-3951 (M-F, 10-3 PM Central) or via email: partyadvisor@mymysteryparty.com
	</body>
</document>
