<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000667" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/54743804/Fast-Food-Restaurant-Business-Plan" time="2012-07-12-15:58" support="83" score="0.21741953418633586" bingtitle="Fast Food Restaurant Business Plan - Scribd" webtitle="Fast Food Restaurant Business Plan">
			<query id="000508" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="001344" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="000342" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000109" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="000540" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="001139" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="000198" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="001134" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="001458" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000201" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000460" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="001339" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000932" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="001357" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="000446" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000218" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000918" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000328" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000321" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000216" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000329" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="001340" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="001483" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="000292" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000196" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="001182" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="001012" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="000189" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000117" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="000949" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="001331" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="000415" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001346" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="001025" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000194" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="001142" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="001165" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000107" bing-rank="242"/>
			<query id="000204" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000501" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000603" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="001172" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="001277" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000211" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000886" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000336" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000729" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000314" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000187" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="001452" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="001466" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="000217" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="001324" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000326" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000341" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000528" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000203" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000323" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000994" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000103" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000742" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="000343" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="001138" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000510" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="001326" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000337" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000274" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000452" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000513" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000980" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000924" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000466" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="001329" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000212" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="001263" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000166" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000963" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="001189" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="001168" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="000524" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="001345" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000734" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="001174" bing-rank="95"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant Business Plan. Fresin Fries Executive Summary ... We will use &quot;tray toppers&quot; to explain the concept ... strategy is to build and open new locations in order ...</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 You are seeing our new document Reader view. Click here to revert. Feel free to leave us feedback on this feature here . × Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 Comment Go Back 
 Download   Fast Food Restaurant Business Plan Fresin Fries Executive Summary Fresin Fries is a locally owned fast food outlet that will be positioned as an international franchise through our creative approach to the company&apos;s image and deta il presentati on. Fresin Fries will provide a combination of exce llent food at value pricing, with fun packag ing and atmosphere. Fresin Fries is the answer to an increasing demand for snack-type fast food, to be consumed while window shopp ing and walking around inside a shopping mall. In today&apos;s highly co mpeti tive environment, it is becoming increasingly difficult to differentiate one fast food outlet from anot her. Singapore, a city state, is now beco ming the model metropolis for Asia&apos;s new economic boom. With more than 11 million visitors yearly, mainly from neighboring countries (Malaysia, Indonesia, Thailand and the Philippines), Singapore&apos;s retail sector is the strongest in the region. Our main priority is to establish one outlet in a crowded mall, preferably in one o f prominent shopping malls in Singapore. Later, our effort will be a further development of more retail outlets in the surrounding area. This plan is prepared to o btain a location for the initial launch of this concept. Additional financing will need to be secured for the two subsequent o utlets, anticipated in month 13 and early in year three. T he financing, in addition to the cap ital contributions from shareholders, will allow Fresin Fries to successfully open and expand t hrough year two. The initial capital investment will allow Fresin Fries to provide its customers with a value-driven, enterta ining experience through the creat ivi ty of its founders. Fresin Fries will entice youngsters to bring their friends and family with o ur innovative environment, fresh-cut Belgian fries, and selection of unique s ignature dipping sauces. Please note that all tables are in Singaporean Dollars (1 USD= S$1.6 0)   1.1 Objectives y To establish a presence as a successful local fast food outlets and gain a market share in Singapore&apos;s fast food industry. y To make Fresin Fries a destination spot for mall-goers. y To expand into a number of outlets by year three, and sell the franchise to neighbor ing metropolitan cities, suc h as Jakarta, Kuala Lumpur, Bangkok and Manila. 1.2 Mission Our main goal is to be o ne of the most successful fast food outlets in Singapore, starting wi th one retail outlet located inside a major shopping mall as a &quot;market tester.&quot; Fresin Fries will strive to be a premier local fast food brand in the local marketplace. We want our customers to have the tot al experience when visiting our outlet(s) and website as they w ill learn about this fascinating new &quot;pop culture.&quot; We will sell merchandise from pre-packaged sauces and t-shirts, to potato cutters, all with our o ffi cial brand attached to them. Our main focus will be serving high-quality food at a great value. 1.3 Keys to Success To succeed in this business we must: y C reate a unique, innovative, entertaining menu that will differentiat e us from the rest of the competition.   y C ontrol costs at all times, in all areas and implement a conservative approac h to growth policy. Although, we provide more than enough fund to open more than one outlet, we want to be on the safe side of the business. y Sell the products that are of the highest quality, as well as keeping the customers happy with all of our product categories from food to store merchandising. y P rovide 100% satisfaction to our customers and maintaining the level of excellent services among other competitors. y E ncourage the two most important values in fast food business: brand and image, as these two ingredients are a couple of main drivers in marketing communications . y G et access to high-traffic shopping malls near the target market. y P romote good values of company culture and business philosophy. Company Summary What is Fresin Fries? Fresin Fries sells gourmet fries i n a cone with a choice of sauce. W e use the concept of Belgian Fries, where the fries are all made from fresh potatoes and fried twice. Our outlet also provides excellent and friendly customer service to support the ambience of fun, energetic and youthful lifestyle. Youthful and fresh surroundings We will imitate successful establishments, such as Jamba Juice and St arbucks, which represent the majority of our core target market, between 18 to 35 years of age. Our store will feature display cooking of our featured Belgian Fries from cutting to frying. Our customers will also be able to read our in-house brochures in regards to all knowledge about Belgian Fries and our featured sauces. Our store will be decorat ed with fast food setting, such as a bright co unter and display menu on the wall. Quality food Each store will offer nothing but freshly fried Belgian fries, sandwiches and variety of unique blend sauces, all served with o ld-f ashioned home-style care. Open everyday Our store is open everyday from 10 am to 9 pm. Variety, variety, variety A different selection of sauces will be featured ever y three months and we will also change our Italian soda flavors to accompany our fries. 2.1 Company Ownership Fresin Fries is a privately held company. It will be regis tered as a Limited company, with ownership 25% - Guy Fry, 25% - Sam Sauce, 25% - Carl Cone, 25% - Harry Hip. page 1 of 36 of 00 
More From This User
 62 p. 39007270 a Term Paper on Jamuna Bank Ltd Fatema Tuz Johoora 90 Reads 36 p. Fast Food Restaurant Business Plan Fatema Tuz Johoora 588 Reads 
Related
 27 p. Business Plan TEMPLATE Anuj Bhargava 1086 Reads 22 p. retail final term paper Amarjeet Mahajan 166 Reads 40 p. 4.3.4 Industry Participants clifford13r1509 1942 Reads 40 p. 5.0 Strategy and Implementation Summary clifford13r1509 1942 Reads 40 p. FresinFries clifford13r1509 1942 Reads 14 p. buisiness proposal1 Muhammed Iqbal 106 Reads 14 p. Retail Plan Karlene Shayne Pangilinan Alivia 119 Reads 9 p. Unedited Business Plan Eva Riana Mak 170 Reads 10 p. Sample Business Plan Isabel Katrina Cajuguiran 676 Reads 10 p. Company Summary surbhi130688 646 Reads 5 p. Market Analysis Summary Siva Kumar Balaga 326 Reads 16 p. Business Plan Project Student Template1 Angel Eyezz 198 Reads 12 p. resturant summary Faizan Sarwar 371 Reads 16 p. A Comparison of McDonald&apos;s, Cafeteria and&quot;Healthy&quot;Fries cynthia_88 884 Reads 14 p. Summary Entrepreneur ambitious heer 88 Reads 1 p. Our Menu eatlocalmenus 1044 Reads 1 p. Our Menu eatlocalmenus 873 Reads 25 p. Furniture Business Plan junaidjavaid99 442 Reads 1 p. Our Menu eatlocalmenus 341 Reads 30 p. Fire Starters Kong Diep 48 Reads 21 p. Convenience Store Business Plan amargupta_bms9259 1363 Reads 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
Fast Food Restaurant Business Plan
 Download or Print This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
