<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000081" url="http://www.amw.com/missing_persons/brief.cfm?id=27969" time="2012-07-12-15:16" support="2" score="0.001987465704868026" bingtitle="AMW | Missing Persons | Yolanda Bindics | Brief" webtitle="AMW | Missing Persons | Yolanda Bindics | Brief">
			<query id="000925" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="000928" bing-rank="50"/>
	<description>... store, at a local fast food restaurant. About a week after Yolanda&apos;s disappearance, investigators said a Jamestown police officer was placed on administrative leave after ...</description>
	<body>
		About Watch Show Archives AMW Radio Community 
 Search AMW   GO 
 Home Fugitives Missing Children Missing Persons Captures Features AMW Video 
 
 Fugitives Home Search Fugitives Browse by Last Name Browse by Geography AMW Dirty Dozen Most Wanted Lists 
 F.B.I. 10 Most Wanted U.S. Marshals 15 Most Wanted GangTECC Most Wanted World&apos;s Most Wanted 
 
 
 Missing Children Home AMBER Alerts Search Missing Children Browse by Last Name Browse by Geography Missing Child Resources 
 
 Missing Persons Home Search Missing Persons Browse by Last Name Browse by Geography Missing Person Resources 
 
 Captures Home Browse by Capture Date Browse by Last Name Browse by Geography 
 
 Features Home Browse Feature Stories 
 
 Videos Home Top Videos Latest Videos Latest Episode 
 
 
AMW Case File
 
 BRIEF CASE RECOVERED PROFILE MEDIA 
 
Yolanda Bindics


 Report a Tip 
 Comment     
 
Latest Airing:

 Web Exclusive 
 
 
 Remains Identified As Missing Mother

New York police have identified remains found in Chautauqua County as those of Yolanda Bindics - a mother of four who has been missing since 2004. »The Full Story 


 Last updated September 18, 2006 
 
 Yolanda Bindics


 Report a Tip 
 Comment     
 
Mother Of Four Missing
 

On August 10, 2004, 25-year-old Yolanda Bindics left work in Jamestown, New York -- and vanished.  

Yolanda, a mother of four, was last seen sitting in her car, talking on her cellphone in the parking lot of the Family Dollar Store where she worked, after locking the shop up for the night. She told her brother, who was watching her four daughters - ages one, three, five and eight - that she was stopping on the way home to buy milk. The brother became concerned when he hadn&apos;t heard from her. The next day, August 11th, police discovered Yolanda&apos;s car two blocks from the Family Dollar store, at a local fast food restaurant.

About a week after Yolanda&apos;s disappearance, investigators said a Jamestown police officer was placed on administrative leave after admitting to having a relationship with Yolanda. The officer, whose name was not released, will remain on leave until investigators can determine the nature of that relationship.

Dozens of volunteers, family members and friends have searched parts of Jamestown to no avail. Police have labeled her disappearance suspicious, and are looking for any clues to her whereabouts. 





 


AMW Radio:

 »August 18 2004 

 
 
 Yolanda Bindics


 Report a Tip 
 Comment     
 Recovered;Sep 10, 2006 
Remains Identified As Missing Mother

 Skeletal remains found in a densly wooded area of Chautauqua County, New York have been identified as those of a young mother who&apos;s been missing since 2004.
Yolanda Bindics disappeared in August 2004, after leaving work at the Jamestown Family Dollar store. A day later, her car was found in the parking lot of a nearby fast-food restaurant and soon, her purse, wallet and keys turned up in a storm drain.
On September 10, 2006, two years after Yolanda&apos;s disappearance, hunters discovered human remains, which have now been identified as Yolanda Bindics. Police say the remains were identified through dental records, but cause of death has not been determined. Police are now looking at forensic evidence collected at the scene in hopes of identifying a suspect in the young woman&apos;s death. 



 
 
 Yolanda Bindics


 Report a Tip 
 Comment     
 Sex: Female Race: White Age at Disappearance: 25 Current Age: 33 Height: 5&apos;7&apos;&apos; Weight: 97-115 lbs. Hair (Color, Description, Facial Hair) : 
 Blond 
 Eyes: 
 Hazel 
 Last Seen: 
 Jamestown, NY 
 Other Possible Locations: 
 New York 
 
 
 Yolanda Bindics


 Report a Tip 
 Comment     
 
 
Photos
 Yolanda Bindics has been missing since August 10, 2004. 
 
Latest Updates
 Authorities Search For Missing Soldier 
Authorities are searching for Kelli Bordeaux, a combat medic who was stationed at Fort Bragg in North Carolina. Kelli was last seen on April 14, 2012,... 
»The Full Story Missing Mississippi Mom Possibly Abducted; SUV Found In Woods 
On April 29, 2012, 65-year-old Linda Gale Reed left work, went to Walmart, and was never seen again.The next day, her vehicle, a GMC Envoy, was found... 
»The Full Story 
 AMBER Alert: Tennessee 
AMW Headlines
 
 AMW Helps Nab Accused Calif. Rapist Pregnant Woman Drags Dying Sister Amidst Gunfire Brother Sought In Sex-Torture Case Groom&apos;s Mother Murdered; Cops Have No Leads Search Continues For Missing D.C. Teen Minn. Police Search For Missing Teen Police Search For Missing D.C. Runaway Marshals Hunt Convicted Sex Offender Cops Hunt Man Accused Of Shooting Mother Of Three Eric Toth One Of FBI&apos;s 10 Most Wanted Ex-Con Wanted For First-Degree Murder, Assault SIGN UP TO RECEIVE AMW NEWSLETTER&amp;ALERTS. 
 
 Fugitives Missing Children Missing Persons Captures Features 

 AMW Video Safety Center My Story Line Of Duty 

 John Walsh About AMW Watch Full Episodes Photo Gallery Report a Tip 

 Show Archive Contact Us Advanced Search Sitemap Email Newsletter 
 
AMW Quick Search
 
AMW is easy! Simply type the first name, last name or &quot;moniker&quot; of the person or case you are looking for and the search box will retrieve a list of all the cases in our system.Wait for the drop down box to appear with a list of possible matches and select the name of the case that you were looking for and click GO.You must type in a minimum of 4 letters.
	</body>
</document>
