<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000677" url="http://www.hotfrog.com.au/Products/Restaurants/Regions/Central-Western-Sydney" time="2012-07-12-15:58" support="2" score="0.0011737070910487189" bingtitle="Restaurants in Central Western Sydney - Hot Frog - Your Australian ..." webtitle="Restaurants in Central Western Sydney">
			<query id="000578" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="000579" bing-rank="233"/>
	<description>Credit Card welcome.Visa, Master Card, Diner&apos;s Club ... West is a child-friendly restaurant that puts all ... Family Restaurant Snacks And Drinks Fast Food Restaurant Fast Food</description>
	<body>
		Login Login using 
 
 
 What are you looking for? Where are you looking? Search 

 You may have forgotten a search term 
 Add your business 
 
Restaurants in Central Western Sydney
 Restaurants   Central Western Sydney (546) 1 - 40 of 546 businesses results Sponsored links Balla Restaurant , Sydney 
 www.star.com.au/Balla Discover A Little Piece Of Milan With Amazing Sydney Views. Book Now Sydney CBD Dining 
 sydney-cbd- dining .au.ask.com/ Find Great Results For Sydney CBD Dining .Find It! Dining in Sydney 
 www.sydney.com/ Dining Get tips on Sydney&apos;s best Food&amp;Wine Restaurants . 
 Accommodation   What&apos;s On Things To Do   Deals 
 Sydney Harbour Restaurant 
 www.harbourrocks.com.au/Scarlett The Rocks Dining at its Finest Right Next to Sydney Harbour. FIREBRAND BBQ CHARCOAL 
Guildford, NSW
 04 05771144 Email 
Australia&apos;s Most Superior BBQ Charcoal . Preferred by some of the most professional chefs countrywide. Firebrand BBQ Charcoal is 100% NATURAL and l…
 
Latest updates
 Wholesale Pallet Buy - 12-Jul-2012
 20% with our Pallet buy offer. Read more: Firebrand BBQ Charcoal - 02-Nov-2010
  Preferred by thousands of industry professionals worldwide, … Read more: 
 More info 
 Golden West Chinese Restaurant 
Winston Hills, NSW
 (02) 9838 7033 Email 
Golden West has proudly participated in the Australian Achievers since 2004, and has successfully been awarded with Highly Recommended from 2004 to 2…
 
Latest updates
 Chinese Foods - 21-Feb-2010
 e 2004, and has successfully been awarded with Highly Recommended from 200… Read more: Chinese Restaurant - 30-Apr-2009
  Golden West Chinese Restaurant has been open since 1991, and esta… Read more: 
 More info 
 
Related information
 Firebrand BBQ Charcoal 
FIREBRAND BBQ CHARCOAL - 02-Nov-2010
  Preferred by thousands of industry professionals worldwide, Firebrand© is the number one choice for all professional charcoal-based cooking, including the restaurant sector, charcoal chicken, korean BBQs, Spit roast or simply for home BBQ&apos;s and shisha enthusiasts. Firebrand© BBQ Charcoal comes in a sturdy and clean carton box which is recyclable and more environmentally friendly than most BBQ charcoal. This is an advantage when storing Firebrand© boxes as it is a big space sa… Chinese Foods 
Golden West Chinese Restaurant - 21-Feb-2010
 mers first! Golden West is fully licensed, bottled wines (BYO) welcome and offers a great range of fine chinese cuisine to be remembered. They are a friendly restaurant that caters for all occasions. Golden West seats 120people and disable welcome (wheelchair access). Want to stay home to eat? For any order over $20 home delivery (detail on contact page). Credit Card welcome.Visa, Master Card, Diner&apos;s Club, EFTPOS acepted.Gluteen Free No Smoking. Prices are subject to change without notifi… Chinese Restaurant 
Golden West Chinese Restaurant - 30-Apr-2009
  Golden West Chinese Restaurant has been open since 1991, and established itself as the local&apos;s secret. Golden West serves modern Chinese food in a warm, relaxed atmosphere. With their friendly staff, Golden West is a child-friendly restaurant that puts all their customers first! Golden West is fully licensed, bottled wines (BYO) welcome and offers a great range of fine chinese cuisine to be remembered. They are a friendly restaurant that caters for all occasions. Golden West seats 120… Complete Food Consultants 
Berala, NSW
 04 15813046 
Food Safety Consultants that provide technical professional advice to minimize and eliminate any food safety issues. Assist with restaurant kitchen designs.Ensure compliance and meet relevant standards and regulati…
 
 Restaurant Cafes food poisoning Food 
 Bravo Gelato 
Rydalmere, NSW
 +61 2 8845 0145 
Bravo Gelato. Australias leading manufacturer and supplier of gelato and sorbet to gelaterie, cafes, restaurants , party hire shops, hotels and function centres.
 
 Italian Restaurant Pizza Restaurant Restaurant Food&amp;Beverage Outlets 
   InsideOut Restaurant 
Parramatta, NSW
 (02) 9687 9045 
Insideout has been established in Parramatta for over 11 years and is the leader in providing good food and service in a well put together business
 
 dinner lunch Restaurant Modern Australian 
 Timms Multicultural Catering 
Merrylands, NSW
 04 66392200 
Catering for all occasions such as weddings, birthdays, anniversaries at cheap prices - very good service.  We also decorate Halls and Main tables.
 
 Catering Service Caterers Wedding Catering Food 
 Indulgence Restaurant Bar And Grill Fuc… 
Parramatta, NSW
 (02)96892288 
Indulgence - Formally The River Canyon - is the newest and best business, casual and formal dining venue in Parramatta. On the banks of the River with views the international cuisine has something to offer for everyone…
 
 Australian Restaurants Grills Dining Restaurant Bar 
 Insideout Restaurant&amp;Bar 
Parramatta, NSW
 (02) 8837 7300 
One of parramattas best Great food, having been a few times, I pretty much settle on the steak with blue cheese butter..it is great. And the best creme brulee I&apos;ve ever had...Parramatta has many restaurants , mostly ave…
 
 Australian Restaurants cafe restaurant Restaurant Food&amp;Beverage Outlets 
 El Phoenician Lebanese Restaurant 
Parramatta, NSW
 (02) 9633 1611 
Our menu has a vast selection of Mediterranean cuisine and several grill and seafood dishes. The Traditional way to eat our cuisine is to order an array of different dishes to share amongst each other. For your convenie…
 
 Continental Restaurants Lebanese Restaurant seafood dishes Mediterranean cuisine 
 Dirty Dick&apos;s Theatre Restaurant 
Parramatta, NSW
 (02) 9830 0673 
Dirty Dick&apos;s Theatre Restaurant - Australia&apos;s premier Theatre Restaurant (established 1970), presents its shows and unique nights of entertainment in selected venues in Sydney, Central Coast, Newcastle, Canberra and reg…
 
 Theatre Restaurant Restaurant Christmas Parties Theatre 
 Daawat Indian Feast (Westmead) 
Westmead, NSW
 88409051 
Indian take-away and Dine-in. At, Daawat Indian Feast (Westmead), we welcome you to try our DELICIOUS Chicken, Lamb, Goat and Seafood dishes. Also available Biryanis (one of our most popular dish), Thalis, Aloo Puri, Br…
 
 Indian Restaurant North Indian Restaurants Food&amp;Beverage Services Indian Food 
 Conaught Place Indian Fine Dining 
Harris Park, NSW
 02 96334455 
Best Indian Restaurant in western Sydney. Real Indian fine food. Heart of North Indian Cuisene is Connaught Place
 
 Dining Indian Functions Food 
 ROYAL HUT { Indian Food Catering } 
Westmead, NSW
 04 21481155 
Royal Hut Indian Food catering We cater for all Occasions Birthday parties, Pooja,House warming&amp;Get together etc. So if you are planning a function give us acall Navi on 0421 481 155 Or Email us royal_hut@yahoo.com
 
 Party Supplies&amp;Services Party Services Caterers Catering 
 Courtney&apos;s Brasserie 
Parramatta, NSW
 (02) 9635 3288 
If you are seeking a restaurant where food is exalted but not to the
exclusion of good company, Courtney&apos;s Brasserie is one of the finest restaurants in Sydney. Central to Parramatta (home to the
Parramatta Eels) and c…
 
 Brasserie Wedding Catering fine dining Corporate Catering 
 Deli Delish 
Parramatta Westfield, NSW
 (02) 9893 7353 
Deli Delish is a NEW Breed of Delicatessens, Bringing back the old day deli with todays modern day environment - Offering the Freshest&amp;Best Quality of Award winning Products.  Offering the highest quality&amp;g…
 
 Catering Service Wedding Catering Platters Functions 
 Chrissy&apos;s Kitchen 
Guildford, NSW
 (02) 9788 4858 
* FOOD CATERING * BONBONIERES * PARTY INVITES * CHOCOLATES Chrissy&apos;s Kitchen is preferred for its authentic Lebanese food, 5 star service and competitive prices. We cater for any occassion, and will impress you with our…
 
 Caterers Wedding Catering Western Food Caterers Food Catering 
 High Top Cleaning Services Maintenance 
Parramatta, NSW
 04 16092929 
High Top Cleaning Services provides competitively-priced, quality cleaning services in the Sydney region.
 
 Restaurant Cleaning hotel cleaning Hotels Holiday Accommodation 
 Navarro&apos;s Kitchen 
Westmead, NSW
 (02) 9633 3305 
Navarro&apos;s Kitchen is a small Cafe and Takeaway, famous with locals for its own unique charcoal chicken with homemade garlic sauce. The menu also includes traditional beer battered fish and chips, burgers (from simple to…
 
 Catering Cafes Takeaway fresh salads 
 Vespucci Designer Events 
Parramatta, NSW
 1300 768 848 
Vespucci Designer Events is a boutique event management company which specialises in the design, planning, management and coordination of weddings and special events. From concept to design, or just some expert advice …
 
 Receptions Wedding Reception Event Management Company Weddings 
 Onlinecupcakes 
Newington, NSW
 04 02989972 
We are a small business which makes quality cupcakes for children&apos;s birthday parties, parties, christenings, weddings, baby showers etc. We also specialise in gift boxes which contain cupcakes, these can be given to so…
 
 Wedding Catering Function Food Parties 
 Ausnet Underwriting Agency 
Parramatta, NSW
 (02) 9890 3387 
Ausnet Underwriting Agency are the leaders in retail shop insurance. Ausnet are backed by Lloyds of London and offer insurance in retail, shops, supermarkets, restaurants , franchises and takeaways. Ausnet also underwrit…
 
 
 Austmont Catering Equipment 
Girraween, NSW
 (02) 9896 3050 
Stainless steel fitout of commercial kitchens and bars Design and fitout of stainless steel benches, cooking equipment, coolrooms, refrigeration, trollies etc Specialising in fitouts of top Restaurants , Hotels, Bars, H…
 
 Party Supplies&amp;Services Party Services Caterers Catering 
 RIVER CANYON WATERFRONT RESTAURANT 
Parramatta, NSW
 02 9689 2288 
Casual&amp;Family Dining - Modern Australian Cuisine Situated on the banks of the Parramatta River, is the River Canyon Restaurant; opened in 1985 by brothers Michael&amp;Frank; since then it has never stopped growi…
 
 Western Restaurants Restaurant Family Dining All You Can Eat 
 GN ReSound 
Regents Park, NSW
 +61 2 9743 9707 
ReSound is among the world&apos;s largest manuafacturers of digital hearing aids that fit any lifestyle. And don&apos;t forget to visit our section on hearing and hearing loss
 
 
 Any Event Catering 
Toongabbie, NSW
 02 9896 6550 
Any Event Catering is your complete hospitality solutions company, with years of experience in the industry All food is prepared fresh and is of the highest premium quality it is cooked to perfection in our pro…
 
 Wedding Catering Catering Catering Services Finger Foods 
 Accommodation at Merrylands 
Merrylands, NSW
 (02) 9535 4994 
Get cheap accommodations in merrylands.  2 and 3 bedrooms available. Please call on 0421 011 172
 
 Pubs Hotels Motels Bed And Breakfast 
 Giulianis Pizza Cafe 
Toongabbie, NSW
 (02) 9688 2188 
Giulianis specialises in
real Italian pizza, pasta, veal, chicken, and seafood authentic dishes.
We have been serving the local Toongabbie community for the past four
years. Chef Greg leads a highly skilled team in the…
 
 Italian Restaurant Pizza Restaurant Italian Cuisine Eating Out 
 Event Organiser 
Parramatta, NSW
 
Event Organiser is a comprehensive online resource for anyone organising an event, providing information, ideas and a virtual market place of event industry products and services. Find planning advice, ideas, tools, tip…
 
 Wedding Catering Function Rooms Function Room Hire Receptions 
 Sydney Olympic Park 
NEWINGTON, NSW
 02 9714 7888 
Sydney Olympic Park offers a tempting choice of food outlets, cafes, bars and restaurants all within strolling distance of the major venues and parklands
 
 Cuisine Sandwiches Takeaway Venues 
 Leos Italian Restaurant 
Granville, NSW
 (02) 9682 3380 
Leo is back&amp;cooking the most authentic Italian food his customers have loved to enjoy over the past 30 years... Enjoy a large selection of seafood, pasta, veal, chicken, steak dishes&amp;homemade desserts Fully …
 
 Italian Restaurant Restaurant Italian Food Function Rooms 
 Gema Group Holdings 
WENTWORTHVILLE, NSW
 02 96319100 
We are members of Restaurant&amp;Catering Association of NSW, Venue Management Association and Australian Bridal Service Our Vision: About Gema Group: Gema Group Catering for 20 or 20 000, by combining all as…
 
 Catering Company Catering Restaurant&amp;Catering Catering Association 
 Hot Box Pizza Co 
Parramatta, NSW
 1300 468 269 
HOT BOX Pizza Co is a family friendly Pizza Restaurant situated in Parramatta Our “Good Old Fashioned Burgers, Subs, Kebabs and Wraps” are amazing
 
 Pizza Restaurant Restaurant Pizza Pasta 
 Piazzetta Bella 
Pendle Hill, NSW
 (02) 9636 4088 
Piazzetta Bella offers a great environment to celebrate special occasions be it birthdays, christenings, engagements and weddings, with an alfresco area reminiscent of a Tuscan Piazza
 
 Italian Restaurant Restaurant seafood dishes risotto 
 Gn Resound 
Regents Park, NSW
 1800 658 955 
ReSound is among the world&apos;s largest manuafacturers of digital hearing aids that fit any lifestyle. And don&apos;t forget to visit our section on hearing and hearing loss
 
 
 Woolpack Hotel 
PARRAMATTA, NSW
 02 9635 8043 
Woolpack Hotel providing Parramatta with newly renovated bars, thai dining and functions in the Parramatta area
 
 Thai Restaurant Bars Functions nightlife 
 Mjmezza 
Granville, NSW
 02 9632 7164 
We offer a variety of delicious authentic foods, which are great for any occasion Monjay Mezza manufacture and distribute Mediterranean finger foods, including our famous Garlic Dip
 
 Restaurant Catering Finger Foods Falafel 
 Reflect Enterprise 
Parramatta, NSW
 02 96879045 
 Restaurants in Parramatta: Come to inside out resturant in Parramatta, Sydney, NSW and feel relax&amp;enjoy a meal inside our bright and airy restaurant - InsideOutRestaurant.com
 
 Restaurant private dining restuarants Resturants 
 Dundas Sports&amp;Recreation Club 
Dundas, NSW
 (02)9638 5900 
Great Local Club, good food, small friendly atmosphere
 
 bistros Function Rooms Bars Sports And Recreation Club 
 Tensor Design 
Merrylands, NSW
 1300 737 998 
Tensor Design offers a range of services, as listed below, to assist you with your online endeavours Call our toll free number 1300 737 998 or to book a free, no obligation demonstration of how installing Rapi…
 
 Restaurant Equipment bistros Caterers Catering 
 Sicilian Parramatta 
PARRAMATTA, NSW
 02 9633 2299 
Sicilian Parramatta is Parramatta&apos;s premier Italian Restaurant catering upto 300 people. Why not Host your next function at Sicilian Parramatta
 
 Italian Restaurant Italian Cuisine Restaurant Restaurant Catering 
 First page Prev 10 pages   1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Last page Next 10 pages 
Businesses (546) 
 Related keywords 
 Restaurant Food&amp;Beverage Outlets Food&amp;Beverage Services Fast Food Catering Accommodation Cafes Holiday Accommodation Chinese Restaurant Italian Restaurant 
 Restaurants by suburb 
 PARRAMATTA, NSW MERRYLANDS, NSW AUBURN, NSW WENTWORTHVILLE, NSW LIDCOMBE, NSW GUILDFORD, NSW GRANVILLE, NSW HARRIS PARK, NSW RYDALMERE, NSW TOONGABBIE, NSW WESTMEAD, NSW NEWINGTON, NSW NORTHMEAD, NSW PENDLE HILL, NSW BERALA, NSW WINSTON HILLS, NSW DUNDAS, NSW ERMINGTON, NSW REGENTS PARK, NSW GIRRAWEEN, NSW HOMEBUSH BAY, NSW GREYSTANES, NSW TELOPEA, NSW PARRAMATTA WESTFIELD, NSW SOUTH WENTWORTHVILLE, NSW 
 Businesses that regularly add new information and match your search 
Most active

 This week All time 
 
 FIREBRAND BBQ CHARCOAL 
 Coupons (1) 
 Dundas Sports&amp;Recreation Cl… 

 
 
 FIREBRAND BBQ CHARCOAL 
 Products (1) Coupons (1) 
 Golden West Chinese Restaurant 
 Products (2) 
 RIVER CANYON WATERFRONT RESTA… 
 Products (3) 
 
 Business profiles just added to Hotfrog that match your search 
Just added
 
 Complete Food Consultants 22-Nov-2009 Daawat Indian Feast (Westmead) 20-Nov-2009 Conaught Place Indian Fine Dining 08-Nov-2009 ROYAL HUT { Indian Food Catering } 19-Oct-2009 RIVER CANYON WATERFRONT RESTAURANT 05-Oct-2009 Australian Commercial Kitchens (NSW) Pt… 17-Jul-2009 
 Most viewed businesses matching your search enquiry 
Most popular
 
 FIREBRAND BBQ CHARCOAL McDonald&apos;s Granville McDonald&apos;s Lidcombe Daawat Indian Feast (Westmead) Dirty Dick&apos;s Theatre Restaura… Golden West Chinese Restaurant 
 
 Small Business Hub 
 
Sharing tips, ideas and advice to help grow your small business.
 View the Small Business Hub 
 Hotfrog AdVantage 
 
Hotfrog AdVantage ads appear above the rest in Hotfrog feature pages. By upgrading today your ad will appear in front of potential customers before they notice your competitors.
 Find out more 
 What are you looking for? Where are you looking? Search 

 You may have forgotten a search term 
 
Create your free Hotfrog business profile
 Add your business 
Join the Hotfrog community on:
 
 About Hotfrog Advertise with us Contact us Terms of use Privacy policy Help 
 
 Hotfrog Small Business Hub 

 Grow your business Case studies Hotfrog how tos 
 © Copyright Reed Business Information Pty Ltd 2005-2012 (v 11.5.8.004 )
	</body>
</document>
