<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000764" url="http://www.mcdonaldsprices.com/" time="2012-07-12-16:06" support="4" score="0.005417236058447605" bingtitle="Mcdonalds Prices" webtitle="Mcdonalds Prices">
			<query id="001434" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="001439" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="001157" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="001156" bing-rank="164"/>
	<description>The cups of Joe we had were pretty impressive. This ... About the only thing I wish I could change if I had ... simply want to get in the car and visit this fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Mcdonalds Prices
 
 My Personal Mcdonalds Prices Guide Blog 
 
 Home About Posts RSS Contact Privacy Policy 
 skip to main | skip to sidebar 
Thursday, May 31, 2012
 
 McDonalds Prices are a Godsend in the Morning 
 
Mcdonalds Menu Prices for Breakfast are Indispensibly Inexpensive!
My kid wakes up every single morning starving! It&apos;s probably because after he does his homework, he&apos;s spends an inordinate amount of time playing the Nintendo Wii 
on the big screen TV downstairs. This means sometimes he&apos;ll nibble on his dinner only because he is anxious to go back and play super Mario Brothers! Anyway, each 
morning, he either likes to eat frozen waffles from Eggo brands, or he likes for me to run down to the corner McDonald&apos;s and grab him some hotcakes. Yes, he is really spoiled but I don&apos;t mind because I want the kid to go to school on a full stomach so he can be energized throughout the day.

That&apos;s something I 
don&apos;t mind because the McDonalds prices for hotcakes in my area is roughly $2.59 to $2.79.

At the same time, I have to admit that I sometimes grab a big breakfast MD&apos;s has to offer and I end up paying less than five dollars to feed both 
of us. My older daughter doesn&apos;t really like Mickey Dee&apos;s all that much because she&apos;s trying to watch her figure and she&apos;s more into the oatmeal for breakfast 
and sandwiches for lunch.

When we take family trips together it is so easy with these McDonalds prices to snatch up food for a family of four in the amount of less than $15. This is 
because I buy the hotcakes for my daughter and son (my daughter&apos;s going to have to live with that) at roughly $2.69 each, and I buy my wife and myself two Egg 
McMuffins and a cup of coffee.

I&apos;ll give you another example; when we go to Disney World we will eat breakfast at McDonalds and will also carry in a couple of 
sandwiches for later on in my wife&apos;s large carry-on bag. So with this, we take advantage two ways; the McDonalds prices are extremely cheap and by packing a 
lunch we save quite a bit of money at lunchtime while everybody else is eating all that fried and fatty stuff!

Also, when we are away on any kind of trip, I prefer treating the family to a decent meal at dinner time so it makes up for the frugality of not spending too much money throughout the morning and afternoon. We normally don&apos;t eat at Mickey Dees at night when we are on vacation just to change things up a little bit even though the Mcdonalds prices are probably something we should take advantage of. Either way, I must say my mornings are filled with Egg Mcmuffins and that good coffee any day of the week and I will continue to do so until some other restaurant can beat the taste and the actual great deal! Posted by Justin Milano at 7:36 PM 0
comments Labels: eat at mcdonalds , egg mcmuffins , frozen waffles , mcdonalds menu prices , mcdonalds prices , nintendo wii 
Saturday, December 10, 2011
 
 McDonalds Prices Can&apos;t be Beat for Breakfast Deals 
 I just got back from Marathon Key, Florida in the Florida Keys this Monday and I have to say I spent quite a bit of time marching myself down to the McDonald&apos;s nearby every single morning to take a vantage of the McDonalds prices on breakfast deals. On the first day of vacation we tried to hook up with some little-known restaurant run by a mom-and-pop duo and although it was pretty good it turned out to be pretty expensive. For a family of four we spent $43 with tip included and all we pretty much had weere pancakes and egg breakfasts. Free Samples&amp;Printable Coupons from your favorite brands. 


The following day after my kids twisted my arm, I woke up a little bit earlier in the morning and took advantage of the McDonald&apos;s prices on their breakfast menu. I got my little seven-year-old boy his favorite hot cakes with extra syrup, my 11 -year-old girl a big breakfast, and about six Egg McMuffins for the rest of the adults that went along with us. Needless to say we ate like kings with McDonald&apos;s breakfast items and everyone was seriously satisfied. The total amount of the bill was a little bit over $18. However, take into account that we did not buy anything to drink and instead relied on the orange juice that I bought nearby at a Publix the day before. With that said, it turns out I spent $21 to feed eight people. Of course we had to rely on the hotel coffee to get us through the morning and I had to chase down a housekeeper to get two extra bags of coffee for the automatic coffee maker in my room! But do you know what? The cups of Joe we had were pretty impressive. Never pay full price. Always use coupons. Start Now! 

This to me is proof positive that there really is no place when you&apos;re on the run to get a cheaper breakfast with good quality than to go visit and take advantage of the McDonald&apos;s prices on your favorite everyday breakfast items. I didn&apos;t even have to use any of the free McDonald&apos;s coupons that I sometimes use after getting them off of eBay. For those of you who don&apos;t know, you can get Mickey D&apos;s coupons on eBay for very cheap and it more than pays for itself after one or two visits after you buy about 10 to 15 coupons, so you can imagine what type of savings you&apos;re going to get. About the only thing I wish I could change if I had the power to do it would be to have a 24 hour McDonalds so I could get breakfast anytime. Sometimes, I would rather eat a McDonald&apos;s breakfast instead of a Big Mac or any of the other specialty Sandwiches just to lower the caloric intake and feel a little bit better consistently. Posted by Justin Milano at 12:54 PM 0
comments Labels: 24 hour mcdonalds , breakfast deals , mcdonalds breakfast items , mcdonalds prices Older Posts Home 
Subscribe To
 Posts Atom Posts All Comments Atom All Comments 
Blog Archive
 
 ▼  2012 (1) 
 ▼  May (1) 
 McDonalds Prices are a Godsend in the Morning 
 
 

 ►  2011 (4) 
 ►  December (3) 
 McDonalds Prices Can&apos;t be Beat for Breakfast Deals... Why McDonalds Breakfast Rules Why McDonalds Food Drives the Kids Crazy 
 

 ►  February (1) 
 Mcdonalds Menu Prices - A Steal When You Are On th... 
 
 

 ►  2010 (4) 
 ►  September (1) 
 McDonalds Prices are Right on the Money When Feedi... 
 

 ►  January (3) 
 Mcdonalds Food Prices Aren&apos;t the Only Reason They ... Save 300 Dollars a Month By Looking For the Lowest... About 
 
 

 ►  2009 (2) 
 ►  August (2) 
 Privacy Policy Contact 
 
 
 How would you rate McDonald&apos;s Prices compared to other fast food places? ( online surveys )   Copyright 2009 Mcdonalds Prices . Powered by Blogger Blogger Templates designed by Deluxe Templates
	</body>
</document>
