<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000565" url="http://www.checkers.com/food.html" time="2012-07-12-15:51" support="12" score="0.06620111137552816" bingtitle="Loaded Big | Burgers - Wings - Fries | Checkers" webtitle="Loaded Big | Burgers - Wings - Fries | Checkers">
			<query id="000941" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="000465" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000290" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000444" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000720" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000283" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000310" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="000453" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000461" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="001122" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000956" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000462" bing-rank="51"/>
	<description>From Burgers to crazy good Wings and hot Seasoned Fries, our food is always made ... At Checkers we make everything fresh to order and the second it’s done we deliver ...</description>
	<body>
		Checkers Drive-In Restaurant BURGERS•FRIES•COLAS 

 FOOD LOCATIONS Location Submit 
 
No results were found for your current location. Enter city, state, or zip above.
 
 
 COMPANY CAREERS FRANCHISING 
 
 
 100% QUALITY CURRENT SPECIAL FULL MENU VALUE COLD CREATIONS 
 
Intro

100% Beef.
100% quality.
100% flavor.

Seasoned, seared and grilled to perfection. Our burgers
are made of 100% Beef and served hot, juicy and fully
loaded with flavor. We don&apos;t know how to do it any
other way. One taste and you will understand why we
are known for our appetite-crushing burger beauties.
 
Made To Order

Heat lamps are 
for the lazy.

At Checkers we make everything fresh to order 
and the second it’s done we deliver it right to 
your hungry hands. We take pride in preparing 
and serving food the right way; hot, juicy and 
full of flavor –  because there’s nothing fresh 
about burgers sitting under a light bulb.
 
Grilled With Seasoning

Sizzle, sizzle goes 
the seasoning.

What exactly makes our burgers so mouth 
wateringly delicious? It’s a secret. Just kidding, it’s 
not. It’s a perfect blend of spices that we generously 
sprinkle on every burger after tossing it onto the 
grill. Juicy stuff huh? It’s a process we call seared 
and seasoned. It’s something you’ll call delicious.
 
Fresh Toppings

Taking a fresh 
stand on freshness.

When it comes to toppings, if it&apos;s not 100% fresh, it&apos;s 
not getting loaded on to our food. And when we say 
“fresh” we&apos;re talking sliced-daily tomatoes and onions, 
and crisp iceberg lettuce, fresh. How&apos;s that for a fresh 
approach to freshness?
 
Unique Flavors

Like nothing you&apos;ve 
ever craved before.

There&apos;s fast food and then there&apos;s Checkers food. From our 
seared and seasoned Burgers and crazy good Wings to our 
rich and creamy Milkshakes and famously Seasoned Fries, 
our food always comes fully loaded with unique flavors 
that are real, and really, really good. Let the craving for 
that one-of-a-kind Checkers flavor begin.
 
VIEW FULL MENU
 DOWNLOAD NUTRITIONAL INFO 
 MOBILE SITE SITE MAP LEGAL CONTACT US 
 ©2012 CHECKERS DRIVE-IN RESTAURANTS, INC. 
 CHECKERS ON FACEBOOK VIEW OUR TWITTER FEED VIEW OUR YOUTUBE CHANNEL 

 CHECKERS
ONLINE JOIN THE
FLAVORHOOD
	</body>
</document>
