<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000985" url="http://gaininja.blogspot.com/" time="2012-07-12-16:22" support="2" score="0.005267359490910932" bingtitle="外忍者 - gai.ninja" webtitle="外忍者    -    gai.ninja">
			<query id="001119" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="000366" bing-rank="160"/>
	<description>When you eat a substantial quantity of high GI food, the amount of insulin ... chocolate biscuits you had with your cup of ... Fast-food restaurant inspired by &apos;cave man ...</description>
	<body>
		外忍者 - gai.ninja
 
 gai: adj. outside of; not covered by; foreign
nin: endurance; patience; conceal; secrete; stealth; sneak
ja: noun. person 
 
 Monday, 9 July 2012 
 
 Self-imposed rest 
 Well, I&apos;m on Day 7 of 7 Self-Imposed Rest Days. I don&apos;t know what I&apos;ve done to my arm/shoulder, but it&apos;s definitely more than just muscle pain so I figured I&apos;d take a full week off all upper-body workouts (you didn&apos;t think I actually meant total rest did you? ;) and see where I am.

On the upside, it&apos;s given me some more free time - I&apos;m working on making a necklace that&apos;s been sitting unfinished on my desk for far too long, plus a present for some friends &quot;Not Wedding&quot;, and I&apos;ve even done a bit of Life Admin and knocked some lingering things off the to-do list. I&apos;ve also had the chance to work on my cardio a bit more. On Tuesday I did a nice 6.5km run with 5 stops for 20 x burpees and 20 x pistol squats. The pistols are really coming on - by the later sets I appeared to have over-come the problem with my right heel raising when I do them. Been doing some interval training too, which reminded me why I kinda ditched all the cray-fast running to focus on strength training ;)

One of the annoying things about the injury is that I was planning to shoot some videos for here - L-sit chin-ups, pull-ups, holds, dips etc. but now I&apos;m going to have to put that on hold. Instead I will aim to do a pistol squat one next, until I&apos;m recovered and back to normal training.

The Stick arrived, and I&apos;ve been doing three sets of full-body rolling a day, with particular attention to my shoulder/arm area, plus a load of tennis ball trigger point work. To answer a question on a previous post - the stick is basically a flexible core (think it could be made of nylon by the looks of it) with smooth plastic tube segments over it and rubber handles. It allows you to roll over muscles with increasing pressure to get rid of knots. By wedging one end under things (bits of you, the wall, the bed, a chair etc.) you can pretty much get leverage to roll anywhere. It seems to be working out quite well - I can feel things loosening up. I am sure you could make something similar with some time and the right tools and materials.

Anyhow, today is the day I am aiming to do some upper body stuff. The plan is this:

 mobility work in a minute (letting my breakfast digest first!) to get my body ready for training later a big-ass warm-up session before starting my workout a maximum of 5 sets of 4 x pull-ups, 4 x dips and 10 x normal push-ups the 40s burpees (40s burpees, 1 minute rest for 10 rounds) lots of stretching 
If that goes well then I will slowly up the volume over the coming weeks. No more training the same body part on consecutive days either. And no more 100 reps until I am sure I&apos;ve not done any kind of long-term damage to my shoulder (I keep reading things about how soft tissue injuries can take 6 months to heal, and I really hope that I&apos;m being overly cautious and that I&apos;ve not done anything too serious).

Anyhow, hopefully next time I will have good news on how that went :) Thunk Fi at 00:54 1 comments 
 &quot;Women athletes fear pressures over appearance&quot; 
 
 
This is the headline of an article published on the BBC website on Saturday, the sub-heading of which is &quot;Young women are being put off sport by fears that training will make them unattractive&quot;.  It makes me sad to read stuff like this.  

Some soundbites:

 &quot;Girls want to be good at their sport, but on the other hand a question around their femininity is raised because they are considered too muscular.&quot; Some studies have suggested that two in five girls refuse to participate in sport because of concerns about their appearance. &quot;This is not going to be an easy problem to solve as effectively it is about changing culture.&quot;  
It&apos;s this last point that sums it up for me, but that the article stops short of saying. In my opinion (and experience) one of the reasons that some men are not readily accepting of fit muscular females is that it intimidates them - it challenges traditional gender roles, and makes them feel insecure about their own bodies, particularly if theirs in no way rivals that of the females. 
 
 Add to that the  preconceived  ideas that people have about a muscular or fit woman (that we are in some way different to other women - more agressive, feisty, alpha, bossy etc.) then of course women are going to feel self-conscious about allowing their body shape to change as a result of the sport they do. 
 
 There are still so many guys that are unaccepting of things that challenge the old-fashioned way of how (they think) women should behave, that until they start changing their ideas in-line with how things actually are in society now, we will always have to deal with nonsense like this. I just hope that more and more women will have the confidence to get involved in sport, regardless of the changes in their body and how that may affect what people think of them. Thunk Fi at 00:40 1 comments 
 Saturday, 7 July 2012 
 
 Story of a lost ferret 
 
 
 As you may guess from both the title and photo above, this post has absolutely nothing to do with training, or indeed anything interesting. Hopefully, though, this bizarre story will give you a few moments of entertainment, as it did me. 
 I saw the poster above just down the road from my house. There are loads of them up around where we live - a very thorough campaign to find what I consider to be a very &quot;unfavourable&quot; (I&apos;m feeling diplomatic today) animal. I took a photo of it as I was a) going to send it to a friend who used to keep ferrets, thinking he&apos;d find it funny, and b) put it on Flickr with a stupid comment like &quot;haha good luck with that!&quot;. 
 Anyhow, in some sort of weird non-divine retribution for my dislike of ferrets, today I was cycling to a friends house and saw something that didn&apos;t quite look like a cat dart under a car. I got off my bike and stalked this thing, which looked like a ferret but was the size of a small feline, as it ran through the front gardens of about five houses and off into a park at the end of the block. I got my camera out to take a photo, but after glaring at me for a second it disappeared into a bush. 
 I remembered I had the picture above on my phone, so pulled it up and sent a text message to one of the numbers on it, giving the location of said ferret... only to get a reply straightaway saying they&apos;d found &quot;Pixie&quot;! So here I am - wrong about the feasibility of finding an escaped ferret &quot;no bigger than a shoe&quot;, but also now wondering whether the thing that I saw was even a ferret at all. In fact all the ferrets I&apos;ve seen haven&apos;t been much bigger than a rat, and this thing was more like a domestic cat in size (or possibly the shoe of a 7 foot basketball player). Either way, it shall remain a mystery, and teach me not to be so dismissive of the homing instincts of small stinky mammals in future. 
 Thunk Fi at 13:16 0
comments 
 Thursday, 5 July 2012 
 
 Vegan recipe: Poriyal 
 
 
 This recipe is a Tamil dish for cauliflower with mustard seeds and chillies - poriyal . It&apos;s an incredibly simple and very tasty way of using a much under-loved vegetable and is very quick to cook - basically it just involves putting things in a hot pan in the right order (although I suppose you could say that of most recipes). You can eat it with rice, Indian bread or other Indian dishes. I had mine with the dal I posted last time . This is a recipe from Madhur Jaffrey, although there are many variations on the internet. She states that the whole chillies should only be eaten &quot;by those who know what they&apos;re doing&quot; - of course I ate them all ;)

 Ingredients: 

 1 x cauliflower Oil 1/2tsp ground  asafetida (aka. hing) 1tsp black mustard seeds 1 tsp urad (aka. urid) dal 2 whole dried red  chilies 6 whole fresh green  chilies Salt Grated fresh or dessicated coconut (optional) 

 Method :

 Cut the cauliflower into small florets (2cm cubed max) Heat the oil in a wok/frying pan/karhai When hot add asafetida.  A few seconds later add mustard seeds.  When they begin to pop (this will happen within a few seconds) add urad dal.  As soon as this turns red-ish, add the chillies.  When the chillies start to darken, add the cauliflower. Stir-fry for 1 minute, then add salt and some water. Cook, adding water as you need to, till the cauliflower is cooked. If you have a lid you can use it and turn the heat down to low for the last 4 or so minutes. You can add the coconut at the end. I usually toast some desiccated coconut and mix it in before serving. You could also add coriander to garnish, if you have some. 

 Thunk Fi at 00:59 1 comments 
 Tuesday, 3 July 2012 
 
 Little update 
 Some cool things have been happening in the past few weeks... The seminars  were a massive inspiration and helped cement both short and longer term goals for me. I&apos;ve made some modifications to my training, which I&apos;ll touch on below.

I&apos;ve frozen, with a view to cancelling, my gym membership until the end of September, which will give me three solid months to focus fully on bar calisthenics, and hopefully the best of the Summer (which is yet to come *crosses fingers*).

I&apos;ve been asked to write for Boxrox, who sponsored the Bar-barian seminars, and am just in the process of putting together my first post for them. Martin (who runs it) and I met for the first time at the seminars, but he remembered me because when I emailed to sign up I teasingly took the piss out of the Crossfit style of pull-up . (Just. Can&apos;t. Resist). Luckily he knew I was kidding :) Anyhow, I will link to the first post when it&apos;s up.

In other blog-related news, I am really excited to have persuaded, albeit without any real persuasion at all, someone to do a guest post for gai.ninja. It will touch on bodyweight training and cross over to another style of strength and conditioning training. That&apos;s all I&apos;m gonna say for now!

I&apos;ve got some goals to achieve in my training: to get my pull-up endurance up and do a muscle up being the main ones, as well as work on some more static holds and stuff like &quot; skin the cat &quot;. I hit upon a plan to get my endurance up, which involved doing 100 reps. So workouts involved doing, say, 20 sets of 5 pull-ups and 10 diamond push-ups, or 10 sets of 10 straight bar dips, 10 regular dips and 10 jumping muscle ups. However... I seem to have done something to my arm... I rested from Saturday to yesterday (Monday), but training last night has just aggravated it again, so I guess I&apos;m on running, burpees and pistol squats for a few days. Kind of annoying as I&apos;ve been making good progress recently, but patience is a virtue blah blah blah :)

I have achieved two mini goals, though - L-sit chin-ups (sets of 3) and on Saturday when I should&apos;ve been resting I accidentally did an L-sit pull-up, which was pretty cool. Anyhow, hopefully will be able to get back to normal training by the end of the week.

 
As well as the new shoes , I&apos;ve bought something else cool: a Stick . It is a myofascial muscle roller, like those foam rollers they have at the gym but hopefully more flexible in how it can be used. It was a toss up between The Stick and The Grid roller, but I don&apos;t have a lot of floor space for that here, and also the prospect of using The Stick to get my upper back and shoulders is pretty appealing right now. I have a lot of crunchy knots that really need to be banished! Hopefully it&apos;ll arrive before the weekend.

 Thunk Fi at 02:39 3
comments 
 Saturday, 30 June 2012 
 
 Review: Vibram shoes 
 
 
 Vibram shoes have a polarising effect... Going upon recent evidence, around two thirds of you will have looked at this photo and thought anything from &quot;WTF!&quot; through &quot;those are fucking hideous&quot; to &quot;they look like the feet of Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles&quot;. The other third is likely jealous, although it&apos;s possible I am overstating the percentages a tad ;) 
 Long-time blog readers will know that I&apos;m a big fan of weird split-toe shoes, owning three pairs of Nike Rift (I still have this pair , currently on the floor beside me) and two pairs of Japanese tabi boots, my favourite of which are these badass silver and gold ones . It was only inevitable I should get a pair of Vibrams - they fit the bill of being both sporty and strange right down to a T.  
 They happened to have some on display in Lillywhites  in my size... I tried them on and holy shit did they feel good! As a martial artist I&apos;m used to being in bare feet and now find it much more comfortable - I can feel what I&apos;m doing, balance properly and just feel connected with the ground. And the rubber sole was so sticky I felt like I could run up the walls like a lizard :) 
 
 A  few days later, after some intensive Googling, a pair arrived  on my desk. One of the various benefits of being half-Dutch is that I am excellent at getting bargains (it&apos;s true what they say!), and as a result only paid£42 for these. I had forgotten that I also had a£12 gift card left in my account too, so only ended up paying£28. Massive, massive result! They are normally around£100, but have a look around and you should be able to get them a lot cheaper. 
 Anyhow, I&apos;ve had them about three weeks now and have been using them for all my day-to-day walking, mostly to and from the office and to the gym/park/shops. Nothing heavy. They were quite tight at first, especially around my big toes (fat), but have now perfectly formed to my feet. They don&apos;t move at all, and the strap at the top (which comes across the achilles) keeps them comfortably snug. 
 
 The first few weeks (and to some degree now) I was very conscious about heel-striking, since I had come straight from trainers designed for over-pronators (Asics 2160&apos;s, IIRC) which are very padded and also have quite a lift between toe and heel. Also I could feel my feet, and especially my calves, having to work harder, I assume as a result of the greater flexation of the forefoot. 
 Yesterday I went for my first run in them (only on the treadmill) - 1km @ 10.5km/h then 200m of walking for three rounds. I didn&apos;t want to hit 3km in one go so thought it best to break it up. The run felt great - feet were ok (went for a slow pace so they weren&apos;t getting pounded) and calves didn&apos;t cramp up. I put the Vibrams on to go out in today, but my feet felt slightly stiff so went with some other shoes instead. I plan to work up to doing longer runs on the common outside by the end of the summer, so I&apos;m really happy with this first step. 
 As well as comfort, balance and &quot;earth-connection&quot;, the other great thing about these shoes is seeing peoples reactions. Kids love them - apart from riding my bike with no hands, it is the only thing I can do which stops them in their tracks and makes their little mouths hang open :) The reactions from adults vary, but mostly involve either double-takes, staring, or both. I did walk past a guy who also had some on, and we grinned at each other, safe in the knowledge of our superior footwear ;)

---

Further reading:

-  Vibram FiveFingers website 
- Very in-depth article in NY Mag  about why shoes are bad for you
- Complete nonsense in the Telegraph about them being a fashion trend (fashionable?! Ha!)

 Thunk Fi at 15:54 2
comments 
 Friday, 29 June 2012 
 
 Diets: Low carb vs. Low fat vs. Low GI 
 
 
 Back is March I did a post called &quot; Sugar is evil &quot;, looking at why sugar is  so bad, about GI and how to make food choices to keep your insulin levels stable. I&apos;ve just been reading about some research which has just been published in the Journal of the American Medical Association which supports the notion that low glycemic index diets are the way forward. Fr om an article in the   NY Times : 

 The study put three groups of people on diets to lose 10 to 15 percent of their body weight. T hey assigned each of the dieters, in random order, to follow four weeks each of three diets with the same number of calories. One was a standard low-fat diet: 60 percent carbohydrates - with an emphasis on fruits, vegetables and whole grains (but not unprocessed ones) - 20 percent from protein and 20 percent from fat. This is the low-fat diet that has been reigning“wisdom”for the last 30 years or more.   

Another was an ultra-low-carb diet, of 10 percent of calories from carbs, 60 percent from fat and 30 percent from protein. And the third was a low glycemic diet, with 40 percent carbs—minimally processed grains, fruit, vegetables and legumes—40 percent fat and 20 percent protein.   

The results were impressive. Those on the ultra-low carb diet burned 350 calories more per day - the equivalent of an hour of moderate exercise - than those on the standard low-fat diet. Those on the low-glycemic diet burned 150 calories more, roughly equivalent to an hour of light exercise. You can read a bit more on the Science Daily site .

Protein is believed in some camps that the 4kcal/g calorie count it has been allocated is actually too high, because it doesn&apos;t account for the higher amount of energy which is expended as it&apos;s digested, which may account for such a dramatic increase in calorie burn (I can&apos;t find the links for this right now - will add them later).  It is also the most  satiating  of the macronutrients, dulling hunger due in part to the fact that it doesn&apos;t spike insulin and elevates leptin, the hormone that controls hunger (as opposed to carbohydrates that do the opposite). You can read more on this on Charles Poliquin&apos;s blog . 

The reason that the article concludes to favour low GI diets is because very high-protein diets can trigger release of the stress hormone cortisol. There are obviously other potentially negative effects, such as the consumption of a relatively high amount of saturated fat (I bet I&apos;m not alone in having heard Atkin&apos;s freaks banging on about how much bacon they eat!). The article concludes, and I pretty much agree, that unprocessed and unrefined carbs are worth adding for a more moderate yet still improved calorie burn.

Personally I follow quite a high protein diet - I shoot for 0.75 - 1g of protein per pound of bodyweight (I&apos;ll let you take a guess and do the maths ;) which I think is a decent level for someone who does a lot of strength training. I get the most volume of carbs during the day from fruit and vegetables, but include a heavy serving of carbs, mainly sweets potatoes at the moment - yum - in my post-workout meal. Obviously this is going to be different on my vegan days (next one tomorrow).

Finally, I will leve you with a link to a blog post about &quot;Hybrid diets&quot; , which is just a guy talking about how he&apos;s combined elements from different diets to create something that works for him. After all, along with keeping calories in check and insulin stable, that is one of the single most important factors in choosing how you eat (and, for that matter, how you exercise, work, live etc.!) Thunk Fi at 04:07 2
comments Older Posts Home Subscribe to: Posts (Atom) 
About Me
 Fi London, United Kingdom The majority of this blog was written in Japan, where I lived for two years, doing too much karate, spending too much time with small children and never quite managing to eat too much sushi.

I got back at the end of 2010 and am based back in south London. I still kick and punch stuff when I can, and at the start of 2012 started getting into bodyweight exercises more. Now all my strength training is bar calisthenics, supplemented with running, burpees and kickboxing. View my complete profile 
Search
 Loading... 
Subscribe by email
 
Your email address:
 
 
 

 
Blog Archive
 
 ▼  2012 (37) 
 July (5) 

 June (13) 

 May (1) 

 April (4) 

 March (12) 

 February (2) 
 

 ►  2011 (16) 
 August (1) 

 July (3) 

 May (1) 

 April (5) 

 March (6) 
 

 ►  2010 (121) 
 December (1) 

 October (3) 

 September (3) 

 August (20) 

 July (10) 

 June (9) 

 May (9) 

 April (26) 

 March (18) 

 February (9) 

 January (13) 
 

 ►  2009 (281) 
 December (10) 

 November (16) 

 October (20) 

 September (24) 

 August (19) 

 July (35) 

 June (26) 

 May (28) 

 April (22) 

 March (24) 

 February (29) 

 January (28) 
 

 ►  2008 (132) 
 December (42) 

 November (54) 

 October (35) 

 September (1) 
 
 
Friends&apos; blogs
 
 Alternate Currency Altogether Elsewhere Carl&apos;s twisted tales of life and love in Japan Despoiler Dylan&apos;s Teeth glitter Lawrence&apos;s Tales Of Adventure... Living Dangerously in the Middle of Nowhere lizzie : lightbox Mysdirection Netninja Olli&apos;s Blog Paul Carr: True Confessions of a New Media Whore Quid Fo&apos; Sho Vex Appeal White Man in Japan YO, CEO 
 
Karate/Martial Arts blogs
 
 Japan Karate Internship Karate Thoughts Blog Martial Views Memoirs of a Grasshopper Okinawa Karate&amp;Kobudo Blog 
 
Japan blogs
 
 Japan | guardian.co.uk Japan Probe Tokyo Times dannychoo.com 世論 What Japan Thinks Gaijin Tonic Japundit - Published news
	</body>
</document>
