<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000117" url="http://customercarecontacts.com/contact-kfc-phone-of-kfc-home-delivery-in-us/" time="2012-07-12-15:18" support="2" score="0.002136028370075182" bingtitle="Contact KFC: Phone of KFC home delivery in US | Customer Care Contacts" webtitle="Contact KFC: Phone of KFC home delivery in US | Customer Care Contacts">
			<query id="000927" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000549" bing-rank="192"/>
	<description>KFC Store Locator To locate a KFC store nearest to ... The fast food restaurant had revenue of over $11 billion in 2008. ... book order on line and make payment through Credit Card ...</description>
	<body>
		Home About Browse Search 
 
Contact KFC: Phone of KFC home delivery in US

 August 9, 2011 customer help Restaurant , 1 

 VN:F [1.9.18_1163] RATE THIS COMPANY/ SERVICE please wait... Rating: 0.0/ 10 (0 votes cast) 
 Contact KFC : Find below customer service details of KFC in US , including phone and address. You can reach the below contact for KFC home delivery, gift cards, vouchers/coupons, gift certificates, menu, KFC stores or other queries. Besides contact details the page also offers information and links on KFC services.

 KFC Head Office 
1441 Gardiner Ln.
Louisville, KY 40213
United States
Phone: (502)874-8300
 
 KFC Customer Service Phone 
U.S.–1-800-225-5532
Canada–1-866-664-5696

 Customer Comments (Address) 
KFC, P.O. Box 725489
Atlanta, GA 31139

 KFC Gift Cards (Phone) 
1-800-544-5774 ext.8360 ext.326

 KFC Local Stores 

 New York 
(212) 630-0315
(212) 681-8501
(212) 665-9430
(212) 767-8347
(212) 563-7440

 Los Angeles 
(213) 623-1645
(213) 483-9412
(323) 581-4395
(213) 483-8917
(323) 753-1375

 San Francisco 
(415) 673-2641
(415) 346-0050
(415) 931-1433
(415) 334-8318
(415) 731-3314

 Washington 
(202) 319-8688
(202) 526-8563
(703) 271-8021
(202) 479-0528

 San Diego 
(619) 696-1454
(619) 297-0534
(619) 284-3975
(858) 274-4049
(858) 492-9153

 Dallas 
(214) 824-2199
(972) 479-9900
(972) 680-7870
(214) 388-4415
(214) 319-9296

 Atlanta 
(404) 888-9977
(678) 705-4293
(404) 658-1532
(404) 767-8158
(404) 691-7455

 Honolulu 
(808) 949-2855
(808) 941-7411
(808) 951-1488
(808) 922-4023
(808) 422-1312 Boston 
(617) 254-2481
(617) 288-2140
(617) 524-1010
(617) 327-2208 

 Chicago 
(312) 322-0011
(312) 733-3469
(312) 328-0541
(773) 363-0307
(773) 772-0833
(773) 363-0307

 Houston 
(713) 522-0970
(713) 748-8235
(713) 785-5755
(713) 862-0289
(713) 734-8066

 Philadelphia 
(215) 629-4956
(215) 465-8194
(215) 225-5553
(215) 476-7339
(215) 739-1717

 Phoenix 
(602) 955-5263
(602) 955-7006
(602) 433-0664
(602) 944-6828
(480) 706-0717

 Oklahoma City 
(405) 525-7580
(405) 943-6004
(405) 302-0488
(405) 787-7481
(405) 842-0076

 Denver 
(303) 777-5416
(303) 629-9811
(303) 399-7603
(303) 755-1196

 Miami 
(305) 633-0603
(305) 642-6169
(305) 633-8397
(305) 685-7608 

&gt;For more KFC locations across US click here
________

 KFC Menu 
To view the complete list of KFC menu click here . Besides KFC chicken, the menu includes chicken strips, boneless wings, sandwiches, desserts and sides.

 KFC Store Locator 
To locate a KFC store nearest to your address click here 

 KFC Coupons 
To register KFC coupons online click here 

 KFC Gift Checks 
To order KFC gift checks online click here 

 About KFC 
 Kentucky Fried Chicken (KFC) was founded by Harland Sanders in the US. The KFC original recipe, made with secret blend of 11 herbs and spices, took birth in the year 1940. KFC is today world’s largest chicken restaurant chain. In fact each day more than 12 million customers are served at KFC restaurants in 109 countries. KFC runs more than 5,200 restaurants in the United States and more than 15,000 units around the world. KFC is part of Yum! Brands, Inc. KFC is headquartered in Louisville, Kentucky, and employs over 30,000 people around the world.  KFC  is ranked #239 on the Fortune 500 List. The fast food restaurant had revenue of over $11 billion in 2008.

 contact kfc , kfc chicken phone , kfc usa 


 
One Response to“Contact KFC: Phone of KFC home delivery in US”

 sarfaraz says: April 5, 2012 at 6:56 am 
I want to send KFC–Family Bucket to my daughter in New Orleans USA but I am in Saudi Arabia. How can I book order on line and make payment through Credit Card. pl Guide.
 Reply 


 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 
 
Quick Search
 
Links
 
About Us
 Customer Care Contacts is your online source for phone, address, email and website of companies and services providers. To view latest posts click here 
Like Us
 
 
Copyright©2012 Customer Care Contacts. All Rights Reserved.   Privacy Policy | Terms&amp;Conditions | Contact Us 

Disclaimer: Customer Care Contacts has made reasonable efforts to ensure the accuracy of the contact listings of companies and service providers. We do not accept responsibility for any errors or omissions in the details listed, including the phone, address&amp;website.
	</body>
</document>
