<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000613" url="http://www.takethisfatandshoveit.com/category/diet-friendly-foods/tasty-snacks/" time="2012-07-12-15:54" support="1" score="0.0014766030516573027" bingtitle="Tasty Snacks — Lose Weight Naturally - How To Lose Weight And ..." webtitle="Tasty Snacks — Lose Weight Naturally - How To Lose Weight And Keep It Off">
			<query id="001247" bing-rank="216"/>
	<description>... forcing you to pull into the nearest fast food restaurant for a ... banish the “growlie monsters” without throwing ... out a measly 10 for a snack – an entire container ...</description>
	<body>
		Lose Weight Naturally - How To Lose Weight And Keep It Off 

How To Lose Belly Fat And Other Unwanted Pounds
 
Our #1 Weight Loss Recommended Product–Clinically Proven Effective
 
 Home About Blog 
 
 Diet Friendly Foods 
 Cooking Tips Diet Friendly Recipes Food Finds Tasty Snacks Worst Light Foods 
 Fitness Healthy Eating My Weight Loss Journal 
 Acupuncture Diary Coffee Shop Musings Non Food Rewards Off Topic Stuff The Fat Girl Diaries Weight Watchers 
 Weight Loss 
 Lose Weight Naturally 
 Featured Weight Loss Plateaus 
 Weight Loss Articles Weight Loss Motivational Quote Weight Loss News Weight Loss Tip of the Day Weight Loss Tips 
 
 You are here: Home / Archives for Diet Friendly Foods / Tasty Snacks 
 4 Indulgences That Are Healthy For You 
 April 27, 2012 By dorrie Leave a Comment 
With summer coming up, I and everyone I know, are thinking ahead to bathing suit season.  Time to work off the winter weight! And while I dust off the running shoes, clean out the cupboards and stock up on greens and proteins, already my cravings kick in.  What about my sweet tooth? And my utter addiction to chips? Already I’ve almost talked myself out of getting in shape.

Like most things in life, I believe you need balance.  Luckily there are several things you can treat yourself too that have many health benefits if eaten in moderation.  Below are some of my favorites.

 Chocolate 

 
 

I was a late bloomer when it came to chocolate. It wasn’t until I was 25 that the cravings hit.  Now I can’t get enough of the stuff.  And wasn’t I happy to find out it’s actually good for you! It’s loaded with antioxidants(good for your heart), seratonin (mood booster) and it stimulates endorphin production (feeling of pleasure).  Dark chocolate is best.  I like to cut up 1 dark chocolate bar and mix it with walnuts to have on hand when I get a sugar attack.

 Red Wine 

 
 

After a long stressful day, there isn’t anything more relaxing than a glass of wine.  Luckily wine, like chocolate, is loaded with antioxidants.  Also, red wine has been shown to contain melatonin.  Melatonin is a natural sleep aid, helping people who drink a glass at night, sleep better. And thanks to a compound found in red wine called resveratrol, it has been shown to reduce Alzheimer’s and dementia.  Moderation of course is key, but it feels not to feel so guilty having a glass now and then.

 Tacos 

 
 

Yes, that’s right, tacos.  Probably my most favorite food on the planet.  Recently I did a cleanse and found that I could still have them.  If you use white corn shells you’ll avoid the gluten. (Or butter lettuce makes a nice alternative for the shell).  Use chicken as your meat.  Marinated in olive oil, orange juice, lime juice, jalepenos, garlic and sea salt makes it very tasty.  Top it with avocados instead of cheese and sour cream.  The avocados are super creamy so you won’t miss the dairy.  And sprinkle some diced onions and tomatoes and you have a delicious dinner that is full of nutrients.

 Hummus and Brown Rice Crackers 

 
 

If you’re like me, you need a crunch to your food.  Eating nothing but soft vegetables and fruit leaves me very unsatisfied.  Hummus is an incredibly healthy dip and it taste fantastic. (My favorite is the roasted pine nut.)  Carrots are also good dipped in hummus. But I really love crackers.  The toasted brown rice crackers are gluten and dairy free.  And they’re really filling.

These are only a few examples but being able to eat and drink these things, if only every so often, makes dieting a whole lot easier.  Life’s too short not to enjoy the finer things.

Lisa is a content writer for a Downtown Seattle Chiropractor .
 Filed Under: Tasty Snacks Tagged With: chocolate , eating healthy , food , health and wellness , healthy indulgences , tasty , wine 
 9 Healthy Snacks For When Cravings Strike–Stick To Your Diet 
 October 15, 2010 By dorrie Leave a Comment 
 9 Healthy Snacks For Those Times When Cravings Strike 

We all have those times when the “growlie monster” in our stomach says “feed me and feed me now!”  It doesn’t care that you only ate lunch an hour ago or that you’re not having your next meal for several hours.

Or even worse than the “growlie monster” is the devil child itself – cravings.  It’s when your mind is screaming at you to eat a bag of salt&amp;black pepper potato chips, dig into a pint of yummy Ben&amp;Jerry’s, find that bag of Kit Kat’s you’ve hidden in the back of the pantry, or is practically forcing you to pull into the nearest fast food restaurant for a burger&amp;fries (never the side salad with light dressing)!  But you know you don’t want to do that because you’re trying hard to eat healthier and lose weight.

Yes, I know we’re only supposed to eat when we are truly hungry and that cravings may or may not mean “I’m hungry.” But, tell that to my body when I’m in “full-on” craving mode.  Sure, drinking a glass of water helps – for the 15 seconds it takes to drink it.  Taking a walk helps, but a 3 hour walk until my next meal isn’t going to happen.  Taking my mind off cravings by keeping my hands busy with something else….well that seemed like a good idea until I took a knitting class where bringing in snacks was encouraged.  Who says you can’t knit and eat at the same time?

Instead I’ve come up with nine favorite “go to” snacks that are healthy and filling, and most importantly, calm my cravings and banish the “growlie monsters” without throwing my calorie consumption into a tailspin:

 Mary’s Gone Crackers Sea Salt Sticks&amp;Twigs With Laughing Cow Light French Onion Cheese for dipping (150 calories for one serving of “Sticks&amp;Twigs;” 35 calories for a wedge of Light Cow Light Cheese) – TOTAL CALORIES: 185 

 Salsa With Blue Corn Tortilla Chips (140 calories for a serving of Kettle brand Blue Corn TortillaChips; 30 calories in ¼ cup of Tostitos medium salsa) – TOTAL CALORIES: 170 

 100 calorie pack Emerald dry roasted almonds (handy to keep stashed in a desk drawer, purse, or in your car to keep the “monster munchies” at bay) – TOTAL CALORIES: 100 

 Grape tomatoes (forget about counting out a measly 10 for a snack – an entire container is less than 100 calories!) – TOTAL CALORIES: 90 

 StarKist Tuna Salad Lunch To Go Kit (the package says it’s a lunch item but at 200 calories for the entire kit it’s more like a snack than lunch to me because there has yet come a day where I can eat a 200 calorie lunch and still not be screaming hungry) – TOTAL CALORIES: 200 

 Single serve bag of 100 calorie popcorn sprinkled with 1 or 2 teaspoons parmesan cheese (about 8 calories per teaspoon) – TOTAL CALORIES: 116 

 Sliced apple sprinkled with 1 teaspoon sugar and a liberal dusting of cinnamon (95 calories for a medium apple, 16 calories in a teaspoon of sugar, 0 calories for the cinnamon) – TOTAL CALORIES: 111 

 Baby carrots with red pepper hummus (about 60 calories for 15 baby carrots; 80 calories for 2 tablespoons Athenos Red Pepper Hummus)  - TOTAL CALORIES: 140 

 String cheese dipped in cocktail sauce (don’t knock it until you’ve tried it – it’s really good!)  (about 80 calories in 1 stick of regular and about 60 calories in 1 stick of light string cheese; about 15 calories in a tablespoon of shrimp cocktail sauce) – TOTAL CALORIES: 95 
 Filed Under: Diet Friendly Foods , Healthy Eating , Tasty Snacks Tagged With: health snacks , healthy snacks when dieting , low calorie treats , stick to your diet , what to eat when your hungry 
 Special K Fruit Crisps Review 
 March 8, 2010 By dorrie Leave a Comment 
 Special K has added to their arsenal of products with strawberry and blueberry fruit crisps.
 

They are shaped like a cereal bar but have a crispy outer shell and fruity filling that is similar to the Pop tarts I loved as a kid.

On the plus side:
- each foil wrapped packet of 2 crisps is 100 calories–an okay calorie count for a snack or for a light dessert
- there’s no high fructose corn syrup in them (I personally think high fructose corn syrup is horribly bad for us)
- they’re an easy-to-eat“on the go”snack
- the filling is tasty and there’s a decent amount of it

On the minus side:
- while the filling tastes good, the crispy outer shell is kind of bland
- they are not filling (less than 1 gram of fiber and only 1 gram of protein in each serving) so I don’t recommend eating them if you’re really hungry.
- there’s not much nutritional value in them (the aforementioned pitiful 1 gram of protein per serving and only 2 percent of the recommended daily allowance of iron)
 
 
They come in two flavors:
	</body>
</document>
