<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000863" url="http://www.weichert.com/26207203/" time="2012-07-12-16:13" support="1" score="0.0001170652156190242" bingtitle="1711 KENOSHA Road, Zion IL 60099, MLS #07253054, Weichert.com" webtitle="1711 KENOSHA Road,  Zion IL 60099, MLS #07253054, Weichert.com">
			<query id="000743" bing-rank="250"/>
	<description>Great location for a fast food restaurant in a new growth path. Increasing traffic counts.. ... Weichert will help you find a property by location, MLS listing number, or ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign in | Sign up Welcome back !
 Click here to logout. 0 open houses 1-800-872-7653 
 Buying Selling Open Houses Mortgage Associates/Offices myWeichert Careers 
 Enter a Street Address, City&amp;State, Zip, or MLS Number 
Commercial Property for Sale in Zion, IL
 Find similar listings in Zion, IL The property you are searching for is no longer an active listing. 
1711 KENOSHA Road, Zion, IL
 $975,000 MLS #/Web ID: 07253054 What others say this house is worth: Zestimate® Eppraisal Find listings near 1711 KENOSHA Road Want to know what your home, or any home, is actually worth? 
Fill out this form or call 1-800-872-7653 to speak with one of our Area Experts.
 First Name Required Last Name Required Phone ( ) - Ext: Phone number is not correct. 
 Just Listed Zion, IL 
 4008 HILL Drive $185,000 Single Family 4 Beds | 2 Baths Courtesy of SELECT A FEE RE SYSTEM   10800 17th Street $169,900 Lots and Land 0 Bath Courtesy of MAIBETH RAPER REAL ESTATE   907 PHEASANT RUN $167,900 Single Family 3 Beds | 2 Baths Courtesy of GOLDEN ARROW REALTY INC.   3310 GILBOA Avenue $158,000 Single Family 5 Beds | 2 Baths Courtesy of COLDWELL BANKER RESIDENTIAL   View more listings in Zion, IL (01) Each WEICHERT® franchised office is independently owned and operated.  ©2012
 Weichert, Realtors. All rights reserved. 1-800-872-7653 Help us improve - take our survey . Legal Disclaimers | Terms of Use | Privacy Statement | Site Map | Browse Listings | Contact Us | About Us Join us on: 
 The data relating to real estate for sale on this website comes in part from the Broker Reciprocity program of Midwest Real Estate Data LLC. Real Estate listings held by brokerage firms other than Weichert Realtors are marked with the Broker Reciprocity logo or the Broker Reciprocity thumbnail logo (a little black house) and detailed information about them includes the names of the listing brokers. Some properties which appear for sale on this website may subsequently have sold and may no longer be available. The information being provided is for consumers&apos; personal, non-commercial use and may not be used for any purpose other than to identify prospective properties consumers may be interested in purchasing.

Copyright © 2012 Midwest Real Estate Data LLC.

Data is updated as of 7/12/2012.
	</body>
</document>
