<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000188" url="http://gaykohsamui.net/food.html" time="2012-07-12-15:22" support="18" score="0.04037786306192232" bingtitle="Samui Food" webtitle="eating on samui">
			<query id="000054" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="000616" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000553" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000116" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000366" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000459" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="001496" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="001119" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="001465" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="001527" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="000899" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000053" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000460" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="001129" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="000962" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="000710" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="001151" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000868" bing-rank="16"/>
	<description>Food Glorious Food : At first glance of any eating guide for Samui you may wonder ... food, Norwegian Reindeer Pate, Tandoori Chicken, and English Roasts, if your cup of ...</description>
	<body>
		Tropical Fruits 

 
Bananas, pineapples, papaya, watermelon and coconut (a Samui icon) are delciously available the year out. But some other treats are only available in season. Most of the fruits listed below are in season and at their best April - June. These wonders of the tropics are worth trying - so put back the expensive imported apples, plums and peaches. Go local! 

 • mangosteen • lychee • rambutan • langsart • guava • snakefruit • pomelo • durian • coconut • dragonfruit • rose apple • jackfruit • 
 
 Southern Thai Specialities 
 
 The coconut, which grows throughout the region, appears in many southern dishes which is fortunate as it mitigates the ferocious chillis in Southern food. Seafood is used in abundance. Shrimp paste is a favourite and adds a distinctive pungent flavour to local dishes. The Muslim influence in the region adds another disctinctive aspect. Islam came with Indian migrants and with them came Indian style flavours and dishes. Tumeric a staple in curry powder appears frequently in the south but is used in fresh rather than dried form. Roti + Mussuman curry a two popular dishes with an Indian heritage served in the South. For a good introduction to Southern Thai food check this website. 
 Self Cater 
 
Planning on renting a house and cooking for yourselves? Good on you! You can buy whatever you need on Samui - though imported (luxury) items such as cheese + wine incur huge taxes
and duties making them rather pricey. Here are some places to shop:
•Dow + Laemdin Local Markets - seafood, vegetables, fruits, sweets, Thai snacks and all manner of things.
•Tesco Lotus, Big C, Tops + Makro Supermarkets
•Wine Connection + Central Wine Cellar
•Colibri Foods - wholesale and retails for European foods and deli items.
Check the online &apos;Samui Directory&apos; for details of these suppliers + more. 
 
 front lobby» gay koh samui» holiday planner» 
 
 new samui» food on samui» festivals» to see&amp;do» thai customs» 
 
 the gay island» night-life» accommodation» massage» make friends» 
 
 getting here» around&amp;about» money stuff» body&amp;soul» the weather» safety&amp;comms» 
 
 start to plan» your holiday» right here&amp;now» 
 
 
Samui Food

There is a huge variety of places to eat around Samui - restaurants, roadside stalls, marketplaces, and vendors who come to your door no less! No worry about ever going hungry where ever you find yourself on the island. The range of food types is also huge - of course there is the full gamut of Thai but you can also enjoy Italian, Japanese, Indian, Vietnamese, Nepalese, and French,... the list goes on. Being an island seafood is a popular choice with fish boat + barbeque restaurants lining the main shopping streets. Bon Apetit!
 bbbb 
 Food Glorious Food     
At first glance of any eating guide for Samui you may wonder where the Thai food is - but don&apos;t fear great Thai food - from cheap market stalls to restaurants on the beach to Royal Thai food offered in luxurious five star hotel settings - is readily available. Fast Food Chains, Pizzas, Sushi, Vegetarian food, Norwegian Reindeer Pate, Tandoori Chicken, and English Roasts, if your cup of tea, are all available on Samui plus much more. The Samui Dining Guide provides (wordy) narratives on the more upmarket and tourist restaurants. The best guide you can pick up after arriving at the airport or your hotel - it is called &quot;Eating on Samui&quot; .

Try the local cuisine to feel as if you really are somewhere different. Thai cuisine is rich in variety and totally its own - it is tangy and spicy and belongs to the landscape and climate. Creamy pasta sauces will not help you cope with the tropical heat - a fresh spicy Thai salad works a treat. Take the risk - give it a go. If you order a dish which is traditionally served very spicy the wait staff will ask you how spicy you want it - but don&apos;t be offended they will ask local guests as well.

In the markets you will find fresh and whole foods, glorious tropical and Thai fruits and small food vendors selling a range of Thai snacks. Snacking is an important part of the Thai eating day - try it and see why it is so popular. Some of the best tastes and smells come from snack stalls (often mobile) - BBQ bananas, noodle dishes, green mango salad, pancakes savoury and sweet, and satay to name a few.
   Some Recommended Eateries
	</body>
</document>
