<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000054" url="http://www.recentnigerianjobs.com/2012/02/african-institute-for-applied-economics.html" time="2012-07-12-15:14" support="2" score="0.0019286759581073978" bingtitle="African Institute for Applied Economics (AIAE) recruitment ..." webtitle="African Institute for Applied Economics (AIAE) recruitment, February 2012">
			<query id="001385" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="001201" bing-rank="233"/>
	<description>Cashier Jobs (5) Cleric Jobs (5) Computer Jobs (51) ... Fast Food/Restaurant Jobs (5) GCE/SSCE Jobs (7) Government Jobs (60) ... Deadline for receipt of applications is three weeks ...</description>
	<body>
		skip to main | skip to sidebar 
 Recent Nigerian Jobs 
 
 The fastest growing Job Site in Nigeria today, keeping you updated with the latest job vacancies in Nigeria! 
 
 Home Contact us Privacy Policy Our Lounge 
 For Latest Job Updates 
Follow Me on Pinterest
 
 
Subscribe via RSS
 
Job Archive
 
 July 2012 (71) June 2012 (168) May 2012 (200) April 2012 (222) March 2012 (247) February 2012 (224) January 2012 (184) December 2011 (144) November 2011 (149) October 2011 (116) September 2011 (102) August 2011 (99) 
 
Job Categories
 
 Abuja Jobs (191) Accounting Jobs (242) Administrative Jobs (147) Agricultural Jobs (10) Architectural Jobs (19) Artist Jobs (3) Auditing Jobs (53) Aviation Jobs (24) Awards (4) Banking Jobs (55) Building and Construction Jobs (20) Bursary Jobs (3) Business and Finance Jobs (62) Career Advice and Self Help (6) Career Humor (2) Cargo/Courier Jobs (4) Cashier Jobs (6) Cleric Jobs (8) Computer Jobs (83) Consultancy Jobs (9) Customer Care Jobs (31) Dispatch rider Jobs (1) Driving Jobs (75) Education and Training (90) Engineering Jobs (290) Entertainment (8) Estate Surveying Jobs (15) Fast Food/Restaurant Jobs (8) GCE/SSCE Jobs (12) Government Jobs (83) Graduate Trainee (96) Guardian Newspaper Jobs (11) Gym Jobs (1) Health Jobs (71) Hotel Jobs (32) HSE Jobs (16) Human Resource Jobs (60) Industrial Jobs (82) Insurance Jobs (27) International Jobs (63) Internship (6) Interviews and Results (7) IT and Telecoms Jobs (185) Lagos Jobs (538) Lecturing Jobs (15) Legal Jobs (32) Logistics Jobs (32) Lounge (19) Managerial Jobs (363) Manufacturing Jobs (57) Maritime Jobs (11) Marketing Jobs (192) Media and Publishing Jobs (29) Medical Jobs (75) Multinational Jobs (20) News (1) NGO Jobs (170) Nursing Jobs (24) NYSC (2) O level Jobs (4) Oil and Gas Jobs (154) OND/HND/BSC Jobs (88) OnShore/OffShore Jobs (3) oth (1) Other Jobs (116) Pharmaceutical Jobs (48) por (1) Port Harcourt Jobs (116) Punch Newspaper Jobs (6) Quantity Surveying Jobs (13) Real Estate Jobs (20) Receptionist (15) Religion Jobs (2) Sales Jobs (208) Scholarships (31) Secretarial Jobs (89) Security Jobs (33) Sports Jobs (1) Teaching Jobs (57) Veterinary Jobs (1) 
 
 African Institute for Applied Economics (AIAE) recruitment, February 2012 
 on Thursday, 9 February 2012 Labels: Administrative Jobs , International Jobs African Institute for Applied Economics (AIAE) recruitment, February 2012 
African Institute for Applied Economics (AIAE) is one of Africa’s leading independent economic research institutions and policy think tanks . Incorporated in 2000, the Institute seeks to promote evidence-based policy making in Africa through applied economic research, policy facilitation, capacity building and networking.
 We require a suitable individual to take up the position of Executive Director for a term of six years beginning from end of May 2012. Reporting to the Board of Directors, the Executive Director is the Chief Executive Officer of the Institute, its Legal Representative and Chief Spokesperson.

 
 JOB TITLE: Executive Director
 ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES: 
Provides leadership in directing the research programme of the Institute.
Provides leadership in organizing national and international research–policy networks.
Oversees planning and implementation of fund-raising.
Responsible for overall administration and financial management .
Develops and manages research and research-based programmes.
Develops and implements plans and programmes for the communication and dissemination of research to policymakers and stakeholders.

 QUALIFICATION AND EXPERIENCE: 
The candidate should have a minimum of a Masters Degree in Economics or related disciplines and minimum of 10 years of relevant leadership and research management experience. Experience and exposure in policy making, international institutions/networks or policy think tanks will be an advantage.

 CAPACITIES AND QUALITIES: The candidate for Executive Director (who should not be above 65 years of age) should have:
Capacity to motivate, administer and manage research and administrative staff by creating a conducive working environment.
Outstanding capability for institutional fund-raising for research, training, research-based policy networks.
Excellent leadership abilities, research team and people management skills.
Ability to conceptualise, develop and manage national and international research.
High intellectual capacity and analytical skills.
Track record of research publications.
Excellent report writing, communication and interpersonal skills.
Capacity to create and sustain partnerships, collaborations and work well with stakeholders.


Terms and Conditions of Service are competitive and negotiable.

 HOW TO APPLY 
Interested candidates should submit applications to executivedirector3@rocketmail.com as follows: A letter of application stating the motivation for applying and the major strengths the candidate hopes to bring to the Institute; A detailed Curriculum Vitae indicating also the names and contact addresses/phone numbers of three possible referees.

Deadline for receipt of applications is three weeks from the date of this announcement
 Someone might need this,why not share or tweet it! 
 Tweet 

 Subscribe To Us Via Email and always be the first to know about the Latest Job Updates! 
 
0
comments:
 
 
Post a Comment


 
 Newer Post Older Post Home 
Latest Job Posts
 
Get Notified by Email
 Subscribe via email to get the latest job updates in your mailbox.Be the first to know and apply!!
 
 
Delivered by FeedBurner
 
Like Us and Get The Latest Job Updates via Facebook!
 
Advertisement
 
Popular Jobs
 
 Novotel Hotels Massive Recruitment,June 2012 GlaxoSmithKline Graduate and Professional Jobs in Nigeria,June 2012 Visafone Nigeria recruitment,July 4th 2012(recruitment@visafone.com.ng) PZ Cussons Nigeria Jobs,June - July 2012 US Embassy Jobs in Nigeria,June 23rd 2012 Mobil Nigeria Apprenticeship Program 2012 FirstNation Airline recruitment in Nigeria, July 2012 British Council Nigeria is recruiting! July 2nd 2012 Radio Talk Nigeria (TrendNET) recruitment for Graduates in Nigeria(http://radiotalkng.com/) United Nations Office for Project Services NGO Jobs in Abuja,July 2012 
 
Our Visitors
   ©2012 Recent Nigerian Jobs
	</body>
</document>
