<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000037" url="http://www.mymajors.com/careers-and-jobs/Fast-Food-Fry-Cook" time="2012-07-12-15:13" support="4" score="0.028400660218719058" bingtitle="Fast Food Fry Cook job and career information" webtitle="Fast Food Fry Cook job and career information">
			<query id="000416" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="000436" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="000167" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="000164" bing-rank="155"/>
	<description>... job description: Prepare and cook food in a fast food restaurant ... Cook the exact number of items ordered by ... Read food order slips or receive verbal instructions as to ...</description>
	<body>
		Login    Login ID / Email Address Password Forgot your password? Find Your Major. 
 Home Quiz Planning 
 For Students 
 MyMajors Mobile App College Major Quiz Find a School Student Blogs Financial Aid Advice Scholarships/Grants Research Majors 
 For Counselors 
 What is MyMajors? Counselor Resources Scholarships/Grants Counselor Blogs Publications 
 For Parents 
 What is MyMajors? Financial Aid Advice Scholarships/Grants Parent Resources Parent Blogs University Parent 
 
 About 
 Mission Network App 
 Blog Majors Careers Schools 
 

 Career: 
 Fast Food Fry Cook 

 Job Description: Prepare and cook food in a fast food restaurant with a limited menu. Duties of these cooks are limited to preparation of a few basic items and normally involve operating large-volume single-purpose cooking equipment.

*A job as a Fast Food Fry Cook falls under the broader career category of Cooks, Fast Food. The information on this page will generally apply to all careers in this category. We are still seeking more specific information about this career from experts in this field. If you can provide us with more information, .
 Is Fast Food Fry Cook the right career path for you? 
 Take the MyMajors Quiz and find out if it fits one of your top recommended majors! 


 
 General Info Education Schools Skills Salary
	</body>
</document>
