<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000502" url="http://www.sparkpeople.com/mypage_public_journal_individual.asp?blog_id=1398400" time="2012-07-12-15:46" support="2" score="0.003671957948855909" bingtitle="Reminding Myself - Why I should keep a food journal." webtitle="Reminding Myself - Why I should keep a food journal.">
			<query id="000034" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="000723" bing-rank="196"/>
	<description>... items such as candy, condiments, etc. Record as you go to ensure accuracy. * When and where you eat: Time of day, how long you were eating, if you ate in a fast-food ...</description>
	<body>
		Start my Nutrition my Fitness Other Goals SparkStreaks Reports Planner SparkMail my SparkPoints Web Search 
 
 Healthy Lifestyle Home Nutrition Fitness Motivation Wellness SparkDiet Lifestyle Centers 
 Maintaining Your New Weight Men&apos;s Health Backyard Gardening College Living Financial Fitness Green Living SparkMoms Natural Beauty Senior Health Women&apos;s Health Brides-to-Be Limited Mobility 
 Videos SparkRecipes.com dailySpark.com 
 
 Health Conditions Home Health A-Z Condition Centers 
 Depression Diabetes (Spark*D Program) GERD (Heartburn) Healthy Heart High Blood Pressure High Cholesterol Insomnia Irritable Bowel Syndrome (IBS) Menopause Osteoarthritis Seasonal Allergies 
 Health News 
 
 Community Home Message Boards SparkTeams Challenge Central SparkPages Blogs Success Stories Secrets of Success SparkPeople LIVE! Friend Feed SparkAmerica 
 
 
 
 SparkPeople advertisers help keep the site free! Learn more 

 
 
 
     YRCARL22   9,235 
 SparkPoints 
 
 
 SparkFriends SparkTeams Favorites 
 
   
   
 Reminding Myself - Why I should keep a food journal. View YRCARL22&apos;s Sparkpage View All Blog Entries from YRCARL22 

 
Wednesday, August 13, 2008
 Why keep a food journal?

* Tracking the food we consume forces us to take responsibility for our food choices. It shows what we&apos;re really eating.
* An accurate food journal helps us see eating patterns, giving us insight into when and why we eat.
* Monitoring the foods we eat helps us estimate calorie intake, so we can make adjustments, by eating less or exercising more.

If you&apos;re beginning a program to change your habits, you may want to start with a baseline food journal that keeps track of a &quot;typical&quot; week of food choices and exercise. This way, you&apos;ll have a better handle on what you need to work on-- problem times or situations, circumstances that make it difficult to eat healthy, and so on. The level of detail you record depends on your goals, but some possible things to jot down include:

* What you eat and how much you eat: You can estimate portions, but be honest and be thorough-- don&apos;t forget items such as candy, condiments, etc. Record as you go to ensure accuracy.
* When and where you eat: Time of day, how long you were eating, if you ate in a fast-food restaurant or the company cafeteria, etc.
* Who you were with and any other activity you were involved in: Were you reading or watching TV, or having brunch with your best friend?
* Your mood while eating: Were you bored, frustrated, happy? This may tell you whether you engage in emotional eating—eating triggered by mood, not hunger.
* Any exercise you did, including the activity, length and intensity, and estimate of calories burned.
* Any special categories for which you want to monitor consumption, such as carbohydrates, fat, or fiber content.

Once you have a baseline journal, you can set priorities for what to work on. Do you eat well when eating by yourself, but go overboard when you&apos;re with friends? Does the routine of a workday keep you in line, while the freedom of the weekend weakens your willpower? Do you subsist on convenience foods that are heavy on processing but light on nutrients and real taste? Important things to consider include:

* What is your real motivation for eating? Are you truly hungry when you eat or are you eating for emotional reasons?
* Do you eat well-balanced meals with reasonable serving sizes? If not, map out the changes you’d like to make.
* Do you eat at appropriate intervals, or do you eat a little and then overindulge later? It may seem counterintuitive, but eating smaller amounts more often may keep your energy high, and prevent overeating.

A food journal allows you to compare your habits to the healthy habits recommended by experts: getting 25 grams of fiber a day, limiting fat intake to 35 percent of your total calorie intake, and consuming fewer calories than your body burns daily. You can then continue to track what’s important to you—whether it involves elaborate detail or very simple information.

Keeping a food journal can make us uncomfortable because doing so forces us to recall things we’d rather not take note of—that chocolate shake we had for lunch, or that extra mound of mashed potatoes we regretted as soon we inhaled it. In other words: no pain, no gain. When you see the foods you’ve eaten listed in black-and-white, you can’t wish them away. But pain, even metaphorical pain, can be the impetus for change—and if used consistently, a food journal can be the instrument of that change.

Studies show that people who keep food journals lose more weight and keep more of that weight off in the long run. The National Weight Control Registry–an ongoing research project tracking more than 3,000 people who’ve lost an average of 66 pounds and kept it off for five years–found that keeping a food journal is the one strategy used by the majority of successful dieters. In fact, in a study of 685 dieters conducted by a health insurance company, the best predictor of weight loss throughout the first year was the number of food records kept per week. Another recent study published in the American Journal of Preventive Medicine found that dieters who tracked their food intake in a &quot;food diary&quot; lost twice as much weight as those who didn&apos;t track their food.

This is why the Nutrition Tracker plays such a key role in the SparkDiet. It gives you a proven, fighting chance. If you&apos;re not yet a Nutrition Tracker user, try it out for a few days and see if it doesn&apos;t help you make better choices, too.


The Key to Weight Loss Success
It&apos;s Write In Front of You
-- By Rebecca Pratt, staff writer
 Report Inappropriate Blog  Member Comments About This Blog Post: 

 
 
 
Be the First to Add Your Comment to the Blog Post

 Log in to post a comment. 
 
   SparkPeople advertisers help keep the site free! Learn more Get An Email Alert Each Time YRCARL22 Posts 


 
Other Entries by YRCARL22

 Here is what you SHOULD expect when it comes to weight loss: - 4/18/2009 Next 5 weeks to just enjoy being home. - 7/13/2008 Family Camping...making memories - 7/6/2008 49 and doing better than ever. - 6/23/2008 
 View All Entries 


 
   

 
 

 
 
 close X 
 View this week&apos;s SparkPeople Deals! 
 
 Featured Today 
 Featured Article: Sneak in Exercise Before Pregnancy dailySpark Blog: 5 Supermarket Shopping Secrets, Revealed Featured Recipe: Chef Meg&apos;s Creamy Watermelon Salad 
 
 
 Like Us On Facebook 
 
 Like Us On Facebook — 
 
 
 
 Login 
 
 Get a Free Diet Plan 
 
 Tell a Friend!
	</body>
</document>
