<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000569" url="http://www.foxnews.com/story/0,2933,504125,00.html" time="2012-07-12-15:51" support="4" score="0.007112161233747637" bingtitle="Florida Woman Calls 911 After McDonald&apos;s Runs Out of McNuggets ..." webtitle="Florida Woman Calls 911 After McDonalds Runs Out of McNuggets | Fox News">
			<query id="001480" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000851" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="000537" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="001102" bing-rank="206"/>
	<description>... 27, made the calls after she tried to get her money back and the cashier ... she paid for a 10-piece Chicken McNuggets at a McDonald&apos;s but the fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Fox News Digital Network   Fox News   Fox Business   uReport   Fox News Radio   Fox News Latino   Fox Nation   Fox News Insider 
 Register Login 
 Account 
You&apos;re logged in as Account 

 Edit Profile Logout 
 

 Search Site 
 On Air Now » On Air Personalities » 

   
 
 Home Video Politics U.S. Opinion Entertainment SciTech Health Travel Lifestyle World Sports On Air 
 
 Previous Slide Next Slide 
 
 
 

 Special Report 

 Weekdays 6p et
 
 

 Fox Report 

 Weekdays 7p et
 
 

 The O&apos;Reilly Factor 

 Weekdays 8p et
 
 

 Hannity 

 Weekdays 9p et
 
 

 On The Record 

 Weekdays 10p et
 
 

 America Live 

 Weekdays 1p et
 
 

 America&apos;s News HQ 

 Weekends 12p et
 
 

 America&apos;s Newsroom 

 Weekdays 9a et
 
 

 The Cost of Freedom 

 Saturday 10a et
 
 

 The Five 

 Weekdays 5pm et
 
 

 Fox&amp;Friends 

 Weekdays 6a et
 
 

 Fox&amp;Friends Weekend 

 Weekends 6a et
 
 

 Fox News Sunday 

 Sunday 2p et
 
 

 Fox News Watch 

 Saturday 2:30p et
 
 

 Geraldo at Large 

 Weekends 10p et
 
 

 Happening Now 

 Weekdays 11a et
 
 

 Huckabee 

 Saturday 8p et
 
 

 The Journal Editorial Report 

 Saturday 2p et
 
 

 Justice with Judge Jeanine 

 Saturday 9p et
 
 

 Red Eye w/ Gutfeld 

 Weekdays 3a et
 
 

 Studio B 

 Weekdays 3p et
 
 

 War Stories 

 Saturday 2a et
 
 

 Your World Cavuto 

 Weekdays 4p et
 
 
Florida Woman Calls 911 After McDonald&apos;s Runs Out of McNuggets
 
Published March 04, 2009 

 FoxNews.com 
 
 
Latreasa L. Goodman
 
 Next Slide Previous Slide 
   Email   Share   Comments 
 


A Florida woman called 911 three times after she paid for a 10-piece Chicken McNuggets at a McDonald&apos;s but the fast-food restaurant ran out of them and refused to give her a refund.



Latreasa L. Goodman, 27, made the calls after she tried to get her money back from a Fort Pierce McDonald&apos;s and the cashier told her all sales were final. Police released the 911 tapes.



&quot;This is an emergency. If I would have known they didn&apos;t have McNuggets, I wouldn&apos;t have given my money, and now she wants to give me a McDouble, but I don&apos;t want one,&quot; police quoted her as saying. &quot;This is an emergency.&quot;



The cashier suggested she choose something else off the menu of equal value to the McNuggets, and offered the restaurant&apos;s cheeseburger called the McDouble.



&quot;She&apos;s trying to force me to eat something off the menu and I don&apos;t want it,&quot; Goodman told 911.



The first dispatcher, a woman, asks if there&apos;s a manager there, but listens to Goodman&apos;s complaints and says she&apos;s sending someone.



The second, male dispatcher tells her he&apos;s aware of the incident and &quot;we&apos;ve got an officer coming out there to talk to you.&quot;



Police say Goodman was cited on a misuse of 911 charge. A current phone listing for Goodman couldn&apos;t be found.



A McDonald&apos;s spokesman said Goodman should have been given a refund, and she&apos;s being sent a gift card for a free meal.



 Click here to hear the first 911 call. 



 Click here to hear the second 911 call. 



 Click here to hear the third 911 call. 



 Click here to read more on this story from TCPalm.com. 



 The Associated Press contributed to this report. 
 
SHARE THIS ARTICLE

   
 
NEWSLETTER SIGNUP
 
Sign up for free e-mail news alerts from FoxNews.com and FoxBusiness.com.
 Subscribe 
 View Article 
 Please enable JavaScript to view the&lt;a href=&quot;http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript=foxnation&quot;&gt;comments powered by Disqus.&lt;/a&gt; 
You must login to comment.
 
 View Article 
 
More Stories
 
   
 
Sections
 
 Home Video Politics U.S. Opinion Entertainment Scitech Health Travel Lifestyle World Sports Weather 
 
Shows
 
 America Live America News HQ America&apos;s Newsroom Cavuto Fox News Sunday Fox&amp;Friends First Fox&amp;Friends Fox&amp;Friends Weekend Fox News Watch Fox Report Geraldo at Large Greta Hannity 
 
 
 
 Happening Now Huckabee Justice with Judge Jeanine Red Eye w/ Gutfeld Special Report Specials Studio B The Cost of Freedom The Five The Journal Editorial Report The O&apos; Reilly Factor War Stories 
 
Tools
 
 Trending uReport Newsletters&amp;Alerts Blogs Mobile Podcasts Radio Fox News Store Apps&amp;Downloads 
 
About
 
 Careers Internships - FNCU Fox Around the World Advertise With Us Terms of Use Privacy Policy (Updated!) Ad Choices Contact Us Email Newsroom FAQ Media Relations 
 
Follow
 
   Facebook   Twitter   YouTube   RSS   Newsletters 
 
 
This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.©2012 FOX News Network, LLC. All rights reserved. All market data delayed 20 minutes.
	</body>
</document>
