<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000592" url="http://www.thefreelibrary.com/Louie+Mele+President+of+McDonalds+Canada+to+Join+Board+of+Directors...-a0174299016" time="2012-07-12-15:52" support="2" score="0.01140808880560857" bingtitle="Louie Mele President of McDonalds Canada to Join Board of ..." webtitle="Louie Mele President of McDonalds Canada to Join Board of Directors of HearAtLast Holdings, Inc. - Free Online Library">
			<query id="000076" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="000070" bing-rank="221"/>
	<description>... of the popular fast-food restaurant chain ... refined process to dispense a hearing aid in about an hour. For more information please visit www.hearatlast.com</description>
	<body>
		Printer Friendly 
19,791,913 articles and books Periodicals Literature Keyword Title Author Topic 
 Member login User name    Password     Remember me 
 Join us   Forgot password? 
 The Free Library &gt; Business and Industry&gt;  Business &gt;  Business Wire &gt;  February 6, 2008 The Free Library &gt; Business and Industry&gt;  Business, international &gt;  Business Wire &gt;  February 6, 2008 The Free Library &gt;  Date &gt;  2008 &gt;  February &gt;  6 &gt;  Business Wire 
 
Louie Mele President of McDonalds Canada to Join Board of Directors of HearAtLast Holdings, Inc.

TORONTO -- (Pinksheets: HRAL)--HearAtLast Holdings, Inc. is pleased
to announce that the Company will appoint Mr. Louie Mele, President of McDonald&apos;s Restaurants There are more than 30,000 McDonald&apos;s restaurants in 119 countries. Restaurants 
The first McDonald&apos;s was not a restaurant at all, but it was a sit-in stand. The company&apos;s early franchises were built to a standard pattern that did not offer seating; this was in part to prevent  of Canada Ltd. a wholly owned subsidiary Wholly Owned Subsidiary

A subsidiary whose parent company owns 100% of its common stock.

Notes:
In other words, the parent company owns the company outright and there are no minority owners.  of
McDonald&apos;s Corporation ( NYSE NYSE

See: New York Stock Exchange : MCD MCD Minor Civil Division
MCD McDonalds (restaurant) 
Mcd Macedonian (linguistics) 
MCD Municipal Corporation of Delhi
MCD Magnetic Circular Dichroism
MCD Mad Cow Disease ) to the Board of Directors of
HearAtLast.

HearAtLast Holdings, Inc. currently operates under a master
licensing agreement with Wal-Mart Canada Wal-Mart Canada is the Canadian unit of Wal-Mart and was founded in 1994 in Mississauga, Ontario with the purchase of the Canadian Woolco stores. Wal-Mart typically competes with Zellers, Canadian Tire, Co-Op, Giant Tiger, and Real Canadian Superstore, Costco, and increasingly  Corp. which allows HearAtLast
to open hearing-aid clinics within numerous Wal-Mart locations
throughout Canada. McDonald&apos;s of Canada Restaurants Ltd. signed an
agreement with Wal-Mart Canada Corp. in 1994 that was considered a
milestone event by the company. Today McDonald&apos;s Canada McDonald&apos;s Restaurants of Canada is the Canadian branch of the popular fast-food restaurant chain McDonald&apos;s. One of Canada&apos;s largest fast-food restaurant chains, the franchise sells food items including hamburgers, chicken, french fries and soft drinks all across the country.  is the
largest licensee of Wal-Mart Canada Corp. with 200 satellite restaurants
co-located within Wal-Mart stores throughout Canada.

&quot;Louie Mele brings with him a tremendous amount of knowledge
and experience from his tenure at the world&apos;s largest and perhaps
most well-known fast food restaurant. Louie has done a tremendous job
with the growth of McDonald&apos;s on a national and international
scale,&quot; stated Matteo Sacco, CEO (1) ( C hief E xecutive O fficer) The highest individual in command of an organization. Typically the president of the company, the CEO reports to the Chairman of the Board.  of HearAtLast. &quot;We
couldn&apos;t possibly be happier about him coming on board to assist us
as we continue to implement the aggressive plan of expansion for
HearAtLast. We are confident that Mr. Mele&apos;s expertise and
relationship with Wal-Mart Canada Corp. will prove invaluable to our
company,&quot; added Mr. Sacco.

&quot;In my role across Canada Across Canada was an afternoon program that formerly aired on The Weather Network. The segment ran from early 1999 until mid 2002. The show ran from 3:00PM ET until 7:00 PM ET. , I am often asked to provide my
expertise in accountability and transparency due to the structure of the
company I lead - McDonald&apos;s Canada,&quot; commented Mr. Mele.
&quot;I have been interested in the HearAtLast business model since it
was presented to me a while back and I continue my interest.
Furthermore, I am impressed at the manner in which HearAtLast has
positioned itself for the future as a collaborative entity providing health services health services  Managed care The benefits covered under a health contract  to patients and assistive devices for patients requiring
hearing enhancement. HearAtLast&apos;s confidence in me as a Board
member is equally returned through my confidence in the
organization,&quot; added Mele.

The Company currently owns and operates 19 hearing clinics, 18
clinics are co-located in Wal-Mart Stores, Wal-Mart Supercenters, and
Sam&apos;s Clubs in Canada and one free-standing clinic is located in
the U.S. in The Villages, Florida.

About Louie Mele

Mr. Mele began his career at McDonald&apos;s as a crewmember in
1972. Through an unrelenting sense of dedication and commitment, he
advanced through various managerial positions, eventually resulting in
his appointment as Operations Manager See datacenter manager.  in 1985. In 1987, Mr. Mele brought
his experience in Canada oversees when he moved to Italy to assume the
role of Director of Operations. In April 1990, he was named President of
McDonald&apos;s Italy. Mr. Mele moved to the United States United States,  officially United States of America, republic (2005 est. pop. 295,734,000), 3,539,227 sq mi (9,166,598 sq km), North America. The United States is the world&apos;s third largest country in population and the fourth largest country in area.  in 1995 to
serve as Senior Regional Manager, SE Division, in Norfolk, Virginia.
Over the next five years, he continued his role as Regional
Vice-President, SE Division, in both Norfolk and then in Tampa, Florida.
In April 2001, Mr. Mele returned to Canada as Executive Vice-President
of McDonald&apos;s Restaurants of Canada Limited, where he focused his
energies on supporting the three Canadian Regional Vice-Presidents in
Vancouver, Toronto and Montreal. Mr. Mele also serves on the Board of
Directors of Ronald McDonald House Charities This article or section needs sources or references that appear in reliable, third-party publications. Alone, primary sources and sources affiliated with the subject of this article are not sufficient for an accurate encyclopedia article. [R] of Canada.

Mr. Mele became Executive Vice-President and Chief Operating
Officer Chief Operating Officer (COO)

The officer of a firm responsible for day-to-day management, usually the president or an executive vice-president.  in August 2002 and was appointed to his current position as
President in April 2005.

About McDonald&apos;s[R] Canada

McDonald&apos;s[R] is the leading foodservice company in the world.
McDonald&apos;s Restaurants of Canada Limited and its Canadian
franchisees own and operate more than 1,400 restaurants and employ more
than 77,000 Canadians coast to coast. Approximately 65 per cent of
McDonald&apos;s Canadian restaurants are locally owned and operated by
independent entrepreneurs. For more information about McDonald&apos;s
Canada, visit the company&apos;s web site at www.mcdonalds.ca.

About HearAtLast

HearAtLast Holdings, Inc. is a Nevada corporation that owns and
operates its wholly-owned subsidiary HearAtLast Inc., a chain of hearing
stores specializing in the sale of digital hearing aids and testing
services. The company develops, owns, and operates hearing aid clinics
co-located within select Wal-Mart stores throughout Canada. HearAtLast
facilities sell a selection of high quality brand name hearing aids Hearing Aids   Definition 

A hearing aid is a device that can amplify sound waves in order to help a deaf or hard-of-hearing person hear sounds more clearly.  and
also offer complimentary screening tests, clinical hearing tests,
instant custom MP3 headphones Head-mounted speakers. Headphones have a strap that rests on top of the head, positioning a pair of speakers over both ears. For listening to music or monitoring live performances and audio tracks, both left and right channels are required.  and custom hearing protection. The
Company&apos;s mission is to consolidate the highly fragmented hearing
services industry while providing unparalleled service to the estimated
30+ million hearing impaired individuals throughout North America. After
a prescription is approved, the independent on-site audiologists and
hearing aid practitioners at HearAtLast utilize a refined process to
dispense a hearing aid in about an hour.

For more information please visit www.hearatlast.com [TABLE OMITTED] 

 Safe Harbor Safe Harbor

1. A legal provision to reduce or eliminate liability as long as good faith is demonstrated.

2. A form of shark repellent implemented by a target company acquiring a business that is so poorly regulated that the target itself is less attractive.  

Statements about the Company&apos;s future expectations and all
other statements in this press release other than historical facts, are
&quot;forward-looking statements&quot; within the meaning of Section 27A
of the Securities Act of 1933, Section 21E of the Securities Exchange
Act of 1934, and as that term is defined in the Private Securities
Litigation Reform Act The Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995 (PSLRA) implemented several significant substantive changes affecting certain cases brought under the federal securities laws, including changes related to pleading, discovery, liability, class representation and awards fees and  of 1995. The Company intends that such
forward-looking statements be subject to the safe harbors created
thereby.

The above information contains information relating to the Company
that is based on the beliefs of the Company and/or its management as
well as assumptions made by and information currently available to the
Company or its management. When used in this document, the words
&quot;anticipate,&quot; &quot;estimate,&quot; &quot;expect,&quot;
&quot;intend,&quot; &quot;plans,&quot; &quot;projects,&quot; and similar
expressions, as they relate to the Company or its management, are
intended to identify forward-looking statements. Such statements reflect
the current view of the Company regarding future events and are subject
to certain risks, uncertainties and assumptions, including the risks and
uncertainties noted. Should one or more of these risks or uncertainties
materialize, or should underlying assumptions prove to be incorrect,
actual results may vary materially from those described herein as
anticipated, believed, estimated, expected, intended or projected. In
each instance, forward-looking information should be considered in light
of the accompanying meaningful cautionary statements herein. Factors
that could cause results to differ include, but are not limited to,
successful performance of internal plans, the impact of competitive
services and pricing and general economic risks and uncertainties. COPYRIGHT 2008 Business Wire
No portion of this article can be reproduced without the express written permission from the copyright holder. Copyright 2008, Gale Group. All rights reserved. 
 Reader Opinion
 Title:
 
Comment:
 

 
   
 
 Article Details Printer friendly Cite/link Email Feedback Publication: Business Wire Date: Feb 6, 2008 Words: 1009 Previous Article: Infonizer and AppOne to Use AppOne&apos;s DocOne Engine to Provide Compliant Indirect Lending Documents for Microsoft DMS Solution. Next Article: Ron Paul National Delegate Count Now 42 or More. Topics: Boards of directors Discount stores Officials and employees 
 Restaurant industry Officials and employees 
 




 Related Articles K. Lake businessman advocates tax revolt to oppose town&apos;s plan to construct housing. $50M expansion planned. Schools&apos; pizza makers will get their piece of the pie. All for benevolent dictatorship: Chief Louie believes tough love and economic development will rebuild native communities. Is Ottawa finally... Chief Clarence Louie of British Columbia was appointed as the chairperson of the National Aboriginal Economic Development Board in April by Jim... 
 
 
 Publications by Name Publications by Date Authors Literature A-D E-O P-T U-Z before 1995 1995-1999 
 2000-2004 2005-2009 2010- A B C D E F G H I J K L M 
 N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z A B C D E F G H I J K L M 
 N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z 

 Terms of use |
Copyright©2012 Farlex, Inc. | Feedback | For webmasters | Submit articles
	</body>
</document>
