<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000489" url="http://www.dmoz.org/Games/Card_Games/Special_Decks/desc.html" time="2012-07-12-15:44" support="1" score="0.00038952983555653054" bingtitle="Open Directory - Games: Card Games: Special Decks:" webtitle="Open Directory - Games: Card Games: Special Decks:">
			<query id="000686" bing-rank="197"/>
	<description>Players are called upon to select an &quot;apple card&quot; from their hand with the name of a person, place, thing or ... A card game set at Friedey&apos;s, the fast food restaurant of ...</description>
	<body>
		about dmoz | help 
 Top : Games : Card Games : Special Decks : Special Decks 

 Various card games which require a special pack of cards often promoted and sold by a particular manufacturer.

Each game is categorized in a sub-directory, if not the site describes more than one card game. 1000 Blank White Cards Invented by Nathan McQuillen of Madison, Wisconsin. 

You take a lot of index cards, cut them in half, draw your own cards and play them on each other. One of the two people involved should read the card aloud. These two activities - creating new cards and playing them on one another - occur simultaneously, although you generally take about half an hour at the start of the gathering just to draw new cards. Abduction A sci-fi game for 2-4 players. Designed by George Vasilakos and published by Eden Studios.

 Players are Abductees aboard an alien spacecraft. Your goal is to be the first to end your turn on an Exit card.

 Location cards are placed to form a map of the alien craft. There are also item and event cards.

 In each turn the active player draws a hand up to five cards, and then takes up to three actions. The other Abductees may play Event cards in response to each action.
 1. Draw hand up to five cards.
 2. Perform action.
 3. Each non-Active Abductee, in clockwise order, may play one Event card.
 2-3 are repeated 3 times. Algebra Game An educational card game to train your math skills in Quadratic Equations, Linear Graphs, Conic Section Graphs, and Trig Functions. 
60 cards in each deck. Each type of deck can be delivered with several different kind of problems. Alibi For 3-6 players. Published by Mayfair Games 1992. Designed by Designer Darwin Bromley and Jim Musser.

A whodunit game, which makes players use their skills of deduction and reasoning to solve the who, what, where and why of a murder. Players score points for solving the mystery, but also for helping other players solve it, forcing them to make strategic decisions during play. AlphaBlitz AlphaBlitz is a word puzzle card game from Wizards of the Coast, suitable for ages 10 to adult. The pack contains rules for two games, Alpha and Blitz. Both games are variations on a common theme, which is one of competitively making words from letters on card displayed on the table. One game (Blitz) is very competitive with elements of time and gameplay, the other (Alpha) is more individualist and has no time element. Apples to Apples Party game from Out of the Box Publishing. 4-8 players from 1999.

Players are called upon to select an &quot;apple card&quot; from their hand with the name of a person, place, thing or event which they think is best characterized by the word on a randomly drawn &quot;orange card&quot;. The selected &quot;apple cards&quot; are then judged by one of the players to determine a winner for that round. Aquarius A pretty abstract game with psychedelic 60s style artwork. For 2-5 players from 8 years old. 60 full color playing cards. Designed and illustrated by Andrew Looney. Published by Looney Laboratories Inc.
 

Aquarius features three types of cards: Elements, Goals, and Actions. Element cards are played kind of like dominoes, with each player trying to win by connecting seven panels of one particular element. Goal cards determine which element each player is going after, and Action cards allow players to shake up the action in five different ways. 
 

The object of the game is to connect seven or more cards with the element shown on your Goal card. Arena Alternate name is Morituri te salutant (latin for &quot;Those who are about to die, salute you&quot;). 
 A fantasy arena combat game for 2-5 players (best with 2 players). Has a small game board, but is rather a card game. 

 Designed is Vladimír Chvátil. English edition published by Altar publishing in Czech Republic, 1997.

 Tactical combat game, where you choose one or two characters, who fights each other. The winner is the one who succeeds to get the opponents &quot;Condition Points&quot; down to zero. The die is only used to mark how you attack and is never thrown. Authors The Game of Authors was originated in Salem and first played in the 1850s. For 3-5 players.

The object of the game is to collect complete sets of four cards each representing the works of the various Authors by calling for cards from other players. Bandit Designed by Elverson.

The game includes 2 rules&amp;options cards, 2 payout charts, and 51 casino-quality cards, featuring authentic slot machine symbols

You don&apos;t have to own a slot machine to play the slots at home. The rules are simple. After placing bets, each player receives one card at a time, until each player has three cards. Players receiving a winning combination are paid by the dealer. The player with the most chips at the end of play wins. Bang Bang! is designed 2002 by Emiliano Sciarra. Published by daVinci (Italy). For 4-7 players, although best with 6-7. Takes about 30 minutes to play.

A spaghetti-western card game. The cards have Italian text and English subtitles.

Shoot on your right and left, have a beer, go to the saloon, hide behind a barrel, escape from jail to find out that your mistress has left with your horse and your Remington gun. Take 2 cards in your turn and play as many card you want from your hand - but there is some psychology in guessing who is what, as it&apos;s only the sheriff who is known from the beginning. In his team are the Deputies who should protect him and against them are the outlaws, who wins if the sheriff is killed and the Renegade who wins if he&apos;s the last man standing, but he can&apos;t kill the sheriff before the outlaws are killed. Beat the Bookie A game about gambling on horse races. Given various odds the bookie chooses which horse will win and the other players bet on what they think has been chosen. The bookie then reveals the horse chosen and settles the bets accordingly.

Can be played superficially relying on pure luck or deeply using great skill. Will appeal to those who enjoy second guessing, double bluffing and a flutter.

The pack consists of 8 horse cards and 44 odds cards. Big Cheese, The Designed by James Ernest and Jon Wilkie 1999. Published by Cheapass Games. 3-6 players and take about 30 minutes.

A bidding game.

Everybody is a rat in the corporate hierarchy trying to get brownie points in hopes of succeeding the boss when he retires next month, and whoever can score the most points with him gets to take his place. And his Big Cheese. Bohnanza A game from Amigo (German version) and Rio Grande Games (English version). 2-7 players who trade, plant and harvest beans in 2-3 fields. Through collecting series of beans, the target is to collect gold coins during the harvesting. Bongalla From the Australian company Bongalla.com
Played with 2-4 players. A mixture of a standard deck and a similar deck with new drug related symbols and satiric cartoons as figures on the cards. Brawl A game published by Cheapass Games 1999. Designed by James Ernest. Takes less than 5 minutes to play.

A fighting game, where the object is to play the most &quot;hits&quot; on your side of the table before someone freezes the action. That usually happens in less than a minute. Decks come packaged in 35-card decks, and each deck represents a different character with a different mix of cards. Bump Published by Tah-Dah 1990. 72 playing cards with 60 plastic money chips.

Be the first player to optain $10,000 worth of money chips. Play the right card to reach the payoff totals and win chips. Play the right card to reach the bump totals of to acquire your neighbors chips. Play a bump, super bump or bump back card and surprise your neighbor out of their chips. Ages 8 to Adult, 3-6 Players. Burn Rate Started as an idea by Rich Koehler. Published by Cool Studio 2002.

Includes: 102 Full-Color Play Cards and 52 Full-Color Employee Cards.

Hire employees in four departments: Sales, Development, Human Resources, and Finance. 

Based on the creator&apos;s experience during the rise and fall of the dot-com world, this is a game like no other. With a simple, fun, and uncannily realistic game system, you and your friends will struggle to stay afloat as the bad business pours in and the money runs out. The object is to be the last one in business, and you&apos;ll win the dubious honor of &quot;Best dot-com CEO&quot;. Caesar and Cleopatra A 2-player game from Kosmos (German edition) and Rio Grande Games (English edition). Designed by Wolfgang Lüdtke 1999.

 Gain as much influence points as possible through playing influence cards on the different patricians and having the most influence when a vote is called upon for a certain patrician. Possible to destroy the other players game by playing one action card. Ccard Summer School in Semantics (at BRICS, Aarhus University, Denmark) and in particular the course about category theory there, was the cause of this game. For 2 or more players. One of the designers is Olle Möller.

 A very abstract card game. The cards are annotated with deep mathematical truth, taken from &quot;category theory&quot;, which is a field even considered esoteric by some mathematicians. Circus Fleacati Published by Amigo 1998. Designed by Reiner Knizia. Original German name is &apos;Zirkus Flohcati&apos;. 3-5 players for 7 year and up.

The object of the game is collect many valuable Circus cards to achieve the highest points score. In the course of the game, cards with circus attractions are displayed in one row in the middle of the table. On his turn, a player chooses and takes a card from the row, either into his hand, or to form a Trio for bonus points. Before selecting his card the player may, if he wishes, draw cards and add them to the row in order to improve his choices. However, if he draws an attraction which is already in the row, he forfeits his right to take a card. The game ends when one player succeeds in staging a Gala Show, with one Circus card from each attraction. Citadels Designed by Bruno Faidutti. English version by Fantasy Flight Games 2001 (includes 10 new characters).
 German version &quot;Ohne Furcht und Adel&quot; by Hans im Glück. The French original name is &quot;Citadelles&quot;.

 For 3-7 players and takes about 1 hour.

 Nominated for the German Game of the Year in 2000. Game of bluffing, deduction, and city-building. Wrapped in a medival theme and gorgeously illustrated, players seek to be the first to complete a grand city of their own. Each game round players secretly take the roles of either the King, Magician, Architect, Assasin, Thief, Bishop, General, or Merchant and seek to use the powers of such offices in their efforts to win the game. Compost Gin Designed by Stan Slaughter 1998.

An educational card game to understand compostings environmental effects. 

COMPOST GIN is patterned after the traditional gin card game. Deck of 52 cards has six different suites represent the ingredients of a compost pile; each card is assigned a point value and has helpful hints on compost materials and methods. With instructions. Great for homeschoolers, teachers. Counter Punch Boxing simulation. Crazy 8ths Educational game published by TK Designs.

Children learn to read music by playing games with musical cards. 56 cards, including a cheat sheet and a rule booklet for 10 different games. Ages 6 and up. Dallas 2-4 players. Ages 8 to Adult. Published 1980 by Mego Corp. Based upon the TV series &quot;Dallas&quot;.
 

 A card game of wheeling, dealing and stealing. To be the first to accumulate 20 million dollars in holdings of Assets and/or Cash. This is done by building your holdings with investments and Ewing Family Connections, relentlessly stealing from opponents and deviously protecting your holdings. Dark Cults Designed 1983 by Kenneth Rahman. Published by Dark House. A 2-player horror game, which takes about 60 minutes.

It is a story-telling card game, foreshadowing Once Upon A Time. In it, the two players represent Life and Death, respectively, and each tries to guide the story to the corresponding outcome. 

This is a card game with beautifully illustrated horror cards based on H.P. Lovecraft&apos;s world. Deelakord Made by Danny Ryan. The intention with the game is to make music theory for beginners easier to learn.

There are 52 cards in a DEELAKORD pack. Of these, 28 are Note Cards, 8 are Sharp Cards, 8 are Flat Cards and 8 are Common Cards. Common Cards may be substituted for any Note, Flat or Sharp Card. May be played solo or with others. Diabolo A German word game published by TM-Spiele 1999. Designed by Reiner Knizia. 2-6 Players. Age 10 and up. Duration 20-30 minutes. 

 Published 2001 in English as &quot;My Word&quot; or &quot;My Word Junior&quot; by Out of the Box.

 Things go devilishly quickly around here. New letters appear on the table. Players study them feverishly. As soon as one player spots a word that can be made from the letters, he calls it out and collects the respective cards. Who will win the most cards? 

 With four to six players, the game ends when each player has been the dealer once. In a two- or three-player game, each player is the dealer twice. The player with the highest total result is the winner. Dino Hunt A pre-historic game published 1996 by Steve Jackson.

Dino Hunt is a family game for two or more players, age 8 and up. In Dino Hunt, you travel through time, visiting the different eras where the dinosaurs lived, to capture them for your modern-day zoo. But the other players have cards that can make your hunt harder - and watch out for that charging T. Rex! 

 Dino Hunt is a single-deck game, so all players draw from the same deck of cards. You can get booster packs to add more cards to the deck, but this is simply to add interest and variety to the game. Every player has the same chance of drawing the new cards, so nobody gets an unfair advantage. 

Published in Germany by Pegasus Spiele with the name &quot;Dino Jagd&quot;. Don German game by Michael Schacht and published by Queen Games (Germany 2001) and Asmodée (France 2002). 3-6 players, but best with 4. Takes about 20 minutes to play.

 Different coloured cards are auctioned, so you might collect as many as possible in each colour. You are not allowed to bet the values of already collected cards and the payed price is shared among the other players, except that the excess is going to a common pool until the next turn. Dragons Gold Designed by Bruno Faidutti. Published by Descartes Editeur 2001. German name is &apos;Drachengold&apos; and French original name is &apos;L&apos;or des Dragons&apos;. For 3-6 playersand takes about 20 minutes. Graphics by Emmanuel Roudier.

 A fantasy negociation game, where each player controls a team of dragon hunters (two knights, a thief, and a wizard). Like all dragon hunters, they only have one goal: the gold, silver, the jewels, and the magic objects. It&apos;s easy to kill the dragon, but the most difficult part comes after the dragon is dead, when the adventuring party has to figure out how to share the spoils. Dutch Blitz Published 1960 by Dutch Blitz Games Company.

Amish, Mennonite, Pennsylvania Dutch card game. Two to four players, age 9 to 100, do their best to rid their &quot;Blitz&quot; pile before the other players as everyone plays at the same time.

Each player gets one of the four decks of 40 cards each. Each deck has a different design on the back (carriage, pump, pail, and plow) to designate players cards. Each player has three cards placed on the table in front of them (post piles) along with a pile of 10 cards (blitz pile). Players try to form sequences of cards (in ascending order, by color) in the center of the table starting from one up to ten. Quickest player to get rid of his blitz pile calls BLITZ and play stops. Cards in center of table count for 1 point each, cards left in blitz pile count for -2 points each. First player to 75 wins.

Fast paced and good for hand-eye coordination. Dvorak Dvorak is a card game where all the cards start out blank; players choose a theme, make up enough cards to get started, then continue to add new cards during the course of the game, provided that the other players approve of the cards.

It can be played in two ways - either as a serious attempt to create a card game around a theme (a film, a book, a sport, or whatever you like), or a ruthless Nomic-style free-for-all, where each Player pursues his or her particular aims without regard for fairness or replayability. Elixir Designed by Frédéric Leygonie and Los Rodriguez. Published in English by Mayfair game (2000) and in French by Asmodee (1996). From 10 year and up for 3-8 players.

 The players participate as malicious sprites, casting spells upon themselves and their opponents. A beer and pretzel game.

 This game utilizes a two deck system, one of spells and one of &quot;finds&quot;. &quot;Finds&quot; are composed of components, magic items, transactions and items. Spells requiring between 1 and 4 components to cast, the first player to cast all his spells wins. EmotrionsOnCards Card game of emotional intelligence. Evergreen Designed by Wolfgang Kramer&amp;Michael Kiesling. Published in German by Goldsieber Spiele 1999 and in English by Rio Grande Games. Players: 2-6 aged 12 and up, Length: 20-30 minutes.

You are dealt a number of cards, featuring an artist and a number which indicates how much influence over the artist the card gives. Several artists can change place because of your turn, and every time an artist moves, its popularity changes. Express Designed by Darwin Bromley. Published 1990 by Mayfair Games. For 2-6 players.

Express is a kind of rummy game with a train theme. Players start with a one-car train and build on their meld to maximize points and bonuses. But players must be wary of train wrecks and derailments. 

You draw cards into your hand in order to make trains which score points. These are laid out in front of you with a loco with carriages, trucks and cabooses forming a scoring train. There are special cards such as breakdown trains, engineer cars and so on that give you scope to steal opponents cards or fight off such attacks. Faerie Haven Published 2001 by Mushroom Circles Games Inc.

Faerie Haven is a single deck, expandable card game for 2-6 players. In Faerie Haven, the object is to collect the most points in faeries than your opponents before the game ends. The basic rules are simple, but some cards have their own special rules. Falling Designed by James Ernest. Published by Cheapass Games.
For 3-6 players. Nominated for Origins award 1998.

A two-minute thrill ride. It&apos;s a freeform card game in which players are falling, fighting, and struggling to hit the ground last. There are no turns in this game. Everyone is playing at once.

One player deals from a mostly-shuffled deck, while the other players play their cards in real time. The Dealer isn&apos;t falling, he just distributes the cards and moderates the game. The other players receive stacks of cards, like Skip, Stop, Hit, and Push, and try to cope with them as quickly and accurately as they can. Sitting on the bottom of the deck are five Ground cards: when you get a Ground card, you are out, and the last player to hit the Ground wins. To win a game of Falling, you have to be lucky, fast, and clever. Or at least two out of three. Family Business Published by Mayfair Games 1982. Re-edition 1995. For 2-6 players, Ages 8 through adult. Playing Time 30 minutes. 

 This fast paced card game of gangster warfare, intrigue and suspense puts the emphasis on fun. Each player is a mob boss competing to survive the murder and mayhem of the Prohibition era. The last player to have a mobster alive wins. Fight City Designed by James Ernest 1999. Players are 2 or more. Playing time is 30 minutes. Content: two 54 card decks and rules. Each player needs his own deck, plus ten counters to represent the money in his bank 

 The story is pretty simple: It&apos;s a City, and they Fight. The game is also simple: Each player&apos;s deck is composed of 50-60 cards, like Locations, Fighters, Weapons and Events. Players take turns bringing cards into play and using the cards they have in play. The object of the game is to run your opponent out of money. Fist of Dragonstones Designed by Bruno Faidutti and Michael Schacht 2002. English version published by Days of Wonder, and French version published by Asmodée. For 3-6 players.

 A bidding game. Players try to outwit their opponents by using gold and magic coins to buy control of an everchanging cast of enchanted character cards. Those characters&apos; powers collect valuable Dragonstones; lend their magical powers; help foil other players, and convert Dragonstones into victory.

 For each character card, players choose the number of coins they want to bid by placing them in a closed fist. All players reveal their bets at the same time with the winner of the auction then gaining control of the card&apos;s powers. Depending on the card they may: win additional coins or Dragonstones; place spells on other players; or win scoring points. Five Alive From 1990. 2-7 players. Takes about 30 minutes. Published 1994 Mattel in USA and Waddington Games in UK.

Players must protect their five lives by either not bringing the point total over twenty-one or by not running out of cards. If a player cannot play a card, he or she loses a life. Last one in wins. Five Crowns Five Crowns has five Royal Families (suits) - the Stars, the Clubs, the Hearts, the Spades and the Diamonds. 

Hand size begins with three cards and increases each deal to 13. Wild cards for each hand are equivalent to the number of cards dealt for that hand. Play is similar to Rummy where players draw cards and attempt to lay-off runs and books. When a player goes out, the cards remaining in the other players&apos; hands are tallied, and added to their score. The goal is to have the lowest score at the end of the game. Flinch Designed by A.J. Patterson 1901. Later editions by Parker Brothers (1934 and 1963) and Winning Moves. For 2 to 8 players, ages 7 years and up.

 Consists of a deck of 150 cards made up of ten series, each numbered from 1 through 15, and a plastic card holder.

 The object of the game is to be the first player to dispose of the cards dealt to him as a &quot;game pile&quot; by playing them in proper sequence to the center of the table. Fluxx Designed by Andrew Looney and Kristin Looney. Published by Iron Crown Enterprises and Looney Labs. Played by 2-6 players, ages 8 and up.

Includes 84 playing cards in 4 types: Keepers, Goals, New Rules and Actions. 

The rules changes when the game progresses. When the game begins, the only rules are that you draw 1 card per turn and play 1 card per turn. But when you play a New Rule, these rules are either changed or added to. New Rules change the number of cards drawn and played per turn as well as the number of cards you are allowed to hold in your hand, the number of Keepers you can have, bonuses for players who have particular Keepers, and more. Football Fever Published 2001 by IB Gaming.

A card game for two players which captures all the elements of a real game of football including passes, tackles, corners, fouls, red and yellow cards and of course goals which can be scored from normal play, free kicks and penalties. 

The game contains 50 illustrated action cards, a set of rules and 4 dice. Fraction Action Educational game for mathematics. Ages 8 to Adult.
Contains two 48 standard size card decks: a beginner and an intermediate deck.

Played like the card game &quot;War&quot; using fractions! Kids have so much fun, they don&apos;t realize they are learning. Easy-to-read &quot;key&quot; at bottom of each card so they do not need assistance from parent or teacher. Freight Train Designed by Alan R Moon. Originally published by White Wind Inc (Alan R Moon own game company). Published by Mayfair Games 1996. For 2-5 players and takes about 90 minutes to play.

 Each player runs their own freight yard and several trains. Using these and a shared main yard, players take eleven different types of freight cars and compete to form the longest trains. 

 The game contains: : 35 Locomotive Cards, 7 Cabooses, 15 Bumper Cards, End-of-Day Card, Wooden Turn Engine, Rule book, and 16 of each of the following cards: Auto Rack, Box Car, Coil Steel, Container, Gondola, Hopper, Ore, Piggyback, Refrigerator, Stock, Tank. Gang of Four Designed by Lee F Yih. Published by Days of Wonder. For 3-4 players, age 8 and up.

The object of the game is to get rid of all the cards in your hand. The other players got points depending of the number ofremaining cards in their hands and the play continues until one or more players have 100 points or more. Winner is the player with fewest points.

Features a special 64-card deck, illustrated using a traditional Chinese theme, plus 2 rules summary cards, a rules booklet, score pad and a Days of Wonder Web-Card, providing you with access to Gang of Four Online. Gargon Designed by Rudiger Dorn. German edition published by Amigo 2001 and English edition published by Rio Grande Games 2001. For 3-5 players. Takes 30-45 minutes.

The game has six suits of 17 cards each (0-15, with two zeroes). One trick is that the back of each card shows which suit the card is. Players can inspect the card backs of other players. 

Te start player leads 1-3 cards. The only restriction is that the start player may not lead three of a kind. Then each player, in order, may play the same number of cards with the same distribution, or pass. So if I lead a pair, then each other player must either play a pair face down or pass. Players are free to play whatever suit they like, except for the last player. The last player cannot introduce a new suit. If you pass you take 1-3 cards from the ends of the two lines of cards which are fae down in the middle of the table. You can see the backs of all these cards. Give Me the Brain Published by Cheapass Games 1996. 3-8 players, playing time 15 minutes. Content is 54 cards and a rulebook. You also need a six-sided die to represent the Brain.

A card game set at Friedey&apos;s, the fast food restaurant of the damned, where all the employees are zombies. The object is simple: play out your hand. The problem is, a lot of the cards require a Brain, and you&apos;ve only got one to pass around. Go Surf Published 2001 by Golden Seal Press. For 2-5 players.
45 surf cards, with 11 books and 4 suits.

Deal five cards to each player, place the balance of the cards in the center of all players. Starting from the left of the dealer, the 1st player asks another player for a particular card, one of which they hold in their hand. If the player they ask has that card, they hand over all the cards of that kind to the player that asked. If they do not have that card they respond Go Surf and the player must draw a card from the center stack. If a player receives the card that they asked for from another player or the stack, they go again. If not it&apos;s the next players turn. Four alike cards are a book. Players continue to collect books until all the cards are gone. The player with the most books wins. Grand National Derby Designed by Reiner Knizia 1996. Published by Piatnik. 2-5 players, played in about 30 minutes. From age of 10 years old.

There are two followers of this game with a changed theme: &quot;Titan: the Arena&quot; and &quot;Galaxy the Dark Ages&quot;.

The Grand National is Great Britain&apos;s most famous horse race over the fences. The horses are ready. The race can start. Take one fence at a time - but who will jump all of them to finish the race? And which player will win the most from his bets? Great Dalmuti, The Designed by Richard Garfield 1995. Published by Wizards of the Coast. For 5-8 players.

 Each player tries to get rid of his cards. The first who manages to do it becomes the Great Dalmuti. The last player becomes the great peon and deals the cards for the next game. The card mix is there is only 1 Great Dalmuti card, 2 Archbishops, 3 Earl Marshalls, 4 Baronesses, etc., down to 12 Peasants, plus 2 Jesters, which have the lowest standing but also have special powers. The lowest cards are the best ones. This brings subtleness in the game, wince with playing three, four or even five of a kind you can make sure that players with better cards will pass. Green Thumb Published by Playful Minds. Ages 7 and up. 2-5 players (best with 4). Although possible to played with 2 decks to squeeze in 7 players. Games last about 15-25 minutes.

 122 Cards in total. 24 Plant cards, 18 Defense Cards, 23 Attack Cards, 6 Disaster Cards, 4 Environment Cards and 7 Special Cards.

 Green Thumb cards captures much of the essence of gardening while enthralling with friendly competition between neighbors who wish to grow the same flowers. You will have to protect your plants from insects and mother nature. And you may even find yourself a bit envious of another players garden, deciding to send over a bug or two to transplant your favorite flower into your own garden. 

Exist also as a shareware computer game for PC on the official Playful Minds site. Groo Published by Archangel Entertainment 1997. Designed by Ken Whitman and Sergio Aragones. 2-4 players and takes about 45 minutes. Based upon a comics character called Groo.
 

The basic set includes 60 cards and seven dice, enough to play with up to four people. The expansion set includes another 55 cards, which will allow you to play with up to six people and makes it a better game independent of the number of players. 
 

Players compete to be the first to build a large town. Of course it isn&apos;t so easy as you are hindered by other players&apos; rampaging armies and the frequent bumbling visitations of Groo the Wanderer. Guillotine Published by Wizards of the Coast. Designed by Paul Peterson. 2-5 players and takes about 30 minutes. The deck contains 110 cards: 50 Noble Cards and 60 Action Cards.

This irreverent and humorous card game takes place during the French Revolution. Players represent rival guillotine operators vying for the best collection of noble heads over three rounds. Player build up their collection of cabezas with various members of the ruling class. The higher ranking the executee, the more valuable the addition to a players stockpile. But, conversely, players much take caution not to wind up with the remains of the &apos;Innocent Victim&apos; or the &apos;Clown&apos;, as such card will actually reduce a player&apos;s score. Hacker Design by Steve Jackson. Published by Steve Jackson Games 1992. For 2-6 players and takes about 120 minutes.

The Computer Crime Card Game. This game was written as a satirical comment on the Secret Service raid on Steve Jackson Games and the hacker community. The hacker community liked it. There&apos;s been no visible reaction from the Feds. 

Players use indials to break into systems and gain root access. Upgrade your hacking tools, deal with other hackers for access and phreak others onto your system. Avoid ICE and law enforcement raids to gain the greatest number of root access sites and win the game.

Theres an expansion published 1993 called &quot;Hacker II: The Dark Side&quot;. It allows 7 to 8 players to play and includes also outdials, military upgrades, multiple accounts, virtual bridges and increased security. It also includes new threats such as Black ICE, viruses and the worm. Hanafuda Hanafuda are a set of Japanese playing cards. They are often referred to as &apos;Flower cards&apos;, because each suit is depicted by a different flower. Each flower is representative of a calendar month around the time it comes into bloom. Indeed, the cards depict the yearly cycle using Japanese imagery. In addition to flowers the cards depict animals, birds, insects, a person and objects like prayer banners and a sake cup. Hand n Foot For 2-6 players, age 10 to adult. Takes 1-3 hours.

Similar to Canasta or Rummy.

The object is to play 22 cards in 2 stacks of 11 cards each: one called a &quot;Hand&quot;, the other called a &quot;Foot&quot;. To make at least 3 groups or more of 7 cards each, playing the Hand first, then the Foot, before going out. Players with the highest score after 4 rounds, wins.

Each card set includes 262 cards or 5 decks. Each card set also includes a set of rules, 6 hint cards and several promotional cards. Hellrail Designed by James Kyle and Wm. V. Niebling. First and secong edition (called Perdition) are published by Galloglass Games. &quot;Hellrail the 3rd Perdition&quot; is published by Mayfair Games Inc 2001.

For 3-4 players and takes about 60 minutes. From 10 years and up.

In the update of the Galloglass game are there are several refinements, but the major change is the addition of many more circle powers and the circle powers are now randomly distributed and may change during the game. The train engines are wood instead of pewter.

Each of the players fancies himself an engineer of the HellRail, conducting the souls of sinners to their torturous abodes in the great Inferno. But, only one of them will triumph and be spared eternal atrocity.

The cards contain sinners (loads), brimstone (fuel), and track, allowing the cards to be played any of three ways.

Each player has a wooden train marker, which he uses to mark his progress on the board. The cards form the track connecting the different levels of hell to the front gate and each other. The players train is formed of sinners which require the expenditure of brimstone to move. High Society Designed by Reiner Knizia. Published by Ravensburger 1995. For 3-5 players, age 12 and up. Takes about 30 minutes to play.

By playing money cards, players bid to get Possession and Title cards and to avoid Misfortune cards. As long as a player has not passed in a round, he can increase his bid by adding more money cards to outbid the others. A round of bidding is over when all players but one have passed. In the end, the player with the highest status, and who has more money than at least one other player, wins the game. Illuminati Designed by Steve Jackson 1985. Published by Steve Jackson Games. Reprinted 1999 as Deluxe Illuminati.

The new edition features full-color cards and improved money chits, but it&apos;s the same game of secret conspiracies battling for world control. 

The phone company is controlled by creatures from outer space. The Congressional Wives have taken over the Pentagon. And the Boy Sprouts are cashing in their secret Swiss bank account to smash the IRS! Two to six players compete to grab powerful groups and increase their wealth and power. No ploy is too devious, no stratagem too low, as you scheme your way to victory. 2-8 players and takes 180 minutes to play.

1995 was a CCG called &quot;Illuminati: New World Order&quot; released.

1999 was Illuminati Y2K released - a supplement deck for Illuminati with 110 more cards. 3-6 players

2001 was Illuminati Brainwash released and adds a gameboard to Deluxe Illuminati, letting players track (and change) the alignments of the whole world. This expansion is designed by Allen Varney and Steve Jackson. 2-8 players and takes 180 minutes to play. Jumbo Grand Prix Designed by Reiner Knizia 1998. Published by Jumbo. For 2-5 players and takes about 30 minutes.

 The object of the game is to create strong race cars and score the most racing points.

 Components: 56 playing cards (divided in 4 categories) and 20 scoring cards. Jungle Speed Designed by Thomas Vuarchex and Pierric Yakovenko. Created in 1991 and self-published it in 1996. Published 1996 by Goldsieber (German version called &apos;Arriba&apos;). French edition published 2000 by Asmodée.

 Contains a totem + 80 cards + a bag + game rules.

 All the cards are distributed, face down. Each player turns up a card in turn, until two cards show up with exactly the same drawing (the color isn&apos;t taken into account). When this situation arises, the 2 players with the identical drawing must grab the totem the fastest, all the other players must not intervein during this duel. The loser of this duel takes his cards back&amp;the cards of the winner and puts them under his stack. The aim of the game is the first player to get rid of all his cards. Kardinal und Koenig Kartenspiel Designed by Michael Schacht. Published by his own company Spiele aus Timbuktu 2001. For 3 to 5 players. Playing time is approximately 45 minutes. Based on the &quot;Web of Power&quot; boardgame from Rio Grande Games. 

Europe, the center of power in the 12th century. Influential Orders struggle for supremacy. By collecting Land cards, you can establish cloisters, bring advisors to council meetings, and improve your network of roads. According to which cards you choose, you can earn different amounts of victory points. At the end of the game, the player with the most victory points wins. 

Contents: 56 Land cards (4 x Danemark, 5 x England, 6 x Italien, 6 x Bayern, 6 x Ungarn, 7 x Kastilien, 7 x Franken, 7 x Sachen, 8 x Frankreich), 15 claiming stones, 8 Law cards, and 1 Scoring Chart. Katzenjammer Blues Designed by Reiner Knizia. Published by Goldsieber Spiele 
 1998. 2-6 players, age 10 and up. Takes about 30 minutes. English edition published by Rio Grande Games.

 It&apos;s showtime. The night-time cats are wailing their blues. The coolest feline foursomes are looking for gigs. Their managers bid high just to get them an audition. Finally all that counts are mice.

 It has a mix of rummy and auction rules. The game ends once 20 points totally have been scored and a 5-point penalty for most jokers. A quick, cutthroat card game, colourfully decorated with cartoony blues-band cats and mice. Killer Bunnies Published by Playroom Entertainment.
 

A non-collectible, expandable card game.
 

Each player is dealt 7 cards, 5 of which stay hidden and of 2 which must be obligated for play in upcoming rounds.
 

During the game, players collect Bunnies, which come in 5 different types and in 5 different colors. Bunnies are placed face up on the table in front of each player. 
 

When the game begins, one of the 12 Carrots is chosen at random to be the Magic (winning) Carrot. When players have at least one Bunny down they may choose or purchase Carrots from Kaballa&apos;s Market. The more Carrots a player collects, the better his chances are of winning the game. But in order to win, players must have at least one Bunny down (alive) when the game is over. 
 

The strategy is for each player to eliminate the other players&apos; Bunnies while protecting his own. 
 

Players may launch a Weapon against an opponent&apos;s Bunny. If the opponent cannot roll higher than the weapon level number then his Bunny will die. 
 

Players may also force an opponent to Feed The Bunny. If the opponent does not have enough Cabbage&amp;Water, then the Bunny will also die. (Players may use money to buy supplies from Kaballa&apos;s Market.) 
 

A player may use other nefarious cards to eliminate an opponent&apos;s Bunny.
 

When all of the Carrots have been taken from Kaballa&apos;s Market the game is over and the Magic Carrot is revealed. The player holding that Carrot is the winner! King of the Elves Designed by Alan R Moon 1999. German edition published by Amigo Spiele and English edition by Rio Grande Games. For 2-6 players and takes about 60 minutes to play.
 German name is &quot;König der Elfen&quot;.

 In these fantasy themed game is the Elven king is dead, and players are competing to become the next king. This game is similar in nature to Elfenroads and Elfenlands in that players try to visit as many cities as possible using optimal transportation cards. The difference is that the lay of the land is also dictated by cardplay. Other players may interfere with your journey through the use of thieves, obstacles, and sea serpents. Klunker Designed by Uwe Rosenberg. Published 1999 by Amigo Spiele (German) and Rio Grande Games (English). For 3-5 players and takes about 30 minutes.

A game about collecting sets of different kinds of jewelry. Players buy cards from each other and play cards out of their hands to complete sets of four. However, the points awarded for a complete set are adversely affected if multiple sets of similar cards already exist. Lord of the Fries Designed by James Ernest 1998. Published by Cheapass Games. For 3-8 players and takes about 45 minutes.

You&apos;re all zombies, trying to fill fast food orders with a limited supply of ingredients.

This is a thematic sequel to Give Me The Brain.

Some orders are easy, like the Cowabunga. One Cow Meat, one Bun. Some are a little harder, like the Chickabunga Conga: same as a Chickabunga (Bird Meat plus Bun), plus Fries and a Drink. Sound easy? Now try your hand at a Lord of the Fries, a Meat Munch, or the infamous Patriarch (Fish Meat, Cheese, Bun, Fries, Drink, and the oft-maligned Strawberry Pie). Lost Cities Designed by Reiner Knizia 1999. English edition by Rio Grande Games, German edition by Kosmos and French edition by Tilsit Éditions. 2-player game, which takes about 30 minutes.

 For the daring and adventurous, there are many lost cities to find and explore. The search can take you to the Himalayas, the Brazilian rain forest, the ever-shifting sands of the desert, ancient volcanoes and to Neptune’s Realm. 

 The object is to mount profitable expeditions to one or more of the five different lost cities. Card play is quite straightforward, with a few agonizing moments sprinkled through what is mostly a fast-moving game. If you start a given expedition, you&apos;d better make some progress in it, or it&apos;ll score you negative points. If you can make a lot of progress, you&apos;ll score quite well. After three rounds, the highest total score takes the day. Luck Plus Published 1983 by International Games, inc.
2-8 players, from age 7 and up.

An abstract card game where the object is to be the first player to eliminate all of your cards by making appropriate matches of numbers on cards to the dice. Lunch Money Designed by John Nephew 1996. Published by Atlas Games. For 2-4 players. You may combine several card decks if you are more people.

Lunch Money is a fast-paced, multi-player card game that combines dark, psychological images with the raw dynamics of a merciless street fight. 

You play cards to take your opponents&apos; counters from them and to defend your own counter pile. A player who runs out of counters is out of the game. The object of the game is to be the last person with any counters left. Manitou Designed by Günter Burkhardt. Published by Goldsieber Spiele 1997. For 2-4 players and takes about 45 minutes to play.

 Components 22 indians, 7 robber cards and 15 buffalo cards with different values for each player.

 It&apos;s time for the buffalo hunt. Each player displays the hunters and great warriors of his tribe which make up his hunting party. Great warriors can capture opponents&apos; tribesmen and score points for you. Strong hunters can win buffalo for the tribe. When every player has played 7 cards, the hunting is over. Metro Card game that shows players around London. Meuterer Designed by Marcel-Andre Casaola-Merkle. Published by Adlung-Spiele 2000. For 3-4 players (best with 4) and takes about 60 minutes to play.

 A successor to the game Verräter by the same publisher.

 Through bluff and strategy, players try to turn against the ship&apos;s captain, seizing the profits intended to be turned at the next port. Game includes a Pirate variant. 

 Meuterer is the German word for Mutineer. Mille Bornes Designed by Edmond Dujardin. Published by Parker Brothers and later by Winning Moves. Original French name is &quot;Mille Bornes&quot; and means &quot;thousand milestones&quot;. A game for 2, 3, 4 or 6 players, usually played as a partnership game by 4 players - 2 on each team. Original game since 1962. Takes about 45 minutes to play.
 

 The equipment consists of 112 Mille Borne cards, a score sheet and possibly a special card tray. The cards are: Distance Cards, Hazard Cards, Remedy Cards and Safety Cards.
 

 As a driver, you must follow the rules of the road. Namely: You can go only when the light is green. You must stop when the light is red. You must obey speed limit signs. If you get a flat tire, you must use a spare. If you run out of gas, you must refill your tank. If you have an accident, you must repair your car.
 

 You and your partner must try to travel 1,000 miles along an imaginary road. But be careful! Your opponents are trying to do the same and will try to slow you down by placing hazards in your path. Your challenge: to accumulate mileage by overcoming these hazards, while also trying to slow your opponents&apos; progress with hazards of your own.
 

 The final object of the game is to be the first team to accumulate a total of 5,000 points in several hands of play. In doing so, you must try to complete a trip of exactly 1,000 miles in each hand played. Mitchell Fan-created card game based on the 1975 adventure-cop movie. Game design Joe Fourhman 1998.

A fixed-deck card game (118 cards) for two to eight players, designed by Joseph Fourhman, based on the television show &quot;Mystery Science Theater 3000&quot; and the movie &quot;Mitchell.&quot; The deck contains 4 types of cards: Investigation cards, Action cards, Reaction cards and Suspect cards plus two additional cards: Mitchell himself and the Plot card.

Try to avoid being investigated by puffy-faced detective Mitchell. Mitchell&apos;s sheer doggedness and eye for clues keeps him bouncing from suspect to suspect, looking for free soup and potato cakes. 

Win the game by playing all your cards. Try to keep your opponent from winning by sending Mitchell after him. Mit List und Tücke Designed by Klaus Palesch, published by Berliner Spielkarten Gmbh&amp;Cie KG (a Ravensburger label), 1999.
For 4-6 players and takes 30-60 minutes to play.

The deck has four suits, each numbered from 1 to 21. After a player leads a card, other players may follow with any card they wish. The high card of the led suit wins that player’s choice of half the cards in the trick. Whoever played the lowest card of any other suit gets the rest and leads to the next trick. Money Designed by Reiner Knizia 1999. German edition published by Goldsieber Spiele and English edition by Rio Grande Games. For 3-5 players and takes about 30 minutes to play.

Players enter the volatile currency market. They begin with a small holding and use it through successive auctions to build a valuable currency portfolio. Each round they bid to exchange a portion of their holdings for new holdings offered on the market or those of other players. Mü und Mehr Designed by Doris Matthäus and Frank Nestel 1995. Published by their own compane Doris&amp;Frank. For 3-6 players and takes about 90 minutes to play.

Amigo held a license of Mü from 1996 to 2001 and sold a slightly different edition with only four games in the box and the Hedgehog suite replaced by Fishes. 

On the nomination list for Game of the Year 1996. Rank 4 at the Deutscher Spielepreis 1996 and Card Game of the Year in Germany 1996. 

A special 5 suited card deck and a collection of 6 different games. This game is also avaiblable from Amigo with 4 rules in the box. Most well known Mü itself, a trick taking game with variable partnership play and a very special bidding phase. The game is highly tactical and a must for experienced card players. Mystery Rummy Designed by Mike Fitzgerald 1998. Published by US Games. 2-4 players and take about 45 minutes.

 This game attaches an interesting theme to a fairly standard Rummy framework. Playing Victims, Suspects, Scenes, and Evidence-melds, players try to build a case against various suspects for the famous Jack the Ripper serial murders. 

 Quick summary of play and scoring for Mystery Rummy Case Number 1: Jack the Ripper (1998), this mysterious rummy game which is first in a series which also includes Case Number 2: Murders in the Rue Morgue (1999), Case Number 3: Jekyll&amp;Hyde 2001 and Case Number 4: Wanted Dead or Alive. Mystic War Designed by James Hlavaty. Published 1992 by Prism Games / 
 TimJim Games. For 3-8 players and takes about 90 minutes to play.
 

The aim is to reach the target on the victory card you have drawn at the beginning of the game. The victory condition may be one of the following: 
 Archmage (10 followers, 40 mystic power, 10 gold), 
 City (40 followers, 10 mystic power, 10 gold), 
 Hoard (10 followers, 10 mystic power, 40 gold), 
 Balanced (20 followers, 20 mystic power, 20 gold) 
 

By using cards you try to reach the above options, as well as hinder your opponent. Each 10 of followers make you draw an extra card, each 10 of mystic power make you keep an extra card and each 10 of gold gives you some other advantages. The different levels also gives you other advantages. 
 

With the resource cards you may either increase or decrease the values on whichever player you want. There are also spell cards, deity cards and event cards, which may affect the game. Nanofictionary Designed by Andrew Looney. Published by Looney Labs. For 3-6 players, age 10 and up. Takes 30-45 minutes to play.

A game about making up tiny stories. Even an extremely short narrative can tell a complete story, provided it contains each of four specific &quot;plot devices,&quot; namely: a Setting, a Problem, at least one Character, and a Resolution. In this card game then, there are four basic types of cards, corresponding to these four plot devices. Each player works at developing the basic structure of a story by building up a collection of these cards. A fifth type of card, called an Action, will allow players to add Complications to their stories, Brainstorm new ideas, Plagiarize from other players, and Uncrumple old ideas out of the discard pile.

The game progresses through three separate phases. First comes the Writing Phase, in which everyone develops the outline of a story by collecting the 4 types of plot devices. Then, in the Storytelling Phase, the players take turns telling short stories based on their cards, embellishing as needed to unite and explain the elements on the cards. This is followed by the Awards Phase, in which prize cards are given to the authors of the most popular stories. However, extra points are also awarded for finishing early, and for having more cards in your story, so the winner is determined at the very end, when everyone adds up their points. Whoever gets the highest overall score wins. Nertz Fast-paced, interactive abstract card game requiring
 quick reflexes, concentration amid chaos and a desire to
 enjoy good competitive fun with friends. Played with two opposing teams.

 The object of Nertz is to score 100 points as quickly as
 possible in as few hands as necessary.

 Includes 52 cards numbered 1-13 in four suits. The Blue, Red, Yellow and White suits have corresponding colored numbers. The Nertz deck also includes two cards that have the Nertz logo in black and white. Two Nertz decks (one Red, one Blue) are required to play Nertz. 

Can also be played with two standard card decks. Nuclear War Designer is Douglas Malewicki 1965. Published by Flying Buffalo Inc. For 2-6 players and takes about 60 minutes to play. It&apos;s said to be possible to be played with up to 20 players with more decks!

A comical cataclysmic card game, a humorous confrontation between touchy world powers as each player attempts to sway his opponents’populations with diplomacy, propaganda, and finally nuclear weaponry. Little old ladies defect in electric cars and the dread supergerm spreads devastation. Oflameron Russian game from the early 20th century where players plot markers through a field of cards with different point values. Oh Scrud A fast-paced spelling game, with everyone working as fast as they can to build words from their cards at the same time. 108 cards. Once Upon a Time Designed by Andrew Rilstone, James Wallace and Richard Lambert 1998. (There are earlier edition, at least from before 1994.) Published by Atlas Games. For 2-6 players and takes about 10 minutes to play.

 The players create a story together, using cards that show typical elements from fairy tales. One player is the Storyteller, and creates a story using the ingredients on her cards. She tries to guide the plot towards her own ending. The other players try to use cards to interrupt her and become the new Storyteller. The winner is the first player to play out all her cards and end with her Happy Ever After card. Overthrone Designed by Frank DiLorenzo and Stacey Merrill 1999. Published by R&amp;R;Games. For 3-6 players and takes about 90 minutes. From 12 years and up.

A card game of power and politics in 17th century France. You play one of six Nobles trying to build the largest power base while bringing down your opponents. Power is gained by having Courtiers&amp;Provinces in play. One action each turn which can include Attacks, Bribes and Duels. With the addition of Event cards you can have Rebellions, Uprisings, Bandits and more. Phase 10 Designed by Kenneth Johnson 1982. Published by Fundex. For 2-6 players. Played in 45 minutes. Republished 1992 by Fundex Games / Third Quarter Corporation.

Equipment: one deck of 108 cards: 24 each of red, orange, yellow, and green cards numbered &quot;1&quot; through &quot;12&quot;, and four &quot;Skip&quot; cards and eight &apos;wild&quot; cards.

A rummy-type card game where players compete to be the first to finish completing all ten phases. Phases include collecting runs of numbers, collecting certain number of a given color cards, etc. After the tenth phase, the player with the least number of points win. Pit Original game from 1919. Published by Parker Brothers 1947 and later edition by Winning Moves. For 3-8 players and takes about 90 minutes to play. From age 7 and up.

 The game is based on the exciting scenes of the American Corn Exchange. There are nine cards each of Barley, Corn, Coffee, Oranges, Oats, Soy, Sugar, or Wheat. The idea is to obtain, by trading, all nine cards of any one kind. If you do this, you have a CORNER. If you corner Wheat, (by getting all nine Wheat Cards), you get 100 points; Corn, 75 points; Oats, 60 points, etc., as indicated on the cards. The game is 500 points. Power Lunch Designed by Jessie Carr and Rob Anderson 1994. Published by Mayfair Games. For 2-6 players.

Each player attempts to score the most points by melding personality cards onto the playing board, a restaurant. If the cards are not sets or sequences (rummy-style), then you need to give a reason why they&apos;d be sitting together. When a player empties his hand or when all tables are closed, the hand ends and points are scored.

Conversation flies in this card game involving well-known personalities at power lunches. Players score points for coming up with creative and plausible reasons why the celebrities in their hand would meet over lunch. Prefix A word game for two or more players from 10 years and up. Published by Merriment Incorporated.
 

Will you sprint to print the longest list?... Choose to use the longest words?... or plan to land the bonus points? Whatever you do, it&apos;s go to be fast if you&apos;re going to win this game of words.
 

From the very first flip of the card, you&apos;re in a highspeed race against time and opponents. Fast writing and quick thinking help, but a pinch of luck gives everyone the chance to win this unpredictable race of words. Queen&apos;s Necklace Designed by the French designers Bruno Faidutti&amp;Bruno Cathala. Published by Days of Wonder. For 2-4 players and takes about 30-45 minutes to play. 

Queen&apos;s Necklace is a game of gem-selling, influence and intrigue at the Court. Two to four players compete in the role of Royal Jeweler to sell rare jewels to the Queen and her court.

Jeweler&apos;s loupe in hand, you must decide how best to spend your hard-earned ducats: on the acquisition of beautiful gems: ambers, diamonds, emeralds, and rubies; or to buy the favors of the various court followers. After three years of craftsmanship, the jeweler who sells the most precious gems and builds the largest fortune will receive the coveted title of King&apos;s Jeweler and a place at the Court. Quicksingle Developed and published by CKC International. From 7 years and up.

A card game based upon the cricket sport.

The game consists of three decks of cards:
- The bowler is dealt a hand of seven bowling cards; These become the selection of possible deliveries for the over.
- Each batter is dealt six batting cards. This is the selection of possible batting shots.
The batting cards are made up of off side and leg side cards and shots can be played into any of the four quadrants of the field.
- The fielder is dealt nine fielding cards, one card for each of the fielders postions. Some of the fielding cards are marked as &quot;catching&quot; cards.
After playing their card the player who is fielding replaces their card from the top of fielding deck so that they always have nine cards in their hand. Quiddler Published by Set Enterprises Inc 1998. A word game for 1-8 players. 

Two decks of cards, each with a letter or two-letter combination, a point value in the corner, and a Celtic-style illuminated letter in the middle of the card.

Each person takes turns drawing and discarding, picking a card either from the deck or the top of the discard pile. When a player can form a word or words using up all of the cards in their hand they lay their cards down on the table. Rack-O Published by Parker Brothers 1992. for 2-4 players, age 8 and up. Also possible to play with partnerships. There is at least one really old edition published by Miltron Bradley Company.

 An abstract card game a deck of cards numbered 1 to 60, four card racks and one card tray.

 The object is to be first to score 500 points in several rounds of play. Each round, you replace the cards in your rack so their numbers read in any numerical progression from a low number at the front to a high number at the back. Rage The latest (German) edition is from Amigo Spiele 2001, although it has been published earlier by International Games as well as by Mattel 1983. For 2-10 players, age 11 and up.

 An abstract card game from the makers of Uno. Rage combines strategy, skill and luck for fun and excitement. The object is to score the highest number of points by taking the same number of tricks you bid.

 The players use the deck of 108 cards total including 6 suits of cards each numbered 0 - 15 (suits coloured red, blue, green, yellow, orange, and purple) and 12 special cards including: 2 wild rage cards, 3 out rage cards, 3 change rage cards, 2 mad rage cards, 2 bonus rage cards. Red Dwarf Designed by Joe Fourhman 1996.

There are four types of cards: Mission cards, Travel cards, Re-Cyc cards and four cast cards.

Fan-created card game based on the long-running British sitcom. Download and print the cards. Complete rulebook on line.

Send the cast of Red Dwarf throughout the ship, outer space and the timestream itself in search of fun, love and an edible pot noodle. Score plot points by completing having the cast complete various missions. Try to keep your opponent from scoring by interfering with his plans. Res Publica Designed by Reiner Knizia. Published by Hexagames 1991, Queen Games 1998 and Avalanche Press Ltd 2000.

 For 3-5 players and takes about 60 minutes. Age 8 and up. Contains 140 cards. Won &quot;Game of the year&quot; award for best card game in Germany 1991. This German version was published by F.X.Schmidt.

 It&apos;s built upon a Rummy system. You gradually build up a hand until you can lay down five &apos;peoples&apos; cards selected from the Romans, Greeks, Huns and so on. This enables you to start collecting &apos;culture&apos; cards which, again, you need five of before you can start claiming the points cards with which you win the game. Scottentots Designed by Reiner Knizia 1999. Published by ASS. A 2-player game, which takes about 20 minutes to play.

Spring is in the air over the Scottish Highlands. Birds chirp peacefully above the grazing pasture between the villages of North- and South-Scottenbury. Suddenly there are heard wild battle-shouts from both north and south, and in no time the fiercest men of both villages face each other across the pasture.

There are nine prizes up for grabs in a game, and the goal is to either score five of them or three in a row. Play three cards on your side of the prize that beat your opponent&apos;s effort on the other side. Players use the deck consisting of one through nine in six suits to build poker-like efforts.

By many compared as a predecessor to &apos;Lost Cities&apos;, by the same designer. Set Designed by M Falco 1991. Published by Ravensburger and by Set Enterprises Inc. For 2-8 players and takes about 30 minutes.

Card game based on visual perception. The deck contains 81 cards, with symbols in all combinations.

 The object of the game is to identify a &apos;Set&apos; of three cards from 12 cards laid out on the table. Each card has a variation of the following four features: Color, Symbol, Number and Shading. Settlers of Catan Designed by Klaus Teuber and based upon his board game &apos;The Settlers of Catan&apos;. The full name of this is &apos;Settlers of Catan Card Game&apos;. German edition &apos;Siedler von Catan Kartenspiele&apos; published by Kosmos.

For 2 Players, ages 10 and up, playing time 45-90 minutes.
English edition by Mayfair Games.

Players begin play with a small principality and two settlements worth two victory points. Victory is yours when you achieve 12 victory points. Players can attack an opponent or focus on expansion through new settlements, holdings and trade to enlarge the principality. Added regions and holdings increase production and improving settlements to cities gains victory points in your struggle to win the contest. Hire knights to engage in tournaments, utilize spies and other special features to thwart your opponents plans. ShowBiz Shuffle Designed by Joan Wendland 1998 and published by Blood and Cardstock Games 2002. Artwork by Larry DeSouza 1999. For 2-4 players 13 years old and up.

Played with 144 cards of 4 types: Bod cards and Biz cards, which are held in the players hand. Genre cards and Cheater cards are used to help play run more smoothly. 

You play the heads of rival movie studios. Out mogul your competition by using the best actors and directors to make big box office hits. Of course if that doesn&apos;t work you could try giving them bad ratings or a drug problem.

Bod card has five cells which are color coded to show the movies the actor or director is good at making: Action, Romance, Drama, Family or Specialty.

When the last card in the Bod deck is drawn, the end game ensues. Beginning with the current player&apos;s turn, each player may complete one final turn. All finished movies scores and unfinished movies gives deduction from the score. Skip-Bo Published 1999 by Mattel Inc. For 2-6 players, individually or partnered. Age 7 and up. Takes 20-40 minutes to play.

 An abstract card game with 144 cards numbered 1 through 12 plus 18 SKIP-BO cards for a total of 162.

 Object is to be the first player to play all the cards in your &quot;stock&quot; pile. 

Skip-Bo is the commercial version of the traditional game known as &quot;Spite and Malice&quot;. Snowball Fight Family game that incorporates the fun and excitement of a snowball fight with the strategy and skill of a card game. Somerset Game using a fifty card deck that consists of seven suits that are portrayed as fractions. Spammers Design&amp;Graphic Design by Jeff Tidball. Published 1998 by Atlas Games. For 2-6 players (best with 3-4). Age 13 and up.

 Including 110 cards, 120 counters and a single die.

 In Spammers, you&apos;ll jump on the e-mail bandwagon. You&apos;ll send mountains of the stuff to unsuspecting mailing lists like Bigots on Parade, the Ivory Tower Academics, and the Last Few Communists. You&apos;ll run scams like the Envelope Stuffer&apos;s Clearinghouse, E-Mail Order Brides, and Walter&apos;s Wankery.

 The object of the game is to have at the beginning of your turn a collection of Scams whose ratings sum to 20 or more or a single scam with a rating of 12 or more. Stack 21 Published by Enginuity LLC. Designed by Andy Daniel.

 An abstract card game including 104 cards. For 2-4 players, ages 8 to adult.

 The object is to make as many of your stacks count exactly 21 as possible, while impeding your opponents&apos; progress. You draw a card at your turn, and can add it to one of your own Stacks, or, if you don&apos;t want to keep the card, you can place in face up onto one of your opponents&apos; stacks - but if the card you gave them puts their stack over 21, you get it back, and are stuck with it. Sting Copyright 1984 international Game Inc.

For 2-6 players, age 9 to adult. Contains 106 cards.

Game in the rummy family. The object of the game is to be the first player to rid your hand of all cards by giving them to your opponents.

Summary of play: Deal 10 cards to each player. Then each player in turn tries to get rid of his cards by grouping the cards in his hand into runs and sets and then placing the cards in front of any opponents. The round is over when a player gets rid of his cards. Player with the lowest point total at the end of 5 rounds is the winner. Stock Car Championship Racing Designed by John McLaughlin and Michael Garton. Published 1995 by McGartlin Motorsport Design. For 2-12 players and takes about 60 minutes to play.
 

Flag to Flag Racing has invent a new exciting racing game. Pits, caution flags, driver arguments, wrecks, its all here in this exciting new game. 
 

The Track Deck determines the number of laps for each turn and any major events such as accidents and car problems that can occur during a race. There are 3 Track Decks available and each one has been developed to statistically simulate the action on actual stock car racing tracks. The SuperSpeedway deck allows you to race on large, high speed tracks, while the One Mile Oval and Short Track decks recreate all the action found on the shorter tracks. With all three decks, you can easily create a championship season that follows actual stock car events. A Driver Deck is used to perform actions and respond to events during the race. A Driver Deck is required for each player. Survival of the Witless Published by Avalanche Press 1997. For 3 - 8 players, ages 12 and up.

 Use, sex, politics, and the invincible &quot;race&quot; card in this multi-player game of that medieval academic ritual - Tenure. Seek the ultimate in bourgeois security by being the first to publish your book and gain tenure. Tabula Rasa Designed by Reiner Knizia 1999. Published by W&amp;L.;For 2-4 players and takes about 30 minutes to play.

An abstract game where players play cards in an effort to acquire tiles that are either color-coded or number-coded. Players take turns, first playing a card onto a tile that matches either the card&apos;s number or its color, then drawing to refill their hands. When all cards have been played, each tile is evaluated, and whichever player has the most cards played to that tile gets that tile&apos;s points. After calculating point totals and figuring in bonuses, the player with the highest score is the winner.

Ten estates for the taking. Playing clockwise, place one of your knights into an estate to strengthen your claim. In the end, the player with the most knights in an estate takes possession. The player with the most valuable estates wins the game. Take 6 Designed by Klaus Palesch and Wolfgang Kramer. Published in USA by US Games 1996. German edition is called &quot;6 Nimmt!&quot; and is published 1994 by Amigo Spiel. For 2-10 players and takes about 45 minutes to play.

It has a deck of cards numbered 1 to 104. Players are given a hand of cards and then five more are played face up in the middle of the table. Players secretly pick one of their cards, and then in ascending order the cards are added to those in the middle of the board. When the sixth card of a set is placed in the middle, the five cards are taken by that player, leaving the sixth card to start a new set. Plus, each card has a variable number of bullheads on it, and when someone has taken sixty-six points worth of bullheads, the player with the lowest total is the winner. Target Designed by Andy Daniel. Published by Enginuity 1997. For 2-4 players and takes about 20 minutes. Age 8 to adult.

Includes 110 cards and instructions.

a rummy game like nothing you&apos;ve ever played. One deck of 80 &quot;Playing&quot; cards are numbered 0 though 9 in 4 colorful suits, plus a 5th &quot;wild&quot; suit, and are used for making melds. Another deck contains 28 all-different &quot;Target&quot; cards, each of which describes a meld and a point value, the more difficult melds having a higher point value. Five Target cards are dealt face up for all to see. Players draw and discard as in rummy. When a player lays down the meld shown on one of the Target cards, they win that Target card, and score the points. A new Target card is then dealt to replace it, so the melds change all the time! What&apos;s more, players can win 2 or more Target cards on a single play by laying down groups of Playing cards which make the melds on 2 or more Target cards. That Guy Created by John Heffron and Joel Zimmer. Published by Eleven Eleven Productions 2000.

A card game that puts women on a scavenger hunt for types of men. Great for bachelorette parties, or girls night out.

Before you hit the town, deal the cards equally to all members of your party.
Hit the town, and try to find real-life guys who match the guys you&apos;ve been dealt, or get real-life guys to do what your card asks. Each time you find a match, or get a guy to do what the card asks, you turn in that card.
Whoever gets rid of all their cards first wins.

The deck contains 38 &quot;That Guy cards&quot;, 5 &quot;Catty cards&quot; and 8 &quot;Command cards&quot;. Tightrope A pretty abstract game about balancing. A trick-taking game designed by Reiner Knizia 1999 and published by ASS in Germany. German name is &apos;Drahtseilakt&apos;.

Each turn, a number of red and blue sticks are up for grabs. The highest card played will take the blue sticks and the lowest card will take the red sticks. The trick is that a red stick cancels a blue stick (that is, a well balanced tighrope walker), and the goal is to score as few points as possible.

The basic game has players simultaneously playing cards, whereas the strategic version plays like a trick-taking game with players selecting a card sequentially. Titan the Arena Fantasy arena combat game by Reiner Knizia. Published by Avalon Hill 1997. 3-6 players.

Titan: the Arena is a rework of Reiner Knizias &quot;Grand National Derby&quot;. 

A sci-fi themed rework by Don Greenwood is called &quot;Galaxy: The Dark Ages&quot;. This one is published by GMT Games year 2000.

You bet on different creature cards and play strength cards on them later to make your bets win in the combat phase. Toe to Toe Baseball Published by Head to Head Baseball Inc 1998.

A game of baseball played with a custom 72 card deck using all the rules of real baseball.

Two players take turns being the hitter or fielder, through 9 innings just like in a real baseball game. The cards let you pitch, hit, strike guys or gals out, hit home-runs, turn double plays, steal bases, sacrifice flys, bunt, pull your pitcher, pinch hit and more. The rules are divided into two parts, a Training Camp to start out and the Major Leagues for more advanced players. Tracs Designed 2001 by K Burns.
 

The game is used as a Tool for Research on Adaptive Cognitive Strategies.
 

 Abstract card game played with a deck of double-sided cards. The backs of the cards show black shapes and the fronts of the cards show colored sets. The two tread designs illustrate the odds in the deck. The deck can be adjusted for 1-4 players and different levels of skill. The rules are easy for children to learn yet challenging enough for experts to play. The same game (with minor variations) can be played alone, against others or on teams. Unity Designed by Dan Olds. Published 1998 by Yeshuateinu Company.

Contains 100 cards. Takes 3-30 minutes to play.

Unity is an exciting original biblical card game where you can have fun learning biblical principles. 

You can learn the word of God while playing because each card has a scripture reference. You play righteous cards in Unity to defeat evil attacks, or can defeat the evil attacks in many other ways. You can invite other players to enter into righteousness. If you don’t enter in–watch out!
It’s a way to learn biblical principles. You can celebrate the biblical festivals by playing special festival cards. UNO Designed by Merle Robbins 1981. Published by IGI Mattel. For 2-10 players and takes about 30 minutes to play. From 7 years to adult.

 Players race to empty their hands and catch opposing players with cards left in theirs, which score points. In turns, players attempt to play a card by matching its color, number or word to the topmost card on the discard pile. If unable to play, players draw cards from the draw pile until they are able to place a card. There are also wild and special cards. Vom Kap bis Kairo Designed by Günter Burkhardt. Published 2001 by Adlung-Spiele. For 2-4 players and takes about 30 minutes. The game is only published in German. The title means &quot;From Cape (Town) to Kairo&quot;.

 Players attempt to be the first to build a railway route from Cape to Cairo through various terrain types in Africa. 

 You bid on terrain cards and purchase missing tracks necessary to cross terrain. Each turn, a number of terrain cards are auctioned off and placed before the appropriate player&apos;s train, representing the next space to be crossed.

 Terrain cards show a number of tracks ranging from 0 to 3 and require from 6 to 10 tracks to cross depending on the type of terrain.

 The first player to complete the crossing over eight terrain segments is the winner. Was Sticht A German game published by Mosquito 1997. Designed by Karl-Heinz Schmiel. 3-4 players. A card game with a number and a colour as trump. These are hidden from the beginning except for one of the players (the dealer).
 

First is 4 different goal tokens taken by each players. The goals may be &quot;take last trick&quot;, &quot;avoid all red cards&quot;, &quot;take most tricks&quot;, &quot;take 3 tricks&quot;.
 

All cards are dealt openly in columns with 4 cards. In the first phase are cards chosen one by one of the players and the one who knows the trump. After every round of choosing cards from the first free column the dealer says who gets the trick if it was played. In this way the other may guess the trump combination.
 

The second phase starts with that all players except the dealer chooses one of their target tokens and reveals them simultaneously. The dealers goal is to reach one of the other players goal alone. 
 

Then it&apos;s an ordinary trick-taking games with the trump numbers as highest cards in the trump colour. Everyone who reaches his goal may discard his goal token. The dealer may choose which of his tokens he may discard.
 

The winner is the one who has discarded all of his goal tokens. Waterworks Originally published by Hasbro 1972. Now licenced to Winning-Moves 1996. For 2-4 players, 8 years to adult. Takes about 30 minutes to play.

Contains 88 cards and 8 plumber disks.

 Object is to be the first player to build a complete, leak free, pipeline from your valve card to your spout card. The number of pipe cards you need to place in between them (but not including them) varies by the number of players. Werewolf A seven or more player game. Wizard Designed by Ken Fisher 1983. Published 1986 by Bicycle and US Games. 1996 it was licensed to Amigo-Spiele for a German version.
 

For 3-6 players and takes about 20 minutes to play.
 

With a 60 card deck comprising a standard deck plus 4 Wizards (high) and 4 Jesters (low). In the first hand 1 card is dealt to each player. In the second 2 and so on. The game is over after the hand in which all cards are dealt. 
 

After examining your cards you state the number of tricks you will win. Each round each player puts down one card. The first Wizard played wins the trick followed by the highest trump card followed by the highest card in the suit of the first card played. 
 

You get 20 points for correctly predicting how many tricks you will win plus 10 points for each trick won. You lose 10 points for each trick over or under the amount you predicted. Zar Designed by Lynn Dalton. 

 ZAR is a cross between UNO and speed. The decks are out of print. It&apos;s based on Crazy Eights and other folk games that are played with a standard deck of cards.

There are three colors. With an Uno deck, use yellow, green, and blue. In each color, use the following cards: 
2x 1s, 2x 2s, 2x 3s, 2x 4s, 2x 5s, 2x 6s, 2x skips, 2x draw twos, 2x reverses. 
Additionally there are these non-color cards: 2x type I wild cards (use Uno wild cards), 2x type II wild cards (use Uno draw fours), 2x type I &quot;dragons&quot; (use Uno red 8s) and 2x type II &quot;dragons&quot; (use Uno red 9s).

The object is to get rid of all your cards; playing consists of discarding a card onto the discard pile. Zero Designed by Reiner Knizia. Published 1999 by Berliner Spielkarten. For 3-6 players and takes about 30 minutes to play. Age 8 to adult.

56 coloured cards with numbers.

Object of the game is to swap one card from their hands with a card from the pool. Each player aims to score as few points as possible at the end of the round. If a player succeeds in achieving a hand with zero points the round ends immediately. 

After playing a number of rounds, the player with the least points overall is the winner. 
 Open Directory Society: Religion and Spirituality: Divination: Cartomancy: Tarot 
 Copyright©2012 Netscape Terms of Use Last update: Wednesday, March 21, 2007 7:07:20 PM EDT - edit
	</body>
</document>
