<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000690" url="http://www.menuhouse.com/" time="2012-07-12-15:59" support="3" score="0.006642748436245947" bingtitle="Restaurant menu design | Takeout Menu Printing at low prices" webtitle="Restaurant menu design | Takeout Menu Printing at low prices">
			<query id="001502" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000056" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="000059" bing-rank="181"/>
	<description>Menu Design • Menu Printing • Tri-Fold Takeout Menus • Cafe Style Menu Inserts • Business Cards • Postcards</description>
	<body>
		Home 
 
 Samples 
 
 Customers 
 
 Templates 
 
 About Us 
 
 Printing Prices 
 Get a Quote 
 
 
 
 

 Menu Design•Menu Printing• Tri-Fold Takeout Menus•Cafe Style Menu Inserts•Business Cards•Postcards
 
 
 


 
Menu designs are an important part of the appearance of your restaurant and the impact they have can be as important as the food you are serving. People are very impressionable and will appreciate a creative logo or individualized designs. When the menu design, restaurant theme, and cuisine served are in accord, your restaurant will come across as more put together and efficient.


For restaurants with take-out options, Menuhouse.com can help boost sales. Pizza parlors, Coffee shops, Sandwich shops, diners and other local food providers can utilize full color take out menus and fliers to target potential customers who live in neighborhoods surrounding your business.

If you currently have a black&amp;white menu file (example: PDF file), send it to us and we&apos;ll add color to really make your menu stand out! We can easily add a full color background for a professional look!

Loyalty programs and coupons can also be added to the take-out menu brochure printing to help persuade customers to return.





 







 
 

 


 
Your Menu Design will WOW your customers!

Now available - Rigid litho printed
laminated menus, which are washable
Custom printed, starting at quantities of 100

Printed on PVC•Laminated with a Polish or Matte Finish

30 mil thick, very durable!

Ask us for a quote today!

941-722-1416
 


 



 NEW - Coupon Cards! Call 941-722-1416 or Visit BestDealCards.com
 
 
 
 Find Out More About Coupon Cards - Call 941-722-1416 

 All cards are printed on Thick card stock in full color with Gloss UV Coating
	</body>
</document>
