<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000266" url="http://chico.ebayclassifieds.com/antiques/marysville/vintage-ashtray-collection-for-sale/?ad=1500508" time="2012-07-12-15:27" support="2" score="0.0026094350888856326" bingtitle="Vintage Ashtray Collection for Sale | Marysville | eBay ..." webtitle="Vintage Ashtray Collection for Sale | Marysville | eBay Classifieds (Kijiji) | 1500508">
			<query id="001043" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000523" bing-rank="54"/>
	<description>Avoid fraud by meeting all sellers in-person to pay for items. eBay ... A McDonald&apos;s fast food restaurant metal ashtray. A 22 Karat gold inlaid one from the Cocoanut ...</description>
	<body>
		Free, Friendly, Local 
 Create your FREE Ad 
 What In All Categories For sale Pets Housing Cars&amp;vehicles Community Jobs Resumes Services Where Search 
 Chico Change default location... 
 
 
 

 eBay Classifieds  »  For sale  »  Antiques 
 Vintage Ashtray Collection for Sale - Please Contact (Marysville) 
 
 
 
 View larger image 
 
         
 

 
 Posted by: Caposhi | View all ads Profile: Registered user, Active since 01/2010 
 
View my profile on:

 linkedin-button-plugin 
 Reply By Email 
 Flag this ad 
 Spam / Duplicates Prohibited / Fraud Miscategorized 
 
 Important Safety Tips: 
Avoid fraud by meeting all sellers in-person to pay for items. eBay Classifieds does not offer any transaction or payment services. Stay safe - read our safety tips . 
 Price: Please Contact Address: Marysville, CA 95901
 ( map ) Date Posted: 06/20/12 Description: Vintage Ashtray collection for sale, all in excellent condition. 10 ashtrays. Buy as many as you would like, or buy them all.

They are ceramic and metal ones. For example, a large Freeman McFarlin Crystal Crackle Jewel Glaze Ashtray, and other ceramic ashtrays from the 50s and 60s.

A Tilso Mama&amp;Kittens Pottery Ashtray made in Japan.

A McDonald&apos;s fast food restaurant metal ashtray.

A 22 Karat gold inlaid one from the Cocoanut Grove at the Ambassador Hotel!!!!

The Ambassador Hotel was a landmark hotel in Los Angeles, California and location of the Cocoanut Grove nightclub. It was the place where presidential candidate, United States Senator and former U.S. Attorney General Robert F. Kennedy was shot on the morning of June 5, 1968.

Some ashtrays are very large from the company&quot;Calif. USA&quot;., which are Art Deco style.

A large Newport cigarette one. There are also other very interesting ones.

Very nice collectible pieces.

Prices vary with each ashtray. Choose to buy as many as you would like or make an offer on all.

Local pick up only.
 
 Ad ID: 1500508 Share: Click to copy 
 
 
 Need help? Just contact Customer Support . 
 Similar ads Recently viewed ads 
 $125 RARE ANTIQUE LEATHER BOOK 1902 -- AUSTIN DOBSON COLLECTED POEMS Posted: 06/19/12 
Recently viewed ads
 
 Page of | Clear all | See all ( ) 
 Why list Vintage Ashtray Collection for Sale on eBay Classifieds? It&apos;s Free, Friendly&amp;Local 

 Share ad via email To: From: (Your email) Subject: Vintage Ashtray Collection for Sale - (Marysville) on eBay Classifieds Message: Send me a copy of this email 

 Validation code By clicking Send your email you agree to our terms of use and privacy policy .   Help About Blog Mobile Apps Privacy Policy Terms of Use Contact Us Popular Items Twitter Facebook YouTube 
Copyright © 2012 eBay International AG Close [x] Your email  * Message  *  Send me a copy of email Validation code Send your email By clicking Send you agree to our terms of use and privacy policy . Your message will be emailed to the poster and not made public.
	</body>
</document>
