<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000179" url="http://officespace.oodle.com/bernalillo-nm/" time="2012-07-12-15:22" support="1" score="0.0007879739342667958" bingtitle="Office Space for Rent in Bernalillo, NM | Commercial Property on ..." webtitle="Office Space for Rent in Bernalillo, NM | Commercial Property on Oodle Marketplace">
			<query id="000802" bing-rank="176"/>
	<description>... on Facebook and Oodle to find unique used cars for ... $46 Retail-Commercial for Lease: Fast Food Restaurant for Lease ... retail use. One-half mile from interstate 25 exit.</description>
	<body>
		Bernalillo, NM 
 
 Browse 
 Merchandise Cars Rentals Real Estate Jobs Pets Tickets All Vehicles Motorcycles Boats RVs All Rentals Office Space Vacation Rentals All Pets Dogs Cats Horses Services Personals Community 
 
 Post Sign In 
 Office Space 
 Home Merchandise Cars Rentals Real Estate Jobs Office Space More 
 Merchandise Cars Rentals Real Estate Jobs Pets Tickets All Vehicles Motorcycles Boats RVs All Rentals Office Space Vacation Rentals All Pets Dogs Cats Horses Services Personals Community 
 
 Login Ask Search Post Search Office Space &gt; USA &gt; NM &gt; Bernalillo Searches Related to
Office Space for Rent in Bernalillo, NM
 Office Space on Oodle New York Office Space Los Angeles Office Space Chicago Office Space Houston Office Space Phoenix Office Space Philadelphia Office Space San Antonio Office Space San Diego Office Space Dallas Office Space Detroit Office Space Best Match 
 Best Match Posted Date Price: low&gt;high Price: high&gt;low Distance 
 
Office Space for Rent in Bernalillo, NM
 (1 - 10 of 10) 
 
 $1,152 Las Huertas Plaza 
 Retail · Bernalillo, NM Retail Property for rents for Rent in Bernalillo Details Las Huertas Plaza - 240 S Camino Del Pueblo Bernalillo NM Anchored by flying star. Great frontage on historic camino del pueblo. Get Bernalillo rental prices and see other Retail Property for rents for Rent in Bernalillo NM. Anchored by flying star. Great frontage on historic camino del pueblo. Tools 
 X Tools Las Huertas Plaza for $1,152 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 3 weeks ago on Rofo (via Rofo) 
 $1,172 Las Huertas Plaza 
 Retail · Bernalillo, NM Retail Property for rents for Rent in Bernalillo Details Las Huertas Plaza - 240 S Camino Del Pueblo Bernalillo NM Anchored by flying star. Great frontage on historic camino del pueblo. Get Bernalillo rental prices and see other Retail Property for rents for Rent in Bernalillo NM. Anchored by flying star. Great frontage on historic camino del pueblo. Tools 
 X Tools Las Huertas Plaza for $1,172 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 3 weeks ago on Rofo (via Rofo) 
 $30,000 210 U.S. Highway 550 
 Commercial · Bernalillo, NM Office Space for Rent in Bernalillo Details 210 U.S. Highway 550 - 210 U.s 550 Bernalillo NM Site is on south side of Highway 550 with traffic counts nearing 40,000 vehicles per day. Terrific location for Retail Get Bernalillo rental prices and see other Office Space for Rent in Bernalillo NM. Site is on south side of Highway 550 with traffic counts nearing 40,000 vehicles per day. Terrific location for Retail Tools 
 X Tools 210 U.S. Highway 550 for $30,000 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 3 weeks ago on Rofo (via Rofo) 
 $1,600 Bernalillo Market Place 
 Retail · Bernalillo, NM Retail Property for rents for Rent in Bernalillo Details Bernalillo Market Place - 130 E Hwy 550 Bernalillo NM Lease incentives negotiable. Make an offer! Visibility along US Highway 550. Excellent access. The property is... Get Bernalillo rental prices and see other Retail Property for rents for Rent in Bernalillo NM. Lease incentives negotiable. Make an offer! Visibility along US Highway 550. Excellent access. The property is centrally located and is w... Tools 
 X Tools Bernalillo Market Place for $1,600 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Posted on Rofo (via Rofo) 
 $1,736 Las Huertas Plaza 
 Retail · Bernalillo, NM Retail Property for rents for Rent in Bernalillo Details Las Huertas Plaza - 240 S Camino Del Pueblo Bernalillo NM Anchored by flying star. Great frontage on historic camino del pueblo. Get Bernalillo rental prices and see other Retail Property for rents for Rent in Bernalillo NM. Anchored by flying star. Great frontage on historic camino del pueblo. Tools 
 X Tools Las Huertas Plaza for $1,736 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Posted on Rofo (via Rofo) 
 $40 Retail-Commercial for Lease: Fast Food Restaurant for Lease 
 Retail · Bernalillo, NM Retail Property for rents for Rent in Bernalillo Details Retail-Commercial for Lease: Fast Food Restaurant for Lease - 200 E Hwy 550 Bernalillo NM Located at the main&amp;main intersection of bernalillo, nm. Get Bernalillo rental prices and see other Retail Property for rents for Rent in Bernalillo NM. Located at the main&amp;main intersection of bernalillo, nm. Tools 
 X Tools Retail-Commercial for ... for $40 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Posted on Catylist 
 $9.56 Office for Lease: Camino Del Pueblo Live/Work 
 Office · Bernalillo, NM Office Space for Rent in Bernalillo Details Office for Lease: Camino Del Pueblo Live/Work - 426 Camino Del Pueblo Bernalillo NM Along main arterial road in bernalillo. Main structure is full residence, 2511 sf with several large rooms that could... Get Bernalillo rental prices and see other Office Space for Rent in Bernalillo NM. Along main arterial road in bernalillo. Main structure is full residence, 2511 sf with several large rooms that could be offices. Tools 
 X Tools Office for Lease: Cami... for $9.56 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Posted on Catylist 
 $10 Office for Lease: Vineyard Village 
 Office · Bernalillo, NM Office Space for Rent in Bernalillo Details Office for Lease: Vineyard Village - 1115 S Camino Del Pueblo Bernalillo NM Excellent location for office/retail use. One-half mile from interstate 25 exit. Get Bernalillo rental prices and see other Office Space for Rent in Bernalillo NM. Excellent location for office/retail use. One-half mile from interstate 25 exit. Tools 
 X Tools Office for Lease: Vine... for $10 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Posted on Catylist 
 $5.90 Industrial for Lease: Contractor&apos;s Office 
 Industrial · Bernalillo, NM Industrial Property for Rents for Rent in Bernalillo Details Industrial for Lease: Contractor&apos;s Office - 208 Calle Industrial Bernalillo NM Ideal for Contractors Office, 3 (3) offices, reception area, restroom Get Bernalillo rental prices and see other Industrial Property for Rents for Rent in Bernalillo NM. Ideal for Contractors Office, 3 (3) offices, reception area, restroom Tools 
 X Tools Industrial for Lease: ... for $5.90 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Posted on Catylist 
 $3,000 Bernalillo Market Place 
 Retail · Bernalillo, NM Retail Property for rents for Rent in Bernalillo Details Bernalillo Market Place - 130 E Hwy 550 Bernalillo NM Lease incentives negotiable. Make an offer! Visibility along US Highway 550. Excellent access. The property is... Get Bernalillo rental prices and see other Retail Property for rents for Rent in Bernalillo NM. Lease incentives negotiable. Make an offer! Visibility along US Highway 550. Excellent access. The property is centrally located and is w... Tools 
 X Tools Bernalillo Market Place for $3,000 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 Posted on Rofo (via Rofo) 
 
 1 …of 1 page 
 Listings on Oodle Marketplace Miami Office Space | Chicago Office Space | Louisville Office Space | Boston Office Space | Ann Arbor Office Space | Springfield Office Space | Charlotte Office Space | Newark Office Space | Cleveland Office Space | Portland Office Space | Lancaster Office Space | Pittsburgh Office Space | Charleston Office Space | Knoxville Office Space | Nashville Office Space .

Find used cars , used motorcycles , used RVs , used boats , apartments for rent , homes for sale , job listings , and local businesses on Oodle Marketplace. 
SET LOCATION
 Bernalillo, NM [change location] http://officespace.oodle.com/bernalillo-nm/||0 miles http://officespace.oodle.com/bernalillo-nm/?r=5||5 miles http://officespace.oodle.com/bernalillo-nm/?r=10||10 miles http://officespace.oodle.com/bernalillo-nm/?r=15||15 miles http://officespace.oodle.com/bernalillo-nm/?r=20||20 miles http://officespace.oodle.com/bernalillo-nm/?r=30||30 miles http://officespace.oodle.com/bernalillo-nm/?r=50||50 miles http://officespace.oodle.com/bernalillo-nm/?r=country||country city country 
Posted By

 Everyone My Connections 
 
Category 
 
 Merchandise Cars Rentals Real Estate Jobs Pets Tickets 

 All Vehicles Motorcycles Boats RVs All Rentals Office Space Vacation Rentals 

 All Pets Dogs Cats Horses Services Personals Community 
 
 Commercial 
 
 Industrial (1) Office (3) Retail (6) 
 
Price
 to Show all options 
Amenities

 Parking (1) View (1) 
 
Square Feet
 to 
Refine By Keyword
 
Zip Code

 87004 (9) 87113 (1) 
 Related Searches square feet 5000 near albuquerque nm office space near alamedan valley albuquerque nm office space for rent near uptown albuquerque nm industrial property for rent near albuquerque nm office space near bear canyon albuquerque nm industrial property for rent near rio rancho nm office space near rio rancho nm office space near taylor ranch albuquerque nm office space near uptown albuquerque nm Important
Safety Tips 
 Always see the place in person before renting. Be cautious of people claiming to be overseas. Don’t wire money or take advance payments. 
 
To learn more, visit the Safety Center .
Report suspicious listings by clicking on .
 Oodle Marketplace, part of the ForRent.com Network Equal Housing Opportunity 
 About Us Blog Help Safety Center Privacy Policy Terms of Use Send us Feedback 

 Add my listings to a Facebook Page Get Marketplace on your Phone 
 ©Copyright 2012 Oodle, Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
