<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000071" url="http://www.hotelmule.com/management/html/15/n-3115.html" time="2012-07-12-15:15" support="1" score="0.0002119526075682363" bingtitle="Cultural influences on service - Hotelmule - Hospitality and ..." webtitle="Cultural influences on service - Hotelmule   - Hospitality and Tourism Industry Portal">
			<query id="001269" bing-rank="250"/>
	<description>e.g., in fast food restaurant services); (2) task-interactive ... selection, as well as a tangible product in the form ... food, seat, pillows, and blankets. The hotels ...</description>
	<body>
		Wiki Network Article Forum Blog Download Group Directory Events Search 
 
 
 Restaurants&amp;Bars Markeing&amp;Sales Human Resources Financial Accounting Front Office Housekeeping Travel Agent Engineering Owners&amp;Investment;&amp;GM; Papers&amp;Academic; Security Tourism Management 
 
Navigation： Hotelmule &gt;&gt; Article &gt;&gt; Tourism Management &gt;&gt; View Article 
 
New Update

 Major Trends Affecting the Travel Industry (2) Major Trends Affecting the Travel Industry (1) Planning Methods for leisure and tourism (2)(Photo) Planning Methods for leisure and tourism (1)(Photo) Hospitality Professor - Travel And Hospitality Career Opportunities Leisure and Tourism Plans and Planning (2)(Photo) Leisure and Tourism Plans and Planning (1)(Photo) Leisure and Tourism Public Policy-making(Photo) The Leisure and Tourism Market versus the State(Photo) Political Ideologies and the Role of the State in Leisure and Tourism(Photo) 
 
Network Recommendation
 
 Send to friend Last | Next 

Cultural influences on service

 Release: Aug 16 2010 05:32  Author: Members View: 2930 times Print    
 The aim of this article is to explore the influence of national culture 
 on service and identify cultural differences in service perception. 

 OBJECTIVES 
After completing this article the reader should be able to:
- Understand the concept of service, service quality and satisfaction with service
- Understand the role and importance of cultural influences on service
- Identify cultural differences in service perception among various nations

 INTRODUCTION 
National culture is an important factor influencing expectations and perceptions of
service quality and satisfaction with service. Different cultural groups attach different
importance to service quality criteria. The examples of cultural differences in service
quality perceptions and expectations are presented.

 10.1 THE CONCEPT OF SERVICE 
Services are intangible activities or benefits one party can offer to another; they do not
result in the ownership of anything. Services are provided in every sector of the
economy: retailing, wholesaling, transportation, telecommunication, finance, health,
education, and many other sectors, including tourism, hospitality, and leisure. Tourists
create demand for a wide range of services, such as transportation, communication,
accommodation, catering, attractions, activities, entertainment, and information (e.g.,
language interpretation and translation). These services cater directly to tourist needs.
Tourists also create demand for indirect services, such as financial, medical, insurance,
retailing, wholesaling, cleaning, printing, drinking water, sewerage, and electricity.
Without indirect services, the provision of direct services would be impossible. As a
result, a tourism product is mostly a service rather than a tangible product.

 10.2 SERVICE ENCOUNTER 
The focus of service is on the service process, performance, or service encounter,
which has been defined as the (1) interaction between the customer and the firm or
service provider; (2) a period of time duringwhich a provider and a consumer confront
each other; and (3) a ‘‘moment of truth’’ – a moment during which customers evaluate
how closely their service expectations are met. What happens between a customer
and a provider during this ‘‘moment of truth’’ determines the quality of the services
offered to a customer, and a customer’s satisfaction with service.

 10.3 SERVICE CLASSIFICATION 
The degree of personal contact with the service encounter allows for distinguishing
among different types of services, such as (1) maintenance-interactive (characterized
by little interaction between the provider and customer because of little risk in transactions,
e.g., in fast food restaurant services); (2) task-interactive (characterized by a
higher degree of interaction because of greater risk in transaction; customers depend
upon the service providers for information and expertise, e.g., banking services,
brokerage services); and (3) personal-interactive services (require the most intense
interaction between the provider and customer, a high degree of customization,
information exchange, and trust, e.g., tourism and hospitality services) (Mills, 1986).

 10.4 KEY CHARACTERISTICS OF SERVICE 
Services are characterized by intangibility, heterogeneity, inseparability, perishability,
lack of ownership, and the importance of people and their characteristics.

 Intangibility 
Services are intangible; they cannot be seen, tasted, felt, heard, or smelled before
purchase. As a result, it is difficult to evaluate and compare them. A customer buys
experiences (e.g., the hotel atmosphere, the way the customer is treated at the front
desk), benefits (e.g., physical comfort of a hotel bed, or psychological, such as enjoyment
and happiness) and memories, rather than a tangible product. Most services offer
a combination of intangible and tangible elements of service. For example, restaurants
offer an intangible product in the form of atmosphere or advice on food and beverage
selection, as well as a tangible product in the form of food. Airlines offer intangible
elements in the form of transportation, and tangible elements in the form of aircraft,
food, seat, pillows, and blankets. The hotels offer intangible elements, such as the
atmosphere of a hotel lobby, and tangible elements, such as the design and architecture
of a hotel.

 
 7 1/7 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 &gt; View all 2 comments 
New comments

 
 Delete Guest (Aug 26 2011 07:37:43, Rate: -5 ) 
 Rate -5 Points 
 Delete Guest (Nov 3 2010 01:38:54, Rate: 5 ) 
 Rate 5 Points 
 View all 2 comments   -5 -3 -1 - +1 +3 +5 
Rate： 0 
 
Give Comments:
 
 Content: 

 Code: 

 Submit 
 
 Hotelmule | Forum | Site Panel | Site Map | Friend Link | Spaces | Contact Us 

Copyright © 2008 Hotelmule All rights reserved
	</body>
</document>
