<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000621" url="http://www.chinaenglish.com.cn/html/c177/2010-02/38778.html" time="2012-07-12-15:55" support="2" score="0.003529859528370513" bingtitle="星座英语：十二星座怎样过情人节_星座运程_中国 ..." webtitle="星座英语：十二星座怎样过情人节_星座运程_中国英语网">
			<query id="000428" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="000179" bing-rank="93"/>
	<description>Aries: You&apos;re determined to receive the most cards ... dime store chocolates and dinner at a fast food restaurant? ... Aquarius: Manufactured holidays aren&apos;t your cup of ...</description>
	<body>
		首页 &gt; 休闲英语 &gt; 星座运程 &gt;正文 背景： 阅读英语 
星座英语：十二星座怎样过情人节
 
 [日期：2010-02-11] 来源： 作者： [字体： 大 中 小 ] 
 
 星座英语 ：十二星座怎样过情人节 

二月十四情人节会给你带来什么样的感觉呢？十二星座对这个浪漫的节日都会有不同的反应。你是怎样度过这个节日呢？华丽的诗词、心形巧克力还是火红的玫瑰？
 



Does February 14 fill you with feelings of cheer or fear? Each Sun Sign has a different way of responding to this romantic holiday. Find out how your Sign handles this much-anticipated day of flowery poems, chocolate hearts and red roses.


Aries: You&apos;re determined to receive the most cards, candy and flowers. Who says sending roses to yourself doesn&apos;t count?


白羊座：期望收到很多卡片、甜点和鲜花。谁说给自己送花不算数？


Taurus: A bouquet of dandelions, dime store chocolates and dinner at a fast food restaurant? Relax, it was just a bad dream!


金牛座：难道仅仅是一束蒲公英，廉价巧克力或者快餐店的一顿晚餐吗？放松点，这只不过是个恶梦。


Gemini: You make two dates for the night -- and then backup plans with your friends in case you decide to flake on your original plans.


双子座：你为今晚准备了两个约会，这样万一原定约会泡汤了还可以和朋友一起。


Cancer: Ooh, there&apos;s nothing like candy heart art and lace doilies to get you going! Martha Stewart&apos;s got nothing on you.


巨蟹座：没有什么能像心形点心和系着绸带的礼物那样吸引你。但是大款可没准备送给你礼物。


Leo: You are displeased by the single red rose some admirer left on your windshield. Clearly you are worth at least a dozen!


狮子座：有人悄悄送了一支玫瑰，这让你很是恼火，因为至少该送一打玫瑰啊！


Virgo: You refuse to share the box of chocolates you receive -- what if someone fingers them? What if someone sneezes on your roses?


处女座：拒绝跟别人分享你收到的巧克力。有人拿手指拨弄怎么办？有人对着你的玫瑰打了个喷嚏怎么办？


Libra: You send valentines to everyone you know: your hairdresser, your fourth grade teacher, your manicurist, your manicurist&apos;s cousin … You don&apos;t want anyone to feel left out.


天秤座：你给认识的每个人都送去情人节的祝福：你的理发师、你四年级的老师、你的美甲师、美甲师的表弟……你不想让任何人被遗忘。


Scorpio: Why go out for a fancy dinner when you already have dessert waiting at home? Who knew that a Cupid costume could be so sexy?


天蝎座：与其在家坐等餐后甜点不如出去享受一次奇特的美味。谁能想到丘比特的衣服会如此性感呢？


Sagittarius: You can&apos;t commit to sending a card -- what if the recipient reads too much into it? You fake temporary amnesia to avoid acknowledging the holiday.


射手座：不想赠送卡片——万一收卡人误解了你的意思怎么办？为了避免这个误会只好假装忘记了这个节日。


Capricorn: Lacy hearts and syrupy sentiments make you sneeze -- besides, nothing says love like a new electronic organizer!


摩羯座：带花边的心形食品和甜甜的味道让你禁不住打喷嚏——毕竟，谁都不会说爱情像一个新的电子记事本。


Aquarius: Manufactured holidays aren&apos;t your cup of decaffeinated herbal tea, but consuming a few vegan chocolates doesn&apos;t make you a conformist, does it?


水瓶座：这种人人都过的俗节似乎不太适合你的品位，但是稍稍随俗一下，也没什么。


Pisces: You live for this stuff! The world would be such a better place if we could all just hold hands and share heart-shaped cookies every day.


双鱼座：似乎你天生就为了过这个节日。如果每天都能分享心形甜点多好啊。

 

 2010年十二星座的情人节礼物 

 休闲英语：青少年十二星座本周星座运程 
 
 0 顶一下 
 收藏 推荐 打印 |
 录入： ying870702 |
 阅读： 0 次 休闲英语：青少年十二星座本周星座运程 你不会说的12生肖12星座英文版 相关文章 推荐英语口语 
 五小时快速学好英语的方法，点击必看！ 秦皇岛网络公司 秦皇岛400电话 秦皇岛SEO优化 英文歌曲 英语歌曲 百听不厌 解酒饮料 醒酒饮料 英语 网站建设 网站制作 网站设计 英语学习 -就到中国英语网 英语四级 英语四级成绩查询 英语 商城系统 - 网上商城系统 - 网店系统 外语 旅游网站制作 - 旅游网站建设 - 旅游网站系统 
 英语评论 请尽量用-纯英文-来评论吧！ 查看全部评论 (0) 
 表情： 姓名： 匿名 字数 
点评： 
 同意评论声明 发表 
 英语Digg排行 
 3 星座英语：适合各个星座的英文名字 2 星座英语：十二星座怎样过情人节 1 双语：十二星座最佳名著（下） 1 1月4日十二星座运程大揭秘 1 星座物语：十二星座饮食习惯大PK 1 超简洁12星座特征概括 1 十二生肖英语喻意 1 休闲英语：青少年十二星座本周星座运程 1 十二星座学习英语大比拼 1 2010年十二星座的情人节礼物 
 推荐英语培训 
 北戴河旅游 北戴河 北戴河旅游景点 
 英文歌曲 最新英语学习 
 06-19 历年六级翻译真题及答案（2007.6） 06-19 历年六级翻译真题及答案（2007.12） 06-19 历年六级翻译真题及答案（2008.6） 06-19 历年六级翻译真题及答案（2008.12） 06-19 历年六级翻译真题及答案（2009.6） 06-19 历年四级翻译真题及解析（2007.6） 06-19 历年四级翻译真题及解析（2007.12） 06-19 历年四级翻译真题及解析（2008.6） 06-19 历年四级翻译真题及解析（2008.12） 06-19 历年四级翻译真题及解析（2009.6） 
 推荐英语学习 
 Powered by iwms 5.0
	</body>
</document>
