<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000048" url="http://www.insiderpages.com/b/3714024596/mid-city-nissan-chicago" time="2012-07-12-15:14" support="1" score="0.011856299614680004" bingtitle="Mid City Nissan - Chicago - Insider Pages - Restaurant Reviews ..." webtitle="Mid City Nissan - Chicago">
			<query id="000696" bing-rank="42"/>
	<description>4444 W IRVING PARK RD Chicago, IL 60641 www.midcitynissan.com ... you and arm and leg and treat you like you just placed an order at a fast food restaurant. Had my car ...</description>
	<body>
		join sign in 
 Find Near Browse Categories 
recommendations that matter most 
 Health&amp;Medical Home&amp;Garden Hair&amp;Beauty Auto
 Services Pets follow us Advertise With Us 
 Chicago, IL &gt; Auto Dealers &gt; New Car Dealers &gt;Mid City Nissan 

 

 

 

 
Mid City Nissan
 ★☆☆☆☆ 3 Reviews Write a Review 
773-282-6200
 4444 W IRVING PARK RD Chicago , IL 60641 www.midcitynissan.com 

 
 Add Photo Edit Business Claim Business 
 
About Mid City Nissan
 Categories 
 Auto Dealers New Car Dealers Hybrid Car Dealers New Truck Dealers Used Car Dealers Used Truck Dealers 
 Details 
 Nissan Nissan Nissan Nissan Nissan 
 
Automotive
 More choices in Chicago: 
 Western Avenue Nissan 
7410 S. Western Avenue Chicago, IL
 
 Gold Coast Bentley 
834 N Rush St Chicago, IL
 
 Reviews 
 
Insider Pages Reviews for Mid City Nissan

Have experience with this business? Write a Review. 
 
Latest reviews from Citysearch .
 ★☆☆☆☆ Rude Dealership 
by Chad4578 at Citysearch 1 Mid City Nissan 
 March 25, 2009 
The people here are atrocious. The charge you and arm and leg and treat you like you just placed an order at a fast food restaurant. Had my car serviced here recently and when I took my car home none of the issues I had asked to be done had been completed. Their service manager than tried placing the blame on me when I had clearly detailed the problem to his associate - talk about poor customer service. Go somewhere else where they won&apos;t rip you off and they appreciate your business.

Pros: Location

Cons: Bad Customer Service


 ★☆☆☆☆ Don&apos;t Go Here 
by TBrien at Citysearch 1 Mid City Nissan 
 March 14, 2009 
They have pushy salespeople and very slow customer service in both sales and service. Not recommended.

Pros: Located off of 90

Cons: Rude Service


 ★☆☆☆☆ Save Yourself a A Headache 
by TTIlson at Citysearch 1 Mid City Nissan 
 March 08, 2009 
If you like rude, mean, non-professional people and an example of awful customer service, this is the place for you.


 Write a Review Get Map&amp;Directions 
Modify or Try Another Search For:
 
New Car Dealers - Chicago, IL
 Find Near Home | About Us | FAQ | Blog | Help/Contact Us | Feedback | Store Finder | Doctor Finder | Sitemap | Privacy Policy (updated) | Terms &amp; Conditions ©2004–2012 Insider Pages. All rights reserved. Partner Sites: MyAutismTeam | Ask Answers | Ask Kids | Life123 | Citysearch | MerchantCircle | Urbanspoon
	</body>
</document>
