<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000305" url="http://www.vagazette.com/articles/2012/04/11/last_word/doc4f7b028c6befa039911001.txt" time="2012-07-12-15:29" support="8" score="0.016427074593254286" bingtitle="The Virginia Gazette, Williamsburg Virginia &gt; Last Word ..." webtitle="The Virginia Gazette, Williamsburg VirginiaLast WordWednesday&apos;s Last Word on Tuesday">
			<query id="001092" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="001081" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="001091" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="001073" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="001079" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000404" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="001095" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="001085" bing-rank="136"/>
	<description>“To the parents who forget to pack utensils/napkins ... Trash in the ’Burg -- “I walk around the city ... Customer service at some fast-food restaurant drive-thru windows ...</description>
	<body>
		Ask the Pro E-Edition Subscribe 
 
 Williamsburg, Virginia - . 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Search ---- vagazette.com Google 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Home Sports Lifestyle Obituaries Extras 
 Games Horoscope Movie Listings Special Sections Dining Guide Church Directory Coupons 
 Classifieds 
 Homes Cars Jobs Apartments Stuff 
 
 
 

Archives&gt;Last Word
 Print | Comment ( 9 comment(s) ) | Rate | Text Size 
 
Wednesday&apos;s Last Word on Tuesday
 



 Modified: Tuesday, April 3, 2012 12:18 PM EDT Originally Published: Wednesday, April 11, 2012 Dominion Power line -- “There is a simple solution for the‘not in my back yarders’whining about Dominion Power’s proposed transmission line across the James River, from Surry to Skiffes Creek. If enough of them disconnect from the electrical grid and convert to coal stoves and kerosene lanterns, there won’t be an increase in demand for electricity and the power company will find the new line to be unnecessary.” 

 Pottery lights -- “The new Pottery was looking great until the light strips were added to the facade. They are a great idea but the lights would have been better if they were not bright white. Pottery administration, please tone them down or turn them off after 10 p.m.” 

 How far have we come? -- “I was walking my dog Friday night near Plumeri Park when a car drove by and someone yelled out‘What’s up,––!’followed by a racial slur. I could clearly see the driver of the vehicle was a white male. There were other passengers in the car. Lucky for me I wasn’t shot in cold blood for walking my dog while black. I am not going to condemn an entire race for the ignorance of a few, but it does make one wonder why some people are so full of hate for an entire race of people.” 

 Trayvon Martin -- “I am happy President Obama commented about the Trayvon Martin killing. Racial profiling in conscious and unconscious racism is the big elephant in the room of America.” 

 “Those who say President Obama shouldn’t have gotten involved don’t understand that this is a national case. Some people don’t want to believe it was racially motivated, but it was. George Zimmerman should have listened to the dispatcher and not gotten out his car.” 

 “In the Zimmerman tape when he called 911, he said,‘There’s a guy who looks like he’s up to no good, maybe on drugs. It’s raining. He’s just waiting around.’The dispatcher asked,‘Is he Hispanic?’Zimmerman:‘No, he looks black.’NBC edited it to say,‘Looks like this guy’s up to no good. He’s black.’That’s just corrupt.” 

 “I am glad the local NAACP has expressed its opinion on the Trayvon Martin controversy. Maybe now it can turn its attention to local matters, such as the minority drop-out rate, poor academic achievement, single-parent households, poverty. In other words, issues where it realistically might have an impact.” 

 Roadwork -- “VDOT’s repaving policy is designed to save money in the long run. Main roads take a beating from heavy trucks, which causes the top layer of the pavement to weaken and crack. Replacing the top layer before it cracks protects the lower layers from damage. It’s like replacing the shingles on a house before the roof leaks and damages the ceiling below. This repaving policy is so good at saving money that all 50 state departments of transportation have adopted it as a standard practice.” 

 “Road reflectors that mark lanes are urgently needed for those making a left turn from Croaker Road onto Route 60 West. They would also be helpful for those making a left turn from Route 199 onto Route 60. In both cases I have seen people turn into oncoming traffic because the elevation differences in the roads makes it difficult to tell the major road at night or in rain and fog. As well, why are the crosswalks for William&amp;Mary students not marked with the embedded lighting as in Charlottesville for University of Virginia students?” 

 “I don’t think the people who resurfaced the roads in Windsor Forest should get a paycheck. They inconvenienced the neighborhood, and the roads are much worse off than when construction initially began. They are bumpy and uneven, just to name a few flaws.” 

 Traffic lights -- “The traffic light at Treyburn Avenue and Ironbound Road has worked inconsistently ever since it was installed. It is not just inconvenient to wait an excessive amount of time to enter Ironbound from Treyburn without any cars on Ironbound. It also becomes a danger when frustrated drivers on Treyburn decide to take considerable chances in ignoring the malfunctioning red light.” 

 Lost and found -- “A single car key on a Carmax key chain was lost in New Town area. Call Mike at 253-8199.” 

 “Does anyone know of a loving home for a dog we found on our back-door welcome mat? He is older, affectionate, mellow, easy-going. Apparently this low-maintenance buddy’s only desire in life is to spend time near you. 570-8090.” 

 School issues -- “We visited the Blayton Elementary science fair with our grandson Wednesday evening and couldn’t have been more impressed. The teachers were extremely professional and caring. We have wonderful schools in greater Williamsburg, and we should be grateful for the level of devotion displayed by those who make it all happen.” 

 “To the parents who forget to pack utensils/napkins, etc., in lunch boxes: Put a little money on your child’s lunch account and that will take care of it.” 

 “Regarding having to pay extra for utensils at Berkeley Middle School: There is a very simple solution. Most of us have extra packaged fast-food utensils that we usually throw away. It would seem to be an easy thing for Berkeley, or any school, to collect them and give them to students who have need for them. I’m sure people would be glad to donate them.” 

 “The speed limit in the James River Elementary School zone is 25, not 35. The information given was incorrect.” 

 “It was stated in the Last Word that the crossing guard didn’t get paid for serving as such. I have found out that the crossing guards do get paid extra. I have never heard of a kid getting hit when they go back to the Community Center when there’s no crossing guard. So the light in the crosswalk is doing its job.” 

 Healthcare bill -- “One of the questions that came up with the Supreme Court judges was,‘Do you expect us to read this entire bill?’That’s the problem. Most congressmen who voted for the healthcare bill never read it. The justices have not read it. Kagan will not recuse herself, who was a solicitor general, who read parts of it, if not all of it. This is a nightmare.” 

 “If the individual mandate requiring individuals to purchase health insurance is struck down by the Supreme Court, I recommend doctors and hospitals faced with giving unaffordable treatments to uninsured individuals require them to sign a legally binding agreement to purchase health insurance for at least the next five years as a condition of treatment.” 

 “Last week when the Supreme Court was hearing the arguments for and against the healthcare law, it was obvious that Sonia Sotomayor did not understand from her questioning that it’s already a law that people get treated if they show up in an emergency room, regardless of ability to pay. She offered that as a solution and had no understanding of that.” 

 “Reference the Last Word of March 28 under‘Presidential election’: The second paragraph was specific about what it terms to be the lies and misrepresentations. One of them is,‘We don’t now have government-run health care.’That’s interesting. What has the Supreme Court been debating for the last few days?” 

 “What was argued in front of the Supreme Court last week was the separability clause. Generally, what they put in bills is a separability clause, which means if one part of the bill is deemed unconstitutional or illegal, that you have the option to remove that from the bill and the bill stands. But in the healthcare bill that was not put in. There is no separability clause, so it all stands together or it all falls together.” 

 “In the March 31 Last Word, there was an unsubstantiated claim about the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission. Today the commission is an independent congressional agency established by the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 to advise the U.S. Congress on issues affecting the Medicare program. The Gazette printed that claim under the headline,‘Healthcare bill.’The casual reader might take the claim as true and assume it is part of the controversial Affordable Care Act.” 

 Trash in the’Burg -- “I walk around the city a lot and pick up trash close to my home, but without trash cans to deposit what’s picked up it’s not likely I’ll pick up more. I’d pick up trash near Merchants Square, but a lot of the trash cans have been removed. Where do I put what I pick up?” 

 Tongue in cheek -- “I spent $60 to fill my gas tank. It was my own fault because I didn’t adhere to our president’s energy policy. Well, I’ve filled my tires and even got a tune-up. Gas prices should be dropping any day now.” 

 “I just moved here from up North. It is hard to believe the colonial capital, located a short distance from the capital of the Confederacy, is home to one of the largest Yankee Candle stores in the country. I guess the union’s winning streak is still intact.” 

 Volunteers needed -- “To anyone who would like to participate in local community theater, the Williamsburg Players is always looking for volunteers. This weekend the Players could use volunteers to help with set-building for the upcoming show. They will be starting at 10 a.m. both days at James-York Playhouse, 200 Hubbard Lane.” 

 Runaround -- “I went into the Department of Motor Vehicles on Friday to pick up tags for my truck. I paid taxes when I bought my truck. I pay taxes to the state for the roads. My tax dollars built the DMV building. My tax dollars pay for the personnel at the DMV. And when I walked in to get my tags, I had to pay a $5 service charge. I asked what the charge was for. The response:‘It’s for a service charge.’If I have to pay a $5 service charge and they want everyone to do everything online, then why are there employees at the DMV? Why doesn’t it just close the branch and do everything online?” 

 Does anyone know... -- “I am a hard-working man in my early 40s and need a place for my family to live. I do all types of maintenance work. I cannot afford $1,000 a month. I would like a house or a mobile home with a yard where my 3-year-old can play. We currently live in an apartment, and have no peace.” 

 “My daughter is preparing to move cross country to Portland, Ore. Please help her cut costs by donating moving boxes and packing paper, etc., that are no longer needed. Call 592-0046” 

 “In response to the person looking for someone to repair an on/off switch on a lamp: Collector’s Gallery specializes in lamp and chandelier repair and rewiring, as well as antique lamp and chandelier restoration. Items are repaired in the company van at the person’s location, when possible. Call 564-4424 and ask for Joe.” 

 “Someone commented recently about a good place to get hair colored, with the woman’s name. I have lost the information. Could you give that info again?” 

 “To the person looking for Central Vac help: Try Protection&amp;Audio Video By Design, 258-1285, protectionbydesign.com .” 

 “To the person looking for a church that welcomes a multi-racial family: I attend King of Glory Lutheran Church, Missouri Synod. We have had no problems there and have been welcomed with open arms. The church is on Longhill Road, with services at 8, 9:30 and 11 a.m., as well as 5 p.m.” 

 “The family looking for a church that welcomes multi-racial families and also has an Awana program: Faith Baptist Church on Rochambeau Road welcomes multi-racial families and offers an Awana program.” 

 “To the person looking for someone to work on a 2001 Honda Odyssey: I recommend Carroll’s Auto at 564-1815. Carroll’s is honest, does an excellent job and has been working on my 1997 Honda, which has over 400,000 miles, for a long time.” 

 “I’m looking for some coffee tables and end tables. 645-3788.” 

 “Whom do I contact about installing a lightning rod at home? Does anyone have an idea of how much that would cost?” 

 “Looking for a person or group collecting magazines to send to our troops overseas. Would be willing to deliver them to wherever you are. 229-8129.” 

 “I am an Army veteran in my mid 50s, fit and presentable, and need employment in greater Williamsburg. E-mail Mike at sixthbn@aol.com .” 

 “I am looking for a gently used speed bag that hangs from the ceiling. 298-6289.” 

 “I am in need of a twin-size bed and mattress for my grandson, donated or at an affordable price. 236-3715 or dtaylor75@cox.com .” 

 “In response to the person looking for gout help, eat unsweetened cherries. As much as possible, avoid scallops, herring, beer, red meat, turkey, asparagus and sugar as well as sugary drinks, as they can cause and worsen gout pain.” 

 “The March 31 Last Word included a question about whether cats can tell when someone is going to die. I recommend the book‘Making Rounds with Oscar,’by David Bosa, MD. It’s available at Barnes&amp;Noble Bookstore or the library. Some cats can tell when a sick person is going to die.” 

 “In reply to cats predicting death, I have never witnessed it. I’ve read where a cat will sit outside a patient’s room the night before the person has died. It’s happened on several occasions. Animals have a sense about death, the same way dogs sniff out cadavers in earthquakes. I only know what I’ve read.” 

 “Is there a place in Williamsburg/Newport News that buys gently used quality furs?” 

 “Those expressing an interest in English-style restaurant fare, Bob’s Sausage Co. of Barhamsville has British bangers available at the Toano Farmers Market on Saturdays.” 

 “For those of Scots/Irish ancestry in the area, the upcoming Williamsburg Highland Games (in late spring) will involve three lively Haggis competitions. One is the Haggis cook-off, with prizes for the best-tasting entries. Following will be the Haggis eating competition. Finally, there will be the athletic contest of Haggis hurling. For details and entry forms e-mail HaggisHurling@aol.com .” 

 Come and get it -- “A solid wood, square table that measures 42 inches needs some refinishing. You pick up. 229-3636.” 

 “Free oak tree already cut, ready to be picked up. Call 229-3473.” 

 “Free for the taking: IBM 10-Card punch, probably from the 1930s and probably still works. 258-5698.” 

 “I have a month’s worth of Nutrisystem dinner entrees and quite a few lunches as well to give away. Call 229-4839.” 

 “I have for free a 20-inch PC monitor, not a flat panel. 565-5708.” 

 Customer service -- “I did my homework before writing this complaint. I visited a local consignment store last week for the fifth time. I thought certainly that would be the day the proprietors would speak to me. Alas, not a single word. So after five times of not being acknowledged, I left and will stay away.” 

 “I am impressed with the quality of the home furnishings at both Aladdin and Chickadees consignment shops. And I love the wardrobe choices.” 

 “It’s the beginning of the spring and tourism season. Customer service at some fast-food restaurant drive-thru windows has poor ratings and poor quality of food. Let’s get it right, please.” 

 “If anyone is looking for an exceptional massage therapist, I recommend Susan Soderholm, who practices in Williamsburg. I gave up other excellent massage therapists for her. 253-1144.” 

 “Whenever I have an appliance problem, I have in the past called Dave Sibley of Sibley Appliance. I find him to be responsive and reasonably priced and would recommend him to anyone.” 

 “I needed to refinish a rusty part recently, and took it to Art Sparks at Peninsula Custom Coaters for an estimate. He recommended sandblasting and ceramic coating. His price was reasonable, the turnaround time was fast, and the results outstanding.” 

 “Thank you to the person who recommended Fertile Ground Landscaping for mulching and weeding. Workers came to my home and did an excellent job.” 

 “Like succulent oysters and omelets? I recommend Jimmy’s in Norge.” 

 “If you haven’t been to the Jefferson Restaurant on Richmond Road recently, you are missing out on a wonderful dining experience. You are personally greeted as you enter by the owner, Mark Wright. Mark also goes around to each table to ask diners if they’re happy with the service and the food and just to chat. We have been pleased with the quality of the food and the service each time we have been there.” 

 Cheers&amp;jeers -- “Who is responsible for the lawn care at the post office on Monticello Avenue? It is a disgrace!” 

 “To the person critical of WWF’s‘Earth Hour’: The point of Earth Hour is to show people that they don’t have to always use electricity when they are awake. It is a small, simple action that everyone can participate in to show support for the clean and healthy future of our planet. Earth Hour is just a baby step and meant to motivate people to do more to help out planet. What is so humorous about that?” 

 Politics -- “President Obama signed an executive order on March 16 called National Defense Resources Preparedness. In a nutshell, it’s the blueprint for peacetime martial law and gives the president the power to take just about anything deemed necessary for national defense. It’s peacetime, because as the title of the order says, it’s for preparedness. Under this order the heads of select cabinet-level positions can take food, livestock, fertilizer, farm equipment, all forms of energy, water resources, all forms of civil transportation and any other materials from wherever they are available.” 

 “Ruth Bader Ginsburg, one of the Supreme Court judges, was invited to speak to a group in Egypt about putting forth their constitution. She said,‘Do not use the U.S. Constitution as a model. It’s old, it’s antiquated, and it doesn’t work.’And she’s on the Supreme Court.” 

 Ginsburg’s January interview praised the Founding Fathers’“grand general ideas that become more effective over the course of... more than two sometimes-turbulent centuries.”The remark about rejecting the U.S. Constitution as a model in 2012 was based on the document’s original exclusion of women, slaves and Native Americans. 

 “Every year Republicans delay the transportation bill after April 1. Big oil pockets $110 million per day in collected tax money that big oil will not have to pay. The 1,000-10,000 transportation and construction-related jobs per day that will start going away after April 1 fits Republican ideology. Just say no to health, women, employment, education and yes to tax breaks for the rich and money down the toilet for military contactors. What a platform to run on.” 

 Global warming -- “The weather is global, and for those who think there’s global warming, don’t tell that to our family members in Europe, who have had the worst winter and the most snow they’ve had in years. And don’t tell that to other family we have in California, outside of Los Angeles, who in March got snow. If that’s global warming, heaven forbid what’s going to happen if it’s cool?” 

 Tea Party -- “Recently, a writer commented unfavorably that the Tea Party is meeting at the James City Library instead of using a restaurant, which could have used the business. The Williamsburg Historic Triangle Tea Party Patriots charges no fee to join, asking only for donations to assist in making pamphlets and marketing materials available for members, and purchasing relevant books for resale to keep members informed, plus rental fees as needed for public meeting rooms and miscellaneous supplies. Occasional refreshments are donated by members. Appreciating the James City Library’s space and location, the organization is meeting there now.” 

 
 
     Saturday&apos;s Last Word on Friday 


 Article Rating
 
 Current Rating: 0 of 0 votes! Rate File: Select Rating: * ** *** **** 
 
 Reader Comments
 Posted comments are for meaningful discussion that is germane to the article. No personal attacks or insults. Submit complaints by clicking Report abuse. 
 politics before truth wrote on Apr 3, 2012 1:12 PM: &quot;5 minutes of research allowed me to find the truth about the National Defense Resources Preparedness Act.
In a March 18 Hot Air post, conservative blogger Ed Morrissey wrote that&quot;this is really nothing to worry about at all,&quot;explaining that the new order is an update to a previously existing executive order:

[T]his is almost identical to EO 12919 from 18 years earlier...Why the update? If one takes a look at EO 12919, the big change is in the Cabinet itself. In 1994, we didn&apos;t have a Department of Homeland Security, for instance, and some of these functions would naturally fall to DHS. In EO 12919, the FEMA director had those responsibilities, and the biggest change between the two is the removal of several references to FEMA (ten in all). Otherwise, there aren&apos;t a lot of changes between the two EOs, which looks mainly like boilerplate.

In fact, that&apos;s almost entirely what it is. The original EO dealing with national defense resources preparedness was issued in 1939 (EO 8248) according to the National Archives. It has been superseded a number of times, starting in 1951 by nearly every President through Bill Clinton, and amended twice by George W. Bush&quot; 
 Report Abuse 
 
 truth before politics wrote on Apr 3, 2012 3:59 PM: &quot;One thing that you left out is Obama changed the language to read in case of a POTENTIAL EMERGENCY, not just a real one. Tell about all the changes he made to the E O , not just the ones that you want people to know about. It sounds like it gives him the ability for a power grab.&quot; 
 Report Abuse 
 
 more truth wrote on Apr 3, 2012 4:02 PM: &quot;And last week the department of homeland security ordered 450 MILLION ROUNDS of 40 cal. cartridges. Is a potewntial emergency on the way?&quot; 
 Report Abuse 
 
 bullying wrote on Apr 3, 2012 6:14 PM: &quot;I am very concerned that, nowadays the word&quot;bullying&quot;is being used synonymously with&quot;participating in criminal activity. An example of bullying would be making fun of someone&apos;s haircut until you make them cry, and encouraging others to make fun of them too. Or taking someone&apos;s seat in the lunch room and intimidating them into sitting someplace else. Stalking, making threats, stealing, and assault is not bullying. For those who experience these acts, we diminish them by calling them&quot;bullying&quot;. It seems as from what I hear about and read about, there is a whole lot of criminal activity going on.....threatening on facebook, physical assault in the school parking lot, etc. I believe in letting kids be kids, but these acts need to be treated as what they are, criminal activity. Kids need to develop a thick skin to survive in this world (always have), but that is not the same thing.&quot; 
 Report Abuse 
 
 Cry Baby wrote on Apr 4, 2012 10:49 AM: &quot;Justice Department under deadline to answer court over Obama&apos;s health law comments

I guess it is Ok as long as they vote the Kings way. When they vote the way the Libs like it&apos;s fine. The Justice Dept is OBAMA.&quot; 
 Report Abuse 
 
 Hey Global Warning wrote on Apr 4, 2012 11:04 AM: &quot;I think God knows what he is doing.

It isn&apos;t like those places have never gotten snow before. A record since umpteen years ago isn&apos;t really a record. Just been a while.&quot; 
 Report Abuse 
 
 Lori Rammel wrote on Apr 4, 2012 6:55 PM: &quot;I was ill with no one to help. I called 911 and received professional, immediate help. The JCC emergency squad members were also professional and knowledgable. After arriving at the Sentara Williamsburg Hospital ER, the service was outstanding....Thank you JCC squad, Noah, RN, and Dr Link.&quot; 
 Report Abuse 
 
 Watch ur back wrote on Apr 6, 2012 12:55 PM: &quot;If you don&apos;t already know, Obama is a plant, seeded by the Muslim community. By the time he’s finished his 2nd term, God forbid, he will have single handedly run the deficit to 22 trillion dollars, if staying the course he is on now. No Vets will get their checks; no Military and civil service retirement checks will go out, no more social security, unemployment, welfare or food stamps. He will be praised by the Muslims for bringing down this great nation. He has buffaloed so many, to include the majority of women, blacks and Hispanics. Just looked what is happening and think about what he is trying to get passed.&quot; 
 Report Abuse 
 
 What wrote on Apr 11, 2012 11:09 PM: &quot;To Watch ur back:

Are you serious? What kind of paranoid delutions do you live with? How could muslims plant a president in office when it is the American people who voted for him. Last I checked, we are not a muslim country. You really need to get therapy!&quot; 
 Report Abuse 
 
Submit a Comment
 Name: Email: Comments: Image Verification:
	</body>
</document>
