<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000386" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20091012090950AAFC9oz" time="2012-07-12-15:35" support="2" score="0.0028540793657985597" bingtitle="How much can I make in a month on minimum wage? - Yahoo! Answers" webtitle="How much can I make in a month on minimum wage? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="001047" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="001053" bing-rank="15"/>
	<description>I am working at a sort of fast food restaurant, and I ma making minimum ... that I am getting paid under the table ... have... do you have to pay a car payment ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Business&amp;Finance &gt; Careers&amp;Employment &gt; Food Service &gt; Resolved Question 
 JadeWolf Member since: March 26, 2009 Total points: 2,374 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
How much can I make in a month on minimum wage?
 I am working at a sort of fast food restaurant, and I ma making minimum wage ($7.25/hour) and I usually work 7 hours a day, 5 days a week. I was wondering how much I could make in a month? I want to double check my math, and the max taxes I&apos;ve seen taken out of my check are $3-4. Me and my bf (and his brother&amp;gf) are going to move into an apartment and I would like to make enough money to be able to help out with the necessities and still make the rent. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 

Additional Details
 Well it is possible that I am getting paid under the table but I am unsure. The last time I got paid the taxes where seriously only like 4 dollars and there are no state tax taken out. And I have no payments. No car and no phone. And yes, we already have the bills and utilities split and everyone is on the lease. 
 3 years ago 
 by spalmer Member since: May 19, 2009 Total points: 51,386 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 The taxes are wrong... more should be withheld from your paycheck. I assume that you claim 0 or 1 as a single individual.

Do you ever get overtime? If so, you could make as much as the company would allow. If not, at 40 hours per week, the most you could gross would be $1,160/month. With proper taxes taken out, you&apos;d take home between $900 and $980/month. Plus, you have to be prepared if they drop you down to 10 or 20 hours a week (happens a lot in fast food). That would bring you down to only bringing home between $150-$350/month. Divided by four people, rent and utilities shouldn&apos;t be bad. Make sure you know who&apos;s going to put which utilities in their names. You&apos;ll want everyone to be on the lease, and you&apos;ll want a contract listing which items are divided by four. Of course, you know what other expenses you have... do you have to pay a car payment, car insurance, cell phone, etc?

Good luck! 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 100% 1 Vote 
 1 person rated this as good 
 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (2)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Judy Member since: February 14, 2006 Total points: 489,632 (Level 7) Badge Image: 
 Add Contact Block 
 Something is wrong with what they are taking out. Your gross would be $253.75 a week so they should be taking out $19.41 just for social security and medicare - that&apos;s 7.65% 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Ryan M Member since: July 24, 2006 Total points: 132,035 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Unless you bf makes MUCH more than minimum wage, you guys will be VERY cash strapped. Simple math shows that the most you can make in a month is just above $1,000 per month BEFORE taxes. About $750 after taxes. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 
 
Discover Questions in Food Service 

 I am applying for a bussing job and i need to write a resume in an email!? I need help finding a job...? Which is better in your opinion for a first job? I am 14 and how could i get a summer job in michigan? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Business&amp;Finance 
 Careers&amp;Employment 
 Administrative and Office Support Financial Services Food Service Government&amp;Non-Profit Health Care Law&amp;Legal Marketing&amp;Sales Other - Careers&amp;Employment Technology 
 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
