<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000027" url="http://boardman.vindy.com/news/2010/dec/04/boardman-police-blotter/" time="2012-07-12-15:13" support="2" score="0.001609126466038101" bingtitle="Boardman Neighbors - Boardman Community News, Sports and Local ..." webtitle="Boardman Neighbors -  Boardman Community News, Sports and Local Information - Boardman Police Blotter">
			<query id="000707" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="000714" bing-rank="214"/>
	<description>Misuse of a credit card: A Romaine Avenue woman found a ... Theft/criminal damaging: A $100 car stereo was ... worker for a Boardman-Canfield Road fast-food restaurant reported ...</description>
	<body>
		Thursday, July 12th, 2012 AUSTINTOWN BOARDMAN CANFIELD POLAND 
 News Events 
 
 Austintown Canfield Poland 
 
 Connect Login Print Subscription 
 
 Connect User Toolbox Print Subscription 
 
 Welcome, View your Public Profile Create your Profile! View your Comments Change your Password Site Help / Report Issue Start your profile today 
 
 RSS Search alerts 

 Latest Photos Previous | Next | More Photos 
 Neighbors | Alisa Manna.18-month-old Sydney (left) watches her mother do ... | »More Neighbors | Alisa Manna.Sydney Spin takes a break on her ... | »More Neighbors | Alisa Manna.Connie Spin (right) from Boardman, shows that ... | »More Lily Sarditch rushed down the slide during Skedaddles&apos;Doughnutss with ... | »More Lilly Munch (left), takes a break from the festivities to ... | »More Neighbors | Submitted.Compco Industries baseball team won the regular season ... | »More Andrea Gross (left) smiled with her son Carson as they ... | »More Neighbors | Alisa Manna.Sydney hugs her mom, Connie Spin, after ... | »More Neighbors | Submitted.New inductees for the Boardman Alumni Award were ... | »More Children learned how to stop, drop and roll in case ... | »More 
   
 «News Home 

Boardman Police Blotter 

 iPod Print 
 
Saturday, December 4, 2010



Nov. 8

Theft: Alexis G. Salgado, 27, of Ashtabula was charged with stealing five bottles of men’s cologne from Sears in the Southern Park Mall.

Theft: Twenty-seven Vindicator newspapers were stolen from a box near Prestwick Drive and Hillman Way.

Aggravated menacing: A Tippecanoe Road woman said her former boyfriend threatened to slit her throat and made other threats of bodily harm.

Theft: Several pieces of jewelry were missing from a home in the 5300 block of Lockwood Boulevard.

Breaking and entering/vehicle theft: A 1998 Chevrolet van was stolen from a residence in the 800 block of Mulberry Lane that someone had entered. Numerous tools and other merchandise were missing.

Possible theft: A Boardman Boulevard woman reported her account was billed twice for a single donation she had made.

Counterfeit: A fake $20 bill was passed at Sbarro The Italian Eatery in the Southern Park Mall.

Burglary: To an apartment in the 5000 block of Firnley Avenue, from which eight Sony PlayStation2 games were stolen.

Assault: A woman alleged her former boyfriend struck her face as she drove near Southern Boulevard and Indianola Road.

Misuse of a credit card: A Romaine Avenue woman found a $100 unauthorized charge to her credit card.

Theft: A manager of New York Music, 7144 Market St., accused a worker of causing the business to be $100 short.

Criminal mischief: A West Boulevard woman told police she saw someone let the air out of a tire on her vehicle.

Theft: Johnathan L. Robles, 19, of 682 Magnolia St., Youngstown, was charged with stealing $61.55 worth of personal items from Walmart, 1300 Doral Drive.

Nov. 9

Theft: Mildred A. Epps, 39, of 3725 Elbertus Ave., Youngstown, was accused in the theft of two pairs of shoes from Payless Shoesource, 48 Boardman-Poland Road. Epps also was wanted on a felony charge of passing bad checks.

Menacing: A Havenwood Drive woman told authorities she found out that a relative wanted to harm her.

Auto theft: A 1995 Hyundai Accent was stolen in the 6200 block of Market Street.

Drug abuse: A traffic stop in the 7200 block of South Avenue resulted in the arrest of 42-year-old Nicholas W. Hetmanski, 1805 E. Western Reserve Road, Boardman, on charges of drug possession and operating a vehicle impaired. Several pills, including two vials of a drug used only in hospitals, were found, a report said.

Theft: Two birth certificates and two Social Security cards were taken from an apartment in the 4000 block of South Schenley Avenue.

Criminal damaging: A Lemans Drive woman said an irate neighbor kicked and damaged the accuser’s apartment door.

Harassment: A Forest Garden Drive woman reported getting a series of unwanted calls.

Burglary: To a vacant Overhill Road residence through a side door. Cooper pipes were missing.

Burglary: Took place in the 100 block of Clifton Drive via the front door. A 52-inch flat-screen TV, a laptop computer, a Wii game system and related parts were stolen, for a $2,300 loss.

Theft: A checkbook and U.S. Savings bonds were removed from a lockbox at a Cascade Drive home.

Nov. 13

Theft/criminal damaging: A $100 car stereo was removed from a vehicle that sustained damage to a passenger-side door at the Southern Park Mall.

Burglary: Nothing appeared to be missing from a residence in the 5300 block of South Avenue after someone had forced open a side door and entered.

Theft: Johnny A. Drouin, 47, of 12921 Springfield Road, New Springfield, was accused in the theft of three Xbox video games and five articles of men’s clothing from Walmart, 1300 Doral Drive.

Theft: Richard A. Lawler, 31, of 1915 Valley Road, Niles, was taken into custody on a warrant after a 35-pack of water and miscellaneous tools were stolen from a storage area at a Market Street doctor’s office.

Theft: Marshawna L. Johnson, 24, of 819 Canfield Road, Youngstown, was accused of stealing nine baby products from Walmart.

Criminal damaging: Four copper landscaping lights were damaged in the 30 block of Brookfield Avenue.

Criminal damaging: Someone damaged a landscaping light to a residence in the 200 block of Erskine Avenue.

Possible theft: A township woman reported her wallet lost or stolen at a Boardman-Canfield Road store.

Burglary: Various medications were taken from an apartment in the 2000 block of Wolosyn Circle, though police found no signs of forced entry.

Theft: A $180 lawn mower was removed from a garage in the 5000 block of Brookwood Road.

Assault: A woman told police another woman pushed the accuser in the chest at a residence in the 1900 block of Cover Drive.

Theft: A Boardman-Poland Road restaurant employee reported the theft of a wallet, cell phone and money.

Nov. 14

Aggravated menacing: A South Avenue man told authorities he opened his door to someone dressed in black with a gun who demanded the victim get on the ground. The homeowner slammed his door, and the gunman fled, a report said.

Criminal damaging: A trailer in the 4000 block of South Avenue had a broken window.

Theft: A woman reported her purse stolen in the township.

Menacing: A Paxton Road woman said her daughter had been threatened.

Harassment: An Auburn Hills Drive man reported receiving a series of unwanted calls.

Harassment: A Homestead Drive woman told police of getting threatening and obscene calls.

Nov. 15

Theft: Two men stole two desktop computers from Walmart, costing the store about $1,800.

Menacing: An Oak Knoll Drive man told police a member of a painting crew he had hired threatened to harm him.

Theft: Factory tires and wheels were stolen from a vehicle at Rick Bayus Motors, 5206 Youngstown-Poland Road.

Drugs: Police took into custody 20-year-old Nathan M. Shores, 7421 Sierra Madre Trail, Boardman, on a warrant from Struthers charging him with possession of marijuana.

Criminal damaging: A vehicle’s driver’s-side mirror was damaged in the 800 block of Afton Avenue.

Felonious assault: A Poland man told police a driver intentionally struck his car near Sheridan and Mathews roads after an argument between the two motorists. The accuser’s car had damage to its front fender.

Theft: A woman noticed her wallet missing at a Boardman-Poland Road eatery.

Harassment: A Huntington Drive woman said her daughter’s boyfriend called, yelling and swearing at her.

Attempted burglary: Ground-floor window screens to a residence in the 6800 block of Paxton Road were tampered with, leading the homeowner to believe someone had tried to break in.

Robbery: A Canfield woman told authorities a man in his 30s forcibly stole prescription medications from her as she left Brown’s Drugs, 5106 Southern Blvd.

Theft: Two women stole 34 items, including food and clothing, from Dollar General, 5953 South Ave.

Nov. 16

Theft: Scott D. Spencer, 19, of 7363 Eisenhower Drive, Boardman, was accused in the theft of bulk candy from Giant Eagle, 1201 Doral Drive.

Harassment: A Youngstown man reported receiving threatening cell-phone calls while at the Southern Park Mall.

Theft: Two women stole numerous body products from Bath&amp;Body Works, 379 Boardman-Poland Road.

Breaking and entering: Someone may have used a key to break into a residence in the 4800 block of Oak Knoll Drive and steal an estimated $1,500 worth of copper piping from the basement.

Possible theft: An Atlanta man reported his identification card lost or stolen at an East Midlothian Boulevard store.

Breaking and entering: Someone entered a storage building in the 6400 block of Southern Boulevard via a side window. Stolen was roughly 150 feet of copper wiring.

Assault: Two men reportedly assaulted each other at a Market Street eatery.

Theft/forgery: An employee at a Southern Park Mall business accused a co-worker of stealing three checks from his checkbook, forging his name and cashing two for $600.

 

Misuse of a credit card: A Youngstown man alleged a worker for a Boardman-Poland Road restaurant deliberately charged his credit card twice for one meal. The employee was fired, a report showed.

Auto theft: A 1985 Chevrolet Lumina was stolen in the 1100 block of Thalia Avenue.

Nov. 19

Theft: Rhiannon L. Summerville, 27, of 8171 Washington-Sharon Road, Masury, was charged in the theft of $302 worth of clothing from Sears in the Southern Park Mall. Summerville also was arrested on a felony charge of heroin possession. Domestic violence: James R. Pesano, 25, of 1729 Lynn Mar Ave., Boardman, was charged with the crime after his girlfriend alleged Pesano had pulled her hair, then threatened to kill her.

Theft: A woman in her 30s stole a trash can and miscellaneous property from Dollar General, 271 Boardman-Canfield Road.

Theft: Two women stole $916 worth of clothing and shoes from the J.C. Penney store in the Southern Park Mall. The items were recovered.

Theft: Three purses were taken from Possessions Inc., 945 Boardman-Canfield Road.

Harassment: An elderly Applewood Boulevard woman reported a man made threatening cell-phone calls.

Breaking and entering: Someone broke into a storage unit in the 400 block of Boardman-Canfield Road and removed numerous Viagra and other pills.

Theft: An employee with Lube Depot, 6122 Market St., told officers a co-worker failed to make a scheduled night deposit.

Criminal mischief: A rear storm door sustained damage in the 300 block of Meadowbrook Avenue.

Nov. 20

Arrest: Officers responded to an unwanted person at the Southern Park Mall, where they arrested 28-year-old Jerome R. McGee, no address listed, on a bench warrant charging him with criminal trespassing.

Domestic violence: Jessica M. Dellick, 21, of 135 Afton Ave., Boardman, faced two counts of domestic violence after her mother alleged Dellick had struck her face and neck, then kicked her stomach during an argument about a cell phone. Dellick’s father alleged she had spit in his face.

Citation: Bryan J. Romito, 24, of 584 KarolinaDrive, Campbell, was cited on a charge of disorderly conduct while intoxicated when, police said, he argued with officers who asked him to leave a Market Street eatery.

Theft: Kayla M. Chaney, 228 Falls Ave., and Trista A. Scott of 75 Benita Ave., both in Youngstown, were arrested after a theft at Walmart, 1300 Doral Drive. The two 20-year-old Youngstown women were accused of stealing house-ware items and cosmetics.

Theft: Several alcoholic beverages were stolen from Giant Eagle, 476 Boardman-Canfield Road.

Robbery: A woman leaving a business in the 4000 block of Market Street told police that a man asked to use her cell phone before punching her head, stealing $1,000 and fleeing on foot. The woman suffered a bump to her forehead.

Theft: Medications, golf clubs and a gym bag were taken from a vehicle at Southern Park Mall.

Theft: Ashley R. Wheeler, 24, of 506 Fourth St., Struthers, was charged with theft and possession of drugs after $47 worth of merchandise was stolen from Walmart.

Nov. 21

Arrest: Police in the 100 block of Mathews Road took into custody 32-year-old Rodney N. Seabrook, 2299 Volney Road, Youngstown, who was wanted on a felony warrant accusing him of violating a court order.

Theft: A mailbox and pole were stolen in the 1500 block of Walker Mill Road.

Theft: A surveillance camera showed a man stealing several pieces of metal from a trash bin behind a business in the 500 block of East Western Reserve Road.

Theft: Miscellaneous toys and clothing were stolen from Goodwill Industries Inc., 285 Boardman-Canfield Road.

Theft: A woman in her mid-20s took a $5 game from Family Dollar, 4028 South Ave.

Theft: Alyssa M. Mansell, 19, of 63 S. Osborn St., Youngstown, was charged with taking four women’s shirts from the J.C. Penney store.

Theft: A $500 X-ray table was stolen from Tiffany Breast Care Center, 7067 Tiffany Blvd.

Arrest: Police responded to a bad-check report and arrested 43-year-old Kelly R. Baker, 4951 Southern Blvd., Boardman, on a warrant from Liberty charging him with failure to appear in court.

Theft by deception: An employee of a BP Unimart station, 310 Boardman-Canfield Road, told police a man in his 30s used deceptive means to steal 20 cartons of cigarettes. The theft came to $600.

Criminal mischief: Eggs struck windows and siding on a residence in the 7600 block of Winterberry Drive.

Breaking and entering: Someone tossed a rock through a front window and entered Quality Truck Body&amp;Equipment Inc., 4440 Simon Road. Stolen were a computer tower and monitor.

Domestic violence: Police charged 38-year-old Willie J. Hayes, 1012 Washington Ave., Farrell, Pa., after authorities responded to a Market Street motel, where a woman alleged Hayes had forcibly pulled her from a bed by her wrists during an argument, causing redness and scratches.

Nov. 22

Menacing: A worker for a Boardman-Canfield Road fast-food restaurant reported a drive-through customer threatened to harm her.

Attempted theft: Someone ransacked a vehicle in the 600 block of Saddlebrook Drive.

Theft/damage: A car in the 300 block of Boardman-Poland Road had a smashed window. Stolen were two bowling balls, a coat, a global positioning system device and a pair of hunting boots.

Theft: A Market Street woman reported a check stolen.

Theft: A $429 cell phone was removed from AT&amp;T;, 7125 Tiffany Blvd.

Theft: Two hair weaves were stolen from The Hair Depot, 4026 Market St.

Theft by deception: The manager of a Youngstown company alleged a worker offering a sales contract to a Terrace Drive woman improperly handled one of two checks.

Harassment: A Wendy Lane woman reported receiving two nude photographs on her cell phone.

Theft: A set of keys was removed from a car at a U.S. Route 224 gas station.

Theft: Six propane tanks were stolen from Kmart, 1209 Boardman-Poland Road.

Theft: An employee of a Boardman-Canfield Road gas station noticed a deposit was short by an undisclosed amount.

Burglary: To a garage in the 500 block of Presidential Drive, from which a GPS unit, a radio, a cell-phone charger and a power strip were taken.

 
 Comments 

Use the comment form below to begin a discussion about this content.
 
Log in to comment

 Username: 

 Password: 

 Forgotten your password? 
 
 
Sign up

 Your e-mail: 
 
 
 
 
 Home • Terms of Use • Privacy Statement • Advertise • Contact 
 ©2012 Vindy.com. All rights reserved. A service of The Vindicator.
107 Vindicator Square. Youngstown, OH 44503 

Sponsored Links:
	</body>
</document>
