<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000842" url="http://thisismoney.businessesforsale.com/thisismoney/Business-Region/US/South-East/South-Carolina/business-for-sale-in-Spartanburg.aspx" time="2012-07-12-16:12" support="1" score="0.0007904059525824341" bingtitle="Spartanburg Businesses For Sale | Buy a Business in Spartanburg" webtitle="Spartanburg Businesses For Sale | Buy a Business in Spartanburg">
			<query id="001430" bing-rank="175"/>
	<description>Buy a business in Spartanburg, change area using the ... Aiken County (1) Anderson (2) Anderson County (5) ... Well known Fast Food Restaurant, located on a main street.</description>
	<body>
		Spartanburg Businesses For Sale


Search from 4 businesses for sale in Spartanburg, US. To view the full details of any Spartanburg business for sale , click the business title. Buy a business in Spartanburg, change area using the links below or Sell a Business .
 You are here: 
 Home » All Countries » United States » South East » South Carolina » Spartanburg 
 
 Aiken (9) Aiken County (1) Anderson (1) Anderson County (3) Beaufort County (8) Camden (2) 

 Charleston (35) Columbia (159) Florence (10) Fort Mill (1) Gaffney (1) Georgetown County (1) 

 Greenville (57) Greenwood (1) Hilton Head Island (5) Horry County (54) Irmo (2) Lancaster County (1) 

 Lexington County (11) Marion County (2) McCormick County (1) Myrtle Beach (62) North Augusta (3) 

 Orangeburg County (2) Richland County (3) Rock Hill (3) Senaca (1) Spartanburg (4) 

 Summerville (1) Sumter County (3) Taylors (2) York County (2) Other (230) 

 
 Accommodation Don&apos;t mind Included Not included 
 
Refine your business for sale search, Advanced Search 

 (What is RSS?) 

 
 1 
 Spartanburg Franchise Store With Established Repeat ClienteleMurfreesboro Location Spartanburg,SC Price $ 42,500 Turnover $ 170,000 Profit Undisclosed A successful established business where literally everyone uses your products and services! A business wher... Well Known Fast Food Restaurant For Sale Location SC Price $ 89,000 Turnover $ 260,000 Profit $ 65,000 Well known Fast Food Restaurant, located on a main street. The current owner has another business opportunity, Growing Car Title Loans Service For Sale Location SC Price Undisclosed Turnover Undisclosed Profit Undisclosed This Title Loan Business is growing rapidly and needs a cash infusion. The owner is offering a 3% a month r... Heavy Equipment Parts Remanufacturing For Sale Location Spartanburg,SC Price $ 999,000 Turnover $ 830,969 Profit $ 45,618 Price reduced by $800,000! Founded in 1983, the company remanufactures, services and sells heavy duty indus... 
 1 
 
 © 1997 - 2011 Dynamis Plc 
 
 Franchise Opportunities Business Opportunities Blog Find a Business Opportunity Starting a Business 

 Terms&amp;Conditions Privacy and Cookie Policy Site Map Help&amp;FAQs Staying Safe 

 Australia Canada Ireland New Zealand South Africa Spain UK USA
	</body>
</document>
