<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000477" url="http://www.abovetopsecret.com/forum/thread797524/pg1" time="2012-07-12-15:44" support="3" score="0.0057835769801094635" bingtitle="What&apos;s in McDonald&apos;s Food Chicken? (Hint: It’s NOT Chicken), page 1" webtitle="What&apos;s in McDonald&apos;s Food Chicken? (Hint: It’s NOT Chicken), page 1">
			<query id="000037" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="001228" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="001511" bing-rank="135"/>
	<description>My wife is always talking about what is in fast food ... the nutritional information for chicken at any fast food ... Yet, I can&apos;t help but tuck into my order of fries, double ...</description>
	<body>
		HOME TOP TOPICS + NEW TOPICS + ABOUT + GET ATS FORUMS RECENT POSTS CREATE ATS ACCOUNT SEARCH LOG IN 
 
 What&apos;s in McDonald&apos;s Food Chicken? (Hint: It’s NOT Chicken), page 1 
 privacy Pages:
 ATS Members have flagged this thread 8 times Topic started on 14-1-2012 @ 04:51 PM by samlf3rd My wife is always talking about what is in fast food, and it is starting to get the attention of people everywhere. If you haven&apos;t already seen it go
watch FoodInc. awesome movie.
Now, my son loves Chicken Nuggets, who doesn&apos;t? They are an easy eat, and can be fun. However, a recent study says:
 
Frying chicken is fairly simple, if a little messy. You dip pieces of chicken into a mix of egg and milk, roll them around in flour and spices, then
cook the chicken in sizzling hot oil until the pieces are brown, crispy and delicious.

But wait! Don’t forget to add a dash of dimethylpolysiloxane, an anti-foaming agent made of silicone that is also used in Silly Putty and cosmetics.

Now add a heaping spoonful of tertiary butylhydroquinone (TBHQ), which is a chemical preservative and a form of butane (AKA lighter fluid). One gram
of TBHQ can cause “nausea, vomiting, ringing in the ears, delirium, a sense of suffocation, and collapse,&quot; according to A Consumer’s Dictionary
of Food Additives. Five grams of TBHQ can kill you.

Sprinkle on thirteen other corn-derived ingredients, and you&apos;re only about twenty shy as many ingredients as a single chicken nugget from
McDonald’s. And you were using pulverized chicken skin and mechanically reclaimed meat for your chicken, right?

No one in his or her right mind would cook chicken like this. Yet every day, hoards of Americans consume these ingredients in Chicken McNuggets, which
McDonalds claims are “made with white meat, wrapped up in a crisp tempura batter.”

However chicken only accounts for about 50% of a Chicken McNugget. The other 50% includes a large percentage of corn derivatives, sugars, leavening
agents and other completely synthetic ingredients, meaning that parts of the nugget do not come from a field or farm at all. They come from a
petroleum plant. Hungry?

Scariest perhaps is the fact that this recipe is a new and improved, “healthier” Chicken McNugget launched in 2003 after a federal judge called
the deep-fried poultry bites “a McFrankenstein creation of various elements not utilized by the home cook.” Also terrifying is the fact that these
McFrankenuggets are overwhelmingly marketed to children who love their fun shapes and kid-friendly size.

While McDonald’s is of course the poster child for fast food ire, if you look at the nutritional information for chicken at any fast food
restaurant, the ingredient list will be dozens of items longer than the egg, flour, chicken and oil recipe you might use at home.

Eating fast food is a habit, but it is one that you can break? No doubt you rarely plan to have a delicious meal at Arby’s for dinner, a lingering
lunch at Carl’s Jr. or a special breakfast at the Burger King in the airport. It just happens. You are late, tired, hungry, broke, or all of the
above. You have no time, and you must find something to eat before you crash. All of a sudden a bright, friendly sign beckons from the side of the
road: Drive-through!

In five minutes you are happily chowing down on an inexpensive, filling meal. But don’t be fooled – the true cost of fast food does not come out
of your wallet, but out of your body, your health, and your years on this earth.

You can break the unhealthy fast food habit: educate yourself about the true ingredients of fast food items, plan ahead for your meals, carry healthy
snacks like nuts to ward off hunger and cook healthy chicken recipes at home. Convince yourself that fast food is the most disgusting stuff on the
planet and is harmful to you and to those you love. After reading this, that shouldn’t be too hard.

Full ingredient list for a Chicken McNugget (from McDonald’s website):

White boneless chicken, water, food starch-modified, salt, seasoning (autolyzed yeast extract, salt, wheat starch, natural flavoring (botanical
source), safflower oil, dextrose, citric acid, rosemary), sodium phosphates, seasoning (canola oil, mono- and diglycerides, extractives of rosemary).
Battered and breaded with: water, enriched flour (bleached wheat flour, niacin, reduced iron, thiamin mononitrate, riboflavin, folic acid), yellow
corn flour, food starch-modified, salt, leavening (baking soda, sodium acid pyrophosphate, sodium aluminum phosphate, monocalcium phosphate, calcium
lactate), spices, wheat starch, whey, corn starch. Prepared in vegetable oil (Canola oil, corn oil, soybean oil, hydrogenated soybean oil with TBHQ
and citric acid added to preserve freshness). Dimethylpolysiloxane added as an antifoaming agent.

Full ingredient list for my mother’s fried chicken:
Bone-in chicken pieces, egg, milk, flour, canola oil, salt&amp;pepper. 

Source: www.weather.com... 
 

 reply posted on 14-1-2012 @ 04:54 PM by samlf3rd Here is what is in the new (very very old) McRib:
 How many ingredients are there?
At face value, the sandwich contains just pork, onions, and pickle slices slathered in barbecue sauce and laid out on a bun. But the truth is, there
are roughly 70 ingredients. The bun alone contains 34, says TIME&apos;s Melnick. In addition to chemicals like ammonium sulfate and polysorbate 80, the
most egregious may be azodicarbonamide — &quot;a flour-bleaching agent most commonly used in the manufactur[ing] of foamed plastics like gym mats and
the soles of shoes.&quot; According to McDonald&apos;s own ingredient list, the bun also includes calcium sulfate and ethoxylated mono- and diglycerides,
among other chemicals.

Ooof. What&apos;s the meat made of?
Pig innards and plenty of salt. Typically, &quot;restructured meat product&quot; includes pig bits like tripe, heart, and scalded stomach, says Whet Moser at
Chicago Magazine, citing a 1995 article by Robert Mandigo, a professor at the University of Nebraska. These parts are cooked and blended with salt and
water to extract salt-soluble proteins, which act as a &quot;glue&quot; that helps bind the reshaped meat together.

Is it really that bad for you?
Well, it&apos;s certainly not good for you. Though &quot;slightly trimmer than the Big Mac,&quot; which contains 540 calories and 29 grams of fat, says Christina
Rexrode at USA Today, the McRib, first introduced in 1982, still packs in 500 calories and 26 grams of fat. And despite its name, one thing you won&apos;t
find inside a McRib is bones. The absence of any detectable &quot;rib&quot; is what gives the unnutritious mush its &quot;quirky sense of humor,&quot; says Marta
Fearon, McDonald&apos;s U.S. marketing director. 

source: theweek.com... 
 

 reply posted on 14-1-2012 @ 04:54 PM by samlf3rd reply to post by samlf3rd 
 

Gym Mats? Sweaty ball sacks in your sandwich-yummy. 
 
 

 reply posted on 14-1-2012 @ 04:58 PM by Vandalour reply to post by samlf3rd 
 

hmm..
dammit.. but it taste so good
there just had to be a catch, same goes with candy and smoking
 
 

 reply posted on 14-1-2012 @ 04:58 PM by yourboycal2 I was just making fun of bacon and sausage lovers on the other thread.


and here is karma with my nuggets lol. I knew they were bad , but soooo good , how they get that chicken to be so yummy and dippipable ready ! 


I think i&apos;ll eat them one last time , and then say to tell with you !


Everything is poison . Typing on this keyboard i&apos;m probably getting germs , and plastic petrolioum byproducts all up in me 

and why is chicken news on weather website lol 
 

 reply posted on 14-1-2012 @ 05:02 PM by BigBruddah I&apos;m not gonna lie, I could really go for some maccas right now, it must be the hangover :/ 
 

 reply posted on 14-1-2012 @ 05:06 PM by samlf3rd I&apos;m about to order a b-b-q pizza right now. I hope my local pizza place at least uses some good products. 
 

 reply posted on 14-1-2012 @ 05:25 PM by scottlpool2003 reply to post by samlf3rd 
 

Wasn&apos;t that in the olden days though or are McDonald&apos;s lying on their website:

Are the Chicken McNuggets really 100% chicken?
The only meat used in McDonald’s Chicken McNuggets is chicken breast meat. The white meat is minced before being shaped into nuggets, and then
coated with a specially seasoned batter at our trusted suppliers, such as Keystone Foods. You may also like to try the Chicken Selects Premium Breast
Strips which are made from white meat chicken which has not been minced. To find out more about Keystone Foods, read their story here.
 www.mcdonalds.com... 

That to me sounds like it is chicken, not &quot;hint, it&apos;s not chicken&quot; :S

EDIT:

Sorry I didn&apos;t read your post properly. I do think your title mislead me but my bad for not reading it properly.

Yeah just read the ingredients and there are a hell of a lot, which are probably disguised as preservatives etc.

 edit on 14-1-2012 by scottlpool2003 because: (no reason given)
 
 

 reply posted on 14-1-2012 @ 05:25 PM by Shadys321 I love McDonalds. 
 

 reply posted on 14-1-2012 @ 05:41 PM by SilentE I hate Mcdonalds so much!

From the food and the staff, all the way to the idiotically built road that leads you to it.

Yet, I can&apos;t help but tuck into my order of fries, double cheese and 9 mcnuggets from time to time. 

Damn you McDonalds!

Damn you to hell! edit on 14-1-2012 by SilentE because: typo
 
 

 reply posted on 14-1-2012 @ 05:49 PM by Hessdalen i stopped eating at fastfood restaurants two years ago and boy i do not regret my decision, especially when i read sth like this =) 
 

 reply posted on 14-1-2012 @ 05:54 PM by 46ACE 500 calories for&lt;.99 from minced up pig leftovers sounds like a rather efficient way to feed a few&quot; billion served&quot; .You want filet- Mignon? Its
down in the meat case $ 15.99/lb...

I like McD&apos;s too: but we just bought a &quot;vitamix&quot; (industrial strength blender/ food processor) and are trying100% whole foods for a bit... I&apos;ve
got plenty of emergency frozen pizza and cold beer in reserve. I can choose to eat what I want (a luxury most of the world does not enjoy).Don&apos;t
even think about outlawing fast food! 
 
 

 reply posted on 14-1-2012 @ 06:00 PM by LittleVoice731 I stopped taking my kids there a few years ago. All they wanted was the toy anyway, so I just go in a buy the toys. Once a woman asked my why I
didn&apos;t want the happy meal and I told her in front of about 15 customers that I would never allow my children to eat the garbage they called food. I
do LOVE their apple pies, but I must resist the urge to eat garbage...so hard. 
 

 reply posted on 14-1-2012 @ 07:00 PM by dreamingawake Originally posted by samlf3rd 
 reply to post by samlf3rd 
 

Gym Mats? Sweaty ball sacks in your sandwich-yummy. 

 

But really what did you expect was in those nuggets, gold?
That&apos;s what nuggets are, crap! 
 Pages:      ^^TOP^^ 

 
 Poor Mans Mock Roast! An Aussie Pensioners experiment with chuck steak! 
   Posted 11 days ago with 5 member flags Get Local! Join a co-op, save money and eat better! 
   Posted 2 days ago with 5 member flags Critisized because I like garden burgers! Health food Stigma? 
   Posted 7 days ago with 4 member flags How OL turned roast chicken stuffing into croutons! 
   Posted 0 days ago with 4 member flags Need smooth soup ideas (not chix) for a sick person. 
   Posted 11 days ago with 3 member flags Junk Food 
   Posted 1 days ago with 2 member flags Ice cream for the summer 
   Posted 19 days ago with 1 member flags America\&apos;s 10 Best Burgers, According To National Geographic 
   Posted 16 days ago with 1 member flags 
 Newest topics, updated in real-time: 

 I stumbled across these.. relates to Dulce underground base 
   Aliens and UFOs : 53 seconds ago Computer Algorithm (You can call him/her AL) as a Automated Reporter. 
   General Chit Chat : 1 minutes ago Do not resist an evil person,what is your under standing ? 
   Religion, Faith, And Theology : 5 minutes ago Have the major Gov&apos; of the world already surrendered to ET ? 
   Aliens and UFOs : 6 minutes ago Californian beach lit up by mysterious blue glow 
   Fragile Earth : 7 minutes ago The Secret World Cabal recruiting thread 
   Video Games : 20 minutes ago 9/11&amp;The Cult of Saturn 
   General Conspiracies : 29 minutes ago What if our brain has been lying to us? 
   General Conspiracies : 30 minutes ago 
 Newest topics getting flags, in real-time: 

 &quot;Today, a homeless looking man handed me $50 and this note. Do any of you have any idea what it mea 
   General Conspiracies : 13 hours ago, 28 flags The Most Damning Documentary Showing Proof That 911 Hijackers Were Govt. Agents!!! MUST-SEE 
   9/11 Conspiracies : 16 hours ago, 22 flags Why We Should ALL be Thanking Ron Paul. 
   Political Issues : 10 hours ago, 18 flags Scientists Prove Ancient Alien Cauldrons in Siberia are Real 
   Paranormal Studies : 15 hours ago, 17 flags Verizon asks U.S. Government for permission to edit the Internet 
   General Conspiracies : 16 hours ago, 13 flags Opossum protein neutralizes nearly all poisons, could have benefits for humans ( ricin and anthrax a 
   Medical Issues&amp;Conspiracies : 17 hours ago, 13 flags Poll: Americans Confidence In Television Media Falls To All-Time Low 
   Breaking Alternative News : 6 hours ago, 11 flags Israeli war threat over Syrian chemical weapons 
   World War Three : 10 hours ago, 11 flags 
 Newest topics getting replies, in real-time: 

 The Bright and Morning Star &quot;Mary&quot; Queen of Heaven and husband Allah 
   Conspiracies in Religions : 17 hours ago, 95 replies How could the first living cell have evolved? 
   Science&amp;Technology : 17 hours ago, 83 replies &quot;Today, a homeless looking man handed me $50 and this note. Do any of you have any idea what it mea 
   General Conspiracies : 13 hours ago, 69 replies How many Disinfomation agents are members here? 
   General Conspiracies : 7 hours ago, 51 replies Israeli war threat over Syrian chemical weapons 
   World War Three : 10 hours ago, 46 replies When you hear &apos;UFO Expert&apos;, which names come to mind? 
   Aliens and UFOs : 16 hours ago, 41 replies Can I Call Someone Out On ATS? 
   General Chit Chat : 14 hours ago, 31 replies Truth of why people don&apos;t take ET seriously 
   Aliens and UFOs : 17 hours ago, 28 replies 
 [close] The Above Top Secret Web sites are a
wholly owned social content community of
The Above Network, LLC.

 This content community relies on
user-generated content from our member contributors.
The opinions of our members are not those of site ownership
who maintains strict editorial agnosticism and simply provides
a collaborative venue for free expression.


ATS Server: www3.theabovenetwork.com 
Header data: 0.015 seconds
Page processed in: 0.181 seconds

 INFO 
 About ATS 
 Info for Journalists 
 Site Statistics 
 Advertising 
 The Above Network 
 Contact Us 
 CONTENT 
 Board Home 
 ATS News 
 Firehose 
 Recent Posts 
 Popular Forums 
 10-Day Summary 
 Email Newsletter 
 RSS Feeds 
 Twitter 
 Facebook 
 VIDEO 
 ATS News 
 Top Videos 
 Videos Home 
 Pro Videos 
 Member Videos 
 HELP 
 DMCA info 
 Join ATS 
 Recover Password 
 Terms&amp;Conditions 
 Privacy Policy 
 Contact Us
	</body>
</document>
