<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000568" url="http://www.ocweekly.com/2009-07-09/food/tk-burgers/" time="2012-07-12-15:51" support="1" score="0.0018424759420155286" bingtitle="TK Burgers Refuses to Conform to the Numbing Sameness of a Fast ..." webtitle="TK Burgers Refuses to Conform to the Numbing Sameness of a Fast-Food Chain - Page 1 - Food - Orange County - OC Weekly">
			<query id="000442" bing-rank="61"/>
	<description>Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter ... TK on Bristol: Cashier not included ... Conforming to the numbing McSameness of a fast-food ...</description>
	<body>
		Food 
 Entire Site Articles&amp;Blogs Restaurants Places Events Music Images Ads Bars Best Of Movies 
 News Home Navel Gazing Moxley Confidential Ask a Mexican Archives Search OC Weekly Flipbook Weekly Newsletter Get Mobile Hey, You! Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Music Home Music Blog Ask Exene Concert Calendar Bars and Clubs Submit an Event Music Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurants Home Food Blog Find a Restaurant Reviews Menus Deals Happy Hours Dining Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurant Ads Arts Home Arts Features Theater Trendzilla OC Bookly Arts Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Film Home Film Blog Film Festivals Film Poll 2011 Showtimes Film Newsletter Get Mobile Free Stuff Best Of Home 2011 2010 2009 2008 Best Of Newsletter Get Mobile Best Of Ads Promotions Home Promotional Events Street Team Free Stuff Promotions Newsletter Get Mobile Deals Post an Ad Jobs Real Estate Advertiser Index Deals Deals Newsletter Alternative Healing MMJ Home MMJ News Ask a Lawyer The Rolling Paper Coupons Dispensary Guide MMJ Newsletter 
Top

dining

Stories
 
 
Features

 Wahoo&apos;s Fish Taco&apos;s New Location--With Tequila! 

By Edwin Goei
 
Features

 50 Years of La Cave; The Best is Yet to Come 

By Arrissia Owen
 
Blogs

 Slater&apos;s Unveils Burger Patty Made of 100% Bacon 

By Michelle Woo
 
Blogs

 Why McDonald&apos;s Wont Serve Breakfast Late 

By Michelle Woo
 
Blogs

 11 Things You Should Know About Tapatio 

By Gustavo Arellano
 
Features

 OC Fishermen Are Out to Sea 

By Michelle Woo
 
Slideshow

 Food Fight! 

By Ed Carrasco
 
Slideshow

 Scenes From Dana Point Lobster Fest 

By Matt Oliver
 
   
 Pin It 
 
TK Burgers Refuses to Conform to the Numbing Sameness of a Fast-Food Chain


 A A A Comments (4) By EDWIN GOEI Thursday, Jul 9 2009 
 McDifferent
TK Burgers refuses to conform to the numbing sameness of a fast-food chain 
 Jonathan Ho TK on Bristol: Cashier not included 
Location Info
 
Map
 
 TK Fast Grill 

 110 Pacific Coast Highway 
 Huntington Beach , CA 92648 
Category: Restaurant &gt; Burgers 

Region: Huntington Beach 

 Photos 

 
 0 user reviews Write A Review Save to foursquare 
0
 
 
Related Content
 
 Beverage Giant Diageo Screws Independent Brewer At Scottish Awards Show May 10, 2012 Cool Films to Watch When It&apos;s Hot Outside May 24, 2012 Record Store Day: Good for Only a Few Stores? April 19, 2012 Creme Tangerine&apos;s Parker Macy Talks Record Store Day 2012 April 20, 2012 Wine Company Trying to Trademark Term &apos;Taco Truck&apos; October 4, 2011 
 
More About
 
 Huntington Beach Mission Viejo Costa Mesa Food and Cooking Eating Out 
 
Like this Story?
 
Sign up for the Dining Newsletter: The week&apos;s top local food news and events, plus interviews with chefs and restaurant owners, dining tips, and a peek at our print review.
 Privacy Policy Cancel Continue 
No one forced me to visit every outlet of TK Burgers, but I did it anyway. And despite bearing a passing resemblance to Morgan Spurlock ’s Super Size Me endeavor, this was purely for pleasure. I didn’t go to write a social commentary or expect some profound revelation about the state of our food culture—and I haven’t. Really, this was just an excuse to eat some good burgers and explore OC’s beloved local hamburger chain beyond its now-iconic Huntington Beach location.

From that post-card-perfect beach scene to the genteel, leafy suburbs of Mission Viejo —where, coincidentally, TK Burgers’newest branch just opened—my week-long foray took me to all five restaurants. I discovered each to be unique and happily assimilated into the neighborhood in which it resides.

But throughout the chain, unshakeable constants exist. Surf stickers and vinyl album covers will always plaster the ceiling. Framed surf photos of local beaches will always line the walls. Modern rock will blare from stereo speakers. And there is an unwritten TK Burger company rule that dictates that all cashiers must be cute females.

Above all, the owner, Jim Kalatschan , is keen on keeping the food at his slowly growing burger empire consistent. His buns are always sourced from Carson bakery Giuliano’s because the bread there holds its integrity best against moisture. It has a texture that is neither too porous nor too dense. His beef patties, the same thickness as a Quarter Pounder, are never frozen. And the toppings never waver from the time-tested and traditional: house-made Thousand Island, thin-sliced red onion, tomato, pickles and iceberg lettuce.

Even so, slight variations in execution occur among branches, which is to be expected whenever food is prepared to order in the un-regimented, un-assembly-line way that TK’s cooks do. But this proves to be endearing. Conforming to the numbing McSameness of a fast-food chain is not a part of TK Burgers’soul or fiber.

The Costa Mesa store on Bristol —housed in an A-frame structure and attracting hipsters from the Lab anti-mall nearby—served my patty well-done. The new Mission Viejo branch—shacked up in an old KFC and already frequented by residents of Republican-rich suburbia—cooked it on the pinkish side. Both were full-fisted, juicy sandwiches—burger brothers that weren’t identical twins but shared the same genetic predisposition and hugged, of course, by that milky pillow of the mother bun.

If you want a great rib-eye sandwich, one of the more premium items, the Newport Beach branch grills the best. Tender and fatty, the steak will make you wonder why we even bother chopping up and reconstituting what is already great sandwich fodder. You do, however, pay a price for the pleasure of eating here. Parking spots are as rare as free seats in the closet-sized dining room. Both are usually claimed by tourists who are mostly unaware that TK Burgers doesn’t offer relish on its burgers (though they ask anyway).

The oddest outpost of the bunch is the second Costa Mesa restaurant, located on 19th Street: It is actually a full-on diner. It’s also the only one that cooks more than burgers. Its breakfast plates put the IHOPs of the world on notice, just as the sandwiches shame McDonalds . French toast comes dusted in cinnamon and is made from eggy bread as thick as an airport paperback. And the huevos rancheros—two eggs on a platform of corn tortilla—is doused with melting cheese and a piquant salsa good enough for the Mexican cooks’mothers to call their own. The side of Spanish rice and beans is further testament that“ buenos días ”is the customary way to say“good morning”in this neighborhood lined with Mexican shops and taquerías .

But if you ask me which one I liked best, it’s always going to be the TK in Huntington Beach, and not just because the scenes depicted in those surfing photos unfold in living color just outside the window. This TK Burgers takes command of the deep fryer better than the others, producing crisply browned fries with a perfect 50-50 ratio of exterior crunch and interior fluff. And yes, the crashing waves, squawking sea gulls and the occasional sight of bikini-clad bodies ain’t bad either. Like I said, no one had to put me up to this.

 TK Burgers, 110 Pacific Coast Hwy., Huntington Beach, (714) 960-3238; 2966 Bristol St., Costa Mesa, (714) 662-2572; 615 W 19th St., Costa Mesa, (949) 548-2858; 24902 Chrisanta Dr., Mission Viejo, (949) 588-7200; 2119 W Balboa Blvd., Newport Beach, (949) 673-3438; www.tkburgers.com . Check website for hours. Sandwiches and burgers, $3.99-$5.99. 
 Check out this week&apos;s featured ad for News 
 Fourth Street Medical Center 

 View Ad View Website 
 More Ads &gt;&gt; 
Get the Dining Newsletter
 
The week&apos;s top local food news and events, plus interviews with chefs and restaurant owners, dining tips, and a peek at our print review.
 Privacy Policy Cancel Continue 
 
 
 Email
to Friend Write to
Editor Print
Article 
   
 
Steve 07/13/2009 10:37:00 PM

Hi Jim: We&apos;ve done some article framing for you in the past.
Would you like us to frame the recent OC Weekly restaurant review??? Please contact us at 909-971-0244
thanks, Steve
 
JB 07/13/2009 10:07:00 PM

Out of all the &apos;legendary&apos; burger places in Southern California, TK Burgers is one of only two that I actually think is worthy of any praise. 
[The other is Fatburger.] 
I know I&apos;m going to get death threats for saying this, but I just don&apos;t understand the fuss over that other place that has &quot;double doubles&quot; on the menu. 
To the owner of TK: keep up the good work. 
I do wish you&apos;d accept credit cards, though. 
I&apos;d visit more often, and still tip your nice-looking staff in cash....
 
Edwin Goei 07/13/2009 7:14:00 PM

I haven&apos;t heard or tried Wimpy&apos;s. A Google search seems to indicate that Wimpy&apos;s used to be right across the street from the pier where the mall is now. That&apos;s a shame. From what I&apos;ve read it sounds exactly like my kind of place (just like TK Huntington is).
 
BeachBumBob 07/12/2009 11:36:00 AM

What a great write up, like you I also like TK Burgers in Huntinton Beach. Do you remember going to &quot;Wimpys&quot; on PCH? I know it was torn down, but werent they suppose to rebuild or the city was going to re-move them somewhere else?

Monday morning, I just might follow your hamburger trail an visit it all of them.
 
 Please enable JavaScript to leave a comment.   
Now Trending


 
 Taqueria Tapatia Owner Shien Wong Sentenced For IRS Evasion 7-Eleven To Give Out Free Slurpees Tomorrow on 7-11 Red Robin Introduces Burgers With Ghost Chili Pepper, a.k.a. &quot;The Hottest Pepper In The World&quot; 
 More Dining Stories &gt; 
OC Weekly on Facebook
 
Slide shows » 

 The Bruery&apos;s New Tasting Room Grand Opening Umami Burger Anaheim Grand Opening Gringo Bandito Taco Eating Challenge @ Chronic Tacos More Slideshows&gt;&gt; 
 
Best of Orange County
 
2011 - Food&amp;Drink

 Best Coffee 
 Portola Coffee Lab Best Pizza 
 Ecco 
 More Food&amp;Drink Awards &gt; About Us | Media Kit | Work for OC Weekly | Esubscribe | Free Classifieds | OC Weekly Advertising | National Online Advertising | Mobile | Privacy Policy | Terms of Use | Site Problems? | RSS | Site Map OC Weekly®is a registered trademark of Village Voice Media Holdings, LLC ©2012 OC Weekly, LP, All rights reserved. Browse Voice Nation Most Popular | Most Recent Newsletters | Mobile Log in Sign up 
 New York Village Voice 
 LA Weekly 
 Phoenix New Times 
 Denver Westword 
 Houston Press 
 Dallas Observer 
 SF Weekly 
 Seattle Weekly 
 St. Louis RFT 
 Miami New Times 
 Minneapolis City Pages 
 OC Weekly 
 Broward/Palm Beach New Times 
 

 
 Voice Places 

Discover restaurants, nightlife, travel, shopping...
 
 VOICE Daily Deals 

Get 50 to 90% off every day on restaurants, movies, massages...
 
 Best Of... 

More than 10,000 of the BEST things to eat, drink, and experience
 
 My Voice Nation 

Join the Village Voice community and get exclusive deals and info
 
 Happy Hour 

Your local Happy Hour guide at your fingertips
 
 or 
 Log in or Sign up 
 Social Connect: 
Use your favorite account to access My Voice Nation.
 
 
Use your My Voice Nation account to log in:
 E-mail 
 
 Password 
 
 Forgot password? Remember me or 
 Sign Up or Log in 
 Social Connect: 
Sign up for My Voice Nation with your preferred network.
 
 
Sign up for a My Voice Nation account:
 E-mail 
 
 Privacy policy 
 Settings Log Out
	</body>
</document>
