<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000210" url="http://www.oppapers.com/essays/Fast-Food-Restaurant-Mcdonald-s/704790" time="2012-07-12-15:24" support="18" score="0.11384514947687172" bingtitle="Fast Food Restaurant: Mcdonald’s - Term Papers - Softleb" webtitle="Fast Food Restaurant Mcdonald s - Term Papers - Softleb">
			<query id="000905" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="000233" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000610" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000601" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="000124" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="001348" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="001487" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000594" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="001355" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="001364" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="000893" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="001378" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000622" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="001504" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000624" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000607" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="001032" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="001010" bing-rank="64"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant: Mcdonald’s Operations ... time) does the process of an order take? 9) Observe and describe the layout of the place. Fast Food Restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Navigation Skip to Content 
 
 OPPapers.com 

 Free Essays and Research Papers 
 
 Join Login Writing Service Resources Help Saved Docs Contact Us 
 
 Search 
 
 Tweet 
 
Get Better Grades Today By Joining OPPapers.com and Accessing Over 650,000 Articles and Essays!
 get better grades 
 Home Page » Recreation&amp;Sports » Cooking Research Papers 
 
Fast Food Restaurant: Mcdonald’s
 
Fast Food Restaurant: Mcdonald’s
Operations Management

Case 1: FAST FOOD

14-03-2011

Hussein El-Ratel

Questions
1) How are in-store orders taken?
2) Are the hamburgers prepared to order, or are they prepared ahead of time and delivered from a storage bin?
3) How are special orders handled?
4) How are the hamburgers cooked?
5) How are the hamburgers assembled?
6) Is a microwave oven used in the process?
7) How are other common items, such as French fries and drinks, handled?
8) How long (time) does the process of an order take?
9) Observe and describe the layout of the place.

Fast Food Restaurant: McDonald’s

1) McDonald provides self-service facilities to its customers. The customers come to the restaurant, book their order at the order and payment counter. The staff of the restaurant provides the food items on the table of the customer or the customer himself can take it to the table. All the franchise of the Organization follows the same 
Is this essay helpful? Join OPPapers to read more and access more than 650,000 just like it!
 get better grades pattern to provide unique and standardized services. The orders are delivered to the customers within the fraction of a minute.

2) There is no fix time to prepare Hamburger. During the lunch hours, a huge rush can be seen at McDonald&apos;s restaurant. For this situation, they prepare Hamburger before the lunch time and store it at their food store and deliver it as per customer requirements. They are also prepared on the demands and orders of the customers. The Production on order is completed when there is a large order at once; otherwise the restaurant always prepares its stock of the fast food ready to be delivered to the customers.

3) The special orders at McDonald are handled quickly, securely and professionally. The Special Orders of the customer are recorded, prepared and delivered according to the requirements of the customer. For instance, when a person orders burger without onion, the process to prepare the burger is molded according to the customer. The Production Process flows in a chain direction. The Process and the... Read Full Essay 
Already a Member? Login Now » 

This essay and over 650,000 other essays are available now on OPPapers.com.
 
 Submitted by: softleb Date Submitted: 05/22/2011 12:07 PM Category: Cooking Length: 4 pages (866 words) Views: 1051 

 Report this Essay Save Paper 
 
Related Essays

 Fast Food Restaurant... Feasibility Report For a... a Different Way To Look At... Nordsee - The Different... Organizational Culture And... Critical Thinking Of Fast... Based Upon The Information... Consumer Attitudes To... The Cause And Effect Of... Fast-Food-Restaurant Causes Of The Popularity... Fast Food Restaurants... The Factors Of Influencing... Is The Job In Fast-Food... Compare And Contrast Two... Benefits Of Fast Food... Fast Food Restaurants... Consumer Purchase... Fast Food Restaurants And... Marketing Of a Fast Food... Advantages And... Research On Fast Food... Us Fast Food Fast Food Market In Canada... The Culture Influence On... Mcdonald&apos;s Vs. All Other... Does Burger King Or... Mcdonald’s: Serving Fast... Analysing Mcdonalds (Fast... The Pricing Strategies Of... 
 Read Full Essay 
Already a Member? Login Now » 
 Reviews ( 1 ) Grade 1 grades Login to grade this document. 
 RSS ©2012 OPPapers.com
 Help 
 About Us Our Blog F.A.Q. Contact Us 
 Other Stuff 
 Terms and Privacy Site Stats Sitemap Advertise With Us 
 Recent Topics 
 Competency Goal 3 Lsi r Assessment Tool Remarriage Analyze The Ways In... Important Of Computer... Importance Of...
	</body>
</document>
