<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000580" url="http://customercarecontacts.com/kfc-canada-contact-phone-of-kfc-home-delivery-in-canada/" time="2012-07-12-15:52" support="5" score="0.006557894488151787" bingtitle="KFC Canada: Contact, phone of KFC home delivery in Canada ..." webtitle="KFC Canada: Contact, phone of KFC home delivery in Canada | Customer Care Contacts">
			<query id="000257" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000930" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="000914" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="001180" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="000272" bing-rank="111"/>
	<description>Order KFC Online To order KFC online click here. KFC ... The fast food restaurant had revenue of over $11 billion in 2008. ... was available at this location, and he did confirm it ...</description>
	<body>
		Home About Browse Search 
 
KFC Canada: Contact, phone of KFC home delivery in Canada

 August 9, 2011 customer help Restaurant , 3 

 VN:F [1.9.18_1163] RATE THIS COMPANY/ SERVICE please wait... Rating: 5.0/ 10 (1 vote cast) 
 Contact KFC–Canada : Find below customer service details of KFC in Canada , including phone and address. You can reach the below contact for KFC home delivery, gift cards, vouchers/coupons, gift certificates, menu, KFC stores or other queries.
 
 KFC Head Office 
KFC Canada
101 Exchange Avenue
Vaughan Ontario L4K 5R6
Canada

 KFC Customer Service Phone 
Phone: 1-866-664-5696

 KFC Home Delivery (contact the below numbers for KFC home delivery)
British Columbia: 1-866-KFC-4-YOU (532-4968)
Alberta: 1-866-KFC-4-YOU (532-4968)
Red Deer: 403-346-8838
Manitoba: 1-866-KFC-4-YOU (532-4968)
Ontario: 1-866-KFC-4-YOU (532-4968)
New Brunswick: 1-866-KFC-4-YOU (532-4968)
Nova Scotia: 1-866-KFC-4-YOU (532-4968)
Québec: 1-888-4-PFK-PFK     (4-735-735)

Newfoundland
Corner Brook: 709-639-8900
Gander: 709-256-8899
Stephenville: 709-643-6600

Saskatchewan
&gt;Regina
306-791-6404
306-791-6410
306-791-6414
306-791-6424
306-791-6434

&gt;Moose Jaw
306-649-6449

 KFC Store Locator 
To locate a KFC store nearest to your address click here
 
 Order KFC Online 
To order KFC online click here 

 KFC Menu 
To view the complete list of KFC menu click here . Besides KFC chicken, the menu includes chicken strips, boneless wings, sandwiches, desserts and sides.

 About KFC 
Kentucky Fried Chicken (KFC) was founded by Harland Sanders in the US. The KFC original recipe, made with secret blend of 11 herbs and spices, took birth in the year 1940. KFC is today world’s largest chicken restaurant chain. In fact each day more than 12 million customers are served at KFC restaurants in 109 countries. KFC runs more than 15,000 units around the world. The fast food restaurant had revenue of over $11 billion in 2008. Read More 
 KFC Canada: Contact, phone of KFC home delivery in Canada , 5.0 out of 10 based on 1 rating 
 contact kfc in canada , kfc canada home delivery 


 
3 Responses to“KFC Canada: Contact, phone of KFC home delivery in Canada”

 Janice says: May 10, 2012 at 12:20 pm 
Hi I went to KFC on Weston an Finch on Monday to buy a 15 PC family meal when I get there cashier told me that they have no macaroni salad only thing that me and my family eat except for the other salad then the guy in the back say I have to wait for 15 min for chicken, then another lady was there and she said that she waiting for 20 min when the cashier told its only 10 min, Its ridiculous when you have to wait for so long. I got very upset that and I walk out the store the cashier know me very well I am a usual customer I go there once a week but recently I don’t like the service so from now on I will go to a different location where I can serve faster
 Reply Sabrina says: January 21, 2012 at 7:46 pm 
To Whom it May Concern:

I visited the KFC/Taco Bell location at the northwest corner of Yonge and Steeles Avenue West in Thornhill on the evening of Friday, January 20th at 6:55 pm, and ended up leaving without dinner.

My mother and I had placed our order and paid, but a comment made by an employee (I assume he was the supervisor on duty) made me request a refund and leave.

I am a vegetarian and I asked the man at the cash if the veggie patty was available at this location, and he did confirm it was. I further inquired if the veggie patty was fried in the chicken oil, and the gentleman did confirm that it was. I was disappointed, but happy that he was honest enough to tell me the truth–kudos to him. I settled with ordering a taco bell combo instead, a KFC combo for my mom, and a coleslaw. (The cashier also confirmed that the french fries that came with the combo were also fried in the same oil as the meat, so I requested the nachos as my side.) I will agree, I probably did ask more questions than the average customer, and the employee was kind enough to answer them.

However, when another man who appeared to be the supervisor came over (he was not wearing a name tag, but said his name was Eric–a middle aged man who appeared to be of Middle Eastern background), shooed the cashier away telling him that that you cannot spend so much time with one customer. Then he took over the cash, turned to us, hastily gave us our receipt and said that they cannot spend so much time with us when there are so many people in the line. When we turned around, there were only two others in the line. I found that so repulsive, I immediately requested my money back (which was quickly returned to me), and left.

If the‘veggie’patty, was indeed vegetarian, I would not have to spend so much time asking questions. But honestly, that is not even my issue here. Even if there were a line, customer service should still be honored, but there was barely any line and this man was not able to handle it.

This is customer service at its worst. I have never received such treatment from any restaurant–sit down, nor fast food–and the behavior of this supervisor is not only demeaning, but also unacceptable. Especially considering that this is a more elite location, it is even more shocking. The waiting customers were also so surprised with the events, that they rolled their eyes and smiled at my mother and I.

Whenever I visit restaurants, I do ask questions of this sort and it has never been an issue. Even when I visit establishments in neighborhoods of a lower socio-economic status, they have time to answer my questions without attitude, and the managers never scolded their employees for spending time with me.

If the Colonel were alive, this type of service would not be tolerated. He must be rolling in his grave right now.

Maybe my $16 purchase was too unimportant for this manager. Perhaps if it were a $30 family meal I was purchasing, then I might have been able to ask my questions without rude comments. But as someone who studied management, I always thought that all customers were important. Or maybe I’m just a misled individual.

Either way, I am so appalled by this manager, that I have already started telling my family and friends not to support the KFC/Taco Bell chain, and most definitely NOT the Thornhill location.

Sincerely,

Extremely Disappointed Customer
 Reply jenny carvallie says: January 13, 2012 at 12:08 am 
Hi I want to make a complain I’m not sure if i have the right email but want some to know when you walk in to kfc at finch and weston rd you must be treated like a customer i went in there to buy a dinner the other day and the lady that serve me was not polite at all her name is Suha she did not look pleasant at very rude after she took my money she was coughing and and bending down she was wiping her nose it was so disgusting, why would you having an employee working when sick and don’t no how to treat a customers.
Regards Jenny.
 Reply 


 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 
 
Quick Search
 
Links
 
About Us
 Customer Care Contacts is your online source for phone, address, email and website of companies and services providers. To view latest posts click here 
Like Us
 
 
Copyright©2012 Customer Care Contacts. All Rights Reserved.   Privacy Policy | Terms&amp;Conditions | Contact Us 

Disclaimer: Customer Care Contacts has made reasonable efforts to ensure the accuracy of the contact listings of companies and service providers. We do not accept responsibility for any errors or omissions in the details listed, including the phone, address&amp;website.
	</body>
</document>
