<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000745" url="http://www.smallfootprintfamily.com/2009/11/19/soy-is-not-a-health-food/" time="2012-07-12-16:06" support="3" score="0.0059302992328130084" bingtitle="Soy is Not a Health Food - Small Footprint Family" webtitle="Why Soy is Bad for You and the Planet">
			<query id="001100" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="000160" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000409" bing-rank="222"/>
	<description>Condiments; Breakfast; Beverages; Personal Care; Cleaning ... just about everything you’d find in a fast food ... soy in moderation, it is safest to consume it as a WHOLE FOOD ...</description>
	<body>
		Home About 
 About SFF Advertise The Fine Print Contact 
 Recipes 
 Raw&amp;Fermented Main Dishes Side Dishes Soups Salads Snacks Treats Condiments Breakfast Beverages Personal Care Cleaning Garden Care Arts&amp;Crafts 
 Bookstore Resources 
 Healthy Living Money Savers 
 Health&amp;Nutrition 
 Foodprints 
 Money Savers Gardening 
 
Soy is Not a Health Food

in Foodprints , Health&amp;Nutrition 
 
The mainstream media has got news for you these days: Overweight? Try soy! Hot-flashes? Eat soy! Blotchy skin? Rub on some soy! Lactose intolerant? Soy!

With all the ads on TV and all the products popping up everywhere, you’d think soy foods were the answer to everything that ails you. Unfortunately, nothing could be further from the truth. Despite the well-crafted, expensive PR campaign, soy is not a health food, and people need to know the havoc it has wrought on both our bodies and the environment. 

A Brief History of Soy

It is only very recently in our history that humans have been eating processed soy foods and soybean oil. Grown on a large, commercial scale by U.S. agribusiness during the 50s and 60s, by the 70s and 80s, the soybean industry was troubled by emerging evidence that soybean oil consumption lowered immunity, increased susceptibility to infectious disease, and promoted cancer.

At this same time, the bigwigs in the soybean industry got the bright idea that if they could demonize the competition by making saturated fats like lard and coconut oil appear to be the cause of heart disease—the nation’s number one killer—people wouldn’t pay much attention to the negative findings coming out about soybean oil. Starting in the mid-1980s, the soybean oil industry began a multi-million dollar anti-saturated fat campaign. Saturated fats increased cholesterol, they said, and high cholesterol causes heart disease. The tropical oils (coconut, palm, and palm kernel oils) were singled out as being the worst offenders because of their high saturated fat content.

Some, but not all, saturated fats can raise total cholesterol, (coconut and palm oils do NOT) but there is no solid evidence that high cholesterol actually causes heart disease. That is why high cholesterol is only considered a “risk factor” rather than a cause. In fact, it looks like high cholesterol is a protective response in the body against dangerous inflammation—which does cause heart disease. But that didn’t stop the soy industry. The soybean industry fed misleading information to gullible consumer advocate groups like The Center for Science in the Public Interest (CSPI), which were persuaded to begin their own campaigns against saturated fats.

These high-profile organizations placed anti-saturated fat ads in the media, published newsletters, magazine articles, and books, and lobbied for political action against the use of tropical oils and other saturated fats. Since the bulk of the attack came from supposedly impartial third parties, their message had more impact. People were swayed against saturated fats and the tropical oils they had been using safely for hundreds, or even thousands, of years.

Restaurants and food manufacturers, sensitive to customer fear, began removing these fats from their foods and replacing them with vegetable oils. Tropical oil consumption plummeted while soybean oil sales skyrocketed. In the United States, soybean oil soon accounted for about 80 percent of all the vegetable oil consumed.

During this time, one thing the soybean industry conveniently neglected to tell the public was that the saturated fats were not being replaced with ordinary vegetable oil, but rather by hydrogenated soybean oil! Hydrogenated soybean oil contains toxic trans fatty acids and is far more damaging to the heart than any other fat. Trans fats have also been linked to numerous other health problems including diabetes, cancer, and various autoimmune diseases. In terms of health, trans fat is absolutely the worst fat that you could consume.

The soy industry was aware of many of the detrimental effects associated with hydrogenated vegetable oils and trans fats, but they succeeded in demonizing all saturated fats, including healthy coconut and palm oils, for the sake of profit. The plan was an overwhelming financial success. Over the next two decades hydrogenated vegetable oils found their way into over 40 percent of all the foods on supermarket shelves, amounting to about 40,000 different products. Hydrogenated soybean oil consumption dramatically increased, and so did numerous diseases now found to be associated with trans fats.

With the growing awareness of the dangers of trans fats in hydrogenated vegetable oils and the landmark announcement in 2002 from the U.S. Institute of Medicine stating that “no level of trans fats is safe in the diet,” tropical oils are returning. Careful review of previous research and more current medical studies have exonerated the tropical oils from the claim that they promote heart disease. In fact, they appear to help protect against heart disease as well as many of the other diseases now known to be linked to hydrogenated vegetable oils.

Many restaurants and food manufacturers are now replacing their hydrogenated soybean oil with palm oil. Consequently, soybean oil sales are declining. In an effort to protect their profits, the soy industry has resorted to two strategies: 1) diversifying their market with new soy products like margarine, soymilk,“nutrition”bars, protein powders, pseudo-meats, livestock feed, biofuel, and more, and 2) returning to demonizing the competition in order to make their products more acceptable.

Desperate to find an alternative means of attack, the soybean industry has found a new ally in highly vocal, politically active environmental groups. Fueled by financial support and misleading data from the soy industry, some environmental groups have now waged a war against palm oil on the grounds that palm cultivation is destroying the environment. They claim that rainforests are being leveled to make room for palm plantations, destroying the ecology and bringing endangered species, such as the orangutan, to the brink of extinction.

Anyone with any sense of responsibility for the environment would be swayed by this argument. The problem, however, is that while palm oil plantations are responsible for some deforestation, the soybean industry is causing more destruction to the environment than probably any other agricultural industry on the planet. 

Soy and the Environment

In the time it takes to read this entire article, an area of Brazil’s Amazon rainforest larger than 200 football fields will have been destroyed, much of it for soybean cultivation.

Today, industrial-scale soybean producers are joining loggers and cattle ranchers in speeding up destruction and further fragmenting the great Brazilian wilderness. Between the years 2000 and 2005, Brazil lost more than 50,000 square miles of rainforest—a large portion of that for soybean farming.

Soybean production in the Brazilian Amazon soared after heat-tolerant varieties were introduced in 1997. In just ten years, exports of soybeans grown in the Amazon Basin have reached 42 million tons a year. Total annual soybean production in Brazil today is about 85 million tons, and Brazil will soon surpass the United States as the world’s leader in soybean production.

Brazil holds about 30 percent of the Earth’s remaining tropical rainforest. The Amazon Basin produces roughly 20 percent of the Earth’s oxygen, creates much of its own rainfall, and harbors hundreds of thousands of species, many yet to be discovered. The Brazilian rainforest is the world’s most biologically diverse habitat.

Close to 20 percent of the Amazon rainforest has already been cut down. At the current rate of clearing, scientists predict that 40 percent of the Amazon will be destroyed and a further 20 percent degraded within two decades. If that happens, the forest’s ecology will begin to unravel. Intact, the Amazon produces half its own rainfall through the moisture it releases into the atmosphere. Eliminate enough of that rain through clearing, and the remaining trees dry out and die, the fragile rainforest soils blow away, and the forest becomes a desert. Currently trees are being wantonly burned to create open land for soybean cultivation. Consequently, Brazil has become one of the world’s largest emitters of greenhouse gases.

The decimation of the Amazon is, for the most part, done legally. Even the governor of the state of Mato Gross, on the edge of the Amazon Basin, is a part of it. Governor Blairo Maggi is the world’s largest single soybean producer, growing 350,000 acres. That’s about 547 square miles of Amazon rainforest that have been leveled for soybean production! He is just one of many industrial-sized soybean operations in the area. In 2005, Greenpeace awarded Maggi the Golden Chain Saw award for his role in leveling the rainforest.

But, clearing and tilling the land for soybean production is only part of the problem. Soybean cultivation destroys habitat for wildlife including endangered or unknown species, and increases greenhouse gases which contribute to global warming. Soybeans need large amounts of acid-neutralizing lime, as well as synthetic fertilizers, pesticides, and herbicides, all of which are creating an environmental hazard. Toxic chemicals contaminate the forest, poison rivers, and destroy wildlife. And, in undeveloped countries, soy production disrupts the life of indigenous tribes who depend on the forest for food and shelter, replaces traditional crops, and transfers the value-added from processing from the local population to multinational corporations.

The environmental destruction caused by soybean farming isn’t limited to the Amazon; it occurs throughout the world wherever soybeans are produced. In the U.S. alone, over 80 million acres of land are covered in soybeans. That’s hundreds of thousands of acres of deforestation, habitat destruction, over-cultivation and destruction of soils, and billions of tons of toxic chemicals spewed into the environment year after year, contaminating our soils, water, and destroying wildlife and human health. And genetically modified soy was specifically developed to withstand the toxins so farmers could spray even more pesticides on them without diminishing yields. 

Over 80% of all soybeans grown in the U.S. (and two-thirds worldwide) are genetically-modified to withstand the herbicide glyphosate, which is usually sold under the trade name Roundup. Because so much Roundup is used on these crops, the residue levels in the harvested crops greatly exceed what until very recently was the allowable legal limit. For the technology to be commercially viable, the FDA had to triple the limit on residues of glyphosate that can remain on the crop. Many scientists have protested that permitting increased residues shows that corporate interests are given higher priority than public safety at the FDA, but the increased levels have remained in force. Glyphosate can now be easily detected in our water supply and in the bloodstreams of most Americans.
 
 Soybeans are arguably the most environmentally offensive agricultural crop in the world. 
 
 Replacing soybean oil with coconut, sunflower or olive oil is not only a healthier option, but each is a relatively low-impact crop that would save countless acres of land from untold environmental damage.

 Soybeans and Health
 Many people believe that soy is good for you—a superfood even. After all, Asians eat soy, and they are some of the healthiest people in the world, right? Claims that soybeans have been a major part of the Asian diet for more than 3,000 years are simply not true. 

In fact, the people of China, Japan, and other countries in Asia eat very little soy, and they typically only eat it after it has been fermented for long periods of time, which destroys the toxins inherent in it. The soy industry’s own figures show that soy consumption in China, Indonesia, Korea, Japan, and Taiwan ranges from 9.3 to 36 grams per day. That’s equivalent to a few, small blocks of tofu floating in a bowl of miso soup. Soy has never been considered a substitute for animal protein in Asia. 

In contrast, many Americans today think nothing of consuming a cup of tofu, a couple glasses of soy milk, handfuls of soy nuts, soy“energy bars,”and soy“veggie”burgers, even all in one day! Infants on soy formula receive the most of all, both in quantity and in proportion to body weight. Soy is also the key ingredient in faux-meat and dairy products with names like Silk, Soysage, Not Dogs, Fakin Bakin and Tofurkey. Then you have to consider the“hidden”soy in the form of vegetable oil, protein isolate, and soy lecithin found in over 70% of all packaged foods and just about everything you’d find in a fast food restaurant. It’s used as filler in hamburgers, as vegetable oil and as an emulsifier. It’s in salad dressing, macaroni and cheese, and chicken nuggets.

“Even if you read every label and avoid cardboard boxes, you are likely to find soy in your supplements and vitamins (look out for vitamin E derived from soy oil), in foods such as canned tuna, soups, sauces, breads, meats (injected under poultry skin), and chocolate, and in pet food and body-care products,”wrote Mary Vance for Terrain Magazine .“It hides in tofu dogs under aliases such as textured vegetable protein, hydrolyzed vegetable protein, and lecithin—which is troubling, since the processing required to hydrolyze soy protein into vegetable protein produces excitotoxins such as glutamate (think MSG) and aspartate (a component of aspartame), which cause brain-cell death.”
 
 In short, there is no historical precedent for eating the large amounts of soy now being consumed, and we are all participating in an experiment whose outcome is still unclear. 
 
Since we Americans eat so much of it, it’s important to understand how soy can affect us. What we do know about soy is a bit alarming:

 Soy contains very high levels of phytic acid, which reduces your body’s assimilation of calcium, magnesium, copper, iron and zinc. High phytate diets have caused growth problems in children. Two senior U.S. government scientists, Drs. Daniel Doerge and Daniel Sheehan, have revealed that chemicals in soy could increase the risk of brain damage in both men and women, and abnormalities in infants. Protease inhibitors in soy interfere with protein digestion and have caused malnutrition, poor growth, digestive distress, and pancreatitis. Lectins and saponins in soy can cause leaky gut and other gastrointestinal and immune problems. Scientists have known since the mid-1940s that soy phytoestrogens are powerful enough to affect fertility and even promote estrogen-positive breast cancer. Although scientists discovered only recently that soy lowers testosterone levels, soy phytoestrogens are known to disrupt endocrine function and are so potent, they are marketed to older women for relief of hot-flashes and other menopausal symptoms. 
 According to a British toxicologist’s calculations, a baby fed exclusively on soy formula would be consuming the estrogen equivalent of five birth-control pills a day. Thirty to 40% of babies in the United States are fed soy formula. If the hormones in soy are strong enough to relieve hot flashes, why would we feed it to children? Soy phytoestrogens are potent antithyroid agents that can cause hypothyroidism and may cause thyroid cancer. In infants, consumption of soy formula has been linked to autoimmune thyroid disease. Vitamin B-12 analogs in soy are not absorbed and actually increase the body’s requirement for B-12. Soy foods increase the body’s requirement for vitamin D. Processing of soy protein results in the formation of toxic lysinoalanine and highly carcinogenic nitrosamines. Free glutamic acid or MSG, a potent neurotoxin, is formed during soy food processing and additional amounts are added to many soy foods. Processed soy foods contain high levels of aluminum which is toxic to the nervous system and the kidneys and strongly implicated in Alzheimer’s disease. Archer Daniels Midland recently withdrew its application to the FDA for GRAS (Generally Recognized as Safe) status for soy isoflavones following an outpouring of protest from the scientific community. The FDA never approved GRAS status for soy protein isolate because of concern regarding the presence of toxins and carcinogens in processed soy. 

Soy Processing

Before soybeans get to your table, they undergo a rigorous process to strip them of their oil. Hexane or other volatile, petroleum-based solvents are first applied to help separate the oil from the beans, leaving trace amounts of these toxins in the commercial product. After the oil is extracted, the defatted flakes are used to form soy protein products. With the exception of full-fat soy flour, almost all soybean products contain trace amounts of carcinogenic solvents.

There’s nothing natural about today’s modern soy protein products; they are very much factory-made pseudo-foods. Textured soy protein, for example, is made by forcing defatted soy flour through a machine called an extruder under conditions of such extreme heat and pressure that the very structure of the soy protein is changed. Production differs little from the extrusion technology used to produce starch-based packing“peanuts,”fiber-based industrial products, and plastic toys.

The process of making soy protein isolate (SPI) begins with defatted soybean meal, which is mixed with a caustic alkaline solution to remove the fiber, then washed in an acid solution to precipitate out the protein. The protein curds are then dipped into another alkaline chemical solution and spray-dried at extremely high temperatures. SPI is then often spun into protein fibers using technology borrowed from the textile industry. These refining processes improve taste and digestibility, but destroy the vitamin, mineral, and protein quality, and increase levels of carcinogens such as nitrosamines. Soy protein isolate appears in so many products that consumers would never guess that the Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology (FASEB) decreed in 1979 that the only safe use for SPIs was for sealers for cardboard packages. 

Soy and Allergies

Many people don’t know that soy is one of the top eight allergens that cause immediate hypersensitivity reactions such as coughing, sneezing, runny nose, hives, diarrhea, difficulty swallowing, and anaphylactic shock. Delayed allergic responses are even more common and occur anywhere from several hours to several days after the food is eaten. These have been linked to sleep disturbances, bedwetting, sinus and ear infections, crankiness, joint pain, chronic fatigue, gastrointestinal woes, and other mysterious symptoms. Although severe reactions to soy are rare compared to reactions to peanuts, tree nuts, fish, and shellfish, soy has been underestimated as a cause of food anaphylaxis.

Soy allergies are on the rise for three reasons: the growing use of soy infant formula, the increase in soy-containing foods in grocery stores, and the possibility of the greater allergenicity of genetically modified soybeans.

According to Monsanto’s own tests, compared to normal soybeans, Roundup Ready genetically-engineered soybeans contain 29 percent less of the brain nutrient choline, and 27 percent more trypsin inhibitor—the potential allergen that interferes with protein digestion. Soy products are often prescribed and consumed for their phytoestrogen content, but according to the company’s tests, the genetically altered soybeans have lower levels of phenylalanine, an essential amino acid that affects levels of phytoestrogens. And levels of lectins, which are most likely the culprit in soy allergies, are nearly double in the genetically-engineered variety.

Soy and Hormones

Humans and animals appear to be the most vulnerable to the effects of soy estrogens prenatally, during infancy and puberty, during pregnancy and lactation, and during the hormonal shifts of menopause. Of all these groups, infants on soy formula are at the highest risk because of their small size and developmental phase, and because formula is their main source of nutrition.

In the years since soy formula has been in the marketplace, parents and pediatricians have reported growing numbers of boys whose physical maturation is either delayed or does not occur at all. Breasts, underdeveloped gonads, undescended testicles (cryptorchidism), and steroid insufficiencies are increasingly common. Sperm counts are also falling. Because of the estrogens in soy, men and boys, in particular, should eat little to no soy. 

Soy formula is bad news for girls as well. With increased estrogens in the environment and the diet, an alarming number of girls are entering puberty much earlier than normal. One percent of girls now show signs of puberty, such as breast development or pubic hair, before the age of three. By the age of eight, 14.7 percent of Caucasian girls and 48.3 percent of African American girls had one or both of these characteristics. The fact that blacks experience earlier puberty than whites is not a racial difference but a recent phenomenon.

Most experts blame this epidemic of“precocious puberty”on environmental estrogens from plastics, pesticides, commercial meats, etc., but some pediatric endocrinologists believe that soy is a significant contributor. Of all the estrogens found in the environment, soy is the likeliest explanation of why African American girls are reaching puberty so early. Since its establishment in 1974, the federal government’s Women, Infants and Children (WIC) program has provided free infant formula to teenage and other low-income mothers while failing to encourage breastfeeding. Because of perceived or real lactose intolerance, black babies are much more likely to receive soy formula than white babies.

Most of the fears concerning soy formula have focused on estrogens. There are other problems as well, notably much higher levels of aluminum, fluoride, and manganese than are found in either breastmilk or dairy formulas. These metals are byproducts of soy processing and all three have the potential to adversely affect brain development. Although trace amounts of manganese are vital to the development of the brain, toxic levels accrued from ingestion of soy formula during infancy have been found in children suffering from attention-deficit disorders, dyslexia, and other learning problems.

Yet the belief persists that soy hormones are“safe”because they are“weak”and“natural.”Although the soy industry has claimed that soy estrogens are anywhere from 10,000 to 1,000,000 times weaker than the human estrogen estradiol, the correct figure is only 1,200 times as weak. Though this still sounds quite weak, it is not—because of the quantity of these estrogens ingested by infants on soy formula, and by children and adults who eat soy every day. 

 Americans consume far more soy phytoestrogens (called isoflavones) than were ever part of a traditional diet in Asia. The average isoflavone intake in China is 3 milligrams, or 0.05 mg per kilogram of body weight. In Japan, the figures range from 10 to 28 mg, or 0.17 to 0.47 mg isoflavones per kg of body weight. In contrast, infants receiving soy formula average 38 mg of isoflavones, which comes to a shocking 6.25 mg/kg of body weight!

The Right Soy

It is not true that if a little soy is good, a lot must be better. For soy, the dose makes the poison. The Chinese learned hundreds of years ago that the only way to safely eat soy is to ferment it, which removes the phytates and reduces the trypsin inhibitors. (Unlike other beans, soaking, and even cooking, will not do this.) So, if you choose to eat soy foods, you will find the most benefit from eating small quantities of organically-grown, whole-food, fermented soy, like real soy sauce, miso, tempeh, tofu, or natto , the way Asian people have safely enjoyed soy for millennia.

The bottom line is when it comes to soy, we are all participating in what Daniel M. Sheehan, former senior toxicologist with the FDA’s National Center for Toxicological Research, has called a“large, uncontrolled and basically unmonitored human experiment.”And soy cultivation—particularly genetically engineered soy—is one of the most devastating things we can do to the environment.

 For more information about soy: 

 The Whole Soy Story: The Dark Side of America’s Favorite Health Food Soy: The Dark Side of America’s Favorite“Health”Food A Word About Soy Genetically Modified Soy and Food Allergies The Hazards of Feeding Soy to Children Warnings on danger of soy formula milk; Edinburgh study highlights Component in Soy Products Causes Reproductive Problems in Laboratory Mice Deforestation in the Amazon Soybean Cultivation as a Threat to the Environment in Brazil The Soy Juggernaut–Deforestation and Land Grabs in Brazil 

 This post is part of Fight Back Fridays hosted by Food Renegade! 
 email print 
Tagged as: food safety , global warming , industrial food 
 
 { 25 comments…read them below or add one } 
 Katie (www.livingcrunchy.com) March 16, 2012 at 10:34 am 
EXCELLENT article. I became intolerant to soy after having my first child, and it was such a blessing in disguise, because I then learned how dangerous it was. I realized that soy is in almost ALL packaged, processed food, and soybean oil almost all salad dressings. I am no longer intolerant of soy, but stay away from it except for organic soy sauce. I just posted an article about how to easily make your own salad dressings to avoid soy. http://www.livingcrunchy.com/2012/03/make-your-own-salad-dressing/ 

 Reply 
 Tawney February 13, 2012 at 1:19 pm 
Wow! This will take a while to absorb because of all the information. I did know about the estrogen levels in soy. I warned my daughter about it so she could avoid giving it to my grandsons. I also stopped drinking soy milk. I was using it because I am lactose intolerant. I didn’t realize all of the hidden sources though! Do you have a particular article you could recommend out of those listed that has the names of soy when used in products? I would like to avoid these things in the future. I still have 2 boys at home!
When my kids were younger I was on WIC and they did recommend breast-feeding. They still do here! Its nice to know one place you think you should be able to trust, is trust worthy to a point. They even give out $ every summer to purchace things at the farmer’s market.
Thank you for taking the time and effort to research and write this article! It is greatly appreciated!

 Reply 
 Anonymous February 13, 2012 at 2:01 pm 
Thanks so much for commenting! I’m glad you got a lot out of the article. The big ones to look for are“lecithin”and“protein isolate”which are almost always made from soy. Of course, the best way to avoid soy is to avoid packaged foods altogether, but that isn’t always possible for everyone.

Welcome to Small Footprint Family and best on your Real Food journey!

 Reply 
 Jennifer February 1, 2012 at 6:39 am 
Really interesting stuff! I’ve long been weary of soy. We try to eat very little of it, my son is allergic anyway, and only eat organic when we do eat it. We’ve found some really great miso and soy products from South River Miso company made from chick peas. How cool!

Thanks again for this great post! I’ve shared it on my FB page.

 Reply 
 Anonymous February 2, 2012 at 5:55 pm 
YW! Sharing is caring, so thank you!

 Reply 
 ahmad zahedi November 30, 2010 at 3:26 am 
Thank you for your reply.

It would be appreciated if you infrom me what are the tosted soy meal antiquality parameters that harmful for human consumption while the white flake dont have it?

As mater of fact in toasting time which poisens being produced that make hazard for human in consumption.

Thank you again for your attention.
Best Reagrds.

 Reply 
 Dawn Gifford November 30, 2010 at 9:28 am 
Sir, if you have not figured this out from reading other parts of my blog, I do not advocate the consumption of industrially processed foods of any kind. Based on my research for this article, I think industrially processed soy–especially in the quantity that Americans eat it–is both horrible for the environment and toxic to humans. The article is very clear with numerous references as to why I and many other experts believe this.

Toasting does not remove the phytates, protease inhibitors, pesticides, estrogens and other toxins present in soy during processing, and it certainly does not have any effect on the devastation that growing soybeans places on the ecosystem.

If you want to consume soy in moderation, it is safest to consume it as a WHOLE FOOD, ideally naturally fermented or simply processed, like miso or natto.

Best,

Dawn @ Small Footprint Family

 Reply 
 Finchop32 January 25, 2012 at 4:05 am 
Hi very interesting article. Do you have any references for your claims? i am not disputing them as i think they may probably be true but would like to do further reading on the subject. Would organic soy beans be ok do you think.? if made with the whole soy bean in a traditional way and not soy isolate? It has definately turned me off processed foods as soy lecithin seems to be in everything these days! Thank you for the information. Fin

 Reply 
 Anonymous January 25, 2012 at 9:26 am 
There is a complete list of the 10 sources I used for this article at the end. Fermented, organic soy grown in the U.S. is the only soy I would even consider eating. Since it is very difficult to get traditionally fermented, organic soy in the U.S., mostly, I just avoid it like the plague.

 Reply 
 Finchop32 January 25, 2012 at 2:00 pm 
Hi Thank for your reply! I am in Australia and there is a wonderful company called Spiral Foods which is ethical and they source a soy milk called Bonsoy made in traditional way in Japan with whole organic soy beans.
Over here we are more concerned with Palm Oil Production as they are cutting down thousands of acres  Indonesian Rainforest every year for Palm Oil Production and the Indonesian Orangatans have become endangered. Palm Oil should also be avoided like the plague.
But i was not aware of the toxins in soy which book mentions that in particular?….I have had some hormonal issues since i introduced soy a few years ago when my youngest became intolerant/allergic to dairy and i was breastfeeding. I cut dairy and felt immediate improvement in my health….I guess as adults we do not need to drink any milk products. My Holistic Doctor who also practising TCM ( Traditional Chinese Medicine) told me to give my son rice milk instead as that is more in line with TCM. But i worry about water use as rice uses so much water!!! Its very hard to eat totally ethically these days but you gotta try.
Thanks Fin


 ahmad zahedi November 29, 2010 at 7:26 am 
thank for your artichle.

Kindly please inform me that to production textured soy protein which raw materials is better (is more safe),tosted defatted soy meal(from DTDC) or defatted soy white flake(From Flash Desolventizer)?
Regards.

 Reply 
 Dawn Gifford November 29, 2010 at 9:18 am 
Processed soy from either source is not fit for human consumption. Thanks for writing.

 Reply 
 Candice Burden October 28, 2010 at 3:39 am 
Hello Dawn

While I don’t mean to imply I disagree with your article on soy, I would like to see your references for it. It would be good to take a look at the studies conducted around soy if you could point me to them!

Kind regards

Candice

 Reply 
 Dawn Gifford October 28, 2010 at 8:24 am 
Um, Candice, there are links to 10 references at the end of the article, as well as a few within the article too.

Also, Dr. Kaayla Daniels (who was recently on Dr. Oz talking about the problems with soy) and her book The Whole Soy Story are invaluable resources, packed with primary source references to the clinical studies most mainstream readers do not have access to.

 Reply 
 Rachelle June 29, 2010 at 4:33 pm 
Thank you for this interesting article!

I hate soy. I hate it because I am severely allergic to it and thanks to subsidization it is in EVERYTHING in North America.
Nowadays it is extremely difficult to find anything pre-made that does not contain some form of soy either obvious or hidden.

Unfortunately the general public are only made aware of the obvious sources of soy and unless you suffer from an allergy are usually oblivious to the long list of hidden sources that are added to almost every product on regular supermarket shelves.

What’s worse is that there is now pressure from the lobbyists to deem soy oil and soy lecithin as‘safe’for soy allergic people to eat so manufacturers won’t be required to list the allergy alert on labels. This is because of results from one very small study out of Europe. A lot of medical sites and doctors will even say soy oil is not a problem because the refining process removes the proteins.

However, just spend one minute on an allergy sufferers forum and you will soon see just how many of us become seriously ill from soy oil and soy lecithin. I become violently ill if I consume soy oil. It is actually one of the soy products that makes me the sickest.

I wouldn’t have such a hatred of soy if it was easier to avoid. It is simply greed and laziness in our food production in the 21st century that is causes this problem of overuse. I see so many products on a daily basis that I should be able to eat and yet can’t because soy was added unnecessarily!

In restaurants instead of making sauces from scratch or using fresh ingredients chefs choose to take the easy way out and contaminate meals with soy-impregnated flavorings. Arghhh!

On the positive side my allergy does force me to eat healthy, real, whole foods. Foods that contain single ingredients. In my opinion if a child can’t read the label then we really shouldn’t be eating it!

Cheers,
Rachelle

 Reply 
 Elly Jemison December 8, 2009 at 2:01 pm 
Hi, I’m not so sure about the prison video–I think they were making a bit of a meal out of it(pardon the pun).
I have been a vegetarian for 20 years, most of my life–In that time I have 2 pregnancies, and breastfed 2 babies–My eldest son is high in Testosterone levels, so I’m not quite sure about alot of these claims, who is backing the scientific research (the government?) as they seem to want to belittle any‘Milk replacement’(recently they were belittling rice milk) yet they push cows milk all the time.
Cows milk must also be full of Oestrogen, as they pump dairy cows so full of hormones, that thier lifes are cut short by 4 times the length it should be. It is also not natural for us to drink any other milk, other than our own–yet our modern diet is based around milk products, how are yoy supposed to cook without an alternative?

 Reply 
 Dawn Gifford December 8, 2009 at 2:43 pm 
Thanks for your comment, Elly!

While phytoestrogens like genestein have been shown to have benefits to human health, they have also been implicated in many studies done by universities, government and industry in causing all sorts of hormonal effects. The soybean industry thinks this is a positive thing, and soy is aggressively marketed as“natural”hormone replacement therapy for menopausal women. Others point to possible negative effects from tampering with hormones, and urge caution, because many people are very sensitive to estrogens, and could develop cancers and other problems if they consume too much.

I agree with you about conventional cow’s milk, which, pumped full of genetically engineered hormones and pasteurized, is also implicated in a host of health problems. I wouldn’t eat conventional dairy products if you paid me. But conventional milk is not touted as a superfood, nor is it consumed in the quantities that soy is. Dairy is also a much smaller industry than soy. As a result of heavy subsidization with everyone’s tax dollars, soy byproducts can be found in nearly everything on grocery shelves these days, and Americans are consuming these hormone-altering foods at unprecedented rates.

While not everyone has issues with soy, like yourself, I have known many people who suffered health problems that went away with the elimination of soy from their diet. My mother, a two-time breast cancer survivor, has been instructed by her oncologist to avoid soy like the plague, including as a skin cream additive. I myself am intolerant to soy hormones, and my daughter is very allergic to soy. We are also allergic to almonds and dairy. Therefore, in our house, we use a lot of both coconut and hemp milk, which, with an abundance of fatty acids, calcium and added B12, are significantly more nutritious than soy, almond, rice or conventional, pasteurized cow’s milk.

 Reply 
 Greenearth November 22, 2009 at 12:17 pm 
Really enjoyed your article. I have recovered from three separate estrogen positive breast cancers and my doctor has told me to stay away from all soy products.

 Reply 
 Stanley Fishman November 20, 2009 at 6:26 pm 
Great post!

Thank you for spreading the truth about soy.

I agree that the best replacement for soy oil is animal fats from grassfed animals, which are so healthy. Unrefined coconut oil is also an excellant substitute. I use olive oil, one of our oldest foods, where animal fat will not work, such as in salad dressing.

The only way we can counter the propaganda of the soy industry is to spread the truth, over and over again.

Thank you so much for doing so.

Stanley Fishman
Author of Tender Grassfed Meat

 Reply 
 Dana November 20, 2009 at 3:24 pm 
“The problem, however, is that while palm oil plantations are responsible for some deforestation, the soybean industry is causing more destruction to the environment than probably any other agricultural industry on the planet.”

The reason why is a no-brainer when you think about it. Where does palm oil come from? Trees. By definition you have to grow trees to have a palm plantation. Where does soy come from? Annual plants, requiring full sun. You MUST cut down all the trees in the area of the field to grow soy.

Now, I do distinguish between“group of trees”and“forest,”unlike some people (Rush Limbaugh famously pooh-poohed the loss of old-growth forest in the U.S. by claiming we have more trees now than when Columbus landed in Haiti), but still, it’s better to have a group of trees in rows on a plantation than no trees at all.

I do wonder why people skirt around the issue of saturated fats from animal sources even as they admit the tropical oils are healthy. We may not always be able to obtain tropical oils in temperate climates in the future, what with the price of fuel steadily rising (and if you believe the Peak Oil alarmists this becomes even more of an urgent issue), so we need to get over the idea that butter, lard, and tallow will kill us when in fact they greatly improve our health and quality of life. They will be the saturated fat sources we can most easily access if we lose access to palm and coconut.

 Reply 
 Dawn Gifford November 20, 2009 at 3:42 pm 
Thanks for your comment, Dana!

I agree completely with you on all accounts: palm trees, peak oil and animal fats.

I am a big fan of animal fats, and use them liberally in my home. I have also posted on making your own butter , and on the myth that saturated fats are bad for you . However, there are times when I need an oil rather than a fat that is solid at room temperature. Butter, for example, is a little tough to make salad dressing with. For that sunflower, olive or even sesame oil make better choices.

 Reply 
 Bethany November 20, 2009 at 1:17 pm 
Dawn,

Thank you for this excellent summary! I really appreciate the work you put into assembling such a great array of information and resources for further research. The soy craze has bugged me for years now, and the more I learn about the motives behind the growth of the industry and the cost in health to the general public so easily swayed by advertising, the more confident I am in my distaste and distrust. Thank you for illuminating the need to return to natural foods/oils that we’ve been using for centuries…

Cheers,
Bethany

 Reply 
 deb November 20, 2009 at 12:31 pm 
Great article–thanks for helping open eyes and hearts on the dangers of this‘miracle’food. It’s really sad to me how many people are eating it in almost every food they consume!

 Reply 
 Kimberly Hartke November 20, 2009 at 3:39 am 
Thanks for warning people about the dangers of modern soy foods. Here are some videos about a hair raising soy feeding“experiment”going on in Illinois prisons. Buyer Beware!

 http://hartkeisonline.com/2009/11/13/prison-soy-press-conference-videos/ 

 Reply 
 Dawn Gifford November 20, 2009 at 11:58 am 
Thanks, Kimberly. I was hoping someone would mention the Illinois prison lawsuit.

-Dawn

 Reply 
 Cancel reply 
Leave a Comment
 
 Name * 

 E-mail * 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments by email. 

 Notify me of new posts by email. 
 
 { 5 trackbacks } 
 
 Tweets that mention Soy is Not a Health Food -- Topsy.com uberVU - social comments Soy is Not a Health Food«Plan It Healthier November Links«All Things Health Soy is Not a Health Food«Criterion Living 
 
Previous post: It’s Easy Eating Greens 

Next post: May We Give Thanks… 
 
 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 To a great extent, every dollar we spend is a vote for how we want the world to be.
Consider the sponsored ads on this site a ballot for health and sustainability. 
KUDOS FOR SFF
 

 Small Footprint Family Green Living Community
	</body>
</document>
