<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000784" url="http://www.orangecounty.net/html/museums.html" time="2012-07-12-16:07" support="2" score="0.0038545990319189573" bingtitle="Orange County&apos;s Museums" webtitle="Orange County Museums">
			<query id="001424" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="001430" bing-rank="4"/>
	<description>Orange County, California guide to local Museums ... the youngest child, this museum offers touch tables, a science station, changing ...</description>
	<body>
		Orange 
 County Museums 
 Museums 
 of Art&amp;Antiquities Historical 
 Homes Museums 
 for Children Natural 
 History Museums Special 
 Interest Museums Near 
 Orange County 
 
   

 

 Museums 
 of Art&amp;Antiquities 
 

 
 
 
 The 
 Bowers Museum of Cultural Art and Bowers Kidseum 
2002 N. Main Street
Santa Ana, CA 92706
(714) 567-3600 

 The Bowers is accredited by the American Association 
 of Museums, an honor only 5% of museums receive. 
 
 
 
 
 
 Heritage 
 Museum of Orange County 
 3101 
 West Harvard Street
Santa Ana, CA
(714) 540-0404 

 The 
 historic plaza features several buildings from 
 the 1890s set among extensive gardens and citrus 
 groves. Among these is the Kellogg House, where 
 it is open to the public on limited days. 
 
 
 
 
 
 Laguna 
 Art Museum 
307 Cliff Drive
Laguna Beach, CA 92651
(949) 494-8971 

 The 
 Museum focuses on the cultural heritage of California, 
 and on the unique history and accomplishments 
 of Laguna Beach .
 
 
 
 
 
 Mission 
 San Juan Capistrano 
Ortega Hwy and El Camino Real
San Juan Capistrano
 

 Mission San Juan Capistrano, the Birthplace of 
 Orange County, was founded more than two hundred 
 years ago. Today it is a monument to California&apos; 
 multi-cultural history, embracing its Native American, 
 Spanish, Mexican and European heritage. 
 
 
 
 
 
 The 
 Muzeo Museum 
(Formerly the Anaheim Museum)
241 S. Anaheim Blvd.
Anaheim, California 92805
(714) 778-3301 

 The 
 MUZEO hosts three traveling exhibitions per year 
 which would otherwise not be displayed in the 
 region. 
 
 
 
 
 
 Orange 
 County Center for Contemporary Art 
117 North Sycamore
Santa Ana, CA 92701
714.667.1517 

 The 
 Orange County Center for Contemporary Art (OCCCA) 
 is artist operated and dedicated to the pursuit 
 of professional excellence and freedom of expression 
 in the arts. 
 
 
 
 
 
 Richard 
 Nixon Library&amp;Birthplace 
8001 Yorba Linda Blvd.
Yorba Linda, CA 92886
(714) 993-5075 

 A 
 privately supported institution which is dedicated 
 to educating the public about the life and times 
 of the 37th President and encouraging interest 
 in history, government and public affairs. 

 The 
 nine acre Library&amp;Birthplace features a 52,000 
 square foot museum, 22 high-tech galleries, movie 
 and interactive video theaters, the First Lady&apos;s 
 Garden, the President&apos;s faithfully restored 1910&apos;s 
 birthplace, and the flower-ringed memorial sites 
 of President and Mrs. Nixon. 
 
 
 
 
 
 Susanna 
 Bixby Bryant Ranch House and Museum 
 5700 Susanna Bryant Drive
Yorba Linda, CA
714-694-0235 

 Yorba Linda Heritage Museum where visitors can 
 glimpse some of Yorba Linda&apos;s unique heritage. 
 Each room depicts a different period or aspect 
 of the area&apos;s history, from Indian times to the 
 first settlement by the Yorba family, and into 
 the modern age. Opened to the public on limited 
 days. 
 
 
 
 
 
 The 
 Dr. Willella Howe-Waffle House and Medical Museum 
 120 Civic Center Drive
Santa Ana 
714 547-9645 

 

 The Dr. Howe-Waffle House was built in 1889 
 by Dr. Alvin Howe and his wife, Dr. Willella Howe. 
 The House is listed on the National Register of 
 Historic Places, as a California Historic Point 
 of Interest, and as a landmark building on the 
 City of Santa Ana&apos;s Historic Register. Tours are 
 given by the Santa Ana Historical Society. 
 
 
 

 back 
 to top 

 

 Historical 
 Homes 
 

 
 
 
 Casa 
 Romantica 
415 Avenida Granada
San Clemente, CA 92672
(949) 498-2139 

 Casa 
 Romantica Cultural Center and Gardens, the historic 
 Spanish Colonial Revival estate of San Clemente 
 founder Ole Hanson, embodies the Romance and Reality 
 of the Southern California experience. 
 
 
 
 
 
 Kellogg 
 House 
 3101 
 West Harvard Street
Santa Ana, CA
(714) 540-0404 

 The 
 Kellogg House was designed by Hiram Clay Kellogg 
 and was built in 1898. The house is now used for 
 hands-on education about the Victorian era for 
 more than 18,000 children each year. Open to the 
 public on limited days. 
 
 
 
 
 
 Richard 
 Nixon Birthplace 
8001 Yorba Linda Blvd.
Yorba Linda, CA 92886
(714) 993-5075 

 On 
 January 9, 1913, Richard Nixon was born in this 
 little Yorba Linda Farmhouse. The Birthplace has 
 been restored with attention to historical detail, 
 on the exact spot where President Nixon&apos;s father 
 built it. 
 
 
 

 back 
 to top 

 

 Museums 
 for Children 


 
 
 
 The 
 Bowers Museum of Cultural Art and Bowers Kidseum 
2002 North Main Street
Santa Ana, CA
(714) 567-3600 

 One 
 of Southern California&apos;s finest museums and Orange 
 County&apos;s largest, the Bowers Museum home to Bowers 
 Kidseum, an 11,000 square foot children&apos;s museum, 
 provides arts and cultural activities for thousands 
 of children and their families. Creativity, stimulated 
 by exposure to art, can be the basis for the development 
 of ideas, problem solving and social understanding.
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Children&apos;s 
 Museum of La Habra 
Portola Park
301 S. Euclid in La Habra
562-905-9693 

 A 
 hands-on environment that opens the world to even 
 the youngest child, this museum offers touch tables, 
 a science station, changing exhibits and much 
 more. 
 
 
 
 
 
 Discovery 
 Science Center 
 2500 Main St.,
Santa Ana, CA 92705.
714/542-CUBE 

 Lie 
 on a Bed of Nails, play Virtual Volleyball and 
 explore Dino Quest at Discovery Science Center 
 in Orange County! More than 100 interactive exhibits 
 and annual events such as Spooky Science and BubbleFest 
 spark childrens natural curiosity! 
 
 
 
 
 
 Heritage 
 Museum of Orange County 
3101 West Harvard Street
Santa Ana, CA
(714) 540-0404 

 The 1898 Kellogg House is the focal point of the 
 Heritage Museum. Inside you will find unique architectural 
 features, antique furnishings, historic photos 
 and maps, and hands-on activities for children. 
 The tour is primarily self-guided, but a docent 
 is always available during public hours to answer 
 questions and provide additional insights into 
 the house, the Kellogg family, and life in historic 
 Orange County. On the same grounds, visitors can 
 find nature trails, a working blacksmith shop 
 and the Maag House, ranch house of citrus and 
 nut grower John Anton Maag and his family. 
 
 
 
 
 
 Pretend City Children&apos;s Museum 
 Located in Irvine 
 

 This interconnected city allows children to &quot;pretend&quot; 
 to be the adults. Children can experience a variety 
 of features every city has to offer. With over 
 15,000 sq. feet of interactive exhibits and activities, 
 Pretend City brings to life every profession, 
 necessity and daily occurrences of a real city. 
 They can do anything and everything from grocery 
 shopping to banking to visiting the doctor to 
 collecting their pay from the local ATM as well 
 as visit the fire station, police station, the 
 caf and all of the many other exhibits. 
 
 
 

 back 
 to top 

 

 Natural 
 History Museums 

 
 
 
 Tucker 
 Wildlife Sanctuary 
 29322 
 Modjeska Canyon Rd.
Silverado, CA 92676
(714) 649-2760 

 Tucker 
 is best known for its wide variety of native and 
 migrating birds, especially hummingbirds. However, 
 its facilities also include a nature science center, 
 two ponds, a bird observation porch and feeders, 
 relaxing patio and picnic areas, a small amphitheater, 
 walking trails, a gift shop, restrooms and an 
 ample visitor parking lot. 
 
 
 

 back 
 to top 

 

 Special 
 Interest Museums 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 

 ExplorOcean/Newport 
 Harbor Nautical Museum 
600 East Bay Avenue
Newport Beach, CA 92661
(949) 673-7863 

 Explore 
 our region&apos;s maritime heritage with family-oriented 
 interactive exhibits, ship models, artifacts and 
 art, located in the heart of the historic Balboa 
 Fun Zone on Newport Bay. In addition to our touch-tank, 
 visitors will enjoy a mix of hands-on activities, 
 interactive programs, and special performances 
 that will connect you to the living museum in 
 our backyard. Our galleries include: The Steele 
 Model Pavilion, the East Wing (Sea of Adventure), 
 Newport and the Extraordinary People galleries. 
 Our goal is to connect visitors to the adventure, 
 inspiration and mystery of the sea with an emphasis 
 on the human experience and mans impact as it 
 relates to the marine environment. 
 
 
 
 
 
 International 
 Surfing Museum 
411 Olive Ave.
Huntington Beach, CA 92648
(714) 960-3483 

 View 
 the Evolution of the Surfboard, surf music, memorabilia 
 and a section devoted to the first Endless Summer 
 movie that includes Bruce Brown&apos;s original camera. 
 
 
 
 
 
 Marconi 
 Automotive Museum 
1302 Industrial Dr.
Tustin, CA 92780
(714) 258-3001 

 30 
 million-dollar collection of historical, exotic, 
 and classic cars. This collection includes Super 
 Bikes, Open Wheel Racing Cars (both Formula 1 
 and Indy), American Muscle Cars, Vintage Racing, 
 High Performance Exotics and more. 
 
 
 
 
 
 Ocean 
 Institute 
Dana Point Harbor Drive
Dana Point
 Phone: 
 949-496-2274 

 The Ocean Institute has become nationally known 
 for its hands-on marine science, environmental 
 education and maritime history programs. On weekends, 
 the public is invited to visit and discover ocean 
 science, history, and literature 
 
 
 

 back 
 to top 

 

 Museums 
 Near Orange County 

 
 
 
 Rancho 
 Los Alamitos 
 6400 
 Bixby Hill Road
Long Beach, California 90815
(562) 431-3541 

 Twice 
 listed on the National Register of Historic Placesonce 
 as the sacred Tongva village of Povuungna, the 
 traditional birthplace of the native people of 
 the Los Angeles Basin, and for its significant 
 historic landscape over time. The site includes 
 traces of the ancestral village, an adobe-core 
 ranch house ca. 1800, four acres of lush historic 
 gardens developed during the 1920s and 30s, and 
 the restored working ranch barnyard of the early-mid 
 20th century. With the long anticipated opening 
 of the Rancho Center, a new exhibition features 
 the Rancho, the people and place over time, within 
 the region and state. 
 
 
 

 back 
 to top 

 

 OrangeCounty.net 
 - Premier listings for all of Orange County Featuring 
 a list of Orange County Museums 

 
 
     
 
 
 

 Home - Orange County Visitor Information - Fun 
 things to do in OC - OC Beaches, Surf&amp;Sand - Art&amp;Music in Orange County - Shopping&amp;Dining in Orange County 

 OC 
 Business - Orange County Health Inforrmation - Orange 
 County Rescources for Residents - OC Education - Orange County Real Estate - Site 
 Map - Disclaimer 

©2011 OrangeCounty.net.
Site Owned and Operated by Purpose Media 
For info on ad rates call 949.443.1323 or sales@orangecounty.net 
Photographic images courtesy of OCBook.com
	</body>
</document>
