<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000417" url="http://www.mainstreet.com/article/career/employment/10-best-jobs-teens" time="2012-07-12-15:40" support="1" score="8.79833911637749e-05" bingtitle="The 10 Best Jobs for Teens - MainStreet" webtitle="The 10 Best Jobs for Teens - MainStreet">
			<query id="000586" bing-rank="245"/>
	<description>10 Ways to Save on Everyday Purchases; 10 Things You Should Never Put on Your Credit Card; 8 Classic Books That Still Aren’t e-Books; 5 Products You Shouldn’t Buy Online</description>
	<body>
		TheStreet Network: TheStreet | StockPickr | BankingMyWay | RealMoney 
Subscribe to our FREE Newsletter
 
 Home 10 simple ways to avoid college debt smart
spending Budgeting   |   Bargains/Deals   |   Technology   |   Autos money /
investing Savings   |   Credit/Debt   |   Stocks&amp;Funds   |   Bonds   |   Taxes   |   Insurance   |   Education Planning   |   News family Kids   |   Marriage/Divorce   |   Family Health career Employment   |   Students/Gen Y   |   Work/Life Balance retirement 401K   |   IRA   |   Long-Term Care real
estate Buying   |   Selling   |   Renting   |   Refinancing   |   Extreme Real Estate   |   Improvements   |   Foreclosure small
business Launching   |   Financing   |   Marketing   |   Women&amp;Small Business lifestyle Food&amp;Drink   |   Luxury   |   Travel tax
center 10 simple ways to avoid college debt 
 Hot Topics   |  wheels  |  unemployment  |  taxes  |  politics  |  managing debt  |  careers  |  More Topics» Posted April 23, 2009 
 
 
The 10 Best Jobs for Teens
 By MainStreet.com Staff Writers Pin It 
When you’re a teenager, getting your first job can be exciting and rewarding. You finally get a chance to make your own money and you can even pick up a valuable skill. Most importantly, part-time jobs teach how to budget , save and manage money . Here’s a list of 10 of the best jobs for teenagers:

 1. Babysitting 
Babysitting is a big responsibility suited for mature teenagers. One way to prove yourself as a qualified babysitter is to take classes that help to train you for childcare. The Red Cross offers babysitter’s training courses that focus on infant and older child care, problem solving skills, emergency care for injuries, illnesses and accidents and overall safety. These classes are designed for teens age 11 to 15 and vary in cost and availability, so check your local Red Cross for details.
 
Related Articles
 
 7 Work-From-Home Jobs You Might Not Know About 7 Red Flags That a Job Posting Isn’t Right for You The Coolest New Job Openings This Week (March 25) Career Q&amp;A: How Long Do I Need to Be in a Job Before I Can Apply Elsewhere? 5 Tips for Finding Work When You&apos;re Over 50 
 
 2. Pet Sitting or Dog Walking 
For teenagers who love animals, dog sitting or walking can be great options. You will likely find yourself working in early morning and evening hours, which can also make this job a great option for those attending summer school.

 3. Retail 
Retail jobs like those at The Gap (Stock Quote: GPS ) or J.Crew (Stock Quote: JCG ) are highly coveted by many teens. However, these positions can be hard to come by in some cities where many adults are competing for the same positions. Check web sites like SnagAJob.com for openings in your area. Keep in mind that many retail stores require previous work experience. Depending on the store and state law, the minimum age for employees may be 16 or 18.

 4. Food Service 
Food service jobs at restaurants are nice options for teenagers because you can make quick money. (Hello, instant gratification!) Be sure to keep track of tips for tax purposes, though!

 5. Camp Counselor 
Many camp counselor positions are available through schools, churches and sporting organizations. These positions are ideal for teens looking to work only during summer vacation. And if you like kids, it&apos;s one of the most fun jobs out there.

 
 1 2 
 Next» Pin It Read More:  gen y , job hunting , summer jobs 
 Add Comment 
 comments powered by Disqus. blog comments powered by Disqus 
Sponsored Links
 
 MOST VIEWED MOST COMMENTED 
 
 10 Things You Should Always Buy Used 10 Ways to Save on Everyday Purchases 8 Classic Books That Still Aren’t e-Books 10 Things You Should Never Put on Your Credit Card 5 Products You Shouldn’t Buy Online 
 
 Contact us Terms of Use Privacy Policy Advertise With Us Sitemap Masthead Archive Newsletter 

 
 
Get your FREE report from 

Don&apos;t miss the secrets behind...

 Dating Out of Your Salary Range 16 Infamous Tax Cheats Green Jobs that Pay Big Bucks 

... and much more!
 First Name: 
 Last Name: 
 Email: 
 OK Cancel
	</body>
</document>
