<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000257" url="http://www.healthline.com/health-blogs/diet-diva/sodium-sensitive" time="2012-07-12-15:27" support="1" score="0.0014246099864581017" bingtitle="Sodium Sensitive? | Healthline - Medical Information for Healthy ..." webtitle="Sodium Sensitive? | Healthline">
			<query id="000025" bing-rank="226"/>
	<description>Processed foods, soup, condiments like catsup, pickles, olives, etc., deli meats, smoked meats, salty snacks, fast food, restaurant food, sauces</description>
	<body>
		Health Topics 
 Acid Reflux Alcohol Addiction Allergies Alzheimer&apos;s&amp;Dementia Anxiety Asthma Bipolar Disorder Chronic Pain Cold&amp;Flu 

 COPD Crohn&apos;s Disease Depression Fibromyalgia Heart Disease Hypertension Insomnia&amp;Sleep Disorders Menopause Nicotine Addiction 

 Obesity Osteoarthritis Psoriasis Pregnancy Rheumatoid Arthritis Skin Care STDs Type 2 Diabetes More... Health Tools 
 Symptom Search Body Maps Treatment Search 

 Drug Search Drug Interactions Pill Identifier 

 Drug Compare Doctor Search Recipe Search 
 
Healthline Blogs
 
 Healthline → Healthline Blogs → Diet Diva → Sodium Sensitive? 
 RSS Feed Diet Diva 
Get advice on healthy eating, nutrition, and weight loss from expert dietitian Tara Gidus. 
 See all posts » 
Sodium Sensitive?


 By Tara Gidus , MS, RD, CSSD, LD/N | Published Jun 19, 2007 TEXT SIZE: A A A 


 



 
 I got a question from a devoted Diet Dish reader about sodium. What is the deal with sodium? Do we really need to watch it? Are certain people more sodium sensitive than others?

A high diet high in sodium has been linked mostly to high blood pressure. It has also been weakly linked to stomach and esophageal cancers and osteoporosis. High blood pressure leads to kidney disease and stroke , so you may have heard it associated with those diseases as well. Diabetes can also lead to impaired kidney function, so diabetics are advised to watch their sodium intake. You become more sodium sensitive as you age, so elderly people are advised to restrict salt.

We actually do need some sodium in our diet, and it is thought that amount is about 500 mg, which is not much when you compare that to the average American who eats between 3,300 and 4,000 mg or more per day. Sodium is necessary for nerve impulses, to help absorb nutrients, and for fluid balance. However, too much sodium can cause the cells to retain too much fluid which increases blood volume and therefore results in high blood pressure.

The big debate in the medical community with sodium is that research suggests that only about 1/3 of the population is sodium sensitive to the point where it is going to make a clinically significant difference in your blood pressure. In addition, no accurate test exists to knowing whether someone is sodium sensitive or not.

If you feel bloated after eating sushi dipped in a lot of soy sauce (or any other high sodium meal), you may be sodium sensitive. Other clues: thirsty, swelling in ankles, feet, legs or hands, increased blood pressure, and feeling sluggish.

 Another interesting note: Your palate really does become adjusted to the amount of sodium that you eat. When people do go on a low sodium diet and then eat something high in sodium they feel like an entire bottle of salt was poured into that cup of soup. If you are adding salt to your food now, you may find that you need to add more and more as time goes on to get the same taste. Best to not add salt at all (of course!) so you don’t adjust to that high level. You will just keep needing more and more as you age.

 How much? 
If you have high blood pressure, kidney disease, heart disease, pulmonary disease, or diabetes, try to keep your diet to less than 1,500 mg of sodium. Everyone else is advised to stay below 2,300 mg.

 Where is it? 
Processed foods, soup, condiments like catsup, pickles, olives, etc., deli meats, smoked meats, salty snacks, fast food, restaurant food, sauces

 Label reading 
 The best way to know how much sodium you are getting is to read labels. It is hard for me to give you a black and white number of how much is too much because it depends on the food. These words on packages might help:

Sodium Free: Contains less than 5 mg per serving
Very Low Sodium: Contains less than 35 mg per serving
Low Sodium: Contains less than 140 mg per serving Light in Sodium: Contains 50% less than a comparable product
Reduced in Sodium: Contains 25% less than reference product 
 Photo courtesy of maverickapollo Email Tara Gidus
 | Follow Tara Gidus on Advertisement 
About the Author
 
 Tara Gidus 
MS, RD, CSSD, LD/N
 
Tara Gidus is a nationally recognized expert and spokesperson on nutrition and fitness. Read more » 
 
Recent Blog Posts

 Jul 11, 2012 
 Superfood of the Week: Peaches Jul 09, 2012 
 Diet Goes Downhill As Day Goes On Jul 06, 2012 
 Where is Your Money Spent at the Grocery Store? 
 
 
Site Map
 Health Topics Drugs A-Z Health Experts&amp;Blogs Full Site Map 

 
About Healthline
 Our Staff About Healthline.com Advertising&amp;Sponsorship Policy About Healthline Networks 

 
Get in Touch
 Contact Careers Advertise With Us Help 

 
Stay Connected
 My Account Facebook 

 
Legal Information
 Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 Copyright©2005 - 2012 Healthline Networks, Inc. All rights reserved.
 Healthline is for informational purposes and should not be considered medical advice, diagnosis or treatment recommendations. more details
	</body>
</document>
