<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000740" url="http://search.janes.com/public/help/search/SearchTips.htm" time="2012-07-12-16:05" support="1" score="0.01138018840543382" bingtitle="Jane&apos;s Search Tips" webtitle="Jane&apos;s Search Tips">
			<query id="001450" bing-rank="127"/>
	<description>... beginning, middle, or end of a word. Their purpose is to allow you to search for ... For example, if the search expression &lt;NEAR/5&gt; is ... sorted in ascending date order ...</description>
	<body>
		Close Window 

 Search tips Quick search 
 Quick search results 
 Search within results 
 Advanced search 
 Advanced search results 
 Refine search page 
 Image search 
 Data Browse Quick search To perform a search type in one or more keywords and click on the search

 button for a list of relevant documents.
This will return results from all of the Jane&apos;s datasets.

For best results, it&apos;s important to choose your keywords wisely. If you&apos;re

 looking for information on Patriot missiles, enter Patriot rather than missiles .

Searching is not case-sensitive, and keywords can be entered in upper,

 lower or mixed case.

 &quot;AND&quot;Searches :
Separate multiple words with spaces to match all of the words.

 frigate submarine torpedo = frigate&lt;AND&gt;submarine&lt;AND&gt;torpedo 

 &quot;OR&quot;Searches :
To match any one or more of the search terms, use the&lt;OR&gt;operator in-between your keywords, for example:

 Rocket&lt;OR&gt;Missile 

Phrase Searching:
Phrase searching is achieved by entering two or more keywords surrounded

 by double-quotes. Only exact matches where the keywords appear adjacent

 in a document will be returned.

An example is as follows:

 &quot;mortar bomb&quot; 

 See &apos;Advanced Search Help&apos; section for more

 information on all operators. Quick Search Results 
 Search Within Results Link: 
This loads the‘Search Within Results&apos; page, and allows you to search

 across just the results from your original query.

 Advanced Search Link: 
Clicking this link will load the Advanced Search Screen. See

 &apos;Advanced Search Help&apos; 

 New Search Button: 
Entering a new keyword into the field, and clicking the &apos;New Search&apos; button

 will perform a new search across the Jane&apos;s data.

 Sort Score Link: 
Clicking this link will re-sort your results by score, in ascending or

 descending order.

 Sort Product Link: 
Clicking this link will re-sort your results alphabetically by publication,

 in ascending or descending order.

 Sort Date Link: 
Clicking this link will re-sort your results by date, in ascending or

 descending order.

 Product Acronym: 
Clicking on this link will load a pop-up window, with a brief description

 of that Jane&apos;s product. For example JPSE&gt;Jane’s Police&amp;Security Equipment.

 

 Paging - Result Page (numbered list) :
This allows you to navigate to any page within your results, or simply

 advance one page at a time. The‘Prev’and‘Next’buttons allow you to navigate back and forth through your results.

 
 Search Within Results 
This allows you to search through the results of your original query,

 just type in one or more words and click the‘Search within Results’button for a list of relevant documents containing both your original

 query, and your new keyword(s).

 See also‘Quick Search Help’ 


 Advanced Search Link: 
Clicking this link will load the Advanced Search page. See‘Advanced Search Help’ 

 
 Advanced Search 

 Stemming: 
The stemming functionality returns documents containing terms that match the root of your term,

 and stemmed variations. For example:
 Destroy &gt;Destroyed, Destroying, Destroys

It&apos;s important to note that not all stemmed variations are matched.

 From the example above, the term Destroyer is not matched.

To return results with no stemming, surround your term(s) with double-quotes.
 Wildcards: 
The Wildcard characters are the question mark (to replace a single character)

 and the asterisk (to replace any number of characters), and can be used at the

 beginning, middle, or end of a word. Their purpose is to allow you to search for

 all possible variations of a keyword. For example:

 Ma?ia &gt;Mafia, Maria

 hydro* &gt;Hydromechanical, Hydrophones, Hydrographic

 *jet &gt;Learjet, Alpha Jet, Water-Jet, Altajet

 defen*e &gt;Defensive, Defensible

 Boolean Operators: 
The Boolean&lt;AND&gt;,&lt;OR&gt;, and&lt;NOT&gt;operators are available

 for use, and are more powerful than using keywords alone.

The&lt;AND&gt;operator is used to return documents that contain all

 of your keywords. An example of use is as follows:

 destroyer&lt;AND&gt;frigate&lt;AND&gt;phalanx 

The&lt;OR&gt;operator is used to return documents that contain any

 of your keywords. An example of use is as follows:

 destroyer&lt;OR&gt;frigate 

The&lt;NOT&gt;operator is used to return documents that do not include

 a keyword. An example of use is as follows:

 submarine&lt;NOT&gt;nuclear 

In addition, the Jane’s search functionality supports use of the

 plus and minus characters as alternatives to the&lt;AND&gt;and&lt;NOT&gt;operators, respectively.

An example of their use is as follows:

 destroyer +frigate
submarine -nuclear 

Note that a space is required between the operator and

 the preceeding term.

 

 Proximity Operators: 
The&lt;NEAR&gt;operator is

 used to return documents where the keywords are in close proximity to

 one another. It is more likely that a document will be of greater value

 to you when your keywords appear close together in a document.

The&lt;NEAR&gt;operator will match documents where your keywords appear

 within 1024 words of each other. An example of use is as follows:

 typhoon&lt;NEAR&gt;RAF 

It is good practice to surround all operators with angle brackets as

 shown, as only the AND, OR and NOT operators

 can be used without angle brackets.

The&lt;NEAR&gt;operator can be configured to operate with a user-defined

 range as follows:

&lt;NEAR/N&gt;

This selects documents containing two or more words within N number of

 words of each other, where N is an integer.

Document scores are calculated based on the relative distance of the

 specified words when they are separated by N words or less.

For example, if the search expression&lt;NEAR/5&gt;is used to find two

 words within five words of each other, a document that has the specified

 words within three words of each other is scored higher than a document

 that has the specified words within five words of each other.

The N variable can be an integer between 1 and 1,024, where&lt;NEAR/1&gt;searches for two words that are next to each other.
If N is 1,000 or above, you must specify its value without commas, as

 in&lt;NEAR/1000&gt;.

You can specify multiple search terms using multiple instances of&lt;NEAR/N&gt;,

 as long as the value of N is the same.

For example, to retrieve relevance-ranked documents that contain stemmed

 variations of the words lightweight, fighter, prototype, and programme

 within 10 words of each other, enter the following:
 
lightweight&lt;NEAR/10&gt;fighter&lt;NEAR/10&gt;prototype&lt;NEAR/10&gt;programme 


 Phrase Searching: 
Phrase searching is achieved by entering two or more keywords surrounded

 by double-quotes. Only exact matches where the keywords appear adjacent

 in a document will be returned.

An example is as follows:

 &quot;mortar bomb&quot; 

 Search Precendence: 
Your search queries will be read from left to right, but certain operators

 take precedence over others.

For example, the query below is interpreted to mean: Look for documents

 that contain Hornet , or look for documents that contain Prowler and Nimitz .

 Hornet&lt;OR&gt;Prowler&lt;AND&gt;Nimitz 

To change the operator precedence, use parentheses as shown below.

 (Hornet&lt;OR&gt;Prowler)&lt;AND&gt;Nimitz 

This expression will now look for documents that contain either Hornet and Nimitz , or Prowler and Nimitz 
 Date Range: 
The date range search field allows you to search for documents with a

 post date between your chosen start and end dates. It’s important

 to note that this is the date the document was made available for release

 to our electronic services, and is not the hard copy publication date.

The format for entering dates is DD-MMM-YYYY - (29-AUG-1976), or you

 can use the calendar buttons to select your dates.

 Document Title: 
This field allows you to search across only document titles. If a search

 term is present in a document title, that document is more likely to be

 relevant to your needs. If you know it, you can also search using a full

 or part document title, to quickly return just the document you want to

 view.

 Country: 
Use the country field, to only return documents related to a specific

 country. Magazine titles do not support the country field, as the magazine

 content is often not country specific.

 # of Results per page: 
Allows you to return 10, 20 or 50 results per page.

 Company: 
The company field allows you to narrow your search, by only returning

 documents that refer to that specific company. Not all titles make use

 of the company field.

 Score: 
The default selection, returns documents ranked according to the search

 term accuracy within the document. The higher the score, the more relevant

 the document.

 Date (descending): 
Returns documents sorted in descending date order, listing the most recent

 documents first.

 Date (ascending): 
Returns documents sorted in ascending date order, listing the oldest documents
 
 first.

 Product (descending): 
Returns documents sorted alphabetically in descending publication order,

 Z-A.

 Product (ascending): 
Returns documents sorted alphabetically in ascending publication order

 A-Z.

 Dataset Selection: 
You are given several options for selecting which Jane&apos;s titles you would

 like to search (e.g. Fighting Ships, Defence Weekly). By default, Janes.com

 will search all of the available titles (datasets).

The following options allow you to alter the selection of titles to search:


  Select the specific datasets that you want

 to search from the list box below.

 
  Datasets you have subscribed to: ( Control + Click to select or de-select multiple datasets) 
Windows users may select or de-select from either box in any combination

 by using the Control (CTRL) key and c licking your

 mouse.
Apple Mac users can select or de-select from either box in any combination

 by holding down the shift key and clicking your mouse.


 Advanced Search Results 
 Refine Search Button: 
Clicking this button will take you to the Advanced Search page, with the

 relevant fields now populated by your original query. From here you can

 adjust any parameter to refine your original search. See also‘Advanced Search Help’ 
 
 New Advanced Search Button: 
This will load a fresh Advanced Search page, for you to perform a different

 search.

 New Quick Search Button: 
This will load a fresh Quick Search page, for you to perform a different search.

 Resort by Score arrow: 
Clicking this link will re-sort your results by score, in ascending or

 descending order.

 Resort by Product arrow: 
Clicking this link will re-sort your results alphabetically by publication,

 in ascending or descending order.

 Resort by Date arrow :
Clicking this link will re-sort your results by date, in ascending or

 descending order.


 Product Acronym: 
Clicking on this link will load a pop-up window, with a brief description

 of that Jane’s product. For example IDR&gt;International Defence Review

 

 Paging - Result Page (numbered list): 
This allows you to navigate to any page within your results, or simply

 advance one page at a time. The‘Prev’and‘Next’buttons allow you to navigate back and forth through your results. 
 Refine Search Page 
This is the Advanced Search page, with the relevant fields now populated

 by your original query. From here you can adjust any parameter to refine

 your original search. See also‘Advanced

 Search Help’ .

 
 Image Search 
 The Image Search feature allows you to perform a keyword search across the captions that accompany all images on Janes.com. Search results are returned in the form of image thumbnails, and their captions. Subscribers can then click on a link

to see the full image, and the associated publication entry.

 You can sort the search results by score, product or date.

 
 Data Browse Navigation: 

The complete Jane’s content is organized into various groups of

 related material. Browse uses what is known as category drill-down to

 allow you to intuitively navigate through your chosen publications.

When you have drilled down to the final category, only documents are

 displayed.

As you drill down you will notice that what is known as the‘crumb

 trail’, will update at the top of the page to reflect the publication

 and level that you have reached.

For example, if you choose to drill down within the‘Systems and

 Equipment’category, and then the‘Section’category

 within Fighting Ships, the crumb trail will display as shown below.

 

Should you then wish to drill down into a different title within the‘Systems and Equipment’category for example, without clicking

 on the‘Back’button on your browser, you can simply click

 on the link to&quot;Systems and Equipment&quot;within the crumb trail.
 Search Within Browse: 
In addition to drilling all the way down to a document, it’s also

 possible to perform keyword searching at each category level.

There are 5 levels in the browse structure.

 
Level 1: The list of datasets (Countries, Images, Markets, News/Analysis,

 Operational Guides, Organizations, Systems and Equipment)


 
Level 2: The list of publications within each dataset


 
Level 3: The categories that make up each publication (Company, Country,

 Date, Section)


 
Level 4: The list of companies, countries, dates, and sections


 
Level 5: The list of records that match each company, country, date,

 and section.



It is possible to perform keyword searching using the search functionality,

 across:

A single dataset at level 1

Single, or multiple publications at level 2

Single or multiple categories at level 3 and 4

Just the list of records in that category at level 5


Being able to drill down into a publication, and then perform keyword

 searches at that level, gives you more control over what you are searching

 when compared with keyword searching using the main search page.

For example using the main search page to search across a specific publication

 section would require you to know the name of that section. Using the

 browse functionality you can visually select your chosen category, and

 search across it.
	</body>
</document>
