<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000461" url="http://www.lazylightning.org/in-n-out-burger-hastings-mn" time="2012-07-12-15:43" support="4" score="0.009355788411116691" bingtitle="In-N-Out Burger: Hastings, MN | Bill Roehl" webtitle="In-N-Out Burger: Hastings, MN | Bill Roehl">
			<query id="000623" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="000560" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="001293" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000969" bing-rank="186"/>
	<description>We were told we could order anything we wanted and ... While we didn’t have to pay for our items as part ... sight of what it is at the end of the day: a fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		In-N-Out Burger: Hastings, MN 

 April 1st, 2012 in Hastings , Restaurants , Reviews , South Metro 
 


 
 In and Out Burger Double 2011 Summer Vacation California Las Vegas July 24, 201126 originally uploaded by Steven Depolo 

A few weeks back I was asked to attend a preview event for a new restaurant chain coming to Minnesota. The information from the PR firm was thin but I signed up to attend the event anyway and I headed over on Friday evening to see who was coming to Minnesota who may be worth visiting.

I have to admit that after receiving similar invitations for both Old Chicago and T.G.I. Friday’s I was a little skeptical that this would be worth my time. When I arrived and smelled burgers cooking I was even more skeptical. Minnesota has been inundated with burger joints lately and with so many other local and chain restaurants serving pretty decent burgers as of late, I really didn’t see why they were making such a big deal out this new chain. Until they revealed the name: In-N-Out Burger .

 Check the date on this post and cautiously continue with that in mind . 

Now, I admit to being no fan of In-N-Out burgers. To me they’re no better than Wendy’s. However, I know that there are plenty of people who absolutely adore this chain and will be lining up for months to get a taste of what they used to have to fly to the West Coast to get a taste.

The restaurant was filled with employees, a few bloggers toting cameras, and some city officials. We were told we could order anything we wanted and we were asked to give our honest feedback about the product and whether we’d had the burgers before.

I ordered a double-double with everything: lettuce, tomato, spread, and onions; an order of fries; and a vanilla shake. The Wife ordered a cheese burger without onions, fries, and a strawberry shake. While we didn’t have to pay for our items as part of this promotional event, from what we were told the prices will be competitive with Five Guys and the various other similar chains serving burgers around town.
The review:




The burgers, again, didn’t impress me much. Even though I hadn’t tried a Nookie Supreme in 2006 when I had my first In-N-Out, time and experience did nothing to improve these for me. That said there were lots of smiles around the room–much in the same way that people believe the burgers at Lion’s Tap in Eden Prairie, because they heard they were great, not because they actually are.

The fries, which never impress me regardless of venue, were fine. Nothing special there but I do appreciate that they make them fresh and in-house–just like any other restaurant worth its salt does.

The shake was ok. I love shakes and have them very rarely and while this was tasty, it wasn’t enough to make me want to drive to Hastings on any regular basis to get them–especially when I’d have to fight the droves of the clueless to do so.

In addition to not caring for the burgers themselves, I really didn’t understand the decision to open the first Minnesota In-N-Out location in Hastings of all places. I feel this would be much better suited somewhere more centrally located such as Minneapolis or St. Paul but the staff on hand assured everyone in attendance that their market research showed Hastings would be an exceptional location for them to begin. At this time they have no plans for other Minnesota locations but they said it is definitely not outside the realm of possibility within the next 2-4 years.

Overall I was unimpressed with the burgers, the location and especially the hype they’re planning around the opening of In-N-Out’s first Minnesota location. I am sure it will be wildly popular and get the traffic they claim but it’s not because it’s really worth it but instead because people want to think it’s a great burger, not because it really is.

Have you ever eaten at In-N-Out before? If so what did you think and what did you order? How do you think it compares to other burger joints both chain and local? Are you planning to be there, waiting in a day-long+ line (their prediction) as soon as it opens next week? Whatever you have to say about this one go ahead and comment on as I’d love to hear your thoughts.

 Address :
In-N-Out
15912 153rd St NW
Hastings, MN 55033

 Hours :
Monday to Sunday: 10:30 AM–1:30 AM
 21 


Related posts:

 The Burger Place: Minneapolis, MN Burger Time: Apple Valley, MN Burger Jones: Burnsville, MN Kirby Vacuum Cleaners: Hastings, MN Liquor Enforcement Entrapment in Hastings? 
 
 Trackback URI | Comments RSS 
 
26 Responses to“In-N-Out Burger: Hastings, MN”

 #
 1 Dan N (153 comments) Says:
 April 1st, 2012 at
 7:21 am 
I’m a fan of In-N-Out but I don’t lose sight of what it is at the end of the day: a fast food restaurant. Much like the extreme hype there was when Sonic first arrived a few years ago, I won’t be running to an INO anytime soon. I’ll wait for the hype to die down and then maybe I’ll swing by but I’m not in any rush to go there. Hastings is quite a drive from where I live now and no fast food is special enough for me to need to drop everything and drive 30+ minutes for.

Are they open now Bill?

 2   0 
 #
 2 Ozzie (57 comments) Says:
 April 1st, 2012 at
 8:02 am 
Happy April Fools Day to you too, Bill!
 
 11   1 
 #
 3 Marty (141 comments) Says:
 April 1st, 2012 at
 8:05 am 
Bill, neither Google earth or Mapquest can find that address. It sounds to me like that should be at about the corner of 160th and General Seiben Drive, using the county numbering system. Am I close? There is a lot of traffic now on 160th and it will only grow.

 1   0 
 #
 4 Dan N (153 comments) Says:
 April 1st, 2012 at
 8:17 am 
Lol, I got got.

 2   0 
 #
 5 SuziMN (124 comments) Says:
 April 1st, 2012 at
 10:02 am 
Man. I totally fell for this. I suck.

 3   0 
 #
 6 Sank (531 comments) Says:
 April 1st, 2012 at
 10:24 am 
There’s no way In-N-Out would put a place here, the state is starting to impose no trans fats laws and carbon taxes for meat producers. I wish though, man do I wish.

 3   0 
 #
 7 lefty (1645 comments) Says:
 April 1st, 2012 at
 11:54 am 
Ozzie, delete your post.

 2   3 
 #
 8 mulch (400 comments) Says:
 April 1st, 2012 at
 1:40 pm 
Kudos Bill…and i thought the Wicked Palate Food Truck was our April Fools day serving given early, that is until I saw the article in the weekly newspaper. LMAO….. da noive.

 4   0 
 #
 9 bb stacker (751 comments) Says:
 April 1st, 2012 at
 1:54 pm 
bill 1, lazy ltg readers, 0

bb
 

 3   1 
 #
 10 Brian Moen (56 comments) Says:
 April 1st, 2012 at
 9:03 pm 
That was pretty good.

 1   0 
 #
 11 Tearitup (365 comments) Says:
 April 1st, 2012 at
 9:17 pm 
It’ll be right next door to the Dunkin Donuts right?

 1   0 
 #
 12 Towngie (94 comments) Says:
 April 2nd, 2012 at
 8:48 am 
I just emailed this to Amanda. I think she was wetting her pants she was so excited. Then I read the comments. :(

When I told her, she IMed me back and said,“I’m gonna kill u.”If that happens, I will blame it on you and this post. Considered yourself warned.

 1   0 
 #
 13 Jill T (70 comments) Says:
 April 2nd, 2012 at
 12:47 pm 
Cruel.

 1   0 
 #
 14 Carrie @ Season It Already! (9 comments) Says:
 April 3rd, 2012 at
 7:00 am 
I didn’t even know there was an In-N-Out Burger in the whole state! I’d say that this will be a great surprise for my husband, except that I know he reads this blog. ;-)

 0   0 
 #
 15 Bill (6411 comments) Says:
 April 3rd, 2012 at
 7:07 am 
And that it’s an April Fools joke ;-)
 #
 16 Carrie @ Season It Already! (9 comments) Says:
 April 3rd, 2012 at
 10:51 am 
Damn. You got me! ;-)

 0   0 
 #
 17 Alex C. (1 comments) Says:
 April 3rd, 2012 at
 12:21 pm 
CRAPPPPPPPPPPP…You had me going! I was SOOO excited! I am from California and crave In-N-Out burgers ALL THE TIME!
Oh well! Good joke!

 0   0 
 #
 18 Tracy (61 comments) Says:
 April 3rd, 2012 at
 8:16 pm 
Well, thank heavens Lakeville will pick up the slack by potentially adding the finest hamburger establishment in the country! I know I was hoping for a McDonalds within walking distance…Especially since there are none for at least 2 miles in every direction…

 0   0 
 #
 19 Bill (6411 comments) Says:
 April 3rd, 2012 at
 9:09 pm 
The proximity to the others is what’s confusing to me. I mean I guess it made more sense when there was thoughts that housing would actually be going up in that area and there would be traffic on that road but seriously, it’s a decade or more away at this point.

Really and seriously, just drive to Farmington or AV and be done with it. Ridiculous.
 #
 20 Nils (277 comments) Says:
 April 4th, 2012 at
 8:55 am 
This is why I read posts from April 1st, on April 4th.

 2   0 
 #
 21 Denise SC (1 comments) Says:
 April 5th, 2012 at
 1:25 pm 
Oh, man, that sucked! I was super excited (despite the scathing review). But I was had!

 0   0 
 #
 22 Home Improvement Poll | Bill Roehl Says:
 April 8th, 2012 at
 7:02 am 
[...] we skipped last week’s poll due to my annual April Fools Day post, the week before I asked if you were looking forward to more summer or more winter. While a few [...]

 0   0 
 #
 23 Greg (429 comments) Says:
 April 17th, 2012 at
 8:05 pm 
Lakeville City Council approved the new McDonald’s in Lakeville. Dino’s building to be razed in favor of a new McDonald’s at Dodd&amp;Cedar.

 0   1 
 #
 24 Nurd52 (221 comments) Says:
 April 18th, 2012 at
 9:29 am 
Yes I know this post was an April Fools day joke, but I’m currently on vacation in Arizona and actually went to an In-N-Out place for dinner one night. It was without a doubt one of the most disgusting meals I’ve ever had. It made White Castle look like an upgrade!

 0   3 
 #
 25 Dave (230 comments) Says:
 April 21st, 2012 at
 3:45 pm 
@Greg–That sucks. I like Dino’s. Not the best“Greek”food around town, but it’s close and a crap load better than anything you can get at McDonald’s. There is so much vacant land around that intersection, including properties that are easier to get in and out of and have better visibility. Why McDonald’s would buy an existing restaurant and tear it down just doesn’t make sense to me. A zoning thing maybe?

I’m sure Dino’s isn’t doing well at that location, I can’t imagine anything in that cluster@#$% mall is, but still sucks to see them go.

 0   0 
 #
 26 Greg (429 comments) Says:
 April 22nd, 2012 at
 8:17 am 
The story is that Mickey D’s wanted to build in that spot back in 2003 when they were developing that area, but for some reason didn’t. Obviously they’ve decided it’s still a good spot, and are now pulling the trigger.

I agree, there are other spots open that would be easier, but I would guess that form their point of view, it’s an ideal spot because all they have to do it build a new kit building, and don’t have to develop parking, curbing, entrances, etc. All of that is already in place.

 0   0 
 

Leave a Reply
 
 Name
 (required) 

 Mail (a valid e-mail address is required and may be verified) 

 Website 

 

 

 

 Notify me of followup comments via e-mail 
 
Subscribe without commenting
 E-Mail: 
 
Additional comments powered by BackType 
 ← City Manager Lays Himself Off?! Book Club: 2012Q2 Book Club–The Kill Artist → 
 
 
Subscribe
                
Subscribe via E-mail
 
 Your email: 
 

   
 
Categories

 Bars and Pubs (207) Books (66) Day Trips (17) Food (125) Geocaching (101) GIS (13) Metro (275)
 Minneapolis (143)
 Skyways (11) 
 St Paul (133) 
 Police Calls (275) Polls (208) Restaurants (480)
 Closed (45) Reviews (244) 
 South Metro (1270)
 Apple Valley (459) Burnsville (473) Eagan (247) Farmington (133) Hastings (57) Lakeville (217) Rosemount (146) Savage (106) 
 Swimming (28) Uncategorized (76) Vacations (94) Website Updates (80) Wedding (11) 
 
Random
 * Commenter Leaderboard 
* Restaurant Review Map 
* Lazy Lightning Book Club 
Recent Comments
 
 Farmington Bans Public Comment on Agenda Items  ( 4 ) 
 Chapter&amp;Verse : Bill,... Bill : C&amp;V, All... Chapter&amp;Verse : ... Chris Johnston : I’m a... 
 
 Can a Grocery Store Keep You in Town Poll  ( 6 ) 
 Tim : Yeah, it is not about... MSPD : I’m not sure... Greg : Sorry, but I... 
 
 Mother“Sleeps Through”Alleged Abuse of Daughter  ( 4 ) 
 Chad : I think in a case... Kassie : This is normal... sui generis : We... dsw : I wonder if the mom is... 
 
 Ze’s Diner: Eagan, MN  ( 22 ) 
 sui generis : Ate here with... 
 
 Blue Ox Sandwich Factory: Burnsville, MN  ( 24 ) 
 The Ox : MSPD…than ks... MSPD : Bill reminded me that... 
 
 Cheeky Monkey: St. Paul, MN  ( 2 ) 
 lefty : I miss Zander Cafe. Kassie : I like Cheeky... 
 
 Pita Plus Sandwich Grill: Burnsville, MN  ( 23 ) 
 Chad : I tried Ramadan the... Bill : JD, yeah, they are.... Jeremy D. : I am thinking I... 
 
 MyBurger, D. Brian’s Lash Out Against Food Trucks  ( 22 ) 
 lefty : It is too bad that... Chapter&amp;Verse : ... whit o&apos; wit : Sandy,... sandy : lefty, Girbaud... Sank : One more point- No... 
 
 Byblos Lebanese Grill: Burnsville, MN  ( 41 ) 
 Jeremy D. : I think there is... 
 
 Mrs. Renfro’s Ghost Pepper Salsa  ( 58 ) 
 Jeremy D. : This salsa was... Bill : You’re trolling... Neil Ray : Also if you... 
 
 Lazy Lightning Book Club: 2012Q3 Selection Voting  ( 7 ) 
 Tearitup : The book that was... 
 
 Union Member and Be Against Union Activities?  ( 31 ) 
 JasonS : I’m in a... 
 

 
South Metro Crime Info
   Dakota Complaints Map 
   Dakota Criminal Complaints 
   Dakota Inmate Dashboard 
   Level 3 Sex Offenders 
   Scott Inmate Dashboard 
Polls
 
 

 Does All of Your Spending Revolve Around Groceries? 
 
 Yes No I don&apos;t have any money 

 

 View Results 
  Loading ... 
 Polls Archive 
 
Recent Photos
 
Archives
 Select Month July 2012 (11) June 2012 (25) May 2012 (26) April 2012 (26) March 2012 (25) February 2012 (25) January 2012 (27) December 2011 (27) November 2011 (27) October 2011 (25) September 2011 (26) August 2011 (27) July 2011 (29) June 2011 (26) May 2011 (27) April 2011 (24) March 2011 (27) February 2011 (26) January 2011 (26) December 2010 (27) November 2010 (28) October 2010 (31) September 2010 (28) August 2010 (32) July 2010 (29) June 2010 (31) May 2010 (35) April 2010 (43) March 2010 (48) February 2010 (36) January 2010 (53) December 2009 (46) November 2009 (36) October 2009 (36) September 2009 (33) August 2009 (36) July 2009 (40) June 2009 (42) May 2009 (44) April 2009 (42) March 2009 (35) February 2009 (29) January 2009 (34) December 2008 (40) November 2008 (37) October 2008 (38) September 2008 (32) August 2008 (35) July 2008 (34) June 2008 (37) May 2008 (33) April 2008 (38) March 2008 (23) February 2008 (22) January 2008 (19) December 2007 (7) November 2007 (8) October 2007 (20) September 2007 (13) August 2007 (2) July 2007 (8) June 2007 (9) May 2007 (10) April 2007 (30) March 2007 (28) February 2007 (19) January 2007 (12) December 2006 (11) November 2006 (17) October 2006 (8) September 2006 (13) August 2006 (18) July 2006 (12) June 2006 (20) May 2006 (12) April 2006 (21) March 2006 (12) February 2006 (13) January 2006 (28) December 2005 (18) November 2005 (17) October 2005 (12) September 2005 (25) August 2005 (9) July 2005 (22) June 2005 (12) May 2005 (20) 
Contact
 About 
 E-mail Bill 
Phone: 651-317-9668 (Voicemail) 
Meta

 Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.org 
 
 
 
 
 All copyrights on this page are owned by their respective owners.
Comments are owned by the Poster. The Rest©2005-2012.
	</body>
</document>
