<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000824" url="http://billingsgazette.com/news/local/article_03d5ecdf-7f69-50cf-8a72-f37e5db1a724.html" time="2012-07-12-16:11" support="1" score="0.0016545054837917782" bingtitle="Empty stockings: Readers can help those in need" webtitle="Empty stockings: Readers can help those in need">
			<query id="001231" bing-rank="179"/>
	<description>She could use a roll of quarters and/or a container of ... earnings from a part-time job at a Billings fast-food restaurant. ... She could also use a colorful throw for sitting in ...</description>
	<body>
		Digital Subscriptions Advertise More 
 Subscriber Services Contact Us About Us Mobile Apps 
 
 
 Join the conversation Log In Register Subscribe 

 Contribute 
 Article Event Photo Video 
 My Account 
 Edit Profile Logout 
 
 65° Partly Cloudy 
 Weekly Forecast 
 Friday 102° 68° Saturday 96° 67° Sunday 90° 64° Monday 92° 60° 
 
 sponsored by Advanced Search | Privacy | About Our Ads 
 News 
 News Web 
 
 Search Web Search powered by YAHOO! SEARCH 
 Home News 
 
Topics

 Local Montana Wyoming Nation World Business Crime Weird Notices Today in History Elections 
 
Latest around the region
 
 Montana wildlife commission to vote on wolf hunt 

HELENA — Montana wildlife commissioners are set to take a final vote on proposed rule changes to the state&apos;s wolf hunt so that it more closely…
 
 Mostly sunny, hot Thursday in store for Billings region 

As has been the case for the last few days, Thursday is likely to be another hot and sunny one.
 
Recent

 Dry conditions, beetle-killed trees raise danger on 1,200-acre Bitterroot fire UM seminar aids resource-protection managers from developing world Federal judge explains decision to block Seeley-Swan timber sale Lieutenant governors honor long Montana-Kumamoto relationship Naumann to be awarded Rankin Peace Prize 
 
 Sports 
 
Topics

 GazPrepSports Cat-Griz College Mustangs Legion Rodeo Youth Local Professional 
 
The Latest
 
 Strong start from Guillon helps Mustangs take down Orem 

At face value, it was a run-of-the-mill matchup between rookies during the Mustangs’ 6-3 victory over Orem on Wednesday at Dehler Park.
 
 Bozeman wins big over Royals 

BOZEMAN -- Isaac Thompson had four hits, Ean Weaver and Sam Olson had three each, and the Bozeman Bucks defeated the Billings Royals 16-3 on W…
 
Recent

 Scarlets sweep Roughriders UW center named to Rimington Trophy watch list Rocky women&apos;s BB signs transfers Rocky to add 3 to HOF Aragon runs personal best in 800 meters in Spain; misses berth in finals 
 
 Opinion 
 Gazette Opinion Guest Opinion Columnists Letters to the Editor Submit a Letter City Lights 
 Entertainment 
 
Topics

 Enjoy Calendar Music Arts &amp; Theatre Community Movies Dining TV Books Games 
 
The Latest
 
 ZooMontana&apos;s struggles captured in new documentary film 

The award-winning production company, Out in the Cold Productions, will feature ZooMontana in a documentary on the survival of ZooMontana duri…
 
 Feature video and photo: 60&apos;s style sunglasses still in style 

Ryanne Frazier, left, models a modern take on 60&apos;s era cat eyes sunglasses by Marc Jacobs. Vicki-Lynn Tacke models a classic aviator sunglass…
 
Recent

 Awaken the Empire and Eyes Set to Kill come to Manny&apos;s next month Brantley Gilbert&apos;s Hell on Wheels tour stops in Missoula, Bozeman New Music Tuesday: July 10 Weekday Sampler: 5 things to do in Billings this week Kids&apos; Time: Fun and inexpensive things for kids to do in Billings this week 
 
 Lifestyles 
 Outdoors Health Your Home Recipes Religion Pets Travel Engagements Weddings Anniversaries Births 
 Obituaries Calendar Get It! 
 Classified Ads Get It! Today&apos;s Deal Contests Garage Sales Garage Sale Map Merchandise Pets SellItMT.com Newspaper Ads Place an Ad 
 Homes 
 Homes for sale Open Houses Map For Rent Welcome Home Find an Agent Montana Land Magazine Place an Ad 
 Cars 
 Cars Recreational Place an Ad Dealers 
 Jobs 
 Local Jobs Virtual Career Fair Post Resume Place an Ad Top Jobs TV Work for us 
 
 
 Hot Topics Accidental death Naked DUI Beer run Ex-NFL QB Sect leader Relay for Life Miles City fire Summer Giveaway Week 
 
 Home / News 
 
Empty stockings: Readers can help those in need
 Print Email « 
 
 » 2010-12-05T00:00:00Z 2011-01-28T15:42:13Z Empty stockings: Readers can help those in need The Billings Gazette December 05, 2010 12:00 am (0) Comments 
 Donations needed for holiday funds 


 • Children&apos;s Protective Services, a state
agency that protects children who are neglected or abused, has a
Christmas fund to tap when no other funds are available.

Money has been used to pay for summer camps, sports feeds,
emergency medication and other needs.

The investigative unit for CPS could also use generic gifts or
cash donations to help children and teens who are unexpectedly
placed in foster care during the holidays. To contribute, call CPS
at 657-3120.

 • Adult Protective Services, a state program to
protect elderly and disabled adults at risk for abuse, also has a
Christmas fund to take community donations. The fund helps APS
clients with emergency supplies, medication co-pays and other
items. To donate, call APS at 655-7640.

 • Head Start, which provides
education and health services to low-income children and their
families, could use gas cards and MET bus passes for clients; a TV
and DVD player to use for parent education; children&apos;s sweat pants,
sizes 3T-7; boys&apos; and girls&apos; underwear, sizes 3T-7; children&apos;s
books; and children&apos;s snow boots, sizes 5-8.

 • The YWCA helps 48 disabled
men and women live as independently as possible in the
community.

Each year, the group hosts a formal dinner for the clients with
an appearance by Santa. To help fill giveaway bags from Santa, the
YWCA could use donations of movies, music CDs, towels, small gift
cards to fast-food restaurants and stores, shavers and card games.
To donate, call 252-6303.

 • The Montana Rescue Mission Women&apos;s
and Family Shelter&apos;s needs list for clients includes
diapers, size 4-5; diaper wipes; pull-on diapers; laundry baskets;
watches; clocks; alarm clocks; small pocket calendars; gift cards;
movie passes; pizza coupons; large-print Bibles; 2X-3X clothing;
gifts for men and teenagers; large and XL pajamas; new towels and
washcloths; small kitchen appliances; city bus passes; wrapping
paper and tape; pocket notebooks and devotionals; pens; stamps and
stamped envelopes; socks, underwear and T-shirts for boys and men;
XL sweat pants for women; men&apos;s toiletries; and toilet paper.

 • The Montana Rescue Mission Men&apos;s
Shelter needs list for clients includes twin-size sheets,
pillows, shaving cream, toothpaste, towels, stocking caps, gloves,
socks, T-shirts and sweatshirts in size large and up, medium-size
duffel bags, day packs, city bus passes, gift cards to fast-food
restaurants in the downtown area, sleeping bags and watches.

 
In a season filled with giving, Empty Stockings allows readers
to connect with struggling families in and around Billings.

The brief profiles offer a way to help single mothers, children
in foster care, elderly residents and others in need.

The names in the profiles have been changed to protect the
identities of those who need your help, but their stories are
real.

To help them, please contact the agency named in bold type at
the end of each listing.

Gifts delivered to those agencies should be new and unwrapped,
although you may include gift wrap with your donation.

u u u

Janice, a single mother of two, has recently obtained custody of
her 4-year-old granddaughter. Janice works full-time, but can
barely make ends meet.

Her daughter, Megan, 16, wears a size 1 in pants and medium in
women&apos;s shirts. She likes drawing and could use a new sketch
pad.

Janice&apos;s son, Joe, 14, wears a size 31x30 in men&apos;s pants and XL
in men&apos;s shirts and needs a winter jacket. He likes to work out and
lifts weights.

Her granddaughter wears 4T shirts and 5T pants. She likes
Barbies and the Disney princesses.

 St. Vincent DePaul Society, 

 2610 Montana Ave., 248-1411 

Chancy, 6, would love an exercise ball for his guinea pig. He
also likes movies and would like a new football jersey to wear in
youth size 7.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 

 2525 Fourth Ave. N., Suite 309, 657-3120 

Carolyn, 68, is raising her grandson, Conrad, 16. Her only
income is from Social Security. Both of Conrad&apos;s parents are
incarcerated, so they provide no child support.

Carolyn needs fleece blankets. She could also use bakeware and
cookbooks and soft socks in a size large.

Conrad enjoys hand-held games, likes hard-rock CD and wears
hooded sweatshirts, size large, men&apos;s. He would enjoy a gift card
to Hastings because he loves to read and enjoys his music.

 Family Service Inc., 

 1824 First Ave. N., 259-2269 

Sam, 2, likes to play outside with trucks and balls. He needs
jeans and wears a 2T.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

David, his wife and five children were victims of a house fire
two years ago. During this time, David became very ill. After a
long struggle, David has finally managed to get the house rebuilt,
but, with money low and the large medical debt from his illness,
they do not have the funds to furnish their house properly.

 Salvation Army, 

 2100 Sixth Ave. N., 245-4659 

Karen, a single mom with two boys, is struggling to find steady
work. She hopes to return to school in the spring, but right now
she is trying to keep her family together and their heads above
water.

Sam, 8, wears size 10 clothing. He needs size 10 slim pants,
medium boxer briefs and medium socks and would like a Hot Wheels
track. Joe, 11, wears a size 12 shirt, size 12 regular pants, boy&apos;s
extra large boxer briefs and boy&apos;s medium socks. He would like a
Nerf gun.

Mom would like a hoodie or starter sweat outfit size 2X.

 Montana Rescue Mission 

 Women&apos;s and Family Shelter, 2520 First Ave. N.,
259-3105 

Monica, a single mother, has four sons. Multiple medical issues
keep her from being able to work. Despite all her medical issues,
she continues to devote all her time to her family. She worries
that she will not be able to give her children a Christmas.

Jack, 13, needs size 16 pants and shirts size large. Cole, 11,
needs pants size 12, and medium shirts. Bob, 10, needs size 10
pants and medium shirts. Harvey, 8, needs size 10 pants and medium
shirts.

The boys share a love of board games, basketball and movies.

 Community Hope, 

 204 Cedar Ave., Laurel, 

 628-7281 

Emma unexpectedly became a single mom of three children after
her husband returned from Iraq and they became victims of domestic
violence. Emma is striving for financial independence. She hopes to
graduate from nursing school, but struggles with the cost of
tuition.

Financial help would allow Emma and her children to feel hopeful
for a brighter future.

 Head Start, 615 N. 19th St., 

 245-7233 

Del recently left his home to become a resident of a nursing
home. He needs T-shirts, size large, a short robe, size large and
socks. He likes sugarless candy.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Barbara is raising three children, ages 11, 7, and 4. The
children&apos;s father left the family suddenly, and Barbara decided to
move back to her home town of Billings to start a new life. Barbara
is actively looking for a job that will support her family. Her
monthly income leaves no extra money for Christmas or to buy
clothes for her growing children.

Donavan, 11, wears size 12 pants and size 7 shoes. He needs a
warm pair of gloves. He likes Legos and would like the movie “How
to Train your Dragon” or a Sorry Sliders board game. He also likes
to play outdoors and would like a new sled.

Carmen, 7, wears size 7 pants and size 2-1/2 shoes. She would
like a pink stocking cap and gloves. She loves Hannah Montana,
Icarly, Taylor Swift, and Hello Kitty merchandise. She would like a
stroller for her baby doll.

Chet, 4, wears size 5 pants and size 12 children&apos;s shoes. He
needs a winter hat and gloves. He likes to play with cars and would
love a Hot Wheels Track and anything connected to SpongeBob.

Barbara could use a winter hat and gloves, pillows, plasticware
and pots and pans. She would like some jewelry to spruce up her
professional look when she finds a job.

 YWCA, 909 Wyoming Ave., 252-6303 

Marvin, an elderly gentleman, likes to go out and visit friends.
He could use new dress shirts, size 16 to 16-1/2 tall and a
lightweight windbreaker or sweater, size large, tall.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Sarah, 14, likes jewelry and loves shopping. She would love to
get some new earrings and fun accessories such as socks, bracelets,
hair doo-dads and a gift certificate for the mall. She wears ladies
size 7 or medium.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Bertha, 61, has diabetes and chronic obstructive pulmonary
disease, COPD. She would love a small card table, perhaps with a
matching chair, where she can work her puzzles and crafts. She
could use a roll of quarters and/or a container of Tide laundry
detergent for her apartment&apos;s laundry room.

She would love a powerful “boom box”-style AM/FM radio to pick
up her favorite Christian radio station.

Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640

Louise, who was recently widowed, had to move into a small
apartment. She lost a lot of her stuff when she moved and really
misses her arts and crafts projects. She likes to knit and do
needlepoint. She could use slippers and maybe some warm sweaters
and blankets.

 St. Vincent DePaul Society, 2610 Montana Ave.,
248-1411 

Jackson, 62, is severely disabled and has spent many years in a
nursing home.

He could use an electric razor and needs jeans, size 42x30.
Jackson loves soda pop and mints, but vending-machine prices exceed
his monthly allowance. With a Walmart gift card, staff at the
nursing home could purchase these items for him.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Tana, 57, is disabled by a mental illness. She needs a sturdy
hand-held can opener and could use a set of silverware. Some
washable scatter rugs, preferably in red, would help disguise a
worn and stained carpet.

To celebrate big events, Tana loves to treat herself and a
neighbor to a Pizza Hut pizza, so a gift certificate would please
her.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Diane, a single mom, is struggling to find a full-time job. At
the moment, she works limited hours at two part-time jobs. She is
not home as much as she would like to be with her 4-year-old son,
Cal, but she does what she can.

She would like a gift card to go to dinner with her son and
enjoy some time for just them. She needs bath towels and would love
scented candles and bath and body items.

Cal needs winter clothing, size 5T. He would love any toys
connected with the movie “Toy Story 3” and likes all superheroes.
He and his mom also like to sit down and do coloring together.

 Family Service Inc., 

 1824 First Ave. N., 

 259-2269 

Mary recently got a job and her own place for herself and her
son John, 5. Mary needs pots and pans and bedding for a queen and a
twin bed. John would love nothing more than a bike for Christmas,
but Mary has been unable to afford one. John has wanted a bike
badly for a while.

 Salvation Army, 2100 Sixth Ave. N.,
245-4659 

Randy, 16, has no family and lives in a group home. He needs
some new shirts, size large, and hooded sweatshirts, size XL. He
would also like a gift certificate to pick out new music and video
games.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Amy, 15, lives in a group home and has no family to share the
holidays. She wears size 16 pants and shirts size XL to 2XL. She
loves country music, horses, “Twilight” and Justin Bieber.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Lucy, 18, and Reagan, 17, will remain in foster care until they
graduate from high school next May. They will be living
independently at age 18. Both girls could use household items such
as pots and pans and bath/kitchen towels.

Lucy also enjoys books. Reagan wears size 7 pants and shirts
size medium. She enjoys music and adventure books.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Wilford, who moved here from out-of-state, has no close
relatives and recently suffered some medical setbacks. He needs
Levi&apos;s, size 33x30, and T-shirts in size medium. Canned food would
help him get through the winter.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Randy, a younger man with a neurological disorder, needs a clock
with large letters and numbers indicating time, date and day of the
week to help him live more independently. Randy needs Levi&apos;s size
33x34; heavy shirts, size medium; a good jacket; socks; and
T-shirts, size medium.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Travis struggles with difficulties related to age and blindness.
He lost his home and is now in the process of moving into a modest
rental unit.

Gift certificates would allow Travis to treat himself to a
Fillet o&apos; Fish sandwich from McDonald&apos;s or a grocery or deli item
from Albertsons, where he shops. He has a weakness for latte coffee
and lives near the “Off the Leaf” coffee shop.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Nathan, 87, lost his money to a relative who tricked him into
withdrawing his savings. He now lives in a nursing home.

Nathan likes to snack on Nutri-Grain bars and Quaker&apos;s “Chewy
Dips” bars. He also enjoys drinking bottled Life Water, especially
orange-flavored. He uses Nivea lotion for his dry skin. If he had a
roll of quarters, he could occasionally buy a candy bar or cold
soda from the vending machines.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Dora is nearly 80. Her small nest egg was not immune to the
country&apos;s economic downturn and no longer exists. Dora would love a
gift card to IGA or Albertsons, where she buys groceries, or to
Sears, where she could buy a set of badly needed tires for her
aging car. Dora also loves Hershey&apos;s Kisses.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Tim works to support a family of six. Kelly, his wife, can&apos;t
work because of her health. They have four children, and they are
afraid one of them may have multiple sclerosis. This child also
requires long-term dental care.

Bobby, 9, wears a size 10-12 large shirt, 10 slim pants, medium
socks, boy&apos;s boxer briefs size 6-8 and children&apos;s size 4 shoes.
Bobby would like action figures.

Steven, 7, wears a shirt size medium 6 -7, pants size 8 regular,
medium socks, size 8 boxer briefs and size 13 shoes. He would like
a toy puppy or kitten. Jayden, 4, wears a size 6 toddler blouse and
toddler pants, size 4 toddler underwear, medium girl&apos;s socks and
size 10 children&apos;s shoes. She would like princess stuff, and her
favorite character is Snow White.

Tom, 2, wears a 3T shirt and pants, small socks, a toddler size
7 shoe and diapers size 4 -5. He would like anything from “Toy
Story.”

This family struggles, but they are very grateful for each other
as well as their friends and family.

 Montana Rescue Mission Women&apos;s and Family Shelter, 2520
First Ave. N., 259-3105 

Pam and Pete are no different than any other American family:
They work hard, pay their bills, but cannot make ends meet. They
have two girls, Shyler, 9, and Trisha 7.

Shyler wears size 12 pants, and girls&apos; large shirts. Trisha
wears size 7-8 and medium shirts. The girls love to do crafts, play
with dolls, dress up and all other types of girly things.

 Community Hope, 204 Cedar Ave., Laurel,
628-7281 

Mark lives in a mobile home with his pets to keep him company.
He would like warm shirts, a jacket, socks and T-shirts in size
large.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Gerrie, a single mother, has three children. Her vehicle&apos;s
transmission is broken. Gerrie is trying to find work, get her
children to school, attend school events and get to routine
appointments. She would like to attend college classes, but lack of
transportation makes this nearly impossible.

She uses the city bus when she is able, but she finds it
impossible sometimes to make the schedules work. Repairing her
vehicle would help this struggling mother meet her goals.

 Head Start, 615 N. 19th St., 245-7233 

Carol lives on a very limited income. She needs a new robe and
pajamas, size 18, and warm socks. She could also use canned food
and paper products to supplement her pantry.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Martha lives in a care facility. Because she enjoys writing and
receiving mail, she would like colored writing tablets, envelopes
and stamps. She needs a cardigan, size 22-24, sweatshirts or
sweaters. “Mumu”-type dresses in size 4X would also be
appropriate.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Adam is a single father who works full-time. He gets to work by
bike, but recently had his bike stolen. His son, Mike, 2, doesn&apos;t
need clothes, but he does need a winter jacket in size 2T. He likes
Bob the Builder and “Sesame Street.”

 St. Vincent DePaul Society, 2610 Montana Ave.,
248-1411 

Barry, 2, likes all kinds of trucks, cars and balls. He is
quiet, but enjoys making engine noises for his cars. He wears size
18 months.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Jordan, age 11, likes being active in sports and loves video
games. He would like a new Air Jordan logo shirt and sweats or a
gift certificate to a sports store. He wears youth size 10-12.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

John, 8, would like a new Air Jordan hat. He wanted one last
year, but didn&apos;t get one. He also wants a new Nerf-style dart
shooter. He likes video games and wears youth size 10-12.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Laurie is cognitively disabled but manages to supplement her
disability check with earnings from a part-time job at a Billings
fast-food restaurant. A man recently took advantage of her, causing
her to lose several hundred dollars of hard-earned savings.

She would love a gift certificate to Tarantino&apos;s Pizzeria, a
favorite restaurant. She would also enjoy a set of new bathroom
towels, preferably in blue.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Betsy, 70, suffers from a severely debilitating mental illness.
She could use a set of cream-colored sheets for her twin bed. She
could also use a large bag in an American Indian design, to carry
books and other items. She would also enjoy gift certificates to
McDonald&apos;s and Pizza Hut.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Sunny is disabled and lives on a limited income. She would like
a winter jacket, any color, size 4X. She also needs XL socks and
size 9 tennis shoes, any color.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Jenn has just become a single mom after a drawn-out divorce. She
is receiving welfare benefits, but no child support. She is going
through a work program and preparing for college courses in
January.

Her son, Jerry, 7, needs winter boots, size 1, and winter
clothing, size 7 in pants and size 12 in shirts. He has asked his
mom for a skateboard and loves wrestling action figures. He would
love a new Mongoose bike for tricks.

 Family Service Inc., 

 1824 First Ave. N., 

 259-2269 

John, 16, enjoys fishing gear and movies. John wears shirts size
medium or large and pants 29x30.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Sarah has a part-time job and two kids, Michael and Felix. She
has a part-time job, but is unable to work fulltime because Michael
is a severe diabetic. If she works more, she will lose insurance
for Michael.

Michael needs pants, size 16, and snow boots, size 6. Felix
needs pants, size 8, and snow boots, size 12. Sarah needs household
necessities and would love a bathrobe, size 2X-3X. The boys would
love a set of Star Wars Legos or the Jumanji board game.

 Salvation Army, 2100 Sixth Ave. N.,
245-4659 

Tiffany, 17, is in foster care until she graduates from high
school in May. She is planning on college and could use household
items such as bath and kitchen towels, dishes and utensils. Tiffany
would enjoy a gift card to Shipton&apos;s Big R because she is saving to
buy muck boots and Carhartt extreme bibs.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Beth, 17, lives in foster care. She needs pants size 5 and
shirts size medium. Since she is getting ready to live
independently, she would like bath/kitchen towels and a comforter
set for a full-size bed.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Jason, an elderly man, lives in the country and is on rural
electric. He is on oxygen around the clock and does not have a
back-up generator. The generator would make him feel more secure in
a power outage.

He also needs warm shirts, size large, and a warm jacket.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Tammy is a full-time student and works part-time. She needs a
coffeemaker, can opener and toaster. She could also use a winter
jacket. She wears a large in women&apos;s.

 St. Vincent DePaul Society, 2610 Montana Ave.,
248-1411 

Bob, 52, is a single dad caring for Amy, 10. He is a severe
diabetic and was in the hospital for more than half this year
because he was unable to stabilize his blood sugar. At times, he
was unable to be home with his daughter for weeks.

He lives on his Social Security Disability benefit and very
little other assistance.

Bob needs a new glucose meter and strips and a gift card to
Albertsons or Walmart for groceries. He could use a robe and
slippers, both size medium men&apos;s. Amy would like inline skates,
size 5; water sand; and computer games of any kind. She needs
winter clothes, size 12/14.

 Family Service Inc., 

 1824 First Ave. N., 

 259-2269 

Francis, a single mom with four children, needs household
necessities such as bath towels, silverware, dishes and pots and
pans. Paul would love an MP3 player or the book “Diary of A Wimpy
Kid.” Sam would love a wallet. Craig and Max both adore Thomas the
Tank Engine and would love a set to play with together.

 Salvation Army, 2100 Sixth Ave. N.,
245-4659 

Hannah, 15, will spend Christmas in a group home. She wears
junior&apos;s size 9 pants and shirts, size medium. She wears women&apos;s
size 8-1/2 shoes and would enjoy some heels. She would also like
some pajamas, makeup and boots with fur. She loves Justin Bieber
and Taylor Swift.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Sam, 16, will spend Christmas in a group home. He wears pants
size 32x30 and XL shirts. He would like cologne, games and
puzzles.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Sarah, 7, and Sally, 6 months, were removed from their parents
due to physical abuse. They live together in a pre-adoptive foster
home. Both girls have significant physical delays, and Sally also
has cognitive delays. Sarah enjoys Barbie dolls and Zu Zu pets,
while Sally likes musical toys and children&apos;s CDs.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Dave, a young man, struggles to live independently. He needs
Wrangler jeans size 33x33; extra large shirts; and a jacket.
T-shirts and socks would be appreciated.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Warren lives alone and cuts wood for heat. Warm shirts in size
large, heavy gloves and a warm hat would make him more comfortable
this winter.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Mabel, an elderly woman, has left her house in the country to
live in a care facility in Billings. Mabel needs washable cardigan
sweaters or sweatshirts, size 2XL, along with socks and pullover
tops.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Paula, a single mother of seven, has four of her own children
and three children from her late husband. She works two jobs, but
has a hard time making ends meet. She doesn&apos;t want any toys for her
children. She likes them to do arts and crafts and games that the
family can do together.

There are four girls, Julie, 9; Tina, 6; Middy, 4; and Lily, 3.
The boys are Johnny, 6; Max, 3; and Dillon, 4.

 St. Vincent DePaul Society, 2610 Montana Ave.,
248-1411 

Juliette, 4, likes Little People toys, doll houses and dolls,
especially American Indian dolls. She has pretty hair and loves
having it done up with hair accessories. She wears youth size
5.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Channelle, 4, likes all kinds of toys and markers or poster
sets. She wears youth size XL.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

David, 5, is learning to love the computer and would like
age-appropriate computer learning games and toys to put together
and take apart. He wears size 5T.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Lori was unexpectedly laid off after being employed at the same
company for 15 years. She received unemployment benefits for almost
1-1/2 years, but it has run out. She has applied for many
positions, but most say she is overqualified. Due to the stress of
the last year, she suffered a breakdown and spent some time in the
hospital.

She is receiving services through vocational rehabilitation and
hopes to start working again soon. She never thought at her age she
would be starting over. She would like socks, size large; scented
candles; and relaxation CDs. She needs towels and really enjoys
reading.

 Family Service Inc., 

 1824 First Ave. N., 259-2269 

Carla, 60, was homeless until recently. She just got her own
place, but she cannot afford necessities for her house. She needs
towels, bedding, dishes, silverware and pots and pans.

 Salvation Army, 

 2100 Sixth Ave. N., 245-4659 

Pamela, 74, underwent major surgery recently. She lives alone in
a small rented apartment. It would be a special treat if she had a
Walmart gift card to occasionally buy something new. She also needs
a small, 5- to 10-gallon, humidifier for her little apartment and a
laundry basket.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Katrina, 66, suffered a series of strokes in October, which
resulted in physical and verbal difficulties. She was taken
advantage of by a car salesman, which left her small savings
account depleted. Katrina could use a set of queen-sized cotton
sheets with pillowcases and a set of bath towels, all preferably in
white, off-white or burgundy.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Tina, 16, lives at home and cares for her infant son, Tony, who
is 6 months old. She is taking GED classes and wants to make a life
for herself and her son.

Tina enjoys reading books, and the “Twilight” series is a
special favorite. She wears size XL women&apos;s shirts and size 16
pants. Tony enjoys musical toys and lights. He needs a winter coat
and clothes, size 12 months.

 Family Service Inc., 

 1824 First Ave. N., 259-2269 

Darla, 57, suffers from multiple sclerosis. She is unable to
walk and is dependent upon caregivers for help with the activities
of daily living. Her medical condition necessitates doctors&apos;
visits, but she does not have a coat.

She needs a warm winter coat, preferably hooded, in any color,
in size 2X or 3X. She has no teeth, but enjoys soft-centered
chocolates, caramels, or peanut butter candy.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Olivia, an elderly woman, needs a vaporizer and could use some
blankets and slippers. She is on a limited income and can barely
get her rent and bills paid.

 St. Vincent DePaul Society, 

 2610 Montana Ave., 248-1411 

Hans, 4, likes trucks that are sturdy enough to play with in the
dirt. He wears size 4T. Jack, 2, likes sing-along toys. He wears
size 3T and needs a winter coat with a hat and mittens or
gloves.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Jack, 11, lives in a therapeutic group home and has no contact
with his birth family. Both of his parents are incarcerated. He has
no other family to be with this Christmas.

Jack wears size 10 regular pants, shirts in a boy&apos;s large and
size 5 shoes. He really wants a remote-control car and also loves
anything related to sports. The Denver Broncos are his favorite
team.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Bonnie, a single mother, just had her three children returned to
her care. She has worked hard to better her life, but has not been
able to maintain employment due to continued treatment
requirements.

Bonnie&apos;s children, 3-year-old Sally and 7-month-old twins Eddie
and Rita, could use your help. Sally wears a 3T and shoes size 9.
She loves looking at books, playing with dolls, and Dora the
Explorer toys. Both babies need clothes, size 12 months, and any
age-appropriate toys. Bonnie could use help to provide them with
new bedding and a gift certificate for a special holiday
dinner.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Betty, 77, was living at home but recently lost her husband, who
had been her caregiver. She then moved to a care facility. She
needs flannel pajamas and long nightgowns, both size small. She
could also use bras, size 32B, small underwear and small knee- high
socks.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Donna, 65, lives in a care facility due to her disabilities. She
would enjoy a blue dress, size 12, along with dress shoes, size 9.
She would also like a blue winter jacket, size 14.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Rita, 86, has dementia, but had been living happily at home
until recently, when she had to move to a care facility. She is
tall and could use size large/tall nightgowns, a large/tall
housecoat and slippers, size 10, to match. She has always enjoyed
floral designs and bright colors.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Tamra was in an abusive marriage for 25 years. This year, she
escaped with her children and is starting over in Billings. She has
no income, but, with help from her family, she has stable housing.
Tamra could use pots and pans, bakeware, silverware, bath towels
and dish towels.

Her son, Gene, 17, would like gift cards to GameStop and
Walmart. He is a senior in high school and would like black and
gray hoodies, size men&apos;s large. Cody, 14, would like gift cards and
needs winter shirts, size men&apos;s large.

 Family Service Inc., 

 1824 First Ave. N., 259-2269 

Camey, 64, works part-time. She has a 1996 Dodge that she uses
to get work, and the window is longer working. She is nervous about
whether it will be fixed this winter.

 Salvation Army, 

 2100 Sixth Ave. N., 245-4659 

Teresa, a quiet elderly woman, lives simply on a small income.
She would like a red button-down sweater and a blue pullover
sweater, both in size medium. She could also use Head&amp;Shoulders shampoo, petroleum jelly and postage stamps.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Georgette, an elderly woman, lost a huge amount of money in a
scam. She needs white tennis shoes, size 7-1/2; laundry soap; and
fabric softener. She could also use a frying pan and
silverware.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Dotty, 64, moved to Billings from out of state. She is looking
for an apartment. She needs white tennis shoes, size 8-1/2; women&apos;s
Levi jeans, size 18; and XL blouses. Dotty likes brightly colored
Western-style blouses with a front pocket and snaps.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Nell and Dwayne are both retired and receive Social Security.
Their daughter passed away, leaving two teens behind. Raising
teenagers on a fixed income has been difficult. Dwayne&apos;s health
problems require costly medication.

They could use a Walmart gift card to help pay for medications
and possibly a dining-out gift card to just relax. Angel, 16, would
like printed hoodies, size medium, women&apos;s. She loves anything from
Bath&amp;Body Works.

Jake, 14, needs winter clothes and a coat, size large, men&apos;s,
and would like a gift card to Hastings. Both need winter items.

 Family Service Inc., 

 1824 First Ave. N., 259-2269 

Maria, 58, volunteers her time all around town. She loves
assisting in any way that she can; however, she needs tires for her
car so that she can drive to all the places she volunteers.

 Salvation Army, 

 2100 Sixth Ave. N., 245-4659 

Linda, a 55-year-old who uses a wheelchair, is on a very limited
income. She is in a semi-assisted living unit. She loves microwave
popcorn of all flavors. She would also be grateful for some new
petite or short pants, size medium, and large pullover tops.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Debra, 71, struggles with the loss of her husband. She lives in
a semi-assisted living unit. Debra enjoys fun slippers, size 5-1/2
or 6, and pullover tops with cute designs, size large.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Darlene, 95, lives independently with help from her caregivers.
She enjoys find-the-word puzzles and mixed nuts (no peanuts).
Darlene has been trying to find a black-and-white tiger- or
zebra-striped soft and fuzzy queen-size bedspread, but has been
unsuccessful so far. She would be very grateful to anyone who could
provide this.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Theresa, a single mom, has many health issues. She had major
surgery in July and spent four weeks in a nursing home
recuperating. She needs clothing — shirts, size 26/28, and pants,
size 4, or extra small in stretchy pants.

Her son, Tim, is disabled, but he helps his mom as much as
possible. He needs winter clothes, size XL men&apos;s, hoodies and a
gift card to Hastings to rent movies.

 Family Service Inc., 

 1824 First Ave. N., 259-2269 

Charles, a 59-year-old veteran, has worked his way out of
homelessness. He has own place with help from the Veterans
Administration. He just moved in and needs household necessities
such as towels and dishes, bedding and pots and pans.

 Salvation Army, 

 2100 Sixth Ave. N., 245-4659 

Hal, 61, is disabled from a stroke, lives alone and has no
family. He needs long-sleeve Western snap-button shirts, size XL,
and some work gloves, size large.

Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640

Homer, 76, lives in a care facility. He has no family and a very
limited income. He needs slippers, size 13. He is a big man and
could use a gift card from a big and tall store, the only place he
can find clothes to fit.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Paul and Alicia are both receiving unemployment and struggling
to find jobs that will be comparable to the amount of their
unemployment income. They have not asked for anything for
themselves. They just want to give their son, Mike, 10, a great
holiday.

Mike would like superhero Legos and likes Zhu Zhu pets. He needs
winter clothing, size large in men&apos;s. The family could use a gift
card for food or nonperishable food items.

 Family Service Inc., 

 1824 First Ave. N., 259-2269 

Katie, 3, is a delightful girl with significant developmental
delays. She enjoys any type of trains including Thomas the Tank
Engine.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 

 2525 Fourth Ave. N., Suite 309, 657-3120 

Louie, 11, and his brother Gabe, 14, have survived many of
life&apos;s hardships, including surviving Hurricane Katrina. Louie and
Gabe have recently been reunified with their mother and are very
excited to celebrate Christmas this year. The family would like a
Christmas tree and Christmas decorations for their house.

Louie loves to play outside and would like new wheels for his
Ripstik. Louie would also like a gas-powered remote-control car.
Louie likes to wear sweatshirts. Gabe would also like a utility
flashlight. Louie wears 12 regular boys pants; size medium boys
shirts and size 7 shoes. Gabe wears men&apos;s jeans 40x32 and size 10
shoes.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 

 657-3120 

James, 8; Vince, 6; Jacob, 4; and Zeb, 2, have been reunited
with their birth parents, and the family is excited to celebrate
Christmas together. James and Vince both need socks, underwear,
snow boots and snow pants. Both James and Vince like Bakugan toys.
James is a big Star Wars fan, and Vince likes Batman.

Jacob also needs snow boots and snow pants. Jacob loves
Diego.

Zeb could use a snowsuit and snow boots. Zeb loves Thomas the
Tank Engine and SpongeBob Square Pants. James wears size 5T in boys
in both shirts and pants and 1-1/2 shoes.

Vince wears size 6T in boy&apos;s shirts and pants and 2-1/2 shoes.
Jacob wears size 4T in shirts and pants and size 9 shoes, and Zeb
wears size 24 month in shirts and 18 months in pants and size 6
shoes.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 

 657-3120 

Susan, a single mom with two kids, lost her job due to sickness.
Without a job, she struggles to support her two children.

 Salvation Army, 

 2100 Sixth Ave. N., 245-4659 

Dane, 8 months, would like learning toys, musical toys and
cardboard books. Dane wears size 6-9 months in clothes and size 3
baby shoes. Aiden is an independent 1-year-old who loves to read
and learn. He also loves to play with trucks and cars. He wears 24
months in pants, size 2T shirts and size 5 baby shoes.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Alex, 7, and his twin brothers, who are 2, are in foster care
together. Alex loves to do experiments and work on science
projects. He would like a spy watch and slipper socks, size
2-1/2.

Conner and Brent would like a tool kit for ages 5 and up. Conner
and Brent also love “Toy Story” and “Sesame Street.” Alex wears
size 10 slim or regular pants, and size 10 boy&apos;s shirts. Brent and
Collin wear size 3T and need sweatshirts.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Abby, 8, and Brook, 5, are sisters who love horses and cats.
Abby loves to draw and would like some art supplies. Brook loves to
play dress-up and would like some princess dress-up clothes and
play make-up. Both girls like to read, play board games and do
puzzles.

Abby wears size 8 girl&apos;s shirts and pants and size 13 shoes.
Brook wears size 6 girl&apos;s shirts and pants and size 10 shoes.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Lila, 61, is developmentally disabled, lives alone and has no
contact from her family. She enjoys embroidery and would like some
pillow slips with small pictures that she can embroider. She also
likes fill-in-the-word puzzles and word-seek puzzles.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Beverly moved into her own place about a year ago and has been
doing OK. But she is having a hard time buying stamps to pay her
bills, gas to get to class and work and find money for food, towels
and bedding.

 Salvation Army, 

 2100 Sixth Ave. N., 245-4659 

Les, 66, lives in a nursing home due to a disabling stroke. His
wife died, and he could no longer live alone. Les needs athletic
shoes, size 9; jeans size 36x30; and a twin-size bedspread. He
could also use some socks, size 9-10; a coffee mug; an electric
razor; and some animal posters.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Dollie, 87, was exploited financially by her children to the
point that she lost her home. She now lives in a small apartment.
She would enjoy some slipper socks in blue or brown, size 11; a
cardigan sweater 1X; and a black stocking cap. Dollie loves to read
mystery and crime books and would enjoy some Diet Pepsi.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Vickie, 61, lives in a care facility. Her daughter left town
with all Vickie&apos;s savings. Vickie has no other family and a very
limited income.

She would appreciate a Christmas cactus; blue slippers with a
firm sole, size 8; a sweatshirt with a snowman on it in size 3X;
and a winter coat in blue, size 3X.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

MacKensy is a widow with two children. She is working part-time
and going to school full-time. She hopes for a better life for her
sons, Karl, 3, and Kaine, 1.

She moved into an unfurnished house and is behind on her rent.
She needs couches and a bed for her youngest son. Her car needs an
alternator and a serpentine belt. Without it, she will have trouble
getting to school or work.

 Salvation Army, 

 2100 Sixth Ave. N., 245-4659 

Freda, 70, lives in a care facility. Her children took all her
savings, and now she lives on a very small income. She needs
long-sleeve blouses, size large, and slacks, size 16. She could
also use a colorful throw for sitting in her recliner.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Anita, 86, recently moved to a care facility. Her family members
live far away, and she rarely sees them. Anita loves to read
mysteries and romance novels. She needs a pretty nightgown and
robe, size medium; slippers, size 8; and some stationery and stamps
to keep in touch with friends and family.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Maria, 65, has severe arthritis. She lives independently with
assistance. She would be very grateful for easy-to-pull-on clothes,
size 12, or medium size slacks and tops, pajamas or nightgowns.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Timmy, 5, and his younger brother, Tray, 1, are in foster care.
Timmy loves to draw with markers and paint. Timmy and Tray could
use snow boots and snow pants for Christmas and could also use some
sweatpants, jeans, underwear and socks.

Timmy also loves to read and play with action figures. Tray
loves to play with cars, Thomas the Tank Engine and any electrical
toys that make noise. Tray loves to explore and figure out how
things work.

Timmy wears size 5T shirts and pants and size 12 shoes. Tray
wears size 12-18 months shirts and pants and size 6 shoes.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Tony, 10, is in a group home and does not have contact with
family members. He could use winter clothing, long-sleeved shirts,
size 10-12. He would love a Grizzlies shirt or skateboarding shirt.
He wears jeans or pants size 10-12.

He would also love a magic tricks kit, the book “Diary of a
Wimpy Kid,” Taylor Swift CDs and posters and the “Iron Man II” or
“Transformers II” movie.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Suzie and her two boys, Brent, 16, and Bobby, 12, need living
room furniture, such as a couch, chair or love seat; a vacuum; and
some pot holders. The boys could also use winter clothing. The
family has very little income and could really use these gifts to
make their home more livable.

Brent wears men&apos;s size XL shirts, coats and underwear; size
36x34 pants; adult size 13 shoes and socks. Bobby wears men&apos;s large
shirts, 36x32 pants; XL underwear and coats; shoes in adult size 10
and socks.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Sharon, a single mom of Nathan, 3, and Sara, 14 months, recently
got a job and has a place to stay. Sara needs a new bed. The family
also needs dishes and bedding, both twin and full sets. Sharon also
would love a jacket for herself, in size large.

 Salvation Army, 

 2100 Sixth Ave. N., 245-4659 

Deidra, 71, has multiple sclerosis. She loves new clothes, size
12 petite pants and large tops. Deidra enjoys country music; soft,
cuddly pajamas, robes and gowns; and fuzzy slippers. She also likes
socks that are “not just plain boring white” and purses that have
lots of pockets.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, 

 Suite D, 655-7640 

Darcey, 62, who is disabled, gets chilled easily and would be
thrilled to have a warm throw or fuzzy, soft robe to cover up with
when she watches TV. She loves angels of any type and
apple-cinnamon scented candles. She also loves clothes that are
feminine yet bright and colorful. She wears size medium pants and
large tops.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 

 655-7640 

Maggie, 60, has had a very difficult life. She loves new clothes
and wears size 1X tops and pants; shoes, size 8W; slippers size
8-1/2; and warm cuddly pajamas and gowns or a robe. Maggie would
also love to have some Christmas decorations for her home.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Margaret, Melissa and Shannon love to attend their music and art
lessons. However, the past couple of months, they have been unable
to because the transmission is out on their mom&apos;s car. It would
make their lives better to be able to drive again.

 Salvation Army, 

 2100 Sixth Ave. N., 245-4659 

Kathy, 14, lost her mother and is unable to be with her family
members because they live out of state. She likes Hannah Montana,
hair clips, jewelry, makeup and books.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Maddy, 45, has a progressively disabling medical condition and
struggles to meet her needs on a fixed income. She would love a
soft fuzzy robe, size XL. She would also be grateful for gift cards
to help with food costs and gasoline for her wheelchair-accessible
van.

She wears pants size large and XL tops that are easy to pull on.
She looks especially good in red.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Penny, a disabled 50-year-old, recently moved into her own
apartment. She would like some knickknacks for decoration. Penny
loves nice clothes, but the move used up any extra spending money.
She wears 2X tops and 1X tall pull-on pants.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Janelle is a friendly and outgoing 68-year-old. She loves
sweatshirts that are feminine and warm, size large, with pants that
match, size 10-12.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Lindsey, 5, and her sister, Laure, 6, enjoy playing with
Barbies, Littlest Pet Shop and dolls.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Jason, 10, has disabilities and lives in a group home. He likes
building things with Legos, superheroes and arts and crafts.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Tammy, 4, is in foster care with her brother, Mike, 7. Tammy
likes to play dress-up, Barbies and Littlest Pet Shop. Mike would
like a remote-control monster truck, skateboard and books suitable
for first-graders.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Maria&apos;s 11-year-old son, Mike, was returned to her care. A short
time later, she was let go from her job. There are two other
children in the home, Linda, 8, and Max, 4.

Mike wears pants, size 11-12 slim, and a boy&apos;s large shirt size.
He also needs boxer shorts. He loves sports and baseball cards.
Linda wears pants, size 7-8 slim, and shirts, size 7-8. She would
enjoy girl-type movies and Barbie dolls. Max wears 6-7 pants and
shirts and would really like a remote-control truck from Santa.

All of the children need short, ankle-type socks.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 

 2525 Fourth Ave. N., Suite 309, 

 657-3120 

Jack, 70, is a disabled Navy veteran. He enjoys reading and
playing games on his computer. He needs clothes that are easy to
pull on because he is waiting to be scheduled for a hip
replacement. He wears size

XXL shirts and XL pants.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Josie, 64, recently moved into her handicapped-accessible
apartment. She would love to have some lamps, tables and
knickknacks or anything else to make her apartment feel more like
home. Josie would also enjoy a nice throw for watching television.
She needs pajamas and slippers, size medium.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Mike, 4, and Eric, 5, could use pajamas and pants. Mike wears
size 5T, and Eric, size 6T. Both boys like superheroes and
trucks.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Arnold, a sweet 78-year-old bachelor, would enjoy having some
prepared meals available. He likes soups, stews and pretty much
anything that is easy to heat up on the stove or in the microwave.
Gift cards for pre-made food at a local deli, Albertsons or Walmart
would be a total delight. He would also enjoy a warm throw for
watching television.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Sandy is a single mom living with her 5-year-old son and her
grandmother. Both she and her mother have very bad backs and are
not able to walk very far. Many days they are not even able to walk
to the grocery store. Any assistance for the family would help
greatly.

 Salvation Army, 

 2100 Sixth Ave. N., 245-4659 

Jennifer, 8, and Jessica, 2, were recently placed in foster
care. Jessica needs a winter coat, size 5T, and warm winter
clothes, size 4T-5T. She loves baby dolls. Jennifer wears girl&apos;s
size 12 and loves anything Hannah Montana, craft sets and making
things.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Dirk, 13, lives with his grandparents who have limited
resources. He could use pants in a size 16 husky and shirts, size
large or men&apos;s small. He loves models. He likes being outdoors and
could use warm gloves, hats and a coat. He has a little dog that he
adores, and he would enjoy giving his puppy dog toys and bones.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Emily, 62, is developmentally disabled. She recently moved into
her own apartment and is enjoying her freedom. She loves embroidery
and could use some new embroidery supplies. Emily also likes
wearing clip-on earrings and watching DVDs of any kind.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Maude, 69, lives in a nursing home. Unfortunately, she was
unable to remain at home, even with her elderly husband&apos;s
assistance. Maude would enjoy a radio for her room and some reading
materials.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Lisa, 11, lives in foster care. She would like new winter
clothes, size 12-14. She loves the color purple. She likes to draw
and enjoys scrapbooking with her foster mother, so she would like
any art supplies or craft sets.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Sandy, 3, and Marcus, 4, recently returned to their single
father&apos;s care. Sandy has long blond hair and loves hair
accessories. She wears size 4T clothes and would like a baby
doll.

Marcus wears size 5. He likes boy-type Disney movies and is into
trucks and cars. He would like a backpack in a car or truck theme
to take to Head Start. Both children could use warm gloves or
mittens, hats and winter coats.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Kris, 45, is developmentally disabled and has lived in a group
home for quite some time. Kris would like sports books related to
baseball, football, and hockey. He also loves outings and could use
both a bus pass and a bowling pass at Sunset Bowl. Kris has a sweet
tooth for plain M&amp;M&apos;s.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Lorna, 91, would enjoy having some knickknacks and a warm throw.
She is particularly fond of angels, as well as statues and pictures
of Jesus Christ and Mary.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Mike, 55 is in declining health and is mentally ill. He has no
family and a limited income. Mike would appreciate a hoodie
sweatshirt, with pants to match, size M. Mike could also use some
socks, size 9-10, and boxers, size medium.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Robert, 88, lives in a nursing home and loves reading Western
novels to help pass the time. Robert could also use some sweat
suits, size large-tall, and a pair of men&apos;s slippers, size
9-1/2.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Rochelle, 1, needs clothes, size 18 months. She likes to play
with toy plastic food and musical toys. She has a new baby brother
on the way who will be born in January, so baby items for a boy
would be wonderful.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Justin, 12, lives in a group home. He needs jeans, size 12, and
shirts in medium large. He could use tennis shoes, size 10-1/2. He
likes wrestling figures, especially Iron Man. He also likes to
draw.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Steve, 77, lives alone. He does not have children, and his
siblings live far away. Steve would love a new pair of brown
leather loafers, size 9-12, and snap-front shirts, size 16-1/2.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Sam, a disabled veteran, loves to listen to classic rock,
especially Aerosmith. He needs bathroom towels and toiletries. He
would also like twin-size bedding and sheets.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Jim, a veteran, could use toiletries and clothing. He wears
pants, size 30x36, and medium shirts.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Cory, 5, and Carol, 7, are in a long-term foster placement. Cory
wears a 5T. He would love a train that would be age-appropriate.
Carol wears pants, size 10 slim, and size 10 shirts. She needs
winter clothes. Carol would enjoy any crafts or art sets. Both
could use winter coats with gloves and hats.

 Children&apos;s Protective Services, 2525 Fourth Ave. N.,
Suite 309, 657-3120 

Jerry is an elderly veteran with contagious energy and a love of
life. He enjoys getting out in the community and would enjoy some
dress gloves, dress socks, laundry soap and toiletries.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

Lorraine, an elderly woman, would love to have new twin-size
sheets and bedding. Her mobility is impaired, and she loves
slippers to keep her feet warm and comforters to wrap up in.

 Adult Protective Services, 

 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D, 655-7640 

George, an elderly gentleman, enjoys staying warm. He would like
some large sweaters and large slippers and socks.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 

Stan enjoys the outdoors. Flannel shirts are a favorite, and
toiletries are always needed. He also needs black cotton socks. He
wears size large.

 Adult Protective Services, 2121 Rosebud Drive, Suite D,
655-7640 
 
Contact Donna Healy at dhealy@billingsgazette.com or 657-1292.
 
Tags
 St. Vincent De :paul , Salvation Army , Family Service , Inc. , Montana Rescue Mission , Adult Protective Services , Child And Family Services , Community Hope , Empty Stockings , Montana Rescue Mission Women&apos;s And Family Shelter , Head Start , Ywca , Christmas Donations View (0) Comments 
No Comments Posted.
 
Add Comment
 
You must Login to comment.

 Click here to get an account it&apos;s free and quick
 
Related Stories
 
 
 Billings man&apos;s health casts shadow on Christmas season 
 
 
More News stories
 
 
 Mostly sunny, hot Thursday in store for Billings region 
 
 Naumann to be awarded Rankin Peace Prize 
 
 Montana to Myanmar: Libraries join professor&apos;s effort to help Asian nation 
 
 Relay for Life event strolling in this weekend 
 
 
Recommendations
 
Sponsored Links
 
 Copyright 2012 The Billings Gazette. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 
Follow The Billings Gazette
 
Facebook
 
Like The Billings Gazette on Facebook
 
Twitter
 
Follow The Billings Gazette on Twitter
 Follow @billingsgazette 
Google+
 
+1 The Billings Gazette on Google+
 
Pinterest
 
Follow The Billings Gazette on Pinterest
 
Email
 
Get email updates from The Billings Gazette

 Email Updates 
 
Text Messaging
 
Get text message updates from The Billings Gazette

 Text Updates 
 
RSS
 
Follow The Billings Gazette via RSS

 RSS Feeds 
 
Trending Stories
 
 Most Read Commented Shared 
 
 1 2 killed, 1 injured in rollover accident on Interstate 90 2 5-year-old boy shot in Heights, undergoes surgery 3 Coroner identifies 2 men killed in Saturday rollover on I-90 4 Plentywood man dies after alleged shooting involving police 5 Man who helped shooting victim says 5-year-old is improving 
 More 
 1 Rehberg blames housing bust on federal government (124) 2 Obama is foisting an unwanted plan on us (85) 3 5-year-old boy shot in Heights, undergoes surgery (80) 4 Guest Opinion: Affordable Care Act similar to earlier conservative proposal (70) 5 Rehberg, Tester differ on legislating campaign-spending disclosure (53) 
 More Latest comments 
Top Stories
 
 7 hrs ago 
 Montana to Myanmar: Libraries join professor&apos;s effort to help Asian nation 
 8 hrs ago 
 Big Sky Resort’s latest thrill-seeking activities take visitors to new heights 
 10 hrs ago 
 House farm bill draws Montana concern 
 13 hrs ago 
 Kids find cool river relief from heat wave 
 17 hrs ago 
 Romney raises money in Montana 
 
 
Deals&amp;Offers
 
 Bret Hidreth is your full service realtor serving south central Montana. 

Contact Brett today at 406-861-0081 or visit his web site www.…
 
 New Downtown Drop-In Daycare Location opening 08/01/2012 

Big Sky Imaginarium
 
Featured Businesses
 
 Pro Install 
 
 Rural Broadband 
 
 Brewer Dental Center-Kevin M Brewer DDS 
 
 Billings Parents On The Go 
 
 Cleaveland Sewer&amp;Excavation, LLC 
 Find a local business I&apos;m looking for: Located near: 
 Hint: Enter a keyword that you are looking for like tires, pizza or doctors or browse the full business directory , powered by Local.com 
 
Classifieds
 
 Jobs Cars Homes 
 Local advertising by PaperG 
Services

 Subscriber Services Advertise Contact Us About Us Mobile Site 

Other Websites

 Sell It MT Today&apos;s Deal Thrifty Nickel Magic City Magazine Billings Business ReDiscover Montana Welcome Home Montana Land Magazine Special Sections 
 ©Copyright 2012, The Billings Gazette , Billings, MT | Terms of Service and Privacy Policy | Find Area Businesses 
Find Area Businesses
 
 Billings Apartments Billings Attorneys Billings Auto Dealers Billings Auto Parts Billings Auto Repair Billings Beauty Salons Billings Car Rental Billings Dentists Billings Doctors Billings Flowers Billings Hotels Billings Insurance Billings Loans Billings Mortgages Billings Movers Billings Pizza Billings Realtors Billings Restaurants Billings Storage Billings Tax Preparation Billings Travel More Billings… Lockwood Apartments Lockwood Attorneys Lockwood Auto Dealers Lockwood Auto Parts Lockwood Auto Repair Lockwood Beauty Salons Lockwood Car Rental Lockwood Dentists Lockwood Doctors Lockwood Flowers Lockwood Hotels Lockwood Insurance Lockwood Loans Lockwood Mortgages Lockwood Movers Lockwood Pizza Lockwood Realtors Lockwood Restaurants Lockwood Storage Lockwood Tax Preparation Lockwood Travel More Lockwood… Laurel Apartments Laurel Attorneys Laurel Auto Dealers Laurel Auto Parts Laurel Auto Repair Laurel Beauty Salons Laurel Car Rental Laurel Dentists Laurel Doctors Laurel Flowers Laurel Hotels Laurel Insurance Laurel Loans Laurel Mortgages Laurel Movers Laurel Pizza Laurel Realtors Laurel Restaurants Laurel Storage Laurel Tax Preparation Laurel Travel More Laurel… Featured 
 × 
Join the conversation
 
 Login Signup 
 
Use your existing billingsgazette.com account or a previously connected Facebook account.
 
Login with billingsgazette.com account:
 
Email&amp;Password Required!
 Email: Password: Remember me on this computer Forgot Password Please Wait… Login
	</body>
</document>
