<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000278" url="http://reviews.opentable.com/0938/24304/reviews.htm" time="2012-07-12-15:28" support="3" score="0.004163245323064711" bingtitle="la Posta Reviews - Rated by OpenTable Diners" webtitle="la Posta Reviews - Rated by OpenTable Diners">
			<query id="001267" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="001424" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="001013" bing-rank="208"/>
	<description>Avenue Santa Cruz, CA 95062 la Posta serves fresh, seasonal meals with authentic ... Great food, great selection of Italian wines! &quot;</description>
	<body>
		Restaurant Reservations - Free•Instant•Confirmed Home Mobile Help Learn More Print this page Restaurant Reviews Restaurant reviews by area Alabama Anchorage Arkansas Atlanta / Georgia Atlantic City Austin Baltimore / Maryland Boston / New England Calgary / Alberta California Central Coast Big Sur (113) Monterey / Carmel (3,284) Ojai (212) Pismo Beach (247) San Luis Obispo / Paso Robles (1,663) Santa Barbara (1,676) Santa Cruz / Capitola / Aptos (1,394) Aptos (7) Capitola (483) Santa Cruz (809) American (72) Californian (27) Contemporary American (266) Indian (5) Irish (4) Italian (172) Mediterranean (119) Mexican (17) Seafood (127) Soquel (68) Watsonville (27) Santa Ynez Valley (981) Caribbean Charlotte Chicago / Illinois Cincinnati / Dayton Cleveland / Akron / Canton Coastal North Carolina Columbus Corpus Christi / McAllen Dallas - Fort Worth Denver / Colorado Detroit / Eastern Michigan East Tennessee Edmonton / Alberta El Paso / Southwest Texas Grand Rapids / Western Michigan Greensboro / Winston Salem / Highpoint Hawaii Houston Idaho Indiana Iowa Jackson Hole Jacksonville / Northeast Florida Kansas City Kentucky Key West / Florida Keys Lake of the Ozarks Las Vegas Los Angeles / Orange County Manitoba / Saskatchewan Memphis Miami / Southeast Florida Minneapolis - St. Paul Mississippi Montana Montreal / Quebec Nashville Nebraska New Mexico New Orleans / Louisiana New York / Tri-State Area North Dakota Northern Michigan / Upper Peninsula Northwest Florida Nova Scotia / New Brunswick Oklahoma Orlando / Central Florida East Palm Springs / Palm Desert Cities Philadelphia / New Jersey Suburbs Phoenix / Arizona Pinehurst Pittsburgh Portland / Oregon Raleigh / Durham / Chapel Hill Sacramento / Central Valley San Antonio San Diego San Francisco Bay Area Seattle / Eastern Washington South Carolina South Dakota Southwest Florida Southwest Indiana / Tri-State Area Springfield / Branson St. Louis Tahoe / Reno Area Tampa / Central Florida West Texas Panhandle Toledo Toronto / Ontario Utah Vancouver / British Columbia Virginia Washington, D.C. Area West Virginia Western North Carolina Wisconsin Find Restaurants in Your Area Select a Location 
 Alabama Amsterdam Anchorage Arkansas Atlanta / Georgia Atlantic City Austin Baltimore / Maryland Beirut Boston / New England Calgary / Alberta California Central Coast Caribbean Charlotte Chicago / Illinois Chihuahua Cincinnati / Dayton Cleveland / Akron / Canton Coastal North Carolina Columbus Corpus Christi / McAllen Dallas - Fort Worth Denver / Colorado Detroit / Eastern Michigan East Tennessee Edmonton / Alberta El Paso / Southwest Texas Grand Rapids / Western Michigan Greensboro / Winston Salem / Highpoint Hawaii Houston Idaho Indiana Iowa Jackson Hole Jacksonville / Northeast Florida Kansas City Kentucky Key West / Florida Keys Lake of the Ozarks Las Vegas Los Angeles / Orange County Malaysia Manitoba / Saskatchewan Memphis Miami / Southeast Florida Minneapolis - St. Paul Mississippi Montana Montreal / Quebec Nashville Nebraska New Mexico New Orleans / Louisiana New York / Tri-State Area North Dakota Northern Michigan / Upper Peninsula Northwest Florida Nova Scotia / New Brunswick Oklahoma Orlando / Central Florida East Palm Springs / Palm Desert Cities Philadelphia / New Jersey Suburbs Phoenix / Arizona Pinehurst Pittsburgh Portland / Oregon Raleigh / Durham / Chapel Hill Sacramento / Central Valley San Antonio San Diego San Francisco Bay Area Seattle / Eastern Washington South Carolina South Dakota Southwest Florida Southwest Indiana / Tri-State Area Springfield / Branson St. Louis Tahoe / Reno Area Tampa / Central Florida West Texas Panhandle Toledo Toronto / Ontario Utah Vancouver / British Columbia Villa de Muerte Virginia Washington, D.C. Area West Virginia Western North Carolina Wisconsin 
 Reserve now: Reserve Now on OpenTable.com la Posta Reservations Restaurant Reviews List &gt; California Central Coast Restaurant Reviews &gt; Santa Cruz / Capitola / Aptos Restaurant Reviews &gt; Santa Cruz Restaurant Reviews &gt; Italian Restaurant Reviews 
 la Posta Reviews List 
 
 la Posta 
 538 Seabright Avenue
Santa Cruz, CA 95062

la Posta serves fresh, seasonal meals with authentic Italian style. Join us for dinner and select from our pan-Italian menu which features fresh, house-made pastas, brick-oven breads, pizzas, and salumi.
We strive to present meals that are farmed and harvested sustainably. Because we serve local and organic ingredients, depending upon the bounty of Santa Cruz&apos; farming community, our menu changes frequently and features an wide array of specials. La Posta’s all-Italian wine list offers a baker’s dozen of wines by the glass or taste, the well informed list includes autochthonous varieties from artisan producers throughout Italy.
La Posta adheres to the Monterey Bay Aquarium Seafood Watch and is certified in the City of Santa Cruz Green Business Program.

 Dining Style: Casual Dining
 Price: $30 and under
 Parking: Private Lot
 Cross Street: Murray
 See more la Posta details 140 Current Reviews Summary of Diner Ratings&amp;Reviews Overall (Outstanding) 4.5 / 5 (140 Reviews) Rating Breakdown 140 reviews 5 stars (80) 4 stars (45) 3 stars (14) 2 stars (1) 1 star (0) Food (Outstanding) 4.5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 4.4 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 4 / 5 Noise Level Energetic Read all 140 reviews Write a review Filter Reviews By: Diners classify this restaurant as: 
 neighborhood gem (104) fit for foodies (97) notable wine list (59) 

 special occasion (49) romantic (39) hot spot (17) 
 see more Sort By Featured Reviews Newest Oldest Highest Rating Lowest Rating Longest Shortest la Posta Reviews List Review 1 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 La Posta consistently serves 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 07/08/2012 2004 Dined on 07/08/2012 2004 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; La Posta consistently serves up some of the best food in Santa Cruz. Although the menu is not terribly long, the choices are always interesting and feature local ingredients prepared by an expert hand. Our party of four enjoyed one of their incredible thin crust pizzas as an appetizer, which was out of this world. (A great bottle of Italian wine as an accompaniment didn&apos;t hurt!) Two of us had one of their house-made pastas--a triangular shaped ravioli that melted in your mouth. I had the tri tip and my dining partner the ling cod. We all cleaned our plates. We split desserts, fresh peach sorbet and a lemon pound cake with lemon verbena gelato. Delicious! I highly recommend La Posta for a fine dining experience in a casual setting. &quot; Dined on 07/08/2012 2004 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 2 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 excellent meal topped off 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 07/08/2012 2006 Dined on 07/08/2012 2006 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; excellent meal topped off with an out-of-this-world cherry compote. heaven! &quot; Dined on 07/08/2012 2006 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 3 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 La Posta is my favorite Seabright 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 07/01/2012 2005 Dined on 07/01/2012 2005 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; La Posta is my favorite Seabright dinner place. Great food, wine and friendly service! &quot; Dined on 07/01/2012 2005 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 4 for la Posta Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Great food, good service. 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/24/2012 2011 Dined on 06/24/2012 2011 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Great food, good service. Only a couple veg options, but they rotate. Seasonal specials were wonderful. &quot; Dined on 06/24/2012 2011 Special Features: neighborhood gem , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 5 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Lovely stop in Italy 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/22/2012 2005 Dined on 06/22/2012 2005 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Wonderful wine list and wait staff. My pizza was a bit soggy in the center, but the surrounding crust was thin and crunchy. &quot; Dined on 06/22/2012 2005 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 6 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 wonderful staff, great food, 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/15/2012 2010 Dined on 06/15/2012 2010 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; wonderful staff, great food, always a treat &quot; Dined on 06/15/2012 2010 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 7 for la Posta Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 A very nice experience. However, 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/17/2012 2008 Dined on 06/17/2012 2008 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; A very nice experience. However, the short menu guarantees that I won&apos;t return often. Only four entree choices seems limited (Secondi piatti section of the menu). My group ordered three of those choices and all were excellent (we each shared and compared). My ling cod was especially nice. The lamb meatballs were as tasty as bolognese meatballs. And the gnocchi was among the best ever, al dente and flavorful. We also enjoyed a quattro cheese pizza in the Tuscan style. But a salad of asparagus that we ordered to share was disappointing. We did not try dessert as it was waiting for us at home. On the wine list we also ordered the tasting flight of Italian wines. It was very good. We were taken aback by the lack of ice tea as a beverag &quot; Dined on 06/17/2012 2008 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 8 for la Posta Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Great for Anniversary Dinner 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/16/2012 2012 Dined on 06/16/2012 2012 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; My husband and I enjoyed the ambiance...thinking the 5:45 slot was a good idea, for it wasn&apos;t too crowded. The service was great and the different dishes were brought at just the right times. We enjoyed every course. I had the veal meatballs, and my husband the chicken with fava beans, and both had delicious flavors. We&apos;d go again, and recommend it to friends and family. &quot; Dined on 06/16/2012 2012 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 9 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Great dining experience. 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/16/2012 2002 Dined on 06/16/2012 2002 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; Great dining experience. The food was wonderful. Had a lovely bottle of wine from Sicily and our waiter was a sweetie!! &quot; Dined on 06/16/2012 2002 Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 10 for la Posta Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Awesome, can&apos;t wait to go back! 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/15/2012 2004 Dined on 06/15/2012 2004 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; These folks know how to cook pasta correctly, al dente! And the pizza is exceptionally authentic, with a thin crust and not a ton of cheese and perfect tomato sauce. The gnocci was out of this world good! &quot; Dined on 06/15/2012 2004 Special Features: good for groups , neighborhood gem Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 11 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 The noise ratings are not 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/12/2012 2012 Dined on 06/12/2012 2012 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; The noise ratings are not totally honest. Quiet and moderate are reasonable. Energetic? What&apos;s that? There was no rating for&quot;loud&quot;which it was. It was also nearly a full house, so understandable, to a degree. The music is always a great pleasure. Noise aside it&apos;s a great restaurant. &quot; Dined on 06/12/2012 2012 Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 12 for la Posta Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 Good but not good enough 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/10/2012 2012 Dined on 06/10/2012 2012 Food (Fair) 2 / 5 Service (Fair) 2 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; The waiter seemed nervous and struggled with pronunciation of items on the menu. Our group was unfamiliar with many menu items and he seemed to also struggle with his explanations. Drinks and appetizers were excellent. 3 out 4 in the party ordered the same dish and they were all satisfied. One person ordered a pasta special which was to include roasted romanesco. The noodles were not warm enough, over cooked and plated like a towering pile of mush. The romanesco felt and tasted boiled- poor texture and missing the delicate nutty flavor and mild char from roasting. It also lacked seasoning and savoriness. I would return to this restautant for a second chance but I&apos;m not sure my company is willing. &quot; Dined on 06/10/2012 2012 Special Features: fit for foodies , notable wine list , romantic Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 13 for la Posta Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 Surprised to be Disappointed 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/10/2012 2006 Dined on 06/10/2012 2006 Food (Good) 3 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Everything about this little gem restaurant seemed to be perfect. Excellent appetizers and salads, delicious home-made bread, very decent red house wine for fair value, great dessert and coffee. What disappointed us were the entrees. We had Tagliatelle and the Roasted Ling Cod. Both were presented well, but seemed uninspired and bland. We were candidly stunned based on the recommendations and lead-in to the meal. Maybe it was because it was a Sunday night. &quot; Dined on 06/10/2012 2006 Special Features: neighborhood gem , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 14 for la Posta Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Had a great dinner there with 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/09/2012 2006 Dined on 06/09/2012 2006 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Had a great dinner there with another couple. Had a couple bottles of the very reasonable and refreshing white house wine, shared a couple appetizers and then each had a primo or pizza. We also shared a couple desserts. It was a perfectly satisfying meal and we were enjoying ourselves/our conversation so much, we didn&apos;t notice the noise level mentioned in some reviews--and noisy places usually do bother me. The service did not make us feel rushed so we enjoyed a leisurely meal. The restaurant was full when we arrived with a reservation at 7:15 on a Saturday, but our table was waiting for us. By the time we left, it had emptied out considerably. &quot; Dined on 06/09/2012 2006 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 15 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Santa Cruz&apos;s best retaurant. 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/09/2012 2008 Dined on 06/09/2012 2008 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Good) 3 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; The best meal I have ever had in Santa Cruz. The food was outstanding, fresh, locally sourced and exquisite preperations. Great Italian wines and save room for dessert. &quot; Dined on 06/09/2012 2008 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 16 for la Posta Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 GREAT PASTAS AND SALADS AND 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/09/2012 2008 Dined on 06/09/2012 2008 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; GREAT PASTAS AND SALADS AND ANTIPASTI &quot; Dined on 06/09/2012 2008 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 17 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 La Posta is one of our favorite 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/08/2012 2010 Dined on 06/08/2012 2010 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; La Posta is one of our favorite little place to go and it never fails to please us. Small menu, great Italian wines. We recommend it to our friends all the time. the only thing I would like to be different is to have more of their fabulous bread. It&apos;s addictive. Vegetarian to Carnivore you won be disappointed. &quot; Dined on 06/08/2012 2010 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 18 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 We gomto la posta regularly 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/03/2012 2007 Dined on 06/03/2012 2007 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; We gomto la posta regularly and think it just keeps getting better. We had just ordered the other night when some friends walked in. Patrice found a table for four for us even though theybwere busy. Our waiter, Noah, slowed our order and we all had a great time. Top notch all the way &quot; Dined on 06/03/2012 2007 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 19 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Always excellent food and 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 06/03/2012 2005 Dined on 06/03/2012 2005 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Always excellent food and friendly staff! My favorite restaurant in Santa Cruz and I can walk to it:) &quot; Dined on 06/03/2012 2005 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 20 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 The menu is fresh, seasonal 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/27/2012 2005 Dined on 05/27/2012 2005 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; The menu is fresh, seasonal and interesting. The waitstaff if outstanding -- personable and knowledgeable about both the food and wine. &quot; Dined on 05/27/2012 2005 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 21 for la Posta Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 Considering the price, we 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/25/2012 2005 Dined on 05/25/2012 2005 Food (Fair) 2 / 5 Service (Good) 3 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Considering the price, we were not impressed by the food. The atmosphere was relaxing and it seemed like a good place to go and have a glass of wine with a good friend. &quot; Dined on 05/25/2012 2005 Special Features: kid-friendly , neighborhood gem Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 22 for la Posta Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 First time. Nice place, will 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/25/2012 2006 Dined on 05/25/2012 2006 Food (Good) 3 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; First time. Nice place, will try again. Special salad and desserts were excellent. Special pasta of the evening was ok nothing special. Partly due to a misunderstanding. Whenb the server described it, we heard fava beans and she said fava greens. So when it arrived it was not what we expected and had we heard correctly we would not have ordered it. Maybe the specials should be printed out rather than oral. &quot; Dined on 05/25/2012 2006 Special Features: neighborhood gem Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 23 for la Posta Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 I love la posta and always 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/22/2012 2012 Dined on 05/22/2012 2012 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; I love la posta and always go there if I am staying in the area several days...it is a real Italian restaurant! Last visit the salmon was a bit over cooked for my liking but other than that all was delicious! &quot; Dined on 05/22/2012 2012 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 24 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 My newest Santa Cruz favorite, 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/19/2012 2005 Dined on 05/19/2012 2005 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; My newest Santa Cruz favorite, second to Soif, also owned by Patrice. &quot; Dined on 05/19/2012 2005 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 25 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Seabright Gem 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/11/2012 2005 Dined on 05/11/2012 2005 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Love having La Posta in the neighborhood. The food is creative, local and seasonal, and with few exceptions always very good. They have an interesting wine list and they&apos;ll let you taste a couple before you choose. Their bread is great too! It&apos;s perfect for a date and comfortable with my kids. I&apos;ll even go alone once in a while and it&apos;s great. Tuesday night is neighborhood night with live music and a complimentary glass of wine with pizza and pasta. It&apos;s busy and noisy, maybe not great for a first date that night, but it&apos;s fun. &quot; Dined on 05/11/2012 2005 Special Features: fit for foodies , kid-friendly , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 26 for la Posta Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Wonderful food and service; 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/10/2012 2012 Dined on 05/10/2012 2012 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; Wonderful food and service; everything was top-notch. Bread and pizza are the best we&apos;ve ever had. Thanks! &quot; Dined on 05/10/2012 2012 Special Features: fit for foodies Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 27 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Love the Tuesday night neighborhood 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/08/2012 2012 Dined on 05/08/2012 2012 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Love the Tuesday night neighborhood specials. Your bread is fantastic! Unique and delicious pizza. &quot; Dined on 05/08/2012 2012 Special Features: neighborhood gem , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 28 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 This was the nicest dining 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/08/2012 2012 Dined on 05/08/2012 2012 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; This was the nicest dining out experience we have had for quite awhile. The atmosphere was warm, friendly, elegant in a simple way. Our waiter was lovely and professional. The food was terrific. And the musicians that were playing there that Tuesday night were excellent and provided the perfect backdrop. We will definitely go back again and tell our friends to check out La Posta! &quot; Dined on 05/08/2012 2012 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , romantic , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 29 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 This was my third dining at 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/04/2012 2011 Dined on 05/04/2012 2011 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; This was my third dining at La Posta. Since my girlfriend ad I are college students(on a tight budget) we usualy reserve dining at La Posta on special occasions. I was really excited to see what they had on their menu since it changes everytime i go there. I ordered the Pork Belly and i have to say that it was the best thing that i have had there. It tasted so good and it reminded me of my mom&apos;s mexican cooking which made it extra specal. I finished my plate very quickly. the waiters where really nice and I have seen them before. I went there around 6pm so there was no noise. Great place. &quot; Dined on 05/04/2012 2011 Special Features: romantic , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 30 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Discovered this wonderful 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/04/2012 2010 Dined on 05/04/2012 2010 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; Discovered this wonderful restaurant (via TripAdvisor and OpenTable) while visiting the Monterey peninsula. The food/service was superb. What a treat! Only thing lacking is a coastal view, but the food artistry more than made up for that! &quot; Dined on 05/04/2012 2010 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 31 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 always delicious, attentive 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 05/01/2012 2010 Dined on 05/01/2012 2010 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; always delicious, attentive service and a fun experience. &quot; Dined on 05/01/2012 2010 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , special occasion , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 32 for la Posta Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 The atmosphere was nice but 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/27/2012 2012 Dined on 04/27/2012 2012 Food (Good) 3 / 5 Service (Good) 3 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; The atmosphere was nice but the food was honestly a bit disappointing. We ordered a pizza and a pasta dish - the pizza was tasty but the toppings slid right off when you picked up a slice and the pasta was very bland with only one asparagus chopped up into tiny pieces on top. We expected more vegetables and more flavorful food for the amount of money we spent. We appreciate the fact that the food is local and organic but think that the execution leaves something to be desired. &quot; Dined on 04/27/2012 2012 Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 33 for la Posta Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Food was delicious. Service 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/27/2012 2004 Dined on 04/27/2012 2004 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Good) 3 / 5 Ambiance (Good) 3 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Food was delicious. Service was OK, waited a bit between courses but the waiter was very helpful with the menu. &quot; Dined on 04/27/2012 2004 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 34 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Noah, our waiter, was wonderful 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/27/2012 2012 Dined on 04/27/2012 2012 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Noah, our waiter, was wonderful and very helpful with great suggestions for dining and wine selection. &quot; Dined on 04/27/2012 2012 Special Features: neighborhood gem Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 35 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Always a treat to dine at 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/25/2012 2009 Dined on 04/25/2012 2009 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; Always a treat to dine at Santa Cruz&apos; best! Imaginative pasta dishes using homemade noodles. Creative ingredients like kumquats and wild nettles. Pizzas for casual dining great for a crowd. &quot; Dined on 04/25/2012 2009 Special Features: neighborhood gem Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 36 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 A wonderful little Italian 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/24/2012 2012 Dined on 04/24/2012 2012 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; A wonderful little Italian place. The food is delightful, being a 23 year old male I could dream of larger portions but for most I feel that is not a problem. The food is also reasonable priced for the quality local ingredients and taste. Tuesday nights even have a deal where you can get a pasta dish or a personal pizza and a glass of the house red for $15 (not to mention live music performed by the Rangells). I don&apos;t care who you are for a place like this that is a fantastic deal. That being said I am one who enjoys buying a bottle of wine. For a young man the wine list is as much as I can navigate, but all my selections to date have been most enjoyable. A great place for a top notch evening. &quot; Dined on 04/24/2012 2012 Special Features: neighborhood gem Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 37 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Great find 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/21/2012 2008 Dined on 04/21/2012 2008 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; We loved the specials, the Meyer lemon ice cream and poached rhubarb was great. &quot; Dined on 04/21/2012 2008 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 38 for la Posta Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 we come here often (it&apos;s our 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/21/2012 2007 Dined on 04/21/2012 2007 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; we come here often (it&apos;s our favorite restaurant) and sometimes bring out of towners who are used to excellent restaurants, as we did this time, but usually don&apos;t come on Saturday night. it was quite crowded but our food was waay too slow to arrive at the table. it didn&apos;t help that our server came a few times to apologize. we should have been comped something. it was embarrassing and a very long wait. Our friends had a long drive home and it was a late one because of the delay (and we didn&apos;t order dessert because of it). &quot; Dined on 04/21/2012 2007 Special Features: fit for foodies , hot spot Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 39 for la Posta Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 Disappointed this time. 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/15/2012 2011 Dined on 04/15/2012 2011 Food (Good) 3 / 5 Service (Poor) 1 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; In the past I&apos;ve had excellent meals and service at La Posta. I&apos;ve recommended the restaurant. However, this time the service was inexpert. When the waitress removed my salad plate, she plunked the eating utensils that had food on them back on the bare tabletop for me to re-use. When my companion and I told her that the Tokyo turnip greens of our vegetable course were almost impossible to cut with a knife and too tough and chewy to eat, her response was the equivalent of&quot;Oh?&quot; &quot; Dined on 04/15/2012 2011 Special Features: notable wine list Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 40 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Santa Cruz&apos;s very best! 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/12/2012 2006 Dined on 04/12/2012 2006 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Hands down my favorite restaurant in Santa Cruz &quot; Dined on 04/12/2012 2006 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , romantic , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 41 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Check out the specially priced 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 03/31/2012 2008 Dined on 03/31/2012 2008 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Check out the specially priced pizza and pasta options on Tuesday nights. &quot; Dined on 03/31/2012 2008 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 42 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 Just had Easter dinner at 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/08/2012 2010 Dined on 04/08/2012 2010 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; Just had Easter dinner at La Posta and were wowed even more than usual by the combination of food, wine, and service! This is our favorite restaurant in the Santa Cruz area and we keep coming back rather than exploring other places because the food and value are so good. keep up the good work Chef Katherine and staff! &quot; Dined on 04/08/2012 2010 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , romantic , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 43 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 The asparagus, beet and kumquat 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/08/2012 2009 Dined on 04/08/2012 2009 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Quiet &quot; The asparagus, beet and kumquat salad was delicious. Both the cannelloni with lamb and the lamb and greens were yummy. The Cannanou wine from Sardinia was full bodied, round and fruity. Would drink it again anywhere. The service was attentive without being too much. I have eaten a number of good meals at La Posta, but this may have been the best ever. &quot; Dined on 04/08/2012 2009 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 44 for la Posta Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 This was our best meal ever 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/06/2012 2002 Dined on 04/06/2012 2002 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Good) 3 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; This was our best meal ever at La Posta, now rivaling our favorite neighborhood places in san Francisco. The interior has been upgraded since our last visit, and we found it now very comfortable. It is now back on our must visit list every time we are in town &quot; Dined on 04/06/2012 2002 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 45 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 La Posta is one of the 2 or 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 04/01/2012 2006 Dined on 04/01/2012 2006 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; La Posta is one of the 2 or 3 best restaurants in Santa Cruz. Food is always good,
ambience is terrific -- casual but at the same time calm and elegant. &quot; Dined on 04/01/2012 2006 Special Features: neighborhood gem , romantic , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 46 for la Posta Overall rating (Outstanding) 5 / 5 
 A favorite place to take friends 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 03/31/2012 2006 Dined on 03/31/2012 2006 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; A favorite place to take friends from out of town. We were very happy with our choices, including an amazing asparagus salad with beets, pistachios and ricotta salata, two steaks, one lamb entree and one halibut. One of the steak eaters was a little disappointed, but cleaned his plate anyway. This restaurant is just right;great food that doesn&apos;t try too hard. &quot; Dined on 03/31/2012 2006 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , romantic , special occasion Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 47 for la Posta Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Great food, great selection 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 03/24/2012 2003 Dined on 03/24/2012 2003 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; Great food, great selection of Italian wines! &quot; Dined on 03/24/2012 2003 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem , notable wine list Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 48 for la Posta Overall rating (Good) 3 / 5 
 our wait service was great 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 03/31/2012 2007 Dined on 03/31/2012 2007 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Poor) 1 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Moderate &quot; our wait service was great but for 2nd time in two weeks the wait between appetizers and main course was unusually long. Kitchen needs to get their act together &quot; Dined on 03/31/2012 2007 Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 49 for la Posta Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 Excellent meal and wine 
 
 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 03/31/2012 2005 Dined on 03/31/2012 2005 Food (Very Good) 4 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; In town for the SC Half Marathon. Had a lovely dinner at La Posta. The service was great, the atmosphere was just right, and the food was fresh, seasonal, and delicious. The sausage and lentil dish was excellent, as was the butermilk panna cota. The server helped us choose a bottle of red from the Italian wine list that was one of the most enjoyable bottles I&apos;ve had recently in a restaurant. A perfect meal with a very reasonable price tag. Can&apos;t ask for much more. &quot; Dined on 03/31/2012 2005 Special Features: fit for foodies , good for groups , neighborhood gem , notable wine list Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. Review 50 for la Posta Overall rating (Very Good) 4 / 5 
 The food is very good but 
 OpenTable Diner Since Dined on 03/24/2012 2009 Dined on 03/24/2012 2009 Food (Outstanding) 5 / 5 Service (Very Good) 4 / 5 Ambiance (Very Good) 4 / 5 Noise Level Energetic &quot; The food is very good but I wish they would do something to lower the noise level. I had a difficult time hearing my dinning companion. &quot; Dined on 03/24/2012 2009 Special Features: fit for foodies , neighborhood gem Share: 0 points 0 of 0 voted this as helpful. Thank you! You have successfully submitted a comment for this review. 1 2 next &gt;&gt;
	</body>
</document>
