<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000857" url="http://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g34778-d1188675-Reviews-Kentucky_Fried_Chicken-Blue_Ridge_Georgia.html" time="2012-07-12-16:13" support="1" score="0.0014575296994535911" bingtitle="Kentucky Fried Chicken, Blue Ridge - Restaurant Reviews - TripAdvisor" webtitle="Kentucky Fried Chicken, Blue Ridge - Restaurant Reviews - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="000595" bing-rank="214"/>
	<description>Ordered three different items they were out of everything after waiting 20 min for them to cook my food and complete my order I got all the way home I find out ...</description>
	<body>
		Kentucky Fried Chicken, Blue Ridge
 
 Home Blue Ridge 
 Blue Ridge Tourism Blue Ridge Hotels Blue Ridge Vacation Rentals Flights to Blue Ridge Blue Ridge Restaurants Things to Do in Blue Ridge Blue Ridge Travel Forum Blue Ridge Photos Blue Ridge Travel Guide 
 Hotels Flights Vacation Rentals Restaurants Things to Do Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
 Home 
 &gt; United States &gt; Georgia (GA) &gt; Blue Ridge &gt; Blue Ridge Restaurants &gt; Kentucky Fried Chicken 
 
 All 30 Blue Ridge Restaurants» 
Kentucky Fried Chicken
 4860 Appalachian Highway , Blue Ridge , GA 30513 (706) 258-3692 Website Menu Got a photo? 
 Add it. Ranked #30 of 30 restaurants in Blue Ridge 11 Reviews Cuisines: Fast Food Restaurant details Update restaurant details Write a Review 
11 reviews from our community
 27% Recommend 
 Excellent 3 Very good 0 Average 2 Poor 2 Terrible 4 
 Rating summary 
 Food Service Value Atmosphere 
 11 reviews sorted by Date Rating English first Any gerigp Cumming, Georgia 2 reviews Reviews in 2 cities 1 helpful vote “Wasre of Time and Money” Reviewed May 26, 2012 
We use to stop here sometime and it was good but the last couple of times it was terrible. Today when we stopped there was hardly and food on the buffet. ISilly me I thought when you went to a buffet you didn&apos;t have to ask for every piece of food you wanted. There was no chicken, no biscuits, no... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? CorvetteC6 Georgia Contributor 20 reviews Reviews in 13 cities 5 helpful votes “Fried food!” Reviewed April 27, 2012 
The buffet wasn&apos;t very well kept. It just looked unappetizing because of the way the food was organized. Taste was okay - certainly not impressive.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 2 more reviews by CorvetteC6 for Blue Ridge The_Hungry_Doctor Lawrenceville Senior Reviewer 6 reviews Reviews in 3 cities “It is KFC...” Reviewed April 24, 2012 
It was OK... it is a KFC... not a 5-star restaurant. So... if you are looking for quick and cheaper food I guess this is for you.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 3 more reviews by The_Hungry_Doctor for Blue Ridge Robert P Mineral Bluff, Georgia Senior Contributor 39 reviews Reviews in 20 cities 12 helpful votes “Very Slow Service.” Reviewed April 22, 2012 
The usual KFC fare, but I find the service to be very slow almost all of the time, especially at lunch time, when you would expect there to be enough help. I think they have management issues.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 6 more reviews by Robert P for Blue Ridge George K Ducktown, Tennessee, United States Senior Contributor 41 reviews Reviews in 15 cities 9 helpful votes “Yuck,just yuck” Reviewed March 18, 2012 
Fast food,greasy from a warehouse.And the worse coleslaw on the planet.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 10 more reviews by George K for Blue Ridge yusopup turtletown 1 review “Don&apos;t go there” Reviewed March 7, 2012 
Mac&amp;cheese was so dry we give it our dog. All of the food was cold. I couldn&apos;t tell if the chicken was extra crispy or orginal. Used to like KFC but I won&apos;t go back. Don&apos;t worry about calling the 800 number, we did and it didn&apos;t do any good.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? bbqman3341 Gainesville, Georgia Top Contributor 319 reviews Reviews in 127 cities 1,138 helpful votes “all you can eat kfc” Reviewed August 10, 2011 1 person found this review helpful 
so what if the sides are less that fantastic, getting all you can eat orginal recipe and crunchy will make this a place you will enjoy coming back to when fried chicken is calling you name. call what you want to, just don;t call me late for supper. this is caravores delight, hot tasty all you want friend chicken. service... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 19 more reviews by bbqman3341 for Blue Ridge bbqman3341 has 1 more review of Kentucky Fried Chicken 
 “Hungry? all you can eat chicken BUFFET” Reviewed October 20, 2008 
 doggett34778 Blue Ridge, Georgia 1 review “DRIED OUT FOOD” Reviewed June 24, 2011 
spent $28.00 on dinner for 3 off the bar. there wasn&apos;t much of anything on the bar. we figured anytime more food would come out, but i notice customers requesting what they want, silverware, biscuits, chicken, the tea ran out and no one made any more.when we came in, we ask for chicken, and was told there was chicken out... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? unhappy30559 Mineral Bluff, Georgia 1 review “CONSISTANTLY TERRIBLE” Reviewed December 21, 2010 
Ordered three different items they were out of everything after waiting 20 min for them to cook my food and complete my order I got all the way home I find out they still did not get the order correct. so I drive all the way back to the store and show them the order is wrong and that what... More 
 
 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? angelsugar Dallas 1 review 2 helpful votes “Best of the best” Reviewed August 16, 2009 2 people found this review helpful 
I have eaten at many KFC restaurants across the country. Many with buffets ,some without. This by far is THE BEST! They have a good value and friendly atmosphere. The help genuinely try to accommodate the customer. We have a KFC in the town we live in with a buffet. They can&apos;t even begin to compare to the KFC in... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? 1-10 of 11 reviews « 1 2 » 
Travelers who viewed Kentucky Fried Chicken also viewed
 Harvest on Main 188 Reviews Blue Ridge, GA Blue Ridge Brewery 80 Reviews Blue Ridge, GA   L&amp;L;Beanery 80 Reviews Blue Ridge, GA Angelina&apos;s Italian Gourmet Market and Delicatessen 16 Reviews Blue Ridge, GA   All restaurants in Blue Ridge (30) 
Been to Kentucky Fried Chicken? Share your experiences!
 Write a Review Add Photos Add Videos 
Owners: What&apos;s your side of the story?

If you own or manage Kentucky Fried Chicken, register now for free tools to enhance your
listing, attract new reviews, and respond to reviewers.
 Manage your listing 
Hotels travelers are raving about...

 Blue Ridge Inn Bed and Breakfast 9 Reviews Read reviews Blue Ridge, GA The Last Resort 9 Reviews Read reviews Blue Ridge, GA Toccoa Valley Campground 4 Reviews Read reviews Blue Ridge, GA 
 All hotels in Blue Ridge (6) 
Browse nearby
 Restaurants (30) | Hotels (6) | Things to Do (17) Kentucky Fried Chicken 4860 Appalachian Highway Blue Ridge, GA 30513 Get Directions What&apos;s Nearby: Hotels Restaurants Things to Do Click map pins for more information. You are zoomed out too far to see location pins. Please zoom back in. Interactive map 
Traveler Photos&amp;Videos
 
 Chicken draining on paper towels NOTICE how nice this chicken looks By unhappy30559 Mineral Bluff, Georgia Grease in the bucket By unhappy30559 Mineral Bluff, Georgia 
 All Photos | Add photos | Add videos 
Popular Blue Ridge restaurants

 Harvest on Main L&amp;L;Beanery Angelina&apos;s Italian Gourmet Market and Delicatessen The Sweet Shoppe Blue Ridge Brewery Joe&apos;s BBQ The Vine Wine Bar&amp;Bistro Blue Orleans Bistro Serenity Garden Cafe Sue&apos;s Cafeteria&amp;Ice Cream Parlor Christy Lee&apos;s Courtyard Grille Great Eats Deli The Village Restaurant Blue Jeans Pizza and Pasta Factory Tin Loong Restaurant in Blue Ridge Bumble Bee&apos;s Cafe Royal Waffle KIng Circle J Family Steakhouse Blue Ridge Mountain Bar-B-Q Yellow Jacket Restaurant 
 
Hotels around Blue Ridge

 Bear Rock Ridge Bed&amp;Breakfast 4.0 out of 5, 5 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 BEST WESTERN Mountain View Inn 3.5 out of 5, 35 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 BEST WESTERN Inn - Murphy 4.5 out of 5, 21 reviews Last reviewed Jul 10, 2012 Serenity in the Mountains Luxury Suites 4.0 out of 5, 26 reviews Last reviewed Jul 7, 2012 Blue Ridge Inn Bed and Breakfast 4.5 out of 5, 9 reviews Last reviewed Jul 7, 2012 Comfort Inn&amp;Suites Blue Ridge 4.5 out of 5, 99 reviews Last reviewed Jun 30, 2012 Quality Inn Helen 4.0 out of 5, 113 reviews Last reviewed Jun 28, 2012 Days Inn Blue Ridge 2.0 out of 5, 43 reviews Last reviewed Jun 25, 2012 San-Ran Motel 3.5 out of 5, 14 reviews Last reviewed Jun 23, 2012 The Fernbrook Inn 4.5 out of 5, 8 reviews Last reviewed Jun 22, 2012 Horse Creek Stable Bed and Breakfast 5.0 out of 5, 14 reviews Last reviewed Jun 17, 2012 Above the Rest Cabins 4.5 out of 5, 86 reviews Last reviewed Jun 13, 2012 Comfort Suites 4.0 out of 5, 12 reviews Last reviewed Jun 12, 2012 Enota Mountain Retreat 4.5 out of 5, 151 reviews Last reviewed Jun 12, 2012 Mountain Top Cabins 4.0 out of 5, 26 reviews Last reviewed May 29, 2012 
 Explore the world Restaurants 
 Cuevas Pedro Antonio de Alarcon in Guadix 3.0 out of 5, 3 reviews T.G.I. Friday&apos;s in North Little Rock 4.0 out of 5, 8 reviews Indian Pavilion in Vienna 4.5 out of 5, 11 reviews Kiki&apos;s in Varadero 4.5 out of 5, 223 reviews Olive Garden in Orlando 4.0 out of 5, 77 reviews Cafe Hidalgo in Isla Mujeres 5.0 out of 5, 55 reviews 
 Hotels 
 The Diplomat Hotel in Prague 4.0 out of 5, 341 reviews Last reviewed Jul 10, 2012 iQ Hotel Roma in Rome 4.5 out of 5, 1,124 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 The Michelangelo Hotel in New York City 4.5 out of 5, 1,125 reviews Last reviewed Jul 12, 2012 Oberkirch Hotel Freiburg Im Breisgau 4.5 out of 5, 53 reviews Last reviewed Jul 9, 2012 
 About TripAdvisor® TripAdvisor®features reviews and advice on hotels, resorts, flights, vacation rentals, vacation packages, travel guides, and lots more. Reviews and advice on hotels, resorts, flights, vacation rentals, travel packages, and lots more! Select a TripAdvisor site: 
 
 About Us | Write a review | Careers | Site Map | Top Cities | Owners | Help Center | Business Listings | DMO/CVB | Investor Relations © 2012 TripAdvisor LLC All rights reserved. TripAdvisor Terms of Use and Privacy Policy . Some photos provided by VFM Leonardo. * TripAdvisor LLC is not a booking agent and does not charge any service fees to users of our site... ( more ) TripAdvisor LLC is not responsible for content on external web sites. Taxes, fees not included for deals content.
	</body>
</document>
