<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000969" url="http://inventorspot.com/articles/mcdonalds_ads_7005" time="2012-07-12-16:20" support="4" score="0.0033593134930217294" bingtitle="Hungry for Some Creative Advertising? 9 Satisfying McDonald&apos;s Ads" webtitle="Hungry for Some Creative Advertising? 9 Satisfying McDonalds Ads">
			<query id="000150" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000155" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000136" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="000151" bing-rank="139"/>
	<description>They were made of the same material as napkins and could actually be ripped off. ... was used to promote the new line of salads from your favorite fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Home » Articles Log in   •   Sign up   •   Subscribe  
 InventorSpot 
 
 Home Inventor Home Invention Info Invention Gallery Services Forum Products Contact Us 
 
Hungry for Some Creative Advertising? 9 Satisfying McDonald&apos;s Ads
 by Amy Gifford Tweet 


McDonald&apos;s is one of the largest fast food restaurants and one of the largest advertisers in the world. Obviously, they are doing something right with their advertising.

Here are 9 fun and creative ads from recent McDonald&apos;s advertising campaignsdesigned  to make you hungry for McDonald&apos;s:

1. Would you like fries with that?


McDonald&apos;s used traditional newspaper advertising throughout actual newspaper copy to showcase their famous french fries.

 

Source: Innovations in Newspaper 

2. Billboard...tough to shake

Even the pole that supports this large billboard was used to promote the triple thick shake from McDonald&apos;s.

 

Source: Brand Autopsy 

3. Big and Juicy

These large posters to promote the Big and Juicy Burger from McDonald&apos;s were used in transportation stations in Sweden. They were made of the same material as napkins and could actually be ripped off.

 

4. Big and Juicy, Part 2

McDonald&apos;s carried this same Big and Juicy campaign to newspaper by inserting over-sized napkins into the newspaper.

 

Source: Frederik Samuel 

5. Where the Green Grass Grows

A&quot;green&quot;billboard was used to promote the new line of salads from your favorite fast food restaurant.

 

Source: Frederik Samuel 

6. It&apos;s Hidden in the Shadows

This&quot;sundial&quot;billboard inChicago, uses the movement of the sun throughout the day to get their main message across...the McDonald&apos;s logo.

 

Source: Ads of the World 

7. Start Your Day Off Right

This morning newspaper ad ran with the caption: Try Our New Breakfast Sandwich.

 

Source: Ads of the World 

8. Tough Decisions

These ads were placed in the home and apartment listing section. The message?&quot;Don&apos;t make big decisions on an empty stomach. McDonald&apos;s. I&apos;m lovin&apos;it.&quot;

Note the volcano and rocket-ships!

 

 

Source: Advertising for Peanuts 

9. Cool Down

When McDonald&apos;s released their new line of iced coffee, they placed these blocks of ice with to go coffee mugs inside around Seattle. The copy read: Cold is Coming.

 

 

Source: Adverbox 

10. Fits Right In

This colorful McDonald&apos;s cheeseburger ad snuck right into the copy of this newspaper story.

 

Source: Advertising for Peanuts 


Do any of these ads make you want to go to McDonald&apos;s?

What do you think of their efforts to make their coffee, cheeseburgers and world famous french fries compelling?  Do you think this fast food advertiser is doing a good job of using  billboards, newspaper and other  ad mediums?

 Amy Gifford 
Featured Blogger
 InventorSpot.com 
 
  Mail to a friend 
  Subscribe to our feed 
  Follow us on Twitter 
 Filed under:

 Food and Drink Lifestyle Marketing Miscellaneous 
 Rock Band 2: Announced and Details Released Social Media&apos;s McRib Gets Raked Over The Coals Taking the High Road: Tibet Invests in 53 New School Buses The SousVide Supreme Water Oven Cooks Food To Perfection 
 Why Moderate Drinking May Defend Against Rheumatoid Arthritis 2012 MINI Cooper China Olympic Special Edition is No Green Bean Acer Releases Iconia Tab A700 – 10” Tablet with 1920x1200 Resolution SONY&apos;s New Cassette Tapes, Redesigned for the Old Generation 
 Comments Jan 23, 2008
by sir jorge (not verified)
 
 amazing 
 
they have the best graphic designers, but then again, they have deep pockets.
 Jan 24, 2008
by Ashley (not verified)
 
 Yes, I REALLY REALLY WANT 
 
Yes, I REALLY REALLY WANT MCDONALD&apos;S RIGHT NOW!

But I usually find their commercials and ads stupid.
The ads don&apos;t make me want to go eat there, I just love the food.
And their new slogan, &quot;I&apos;m lovin&apos; it&quot;, I hate it.

I miss &quot;Put a Smile on&quot;!

Maybe it&apos;s just me, but advertisements don&apos;t really affect my decisions. I&apos;m sure when I was younger, I was intrigued, for example, with McDonald&apos;s commercials, and although the above examples are really cool, I don&apos;t think I&apos;d say to myself, &quot;Hey, those ads are really cool so I should go eat there&quot;.

But for the majority of the world, I think it would work.
 Jan 28, 2008
by Anonymous (not verified)
 
 Do not want 
 
McDonalds advertising has all the charm of being covered in corn syrup&amp;stuck on a New York subway in August. I met a woman a few years ago at a party, who not only claimed to be the creator of the &quot;Smile&quot; campaign, but also claimed that it was her least-proud advertising moment.
 Aug 28, 2008
by Anonymous
 
 wrong 
 
there are 10 advertisements not 9
 Aug 28, 2008
by Anonymous
 
 dggfg 
 
i really like the umber 6 advertisement but i dnt thkn that advertisements make us want 2 eat or buy the product i thnk they r just a way of letting us knw that their business is around :)
 Aug 28, 2008
by Anonymous
 
 ;) 
 
spot on mate!
 Oct 9, 2008
by Anonymous
 
 Mc Donalds burgers have shit 
 
Mc Donalds burgers have shit in it....for real
 Most Popular Articles Today 
 Why Moderate Drinking May Defend Against Rheumatoid Arthritis Hotel 626: the Online Haunted House 2012 MINI Cooper China Olympic Special Edition is No Green Bean Top 10 Most Creative Anti-Smoking Ad Campaigns World&apos;s First Eyeball Tattoo - Ouch! Acer Releases Iconia Tab A700 – 10” Tablet with 1920x1200 Resolution Add The Spiral Hot Dog Cutter To Dad&apos;s Barbeque Gadget Arsenal Art of the Yakuza: Japan&apos;s Tattooed Men&amp;Women SONY&apos;s New Cassette Tapes, Redesigned for the Old Generation The Top 10 Coolest Olympic Mascots McRib Gets a Reboot as Japanese Chain Rolls Out the “Ribusando” China&apos;s Spring Airlines Considers Installing Vertical Seats (Rumored) Winklevii&apos;s Social Network&quot;Zurker&quot;For The People&amp;Of The People (Models too!) How to Select a Home Automation Provider, From Vivint to HAI Zillow.com Brings A New Trend To Real Estate With User Interactive Website 
 more Forum Topics 
 Licensing assignment deal virtual prototype services From the UIA Board President Video of Steve Key! Good info Leverage when Licensing under PPA ? KickSTARTER.com Launching Dreams Light bulb of the future will be $60, but with ... Odorless and Overflow-less Toilet System Inventor Thanks Roger Brown and Mark Reyland Hi to all I would appreciate your vote!! Invention USA &quot;Shark Tank&quot;Contest 2012 Revenues... INFO on branding / web presence Jokes/Pranks&amp;Novelty Candy $$$$$$$$$$$... www.getontheshelf.com Open shark tank project free bicycle invention Why EVERYONE should File a Provisional Patent A... The Magic Toob wins the The Next Big Zing Award! Latest sales numbers... Wanted to point out the importance of .com avai... Treat your customers well and they&apos;ll reward you! Magic Toob Hits Monthly Sales Record 
 more Article Categories Art and Design Boomers Business Cars and Motors Children Clothing Computers Education Electronics Entertainment Entrepreneur Environment Fashion Fitness Food and Drink Fun Funny Gadgets Health Home Innovation International Invention Lifestyle Marketing Media Men Miscellaneous Nature News Outdoors Parenting Products Reviews Science Shopping Social Media Sports Technology Toys Travel Trends Websites Weird or Wacky Women more tags Invention Writers 
 Boomer Babe China.new Gadgetry Inc Jill Harness Lady Bee LeFleur Must Love Gadgets Myra Per-Lee Rey M.L. Ron Callari Spencer Lanoue Steve Levenstein T Goodman Toby 
 Contributing Writers...» Recent Articles 
 How to Select a Home Automation Provider, From Vivint to HAI Why Moderate Drinking May Defend Against Rheumatoid Arthritis 2012 MINI Cooper China Olympic Special Edition is No Green Bean McRib Gets a Reboot as Japanese Chain Rolls Out the “Ribusando” Fujitsu Announces STYLISTIC Q702&amp;LIFEBOOK T902 Business Tablets China&apos;s Spring Airlines Considers Installing Vertical Seats SONY&apos;s New Cassette Tapes, Redesigned for the Old Generation Shark&apos;s Fin Soup to be Banished from Chinese Official Banquets Train Window Smartphone Charger Stand from Genius Cell (Rumored) Winklevii&apos;s Social Network&quot;Zurker&quot;For The People&amp;Of The People (Models too!) 
 more Stuff for Inventors 
 Inventor Home Page Inventor Forum Invention Gallery Inventor Information Service Provider Directory Myra&apos;s Invention Blog Helpful Books Invention Store 
 
 
 Home Inventor Home Invention Gallery Invention Information Forum Archive Contact 
 Copyright©2006-2012. Aha Cafe LLC. All Rights Reserved. About Us. 
Your use of this site is deemed to be your agreement to be bound by our Terms of Use and our Privacy Policy .
	</body>
</document>
