<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000199" url="http://www.family-vacation-getaways-at-los-angeles-theme-parks.com/Disney-Dining.html" time="2012-07-12-15:23" support="1" score="0.001767135742724284" bingtitle="Disney Dining - family vacation getaways at los angeles theme parks" webtitle="Disney Dining">
			<query id="001282" bing-rank="218"/>
	<description>... for some of the Disneyland Resort&apos;s restaurants, including a selection at ... microwave a TV dinner in your hotel room, or stick to the &quot;value menu&quot; at a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Disneyland Restaurants

Enjoy themed restaurants and (mostly) reasonable prices




 


In the slide show above, you&apos;re viewing pictures of restaurants at Disneyland Park! Disneyland&apos;s restaurants focus mostly on casual dining and generally feature counter service or cafeteria-style lines. Just because quick-service restaurants dominate Disneyland&apos;s line-up of dining choices doesn&apos;t mean that it&apos;s not fun to eat breakfast, lunch or dinner at the theme park. On the contrary!

 Disneyland&apos;s restaurants are decorated in keeping with the themed area of the park in which they&apos;re located... influencing both the restaurants&apos; decor AND selection of foods on the menu. Where can you find authentic-tasting gumbo? In New Orleans Square, of course! Or how about enchiladas with a real &quot;sabor Mexicana?&quot; In Frontierland, home of Disneyland&apos;s cowboys and vaqueros.









Disneyland Restaurants: Common elements

All Disney dining features the following similarities
 Although, as mentioned above, the restaurants of Disneyland Park have different themes, different decor, and different cuisine, there are still things that all restaurant in the park have in common.
1.) Recipes used at Disneyland are geared towards North American taste buds. You&apos;re going to find a whole lot of emphasis on American food at Disneyland. There will be virtually no extremely exotic cuisines inside the park. The most &quot;exotic&quot; food you&apos;ll find will be Mexican or Cajun...two cooking styles which have been more or less adopted as nearly mainstream American varieties.

 2.) Disney dining spots are most crowded at &quot;traditional&quot; meal times. Thus, to get your quickest food service, it&apos;s best to avoid eating lunch between 11 am and 2 pm, or dinner between 5 pm and 7 pm. Of course, if your tummy starts growling...ignore that advice! Not all of the Disneyland restaurants are &quot;stuffed full of people&quot; at meal time---for example, I eat at Red Rockett&apos;s Pizza Port (in Tomorrowland) at traditional mealtimes and have no trouble getting served quickly.

 3.) You CAN make advanced reservations for some of the Disneyland Resort&apos;s restaurants, including a selection at Disneyland Park, Disney&apos;s California Adventure, and Downtown Disney.

 How do you make a reservation at a Disneyland restaurant? To find out if the restaurant of your choice takes reservations and to reserve your dining time, call the Disneyland restaurant reservations phone number, (714)781-DINE 

 4.) Prices on the menu never include beverages or desserts. An exception to this rule is Disneyland&apos;s children&apos;s meals.

 5.) Children&apos;s menus are available at most restaurants. The price is about $6, a figure which hasn&apos;t changed in several years. The Disneyland kid meals include the main dish and a side dish. These DO include beverages in the price, plus a souvenir plastic box.

 6.) You don&apos;t need to tip except at the few table-service restaurants in the theme parks.

 7.) As a courtesy, try to leave your table clean for the next party because counter service restaurants don&apos;t clean the dining tables between each customer. Of course, this is Disneyland, where &quot;cleanliness is next to godliness,&quot; and during off-dining times, tables WILL be cleaned religiously between customers. But, the sheer volume of people dining during the busy hours means that one family will be scouting around for empty tables as they carry their food...just waiting for another family to leave so they can sit down somewhere! OF COURSE, any time you ask, your table will be cleaned for you. And, I have had the experience of table-cleaners asking them to let me wipe off the table AFTER I&apos;ve grabbed a newly-open spot at rush hour; some employees are particularly thorough!

 8.) Some food is relatively cheaper than others: For example, a funnel cake with topping, at $5.99, is not too bad a deal. Funnel cake prices at Disneyland are consistent with other theme parks, and can serve more than one person. They&apos;re also a hard-to-find treat that would be lots of trouble to make at home. On the other hand, paying $3.50 for an ice cream bar...even though that&apos;s what other theme parks charge, too...seems pretty outrageous for something you can get much cheaper at any grocery store.






Disney Dining -- General Price Ranges
 Because Disneyland Park has the most expensive theme park ticket prices in Southern California, many people assume that Disneyland&apos;s food prices will be outrageous. This isn&apos;t the case. Meal prices compare favorably with restaurants of a similar type outside the park. Unless you plan to picnic, microwave a TV dinner in your hotel room, or stick to the &quot;value menu&quot; at a fast food restaurant, you won&apos;t be paying much more to eat inside Disneyland Park than you will if you leave and go elsewhere.
Once exception to the rule is beverage prices. Food prices may be reasonable, but buying a soda or carton of milk is going to cost plenty! Disneyland is not alone in this practice; every theme park in Southern California charges $3+ for a soft drink.

 General prices for food at Disneyland Park:

BEVERAGES: Beverage prices remain constant throughout the park, whether you&apos;re purchasing them at an open-air vendor&apos;s cart next to your favorite ride, or whether you&apos;re ordering at Disneyland&apos;s tony full-service restaurant, the Blue Bayou. You can expect to pay approximately the following prices for your beverages throughout the park---
a.) Soft drinks and bottled water--- around $3
b.) Tea and &quot;regular&quot; coffee--- around $3
c.) Specialty Coffee Drinks (eg. lattes, where available) $3 to 4 depending on the drink
d.) Milk and small-sized juices--- under $2
e.) Chocolate milk, hot cocoa and medium-sized juices--- around $3


Note: Bottled water is one of the few &quot;food&quot; items that you&apos;re officially allowed to bring with you into the park. Alcoholic beverages are not served at Disneyland Park, nor may they be brought into the park in your personal items.



 FAST FOOD CHOICES: The prices of the following Disneyland menu items are approximately:

 a.) Hamburgers&amp;Cheeseburgers, $7.50&amp;up, depending on the fixings; side dish (eg french fried) included with this meal
 b.) Grilled or crispy chicken sandwiches, $7.50-$8, including side.
 Sandwich, eg Turkey Club, about $7.59 at a fast food stand; specialty sandwiches can be higher
 Main dish salad, eg. grilled chicken Caesar salad, about $8.50 (no side dish)






Disney Dining and Menus -- New Orleans Square

Just as New Orleans is one of the top dining capitals of the USA, New Orleans Square at Disneyland is the top Disney Dining spot at Disneyland Park. Not only is the park&apos;s high-end restaurant, the Blue Bayou, located there, but its also home to a number of other less-pricey restaurants, making New Orleans Square &quot;dining central&quot; at Disneyland Park.
We&apos;ll start off with that hard-to-get-into Disney dining table service restaurant, The Blue Bayou. Note: menu changes occur at Disneyland, just as they do in restaurants outside the park. So you may or may not find these same items on the menu when you make your visit.




 BLUE BAYOU RESTAURANT MENU EXAMPLES


 
1.) Appetizers--- The Blue Bayou Restaurant is one of the few restaurants at Disneyland Park which offers appetizers. Sample appetizers are---Shrimp cocktail served with papaya and mango chutney, Calamari (octopus) with Cajun Remoulade sauce, and Sausage-stuffed mushrooms. Appetizer prices range from about $9--11.

 2.) Entrees--- Prices for entrees have reached the $24--30+ mark at the Blue Bayou. This is great for those who can afford it...and the Blue Bayou restaurant CAN raise its prices since they have more would-be diners than they have space. However, I can remember the days when the Blue Bayou was more reasonably priced...and would be very happy if those days returned!

Sample entrees include beef dishes--such as Prime rib and Tri-tip; Roast pork loin; and seafood dishes, such as Shrimp Brochettes, Salmon Filet and Crab Cakes. All entrees are served with potatoes and vegetables, and are decoratively garnished. You&apos;ll have your choice of soup or salad to start your meal, as well.
 A la carte items include such New Orleans favorites as Gumbo and Jambalaya, and the &quot;house signature sandwich,&quot; the Monte Cristo.
More than the food, the ambiance of dining in a &quot;French Quarter Courtyard&quot; alongside a firefly-lit bayou at night makes this a must-visit restaurant for many visitors.




FRENCH MARKET RESTAURANT

 The French Market is a Disneyland restaurant featuring patio dining in a beautiful setting where iron lacework abounds. New Orleans-style jazz musicians entertain the crowd. Colorful swaths of fabric form a &quot;roof&quot; overhead. At Disneyland&apos;s French Market Restaurant, you&apos;ll be able to order menu items such as the following---

 Entrees--- in the $9--13 range. These include a creole-style fried chicken with a red beans/rice/sausage combo; an American-style deep-fried chicken served with steak fries; and Fettuccine served with a ham/crawfish sauce. All entrees are served with a side salad and a roll.

 Sandwiches--- A selection of sandwiches in the $10-11 range includes several Po Boys and a French Dip Roast Beef sandwich served with steak fries.

 Main-Dish Soups--- in the $9--12 range, you&apos;ll be able to order a hearty portion of clam chowder, beef stew or the soup-of-the-day served in a large, sourdough bread bowl.

 Children&apos;s meals are available for $6-$7.




 CAFE ORLEANS 


 
The Cafe Orleans is a casual-dining restaurant featuring patio dining.

 Main-dish Soups--- For under $10, you can get clam chowder or the soup-of-the-day served in a large sourdough bread bowl.

 Main-dish Salads--- All varieties cost under $10, and are served over a bed of romaine and iceberg lettuce, garnished with tomatoes. Toppings include---

 .......Chicken, such as the Uptown Chicken Salad containing mangoes and celery, and topped with a citrus dressing.

 .......Beef , such as the French Quarter Beef Salad, which mixes the carved beef bits with bleu cheese crumbles and bleu cheese dressing.

 .......Ham, such as the Garden District Ham and Cheese Salad, which mixes carved ham, Swiss cheese and apple slices, and is covered with a vinaigrette dressing.

 Sandwiches--- You&apos;ll find several &quot;Po Boy&quot; sandwiches (the New Orleans name for Submarine Sandwiches) available here, as well as the popular French Dip roast beef sandwich, costing in the neighborhood of $10.




ROYAL STREET VERANDA

The Royal Street Veranda in New Orleans Square is the place to go to find your favorite specialty coffee drinks, and to enjoy a main-dish sized bowl of gumbo or chowder to go with it.

 Main-dish soups--- costing around $9 are served in large, sourdough bowls and include meaty or vegetarian gumbos or creamy clam chowder.

 Specialty coffee drinks--- in the $3--4 range include both hot AND cold Cafe Mocha, Cafe Latte and Cappuccino.



 Helpful Links:    Family-Vacation-Getaways.com HOME ::    Latest News ::    Privacy Policy ::    Back to the TOP of Disney Dining 


 Explore a different Disneyland Resort topic:    Disneyland Resort overview ::    Disneyland Park ::    Disneyland Touring Plan ::    Disney&apos;s California Adventure ::    Downtown Disney ::    Disneyland Hotels ::    Disneyland Dining ::    Disneyland Hours, Entertainment&amp;contact info :: 


 Plan a different SoCal family activity:    SoCal Attractions Overview ::    Beaches ::    Camping ::    Christmas Fun ::    Family Fun Centers ::    Halloween Fun ::    Hollywood fun ::    Parks ::    Restaurants ::    Road Trips ::    San Diego Fun ::    Shopping ::    Outlet Shopping ::    Theaters ::    Theme Parks ::    Water Parks ::    Zoos :: 



 Search our sites:


 Custom Search 






 Do you love roller coasters and rides?

Click here to find discount tickets, offers and specials for your favorite theme parks!

Copyright 2005-2012 by Vicki Funes; all rights reserved worldwide
	</body>
</document>
