<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000717" url="http://newhope360.com/legislative-update-accessible-fresh-food" time="2012-07-12-16:04" support="1" score="0.001249427202124559" bingtitle="Legislative update: Accessible fresh food | Regulation and ..." webtitle="Legislative update: Accessible fresh food | Regulation and Legislation content from New Hope 360">
			<query id="000186" bing-rank="78"/>
	<description>Under the bill, businesses would receive a rehabilitation tax credit in some instances, which ... Here, we’ve had people disallow the licensing of another fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Navigation Skip to Content New Hope 360 Search: Register or Log-in Username: * Password: * Remember me 
 Forgot Your Password? 
 close 
 
 
 Subscribe About Us Advertise Press Standards RSS 
 
 Business 
 Agriculture Classifieds Direct to consumer Distribution Finance and Investment International Manufacturing Marketing News Packaging Product Development Quality Control Regulation and Legislation Research Retailing Supply Chain Management Sustainability Technology 
 Events 
 Conferences Tradeshows Webinars 
 Food&amp;Beverage 
 Beverage Dairy Ethnic Functional Gluten Free Meat&amp;Poultry Non-GMO Produce Recipes Seafood Special Diets Sweeteners Vegetarian&amp;Vegan Whole Foods 
 Health 
 Allergies&amp;Sensitivities Babies&amp;Children Blood Sugar Management Bone&amp;Joint Health Cognitive Health Detox Energy Exercise&amp;Fitness Eye Health Healing&amp;Prevention Healthy Aging Heart Health Immune Health Men Oral Care Pain Management Reproductive Health Sleep, Stress&amp;Fatigue Weight Management Women 
 Beauty 
 Beauty, Cosmetics&amp;Skincare Hair&amp;Nail Care Nutricosmetics 
 Ingredients 
 Amino Acid Capsules Carbohydrates Carotenoids Colorants Enzymes Fats&amp;Oils Flavonoids Flavorings Green Foods&amp;Algae Herbal Minerals Prebiotics Preservatives Probiotics Specialty Super Foods Sweeteners Vitamins 
 Supplements 
 Amino Acids Antioxidant Bone Health Children&apos;s Digestive Support Energy Enzymes Food-based Supplements Garlic Green Food Herbal Joint Health Minerals Mushrooms Omega Supplements Prenatal Probiotics Protein Sports&amp;Fitness Performance Vitamins 
 Lifestyle 
 Fair Trade Green Living Healthy Home Organic Pets Technology 
 Find&amp;Compare 
 Advertisement Home &gt; Business &gt; Regulation and Legislation &gt;Legislative update: Accessible fresh food 
Legislative update: Accessible fresh food
 Oct. 27, 2009 Angela Cortez  |  Natural Foods Merchandiser 
 
 EMAIL 
 Tweet 
 Comments 0 
More About:

 Adulterated Dietary Supplements 
 Advertisement 
Bobby Rush, D-Ill., would make fresh food more accessible for residents in low-income areas where supermarkets can be more than two miles away. The Food Desert Oasis Act of 2009 would designate certain cities as food desert zones, which would be treated much like enterprise zones, enticing certain businesses that derive at least 25 percent of their gross sales from fresh fruits and vegetables to receive tax incentives for opening supermarkets.

“We’re excited,” says Terry Richards, legislative counsel for Rush. “This is an opportunity to develop an economic base for employees, consumers and residents, and provide a significant opportunity to invest in healthy living.”

Richards says there is a food scarcity problem when people in low-income areas can’t easily obtain fresh, healthy food, but are bombarded with high-sugar, high-fat convenience food.

Under the bill, businesses would receive a rehabilitation tax credit in some instances, which would provide money for redevelopment in urban centers. Employers would receive a tax credit of $1,500 for every employee hired from within a food desert zone, and tax-exempt bonds would be used on a variety of store upgrades, including building, equipment and even product purchases.

“Those things are a very good idea because the prevalence of obesity is highest in the poorest areas where one of the problems is the access of healthy foods,” says Kelly Brownell, director of the Rudd Center for Food Policy and Obesity at Yale University.
Cities that would be designated food desert zones are Chicago; Detroit; Cleveland; Cincinnati; Milwaukee; Houston; San Antonio; Memphis and Nashville, Tenn.; Birmingham, Ala.; Kansas City, Mo.; St. Louis.; Indianapolis; Baltimore; Atlanta; Richmond, Va.; Los Angeles; Washington, D.C.; Philadelphia and New Orleans.

Under the Food Desert Oasis Pilot Program, annual reports would be submitted to Congress. The reports would include an analysis of increases or decreases in the health of the residents in the food desert zones and the impact of the government investment in such areas. The bill was recently transferred to the House Committee on Ways and Means. The cost of the program is currently under review by the Congressional Budget Office.
 –Angela Cortez 

 Retailers and activists weigh in 
“I think the food desert act sounds like a great idea. I don’t think that alone would make us expand into another neighborhood, but politically, I think it’s really a good thing. Here, we’ve had people disallow the licensing of another fast food [restaurant] in the northwest area. I think it’s good. I’d support the legislation.”
– Peggy Silvestrini, owner of Beans&amp;Barley, a natural foods store in Milwaukee 

“We’re in the process of trying to move our store to one of the food desert areas. We’re moving into an area that needs to be revitalized. There is no grocer in a 4-mile or larger radius. Having the experience that I’m going through now, I know this legislation is definitely a good thing. Where we are there is a large concentration of people in the area, but they have no resources to get their food. We’re looking to move because the buildings also are cheaper there and we’re looking to expand, but it’s not an area attractive to other businesses, so having an incentive like [the food desert law] would attract other businesses to an area like this.”
– Karen King, owner of Choices Natural Market, Rockford, Ill. 

“Operators want to go into these communities, but they face barriers associated with financing. This is a health issue. One in five children is obese and more than 30 percent of children are overweight. It’s a costly epidemic. In 2008, obesity was responsible for $147 billion in medical costs, and that is expected to rise. The [healthy food] access problem is an issue in many communities, especially low-income, urban and rural, as well as communities of color. The leading health organizations say that increasing healthy food in underserved areas is critical.”
– T racey Giang, senior associate of The Food Trust, which runs the Pennsylvania Fresh Food Financing Initiative, a statewide program that supports the development of supermarkets in underserved areas
 
 
 Print reprints Favorite 
 
 
 EMAIL 
 Tweet 
 
Discuss this Article 0 
 
Post new comment
 Name: Sign In or register to use your New Hope 360 ID Email: (optional) Your comment: * 
Related Articles
 
 Lazy Cakes update: Durbin raises concerns with FDA over melatonin-laced food FDA Steps in to Make Fresh-Cut Veggies Safer for Consumers Update: FDA&apos;s stance on genetically engineered animals GMO update Legislative Update: A Snapshot Of Capitol Hill 
 
 Subscribe to the New Hope 360 Newsletter! 
 
Keep up with the latest news with our daily newsletter
 Subscribe Advertisement 
Editor&apos;s Picks
 
 Will an IPO enable Natural Grocers to take on Whole Foods Market?   GMO labeling hits the Washington, D.C., sausage grinder   Is our food too clean?   Campbell&apos;s goes big in functional beverages with Bolthouse Farms acquisition   The easiest healthy pie crust ever   
 Advertisement 
Connect with NFM
 
 Twitter Facebook LinkedIn RSS Podcasts 
 Advertisement 
NewHope360.com
 
 Home Business Events Food&amp;Beverage Health Beauty Ingredients Supplements Lifestyle Find&amp;Compare 
 
Site Features
 
 Subscribe RSS Job Listings Sitemap Site Archive Terms of Use Privacy Policy View Mobile Site 
 
New Hope Natural Media
 
 About Us Contact Advertise Standards Graphic Center 
 
Follow Us
 
 Facebook Twitter 
 
Search NewHope360.com
 Search: 
New Hope 360 Sources
 
 Delicious Living Engredea Monograph Engredea News&amp;Analysis Functional Ingredients Natural Foods Merchandiser Nutrition Business Journal 
 
New Hope 360 In Person
 
 Natural Products Expo East Natural Products Expo West Natural Products Expo Asia NBJ Summit Nutracon Conference Nutracon Asia Engredea Engredea365 The Organic Summit Natural Products Association MarketPlace NutriCosmetic Summit NutriCosmetic Summit Asia 
 Copyright©2012 Penton Media, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
