<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000536" url="http://www.dreamindemon.com/page/21/" time="2012-07-12-15:49" support="1" score="0.0010895442054059399" bingtitle="The Dreamin&apos; Demon" webtitle="The DreaminDemon">
			<query id="001210" bing-rank="52"/>
	<description>The empty car looked to have barely survived the ... like a customer that Landmark would like to keep ... of brain break after eating at a Wendy’s fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		NEWSLETTER RSS 
 
 dreamindemon is just a place for murder fanatics, people who are just as bad as the coldblooded criminals. —  Angry Student 
 
 Home About Us Contact Forums Reviews Random Article 
 
 Advertise! 
 
 Filter Articles: Fiction 
 Movies Books Television Music Comics 
 Non-Fiction 
 Murder Sex Crimes Child Abuse Missing Persons Domestic Violence Assault and Battery Drugs and Alcohol Weird News 
 Contribute 
 
In The Mean Time...
 
 CFO For Champagne Beverage Arrested For Producing Child Porn 
 April 11, 2012 at 8:35 am by Rebekah Herzberg   
 Covington, LA– This happened last month, but it is local to me and as a mother of one child with another on the way, I had to get this guy on the front page.

The FBI say that over an eight year period, 66-year-old Charles Edward“Chuck”Reese, the CFO for Champagne Beverage, paid two women $750, 000 for sexually explicit videos of themselves along with their children, relatives, and even their pets.

The investigation into Charles Reese’s activities began when Photobucket.com alerted authorities to inappropriate media that had been uploaded by a user. One video showed a woman engaged in a sex act with a boy around 2-years-old. One subpoena later, and the FBI were able to identify the woman as a 28-year-old living in Vidor, Texas. The boy in the video was her own son.

The woman also happened to be dead, having passed away in a hospital for reasons that have not been disclosed. Investigators were able to retrieve the woman’s cell phone regardless, and found that it contained even more sexually explicit videos involving other children.

Specialists interviewed the woman’s two daughters, ages 6 and 9, and one told them that her mother made her perform and simulate sexual behavior with her 2-year-old brother and a 3-year-old cousin.…
 Continue Reading 64 Comments 
 Teacher Who Left Wife For Teen Student Jailed For Sexual Abuse 
 April 10, 2012 at 2:51 pm by Caustic   
 Modesto, CA –A California teacher who made national headlines for leaving his wife and three children for a teen student, has been accused of sexually abusing a different teenage girl that he taught in 1998.

Jordan Powers, 18, quit school to move in with her teacher James Hooker, 41, has now dumped him following his arrest for alleged sexual misconduct with another student. Jordan, who last February defended their odd pairing on national news, now fears there may be more students

“My heart dropped. I felt betrayed. I just have a gut feeling there are other girls,”Powers said, according to the ABC News interview. She went on to say,“He called me from jail and, yes, I told him that we’re done. I lost everything for this guy. I lost my senior year. I gave up all my friends at high school because they didn’t agree with me.”

Jordan’s mother, Tammie Powers, is pushing for a bill in California that would make it a felony for a public school teacher to date a student in the same school, regardless of age, even if the student is 18. Currently, 23 states now have a law forbidding teachers to date students regardless of age.…
 Continue Reading 108 Comments 
 Father’s Sailboat Ride In Frigid Lake Turns Deadly For Family 
 April 10, 2012 at 2:37 pm by kniption   
 Benidji, MN - A father’s sailboat ride for his three young children turned deadly when–after the craft capsized–the four tumbled into a frigid northern Minnesota Lake. Two of the children are now dead and the third remains hospitalized in critical condition .

Dan Risland, 31, had reporedly taken his sons, 8-year-old Isaiah , 6-year-old Zech , and 2-year-old Jacob , out on his new sailboat Friday afternoon on Clearwater Lake in far Northern Minnesota. According to reports, ice had only recently melted off the lake.

Clearwater County Sheriff Mike Erickson said that, at about 3 p.m., strong winds tipped the boat and‘threw them into the water.’Risland was reported to have tried to reach his sons–all of whom were wearing life jackets–but he struggled in the wind and waves. The sheriff said that the father was becoming hypothermic, so he told Isaiah to watch his brothers while he swam to shore for help.

According to police, by the time authorities arrived, the boys had been in the 40-degree water for about an hour . The two younger boys died of hypothermia. At last report, Isaiah Risland remained at Children’s Hospital in Minneapolis in critical condition.…
 Continue Reading 52 Comments 
 Man Accused Of Blackmailing Teens Into Performing Sex Acts 
 April 10, 2012 at 1:01 pm by Morbid   
 BRAZIL, Indiana– Police have arrested a man in Indiana, accusing him of blackmailing at least 100 people, mostly boys 14 to 16 years old, into performing sex acts online .

Richard Finkbiner, 39, is facing sexual exploitation of children charges, stemming from an investigation that began after two of his victims went to police to report his activities.

Basically, Finkbiner would use a fake online identity and form relationships with his victims, ultimately getting uncoerced camera footage of them posing naked or performing sex acts. Using this material, he would turn the boys into his own personal“slaves”by threatening to post the videos to gay porn sites if they did not continue supplying more material.

“You want to play this game, or you want to be a gay porn star?”Finkbiner allegedly told one victim during a video Skype call, the federal complaint said.

But his twisted game ended when one 14-year-old boy in Michigan couldn’t take it anymore.

“I’ll add your name and email so if anyone googles u they will see ur video,”Finkbiner allegedly informed the teen, forcing him into providing more sexually explicit video. The teen eventually“broke down”from stress after a second incident.

He“became emotional and hysterical, and disclosed to his brother what was happening,”FBI Special Agent Ryan Barrett said.…
 Continue Reading 23 Comments 
 Woman Accused Of Abandoning Baby During Shoplifting Attempt 
 April 10, 2012 at 10:52 am by Morbid   
 KENNER, La.– Police are looking for a woman who, after getting caught shoplifting, Tased a mall security guard before abandoning a baby in the parking lot .

It all happened Saturday night at Esplande Mall after an employee at Gymboree watched a woman stealing items from the store as she pushed a baby boy in a stroller.

The employee confronted the woman, along with a security guard, and was in the process of calling her manager when the woman shot the guard with a stun gun and took of running while pushing the stroller.

She was pursued into the mall parking lot where she jumped in a vehicle and fled the scene—leaving the baby in the parking lot.

The 2-month-old baby was taken into protective custody until his mother, Stephanie Johnson , came forward and told police that the woman who abandoned her baby at the mall was the child’s babysitter, a woman named Brittany London.

After being alerted that her name was being trashed on Facebook and Twitter, London went to police herself and informed them that she didn’t know Johnson“at all”and that Johnson may have gotten her name off Facebook.

“She says that she’s friends with a friend who’s friends with me or one of her friends is friends with me.…
 Continue Reading 36 Comments 
 Woman Poured Bleach On Ex-Beau’s Groin As He Drove 
 April 10, 2012 at 8:12 am by Rebekah Herzberg   
 Gainesville, FL - Shenay Jackson, 19, is accused of pouring bleach into her ex-boyfriend’s lap while he was driving.

The pair were arguing in the car when Jackson first pushed him in the face before using the bleach to change the race of his penis. The bleach soaked through the unidentified man’s clothes, causing a burning sensation to his naughty bits that resulted in him pulling over to remove his clothing.

Jackson admitted to police that she got into an argument with her ex, but only picked up the bottle and shook it, causing some of it to splash on him. She never intended to get any on him.

However, the police report states there were puddles of bleach inside the car, far more than would be present had it came from merely shaking the bottle, and the man’s clothing were soaked and displayed severe discoloration.

Jackson was charged with simple battery, a first-degree misdemeanor, and was being held at the Alachua County Jail. I can’t help but think the charges would have been more severe had this been a man using bleach to make it rain on his girlfriend’s vagina.…
 Continue Reading 33 Comments 
 Wheelchair-Bound Man Imprisoned For Chihauhau Sexual Assault 
 April 10, 2012 at 8:00 am by kniption   
 Sacremento, CA– This is actually from a few months back.  Oddly, it is only now making the rounds in Australian news–where I picked it up.  I wrote it up before realizing the time warp.  Oh well.  Australia’s disconnectedness is your gain…

A wheelchair-bound California man will serve 10 years in jail after sexually assaulting an 8-month-old Chihuahua.

According to court documents, 55-year-old Robert Edwards De Shields–who is described as a wheelchair-bound methamphetamine addict–had been offered a temporary place to live in a South Sacramento home. Prosecutors said when the homeowners came home one day in March, they reportedly found De Shields holding the‘scared’ Chihuahua named Shadow . When the dog was missing the following day, Shadow was reportedly found in the garage with De Shields in‘pain and shock.’

A veterinarian would later find severe injuries to the dog’s rectum and internal organs , and evidence of asphyxiation. Sacramento County sheriff’s deputies made the arrest.

A jury convicted De Shields after a trial that contained graphic testimony about his abuse of Shadow including strangulation and penetration with a foreign object. De Shields was then subsequently sentenced to 10 years in state prison and has been ordered to register as a lifetime sex offender .…
 Continue Reading 36 Comments 
 Pastor Charged After Boy Beaten And Forced To Dig His Own Grave 
 April 9, 2012 at 1:26 pm by kniption   
 Corona, CA - The pastor and two other men affiliated with a Heart of Worship Church in Corona, California have been charged of with kidnapping and torturing a boy as a form of discipline for bad behavior.

Pastor Lonnie Remmers, 54, Nick Craig, 22, and Darryll Jeter, 28 are all facing charges including kidnapping, criminal threats and assault.

According to police, the teen’s mother took him to a men’s group home group home operated by the church for intervention because she believed he had been involved in‘sexual misconduct .’Corona police said it was unclear if she knew how the men were planning to discipline her son.

Investigators say Remmers instructed Craig and Jeters, who lived at the home, to‘scare the boy.’Police said Craig and Jeter drove the teen about 100 miles to the Barstow desert, forced him to dig a grave , threw dirt on him, and beat him with a belt. The boy was then reportedly driven back to Remmers’house where the pastor used a pair of pliers to inflict pain on the boy, police said.

According to police, the boy did not have to be hospitalized.

Craig and Jeter were booked on suspicion of kidnapping, torture, child abuse and conspiracy.…
 Continue Reading 41 Comments 
 Man Rides Motorcycle Into Bar And Demands Fight, Bar Complies 
 April 9, 2012 at 12:24 pm by kniption   
 South Haven, IN - Police say a man drove his motorcycle inside an Indiana bar Saturday night and challenged the bar to a fight. The bar resoundingly said‘yes.’

Witnesses said John Daniels, 43, drove his motorcycle into Sportsman’s Bar through the opened front door just before 7 p.m. Saturday and asked if anyone wanted to fight.

While bar employees tried to push the motorcycle outside, Daniels reportedly got off the bike and began fighting with employees and other patrons. Sheriff’s police were called to the bar for‘a large fight in progress.’

Police arrested Daniels on a battery and disorderly conduct charges and an additional charge of felony mugshot grimacing . Police also arrested Thomas Hines, 47, who told police that he began fighting alongside Daniels because‘everyone attacked [him].’

Hines was also charged with battery and disorderly conduct charges.  Additional charges against both men for unlawful possession of douchey facial hair and felony resisting middle age are presumably still pending.…
 Continue Reading 32 Comments 
 Man Forced Woman To Perform Oral Sex On Son-In-Law 
 April 9, 2012 at 11:16 am by Rebekah Herzberg   
 Houston, TX - Houston police say Phillip Don Oliver, 25, has been arrested and charged after forcing his way into an apartment and forcing the people inside to commit sex acts on each other .

Oliver, also known as,“Showtime”and“Wild Thing,”thought the man who lived at the apartment owed $200, 000 to another man named Rico and he was there to collect the debt.

According to the court documents, Oliver and an accomplice forced their way inside the home by threatening the victim with a gun.  After denying knowledge of a debt to a man known as“Rico,”Oliver gathered the man’s wife, mother-in-law, and an infant into the bathroom then forced the adults to undress.

Oliver made the man kneel down and stick his head into the toilet while he flushed it repeatedly. He then inserted the barrel of his firearm into the man’s rectum while he was kneeling on the floor, before removing the barrel and sticking it into the mouth of the man’s wife–joking and laughing the entire time.

Oliver then put the gun to the head of couple’s 6-month-old daughter and forced the man to put his penis in his mother-in-law’s mouth and ordered her to perform oral sex on her son-in-law.…
 Continue Reading 48 Comments 
 Man Charged After Throwing Two Dogs Into A Fire Pit 
 April 9, 2012 at 10:31 am by Morbid   
 WOOD COUNTY, TX– Some asshole in Texas is facing criminal charges after throwing two dogs into a fire pit .

According to the police, four people were sitting around a fire pit getting drunk when 28-year-old Larry Lowery grabbed a dog and tossed it into the flames. A 5-year-old girl witnessed this and told her grandmother, Faye Norris, who confronted Lowery.

She says Lowery acted as if the entire thing was a joke, but apologized for his actions. Not long after, he tossed a second dog into the pit and then bragged about it.

According to one of Lowery’s neighbors, one of the two dogs was able to escape the fire pit and was last seen running away while on fire.

Lowery told police he grabbed a stray dog that had bitten him two weeks earlier and accidentally tossed it into the fire pit after he stumbled. He has been charged with felony cruelty to animals and since released on a $5,000 bond.

“It takes a mentally disturbed individual, my opinion, to do something that cruel,”said Norris. That’s not just your opinion, Norris. That’s probably the general consensus of those of us who are not mentally disturbed.

…
 Continue Reading 31 Comments 
 Boy Critical After Being Mauled By Family Pit Bull 
 April 9, 2012 at 10:06 am by Morbid   
 MOUNTAIN HOME, Ark.– A 3-year-old boy is in critical condition after the family pit bull mauled him on Thursday.

Ryan Moody was rushed to the hospital suffering from bite wounds to his face and head, then airlifted to another hospital in Little Rock for surgery. According to his mother, Amber Moody, their nine-month-old pit bull attacked Ryan in the front yard.

Police have since learned that Amber adopted the pit bull from the Humane Society last March. I didn’t know this, but the Humane Society normally doesn’t adopt out pit bulls to families with young children.

Amber was able to get around this technicality by simply putting,“none”‘in the section of the adoption form asking for the number of children in her home. But some chick at the Humane Society wants to remind everyone that it’s not the breed as any breed of dog poses a threat to young children.

“If a dog is sleeping and the child goes and jumps on it, it doesn’t even know who jumped on it. It’s first reaction is to turn around and snap,” said Margaret Shepherd , the Executive Director of the Humane Society.

Balderdash and piffle, I say. That pit bull attacked the boy because the boy was alive .…
 Continue Reading 130 Comments 
 Teen Facing Attempted Murder Charges After Driving Into Crowd 
 April 9, 2012 at 9:53 am by Morbid   
 St. Petersburg, FL —A teenager in Florida is facing murder charges after being accused of intentionally driving her car into a crowd of people .

According to reports, 18-year-old Shatavia Hall and her sister were involved in an outdoors fight with several other people.

After the fight broke up, police say that Hall and her sister got into a Pontiac Grand Am which Hall drove over a curb and into a yard and toward a group of at least five people who had remained after the fight.

Some were able to jump out of the way, but three others were not as lucky and were struck by Hall. Othel Dawson, 70, was hit along with his 13-year-old grandson who was flipped over the vehicle. Another child was also hit, but no one suffered any serious injuries.

Witnesses say Hall could be heard laughing as she drove away from the scene. Police would arrest her an hour later at her home. She has been charged with three counts of attempted murder. Her sister has not been charged.…
 Continue Reading 16 Comments 
 Man Accused Of Beating Handicapped Man Over Playboy 
 April 9, 2012 at 8:59 am by Morbid   
 York, SC– A man in South Carolina is facing assault charges after police say he beat a handicapped man during an argument over a Playboy Magazine .

On Wednesday, police were called to a home and found 24-year-old John Edward Pack on the front porch suffering from a seizure, a possible broken rib, a broken eye socket and neck injuries.

After medics were able to get the handicapped man’s seizure under control, he told police that he had been beaten by 42-year-old Randall Rumfelt, a man who lived with his mother. He said that a drunken Rumfelt wanted the Playboy Magazine he had in his possession, and kicked his ass to get it.

But Pack’s mother told police that she witnessed the fight and that Pack handed her the magazine before hitting Rumfelt first. After her son got his ass beat, she says she helped clean his wounds before he walked to his grandmother’s house a few houses away.

Rumfelt was arrested and charged with second-degree assault and battery. He’s currently being held under a $10,000 bond. Pack’s mother was also arrested because she didn’t get medical help for Pack and failed to report the incident to police.…
 Continue Reading 19 Comments 
 Bus Driver, Teen Honored For Stopping Hit-And-Run Driver 
 April 6, 2012 at 3:27 pm by kniption   
 Bethlehem, PA - After an unnamed 17-year-old driver hit a bicyclist and attempted to flee, his quick apprehension by a city bus driver and another motorist was caught on tape.

Bicyclist Frank Pavlick, 50, was hit Monday afternoon by the teen driver while riding in the northbound lanes of the Fahy Bridge.

“The…guy didn’t even try to pass me,” Pavlick said. “It was an explosion, literally. The tire exploded, the rim exploded.”

Video shows that immediately after the impact, the car driver sped off . Up ahead was a LANTA municipal bus. The bus driver, seeing the accident behind him, maneuvered his vehicle to stop the fleeing driver. A second driver then boxed him in from behind after checking to see if Pavlick was ok.

 

Bethlehem Police Commissioner Jason Schiffer and Mayor John Callahan honored the two men responsible for detaining the hit-and-run driver. Those men, Richard Gubish Jr., 43, and Jud Smull, 17, were commended for their quick thinking. Pavlick, the rider, expressed his gratitude to both men.

“These guys, I’ve been waiting to meet and say thanks in public and in private,” Pavlick said during remarks.

Pavlick suffered minor injuries in the wreck. This was impressive given the condition of his bike.…
 Continue Reading 65 Comments 
 Man Sentenced To 50-100 Years After Raping Multiple Children 
 April 6, 2012 at 9:02 am by kniption   
 Tunkhannock, PA - A Pennsylvania man has been sentenced to 50-to-100 years in prison for sexually abusing 4 underage girls and an underage boy.

Vincent Clark, 42,  had been found guilty by a jury on Dec. 16 for 34 sex-related charges for crimes that occurred between 2006 and 2009.

The victims–who are now between the ages of 8 and 15–were all at the sentencing hearing. The children had testified that the assaults happened in Clark’s home, in his tractor trailer, and on his all-terrain vehicle .

“These children [are] not who they were meant to grow up as. Their souls are completely different,”a victim’s mother said.

During the trial, a member of the Pennsylvania Sexual Offenders Assessment Board said that Clark declined to participate in his own psychological assessment. She instead used victim forensic interviews, police affidavits, and prior criminal information to determine that Clark suffered from pedophilia that was acquired and/or congenital. This resulted in Clark being sentenced as a sexually violent predator .

Clark’s oldest victim–a 15-year-old girl–reportedly began to cry while addressing the judge at the sentencing hearing.  She then suggested a death sentence would be appropriate. A second victim–a 13-year-old girl–said Clark should“not have the satisfaction of walking on this earth”for all that she lost during the last five years of her life.…
 Continue Reading 84 Comments 
 Page 21 of 449 « First « ... 10 ... 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 ... 40 50 60 70 80 ... » Last » 
 
 
Search: With My Good Eye Closed
 Search for: CLICK HERE TO ADVERTISE WITH US! IT&apos;S CHEAP! 

 
Never miss a friggin&apos; article by checking our daily RSS feed or subscribing to our daily Newsletter!

 
Peer Pressure
 

 Follow @dreamindemon 

 

 
Prophets of Doom
 Place your ad here 
 Loading... 
This Week&apos;s Top 10

 Lawyer Claims Wayne Treacy Was Insane When He Stomped Josie Ratley’s Head : DEERFIELD BEACH, FL-- Two years ago we reported on Wayne Treacy, the then 15-year-old who used some steel-toed boots to turn a 15-year-old girl&apos;s brains into a bowl of mashed potatoes because he got upset over some texts she had sent him. Today, open New Mom Goes On Violent Rampage In Maternity Ward After Smoking Bath Salts : ALTOONA, PA -- It&apos;s amazing that God sees to it that couples able to provide a loving household for a child are not able to conceive or adopt one, but will seemingly ensure the biggest morons are equipped with vaginas capable of shooting out babies l Boy, 8, Shoots 5-Year-Old Friend Near Montana Dog Park, Leaves Him To Die : BILLINGS, Montana -- An 8-year-old boy has been accused of shooting his 5-year-old friend and then leaving the boy to die.The two boys were at a High Sierra dog park with their parents and had been given permission to go to a nearby wooded area t High On Bath Salts, Man With Feces In His Mouth Tried To Fight Cop : GWINNETT COUNTY, GA -- And the bath salt train just keeps on rollin&apos; along. This time a Georgia man was arrested after snorting bath salts, eating shit, and then trying to fight a cop.It all started last Tuesday when 21-year-old Matthew Hammond&apos;s Mother Shot To Death After Confronting Speeding Driver : Mobile, AL -- A 40-year-old mother of two was gunned down in front of her home Saturday after she confronted a group of men in a car speeding through her neighborhood.The dark gray or green Honda Civic or Altima with dark, tinted windows drove do Man Loses Hand To the Lamest Firework On Earth : Kenner, LA - Daniel Duzac, 19, who will no longer be able to count higher than three with his shoes on, lost a left hand and two fingers on his right when a self-constructed &quot;sparkler bomb&quot; exploded in his then-complete hands on July 3rd.Duzac ha Sex Offender Stabbed 10-Year-Old Boy Inside Wendy’s Bathroom : Portland, Ore. -- A registered sex offender was arrested the other day after he tried to sexually assault a 10-year-old boy in a Wendy&apos;s bathroom and stabbed the child several times when he fought back.Police say on Sunday, 49-year-old Adam Lee B Father Beat Man Who Tried To Meet His 12-Year-Old Daughter : COOKEVILLE, TN -- A 42-year-old man&apos;s plan of meeting a 12-year-old girl he met on Facebook was interrupted the other night when the girl&apos;s father introduced the man&apos;s face to his fist.The girl&apos;s father noticed that his daughter had been receivin Florida Teen Loses Part Of Arm After Alligator Attack : MOORE HAVEN, FL -- A 17-year-old in Florida is lucky to be alive today after being attacked by an 11-foot alligator and only losing part of his arm.The only reason why I am even posting this story is because of the victim, Kaleb Langdale, also kn Girl, 11, Home After Having Part Of Nose, Lip Bitten Off By Dog : HOLLYWOOD, FL -- Unlike most dog attack stories I post about, I am posting this one to help get the word out on how you can help out an 11-year-old girl after she had a portion of her face bitten off by a friend&apos;s dog.Back in June, 11-year-old Ja 
 
Recent Comments
 Powered by Disqus 
 More Crime News From Reality Bites 

 Justice For Brayden; Charges Laid In His 2006 Abuse, 2011 Death July 12, 2012 Rajwinder Kaur Missing, Family Receives Text&quot;The Girl With This Phone Is Dead&quot; July 12, 2012 Steven Gregg Doesnt Just Want Your Money When Robbing You, Also Wants Your BBQ Sauce July 11, 2012 Jesus Castillo-Dimas Runs Down GF&amp;2yo Son, Killing the 2yo July 11, 2012 Robber Gets Thirsty While Hiding Out, Drinks Engine Fluid July 11, 2012 DWI Leads To Guy Shannon&apos;s Arrest In Cold Case Killing Of Marcia Davis 23 Years Ago July 11, 2012 Fred Freeman Wisconsin Basketball Coach, Beats Up Female Player, 17, After Loss July 11, 2012 Mercila Owens Allegedly Stabs Ex-Boyfriend in the Back. Literally July 11, 2012 Teacher Matthew Ellsworth,Had Sex With Student Pleads For Mercy B/C They Fell In Love July 11, 2012 Man Dies In Crash After Running Over His Wife July 11, 2012 Michael Walsh missing since 1985 identified July 11, 2012 Juan Acosta Allegedly Gets Drunk And Drives Over Tent, Killing Two Kids July 11, 2012 
 
Stuff You Should Buy

 
 
 
 
 States of Bliss 
 Select A State Alabama (47) Alaska (7) Arizona (121) Arkansas (44) California (307) Colorado (97) Connecticut (48) Delaware (17) Florida (732) Georgia (116) Hawaii (1) Idaho (24) Illinois (161) Indiana (143) Iowa (41) Kansas (21) Kentucky (77) Louisiana (66) Maine (15) Maryland (40) Massachusetts (87) Michigan (100) Minnesota (62) Mississippi (17) Missouri (99) Montana (16) Nebraska (25) Nevada (47) New Hampshire (34) New Jersey (66) New Mexico (74) New York (181) North Carolina (148) Ohio (228) Oklahoma (108) Oregon (81) Pennsylvania (174) Rhode Island (15) South Dakota (4) Tennessee (91) Texas (283) Utah (59) Vermont (16) Virginia (56) Washington (103) Washington DC (1) West Virginia (37) Wisconsin (77) Wyoming (1) 
Categories
 Select Category Abandonment Abduction Abuse Accident Alcohol Amber Alert Animal Cruelty Armed Robbery Arson Asphyxiation Assault Attempted Murde... Attempted Rape Attempted Suici... babysitter Beating Bestiality Biting Bribery Bullying Burglary Burning Cannibalism Carjacking Case Updates Celebrity Child Abuse Child Endangerm... Child Molestati... Child Murder Child Neglect Child Pornograp... Conspiracy Contamination Contributing to... Corpse Abuse Cracked Spine Crime Crime Screen criminal mischi... Cyber-bullying daily bite disorderly cond... Domestic Violen... Drowning Drugs Drugs and Alcoh... Drunk Driving Drunk In Public Ederly Abuse Entertainment Extortion Facebook Failure to Noti... False Report Familicide Featured fight Filicide Fratricide fraud gang Hanging Harassment Hate Crime Hazing Hit and Run Home Invasion Honor Killing Imprisonment Incest Indecent Exposu... Infanticide Interviews Intimidation Juvenile Kidnapping Kids Who Kill Killing Spree malpractice Manslaughter Mariticide Mass Murder masturbation Matricide Mauled Mental Illness Method Minister Missing Person Molestation movie Movie Movie Poster Mugshot Murder Murder-for-Hire Murder-suicide Mutilation Myspace Mystery Necrophilia neglect Negligence News Obscenity Parenticide Patricide Pedophile Peeping Tom pervert Podcast Poisoning Police Brutatli... Pornography prank Prostitution Public Indecenc... Rape reality bites Reckless Drivin... Reckless Endang... Resisting Arres... Reviews Road Rage Robbery school shooting Serial Killer Sex Sex Offender sexting Sexual Abuse Sexual Assault Sexual Battery Sexual Exploita... Sexual Miscondu... Shooting shooting spree Shoplifting Short Story Site Announceme... Site News Smothering Smuggling Sodomy Solicitation Solicitation Sororicide Spousal Abuse Stabbing Stalking Starvation Statutory Rape Strangulation student Suffocation Suicide Suspicious Deat... Tampering teacher Theft Threats Torture Trailer unlawful restra... Uxoricide Vandalism Vehicular Homic... Video Vigilante voyeurism Weird News When Animals At... 
Archives
 Select Month July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 June 2007 May 2007 April 2007 July 2006 ADVERTISE WITH US! 
 
 
Kickass Sites

 Bonnie! Crime Crawlers Fark Kindertrauma Muggn Obvious Winner Police Daily The Weekly Vice To the Chest WordPress Plugins World Gone Mad 
 
 
DREAMINDEMON.COM Copyright©2004 - 2011 DREAMIN&apos; DEMON LLC·Except where otherwise noted , content on this site is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License · DreaminDemon Blood Red theme by Lee Malta .
 
 WordPress · Log in · Dashboard
	</body>
</document>
