<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000884" url="http://menusubway.com/potbelly-kitchen-caters-to-chicagos-cravings/" time="2012-07-12-16:14" support="5" score="0.0072916471187233385" bingtitle="Potbelly Kitchen Caters to Chicago’s Cravings | Subway Menu" webtitle="Potbelly Kitchen Caters to Chicagos Cravings | Subway Menu">
			<query id="000216" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000529" bing-rank="249"/>
			<query id="000211" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="000523" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000528" bing-rank="119"/>
	<description>... sandwiches, assorted dry cereals and a tray of ... Steer clear of traffic with nuvi&apos;s traffic receiver by ... Can You Eat Healthy at a Fast Food Restaurant? A Healthy Food ...</description>
	<body>
		Subway Menu A Healthy Fast Food Skip to content 
 Home Subway $5 Menu Subway application online Subway Breakfast Menu Subway Catering Service Subway Franchise Subway Menu Coupons Subway Menu Prices Subway nutrition Facts Subway Sandwiches Privacy Policy 
 ← Submarine Sandwich Jobs at Subway The Healthy Fast Food Trap → 
Potbelly Kitchen Caters to Chicago’s Cravings
 Posted on May 11, 2011 by admin 

 
CHICAGO–Chicago’s own Potbelly Sandwich Shop has opened its new Potbelly Kitchen, catering to the city’s Downtown business district for early-morning breakfast meetings, board room lunch buffets, working dinners and office-wide afternoon coffee-cookie-shake-breaks.

Combining new menu features such as a hot breakfast bar and Build-Your-Own sandwich and salad bars with toasty warm sandwiches, freshly baked cookies, chips and drinks, Potbelly Kitchen caters to groups of 20 or more.

“When you have that undeniable‘gotta get a Potbelly sandwich urge’, we’re there for office meetings and events,”said Pam Kopacz, Potbelly Kitchen’s General Manager, who previously has led restaurant operations at the Madison and Franklin Chicago Loop Potbelly Sandwich Shop location for eight years.“We’re helping people satisfy their hunger whether they’re in a jam for a fast order or planning an event at a later date.”

The new Potbelly Kitchen caters to Chicago businesses and residences in an area bounded by Chicago Avenue on the north, Polk Street on the south, Racine Avenue on the west and Lake Michigan on the east. Delivered straight to their door and fully set-up, Potbelly Kitchen customers need only come prepared to eat fresh, tasty food. Fresh fruit, veggie plates and the Chicken Parmesan sandwich bar are just a few of the great new Potbelly Kitchen catering offerings.

“Our shops serve great tasting food, freshly made, and we’re doing the same at the Potbelly Kitchen,”Kopacz added.

For breakfast, the catering menu features scrambled eggs, bacon, potatoes, sausage, hot breakfast sandwiches, assorted dry cereals and a tray of assorted bakery items. Potbelly’s Originals and Skinnys sandwiches are available for lunch or later, as well as a new Deli Sandwich Bar platter, filled with a variety of meat and cheeses so people can create their own sandwiches. Also new is a Hot Sandwich Bar with a choice of Meatballs-N-Marinara, Chicken Parmesan or Italian beef sandwiches.

To complete the meal, Potbelly is offering a new build your own Salad Bar with fresh greens and an array of fresh toppings.

Individual shops will continue to fill catering requests for groups of less than 20 people. Orders for groups of 20 or more can be placed online at http://www.potbelly.com or by calling Potbelly Kitchen at 1-773-POTBELLY.

 

Soup r Sandwich is not your regular sandwich shop! We offer fresh salads, soups and sandwiches with unique flavor combinations made each day. We have a commitment to offer a healthy and tasty lunch nothing fried, no extra salt added and lean meats.
 
Recommended Reading / Products:
 Garmin nüvi 1300 4.3-Inch Widescreen Portable GPS Navigator The NUVI1300 4.3&quot; Ultra Thin GPS Navigator features a wide screen ultra slim design (approximately 25% thinner than previous models), enhanced user interface, ecoRoute, public transit mode and text-to-speech. The nuvi 1300 offers pedestrian navigation capability enabled through optional CityXplorer maps. CityXplorer maps are available for select tourist destinations in North America and Europe and can easily be downloaded directly to the nuvi. The nuvi&apos;s enhanced user interface features improved graphics and a new slide control for menu operation, while ecoRoute suggests fuel-efficient routes to save drivers money and fuel. Also, Garmin&apos;s new public transit mode allows you to navigate using buses, tramway, metro and suburban rail systems. ecoRoute - Drivers can view suggestions for fuel-efficient navigation, conserving both money and fuel Public transit - Navigate using buses, tramway, metro and suburban rail systems with optional CityXplorer content. Available for download at garmin site. Where Am I? feature - Find the closest hospitals, police stations, gas stations, nearest address, intersection and coordinates Bright 4.3 diagonal color display; 480 x 272 pixels; WQVGA TFT display with white backlight Trip computer records mileage, max speed, total time and more Built-in travel kit includes features such as picture viewer, world clock, currency and measurement converters and calculator MicroSD memory card expansion slot Offers a 3-D mapping perspective, or 2-D overhead view Unit dimensions - 4.8W x 2.9H x 0.6D; Weight - 5.7 ounces. Built-in lithium-ion battery - Lasts up to four hours depending on usage. Includes sturdy suction cup mount that allows for easy adjustment and quick release POI loader program - Set up proximity alerts for school zones, create custom POIs and more Garmin nüvi 2460LMT 5-Inch Widescreen Bluetooth Portable GPS Navigator with Lifetime Map&amp;Traffic Updates The voice-activated 5&quot; large screen nuvi 2460LMT is so easy to use you just talk to it. Its hands-free calling compatible and comes with FREE lifetime maps and traffic. A multi-point route planner automatically sorts multiple destinations into an efficient route. Includes lane assist with junction view, trafficTrends historical traffic, myTrends predictive routing, and speaks street names.Includes Free Lifetime Map UpdatesWith free Lifetime Map and Traffic updates, you always have the most up-to-date maps, points of interest and navigation information available at your fingertips. Traffic information is updated constantly, and map updates are available for download up to 4 times a year. Both features are ready to go, right out of the box, with no subscription or update fees and no expiration dates.Speak Commandsnuvi 2460LMT not only tells you where to turn but listens to your spoken commands. With its innovative speech recognition, you can control nuvi with your voice - allowing you to keep both hands on the wheel. Simply wake up nuvi with a customizable voice command and begin speaking menu options that are clearly displayed on the screen. Tell nuvi &quot;Find Address&quot; and speak an address to start navigating.Experience nuRoute Technology with trafficTrends and myTrendnuvi 2460LMT includes nuRoute technology with trafficTrends historical traffic and myTrends predictive routing. With trafficTrends, your nuvi 2460LMT automatically learns daytime trends for traffic flow to improve your routes and better predict your estimated time of arrival based on time of day and day of week. With myTrends, when you save your regular destinations in your &quot;Favorites,&quot; your nuvi 2460LMT will, over time, begin to figure out where you&apos;re going even without your telling it! It provides time of arrival and relevant traffic information. So whether you&apos;re driving Garmin nüvi 1370/1370T 4.3-Inch Widescreen Bluetooth GPS Navigator with Maps of North America&amp;Europe and Lifetime Traffic The NUVI1370T 4.3&quot; Ultra Thin GPS Navigator features a widescreen ultra slim design (approximately 25% thinner than previous models), enhanced user interface, ecoRoute, public transit mode and text-to-speech. The n vi 1370T offers pedestrian navigation capability enabled through optional CityXplorer maps. CityXplorer maps are available for select tourist destinations in North America and Europe and can easily be downloaded directly to the nuvi. The nuvi&apos;s enhanced user interface features improved graphics and a new slide control for menu operation, while ecoRoute suggests fuel-efficient routes to save drivers money and fuel. Also, Garmin&apos;s new public transit mode allows you to navigate using buses, tramway, metro and suburban rail systems. Steer clear of traffic with nuvi&apos;s traffic receiver by receiving alerts about traffic delays and road construction that lie ahead on your route. Map data is provided by NAVTEQ Bluetooth wireless technology, enables hands-free calling with a compatible phone ecoRoute - Drivers can view suggestions for fuel-efficient navigation, conserving both money and fuel Speed limit indicator - unit displays speed limits for most major roads Public transit - Navigate using buses, tramway, metro and suburban rail systems with optional CityXplorer content. Download at garmin website Where Am I? feature - Find closest hospitals, police stations, gas stations, nearest address, intersection and coordinates Bright 4.3 diagonal color display; 480 x 272 pixels; WQVGA TFT display with white backlight Trip computer records mileage, max speed, total time Built-in travel kit includes picture viewer, world clock, currency and measurement converters and calculator MicroSD memory card slot Offers 3-D mapping, or 2-D overhead view Dimensions - 4.8W x 2.9H x 0.6D; Weight - 5.7 ounces Built-in lithium-ion battery - Lasts up to four hours depending on usage Includes suction cup 
Related Posts:

 Get A Variety Of Meals At A Pizza Restaurant A Delicious Sandwich Will Quiet Your Rumbling Tummy Subway menu Nutritious Fast Food–Enriches you Healthy and Trendy Fayetteville Restaurants 
 This entry was posted in Subway Menu and tagged Caters , Chicago&apos;s , Cravings , Kitchen , Potbelly . Bookmark the permalink . ← Submarine Sandwich Jobs at Subway The Healthy Fast Food Trap → 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 
 
 Search for: 
Recent Posts

 Subway Menu Coupons Subway job How to Win Free Subway Coupons Subway Sandwich Coupons-Is it Really Worth Your Time to Use These Coupons? Can You Eat Healthy at a Fast Food Restaurant? A Healthy Food Choice With Subway Diet Subway Sandwich Sauces What are Subway restaurant operation hours? 100% Proven Diet Plan Lose 5 Pounds in a Week Subway Coupon–Printable Subway Coupons 
 
Categories

 sub sandwiches Subway coupons subway franchise Subway Job Subway Menu subway menu nutrition subway menu prices Subway Weight Loss 
 
Tags
 Best Better Choice Coupon coupons Diet Exactly Famous fast food Franchise franchises FREE Healthy Jared Joke Just Known Less Little Look Loss Meals menu money Need Nutrition Opportunities Price print Prior Quizno&apos;s Restaurant Sandwich Sandwiches save Story Subs Subway subway $5 menu subway coupons subway menu Them ways Weight 
 Subway Menu Proudly powered by WordPress.
	</body>
</document>
