<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000380" url="http://www.maxim.com/rides/kam-heskin" time="2012-07-12-15:35" support="1" score="0.00032267983077455167" bingtitle="Kam Heskin | Maxim" webtitle="Kam Heskin | Maxim">
			<query id="000560" bing-rank="249"/>
	<description>... FOR THE FRY BOYS: “I’ve worked at every fast-food restaurant and ... chivalry in a man, where he’ll pick up the bill ... Give a Gift</description>
	<body>
		Skip to main content 
Search form
 Search 
User menu
 
 Subscribe Give a Gift 
 
Main menu
 
 Girls 
 Girls of Maxim Hometown Hotties Today&apos;s Girl Hot 100 Maxim Gamer Girl 
 Sports 
 The Big Leagues UFC Other Sports Girls of Sports Maxim Action Sports Maxim Olympics Maxim Campus Challenge 
 Entertainment 
 Gaming Movies TV Music Comics 
 Gadgets&amp;Rides 
 Gadgets Rides Torture Tests Gift Guides 
 Upkeep 
 Clothes Grooming Fitness Money Keeping Up With Hotties 
 Vices 
 Booze Food Travel Gambling Sex&amp;Relationships Las Vegas 
 Tough S#&amp;t 
 Military Maximum Warrior True Crime Scars 
 Funny 
 The Dump Blog Found Porn Beat This Caption Jokes Comedians Stupid Clips 
 Maxim TV 
 
Main menu
 Home Girls Home Girls of Maxim Hometown Hotties Today&apos;s Girl Hot 100 Maxim Gamer Girl Sports Home The Big Leagues UFC Other Sports Girls of Sports Maxim Action Sports Maxim Olympics Maxim Campus Challenge Entertainment Home Gaming Movies TV Music Comics Gadgets&amp;Rides Home Gadgets Rides Torture Tests Gift Guides Upkeep Home Clothes Grooming Fitness Money Keeping Up With Hotties Vices Home Booze Food Travel Gambling Sex&amp;Relationships Las Vegas Tough S#&amp;t;Home Military Maximum Warrior True Crime Scars Funny Home The Dump Blog Found Porn Beat This Caption Jokes Comedians Stupid Clips Maxim TV Home 
Gadgets&amp;Rides
 
 Gadgets Rides Torture Tests Gift Guides 
 Previous - POPULAR STORIES - 
 Party With The Hometown Hotties 1 of 20 SOUL by Ludacris. Enter For A Chance To Win 2 of 20 Enter to Win a Trip to Spring Break 2013! 3 of 20 Maxim Action Sports 4 of 20 Maxim Olympics 5 of 20 Hometown Hotties 6 of 20 The 2012 Hot 100 List 7 of 20 Malin Akerman 8 of 20 12 Best Fake TV Bands 9 of 20 Hanging Out with the Stars of Finding Bigfoot 10 of 20 Get Hometown Hotties In Your Pocket 11 of 20 Women in Black 12 of 20 Rosie Huntington-Whiteley 13 of 20 MAXIM: Subscribe Today! 14 of 20 Dawn Olivieri 15 of 20 Maxim&apos;s Sexiest Singers 16 of 20 The Newest 4G Gadgets 17 of 20 8 Great Fighters Who Became Kickass Actors (... 18 of 20 MAXIM: Subscribe Today! 19 of 20 Dwight Howard and His Joyrides 20 of 20 
 Next Rides 
 FRIES WITH THAT? Kam Heskin conquered haunting memories of an awkward childhood, a failed career in fast food and a stint on Sunset Beach to find professional success in Tomcats .

 TIPS FOR THE FRY BOYS: “I’ve worked at every fast-food restaurant and menial job there is. And I got fired from them all. At Taco Bell, they made me a sweeper. They kept me away from the food. One time a woman called me over to complain about her brown lettuce. I tried to help her, but the other employees ignored me. Finally, I shouted, ‘Guys, there’s something wrong with the lettuce!’ The manager was livid. You can’t say that in front of customers.”

 WANTED: FRANKENSTEIN WITH CASH: “I’m attracted to strength in a man. Not just physical—though I do have a thing for broad shoulders—but the kind of strength of character that means he can be his own person and allow me to do my thing. I don’t like cheapness. I like chivalry in a man, where he’ll pick up the bill and not go over it, saying, ‘You had this; I had that.’”

 THAT’S OUR FAVORITE POWER TOOL, TOO! “I love drills. I’m a drilling fanatic. Whenever I move, the first thing I do is get out the drill and start hanging pictures. The heavier the picture, the better. I fix things while my boyfriend is in the kitchen scrambling eggs or something. Also, the electric saw. I love the heat and smell of cutting wood.”

“I was a really late bloomer. I didn’t talk to a lot of people in junior high and high school. No boyfriends. I didn’t think of myself as pretty at all. I had a silly perm and wore glasses, and I was so skinny.”

Kam Heskin

Kam Heskin

Kam Heskin

Kam Heskin

Kam Heskin

Kam Heskin

Kam Heskin

Kam Heskin

Kam Heskin
 
Kam Heskin
 

 
Subscribe to Maxim Magazine | Download Maxim Apps 


 
Follow us:
 Follow @maximmag 
Latest Video
 Red Bull Wake Open 2012 
Get Maxim Today
 
 Only $1.00 an Issue! Go Digital, get it anywhere Give it as a gift 


 Subscribe FROM OUR PARTNERS 
 The 20 Hottest Photos of Macri Elena Velez The 20 Hottest Photos of Selena Gomez 
 
 The Sexiest Non-American Athletes to Look for in the London Games The 10 Most Anticipated College Football Games of 2012 
 
 15 Movie Sequels You Didn&apos;t Know Existed A Tribute to Marisa Miller 
 Expand/Collapse 
Subscribe to Maxim
 Close 
 83% off the newsstand price $1 an Issue That&apos;s like getting 20 issues FREE! 
 Subscribe 
 The Worst Church Sign Fails The 20 Hottest Photos of Alena Blohm Muse Wants to Hype You Up for the Olympics Even the Cookie Monster Is Covering Call Me Maybe The 20 Hottest Photos of Kim Cloutier 
 
 Steve Nash Arrives in LA, Ready to Be a Laker Jessica Alba Bikini Photos Who Would You Rather, Magic Mike Wives Edition: Camilla vs. Jenna Bikini-Clad Scarlett Johansson Gets Some Sun Savanna Guthrie Officially Co-Anchor, Lauer Gets Anchor Wood 
 
 Pipeline Porn Jumping for a Purpose Red Bull Primed: Trey Hardee X Games 18: Meet Garrett Reynolds X Games 18: Interview with Ryan Decenzo 
 
 Building the Batmobile Destroyed Arcade Game Drunk Guy Serenades His Cat Andre Agassi vs. Ball Girl Worst Gunshot Reaction Ever 
 
 
 
Categories
 
 Girls Sports Entertainment Gadgets&amp;Rides Upkeep Vices Tough S#&amp;t Funny Maxim TV 
 
The Magazine
 
 Renew Subscription Give a Gift Order Back Issues Customer Service Subscribe Digital Editions Magazine Advertising 
 
Popular
 
 The 2012 Hot 100 List Hometown Hotties Girls Who Love Maxim Submit Images to Maxim Found Porn Submission 
 
About Maxim
 
 Contact Us Careers Subscription Issues Digital Advertising Privacy Policy Terms&amp;Conditions Site Map 
 
&quot;Maxim Digital&quot;, &quot;MAXIM&quot;, &quot;MAXIM ONLINE&quot;, &quot;Maximonline.com&quot;, &quot;Maxim.com&quot; and the &quot;M&quot; Logo&quot; are registered trademarks owned by Alpha Media Group Inc. &quot;Maxim.com&quot; and &quot;MAXIM TO GO&quot; are trademark owned by Alpha Media Group Inc.
	</body>
</document>
