<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000917" url="http://www.freewebs.com/clittle/index.htm" time="2012-07-12-16:16" support="1" score="0.0006396208170128621" bingtitle="Games,vids,pics and hints all in one | Get a game find a hint" webtitle="Games,vids,pics and hints all in one | Get a game find a hint">
			<query id="001148" bing-rank="237"/>
	<description>Win the Gold cup in ALL the Single Player Races ... Take any car and slowly push it through the barricade, as ... While “just” a fast food restaurant, you will want to stay ...</description>
	<body>
		Games,vids,pics and hints all in one

Get a game find a hint
 Home 
 Home hints and glitches also Videos Funny vids Play my games Chavs 
 
 Welcome
 
 Welcome 

 Welcome to my website I have created this to help you throught out the site you&apos;ll find cheats , hints , codes , games , music , funny videos and just videos about the games the games . If you are unsure or want surgest on anything just e-mail me at cal_in_da_house@hotmail.com dont be afaid to just do it . Now you just scroll down and check out my site .                          

                                                                                                   

  
 
 Some Tips And Glitches
 
 

 Send me some Glitches and tips also hints maybe you ll find some Tips , Glitches and Hints for you ( Only for xbox 360) 

  Inclueding Call Of duty 3 , Gears Of War , Lost Planet , Test Drive Unlimited , Project Gotham Racing 3 , Perfect Dark Zero and Saints Row. 

  

 

  

 Call Of Duty 3 Glitches and Tips 
   
      
 
 Purple Heart 
 One of the secret unlocks for COD 3 is the purple heart: when you die 10 times continually on same mission you will achive this unlock (5 points) 

 

 
   
 
 Hints 
 
   
 
 
 
   
 
 Big Air 
 
 &quot;EXTREME! Found a big jump and caught some air&quot; - That&apos;s what it says when you have unlocked it, but you get the point! Note: Only in single player&amp;easily done on &quot;Night Drop&quot; 

 PICS!!Call Of Duty 3 And Videos 
 
   
 
 
 


 
        
  
 
 
   
 
 
               

 


 
   
 
 Glitches 
 
   
 
 
 
   
 
 how to float over a car 

 Entry Location: 
Poisson (multiplayer)

 All you have to do is go to any nearby unusable open bed truck in a tank, and then park as close and parallel as possible to it. Then you&apos;ll have to aim towards the truck and then jump out (the X button) while holding the left analog stick toward the direction of the of the the truck. If done correctly you&apos;ll be standing in mid-air. 

 
 
   
 
 
 
   
 
 
 
   
 
 Through blocked windows 

 Entry Location: 
Blown up houses windows

 When you come to a building that has the door a mile away, if the house is blown up, go to one of the windows that has shutters of on it. Run up and jump then quickly crouch, you will land on the window then just walk through to the other side. It saves a lot of hassle trying to find doors  

 
 
   
 
 Places they never look 

 Entry location: Les Ormes 

  

 In the town center next to the round about look for a sign saying Soze Genciance Vare. Face the sign so your really close looking at the sign on your front. Behide you will be a wall , look for an entrance and then you&apos;ll see some bushes , walk into them to the back then turn to face the way you come in and go prone , you can take a break now (thats the life)  

  

 Found By Alex Liddle. 
 
   
 
 
 
   
 
 Get into house on Eder Dam 
 
 Park a bike next to the door of the house on the south east side of the map then you get out of the bike and you will go through the door. If you get pushed away from the door the bike is to close, if nothing happens you are too far away  
 
 
 
 
 
 
   
 
 
 
   
 
 
 Ask about queries on any games in the Ask box!!!Or just talk its free!!! 
 
   
 
 
 
   
 
 
 


  

  

 

  

  

  

 Project Gothham Racing 3 

 1. Earn additional Kudos in a Street Race by raising the difficulty level and then beating the target.

 2. All-wheel drive (AWD) cars have outstanding traction, making them excellent performers in Timed Runs in the rain. Choose the Skyline GTR and Feroce for Street Races.

 3. Hitting a cone is just like hitting a wall.

 4. As you advance through the levels, the powerslide is critical. A powerslide has three steps: (1) brake before the turn; (2) head into the turn, and press the hand brake to force the back end around; (3) when the car aligns with the turn&apos;s exit, release the hand brake and resume acceleration.

 Top Hint: How to earn Kudos during a race: 
* Slide bonus: Points are awarded based on speed and length of slide.
* Cone Gates bonus: Drive through cleanly.
* Speed Gates bonus: Points are awarded based on car&apos;s speed as it passes through speed gates.
* Clean Section bonus: Bonus is awarded for completing a track section without hitting anything.
- Award is based on length and difficulty of track.
* Overtake bonus: Earn 10 points for each car you pass during a race.
* Big Air bonus: Award is based on length of time car is in air.
* Two-Wheels bonus: Award is based on length of time car is on two wheels.
* Time bonus: Some events award Kudos for time remaining on the clock when the race ends.
* Combo bonus: Points are based on the number of Kudos-earning maneuvers you string together.
 
 

  

  

 Perfect Dark Zero 

 Unlockable weapons and Xbox 360 Acheivements for Perfect Dark Zero 
 
 Perfect Dark Zero Xbox 360 Acheivements 

 There are allot of Xbox 360 Acheivements for Perfect Dark Zero. They are all listed below as well as how to get them. As with all Xbox 360 games the total when you receive them all will add up to 1000 Gamerscore points. 
 

 1 Co-op Mission On Dark Agent 
Complete 1 Co-Op misson on Dark Agent Difficulty 
 1 Solo Mission On Dark Agent 
Complete 1 Solo misson on Dark Agent Difficulty 
 10 Explosive Kills 
Get 10 kills using explosive in any Multiplayer modes 
 10 Flags Captured 
Capture 10 Flags in Capture The Flag mode 
 10 Headshot Kills 
Get 10 Headshots kills in any Multiplayer mode 
 10 Kills in Killcount 
Get 10 kills in Killcount mode 
 10 Kills in Team Killcount 
Get 10 kills in Team Killcount mode 
 10 Melee Kills 
Get 10 Melee kills in an Multiplayer mode 
 10 Minutes Survived 
Survive 10 minutes in Onlsaught mode 
 10 Players Infected 
Infect 10 Players in Infection mode 
 10 Rounds Survived 
Survive 10 Rounds of Eradication mode 
 10 Sniper Kills 
Get 10 Sniper kills in any Multiplayer modes 
 10 Territories Held 
Score 10 points in Territory Gain mode 
 10,000 CR Property Destroyed 
Destroye 10K CR of property in Sabotage 
 100 Explosive Kills 
Get 100 kills using explosive in any Multiplayer modes 
 100 Flags Captured 
Capture 100 Flags in Capture The Flag mode 
 100 Headshot Kills 
Get 100 Headshots kills in any Multiplayer mode 
 100 Kills in Killcount 
Get 100 kills in Killcount mode 
 100 Kills in Team Killcount 
Get 100 kills in Team Killcount mode 
 100 Melee Kills 
Get 100 Melee kills in an Multiplayer mode 
 100 Minutes Survived 
Survive for 100 minutes Onslaught. 
 1000 Explosive Kills 
Get 1000 Explosive kills in any Multiplayer Mode 
 1000 Headshot Kills 
Get 1000 Headshot kills in any Multiplayer Mode 
 1000 Kills in Killcount 
Get 1000 Kills in Killcount Mode 
 1000 Kills in Team Killcount 
Get 1000 Kills in Team Killcount Mode 
 1000 Melee Kills 
Get 1000 Melee kills in any Multiplayer Mode 
 1000 Player Infected 
Infect 1000 Players in Infection mode 
 1000 Rounds Survived 
Survive 1000 Rounds of Eradication mode 
 1000 Sniper Kills 
Get 1000 Sniper kills in any Multiplayer Mode 
 5 Co-op Missions On Dark Agent 
5 Co-Op missons on Dark Agent Difficulty 
 5 Solo Mission On Dark Agent 
Complete 5 Solo missons on Dark Agent Difficulty 
 Complete Co-Op Agent 
Complete Co-Op on Agent Difficulty 
 Complete Co-Op Secret Agent 
Complete Co-Op on Secret Agent Difficulty 
 Complete Single Agent 
Complete Single Player on Agent Difficulty 
 Complete Single Dark Agent 
Complete Single Player on Dark Agent Difficulty 
 Complete Single Perfect Agent 
Complete Single Player on Perfect Agent Difficulty 
 Complete Single Secret Agent 
Complete Single Player on Secret Agent Difficulty 
 Completed Co-Op Dark Agent 
Complete Co-Op on Dark Agent Difficulty 
 Completed Co-Op Perfect Agent 
Complete Co-Op on Perfect Agent Difficulty 
 Played 10 Dark-Ops Games 
Play 10 Dark-Ops games 
 Played 10 Deathmatch Games 
Play 10 Deathmatch games 
 Played 100 Dark-Ops Games 
Play 100 Dark-Ops games 
 Played 100 Deathmatch Games 
Play 100 Deathmatch games 
 Played 1000 Dark-Ops Games 
Play 1000 Dark-Ops games 
 Played 1000 Deathmatch Games 
Play 1000 Deathmatch games 

  

  

  

 Test Drive Umlimited 

 Test Drive Unlimited Cheats 
Cheats are cheats, codes, passwords, or other tricks that can be used to help you beat a game or otherwise get more out of it. Here is where you&apos;ll find all of the various cheats and codes that are available for this game. 


 180 in Heavy Traffic 
When you reach the Champion level a speed challange opens up in the middle west of the island.. all you have to do is get an enzo and another fast a class car....at the start spin it around and ride the shoulder... if its a stage 3 enzo you should hit 180 in about 7 sec...then wash rinse repeat....easy way to make money Edit 

 
 paint shops 
There are three regular paint shops. One is on the middle west coast, close to the Fatal At-track-thon time challenge and the Semporio gift shop. Another one is south downtown, close to the Foxx gift shop and the Diana supermodel challenge. The third one&apos;s north-east, close to the Drive in Kallua Beach and Beach Route multiplayer challenges. The deluxe paint shop is south-east, close to the Around the Corner time and the Razor&apos;s Edge multiplayer challenges. 


 Easy Million Dollars 
On Expert Level, The Millionaire Challenge will reward the winner a hefty sum of...one million dollars! And the challenge isn&apos;t even hard. An easy way to victory is use the MV Agusta motorcycle upgraded to level 3. Repeat the race for more money, more money, and more money! Easy Money - Winding Road 
Located at the southeast corner, take the winding road challenge to bank $10k in just thirty seconds. 
 The winding road challenge neither has a finish line nor a complicated requirement. In fact, it&apos;s pretty easy: hit 140 mph on a winding road. 
 Right when the challenge starts, jump out of the start line, turn around immediately, and head towards the nice, straight street. There, you can max out your speed as little as 15 seconds. Don&apos;t forget to hit the A-button when you&apos;re done. Repeat the process for some serious cash. 

 Best Cars 
There is no single best car, but there are better cars for each category.
Group G: AC 289, Lamborghini and Shelby Daytona
Group F: Alfa Romero and Audi TT
Group E: Skyline GTR
Group D: Maserati GranSport, Aston Martin DB9 and the Lotus Esprit
Group C: Corvette C6 or Noble M12
Group B: Corvette C6 is everything you need
Group A: Ferrari Enzo 
 

 

 
 
 Editing challenges 
After you&apos;ve unlocked editor mode, you can create challenges at any time, playing online or off. Still, you must be playing online and visit a drive-in in order to share your custom challenges with the rest of the game&apos;s community. 

 Playlist 
You can create up to four custom playlists on your Xbox 360 console. To make them compatible with your in-game car radio, their filenames must contain the keyword Testdrive. 


 
 Cars 
 Description: Cars and tracks and dealerships and more.
 Where Entered: Complete certain tasks to unlock the items.   
 UNLOCKABLE HOW TO UNLOCK   Alfa Romeo 8c Competizione Get 1st place in the Tour of the Island race. All Challenges ope Get Champion rank. Bike dealerships Find all the car dealerships. Chrysler Firepower Concept car Complete all Courier driving missions. Chrysler ME Four-Twelve Get Gold in all the Race challenges Ford Island Get Expert Ranking Ford Mustang GT-R Concept Past all Top Model driving missions Ford Shelby GR-1 Concept Get Gold in all the Speed challenges Oahu Raceway Get Pro Rank Paint shops Get Gold on Around the Crater Race Tuner shops Achieve Amateur rank. Volkswagen W12 Coupe Get Gold in all the Time Challenges Volkswagen W12 Roadster Beat all the Hitch-Hiker driving missions Walmaealamae Haven of Peace Find all the roads on the island 
 
 
 


 UNLOCKABLE HOW TO UNLOCK   Single Player Vic. - Level 1 (20) Win the Gold cup in 5 Single Player challenges. Single Player Vic. - Level 2 (20) Win the Gold cup in 10 Single Player challenges. Single Player Vic. - Level 3 (20) Win the Gold cup in 20 Single Player challenges. Single Player Vic. - Level 4 (30) Win the Gold cup in 40 Single Player challenges. Single Player Vic. - Level 5 (40) Win the Gold cup in 60 Single Player challenges. Single Player Vic. - Level 6 (60) Win the Gold cup in all the Single Player challenges. Single Player Time Challenges (15) Win the Gold cup in all the Single Player Time challenges. Single Player Race Challenges (20) Win the Gold cup in ALL the Single Player Races challenges. Single Player Speed Challenges (10) Win the Gold cup in ALL the Single Player Speed challenges. Island Tour (10) Win the Gold cup in the Island Tour challenge. Multiplayer Vic. Level 1 (10) Win 3 multiplayer Ranked Races. Multiplayer Vic. Level 2 (20) Win 15 multiplayer Ranked Races. Multiplayer Vic. Level 3 (35) Win 30 multiplayer Ranked Races. Multiplayer Vic. Level 4 (60) Complete all the missions: Top-Model, Hitchhiker, Vehicle Transport or Courier Instant Challenge Victories (10) Win 5 matches in Instant Challenge Sharing Custom Challenges (10) In the Drive In, share 3 custom challenges Custom Challenge Victories (10) Win 2 matches in the custom challenge Drive In Club Member (10) Be a member in a Club Club Race Victories (10) Win 3 matches in Inter-Club Races Trade (10) Buy or sell a car to a member in Trade Ferrari Collector (20) Have 3 different Ferraris Lamborghini Collector (20) Have 3 different Lamborghini Mercedes-Benz Collector (15) Have 3 different Mercedes-Benz Chevrolet Collector (10) Have 3 different Chevrolet Aston Martin Collector (15) Have 3 different Aston Martin Ford Collector (10) Have 3 different Ford Bike Collector (10) Have 3 different bikes Ben Sherman Collector (10) Have 10 different Ben Sherman Gear *ecko unltd. Collector (10) Have 10 different *ecko unltd. Gear Tuner (10) In the Tuning Shop, buy a performance pack for your car Explorer (40) Explore every road on Oahu Easygoing Tourist (10) Drive 30 miles Steadfast Tourist (25) Drive 200 miles Traveller (30) Drive 400 miles Seasoned Traveller (35) Drive 1000 miles Eagle-Eyed Driver (40) Drive 5,000 miles Owner (20) Have 2 houses Real-Estate Tycoon (30) Have 15 houses Small Collector (15) Have 2 different cars Amateur Collector (20) Have 4 differet cars Confirmed Collector (25) Have 10 different cars Most Varied Collector (30) Have 20 different cars Extreme Collector (30) Have 50 different cars 
 
 

  

  

  

 Saints Row                                           

 

 Saints Row Passwords 
 Phone Numbers: Cheats, Rides, Help, and Funny messages... Pause the game and press the L or R Trigger until you reach your phone.
 Select DIAL and enter one of the following numbers then press CALL.
NOTE: The ( ) and - symbols are automatically entered for you, you just need the number. The only symbols you&apos;re required to enter are the # or * if contained in a number. Warning: The codes that have # in front of them are considered cheats and you won&apos;t get achievements doing this. 
 Password Effect 911 Ambulance (Restores Health) #42637867 Unlock Special GameStop T-Shirt Cheat (555) 018-0174 Eagleline Yellow (Taxi Service) 555-455-8008 TNA Taxi Service 555-5966 Eye for an Eye Voodoo 555-7296 On the Fence (Pawn Shop) 555-3863 Lik-a-Chick 555-6238 The Dead Cow 555-3493 Rim Jobs 555-9467 Legal Lee&apos;s 555-9473 Grounds for Divorce 555-5926 On The Rag Clothing #AMMO Infinite Ammo #10 God&apos;s Wrath (lightning strikes randomly) #66639 Give money 1-555-ITS-OVER Suicide Hotline 555-2626 Stocks 555-3765 Brown Baggers #SPRINT Infinite Sprint #Rocket Enables &quot;Give RPG Launcher&quot; #AS12Riot Enables &quot;Give AS12 Riot&quot; #12Gauge Enables &quot;Give 12 Gauge&quot; #Tombstone Enables &quot;Give Tombstone&quot; #T3KUrban Enables &quot;Give T3K Urban&quot; #GDHC50 Enables &quot;Give GDHC .50&quot; #Shepherd Enables &quot;Give .44 Shepherd&quot; #NR4 Enables &quot;Give NR4&quot; #Pipebomb Enables &quot;Give Pipe Bomb&quot; #Vice9 Enables &quot;Give Vice 9&quot; #Knife Enables &quot;Give Knife&quot; #Molotov Enables &quot;Give Molotov Cocktail&quot; #Grenade Enables &quot;Give Hand Grenade&quot; #268 Spawns an Ant #2855364 Spawn a Bulldog #732737 Spawns a Reaper (Hurst) #78682 Spawns a Quota #3378469 Spawns a Destiny #22766 Spawns a Baron #7288537 Spawns a Rattler 5552445 Chicken Ned #fullhealth Full Health #sunny clear skies #shogun Shogun in garage #66732374 Spawns a Nordberg in your g arage #262852623 Spawns an Anbulance in your garage #746486 Spawns a Shogun in your garage #5878423 Spawns a Justice in your garage #867839 Spawns a Vortex in your garage #936484 Spawns a Zenith in your garage #882727 Spawns a Tuasar in your garage #267667 Spawns a Cosmos in your garage #566636 Spawns a Komodo in your garage #pimpcane Gives a pimpcane shotgun #nocops No Cop Notoriety #nogangs No Gang Notoriety #Nightstick Enables &quot;Give Nightstick&quot; #936484 Enables &quot;Give Zenith&quot; #7288537 Enables &quot;Give Rattler&quot; #3373352623 Enables &quot;Give Fer De Lance&quot;, the best car in the game! #KEYSTONE Spawns &apos;Keystone&apos; in your garage #TAXI Spawns &apos;Taxi&apos; in your garage #BETSY Spawns &apos;Betsy&apos; in your garage #CAVALLARO Spawns &apos;Cavallaro&apos; in your garage #TRAXXMASTER Spawns &apos;TraxxMaster&apos; in your garage #HALBERD Spawns &apos;Halberd&apos; in your garage #843562 The Job #27409863 Give Ar-40 Xtnd Rifle #K6Krukov Give K6Krukov (555) 455 8008 TNA Taxi (555) 819 8415 Big Willys Cab #FBI Spawns FBI #mag Spawn Mag in Garage #Macmanus Gives McManus Sniper Rifle #hollywood Spawns Hollywood in Garage 555-2564 On Thin Ice 555-MART Crash Landing #BaseBall Spawn BaseBall Bat #Newman Spawns &quot;Newman&quot; in your garage (Mail Truck) #Macanus Gives you the &quot;McManus&quot; sniper rifle #Anchor Spawns &quot;Anchor&quot; in your garage (Newsvan) #Quasar Spawns &quot;Quasar&quot; in your garage #Hammerhead Spawns &quot;Hammerhead&quot; in your garage #Compton Spawns &quot;Compton&quot; in your garage #Baron Spawns &quot;Baron&quot; in your garage #Gunslinger Spawns &quot;Gunslinger&quot; in your garage 555-3248 Impressions Clothing #84816 Spawns a Titan #87935 Spawn a Voxel #34836 Spawn a Five-O #635766 Spawn an Nelson #947266 Spawn an Zircon #2668534437 Spawn an Bootlegger #94667 Spawn an Zimos #2277429 Spawn an Capshaw #742462438 Spawn an Richochet #67468 Spawn an NRG V8 #52383792 Spawn an La Fuerza #66254642473 Spawn an Mockingbird #5225722248 Spawn an Jackrabbit #42664225 Spawn an Hannibal #8277489 Spawn an Varsity #84676463 Spawn an Thorogod #money $1000 cash 555-6328 Freckle Bitch&apos;s Phone Number #778 Repairs the car you&apos;re in #38452277 Makes cars deliberately try to kill you. #SKRSPREE Give SKR-7 Spree #662677 Deletes Police Notorioty(Not Infinite) 
 
 Getting through red barricades in Demo version 

 Take any car and slowly push it through the barricade, as your body does not allow you to. When the car door is half way inside the barricade and halfway outside the barricade, get in the car. Note: You may get stuck permanently. However, if done correctly you should be able to continue driving through the barricade until you are far enough to get to the other side and exit the car. 
 
 Achievements 

 Complete the following achievements to unlock Xbox Live Gamerscore points:

Colombian Made (40 points): Take over Los Carnales territory.
Regicide (40 points): Take over Vice Kings territory.
Road Warrior (40 points): Take over Westside Rollerz territory. 
Ruler of Stilwater (160 points): Help the 3rd Streets Saints take over Stilwater.
Thug (10 points): Reach a TrueSkill rank of Thug in any multi-player mode.
Killa (20 points): Reach a TrueSkill rank of Killa in any multi-player mode.
Gangsta (40 points): Reach a TrueSkill rank of Gangster in any multi-player mode.
Kingpin (80 points): Reach a TrueSkill rank of Kingpin in any multi-player mode.
Penny Pincher (10 points): Earn $1,000,000 in the city of Stilwater.
Grifter (10 points): Earn $200,000 in Insurance Fraud.
Shopaholic (10 points): Acquire 100 clothing and jewelry items for your single player wardrobe.
Coupon Clipper (10 points): Purchase 100 clothing and jewelry items for your multi-player wardrobe.
Leader of the Pack (10 points): Acquire all 7 Homies.
Getting Up (10 points): Tag all tag locations hidden throughout Stilwater. 
Grease Monkey (10 points): Own a total of 50 cars.
Racket Lord (160 points): Complete all activities in Stilwater.
Contract Killer (10 points): Complete all of the Hitman locations.
Demo Demon (10 points): Complete all levels of Demolition Derby.
Fast and Furious (10 points): Complete all of the Hijacking locations and levels.
Fluffer (10 points): Complete all of the Escort locations and levels.
Pimp (10 points): Complete all the Snatch locations and levels.
Pusher (10 points): Complete all of the Drug Trafficking locations and levels.
Scavenger (10 points): Complete all of the Chop Shop locations. 
Tuner (10 points): Complete all of the Racing locations and levels.
Vandal (10 points): Complete all of the Mayhem locations and levels.
Bulletproof (10 points): Complete Co-op level Turbulence at the highest difficulty level.
Errand Boy (10 points): Complete Co-op level Mob Rule at the highest difficulty level.
Canonized (10 points): Join the 3rd Street Saints.
Reclamationist (10 points): Retake Saint&apos;s Row.
Additionally there are thirteen secret achievements, all of which are unidentified at this time. 
 
 Longer lasting stamina 

 To make your stamina last slightly longer than usual, rapidly tap RB for a longe r lasting sprint. 
 
 Robbing Friendly Fire and getting extra ammo 

 When robbing Friendly Fire you may notice some of the pedestrians will be looking at the g uns. Start a robbery and they will drop the guns in terror. After that you should be able to pick up the gun. 
 
 Scared homeless person 

 At the front of the drug store is usually a homeless person sleeping on the bench. Buy a 40.oz and get close to the character. Face them and drink the 40.oz to to slam it over his body. He will then scream and run in terror. 
 
 Get Out of the Demo Wall 

 In the Demo There are Red Walls that read Demo on them boxing you into the game area. You can leave the demo area by doing the following:

Get into a car, drive next to a demo wall making sure the drivers door is right next to it and exit the car. If you did this correctly you should be on the other side of the wall. On the other side of the wall inside the basket ball court you will find an AK-47. If you walk too far then the Demo will end. 
 
How to get a high police level quick!

Go to a store any store day or night and enter it. once inside hold up the shopkeeper. when he opens the safe let him sound the alarm and then kill him. when you have done that wait inside the store an equip yourself with a gun. notice that the police notority level keeps going up.
 
In-Game Unlockables

Finding and tagging each gangs tag locations will get you a reward as well as finding all the tag locations.

Unlockable - How to Unlock

&quot;Atrazione&quot; Exotic Car - Complete all 3 Hitman Activities
10% Stamina Boost - ALL Los Carnales tags
10% Stamina Boost - ALL Westside Rollerz tags
10% Stamina Boost - ALL Vice Kings tags
Anchor (car) - Suburb District/Misty Lane Escort
Attrazion - Truckyard District/Copperton Hikacking
Cheap car repair - Complete all chop shops
Dressed To Kill (clothing) - Airport District/Wardill Airport Escort 
Gold Plated GDHC .50 - Complete &quot;Projects Hitman&quot;
Grenade - Complete &quot;High End Retail Mayhem&quot;
Health regenerates fast - Complete all 3 Insurance Fraud Activities
Infinite Stamina - ALL tags found and sprayed
Jewelery - Suburb District/Tidal Spring Hijacking 
Leather Face - Complete all hijacking activities
Molotov Cocktail - Complete &quot;Barrio Mayhem&quot;
Pipe Bomb - Complete &quot;Suburbs Mayhem&quot;
Platinum AS12 Riot - Complete &quot;Airport Hitman&quot;
Platinum RPG Launcher - Complete all 3 Hitman Activities
Platinum T3K-Urban - Complete &quot;Chinatown Hitman&quot; 
Receive Discount When Repairing Car - Complete ALL Chop Shops
Reduced damage from bullets - Complete &quot;Adept Way Insurance Fraud&quot;
Reduced damage from cars - Complete &quot;Cecil Park Insurance Fraud&quot;
Reduced damage from explosions - Complete &quot;Chinatown Insurance Fraud&quot;
RPG Launcher - Complete all 3 Mayhem Activities
Samantha (homie) - Red Light District/Bavogian Plaza Escort
Special Variant of Hollywood - Complete Docks&amp;Warehouses Chop Shop
Special Variant of Ricochet - Complete Chinatown Chop Shop
Special Variant of Stiletto - Complete Downtown Chop Shop
The Job (car) - Complete all the activities
Titan - Airport District/Wardill Airport Hijacking
 
Unlock Zombie Lin

You must finish the Rollerz storyline, then call &quot;Eye for an Eye Voodoo&quot; at 555-5966. Zombie Lin will then be unlocked as a Homie.

 

 

 Unlock Cribs Complete Missions to unlock these Cribs. Each Crib contains a Weapon Cache, a safe, a save-point and a wardrobe. 
 Unlockable How to Unlock Price&apos;s Mansion Complete &quot;Semi-Charmed Life&quot; Saints Row Loft Crib Complete &quot;Back To Basics&quot; Benjamin King&apos;s Penthouse Complete &quot;Return Of The King&quot; Angelo Lopez&apos;s Beach House Complete &quot;What Goes Up...&quot; 
 

 Gang Tags around Stillwater    Click on the words to your left 

 

Welcome To Saints Row
 




The game starts off with your character taking a leisurely midnight stroll down 3rd street, a neighborhood under siege, in the gang infested town of Stilwater. Suddenly, all hell breaks loose when rival gangs clash over a recent tagging incident and your character is caught in the middle. Slightly injured and lucky to be alive, you are taken in by Julius Little, the leader of the 3rd Street Saints. After being jumped in, or as they call it these days canonized, you are officially inducted into the 3rd Street Saints and the game begins.



In order to rise up through the ranks you will need to earn respect, take on missions and complete activities as you fend off rival gangs and take over their territory. Not only do you have to watch your back for rival gangs, the streets fight back and the law is on every corner.





 

Whos Who In The Zoo


 




There are four main gangs in Stilwater: Vice Kings, Los Carnales, Westside Rollerz and the 3rd Street Saints. Each group specializes in different gang related activities.



 

Vice Kings


 




   


Benjamin King is an old school gangster from the 70s that has traded in his bandanna for a business suit. King is the leader of the Vice Kings, one of the largest gangs in Stilwater. The Vice Kings have successful businesses, on both sides of the fence, businesses that range from a thriving recording studio to big time brothels all over town. Benjamin King rubs shoulders with some of the most influential people in Stilwater and has high level police officials and corrupt politicians on the payroll. Second in command is Warren Williams, a second rate rapper dying to prove himself as a hard core gangster. Next in line is Anthony Green, long time friend of Benjamin King and high level enforcer for the VKs. Tanya Winters, a conniving woman who manipulated her way into running the Vice Kings prostitution racket. The Vice Kings color is yellow.





 

Westside Rollerz


 




   


The Westside Rollerz are primarily made up of Stilwaters Fast and the Furious crowd. The gang is made up of street racers and tuners that mainly run auto theft rings, chop shops and hijacking operations. The leader of the West Side Rollers is a muscle bound maniac named Joseph Price. Prices right hand man and master mechanic is Donny. Working behind the scenes, and some say controlling the Rollerz, is Prices uncle, William Sharp.



 

Los Carnales


 




   


Easily the oldest gang in Stilwater, Los Carnales has been around for over 30 years. Founded by their father, Hector and Angelo Lopez now run the gang with the help of Victor Rodriguez, Los Carnales enforcer. Los Carnales has strong ties to Columbian drug lords and the proceeds from a rather brisk drug trade has helped them build and maintain the Los Carnales empire for over three decades.





 

3rd Street Saints


 




   


The 3rd Street Saints are run by Julius Little. The Saints have reorganized under the leadership of Julius to take back 3rd street from rival gang members. The three main lieutenants in Saints Row are Johnny Gat, Dex and Troy. Lin, the highest ranking female lieutenant in the Saints, is currently working undercover as one of the Westside Rollerz.

 Info 

Anyone that has ever played the Grand Theft Auto series or one of the many knock offs will immediately recognize the junior-gangsta trying to come up through the ranks storyline but that isnt a knock against Saints Row. In fact, the story is actually pretty good and the voice acting is very well done.



Saints Row has a pretty robust character creation system that allows you to mold your player into almost anything you like, including a mirror image of yourself if you choose. If you are narcissistic and want to design your character to look just like you do, it is completely possible:



   




Looking at that picture, it is easy to see that you can mold your on-screen player into a virtual doppelganger, a spitting image of yourself. This adds new meaning to the term putting you in the game. The only thing you cant do is be a girl, female players are simply out of luck or, as they say in Saints Row, assed out.



Once you get started playing the game, you are told that in order to get anything done, you need respect. That phrase , uttered by Julius Little at your first gang meeting, is meant figuratively and literally.



 


 




In order to do any mission, you need respect. In order to get respect, you must do a bunch of low level activities like snatching hos f rom pimps and delivering them to brothels, street racing, demo derby activities, tagging and drug trafficking. Here is the kick though, each time you do a mission, it uses up a certain amount of the respect youve earned. This means that you will need to go get more respect between missions. While this is a great way to make the player do more things than just go from mission to mission and beat the game, it does hamper some of the free-roaming feel of the game a bit.



 


 




As you work your way through the missions, more of the story is revealed to your player. Finding your way from point A to point B is a snap thanks to the handy GPS equipped map. Simply open your map, put the pointer where you want to go, click the button and you have a handy GPS guide to help you reach your destination.



Once you complete a mission in a particular series, you will gain that territory and a new mission location will pop up on the map. Sometimes these new missions are simply gang strongholds or mini-missions but they can be just as difficult as regular mission. Once you gain an area on the map, that doesnt mean you are safe, rival gangs will usually try to retake their turf and you will have to push back the rival gang by taking out several lieutenants guarding the area.



 


 




Your character earns money from these newly acquired areas of town, the more of the map you control, the more money you earn. Dont have enough money? Borrow it from the loan shark. Dont pay the money back in the required time limit and you will be hunted down by the loan sharks crew.



While cruising around Stilwater, listen to the radio. Advertisements, aside from being hilarious, will let you know which stores in town are having sale s. Hear an advertisement for 25% off all guns at Friendly Fire gun store? You have 24 hours to go to the store and get that 25% off.





 

Stores Around Town


 




There are many places around Stilwater that you will need to know about that are critical to your survival. While the liquor store or second hand clothes store might not sound as important as the gun store, they are all important for various reasons (from the game manual):



 

Friendly Fire


 




   


This is the gun store. There are several locations around town where you can buy a wide variety of weapons ranging from pistols, rifles and knives to heavier stuff like RPGs and grenades. Ammo is extremely expensive so choose carefully. To save money, you can adopt the weapons of the realm, that way, when you waste a rival gang member you can use the ammo he drops.



 

Freckle Bitches


 




   


While just a fast food restaurant, you will want to stay stocked up on burgers / food to revive your health. The burgers have funny names like The Fist and The Twins but make no mistake; these are life savers, quite literally.
 
 
 

Brown Baggers


 




 


The local liquor store stocks everything from ice cold 40oz bottles of beer to drugs and paraphernalia. Using beer or drugs helps rives your character during battle but it does make your vision blurry and the screen distort so it is best to stick to food to revive your health. Strictly for comedic value, there is nothing like whipping out the ol bong during a fire fight. Snoop Dogg would be proud. 



 

Sloppy 2nds / On The Rag


 




   


Used clothing is far less expensive than new clothes but the bonuses you get for wearing these clothes is not as good as the bonuses you get from wearing designer duds. Sales on these items bring the cost of clothing down to almost nothing.



 

Branded / Impressions


 




   


The better clothes you wear, the higher the clothing bonus you get when you complete missions and activities. There are no finer clother than those at Impressions and Branded but you will pay for the quality.



 

On Thin Ice


 




Get your bling on at On Thin Ice. The more jewelry you wear, the higher the clothing bonus you get when you complete missions and activities. Rings, necklaces, pendants and medallions are just the beginning; why not get a dozen platinum face piercings while you are there.





 

Rim Jobs


 




   


This is where you take your cars to get them repaired, painted and customized. You can also pick up any car that is in your collection from any local Rim Job location. Customizing vehicle you steal automatically adds them to your garage. The ability to quickly repair your vehicle can be extremely important during missions as well.





 

Forgive And Forget


 




   


When the heat gets to hot, head to Forgive and Forget and they will remove all your police and gang notoriety . Very helpful when being hounded by the po-po because of your 1 5 star rating. While it is fun to be chased all around Stilwater by the cops, it is nice to be able to whip in and get instant forgiveness. Handy during missions as well.



 

Image As Designed


 




   


If the cops are on to you or you are just sick of the way you look, drop into Image As Designed for a little plastic surgery and get a new look. A great way to get the cops off your back too.



 

Foreign Power


 




Aside from the obvious reasons you would buy a car at Foreign Power, you can also buy vehicles here that will help you complete activities and missions. While 99% of the cars you will own are acquired be theft, there will be a few times during the game when buying your vehicle comes in handy.



Now that we have covered the items you can purchase in Stilwater, not everything is for sale, many items have to be earned. Some these items are attained by completing missions, some items have to be straight up ganked from their rightful owner. 



 




Helping you gank these items are your homies. The more respect you earn and the higher you move up the ranks , the more homes you can have. You can have up to 3 homies with you at any given time and, believe me, they can literally be life savers at times. While doing missions, these homies will watch your back, help you take down rival gang members / police and take down target cars during chases.



 


 




Never underestimate the power of the homie. Stand around long enough and you will heart a list of hilarious complaints from your homies as well. Some homies are unlocked as you play through the game, for instance, wheel woman can be called on your cell phone to pick you up for various missions and activities.



 


 




At first, the only crib available to you is a run down house in Saints Row. As you take over territories you will gain new, much more elaborate homes to save your game, change your clothes or weapons and store / retrieve your money and cars.
	</body>
</document>
