<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000228" url="http://www.startupbizhub.com/start-a-fashion-company.htm" time="2012-07-12-15:25" support="1" score="0.0012341713750613776" bingtitle="Start a Fashion Company - Startup Business - Innovative Business ..." webtitle="Start a Fashion Company">
			<query id="001272" bing-rank="133"/>
	<description>... Business Startup Guide Start a Credit Card Company &gt;&gt; ... We carry large selection of silks, fabrics, and ... Starting a Chinese Fast Food Restaurant; Starting a Hostel ...</description>
	<body>
		News   Franchise 
 29   
Start a Fashion Company


 If you have knowledge or experience in fashion designing you can start a company making clothes, shoes and accessories and selling them to specialty stores or in your own boutique. Our basic guide will help you discover what you need to know about starting a fashion company. 

Fashion generally refers to the prevailing style at a certain period of time, but most often people associate it with clothing and accessorising.

 

It is an important part of our culture so that it has become a multi-billion dollar industry. Yearly, fashion shows are held in fashion capitals of the world like Paris and New York. One can start a company under this industry as a clothing designer, accessories designer or footwear designer. What you need to have is knowledge of fashion, textile fabric and ornamentation, maybe from a university or design school or from working in a fashion designing company. Better still if this knowledge is supplemented by a degree in business or marketing. Visit The National Association of Schools of Art and Design for a list of accredited institutions that offer art and design courses.

Starting a Fashion Company Big or Small

If you are planning to start a fashion designing business, you must first determine how large your business should be. Of course, it would depend on how much capital you have. Determining how big or small your business would be will clarify what will be your function in your business. If you have considerable experience and is starting big, you can be a lead designer for a staff of technical designers. As such you become responsible for creating the designs, and choosing the colours and fabrics, but it is the group of technical designer that should do the work of turning into final product the designs you made. It means you will have your own patternmakers, tailors, hand sewers and dressmakers.

If you are starting small, which may mean alone with just an assistant, you do most or all of the work, from designing to patternmaking to sewing the clothes. You can design clothes made of high-quality, expensive textiles sewn with top-of-the line expertise for individual clients or you can do original work for specialty stores, or retail your work in your own store. You can start this project as a home business. What you would need are fabric, sewing machines, lightings, need-craft kits, scissors and cutting tools, and pattern making tables. Fashion designers can earn up to $80,000 yearly.

Miscellaneous Tips for a Fashion Designer

 computer-aided designs are gaining popularity, but keep your sketching ability as they always remain useful for a fashion designer keep yourself updated about what&apos;s going on in the fashion business by associating with people within your local fashion industry and reading from magazines what others are saying about coming trends in fashion so that you will be able to make designs that are relevant to the times create a fashion look that clients could identify as being your work develop a strong sales and presentation skills–you’d need this as much as your fashion designing skills in bringing your business to success 



 &lt;&lt; Biotechnology Business Startup Guide     Start a Credit Card Company  &gt;&gt; 

29 Responses to &quot;Start a Fashion Company&quot;.
 1. april on 4/7/2009 2:46:24 PM wow that was a lot to read please help me with every thing i am only 13 years old. 2. Mathew on 4/22/2009 4:20:43 AM That was really OK. I actually want to start a fashion school which will handle training on dress making, jewelry, make up, etc. What suggestion would you have for me. I need some materials to study first. joyjudah@yahoo.com 3. janelle on 5/18/2009 10:45:33 PM wow that&apos;s cool but what i was looking for was how much money it pays to start designing or becoming a fashion designer 4. anthony on 6/1/2009 2:01:56 PM give me some fashion manual. 5. hb on 6/11/2009 10:59:06 AM it doesn&apos;t pay much - beginning designers in big cities w/ BFA degrees can expect to earn around 32,000, annually... once you gain experience, after about 8 yrs, you can expect to earn about 75-125k, starting a business in this area is very costly due to materials and labor expenses.... between 250k-1m depending on size and location. 6. sandra on 8/10/2009 8:12:08 AM I&apos;m so interested in fashion and I&apos;m 15 years old. one of my biggest dream is to open up a fashion business in the future, i can&apos;t saw that well and my designing skills needs to improve. i love designing and anything that got to do with being creative. i do have very big passion for fashion and i would love to achieve my dreams. what are some advise can you give me? 7. lims vincent on 8/13/2009 6:52:05 AM I am planning to start a business in Abu Dhabi, UAE. Anyone in India who is interested in approaching me with wholesale garments, with the latest fashion in chudidhaar, salwar, and other garments.. 8. loveth on 9/24/2009 1:51:10 PM i need materials on this 9. ankur on 10/13/2009 2:47:38 PM Mr. Lims Vincent, it would be my pleasure to explore some business opportunity with you so email me if you can at ankurjas1980@yahoo.com 10. Orzbor Williams on 4/21/2010 6:30:50 AM i 24 years and in Ghana, aspires to be a great fashion designer, what help do you have for me. and where will i get the nice fabric from 11. keisha on 5/4/2010 3:28:21 PM am only 15 i really love designing clothes i have lots of ideas right now please contact me as soon as you can thanks 12. Rea on 6/23/2010 3:45:26 AM We carry large selection of silks, fabrics, and fashion products. We are supplier for buyers and also can do large production of sewing, cutting for your design. We are located in Cambodia. Contact me at sapphirise@yahoo.com Thanks. 13. olivia dobrin on 7/8/2010 12:31:18 PM i really want to become a fashion designer with my friend but we have no idea on how to? how much does it cost? how to get money? i need help@!! anyone can you help me!!!!!!! i love to design clothes but not sure were to begin!! 14. Anamika Purti on 8/16/2010 3:07:10 PM I just had a desire to implement my skills in fashion designing business... i have not done any course concerning this 15. Anamika Purti on 8/16/2010 3:10:19 PM What are the courses necessary regarding business establishing in fashion....m 26...n has not been associated to this field...what kind of Masters degree is required 16. Bukky Pearse on 9/26/2010 3:24:57 PM am a Nigerian located in Lagos, i want to start a fashion label known all over the world. I need to improve my designing skill and my finishings. How do i go about it. is there any online course i can do? 17. Sasha on 1/17/2011 11:58:58 PM To anyone who wishes to become a designer, the first thing you need to do, if you are in an English speaking country, learn to write well in English. You will have to do a lot of paper work and a LOT of writing. Also, you will have to do more than just take a few courses if you want to do more than just work from your home. You will need to take an entire program. Parsons and are among the top design schools, but if you have to study at home the Academy of Art University offers both a bachelors and masters degree program in fashion design completely online. You need to do a lot more research than asking people on this website to give you one-on-one help - they really don&apos;t care THAT much. You need to decide exactly what you want to do. Do you want to work for yourself? or for a big company? What part of the fashion creating process are you interested in? clothing design? textile design? pattern making? buying? . . . You need to know what you want before you ask others for help with how to get there. 18. Sophia Ratnam on 1/21/2011 9:11:26 PM Wellington, New Zealand. I am planning to start up a designer wear in womens wear.I have great interest in creating different designs with skirts.I take interest in making different kinds of skirts.I have already made about 15 designs for my skirts which include long version and short version.I am looking for fabric supplier where i can get good fabric for cheaper price.Also i would appreciate if i can get somewhere i can get my garments made with good quality. sophie.ratnam@hotmail.com 19. aisha ahmed on 1/27/2011 4:18:49 PM please i want to start a fashion school but need a professionally recognized fashion school for franchise. or a sort of affiliation, but at an affordable price. i&apos;m from kaduna city, nigeria 20. Kiera on 2/25/2011 12:47:15 AM Hey, I am considering creating a website where young designers (including me) can sell their designs and get opinions and suggestions in making them better.. I would need a few designers to start off with. I&apos;m looking for fashion designers of any age that are interested in designing and making their clothing, I will then post them on the website so then people can buy the designs and then the designer will receive money for their designs. I might start off with a $1 fee for posting each design... But you will receive all profits on sales... Anyone interested? Email me: kcblab@hotmail.com. If you are interested or want more information.. 21. Nifemi on 3/17/2011 5:40:35 PM Am a nigerian, based in Lagos. have great passion for fashion designing. am a student in one of the fashion school around. need to improve my designing skills and finishing. please, need a good school in Ghana, South-Africa or London. so that i can sharpen the little skills have got. thks 22. Chikita on 6/18/2011 7:14:48 PM San Fernando Ca. Hello I have a degree in Fashion Design..(AA) The skills I have is out of passion and what I was taught at school. My goal is one day being able to have a clothing line of my own for plus size women Active Wear/Ready Wear as well Career Wear, Though out time I have bought 3 industrial machines, 1 straight needle/1- 5&apos;needle overlock/1 Merrow stitch. I love what I do and have studied I just don&apos;t have much knowledge of starting my own business as well Money. Not very many people believe in me because theirs NO! Money! to start up......any good advise that won&apos;t detour me from my goals... 23. Taniya .S. on 7/26/2011 8:21:48 PM Charlotte NC I&apos;m 11 years old and i wanna start my own fashion company i&apos;ve been designing clothes for years and i love it i want to share my things with the world what can i say I Have a passion 4 fashion 24. Adeola on 8/15/2011 12:01:25 PM I want to start a fashion school, dress making. i need ideas on how to start small and grow big. and i need where i can get good fabric for less price. OGUN STATE, SAGAMU NIGERIA 25. D|ASIKO on 9/19/2011 11:55:23 AM Lagos, Nigeria. I am young and talented with a degree in Fashion Designing. I have my fashion line but it&apos;s small scale. My goal is to have a full-fledged fashion company with state-of-art machines, warehouse, sales outlets and my team of staff. I need financing....i hereby write to interested investors to please email me: adeolafalodun@yahoo.com...Thanks! 26. Indu Arora on 12/9/2011 7:09:08 AM If you are a retailer I have high end to luxury line of apparels for mens and womens. I am located in USA and designs are from USA, Switzerland NZ etc. 27. tijani mariam on 12/29/2011 5:30:47 AM hi,i&apos;ve gone thru your site and people&apos;s comment-guess am in the right place.am a graduate of accounting from one of nigerian university,residing in lagos nigeria.decided to quit my job about two years ago b&apos;cos i felt the to start something i have always had passion for and also to be my own boss.finished my basic sewing skill course about a year ago but since then i&apos;ve only been sewing for my self and my daughter b&apos;cos people around dont believe in me and i believe in starting from home b&apos;cos in my opinion,it will enable me improve&amp;build confidence in myself before getting an outlet outside.but the customers are not forthcoming certainly not becos my work is bad. though,there&apos;s still room for improvement and am still learning.how can i get customers while i operate from home and continue with my skill and confidence building in preparation for the outside world?My dream is to become a famous and renowned designer throughout the world building my success from the scratch with hard work.I WANT MY SUCCESS STORY TO BE A SOURCE OF INSPIRATION TO OTHERS,thanks! 28. SALIM on 2/5/2012 12:17:04 AM i start of perfumes and watch , location near airport, doha, Qatar 29. ShanteldeWet on 3/17/2012 8:31:32 AM I am 18 years old and have a double dose passion for fashion. I don&apos;t have money to study next year so I&apos;m going to work and save money for later studies. I just want to get experience in the fashion world so long but every time people say I need experience. So I just want to know is there anyone who let young people work for them and get experience and let them study part time? I am in South Africa but my dream is to be a fashion designer in Los Angeles or New York. 
 Name: 
 Email: 
 Comment: 
 Write your business location to help you better. Exp: City, State, Country 
 ( All the above fields are required. ) 
 

 Sign up for Newsletter 
Restaurant Business

 How to Start an Indian Restaurant Business Juice and Smoothie Bar Starting a Chinese Fast Food Restaurant Starting a Hostel Business Startup Sushi Restaurant 

Mobile Business Ideas

 How to Start Mobile Catering How to Start Your Own Charter Fishing Business How to Start a Mobile Spa Business Mobile Detailing Business Startup Kit How to Start Mobile Notary Business 

Farming Business Ideas

 How to Start a Poultry Farm Starting Chicken Farm Business Starting a Dairy Farm Business How to Start a Fish Farming Business Start a Rabbit Farm 

Service Business Ideas

 Starting a Recruitment Agency How to Start a Courier Business Starting Your Own Money Lending Business Starting Your Own Guest House Business Starting Your Own Computer Training Center 
 
 Advice for Small Business Business Insurance Information Business Marketing and Advertising Entrepreneur Business Idea Farming Business Ideas Financing a Small Business Free Business Ideas Home Based Business Opportunity Ideas for Small Business Instructor Guides Internet Business Ideas Professional Career Opportunities Repair Business Opportunity Restaurant Business Opportunities Retail Store Ideas Rural Business Opportunities Service Business Ideas Shop Business Ideas Small Business Articles Small Business Opportunities Small Manufacturing Business Starting Rental Business Startup Company Ideas 
 Company Start up Help New Company Ideas 
 Store Business Opportunities Tips for Buying and Selling Unique Business Opportunities Wholesale Business Opportunities 

Small Business Ideas

 How to Start a Towing Business How to Start a Trucking Business Starting a Taxi Business How to Start a Movie Theater How to Start a Shoe Business 

Small Business Articles

 How to Start a Gas Station How Much Does it Cost to Charter a Private Jet Starting a Night Club How Do You Calculate The Mark Up Price 

Home Based Business

 Starting a Home Health Agency How to Start a Home Baking Business Starting a Funeral Home Business Ideas for Home Based Business Starting a Woodworking Business 

Shop Business Ideas

 Starting a Pawn Shop Business How to Start a Meat Shop How to Start a Donut Shop How to Open a Sandwich Shop How to Start Auto Body Shop 

Store Business Opportunities

 Starting a Grocery Store Business Starting a Fashion Clothing Store How to Open a Liquor Store How to Start a Beauty Supply Store How to Start a Drug Store Business 

Startup Company Ideas

 How to Start a Tour Company How to Start a Security Company Start a Cosmetics Company How to Start a Skateboard Company Starting Your Own Repossession Company 
 Copyright©2007 - 2012 StartupBizHub.com. All Rights Reserved.
 About Us | Privacy | Contact Us 
 Site Map
	</body>
</document>
