<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000562" url="http://momsonthemove.tv/tips/show.asp?category=Travel" time="2012-07-12-15:51" support="9" score="0.004016375661470345" bingtitle="Moms on the Move" webtitle="Moms on the Move">
			<query id="001144" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="001426" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="000235" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="000141" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="001241" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="001248" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000924" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="000391" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="001237" bing-rank="89"/>
	<description>Laundry sheet under car seat freshens car! Reusable bottles and fruit ... even to have on hand for that messy ice cream cone or leaking soda cup from a fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Choose a Topic:   Health    Parenting    Relationships    Home&amp;Food    Style    Women and Business    Travel An ounce of mother is worth a pound of clergy.—Spanish Proverb Advertisement 
   
Travel Tips
 Coloring books and Snacks 
Bring coloring books and crayons and plenty of drinks and snacks on road trips to keep the kiddies occupied.
 Dryer sheets for air freshening 
Laundry sheet under car seat freshens car!
 Reusable bottles and fruit 
Carry reusable bottles of water and fruit for snacks in between running errands.
 Bonnie Day Frozen Chocolate bars 
I freeze chocolate candy bars when we go to the park or the beach. When the kids are ready for candy it does not melt all over them in the sun.
 Marilyn Wons 
These are great for soccer / sport snacks, if served cold very refreshing! A healthly snack that kids think is fun and that you are a &quot;cool&quot; Mom for getting them.
 Marion Reigner Squeezable Applesauce 
Never leave home without wipeys. But then saw this squeezable applesauce pouch and thought this may be one case I wouldn&apos;t need it in.
 Donna Timmerman Ziplock bags for snacks 
I usually make sure to pack ziplock bags to throw any unused snacks in so they don&apos;t leak in the backpack!
 alyce poyner Night-Light for Traveling 
Pack a small night-light when traveling with small children. When staying in new places, it makes for easier moving around in the middle of the night. It can also help young children more comfortable falling asleep in a strange place.
 susan varney Snacks for the road 
Always take snacks with you where ever you go. It always makes for a happy kid.
 Lisa Harverson Magnet Board 
Carry a small magnet board and magnets for entertainment in confined spaces
 Dan Audio Books to the Rescue! 
Audio books, from the library!!! A lifesaver on any road trip I take. We just got home from a 12 hour drive and we listened to the book &quot;Shiloh&quot;. Even the 3 yr. old sat calmly and listened to the narrator&apos;s voice. I actually got some knitting done!
 Paula Harmon Seperate activities 
For families with multiple kids, make sure each kid has their own little set of travel activities. This cuts down on the &quot;disagreements&quot; in the car.
 Rona Gregory Separate Toys for Kids! 
For families with multiple kids, make sure each kid has their own little set of travel activities. This cuts down on the &quot;disagreements&quot; in the car.
 Rona Gregory Wipes for the the car 
ALWAYS keep wet wipes in your purse and car...you won&apos;t regret it when you need them in a hurry!
 Christine W Keeping the trash out of the car! 
Always keep an empty plastic shopping bag in the car for trash, or other spills that might crop up.
 Jennifer Healthy snacks for on the go! 
Always carry a healthy snack in your purse/diaper bag as you just don&apos;t know what the day will bring. Any cereal (Cherrios, Chex), trail mix, dried fruit are great to ward off the hungries and cries and keep everyone relaxed and happy.
 Ann Extra clothes for the car 
Always have a change of clothes and undies for every child for &quot;emergencies&quot; in a totebag in the car. I even carry extra socks and sweatshirts.
 tiffany Games for the road 
I take several small games so that the kids don&apos;t get bored :)
 Karen Gonyea Laundry Soap to the Rescue! 
keep a small bottle of laundry soap in a grocery sack in the car and then when there is a child accident on clothing you have soap on hand to prevent the stain from setting in and you also have a place (in the sack) to keep the stain and soap spot moist until you get back home =)
 Anna Nelson Hit the Dollar Store! 
I buy $1 store items and keep them hidden until my son gets bored at the airport. I briung out one at a time. he always loves getting new toys.
 nadine mcpherson Ziploc baggies in the car 
Keep ziploc baggies in the car for snacks that get opened in transit and need to be contained.
 Amy Juice boxes and PB&amp;J;Crackers 
Always keep juice boxes in your bag and peanut butter crackers for snacks. ;-)
 Carolyn Unexpected trips to the library 
As a grandma, I keep a compact, folding tote in the glove box for unexpected trips to library, etc. I can easily carry many books a preschooler will check out.
 Don&apos;t Overpack 
When traveling don&apos;t overpack. I found that the things my kids love most are crayons / markers, coloring books and DVDs or handheld video games. It is so easy to try and pack their entire toy box to keep them entertained, but once you get to your destination they will be distracted by the change in routine, family, friends, etc.
 marybeth i. Travel at night 
When traveling by car I find it best to leave around bedtime, the kids usually sleep all the way through.
 Kathy Riggers 
Always travel with peanut butter crackers - you will need them more times then you need to say &quot;hey, get that out of your nose!&quot;
 Eric Cooper Disposable wipes for the road 
I like to keep disposable wipes and bibs handy when traveling.
 Carry a backpack! 
My tip is for mom to carry a backpack! It gives her the freedom to hold hands in parking lots, undo car seat straps, etc. I have been holding hands with my daughter several times with my purse on my shoulder, only to have it slide down and hit her in the head.
 Cindy Activities for the car 
always keep small activities,(coloring books,books,small toys and puzzles)in your car for traveling or long waits.
 Redbox movie rentals 
You can rent movies from Redbox to watch while you travel then return them to a redbox location at your final destination.
 Casey &quot;Happy Bag&quot; for long car trips 
I keep a &quot;Happy Bag&quot; in the car for long trips with snacks,games,books,crayons etc.
 Flying 
When flying on open seating, have one parent go in ahead of the other to secure the seats. This way, while you are folding up the stroller, getting the carseats together, carry-ons, etc., you will be able to sit together and make there are at least two seats together with a child.
 Denise B. Cheerios and Crayons 
My best tip is to always have cheerios and crayons with you... 
Nothing quiets a child down faster than something to draw with and cheerios to snack on !!
 Douglas License Plate Game 
On a long trip have the kids to write down the states from the license plates that they see and where it is on the US map.
 Frank Towelettes for the road 
always bring a ziplock bag filled with moist towelettes in it.
 (Your Name) Be Prepared 
Always go out of the house prepared. I always keep a bag with toys, bottled water, snacks, wipes, crayons, coloring books, etc., to keep the kids occupied whenever we run into unexpected delays. The kids know that this is our special bag only to be used when we out, so they look forward to seeing if Mom put something new in it for them.
 Margaret Smith Distracting the Toddlers 
on our long overseas trip I brought band-aids and a small flash light to distract a cranky toddler on the airplane.
 Stephanie Vollowitz Kleanex for on the Go! 
use a small container for kleanex for your small purse!
 Amber Begordis Long trips 
when on long trips organize your bag into specific sections e.g games, snacks, clean up stuff, bottles etc.It makes life easier.
 matt m EMERGENCY KIT in Car! 
Always have tucked in a small bag in the trunk of the car 3 diapers, a receiving blanket, and a few bottles of water sealed by the manufacturer, and a few snacks that do not spoil. I got stuck several times with friends and they were amazed when I pulled out the emergency bag and was able to have enough stuff to get past the major issue and get onto looking for longer term items, before anyone else had even started.
 Virginia Briguglio Money in you shoe 
Hide money inside the soles of your shoes when travelling.
 Terri P empty trash while pumping gas 
Every time you fill up the car, empty the trash in the car while the gas is pumping. When I started doing this, I quit having so much junk clutter up my car and my kids get to help!
 Mandy Tee-shirts For the Road 
when traveling with my children, I would purchase a package of plain white tee-shirts for the children to wear over their clothes until we got where we were going. As they got older we painted and decorated them.
 susan reynolds-dover Disposable Sippy Cups 
I leave disposable sippy cups in the car. Take juice in the cooler and fill them up with cold juice when needed.
 Vicki Russell Keep shout on hand 
I carry a napkin soaked in Shout in a ziplog bag to remove any stains from clothing or carseats while traveling. I just wet the napkin with water to activate the Shout.
 Angie Jones cooler for the car 
Get a little cooler (I prefer the hard ones) to keep in your car for when you go out with kids. That way you have cold drinks&amp;you save the money you would have spent at the gas station. I do this if I am going to be gone longer then an hour with either of my kids! Saves you from complaints about being thirsty&amp;paying higher prices.
 Ginny Roll of Quarters 
When our kids were younger we traveled so much and I would give them each a roll of quarters and everytime one would ask how much farther until we were there I would make them give me one of their quarters. At the end of the trip, whatever quarters were left was their money to do with whatever they pleased. It worked like a charm!!!
 Linda Troy Snacks,bandaids and quarters 
Always carry: a snack, bandaids, quarters and a drink if room permits. Bonus points for having something that will entertain the kids.
 Christy Dried fruit in the car 
Pack dried fruit in the glovebox of your car. It doesn&apos;t spoil and it comes in handy to make it home to lunch if you are running a little late.
 Kristie Noguera Extra paper towls 
Keep a quart size ziploc bag with paper towels in your car for those last minute stomach upsets.
 (Your Name) freeze lunch 
I freeze all lunches when going on a car trip. When it is time to eat, they are already thawed in the car cooler.
 Marilyn code words 
My tip would be, to always have a code word when out of town. Your in new places with strangers, and your family would be the only ones who knew it. If in trouble use the code word. Then go from there, with any needed help.
 Cheryl English traveling 
When traveling a long distance in the car for vacation, we now pack our selves and the 5 kids in a laundry baskets instead of suitcases. This makes everthing easier to find, as you can view items through the sides. If a sudden change of clothes or jacket is in need, it is all easily accessible and viewable. The baskets stack much easier then suitcases and their is no need to unpack. We just put the baskets in the closet on the floor and you have instant drawers sorted for each person. I always put one extra basket on the bottom, which takes no room and this becomes our &quot;dirty laundry&quot; basket to keep the room neat and organized. This benefits everyone in organization, finding items they need and neatness of the room, something benefical for everyone especially a family of 7.
 Christine Olsen-Liney baby powder for the beach 
When going to the beach, bring baby powder because it helps take the sand right off!
 Michelle Spiess cherrios for the road 
Keep snacks in the diaper bag-- a few Cheerios might get you thru a tense moment at the grocery store.
 Winifred Gilmore wet wipes 
My tip is to bring wet wipes EVERYWHERE! You never know when you will need them.
 Monique Rizzo waterproof bag 
Keep a waterproof bag handy in the car. 
It&apos;s great for wet clothes and to catch the throwups along the way.
 pamela Stewart preparing for travel 
To prepare the child for a change like leaving for the store. Forewarn the child with a count down from 15 minutes. As it gets closer make more announcements. This reduces the child&apos;s anxiety and provides him/her structure.
 Loc Vu toy and snack 
Always keep a toy&amp;snack to help keep them busy at doctor offices, shopping, etc.
 Jennifer Williams diapers for the car 
Always keep a small bag of disposable diapers in the trunk of your car. You never know when you might need them.
 catherine coopeland extra clothes in the trunk! 
I always keep spare wipes and diapers and extra toys and outfits in spare bag in trunk just in case.
 dawn snack for the ride 
Best tip for me,, is alway bring snacks with you. My little ones get hungry as soon as we leave the house :).
 Ann Marie Walker towl in the car 
Keep a towel under your child&apos;s car seat. This will help protect the fabric against muddy shoes, sticky juice, and all other messes kids seem to be a magnet for... and your seats will still look great after the kid is big enough to get rid of all car seats.
 Marissa snacks in the car 
Keep the car stocked with snacks and drinks espeically water!
 Rosanne Morrison wipes on hand 
keep wet wipes in purse for a quick clean up
 tina buffler-hill cooler in the car 
Keep a small cooler with fruit juice bottles and frozen water bottles in the car for when your on the move with kids.
 (Your Name) extra cup holders 
Need a cup holder for either your car or for a childs table or lapdesk: Take a travel type mug with a flat bottom and add velcro to it. Add the other side of velcro to your dash or the childs lapdesk.
 Cheryl Hutton Sick bags 
Next time you fly, save the &quot;Sick Bags&quot; that are in your seat pocket. They come in handy to have in your car when your child gets car sick... or even to have on hand for that messy ice cream cone or leaking soda cup from a fast food restaurant. The bags are water resistant so they do a great job at preventing a potentially frustrating incident.
 Marissa dry erase maker in the car 
My tip is to get a dry erase marker and keep it in your car. When you are driving somewhere new write the directions on the very top of the windshield or on the drivers door. no lost paper. 

OR write your agenda for the day on an out of the way spot on your windows. That way you remember to do the small things!
 Chelle Byerly be prepared for all seasons 
Have a box of stuff in your vehicle to be prepared for anything that might be needed in the different seasons. Like sunscreen for summer and extra hats and mittens in the winter.
 Angel plan trips based on location 
plan all the shopping trips..business trips ect according to location if possible.. the you only have to make it out of the house once
 spring stansbury a snack and toy for the ride 
Always bring a snack a toy car when traveling with two year old son!
 Shawntae games for travel 
When traveling w/small kids always take along some easy, fun games to pass the time in the car.
 Linda Russell snacks in the car 
Also keep snacks in the car or in your purse for the kids.
 Tina pack light 
Just take life easy and pack light. the less you carry out the less you carry back in!
 Valerie mabrey extra toys 
Before you take a trip, buy a new toy and hide it in your carry on. When your child starts to get fussy on the plane, pull out the exciting new toy and watch the tears disappear!
 Sarah Stern extra clothes 
You take along extra clothing for your kids should they get a little messy, so why not do the same for yourself?
 HC Travel entertainment for the car 
We keep a small plastic pin in the car with coloring books, audio cds, crayons, sketch pads, small toys and a few non perishable snacks. That way if we get stuck in traffic or have a long journey we are always prepared.
 Jenn S. Travel bags for the kids 
When flying, I pack quart size ziploc bags with different activities. Each bag has an mess-free snack and recently purchased book, game or craft. 1 bag for each hour of flight time. This makes it easy to grab (as well as organized) in our travel bags. An idea I came up with after traveling internationally and getting lucky enough to sit in bulkhead seats with my girls. Our bags were required to go in overhead bins and we were pretty bored while waiting for the seatbelt sign to go out. On the way back I used the zip baggy, which fit nicely in the magazine pocket. I switched them out as the flight went on, keeping the kids happy and still for the 7 hour flight.
 Jennifer Weil Travel during the holidays 
We always carry ziploc bags when staying with family during the holidays. All dirty diapers go in the bag to avoid smelly garbage.
 (Your Name) Preparing for Trips 
always bring plenty of simple toys on trips
 Lynda Brann Talk about a recent book you&apos;ve read! 
When traveling, my family and I each tell about a book that one just read. Time goes quickly!
 (Your Name) Map Following For Kids 
When you are going on a trip, whether it is around town or across a couple of states, print out a map for your children to follow where they are going. It makes the children understand where they are, and where they are going.
 Amy Marazas Boring is so boring... 
It&apos;s so boring sitting in a seat with nothing to do. Sometimes we, as busy adults, forget that. That&apos;s why it is crucial for us to bring something for our kids to do, so none of us go crazy from either boredom or their solution to boredom. Put together a tote bag full of fun and portable stuff to do (travel/electronic games, coloring/activity books, colored pencils, etc) and take it with you everywhere. That way, if there is a wait involved somewhere, they&apos;ll be perfectly happy...and if you want to put some things in there for you to do, too, all the better. I get bored sometimes, too.
 Heather Keep them educationally entertainined! 
On long car and plane trips , we rent the kids audiobooks from our local library. It&apos;s free and keeps them entertained for hours.
 Jennifer Shelepet If I had a nickel for every time... 
When on long car trips, I give my kids a roll of nickels each. Whenever they ask how much longer till we get there, they have to give me back a nickel. Sure stops that conversation!
 Potty Stop 
Make a potty stop mandatory before everyone gets into the car. Regardless of how sort the trip.
 carol donnermeyer Travel Time Prep! 
My best tip is one for riding in the car. Always have a bag prepared for drives that are longer than just down the road. Put some snacks, toys, books, etc into the bag and keep it close to the door you exit. When the snacks need replenished, do it right away and put it back so it&apos;s prepared for the next trip. Entertainment will keep them from hollering &quot;Are we there yet?&quot;
 Tiffany Smith Ready To Go 
If we are leaving early for vacation, I bathe the kids the night before and put them to bed in a comfortable set of clothes. That way when we need to leave the next morning, they are already clean and dressed!
 Cheryl Patterson Don&apos;t throw this away... 
Keep used paper towel tubes and tuck old plastic grocery bags inside tube and keep under car seat for those stinky diapers on the go!!!
 Rhonda Larsen Empty Bottle On The Go 
Pack an empty bottle for your little one. You never know if your prepared bottles will spill, leak out, etc. Water fountains are readily available and you can always offer your little one sips of water..especially in the summer!
 Tonya Williams Bottle On The Go! 
When you go out, bring dry formula in a plastic container, and a baby bottle filled with water. This way, it won&apos;t spoil and you can make a bottle on the go!
 Sarah Drouilard Hot Summer Days 
When taking your kids out on hot summer days, be sure to bring along a thermos filled with ice and an ice chest with frozen fruit drinks. It is very easy for young kids to get dehydrated.
 Michelle Henriquez Zipper Storage 
Always keep lots of zipper storgage bags in the diaper bag. They work great for storing wet clothing, dirty diapers, and other things.
 Christina sly &quot;Two&quot; Many 
Just remember, when going out, always pack two of everything. Just in case. It has saved me many of times.
 Ashley Domes Glovebox Stash! 
I keep a stash of diapers and a small travel-size pack of wipes in the glovebox for those times when I&apos;ve forgotten our diaper bag.
 (Your Name) 
Throw a chain of old metal measuring spoons in your purse. It will come in handy when you have to measure meds for the baby as well as keep him occupied while you need to do some waiting.
 Barbara Fox 
Due to the new FAA regulations regarding bringing liquids onto a planes, consider the following. When traveling by air, premeasure formula into the number of bottles you think your baby will want during the trip. Then, once in the terminal, just add the appropriate amount of water and you are good to go for your entire flight.
 KA 
Always carry a damp wash cloth, sealed in a zip lock baggie in your diaper bag. It&apos;s especially good for car trips when a wipe isn&apos;t enough!
 Martha Brooms 
Freeze a couple of bottled waters to take along on your travels. Put them in your snack container and to keep your snacks cool. As they melt you will also have a nice cold drink to hydrate.
 Linda Denisen 
Keep a moist washcloth in a ziplock bag and store it in your diaper bag at all times. If you run out of wipes, or need to clean a chocolaty face, you&apos;re all set!
 C Brown Colths On Hand 
Quick Tip: Keep several microfiber cloths underneath the front seat of your vehicle. Use them to dust off the dashboard, radio and steering wheel.
 Beverly Wilson There&apos;s Nothin&apos; Wrong With Backup 
I always keep a fully stocked diaper bag in the car. It has diapers, wipes, extra paci, blanket, and non-perishable snacks. This way if I run out of the house without my regular diaper bag, or I run out because I forgot to refill my regular bag, I ALWAYS have a backup stash. It has saved me so many times.
 Heather Schmidt Zip-Lock Your Travel 
When travelling, I always use zip-lock baggies to store items, like toothbrushes and other personal items. I also bring along extra baggies for storage of items that may get wet, like swimsuits and seashells.
 David Kimble Play Ding 
Play Ding - to fill up travel time and keep things from getting boring me and my little one play ding. We take turns telling a story starting with once upon a time. Then as we go along if one of us decides to have the story change and say ding. Then the pther person has to change the sentence. You can ding up to 3 times in a row - then you take over the story until you get dinged. It boosts quick and creative thinking, plus shows that there is more than one way to look at things.
 Marian Car Seat Smarts 
I put velcro on either side of my son&apos;s carseat and attached one part to each of the straps so that there is not any fumbling underneath him to find the straps.
 Stephanie Beagley Keep Cool Car Trips 
If on a summertime car trip, always keep wet washcloths, with a few ice cubes, in zip lock bags. They are great for cleanups and cool downs.
 Nicole Perry Formula To Go 
Avoid lugging around powdered formula by using old prescription bottles to hold one serving of the powder. Since the lid locks in place, it won&apos;t spill in your diaper bag. Throw a bottle of water in your bag and you are good to go.
 Angela Swift Alphabet Car Games 
Help the miles go quickly on a trip with fun games that sharpen kid&apos;s observation skills - like saying something you see that starts with an A, then B, then C and so on. Another good game is counting the semi-trucks you see on the road - or the number of blue cars or anything else you think of to see and count.
 Carrie Baird Car Games 
Our children were often bored on a trip. We made up a game of looking for double numbers or letters on a license plate. We also had them look for signs that started with a certain letter of the alphabet. We would start with the letter A and work out way through the alphabet. Not only did it keep them occupied but taught them their numbers and letters. It was surprising how the miles went by so quickly.
 Jennie Smith Travel Goodie Bags 
On car trips as well as plane trips I put together &quot;goodie&quot; bags using brown paper lunch sacks and items from the dollar store. Every hour, or every so many miles the kids get to open a bag and play with something that will keep them busy for awhile. You can include games, snacks, money for the next stop on the road, or any small toy. I string the bags together on yarn and write their name on it, so each knows whose bags are whose.
 Deborah Duncan Fast Food Toys 
I keep an old suitcase filled with free Happy Meal, Wendy&apos;s, or Burger King toys in the trunk of my car. Whenever we go somewhere like basketball practice or swimming lessons all of the kids enjoy playing with all of the toys and they can even take one home!
 Michelle Anthony Car Games 
A time consuming game we used to play during long car trips with our parents. (For older kids who can read&amp;write). Have the kids pay attention to all the other cars they pass, and either have them keep track of different makes/models of cars or the states from the license plates. The child who got the most would get the top prize when we arrived at our destination, but each child would &apos;win&apos; something. (Even $5 or $10 to a kid is alot on vacation!)
 Linda Russell Car Information Organization 
Keep a small binder in the door or glove compartment of your car. Put tire information, warantees, insurance information and so on. This way you will always appear very organized.
 Sharon Davis Port-a-potty 
Once my son was potty trained I worried about going to the park, beach, etc. where there might not be an accessible toilet. I purchased a great portable potty that looks like a litte suitcase. It has come in handy not only for my son, but for his friends who &quot;had to go&quot; while we were out and about. It helps us enjoy our time out, not worrying about whether he&apos;ll need &quot;to go.&quot;
 Viva End vacation clothing hassles! 
On our recent family vacation with our kids (7 and 4), we packed their clothes by day. Before we left home, the boys picked out their clothes for each day, a complete outfit - including socks and underwear, and put them in individually labeled ziplock bags. 

When we got to our destination, we didn&apos;t have to sort through piles of unorganized clothes - and the ziplock bags were great for carrying home wet or soiled items throughout the trip!
 Marianna Ballard Cure the Front Seat Fight 
How to cure the front seat fight? I&apos;ve tried 1. dual air bags 2. If you are in the front seat on the way back the other can sit in the front seat. Rotate. It stopped the fights.
 Sharon Duffel Bag 
My best mom&apos;s on the go tip would to be to look for a good duffle bag with a separate waterproof compartment. This has saved me a lot of work, keeps swimming things, wet things, etc from getting near the clean things.
 Sharon Davis Leave Behinds 
After shopping, I Always leave, snacks, water and juice in the car! No more packing up before we got to leave quickly! 

All sporting gear is left in the car too!
 Jennifer Boylan Travel Car Game 
My kids and I have a car game we call &quot;rubber neckers&quot;. Someone says we are looking for a boat, a pink house, a cow,etc. and you get a point if you&apos;re the first one to spot the object.(only one item at a time) This will keep kids busy in the car for hours. It has saved my sanity many times on long car trips.
 Miriam Bragan Double Toiletries 
Buy doubles of your toiletries, pack one set in your suitcase and shorten your trip preparation by almost half for all future trips!
 Robin Fleming Always pack a small purse 
Always pack a small purse with you in your carry on or suitcase so when you arrive at your destination and are just going to the hotel restaurant or a short errand, you don&apos;t have a large bag with you, and it helps prevent pickpockets or bag snatchers!
 Vilma Rosado Learning That Sticks 
Here&apos;s a great way to keep your kids occupied on long car trips (It was my daughter Rhianna&apos;s idea when she was only 4 yrs. old!): Take along a bunch of educational refrigerator magnets (ABCs, 123s) and a small metal sheet pan. Voila&apos;! An instant magnetic learning board.
 Lisa Haynes Skipping Convenience Foods 
Eating out &quot;on the road&quot; can be expensive&amp;time-consuming. Even on &quot;fly-away&quot; trips, I have always brought breakfast with us. I make a date, banana bread, etc., take juice, milk, fruit, paper plates, plastic utensils. Most motels&amp;hotels now have coffee-makers and offer free ice. I use my cooler-bag&amp;keep it stocked with ice. Everything stays fresh&amp;time, money can be saved - Plus less squables trying to rush out by check-out.
 Dianne W. Fuzek Baby Backpack 
A back pack for our baby was the best way to keep our son happy, close, and content while visiting any place from museums to botanical gardens. No bulky stroller for others to trip over and our hands are free to point, gesture, grab a railing, or just hold hands.
 Audrey Popp Living out of a suitcase. 
My son is preparing for his first major travel experience without family along and, you guessed it, he is going to Australia!!!(Yes, his father and I are green with travel envy!) In order to prepare him for his two week experience, we have had him living out of his suitcase for the last month. By the time he has to actually do it he should be practiced enough to pack and repack with ease. We are hoping this will make his trip a little less hectic with Mom not there to help out.
 Trudy Heise Ziplock Packing 
Free up your time on vacation by putting matching outfits into zip-lock bags. Don&apos;t forget the socks, underware, and matching ribbons. Children can get theirself dressed leaving more time for yourself.
 Betty Neuendorf Quarter Rewards 
Going on a long trip with the kids? Give them each a roll of quarters at the start of the trip. Each time you have to get on them for something they have to give you one quarter. BUT... each quarter they DON&apos;T have to forfeit, they get to keep!
 Renee Borders Entertain while in the car 
Keep a small backpack by the door packed with books, crayons, non-perishable snacks, and small toys to keep your child occupied during car trips or appointments. If it stays by the door, it is easy to grab on the way out, and the items in the bag seem like new items every time your child uses them because they haven&apos;t seen them for a while.
 un-cole-a@juno.com For the ride! 
Make a kids &quot;goody bag&quot; to keep in your car. Fill it with games, puzzles, coloring books and crayons, bubbles, toys, etc. This way if any unforeseen circumstances arise (flat tire, traffic jam) the kids can keep busy, and have fun too!
 spa@goodtobeyou.com Quench Their Thirst 
When going on an outing with your children always put bottled water (or juice boxes)in the freezer the night before so that you can use the bottles as your ice and as the day goes on the water will begin to melt and you have water to give your children to drink instead of purchasing drinks while on the road. - Saves money, time, and gives your child a better way to quench their thirst.
 cherylhoffmanhes@aol.com Travel Gifts 
When flying on vacation pack your carryon as if you will be in the airport for 24 hours; no matter what happens- your plane is delayed, cancelled, etc. you are prepared. Have snacks, drinks, diapers, wipes,and bathingsuits (if they lose your suitcase you can still go swimming). Buy a bunch of inexpensive presents(activities like books, markers, etc.) for your kids. On the plane, every half hour they can unwrap one. Unwrapping the present is a fun activitiy in itself; then they can play with the gift. It makes the time on the plane a lot of fun.
 karenk86@comcast.net Traveling in a car 
Not looking forward to the hour long car ride to my parents house with my 6&amp;3 year old, I struggled with something to keep them occupied.
They said the ride was &quot;boring&quot; and we all know what kids do when they are bored. I switched the placement of their carseats and it opened a world of new views. Abbey was now able to see what Jacob had been seeing for years. I knew it was a success - when I heard no fighting and Abbey say, &quot;Wow Jacob, you never told me you could see WAWA from your window&quot;!

 cyndi@nathanswish.com Road Trip 
When going on a road trip with my kids, I got tired of the &quot;Are we there yet?&quot; every 5 minutes. Before leaving on a trip, I went to the bank and got a roll of dimes (due to inflation make that quarters now) for each child. I told them they had to pay me a dime for each time they asked &quot;Are we there yet&quot;. I also told them that whatever coins were left when we arrived was theirs to spend as they chose. We usually arrived with a full roll of coins and no headache from THAT repeated question.
 snowwhite306@hotmail.com Remove sand from small children at the beach 
When at the beach with small children and sand is every where - after you rinse off in the shower sprinkle some baby powder on the little ones bodies. The baby powder makes removing the sand a breeze. No scratching there delicate skins!!
 rita.m.grmek@nap02.usace.army.mil Travel Crates 
We found a great way to travel to keep a couple seatbelted kids entertained in the back seat but unable to physically harass each other. Get two half milk crate type boxes. Belt the two boxes, each one filled with the particular child&apos;s favorite toys, into the middle seat belt of the car between the two kids. Each kid has their stuff, they can see and talk to each other, but the crates keep them just separated enough so they can&apos;t pound on each other.
 gmphillips@erols.com Port-a-Potty Alternative 
I am the mother of a 13yr old boy and a 10yr old diabetic daughter. After several close calls with my daughter and/or the other kids in the car having to go to the bathroom and there was no bathroom available, I decided to go to the dollar store and buy a bucket. Not to big and not to small. I keep it in the back of the van along with flushable wipes and a small can of lysol. This has saved us so many times. Even other kids have used it. It avoids accidents. And when the buckets starts to look bad, I toss it and get a new one. Hope this tip helps some other mothers who taxi their kids around all over the place like I do.
 donnalfinore@aol.com Return to the list of Tips 
 
 
 Folow Us On Home | As Seen On The Show | Experts | Mom Space | Mind, Body, and Spirit | Message Boards | Linda&apos;s Blog | Ask Linda | Mommy Must Haves 

About Us | Contact Us | Sponsors —Copyright©2012 Moms on the Move
	</body>
</document>
