<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000197" url="http://www.rcgroups.com/forums/showthread.php?t=1115452" time="2012-07-12-15:23" support="1" score="0.0001334543458056876" bingtitle="Alpine cup F3J Bovec, Slovenia - RC Groups" webtitle="Alpine cup F3J Bovec, Slovenia - RC Groups">
			<query id="001152" bing-rank="215"/>
	<description>Aircraft - Sailplanes Multi Task F3X Discussion Alpine cup F3J Bovec, Slovenia ... One competitor fly his Xplorer near 5 minutes with one tips after midair and Antun ...</description>
	<body>
		User Name Remember Me? Password Forgot your password? Create a new account 
 
 Register Blogs Classifieds Clubs Forums Maps Regions Topics Search 
 
 Major Topics All Aircraft Boats Cars Aircraft Airplanes - Electric Airplanes - Fuel Airplanes - Sailplanes Helis - Electric Helis - Fuel Jets - Electric Jets - Fuel Other Topics Articles Exotic Aircraft Off Topic Discussion Related Hobbies Support Video Gallery Vendors 
 
 Go to Page... 
 
   Aircraft - Sailplanes Multi Task F3X Discussion Alpine cup F3J Bovec, Slovenia 
 
 
 
 

 Thread Tools 
 
 Sep 22, 2009, 12:33 PM 
 #1 
 Sotir Registered User Sofia, Bulgaria Joined Sep 2003 173 Posts Alpine cup F3J Bovec, Slovenia We had great weekend in Bovec, Slovenia. This was last Eurotour F3J competition for a &apos;09. 98 participants - most of best f3j pilots in Europe was there. Very nice competition well maked. THANK YOU ORGANIZERS AND TIME KEEPERS. Nice, mostly sunny but challenging weather. Near no wind but thermals also not hard.
One competitor fly his Xplorer near 5 minutes with one tips after midair and Antun Sikic manage to make 10 with only one half of horizontal tail. He found low thermal - 20-25 m above the ground and maxed his time.
On last flyoff flight Larry Jolly and Arijan Hucaliuk make amazing show for as not involved in flyoff. It was 4 or 5-th minute and Larry come near at 15 m and found good air. He start circling and after 30 seconds on near same altitude come Arijan. They make last 10 minutes in this good air 100-150 m away from landing spots on altitude 20 to 50 m.
On last preliminary flight Murat Esibatir also was very low and make 5-6 minutes under 50 m but unfortunately he land near 30 seconds earlier after very precision hunting of good air.
Finaly Arijan take a win with his Xplorer
Hucaljuk Arijan 897.6 99.0 996.6 1000.0 0 1000.0
Hucaljuk Arijan 897.8 100.0 997.8 1000.0 0 1000.0

here some pictures from Slovenian forum
 http://forum.modelarji.com/viewtopic.php?t=43139 Attached Files 
 
 Alpine-Cup-F3J-2009-Groups.txt (79.1 KB, 129 views) 
 
 Alpine-Cup-F3J-2009.zip (9.0 KB, 127 views) 
 
 Last edited by Sotir; Sep 22, 2009 at 12:49 PM . 
 
 Sign up now to remove ads between posts 
 
 Sep 22, 2009, 04:26 PM 
 #2 
 Kiesling Registered User San Diego Joined Aug 2004 1,498 Posts Thanks for the report Sotir,

What rule did they use for the refly in the flyoffs? It appears that they discarded everyone&apos;s score from the first attempt even though they flew the complete round. . .

Thanks,
Tom 
 
 Sep 22, 2009, 11:08 PM 
 #3 
 SmokinJoe101 Registered User Joined Jan 2004 917 Posts Sotir,

Great pictures and what a nice field... Like the Mr. Chicken wagon 

was Primo flying a spread tow explorer? 

sj 
 
 Sep 23, 2009, 01:28 AM 
 #4 
 Sotir Registered User Sofia, Bulgaria Joined Sep 2003 173 Posts Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Kiesling Thanks for the report Sotir,

What rule did they use for the refly in the flyoffs? It appears that they discarded everyone&apos;s score from the first attempt even though they flew the complete round. . .

Thanks,
Tom 
 FAI rules are used. On first flyoff time keeper of Jo Grini had fault and because of this was reflight.
Primosh use a spread tow Xplorer.

Here is a video with Arijan from ECH in Wloclawek, Poland.

 F3J European Championship Wloclawek (1 min 16 sec) 
 
 
 Sep 23, 2009, 09:03 AM 
 #5 
 Kiesling Registered User San Diego Joined Aug 2004 1,498 Posts Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Sotir FAI rules are used. On first flyoff time keeper of Jo Grini had fault and because of this was reflight.
[/url] 
 Thanks Sotir, I misread the scores the first time. . .

Thanks for the video.
Tom 
 
 Sep 23, 2009, 04:29 PM 
 #6 
 Larry Jolly Registered User Joined Oct 2003 1,242 Posts Bovec Guys,
Just got back to Oceanside late last night. What a competition location, a flat glider field surrounded by the Alps. Historically the location is the seen of some horrific battles and is the setting for Hemingway for Whom the Bell Tolls. My good friend Primos Rizner had told me I must come to this competition and he was right. This contest was one of the best run I can remember and was a great way to spend the weekend. The area is a wintersports area so accommodations are close by and good. Part of the Turkish group including Philip spent 3 hours on Friday white water rafting. Lift was spotty and weak all 3 days. I worked for 8 minutes in practice Friday for about a 200 foot altitude gain. The tactic if you were not sinking out you should S turn or large circle in it, making the best of it, until you had some place else to run to. As Sotir has stated the top European competitors were there and that equated to some very competitive flying. In the flyoff I was lucky to have Primos spotting and throwing for me. I had a 55.8 and a 56.3 with 99&apos;s in the first 2 flyoffs. Both Arijan and I did real short tows on the reflight round and never really hooked up in the big air out the back. I didn&apos;t feel like walking and so I headed up wind hoping for a miracle. I saw this gentle bump and Primos excitedly says Good Air Good Air...... I actually said Where are you lookin???? Then Arijan joined us and We spent the next century trying everything to get out, and not mid air. In the end the weak meandering thermal never did really break all though it threatened to several times. I would like to invite some Americans to go try a Eurotour event next year I can advise the pros and cons of each venue if you are interested. Thanks to all my European friends it was great flying with you guys this season. I managed a respectable 15 place in Eurotour 2009 out of 420 competitors. Many thanks and congratulations to the Contest helpers and organizers you guys were awesome. LJ 
 
 Sep 23, 2009, 04:34 PM 
 #7 
 Francesco Registered User United States, CA, Berkeley Joined Apr 2001 334 Posts Here&apos;s a picture from one of the fly-off rounds. 11 sailplanes are climbing together in the same thermal... it really must be viewed large, so click the pic to enlarge it.
 
 
 Sep 23, 2009, 04:38 PM 
 #8 
 Francesco Registered User United States, CA, Berkeley Joined Apr 2001 334 Posts Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Larry Jolly Historically the location is the seen of some horrific battles and is the setting for Hemingway for Whom the Bell Tolls. 
 The Soci valley has indeed seen its share of horror during WWI, but to my understanding For Whom The Bell Tolls was set in the Spanish Civil War. 
 
 Sep 23, 2009, 04:50 PM 
 #9 
 pmccleave Registered User USA, KS, Wichita Joined Sep 2002 869 Posts Francesco,

Thanks for the picture, I set it as my background on my computer.

See Ya,

Pat 
 
 Sep 23, 2009, 04:56 PM 
 #10 
 FLY F3B or F, J, K, or even TD Joined Jun 2007 2,327 Posts Awesome Francesco, just awesome. Thanks for the reports Sotir, and LJ.

Welcome home LJ.

Mike 
 
 Sep 23, 2009, 06:05 PM 
 #11 
 Larry Jolly Registered User Joined Oct 2003 1,242 Posts Francesco,
I thought that as well. Primos mentioned this and I haven&apos;t had time to check it out. Maybe he meant that Hemingway was here. Sorry for the confusion. LJ That picture with 11 models is 2-3 minutes in to the reflight. I would be the guy on the bottom saying where is everyone going. The train pulled out of the station and Arijan and I missed it. 
 
 Sep 23, 2009, 06:07 PM 
 #12 
 Francesco Registered User United States, CA, Berkeley Joined Apr 2001 334 Posts Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Larry Jolly Francesco,
I thought that as well. Primos mentioned this and I haven&apos;t had time to check it out. Maybe he meant that Hemingway was here. Sorry for the confusion. LJ That picture with 11 models is 2-3 minutes in to the reflight. I would be the guy on the bottom saying where is everyone going. The train pulled out of the station and Arijan and I missed it. 
 So the twelfth plane missing from the pic is Arijan&apos;s? I have to admit I didn&apos;t count the planes while I was shooting, I realized that I managed to capture all the models but one only when I was at my PC... 
 
 
 Return to Multi Task F3X 
 
       DRIVE  /  FLY  /  SUPPORT     
 
 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
 
 Thread Tools Show Printable Version Show Attachments in this Thread 
 
 Similar Threads Thread Thread Starter Forum Replies Last Post Video Spor Yapi Cup F3J davzucker Airplanes - Sailplanes Videos 1 Jul 05, 2008 08:34 AM &quot;JW Wins Calgary Cup F3J!&quot; GordySoar@aol.com RCSE 2 Aug 02, 2004 08:11 AM 

 
 
 
 Forum Functions Calendar 
 External Feeds 
 Members 
 Recent Attachments 
 Recent Videos 
 RCG Plus (beta) 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Top Projects Blogs 
 Chat 
 Maps.RCGroups.com 
 Mobile Version 
 Site Links Advertising 
 Our Sponsors 
 Contact Us 
 FAQ 
 Review Policies 
 Rules 
 Site History 
 Terms of Service 
 RCG Sites The E Zone 
 Lift Zone 
 RC Power 
 Flying Giants 
 Crack Roll 
 RCCars 
 
All RCGroups content copyright 1996 - 2012 by RCGroups.com
and Jim Bourke except where otherwise indicated.

Terry the transmitter, the RCGroups name and logo,
The E Zone, Lift Zone, and RC Power are all trademarks
of RCGroups and Jim Bourke.

Please report any misuse of our trademarks using the contact form . Thank you.

 
 
 Style Default Fluid Classic Back to Top
	</body>
</document>
