<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000480" url="http://www.chacha.com/question/can-you-place-an-order-for-sonic" time="2012-07-12-15:44" support="4" score="0.0062997343199459105" bingtitle="Can you place an order for Sonic? | ChaCha" webtitle="Can you place an order for Sonic? | ChaCha">
			<query id="000104" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="001484" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000541" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000555" bing-rank="11"/>
	<description>ChaCha cannot place an order for you we can give you the menus and phone numbers of the ... In is an American fast-food restaurant chain base... How do you order at ...</description>
	<body>
		About ChaCha 
 
 ChaCha 

 Questions Categories 
 Entertainment 
 Art&amp;Design Celebrities Events Games Humor Literature Movie Showings Movies Music Song Lyrics TV&amp;Radio Theater 
 Sports 
 Baseball Basketball Football Golf Hockey Motorsports Olympics Scores Soccer Tennis 
 Culture 
 Christianity Cultures&amp;Groups Demographics Education Family Historic Figures History Islam Judaism Mormonism Mythology&amp;Folklore Name Etymology Relationships&amp;Dating Religion&amp;Spirituality 
 Politics 
 Campaigns&amp;Elections Law Military Political Figures State&amp;Local Gov. U.S. Government Wars&amp;Conflicts World Governments 
 Lifestyle 
 Bars&amp;Nightlife Dining Out Food&amp;Drink GLBT Green Living Home&amp;Garden Pets Recreation Shopping Style&amp;Beauty 
 Lookup 
 Definitions Mail&amp;Shipping Non-Famous People Puzzles Translations Weather&amp;Time White Pages Yellow Pages 
 SciTech 
 Animals&amp;Plants Astronomy Automotive Biology Chemistry Computers Consumer Electronics Earth Sciences Internet Math Physics Science 
 Business Health Travel 
 Galleries Quizzes 
 Sign In 
 Please enable JavaScript in your browser to immerse yourself in our rich user experience. 
 X 
 
 
Can you place an order for Sonic? 

In: Customer Service › ChaCha Info 
 
Rate This Answer
 
ChaCha cannot place an order for you we can give you the menus and phone numbers of the restaurant closest to your location. 
 Answered

 
 - 65 days ago at 7:44pm on May 07 2012 
Related Questions for ChaCha Info 

 
 What kind of side orders does sonic have? 

Sonic has as side items Apple Slices, Onion Rin...

in Dining Out | 9 hr 30 min ago via Android app 
 
 How many calories are in an order of mozzarella sticks from Sonic Drive-in? 

There is 410 calories per order of Mozzarella S...

in Food&amp;Drink | 14 hr 36 min ago via iPhone app 
 
 How do you order at subway and sonics? 

Subway and Sonics are botth fast food restauran...

in Dining Out | 1 day ago via Android app 
 
 How many calories are in an order of cheddar peppers from Sonic? 

There are about 330 calories in an order of Che...

in Customer Retention | 9 days ago via Android app 
 
 How many calories are in an order of ched r peppers from Sonic Drive In? 

The Sonic Drive In Ched &apos;R&apos; Peppers contain 290...

in Dining Out | 9 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 Can you order inside a Sonic? 

Some of the locations have inside booths. Other...

in Dining Out | 13 days ago via web 
 
 How many calories are in an order of cheese sticks from Sonic? 

Sonic Drive-In is an American fast-food restaur...

in Food&amp;Drink | 15 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 How many calories are in an order of french toast sticks from sonic drive in? 

French Toast Sticks (4 Count): Calories 480. Ca...

in Diet&amp;Nutrition | 16 days ago via Android app 
 
 Why does Sonic give mints with your order? 

Each customer receives a mint - a tradition sta...

in Dining Out | 22 days ago via sms text 
 
 Does sonic do call in orders? 

Most Sonic Drive In&apos;s do take call in orders. B...

in Dining Out | 22 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 What is the best thing to order from Sonic when your high? 

I think mozzarella sticks are the best thing on...

in Addiction&amp;Drug Abuse | 22 days ago via Android app 
 
 What is the best thing to order at sonic? 

I recommend you to order the SONIC Bacon Cheese...

in Corporate Info | 27 days ago via Android app 
 
 See All Questions ▶   
Related Galleries for ChaCha Info 

 
 
 
 Top Ten Reasons to Become a ChaCha Guide 
 Viewed 14 times 
 
 
 
 12 Awesome iPhone Apps You Haven&apos;t Heard Of 
 Viewed 2919 times 
 
 
 
 ChaCha&apos;s Web Writers 
 Viewed 846 times 
 
 
 
 ChaCha+Iris Video Contest Rules 
 
 
 
 8 Easy Ways to Improve Your Diet 
 Viewed 3703 times 
 
 
 
 Reasons Summer Totally Sucks 
 Viewed 364 times 
 
 See All Galleries ▶ 
Related Quizzes for ChaCha Info 

 
 
 
 Can You Match These Celebrities to Their Famous Fathers? 
 
 
 
 Can You Name the Celeb Sports Team Owner? 
 
 
 
 Are You Left or Right Brained? 
 
 
 
 Are You an Emotional Eater? 
 
 
 
 Do Your Neighbors Hate You? 
 
 
 
 Could You Run a Marathon? 
 
 See All Quizzes ▶ 
Share This Page:

 Facebook Tweet Email 
 Advertisement 
Top Trends in Customer Service 

 Forever 21 Coupons» 
 
Top Trends

 Love» 100 Floors» Say in Spanish» Boy» Facebook» Illegal» Website» Area Code» Hurt» Cancer» 
 Advertisement Home › Categories › Customer Service › ChaCha Info 
Text Your Question

* ChaCha does not charge for its service.
Message and Data Rates May Apply.
If you need help, text HELP to 242-242 .
To cancel your service, text STOP to 242-242 .
 
ChaCha Mobile Apps
 
 ChaCha for iPhone ChaCha for iPad ChaCha for Android 
 
Connect

 Become a ChaCha Fan on Facebook Follow ChaCha on Twitter Follow ChaCha on Pinterest Follow ChaCha on Google+ Follow ChaCha on Apple Follow ChaCha on Android 

 About Contact FAQs 
 
Services

 Questions&amp;Answers Become a Guide Work for ChaCha 

 Advertise With Us ChaCha Mobile Affiliate Program 
 
©Copyright 2006-2012 ChaCha Search, Inc.–Experimental Use, All Rights Reserved, May Be Covered by US or Foreign Patents or Patents Pending. Copyright Notice | Terms of Use | Privacy
	</body>
</document>
