<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000491" url="http://www.pennlive.com/midstate/index.ssf/2010/09/eatn_park_to_close_its_last_ha.html" time="2012-07-12-15:45" support="2" score="0.0024452872073140817" bingtitle="Eat&apos;n Park to close its last Harrisburg-area restaurant | PennLive.com" webtitle="Eat&apos;n Park to close its last Harrisburg-area restaurant  | 						PennLive.com">
			<query id="000699" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000702" bing-rank="73"/>
	<description>I was one of those kids at the Eat &amp; Park when there were car hops, and the cops counted the number of ... one less nasty fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Sign in | Register for free Sign in to PennLive.com Username   Password Remember me I forgot my username or password» Don&apos;t have an account?
 Register now for free , or sign in with any of these services:

 

 AIM    Google    OpenID 
 Site Search Search Local Business Listings 
 
 Home News Opinion Sports Entertainment Living Interact Jobs Autos Real Estate Rentals Classifieds Find n Save 
 Home &gt; Breaking Midstate News with The Patriot-News &gt; Business 
Eat&apos;n Park to close its last Harrisburg-area restaurant

Published: Wednesday, September 29, 2010, 5:18 PM
 By SUE GLEITER, The Patriot-News The Patriot-News 
 Follow 37 Tweet Share close Digg Stumble Upon Fark Reddit Share Email Print 
Last call for Smiley Cookies.

The midstate’s only Eat’n Park restaurant at 4641 Lindle Road in Swatara Twp. will close at 2 p.m. Friday, said Pat Kehew, Eat’nPark community marketing director.

“There is mixed emotions,”she said.

The closing will mark the end of an era for the Pittsburgh-based Eat’nPark chain, which at one time operated five restaurants in the Harrisburg area including Lemoyne, East Pennsboro and Carlisle. The company closed its Fairview Twp. restaurant in April.

In addition to the Swatara Twp. restaurant, the Eat’n Park at 145 Memory Lane in York will close on Friday, Kehew said. About 90 employees from the two restaurants were informed of the closings on Tuesday, she said.

The chain has built its image around the trademarked sugar cookies iced with smiling faces that are available in various seasonal color combinations. Eat&apos;n Parks also boast in-house bakeries and extensive diner-like menus featuring breakfast.

The restaurants and employees are heavily into community fund-raisers, mostly raising money for children’s hospitals.

Eat’n Parks started in 1949 as Pittsburgh’s first drive-in restaurant with car-hops.
The concept created such a stir that police had to be called in to direct traffic on Saturday nights. To be a little different, the original owners reversed the park and eat signs that were cropping up everywhere in those days to come up with the Eat’n Park name that has stuck ever since.

Eat’n Park restaurants operate in Ohio, West Virginia and Pennsylvania.

 Related topics: eat&apos;n park , harrisburg 
 
Sponsored Links
 
 Share this story Print Email Story tools 
 
More stories in Breaking Midstate News with The Patriot-News
 Previous story
 Giant Food Stores wins hunger-relief award from USDA Next story
 House of Representatives passes Marcellus Shale gas tax; Senate will take up measure Oct. 12 Copyright 2012 PennLive.com. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 37 
Comments Feed 
 View: 
 
 Oldest first | Newest first   1 | 2 | 3 Next comments » howdi September 29, 2010 at 5:30PM Follow 

Someone should bring back the Roy Rogers chain to our area. I still frequent them when I travel in Md or on the Tpk but it would be nice to have them on east and west shores again. I know the food is not the healthiest but the roast beef is not too bad and the chicken was delicious but would be better baked.

Will miss the couple times a year all you can eat breakfast buffet at Eat N Park although I can get the same at Old Country Buffet. Have to say my last visit to ENP the tables were very sticky and the place looked a bit dirty but guess they were on the way out.

Hasta la vista



 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new towtruck September 29, 2010 at 11:34PM Follow 

@howdi: There&apos;s no excuse for sticky tables or dirty appearance in any restaurant. My first Eat N Park experience was in the Pittsburgh area, in the 1980&apos;s, and I really liked the place. I am sad for all those who lost their jobs.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new ENOLAGAY September 30, 2010 at 10:28AM Follow 

TEA .... not putting down the opportunity&apos;s for all in this country to make it, but looking at the foreign market in our country today leeds to one&apos;s currosity of why the resturants run by CHINA, GREESE, PALESTINIANS, are a success in our country, and the american enterprise&apos;s run by the americans are folding. I guess it works if you buy their car&apos;s and eat their foods.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new sosickncute September 30, 2010 at 11:18AM Follow 

opportunity&apos;s leeds currosity resturants GREESE american enterprise&apos;s americans car&apos;s

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new necrosage2005 September 30, 2010 at 11:28AM Follow 

@ENOLAGAY, racist much? Not only that, but you are a rather horrible speller. This is more along the lines of what your nonsensical rant should really read like: &quot;TEA .... not putting down the opportunities for all in this country to make it, but looking at the foreign market in our country today leads to one&apos;s curiosity of why the restaurants run by CHINEESE, GREEKS, AND PALESTINIANS, are a success in our country, and the American enterprise&apos;s run by the Americans are folding. I guess it works if you buy their cars and eat their foods.” Actually, you were doing just that. It is “your” American companies’ fault for leaving the USA. If they wouldn’t pick up their businesses and go to other countries to produce things for you to buy you wouldn’t have the stuff you have. People, like those in YOUR family came here for the same thing – opportunity. Also, Eat’n Puke sounds like an American company to me, since it is out of Pittsburgh. If they would put out a better product they wouldn’t have to close restaurants down. I mean, it isn’t like you don’t have an option and, oh, I don’t know, (learn to) cook at home!

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new ENOLAGAY September 30, 2010 at 4:05PM Follow 

necrosage### Regardless how I spell and punctuate my claims, has nothing to do with the credibility and honesty that one writes. Its a known fact that most of these foreigners who&apos;s claim to fame around here lately of having good food cheap is something that one should be able to visit their kitchens and actually see their pet mice and roaches that they have running around their kitchens. Ask any pest control person.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new poppyseed September 30, 2010 at 3:46PM Follow 

But you ARE putting down the &quot;opportunity&apos;s&quot; for all in this country by your need to insert racism into this. Chinese, Greek, Middle Eastern (Lebanese, Syrian) restaurants, and others are established on the basis of their providing good food. Period. There where you go when you would like to have an actual meal of real meats and vegetables beyond &quot;crispy lettuce&quot; and &quot;crispy fries.&quot; Times change, tastes change, regional preferences change (which is why Eat&amp;Park isn&apos;t closing everywhere). I was one of those kids at the Eat&amp;Park when there were car hops, and the cops counted the number of times we all drove in and out of the lot to &quot;see who was there.&quot; That was so long ago that they didn&apos;t make &quot;happy face&quot; cookies yet, just strawberry pie.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new towtruck October 02, 2010 at 12:37AM Follow 

One reason that &quot;Chinese, Greek, and Palestinian&quot;&amp;other ethnic restaurants are so successful in USA is: many of us (myself included) LIKE ethnic foods. Or, we want something different, out of the ordinary, to eat. I would like to go try out that Middle Eastern restaurant in Carlisle. Another reason for their success: those restaurants often employ family members, and they might be able to pay them less than they&apos;d pay an &quot;outsider&quot;. Of course, many of these groups have a strong work ethic. And, yes, I do believe that these people have the support&amp;financial backing of groups, like fraternal organizations, of their nationalities. That last statement also explains why people can enter this country with little or no money, and have a business within 5 years. Yes, they do have a great work ethic, I am sure, but it takes money to start&amp;run a business, so they are also getting help. Of course, Americans have a strong work ethic as well, but without outside help (from family or a fraternal organization, for instance), it is much harder to start up a business.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new spelczecher September 29, 2010 at 5:42PM Follow 

I haven&apos;t been there for years, but my kids used to love going there and our men&apos;s prayer group would meet there for breakfast on Saturdays. Time marches on, I suppose. Best of luck to those out of work employees in finding another job soon. It&apos;s tough out there.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new koffee September 29, 2010 at 6:51PM Follow 

Sometime ago we were in the area down there. We were going to eat at that Bob Evans but it was really crowded. So we drove across the lot to Eat and Puk. Starting getting out of the car and the smell of rancid grease hit my nose. Got right back in the car and drove back over to Bob Evans and waited to eat. If you want to run a business you must learn - clean your grease once in awhile.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new riverwoman16 September 29, 2010 at 6:55PM Follow 

&quot;About 90 employees from the two restaurants were informed of the closings on Tuesday, she said. &quot;

So employees got a whole 3 days notice? Though compared to some people who get no notice at all that their job is gone, I guess 3 days isn&apos;t so bad.


 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new got weed? September 29, 2010 at 8:25PM Follow 

The place is an armpit.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new thelizzy September 29, 2010 at 8:30PM Follow 

they should open a red robin in york where eat &apos;n park was. we need a red robin in york so badly.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new towtruck September 29, 2010 at 11:36PM Follow 

@thelizzy: I hope York does get a Red Robin---the food is great!

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new oneblinddog September 29, 2010 at 10:42PM Follow 

one less nasty fast food restaurant.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new   1 | 2 | 3 Next comments » 
 
Post a comment
 (You may use HTML tags for style) 
 

You must accept the terms of service before you can post a comment.
 
Post a comment
 
Sign in to PennLive.com
 Username Password 
  Remember me? I forgot my username or password» 
Don&apos;t have an account?

 Register now for free , or sign in with any of these services:
 
 AIM Google OpenID 
 
More Breaking Midstate News with The Patriot-News

 Most Comments Most Recent 
 
 Breaking Midstate News with The Patriot-News stories with the most comments in the last 2 days. 182 Paterno family releases statement in advance of Freeh report findings 138 Joe Paterno&apos;s newly released letter: &apos;Penn State is not a football factory&apos; 70 Freeh report on Penn State related to Jerry Sandusky scandal to be released Thursday 66 Paterno family says Joe&apos;s side of Sandusky child sex abuse scandal has been left untold 67 Emotions boil at Harrisburg meeting over receiver&apos;s push to raise taxes 
 
Most Active Users
 What&apos;s this? 
 Users with the most Breaking Midstate News with The Patriot-News comments in the last 2 days 49 nycvirago 45 distcoach2 37 High Heels 30 ourcounty-2 24 glenn15 
 
Connect with PennLive.com
 What&apos;s this? 
 
 All Facebook&amp;Twitter accounts » From Our Advertisers 

 
 Advertise With Us» 
Popular Tags
 What&apos;s this? 

 
 Site Search Search Local Business Listings 
 Site Index | Advertise | Contact us Make us your home page Home | News | Weather | Sports | Entertainment | Interact | Living | Jobs | Autos | Real Estate | Classifieds | Shopping | Place an Ad 
 Your Photos Your Videos Pennsylvania blogs PennLive.com forums Special Projects Today&apos;s Patriot-News 
 
 Find a Job Post a free classified ad Apartments and Rentals Business Finder Sell your car Special Guides 
 
 Pets Dining Weddings High School Sports Penn State Football Obits/Death Notices 
 
 Subscribe to our content (RSS) Get breaking news alerts PennLive.com Twitter feed Local Sounds radio PennLive.com mobile site 
 Subscribe to The Patriot-News today and get incredible savings off home delivery! Subscribe Now! Registration on or use of this site constitutes acceptance of our User Agreement and Privacy Policy (Revised November 1, 2011)

©2012 PennLive LLC. All rights reserved ( About Us ).
The material on this site may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, cached or otherwise used, except with the prior written permission of PennLive LLC.

 Community Rules apply to all content you upload or otherwise submit to this site. Contact interactivity management .

 Ad Choices
	</body>
</document>
