<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000559" url="http://virginiabeach.citysearch.com/review/10606375" time="2012-07-12-15:51" support="22" score="0.05164213629861041" bingtitle="Cogans Pizza User Reviews - Norfolk, VA 23517 - Citysearch" webtitle="Cogans Pizza User Reviews - Norfolk, VA 23517 - Citysearch">
			<query id="001287" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="001035" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000563" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="000096" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="000564" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000155" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000112" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000658" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="001255" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000591" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="001004" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="001047" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="000221" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="000586" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000910" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="001283" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000144" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="001272" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000576" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="000127" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="001020" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="000570" bing-rank="216"/>
	<description>If you want fast food, go to a fast food restaurant. ... to wait a ridiculous amount of time for my food. ... to be honest, they charged my card for my bill ...</description>
	<body>
		Deals Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Hotels Shopping Best Of Citysearch 

 Mobile Login / Join 
 More More Go! Advertise With Us 
 Citysearch has shed its old skin! In addition to our new look, there&apos;s a boatload of new features. Poke around! Tell us what you think! 
 Virginia Beach, VA Metro &gt; Norfolk &gt; Restaurants &gt; Cogans Pizza Cogans Pizza (757) 627-6428 
 1901 Colonial Ave , Norfolk , VA | Directions  
 23517 36.867700 -76.292700 View Website 
 
 Hours 
 Daily 11:30am-2am ; Open 7 Days ; Open Holidays Menu Share Save 
   Own this Business? Best of Citysearch Recommend this business? Thumbs Up Thumbs Down ? 45 % 100 24 18 Votes Add a Photo Site Feedback 
 Overview Tips (24) Photos (0) 
 Write a Tip for Cogans Pizza 
 Sign in to Write a Tip 
 Write a Tip... optional 
 
 
Tips from Citysearch

 Citysearch ( 18 ) | Around the Web ( 6 ) 
 Sort by:
 Date Rating Popular 
 Doesn&apos;t Recommend pizzahog Joined 2 years ago 1.0 February 05, 2010 
 Lose the manager!. The red haired chick that masquerades as the night manger should be banned from working with people anywhere. After signing up for a table we waited for two hours. At first we didn&apos;t catch on, but the&quot;manager&quot;was seating people (six tables- probably her friends) that came in after us. We called this to her attention with no resolution. The second time I made an issue, she said that she thought we left and would put us back at the botttom of the list. Right! We work too hard to spend our time and money where we are treated so poorly! One star is too much! … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends SonjaB Joined 2 years ago 5.0 February 03, 2010 
 Great Food, Great Beer, Great People!. I know that most Americans want everything fast but sometimes you have to slow down; savor and enjoy little things like good food and good friends. Cogan&apos;s has been a favorite of mine since I was first brought there. I have yet to try anything on the menu that I don&apos;t like and there are too many beers to ever get tired of any single one.

Some may say the service is slow, but as a former waitress I understand is not in the waiter/waitress&apos;s control and cooking time is one of them. A pizza from Cogan&apos;s is prepared after you order it, meaning it&apos;s going to take time; to put together, to bake, and to be delivered. If you want fast food, go to a fast food restaurant.

I have never been met by the wait staff at Cogan&apos;s without a smile and I have never had to wait a ridiculous amount of time for my food.

A great place for those who enjoy life, not for those who are impatient. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends MantaWave Joined 3 years ago 4.0 November 30, 2009 
 From an objective Norfolk local. I don&apos;t really know why I&apos;m here... Oh yeah. I was looking up&quot;Azalea Inn&quot;to hopefully write to them lamenting the $40 tab (with tip) I just got for a simple pizza and (1) pitcher of domestic beer.....and then I find these unfair reviews of Cogan&apos;s. ...

In my opinion, Cogan&apos;s is the best.

Great (reasonably priced) beers. Very solid, if not EXCEPTIONAL pizza, and their Sunday, and Monday specials. .... I really don&apos;t know what kind of pretentious hole some of these others reviewers crawled out of.

~G … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Doesn&apos;t Recommend fifthbeatle Joined 3 years ago 1.0 November 30, 2009 
 Haven&apos;t been there yet....... I was planning on paying Cogan&apos;s a visit.........but after reading the horrible reviews I&apos;m canceling my plans.I didn&apos;t plan to eat there, and now I never would,......I was looking for a place to play music.After hearing that the cook killed a cockroach and then made a pizza......WITHOUT WASHING HIS HANDS........I don&apos;t even want to touch the floor with the bottom of my shoes!!! How could people be so blind to such a DIRTY place?! Cogan&apos;s should be shut down!!!!!! I didn&apos;t think this place deserved one star but they wouldn&apos;t let me leave the site without it. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Doesn&apos;t Recommend relli018 Joined 3 years ago 1.0 July 21, 2009 
 Screw this place. Food is not bad, but how bad can you really screw up pizza. My issue is they overcharged me too. Well, to be honest, they charged my card for my bill and another different bill. I called the manager, who told me he wasn&apos;t the manager, and said a similar phrase as in another post,&quot;The sorta things do sometimes happen.&quot;He went on to tell me he was too busy to help me cause he had other customers. Hey Jacko....you ripped me off. You have my money now why don&apos;t you finish with me before you go and rip someone else off?

The food is OK and the pizza is par quality, but REALLY greasy. I will never eat there again especially after reading several of these r o a c h comments. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Doesn&apos;t Recommend Norfolkites Joined 3 years ago 1.0 June 30, 2009 
 I miss the old Cogan&apos;s. I had been out of the area for a couple of years and was excited to be getting back to Norfolk, and my favorite haunt, Cogan&apos;s. Good grief! What has happened!? I went in there with a couple of friends for a pie and beers on a Sunday afternoon...hoping history would be favorable...it was not. The service, if you can call it that, was just wrong. Rude, borderline abusive, oh, and make sure that if you pay with a credit card you circle under and bold face the total and compare it with the other slip...a fifty dollar bill mysteriously became eighty! Where is, or what happened to Fillipowski? It was a tight place back then, but not now. Oh, and if you look real closely around the baseboards, you might see Cogan&apos;s new mascot. No longer the gorilla, it is now a cucaracha. For some reason CitySearch would let me write what I really meant to say ? … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Doesn&apos;t Recommend privatemoon Joined 3 years ago 1.0 January 21, 2009 
 this place is starting to stink. What happened to Cogans? I have been working in this industry for ten yearsm an own my own restraunt. It seems they need to higher better waitstaff in the Ghent area. I was in recently with my wife, we ordered a pizza and a picher of beer. The beer was warm. And recently it seems we just get lousy service, they were not as attentive as they used to be. I give this place one star because for a unique place as it maybe it is not what it used to be. Lousy food, lousy service. lousy health standards … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Doesn&apos;t Recommend lovetohate Joined 4 years ago 1.0 December 29, 2008 
 NEVER AGAIN. A friend and I decided to eat at Cogans around xmas. I have never actually ate there before (just drank late night) and I will tell you I will NEVER eat there again. I ordered the spinach chicken pasta. I maybe had about two bites when I crunched down on something. Immediately I knew it was a b u g and a HUGE one at that. I exited the b u g into a napkin and ran into the bathroom to p u k e. The friend I was with called over the waitress and showed her the critter. It was bad enough that I had a b u g inside of my mouth, but the customer service was even more disgusting. Naturally, since I had a little more protein in my food than expected, my friend could not eat her food. I mean, would you? The manager told the waitress to take off the pasta. We asked to speak to the manager. She came out and we explained to her that my friend could not eat her food and it should be taken off. I have been a waitress before. If this situation ever happened to us the table would not have to pay for anything. Because that is good customer service. The manager refused to take off my friends food, or the fries and 1 beer I had ordered. I didn&apos;t want to argue because I wanted to go home and clean my mouth. To me it looks bad for a restaurant not to comp food when something like this happens. Our complaint was legitimate, and the r o a c h was the proof. The manager kind of shrugged us off and said&quot;well this kind of stuff does happens&quot;. That comment ticked me off even more. I should not have had to pay for anything except the tip.

Cogans just lost a few customers, because bad news spreads like wild fires. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Doesn&apos;t Recommend Krue Joined 4 years ago 1.0 July 14, 2008 
 Watch your credit card bill. Great beer selection, good food what could go wrong. Alot.....When you have a bartender that constantly forgets your drink orders, apologizes because she just quit smoking then acts like you are hassling her when you ask her if she is still going to get your drinks while she is looking at a magazine. I guess I can kinda overlook all of that. That is until I got my credit card statement that is. Guess she felt a little extra gratuitous and decided to add a little more for herslef. Not on my watch honey~ What a shame. The place did have a good atmosphere. But based solely on that one employee, Cogans doesnt even deserve the one star Im giving it. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Doesn&apos;t Recommend abraid Joined 4 years ago 1.0 June 19, 2008 
 Don&apos;t get delivery!!. Man, I really love the food at Cogan&apos;s but not when it arrives 2+ hours late!! The past two times I&apos;ve eaten here I&apos;ve had it delivered and BOTH times the food came 2+ hours AFTER it was supposed to (so basically almost three hours after I ordered!!) and was cold and GROSS!!

I&apos;m really disappointed since their pizza is good and I like supporting a local business but this is just ridiculous!! Looks like I&apos;ll be ordering from Papa Johns or Pizza Hut next time... … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart 
 1 2 Next 
 
People who viewed this also viewed…
 
 50 % California Pizza Kitche… 300 Monticello Ave Ste 149 
 Norfolk, VA 
1.3 mi away Brickhouse Pizza&amp;Subs… 4027 Bowdens Ferry Rd 
 Norfolk, VA 
1.1 mi away Papa John&apos;s Pizza 2001 Colley Ave 
 Norfolk, VA 
0.3 mi away 
 
Things to do near Cogans Pizza
 
 Restaurants Movie Theaters Banks 

 Bars Shopping&amp;Malls Hotels 
 Best of Citysearch 2006 Pizza 
 About Apps Careers Privacy Policy Terms of Use Contact Us Blog FAQs 
 
Partner Sites:

 Ask Kids     Bloglines     Expedia     Hotels     Hotwire     Insider Pages     MerchantCircle     Reference     The Daily Beast     Thesaurus     Urbanspoon 
 ©2011. Citysearch is a registered trademark of CityGrid Media. Data provided by Infogroup. All rights reserved. 
 Popular Categories Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Shopping Hotels Deals Sports&amp;Recreation Cafes Movie Theaters Directory&amp;Services 

 Change City New York City Los Angeles Houston Chicago Atlanta Seattle Portland Philadelphia Austin San Francisco More…
	</body>
</document>
