<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000691" url="http://eatatbetos.com/" time="2012-07-12-15:59" support="8" score="0.021296259582787053" bingtitle="Beto&apos;s Mexican Restaurant | Cinco de Mayo Party | Charity Events ..." webtitle="Beto&apos;s Mexican Restaurant | Catering | Private Parties">
			<query id="000422" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="000705" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="000716" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="000434" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="001145" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000173" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000185" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="001156" bing-rank="103"/>
	<description>Beto&apos;s Mexican Restaurant and Bar | Catering. Our Story ... has become one of D/FW&apos;s hot spots for Mexican food ... Join our mailing list and receive special offers.</description>
	<body>
		Beto&apos;s Mexican Restaurant on Facebook 
Beto&apos;s Mexican Restaurant and Bar | Catering

 
Our Story 

Beto&apos;s Mexican Restaurant 2530 W. Interstate 20 Grand Prairie TX 75052 - 972-660-1289. Arising from humble beginnings, the quintessential Mexican restaurant &quot;hole in the wall&quot;, Beto&apos;s has become one of D/FW&apos;s hot spots for Mexican food cuisine. The Sanchez family has passed down recipes for generations to share with their guests.
 
 In order not to get caught up in the Tex-Mex bandwagon, Beto&apos;s Mexican Restaurant has focused on traditional Mexican food cuisine. With specialties such as Carne Guisda, Chile Rellenos, and Homemade Tamales, Beto&apos;s is a testament to old fashion cooking.
 
 Co-Founder and patriarch, Humberto Sanchez, was born in Monterrey, Mexico. With a passion for Mexican food, Humberto pursued his dreams of opening his own restaurant using his Grandmother&apos;s recipes. With the help of his family, Mr. Sanchez achieved his dream in July of 1993 and opened his first Beto&apos;s Mexican Restaurant in Grand Prairie, TX, just a stone&apos;s throw from Dallas, Fort Worth, and Arlington.
 
 As they say, &quot;The rest is history.&quot;
 
 Established in 1993
 Beto&apos;s Mexcian Restaurant is a vibrant, family owned Mexican restaurant. Rising from near obscurity, Beto&apos;s has established itself as one of the premier dining locations of the Dallas / Fort Worth area. Nestled conveniently in Grand Prairie, next to Arlington for you &quot;out of town-ers&quot;, Beto&apos;s has been a fan favorite for the diner that wishes to escape the &quot;chain&quot; experience. With true family recipes, home made tortillas, and home made chips, Beto&apos;s is a palate&apos;s paradise. Professional catering services available.

Tags

Arlington Catering 

catering Mexican wedding Arlington Grand Prairie Texas caterer bar authentic Fort Worth Dallas restaurants take out local best Mansfield facebook catered Beto&apos;s Duncanville to go food Tex Mex catered event office outdoor rehearsal dinner venue private corporate full service special event dinner lunch cantina fine

Local Attractions

 SixFlags Over Texas 

 Hurricane Harbor 

 Dallas Cowboys Stadium 

 Texas Ranger Stadium 

 Lone Star Park 

 Joe Pool Lake - Loyd Park 

 Air Hogs QuickTrip Park 
 
 
 
 Join our mailing list and receive special offers. Email: 
 
 Follow @eatatbetos
	</body>
</document>
