<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000907" url="http://www.arrowheadbuildingsupply.com/about/" time="2012-07-12-16:16" support="2" score="0.0006452621880029773" bingtitle="About Arrowhead - Building Supplies, Building Materials, Roofing ..." webtitle="About Arrowhead">
			<query id="000452" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="001269" bing-rank="67"/>
	<description>Three-hour delivery or 15-minute pick up. Largest Delivery Fleet – Over 35 ... gorgeous 4, 000 s.f. showroom and drive-up window just as one would seat the fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		July 12, 2012
 
 636-970-1976 | ALL STORES OPEN 6 A.M.–5 P.M. | About 
 Customer Feedback Download Forms 
 Contractor Services 
 LionGuard Aerial Roof Estimating Dumpster Services Rooftop Delivery Job Locker Recycling Program Weather Storm Reports 
 Contact 
 St. Peters Belleville Strafford Pevely Hollister Lowell 
 
 
 Arrowhead Building Supply 

Roofing supplies, building supplies St. Louis, decking, siding, versetta stone
 
 Home Roofing 
 Commercial Roofing Residential Roofing 
 Gutters 
 
 Siding Decking&amp;Railing Windows and Doors Manufacturers 
 3M Afco Atlas Roofing First American GAF IKO Karnak Leister Lomanco Metal Sales Mid-America Siding Nichiha Fiber Cement OMG Roofing Products Owens Corning Pactiv Quality Edge Royal Edge Tam-Rail Tamko Tapco Typon Union Velux Vytec 
 Resources 
 Weather 
 Southern Missouri Weather St. Louis Metro Weather 
 Storm Reports Product Catalog Event Schedule Download Forms Lead Generation Organizations Site Map 
 News Product Catalog 
 
 St. Peters Belleville Strafford Pevely Hollister Lowell FOR QUOTES OR DELIVERIES, CLICK HERE OR CALL 636-970-1976 
 You are here: Home / About Arrowhead 
About Arrowhead
 
 

10 Reasons Why You Should Use Arrowhead Building Supply . .

 Nationally Recognized Customer Service. Largest Delivery Fleet–Over 35 delivery trucks. Largest Inventory–Over 60,000 squares of roofing and siding in stock. Largest Product Selection–Over 20 major building materials brands handled every day. Largest Service Area–Five Missouri and Illinois locations with same day service within 100 miles of all locations. Experienced Team - More than 2,000  customers and counting and a management team with 200+ years experience. Dumpster Service Fleet–Nearly 200 dumpsters available for your roof tear-offs. Job Lockers–Store your materials and tools safely and securely on the job site. Builders Club–Receive trips and merchandise just for being loyal to Arrowhead. Regular training and workshops with leading suppliers. 

 

Arrowhead’s mission:“To be the best exterior supply company in the industry.”

 

 

We will accomplish this through the use of our patented and innovative delivery systems, by providing the best service platform in the industry (Service 3/15), staffing the most knowledgeable experts and by offering the greatest variety of products from the most reputable manufacturers in the business.

 Our pledge to you begins with (Service 3/15). Upon your request, anything stocked in any of our multiple warehouses can be delivered to your jobsite in just 3 hours or less, at NO extra charge. No other supplier does that….anywhere!

 

The Arrowhead Team 
 

 

We have taken time to hire the best experts and service-oriented personnel in the business. Arrowhead boasts well over 200 years of combined experience with our teams. We have many experts who have been in the business for more than 15 years, some well over 20 years!

Facilities

 

Arrowhead Building Supply, Inc. has five locations to serve you, including three surrounding the St. Louis area and two locations covering Southwest Missouri and Northern Arkansas.

 Our St. Peters corporate headquarters consists of three buildings on 10 acres totaling over 61, 000 s.f. Our Pevely location boasts a beautiful 36,000 s.f. warehouse with 6000 s.f. of showroom space! Our Belleville location rest on just over an acre of ground on Hwy 15 and South 11 th Street. Our Stafford store in on four acres just outside of Springfield, Missouri and opened in 2008. Our newest store in Hollister, Missouri is 26, 000 s.f. and features a gorgeous 4, 000 s.f. showroom and drive-up window just as one would seat the fast food restaurant! 

All in all, Arrowhead has close to 150, 000 square feet of warehouse space for our customers.

Unmatched Service Commitment 
 

 

Put plainly…Service 3/15! At no extra charge, anything stock can be delivered on your jobsite or warehouse within just 3 hours or less. Also you can pick up materials at any of our location in just 15 minutes or so. Arrowhead eliminates the worries associated with scheduling and picking up materials. Our business is built around YOU, the customer. We don’t tell you when you when you can have it; we ask you when you want it. We get you what you need, when you need it.

Largest Loading Fleet In the Area 
 

We have the largest fleet of delivery trucks in our market. Our trucks swarm in our territories all day, everyday! Arrowhead has 45 trucks in its fleet, including:

 27 Conveyor Trucks 9 Pick-up Trucks 4 Box Trucks 3 Knuckle Booms 2 Tractor Trailer and Flat Bed Trucks 

Innovations in Roof Loading 
 

We use specialized delivery equipment design and built by PowerLift Handling Material Systems, LLC ( www.powerlift4u.com ) to maximize the efficiency and minimize human labor and delivery times. Our truck beds actually transfer material to the rear of the delivery truck, and then raise the materials for off-loading!

We also use the amazing Power hitch exclusively for our shingle recycling trailers, to again, save on time and effort. Our Hollister, Missouri location features a built-in-drive-thru window so customer can pick up small without ever exiting their vehicle. “Fast Food” has now become “Fast Building Materials.” All Arrowhead warehouses are drive-thru building so our customers can come inside out of the elements and stay warm and dry while visiting us.

Mobile Recycling Container Service 
 

 

Arrowhead also has around 200 dumpster trailers in our fleet for roof tear-off jobs and projects. These trailers are rubber-tire and agile, perfect for any situation. They hold approximately55 squares of 3-tab shingles, or 35 squares of architectural shingles. They can be rented for one simple fee, no tax, no daily charge! Just two phone calls and your roofing debris is gone. just another way Arrowhead adds value to our customers.

Key Suppliers

 VINYL SIDING from Royal and Crane . FIBER CEMENT SIDING from CertainTeed and James Hardie, as well as Nichiha panelled veneer systems ROOFING from TAMKO, Owens Corning, IKO, GAF and Atlas . We also have Metal, Slate, Tile and Wood Shake STONE veneer panelled system from Versetta Stone&amp;Owens Corning (manufactured stone) DECK materials from Evergrain Composite Decking WINDOWS from PlyGem and American Window (Earthwise) DOORS from Mid Am GUTTERS from Alsco and Quality Edge SKYLIGHTS from Velux RAILING from Landmark, TAM-RAIL and Evergrain ACCESSORIES from Mid America, AFCO, Quality Edge, Lomanco, Pac-tiv and others 

 

 
 
 Unsurpassed Customer Service 
Three-hour delivery or 15-minute pick up Largest Delivery Fleet 
Over 30 delivery trucks in our fleet 
Largest Inventory

Over 60,000 square feet
of roofing and siding in stock Largest Product Selection
 Over 20 major building materials
brands handled every day Largest Service Area
 Five Missouri and Illinois locations with same day service within 100 miles of all locations Experienced Team
 1600+  customers and counting and a management team with 100+ years experience Dumpster Service Fleet
 Nearly 200 dumpsters available
for your roof tear-offs. 

 
 
 
 
 
Quick Links
 Request
an Estimate Or Delivery 
 Download
Forms 
 See
Event Schedule 
 Read
Our Blog 
 Site
Map 
 Weather
Reports 
 
Arrowhead Contractor Services
 
 Builder’s Club 

Redeem Points For Trips and Gifts As our Way of Saying Thank… more... 
 
 Free Take Off Service 

Arrowhead provides roofing contractors, sub-contractors and architects… more... 
 
 Contractor Referral 

Arrowhead supplies the building materials, but we are not contractors.… more... 
 
 Job Locker Keeps It Secure 

Save time with Arrowhead&apos;s new Job Locker service.  This handy… more... 
 
 See More Services . . . 
 
CUSTOMER FEEDBACK
 
 “Once you become a customer of Arrowhead, there is
no reason to see anyone else.” “They go beyond the other suppliers.” “The other companies have never treated me as
special as Arrowhead has.” “ They continue to respond to our needs, through
rapid response, fair pricing and outstanding customer service.”     More 
 
 
AFFILIATIONS
 
Latest Blog Posts
 
 Golf Tournament Sets Record Donation for JDRF 
 
 Free Use of New AttiCat Blown-In Insulation System 
 
 JDRF Golf Tourney Set for May 11 at Bear Creek 
 
 New Truck Fleet to Serve You Better 
 
 Aerial Roof Estimating 
 
 Return to top of page 
 
Copyright©2012 Arrowhead Building Supply Inc. · Log in
	</body>
</document>
