<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000019" url="http://www.katom.com/cat/trash-cans.html" time="2012-07-12-15:12" support="16" score="0.018252822880404647" bingtitle="Trash Cans | KaTom Restaurant Supply, Inc." webtitle="Trash Cans | KaTom Restaurant Supply, Inc.">
			<query id="000026" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000620" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="000008" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="000432" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="001451" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="001374" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="001011" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="001356" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="001482" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000602" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="001469" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="001449" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="001452" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="000165" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000414" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="000885" bing-rank="19"/>
	<description>KaTom carries a great selection of trash cans for heavy duty use! Find the top ... Condiment &amp; Food Dispensers; Toasters; Chop, Core, Dice, Slice, Wedge and Fry Cutters</description>
	<body>
		Need help with your purchase?

Chat with a KaTom specialist
 No, thanks Residential Clearance ( Log In or Register ) Track my Order 
RESTAURANT SUPPLY, INC.
 1-800-541-8683 
 Restaurant Equipment 
 Commercial Refrigeration Commercial Ice Makers Ovens&amp;Ranges Food Warming Equipment Commercial Fryers Grills, Griddles, Char-Broilers, Hot Plates&amp;Accessories Sinks, Faucets&amp;Accessories Shelving&amp;Carts Commercial Dishwashers Slicers Work Tables, Butcher Blocks&amp;Equipment Stands Commercial Mixers Food Bars&amp;Accessories Vegetable and Salad Dryers Hoods&amp;Accessories 
 

 Kitchen Supplies 
 Textiles, Aprons, Towels, Smocks, Pot-holders, Gloves Baking Supplies Storage Containers&amp;Food Bar Crocks Steam Pans&amp;Covers Kitchen Utensils Chafers Trays&amp;Tray Stands Cookware Knives, Turners&amp;Accessories Hot Food Pans, Covers&amp;Accessories Food Pans&amp;Accessories Foodservice Brushes Can&amp;Bottle Openers Time Clocks&amp;Timers Signage 
 

 Tabletop 
 Serving Items Dispensers Silverware&amp;Flatware Table Tents, Card Holders&amp;Decorative Drinkware Baskets Dinnerware Shakers&amp;Mills (Salt, Pepper, Cheese&amp;Other) Presentation Cookware / Serveware Cooling Tubs Menu Covers&amp;Guest Checks Cash&amp;Carry Items Dessert&amp;Pastry Carts Buffet Stands and Risers Table Coverings / Tablecloths 
 

 Countertop 
 Concession Equipment Food Warmers Mixers&amp;Accessories Drink Dispensers Condiment&amp;Food Dispensers Toasters Chop, Core, Dice, Slice, Wedge and Fry Cutters Coffee&amp;Tea Equipment Blenders Hot Dog Equipment Popcorn Machines, Accessories&amp;Supplies Food Processors Meat Processing Equipment Pancake, Waffle,&amp;Crepe Supplies Induction Range 
 

 Bar Supplies 
 Bar Refrigeration Bartending Supplies Bar Drinkware Portable Bars Speed Rails Wait Service Supplies Wine Supplies Bar Matting Glass Racks and Hangers Bar Glass Washers Blenders&amp;Mixers 
 

 Furniture 
 Outdoor Furniture Coca Cola Series Furniture Tables&amp;Bases Portable Bars Youth Seating Crowd Guidance Systems Restaurant Booths Restaurant Seating Chairs Cluster Seating Bar Stools Cashier / Reception Stands Merchandising Carts&amp;Kiosks Kitchen Countertops Rubbermaid Indoor / Outdoor Planters Patio Heaters 
 

 Catering&amp;Buffet 
 Tabletop Serving Items Carts Catering&amp;Buffet Storage Containers Steam Pans&amp;Covers Food Bars&amp;Accessories Chafers Trays&amp;Tray Stands Dinnerware Coffee Percolators&amp;Urns Tea Brewers&amp;Dispensers Commercial Coffee Makers: Thermal / Airpot Brewers Food Pans&amp;Accessories Catering Food Carriers Serving&amp;Buffet Series 
 

 See
More 
 Pizza Equipment Replacement Parts Request a Quote Shop By Brand Buyer&apos;s Guides Learning Center KaTom Kids Jamie Oliver Free Shipping KaTom Coupons Janitorial Go Green 
 
 Order #: Zip Code: Katom  &gt;  Janitorial  &gt;  Trash Cans&amp;Accessories  &gt;  Trash Cans 
Shop By Category
 Utility Trash Cans 
 Decorative Trash Cans 
 
Shop By Brand
 Rubbermaid 
 Waymar 
 Update International 
 Carlisle 
 San Jamar 
 Polarware 
 Dispense-Rite 
 American Metalcraft 
 Bon Chef 
 Cecilware 
 Continental Commercial 
 Kelmax 
 Krowne 
 Win-Holt 
 
Trash Cans

No matter what your business is about you&apos;re sure to produce some sort of garbage or waste at the end of the day. Dispose of your garbage in a trash can from KaTom Restaurant Supply! KaTom&apos;s selection of trash cans come in a variety of different styles and uses so you&apos;re sure to find the trash cans perfect for your establishment. Trash cans from KaTom are affordably priced with you in mind! Order the trash cans your business needs with KaTom today!
 
 Utility Trash Cans 

If you&apos;ve got garbage, KaTom has the solution for you! KaTom Restaurant Supply has a great selection of utility trash cans to choose from, including recycling utility trash cans and space saving utility trash cans. Need a large utility trash can for your business that you can easily move? No problem. Roll your garbage to the dumpster in one of KaTom&apos;s mobile utility trash cans! Order the utility trash cans your business needs with KaTom to experience great KaTom pricing!
 Rubbermaid FG105443 BLA Self-Dumping Hopper, .5 cu yd Capacity (750 lbs), Tilts, (4) 6 in Casters, Black 
$1,299.48
 Rubbermaid FG354007GRN Slim Jim Station Recycling Container, 23 gal, Vented, Recycle Symbol, Green 
$37.50
 
 Decorative Trash Cans 

Your visible trash cans can say a lot about your business to customers. Don&apos;t use an eye sore of a trash receptacle; use a decorative trash can from KaTom instead! These decorative trash bins stay neat and attractive while accepting waste. KaTom carries decorative trash cans in several styles to best fit your individual business needs. Shop with KaTom today for decorative trash bins and save with competitive pricing!
 Waymar DMTSE Trash Module, Double, Laminated, Holds (2) 35 Gallon Liners, Self Edge 
$990.00
 Rubbermaid FGR12WU500PL Aspen Ash/Trash, Weather Urn, 12 Gal, 14 in, Black w/ Perforated Steel Panels 
$358.30
 
Be in the know and receive exclusive savings
 
KaTom Restaurant Supply

 About KaTom Career Opportunities Product Review 
 
Customer Care

 Contact Us Return Request Order Tracking My Account Financing&amp;Leasing Shipping Information 
 
Shopping With KaTom

 Restaurant Equipment Kitchen Supplies Tabletop Countertop Bar Supplies Furniture Catering&amp;Buffet Shop By Brands 
 
KaTom Policies

 Return Policy Shipping Policy Privacy Policy Terms of Use Secure Shopping 
 
Let&apos;s Get Social

 Facebook Twitter YouTube Google Plus Pinterest 
 
What People Think of KaTom.com
 
Copyright©2001-2012 KaTom Restaurant Supply Inc. All rights reserved.
 
Safe Shopping Guarantee
 
 E-Mail Us With Questions Live Chat 1-800-541-8683 
 Monday - Friday 
 8am - 8pm EST 
 Name 
 E-Mail 
 Phone 

To verify that you are a human user, please answer:
 What is the sum of ? 
 What is the best way to contact you? E-Mail Phone 
 Questions or Comments
	</body>
</document>
