<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000016" url="http://james-cooper.suite101.com/how-much-salt-should-i-have-each-day-a350369" time="2012-07-12-15:12" support="1" score="0.0016687250722089843" bingtitle="How Much Salt Should I Have Each Day? | Suite101.com" webtitle="How Much Salt Should I Have Each Day? | Suite101.com">
			<query id="001142" bing-rank="207"/>
	<description>For half the US, one cup of soup fills the goal ... the cook pour salt on the French fries at a fast food restaurant ... Table salt is sodium chloride, and is the major ...</description>
	<body>
		How Much Salt Should I Have Each Day?
 Tweet 
 Feb 21, 2011 James Cooper 
 0 Comments
 Join the Conversation One Cup of Soup Can Be Too Much Sodium - (c)J Cooper The newest recommendations for daily salt (sodium) intake are startlingly low. For half the US, one cup of soup fills the goal; any more salt is excessive. 
Watching the cook pour salt on the French fries at a fast food restaurant, one can see how Americans have come to consume more salt per person than ever before, and more per person than many other industrialized countries. Experts say the high salt intake contributes directly to stroke, heart attack and heart failure risk. Also, Americans like salty foods (chips, fries, popcorn, hot dogs) and with the salt comes high calories, contributing to overweight and obesity.

Americans like the taste of salt, but don&apos;t need much salt. To be specific, we are talking about sodium. Table salt is sodium chloride, and is the major source of sodium in most cultures.
 
New Sodium Guidelines

The US Department of Agriculture and Department of Health and Human Services put together a panel of experts to make recommendations about daily dietary intake. Sodium was one of the topics. The most important recommendations had to do with upper limits of sodium intake—the&quot;do not exceed&quot;recommendations. The experts call these Tolerable Upper Intake Levels. The 2010 recommendations are:

 1500 mg/day for African Americans, and people with high blood pressure, diabetes, kidney disease, and people age 51 and older. 2300 mg/day for all others ages 14 and older 

The 1500 mg/day recommendation extends to almost half the US population, and is less than half the average intake of Americans today. Even more stringent levels may apply to people with certain clinical conditions.
 
More on this topic
 
 The American Diet is Too Salty; The Government Urges Cutbacks Dietary Sodium Intake Hidden Salt in Foods 
 
Ways to Reduce Sodium Intake

Cutting back on salty French fries is one way to reduce sodium intake, but, perhaps surprisingly, the food types responsible for the most sodium intake are yeast breads, chicken dishes, pizza, and pasta. That&apos;s because they are consumed so often. Ways to reduce individual sodium intake include:

 Lock up the salt shaker (or limit its use) Use more fresh vegetables (processing often includes adding sodium) Read product labels and select lower sodium foods Ask for low sodium dishes in restaurants Consume fewer calories; salt comes in breads, pizza, pasta dishes 

How Much is Not Enough Sodium?

The experts couldn&apos;t produce a Recommended Daily (RDA) Allowance because minimum requirements are not known (what is the minimum amount of sodium needed for 98% of the population to prevent sodium deficiency disease?). Instead, they advised Adequate Intake levels, which are levels found in healthy people. These are the&quot;at least this much&quot;levels and take into account sweating (a major loss of sodium) by unacclimatized people working in a hot environment.

 1000 mg/day ages 1 to3 years 1200 mg/day for ages 4 to 8 1500 mg/day for people ages 9 to 50 1300 mg/day for ages 51 to 70 1200 mg/day for ages 71 and older 

Source

 Dietary Guidelines for Americans 2010 
 Copyright James Cooper . Contact the author to obtain permission for republication. 
 James Cooper - I&apos;m on the faculty of a health science department at a large university. Most of my articles derive from conferences or presentations ... 
 Print Article Tweet Advertisement Leave a comment
 NOTE: Because you are not a Suite101 member, your comment will be moderated before it is viewable. Submit
 What is 10+3? Advertisement 
More on this topic
 
 2010 Dietary Guidelines for Americans and the New Food Pyramid U.S. Salt Intake Remains High Despite Health Risks Lower Blood Pressure Naturally with Two Hypertension Helpers 
 more in nutrition » Advertisement Latest Articles • About Us • Terms&amp;Conditions • Privacy Policy • suite101.de • suite101.fr • suite101.net • Suite101 Blog Nutrition @ 
 Write for Suite101 Sign In 
 
 Nutrition Food Facts Vitamins&amp;Minerals Balancing Meals Proteins/Carb/Fats More 


 
 Home Health&amp;Wellness Nutrition
	</body>
</document>
