<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000518" url="http://www.onlineseats.com/venue/ricoh-coliseum.htm" time="2012-07-12-15:48" support="1" score="0.0013511552613923116" bingtitle="Lorain Ticket Broker - Lorain OH Events - Lorain Venue Information" webtitle="Lorain Ticket Broker - Lorain OH Events - Lorain Venue Information">
			<query id="000109" bing-rank="154"/>
	<description>... Coliseum in 1983 and remodeled it from an fast food restaurant ... the concert hall you can use to pinpoint a place to ... Contact Us | FAQ | Order Status</description>
	<body>
		Tickets Broker  &gt;  Venues  &gt; Ricoh Coliseum Ricoh Coliseum Events • Toronto • Ticket Broker 
Ricoh Coliseum - Venue Tickets, Schedules, Seating Charts, and Information
     
 HOME SPORTS CONCERTS THEATER LAS VEGAS BROADWAY 
 Call Us:  1-866-999-4518 Search: Jul 12, 8:48 AM 
Toronto Area Ticket Broker - Seller
 
 Ricoh Coliseum has never failed to be a superb auditorium to watch live performances. The venue provides a feel that will please the audience and leave them thrilled. Every spot in the 1,800-capacity theater offers a clear perspective of the stage. The tickets’ surcharge for every play at Ricoh Coliseum is worth it just for the enchanting feel.

Ricoh Coliseum’s celebrated reputation guarantees that well-known productions are in residence each season. Those dramatic works visit for long runs that have a production scheduled almost each day. Ricoh Coliseum performances frequently have celebrated actors and actresses like a Alan Arkin or a Kate Mulgrew. Periodically, a heavily-publicized movie talent will perform in a show.

Brian Francoeur purchased the Ricoh Coliseum in 1983 and remodeled it from an fast food restaurant after the first owner sold it to him after he inherited it. The auditorium’s layout was based by a theatre the owner visited in Leipzig. Ricoh Coliseum has become one of the premier houses in the world.

Ricoh Coliseum has plaies every month and fans are always requesting more tickets. promises to have a stock of seats to look at to those dramatic pieces, no matter how in demand they might be. Besides tickets, we have a convenient schedule of the popular play at Ricoh Coliseum, along with a up-to-date seating chart and accessible map of the area around the concert hall you can use to pinpoint a place to eat after the show.
 Ricoh Coliseum Tickets 
Ricoh Coliseum Address
Address:100 Princes&apos; Blvd
City:Toronto   State:ON
Zip:M6K3C3 
Ricoh Coliseum Seating Chart
 Click to see larger image 
Upcoming Ricoh Coliseum Schedule
 Event City Date Apassionata Toronto Friday 7/20/12 8:00 PM   Apassionata Toronto Saturday 7/21/12 3:00 PM   Apassionata Toronto Saturday 7/21/12 8:00 PM   Apassionata Toronto Sunday 7/22/12 3:00 PM   Contact Us | FAQ | Order Status BROWSE CATEGORIES SPORTS TICKETS MLB Tickets NBA Tickets NFL Tickets NHL Tickets College Basketball Tickets College Football Tickets Boxing Tickets Soccer Tickets Golf Tickets Auto Racing Tickets Tennis Tickets Olympic Tickets WWE Tickets Horse Racing Tickets Miscellaneous Tickets more tickets... CONCERT TICKETS Pop Rock Tickets Alternative Tickets Hard Rock / Metal Tickets Jazz / Blues Tickets Country / Folk Tickets Comedy Tickets more tickets... THEATER TICKETS Ballet Tickets Cirque Du Soleil Tickets Broadway Tickets Off Broadway Tickets Opera Tickets Musical / Play Tickets New York Theater Tickets Comedy Tickets more tickets... LAS VEGAS TICKETS Cirque Du Soleil Tickets Celine Dion Tickets Mamma Mia Tickets O Tickets Danny Gans Tickets Steve Wyrick Tickets La Femme at MGM Grand Tickets Lance Burton at Monte Carlo Tickets Lord of Dance Tickets Penn and Teller at Rio Tickets more tickets... 
 About SSL Certificates Featured Concerts 
 Celine Dion Tickets Cher Tickets Dave Matthews Band Tickets Jimmy Buffett Tickets Jonas Brothers Tickets Kanye West Tickets Kenny Chesney Tickets Rush Tickets Steve Winwood Tickets The Police Tickets 
 Featured Theater 
 Blue Man Group Tickets Chicago - The Musical Tickets Cirque du Soleil - Ka Tickets Cirque du Soleil - Zumanity Tickets Grease Tickets Jersey Boys Tickets Lion King Tickets Monty Pythons Spamalot Tickets South Pacific Tickets Wicked Tickets 
 Featured Sports 
 Baltimore Orioles Tickets Boston Red Sox Tickets Chicago Cubs Tickets Chicago Cubs Rooftop Tickets Detroit Tigers Tickets Green Monster Tickets Los Angeles Angels of Anaheim Tickets Los Angeles Dodgers Tickets New York Mets Tickets New York Yankees Tickets 
 Las Vegas Events 
 Amazing Tickets B B King Tickets B-52s Tickets Billy Joel and Elton John Tickets Brooks Dunn Tickets Cirque du Soleil Tickets Cirque du Soleil - Mystere Tickets Eagles Tickets Earth Wind Tickets Ringling Tickets 
 Featured Venues 
 Apollo Victoria Tickets Fenway Park Tickets Ford Center Of Performing Arts-il Tickets Gershwin Theatre Tickets LaSalle Bank Theatre (Shubert Theatre - IL) Tickets Minskoff Theatre Tickets Pantages Theatre-ca Tickets Prince Edward Theatre Tickets Virginia/August Wilson Theatre-NY Tickets Yankee Stadium Tickets 
 Featured Cities 
 Anaheim Tickets Beijing Tickets Boston Tickets Bronx Tickets Chicago Tickets Las Vegas Tickets London Tickets Los Angeles Tickets New York Tickets Toronto Tickets 
 Tickets are sold for more than face value. Site-map | Sports-map | Concerts-map | Theater-map | Las Vegas-map | City | Others 
 Contact us | About us | Policy | Help | Resources | FAQ Copyright 2012© - Onlineseats - Buy concert sports theater tickets online
	</body>
</document>
