<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000181" url="http://www.ehow.co.uk/list_5993459_party-ideas-girls-6th-birthday.html" time="2012-07-12-15:22" support="1" score="0.001680276597246479" bingtitle="Party Ideas for Girls on a 6th Birthday | eHow.co.uk" webtitle="Party Ideas for Girls on a 6th Birthday | eHow.co.uk">
			<query id="001138" bing-rank="174"/>
	<description>You could take the easy way out and pile all the birthday guests in the minivan and head to a fast-food restaurant with games and ... Tempting trays: festive party food</description>
	<body>
		Food Home Style Money Family Health more 

 Computers&amp;electronics Hobbies 

 Lifestyle 

 Science&amp;education 

 
 
 eHow.co.uk » Family » Party Ideas for Girls on a 6th Birthday 
 
 
 
Party Ideas for Girls on a 6th Birthday
 Written by Valerie Anders 
Make it a memorable occasion.
 
 Your little girl is turning six next month, and you want to do something different and memorable for her birthday. You could take the easy way out and pile all the birthday guests in the minivan and head to a fast-food restaurant with games and jungle gyms. Or you can invest a little time and have a party that she will remember forever. 
 
Prissy Missy Tea Party
 
A girls-only event.
 
Most little girls love a tea party. You can make your little girl&apos;s party different in several ways. Look for invitations that evoke the theme you are using. You can sometimes find blank notecards that have pictures of teacups and print them yourself using your computer and printer. Another option is downloading pictures of teacups that can be printed on blank cardstock. Invite the girls to come in their Sunday-best dresses. When they arrive, let them decorate inexpensive straw hats with silk flowers, ribbons, broken costume jewelry, beads and tulle. Serve lemonade or punch in real teacups, which can be borrowed from neighbors and family or purchased at a thrift store. Finger sandwiches and miniature cupcakes could be served on doily-lined plates. As party favors, let the girls take home the hats they designed.
 

 
Treasure Hunt
 
Everyone loves a treasure hunt.
 
A treasure hunt will take a little more time and preparation, but it&apos;s so much fun. Prepare simple maps that fit the children&apos;s reading levels. As they arrive, separate them into teams of two or three girls, and let them use the clues to find the things you have hidden around the house and the yard. Everyone&apos;s maps can be a little different, or the clues can be arranged in different orders, so that everyone is not looking for the same things at the same time. Refreshments can include hot dogs roasted over a campfire and punch served in coconut-shaped containers. Send everyone home with a small treasure chest, an eyepatch and a tri-corner hat.
 

 
South of the Border Fiesta
 
Assemble your own tacos.
 
As the children arrive, give each one an inexpensive sombrero purchased from a party supply store. You could also make striped scarves for them to wear over their shoulders. Since most children love tacos, let them make their own. Set up a taco bar, including soft and hard tortilla shells, seasoned meat, tomatoes, lettuce, cheese, sour cream and salsa. After Pin the Tail on the Donkey, let the children have a swing at a piñata. Then, as party favors, give them small bags in which to take home the candies they collect from the piñata.
 

 
Stone Soup
 
This becomes soup?
 
When you send out invitations for this unusual party, ask each child to bring something different to help make &quot;stone soup.&quot; One could bring a potato, another a carrot and another might bring a stalk of celery. Have the ingredients on hand, just in case the children forget. Then you can give them the ingredients as they arrive. Read the story &quot;Stone Soup,&quot; and then enjoy making a pot of fresh soup with the children. Grilled-cheese sandwiches and a birthday cake complete the refreshments. For party favors, send each child home with a goody bag which contains a recipe for her own stone soup that she can make with her family.
 

 
 References 

 Thrifty Fun: Tea Party Ideas for a Six Year Old Berkeley Parents Network: Birthday Party Ideas for Five Year Olds DLTK&apos;s Educational Activities: Stone Soup 
 
 Don’t miss: Slideshows 
 
 The top 10 baby books for mummies 10 odd band food demands Kings of social media, the most popular Facebook pages 
 
 Comments 
 
Editors’ pick
 10 baby-friendly cafes in London 
Social activity

What your friends are reading
 
You may also like…

 Birthday Party Ideas for a 10 Year Old Girl Ideas for a 6th Birthday Party Great Birthday Party Ideas for Girls Preteen Girl Birthday Party Ideas Girl&apos;s 11th Birthday Party Ideas 
 
More editors’ picks

 Tempting trays: festive party food Motorbikes for girls Throw your very own Jubilee street party Top 21 things to do on your 21st birthday 
 
Copyright©1999-2012 Demand Media, Inc. About us 

Use of this site constitutes acceptance of the Terms of use and Privacy policy of eHow. Ad Choices en-GB
	</body>
</document>
