<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000481" url="http://homeparents.about.com/od/diningout/Dining_Out_With_Your_Family.htm" time="2012-07-12-15:44" support="4" score="0.026950108318910152" bingtitle="Money Saving Tips: Dining Out With Your Family" webtitle="Money Saving Tips: Dining Out With Your Family">
			<query id="000150" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000126" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000155" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000133" bing-rank="45"/>
	<description>Next time you eat out at a fast food restaurant, save those napkins. Here are some of the money-saving uses for them.</description>
	<body>
		Parenting 
 Stay-at-Home Parents Search 
 Stay-at-Home Parents Home Management Parenting Help Time for You 
 Filed In: 
 Family Budget &gt; Money Saving Tips 
 
Dining Out With Your Family
 Our readers have shared some of their frugal tips help you save money. 
 Eat an Appetizer 
 Rather than ordering a complete meal, you and your spouse can eat out for much less by sharing an appetizer. Here&apos;s how. 
 Fast Food Play Center 
 Take your kids to a fast-food play center for an inexpensive, but fun, family outing. 
 Kids Drink for Free 
 Here&apos;s a hint for saving money by sharing your drink with your kids when eating out. 
 Napkins as Bibs 
 When eating out, this tip will help you save money by using napkins as bibs. 
 Order Water and Save 
 Buying drinks for your family can be expensive, so why not order water. It&apos;s free. 
 Save on Drinks When Eating Out 
 Here&apos;s a tip for saving money on drinks when eating out. 
 Save Those Napkins 
 Next time you eat out at a fast food restaurant, save those napkins. Here are some of the money-saving uses for them. 
 Supersize Your Order When Eating Out 
 Next time you eat out at a fast-food restaurant this tip for supersizing your order could save you money. 
 Discuss in our forum 
 Explore Stay-at-Home Parents Must Reads 
 Can I Stay Home? Get a Guilt Free Break Slash Your Grocery Bill Should Both Parents Work? 15 Minute Cleanups for Every Room 
 Most Popular 
 Ice Cream Maker Vanilla Ice Cream Ziplock Bag Ice Cream Borax Powdered Sugar Icing/Glaze 
 By Category 
 At-Home Survival Guide Benefits: Why Stay Home From Workplace to Home Family Budget Home-Based Business Education and School Family Health and Safety Fun and Leisure Raising Your Children Get Organized Holidays Home Decorating and Crafts Home Maintenance Housekeeping Tips In the Kitchen / Recipes 
 Stay-at-Home Parents 
 About.com Parenting Stay-at-Home Parents Family Budget Money Saving Tips Dining Out 
 
 Most Popular Latest Articles RSS 
 
 Advertise on About.com Our Story News&amp;Events Work at About SiteMap All Topics Reprints Help 

 Write for About User Agreement Ethics Policy Patent Info. Privacy Policy Your Ad Choices 
 
©2012 About.com. All rights reserved.

A part of The New York Times Company .
	</body>
</document>
