<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000462" url="http://lastelection.wordpress.com/category/humor-if-one-can-laugh-at-such-a-serious-situation/" time="2012-07-12-15:43" support="1" score="8.729332535072568e-05" bingtitle="Humor (If one can laugh at such a serious situation) « You Wanted ..." webtitle="Humor (If one can laugh at such a serious situation)You Wanted Change.  You Now Have It!  But At What Cost?">
			<query id="000586" bing-rank="247"/>
	<description>• New debt on the credit card: $16,500 • Outstanding ... fast food workers “duct taped inside fast food restaurant ... out half of the heart from a person; we put ...</description>
	<body>
		You Wanted Change. You Now Have It! But At What Cost? 
 
 
Pages

 About Conservative Websites WHERE ARE WE HEADED? 
 
 
 
 July 2012 S M T W T F S «Jun     1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31   
 
Categories

 Christian Perspective Conservative Perspective Democrats Global Warming Humor (If one can laugh at such a serious situation) Immigration Iraq Obama and the Media Obama Stuff ObamaCare Race in America Terrorism The Islamic Conspiracy The Left Uncategorized US Economics US Politics Who Is Obama? 
 
Recent Posts

 Titanic Mistake (sent by the van Luyns) Muslims Desecrating Allied Soldier’s Graves (sent by June Hankins) Government Gone Wild Video U.S. Bridges, Chinese Contractors (sent by June Hankins) Daddy Is A Gay Dancer (sent by June Hankins) BUCHANAN TO OBAMA (sent by Bob Luttrell) The Entire Campaign In One Cartoon (sent by Betsy Woodruff) Scottish Drinking Song (sent by Alyce Getz) No, Mr. President (sent by Joey Murray) List of Republican Budget Cuts (sent by Joyce Griffith) Great Sign (sent by Gene Wilson) OBAMA’S CZARS (sent by Cheryl Robinson) Mr. and Mrs. Cranky Pants (sent by Polly Campbell) Gimme Generation (sent by Alyce Getz) Dealing With Muslims (sent by Steve Hill) 
 
Archives

 June 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 
 
 
 Titanic Mistake (sent by the van Luyns) June 10, 2012, 9:20 am
Filed under: Humor (If one can laugh at such a serious situation) , Obama Stuff 
 
 Comments Off 
 
 Daddy Is A Gay Dancer (sent by June Hankins) February 21, 2012, 10:31 am
Filed under: Humor (If one can laugh at such a serious situation) 
One day a fourth-grade teacher asked the children what their fathers did for a living.  All the typical answers came up–fireman, mechanic, businessman,  salesman…and so forth..

However, little Justin was being uncharacteristically quiet, so when the teacher prodded him about his father, he replied,“My father’s an exotic dancer in a gay cabaret and takes off all his clothes to music in front of other men and they put money in his underwear. Sometimes, if the offer is really good, he will go home with some guy and stay with him all night for money.”

The teacher, obviously shaken by this statement, hurriedly set the other children to work on some exercises and took little Justin aside to ask him,“Is that really true about your father?”

“No,”the boy said,“He works for the Democratic National Committee and helped to get Obama elected, but it’s too embarrassing to say that in front of the other kids.”

 Wikipedia: wally definition:”’Scottish”’fine, sturdy. → 
 Comments Off 
 
 The Entire Campaign In One Cartoon (sent by Betsy Woodruff) February 20, 2012, 12:24 pm
Filed under: Humor (If one can laugh at such a serious situation) 
 “The problems we face today exist because the people who work for a living are outnumbered by those who vote for a living.” 
 
 Comments Off 
 
 Scottish Drinking Song (sent by Alyce Getz) February 20, 2012, 11:23 am
Filed under: Humor (If one can laugh at such a serious situation) 
This is a hoot!

http://www.youtube.com/watch_popup?v=MZ35SOU9HTM
 Comments Off 
 
 Great Sign (sent by Gene Wilson) February 6, 2012, 8:32 pm
Filed under: Humor (If one can laugh at such a serious situation) , Terrorism 
 
 Comments Off 
 
 Simple Economics (sent by Jim Davis) January 10, 2012, 11:14 pm
Filed under: Conservative Perspective , Humor (If one can laugh at such a serious situation) , US Economics 
Lesson #1:

Why the U.S. Credit was downgraded:

• U.S. Tax revenue: $2,170,000,000,000
• Fed budget: $3,820,000,000,000
• New debt: $ 1,650,000,000,000
• National debt: $14,271,000,000,000
• Recent budget cuts: $ 38,500,000,000

Let’s now remove 8 zeros and pretend it’s a household budget:

• Annual family income: $21,700
• Money the family spent: $38,200
• New debt on the credit card: $16,500
• Outstanding balance on the credit card: $142,710
• Total budget cuts: $38.50

Got it?

OK now Lesson # 2: Common Sense

Here’s another way to look at the Debt Ceiling:

Let’s say, You come home from work and find there has been
a sewer backup in your neighborhood….and your home has
sewage all the way up to your ceilings.

What do you think you should do?

1.   Raise the Ceilings, or
2.   Pump out the sewage

Your Choice is coming November 2012.

 
 Comments Off 
 
 2012 Bumper Sticker (sent by Betsy Woodruff) January 8, 2012, 7:54 pm
Filed under: Conservative Perspective , Humor (If one can laugh at such a serious situation) 
 
 Comments Off 
 
 Perspective….. (sent by Betsy Woodruff) October 17, 2011, 3:27 pm
Filed under: Conservative Perspective , Humor (If one can laugh at such a serious situation) , US Politics 
perspective…..

All you Need to Know about Government Bureaucracy:

** Pythagorean Theorem:……………………….24 words.
** Lord’s prayer:…………………………………..66 words.
** Archimedes’Principle:……………………….67 words.
** 10 Commandments:…………………………179 words.
** Gettysburg address:…………………………286 words.
** Declaration of Independence:…………..1,300 words.
** US Constitution with all 27 Amendments:……..7,818 words.
** US Government regulations on sale of cabbage:…….26,911 words.

SORT OF PUTS THINGS INTO PROPER PERSPECTIVE, DOESN’T IT?
 Comments Off 
 
 Debt Limit Analogy (sent by Trudy van Luyn) October 17, 2011, 3:21 pm
Filed under: Humor (If one can laugh at such a serious situation) , US Economics 
Here is a crude but effective way to look at the debt ceiling—maybe even Liberals might understand it!

Suppose you come home from work and find there has been a sewer backup in your home, and you have sewage up to your ceilings.

What do you think you should do??
A.     raise the ceiling?
B.      pump out the sewage?
 Comments Off 
 
 Trick or Treat (sent by Bob Watson) October 14, 2011, 10:40 am
Filed under: Conservative Perspective , Democrats , Humor (If one can laugh at such a serious situation) 
 
 Comments Off 
 
 Bikers versus PETA (sent by Steve Hill) September 30, 2011, 8:00 pm
Filed under: Humor (If one can laugh at such a serious situation) 
What a wonderful coming together of two diverse groups! We need more gatherings where the idiot activists are given warm, moist, aromatic welcomes like this one. This is why PETA usually protests women wearing fur rather than bikers wearing leather. Sounds to me like the old saying,“you mess with the bull, and you get the horns”. Gee, I guess these characters thought that Bikers where going to be politically correct like the rest of the wimpy world.

Johnstown, PA (GlossyNews)–Local and state police scoured the hills outside rural Johnstown, Pennsylvania, after reports of three animal rights activists going missing after attempting to protest the wearing of leather at a large motorcycle gang rally this weekend. Two others, previously reported missing, were discovered by fast food workers“duct taped inside fast food restaurant dumpsters,”according to police officials.

“Something just went wrong,“said a still visibly shaken organizer of the protest.“Something  just went horribly, horribly, wrong.“The organizer said a group of concerned animal rights activist groups,“growing tired of throwing fake blood and shouting profanities at older women wearing leather or fur coats,”decided to protest the annual motorcycle club event“in a hope to show them our outrage at their wanting to use leather in their clothing and motor bike seats.”“In fact,”said the organizer,“motorcycle gangs are one of the biggest abusers of wearing leather, and we decided it was high time that we let them know that we disagree with them using it. ergo, they should stop.”

According to witnesses, protesters arrived at the event in a vintage 1960′s era Volkswagen van and began to pelt the gang members with balloons filled with red colored water, simulating blood, and shouting“you’re murderers”to passersby. This, evidently, is when the brouhaha began.

“They peed on me!!!”charged one activist.“They grabbed me, said I looked like I was French, started calling me‘La Trene’, and duct taped me to a tree so they could pee on me all day!”

Still others claimed they were forced to eat hamburgers and hot dogs under duress. Those who resisted were allegedly held down while several bikers“farted on their heads.”

Police officials declined comments on any leads or arrests due to the ongoing nature of the investigation; however, organizers for the motorcycle club rally expressed“surprise”at the allegations.“That’s preposterous,“said one high-ranking member of the biker organizing committee.“We were having a party, and these people showed up and were very rude to us.  They threw things at us, called us names, and tried to ruin the entire event. So, what did we do? We invited them to the party! What could be friendlier than that? You know, just because we are all members of motorcycle clubs does not mean we do not care about inclusiveness. Personally, I think it shows a lack of character for them to be saying such nasty things about us after we bent over backwards to make them feel welcome.”

When confronted with the allegations of force-feeding the activists meat, using them as ad hoc latrines, leaving them incapacitated in fast food restaurant dumpsters, and‘farting on their heads,’the organizer declined to comment in detail.“That’s just our secret handshake,”assured the organizer.
 Comments Off 
 
 Medical Expertise (sent by Bubba Gochenour) September 23, 2011, 6:54 pm
Filed under: Humor (If one can laugh at such a serious situation) 
A doctor from Israel says:“In Israel the medicine is so advanced that we cut off a man’s testicles; we put them into another man, and in 6 weeks he is looking for work.”

The German doctor comments:“That’s nothing, in Germany we take part of the brain out of a person; we put it into another person’s head, and in 4 weeks he is looking for work.”

A Russian doctor says:“That’s nothing either. In Russia we take out half of the heart from a person; we put it into another person’s chest, and in 2 weeks he is looking for work.”

The U.S.doctor answers immediately:“That’s nothing my colleagues, you are way behind us….in the USA, about 2 years ago, we grabbed a person from Kenya with no brains, no heart, and no balls….we made him President of the United States, and now……. the whole country is looking for work
 Comments Off 
 
 Obama Joke (sent by Eddie Bailey) September 23, 2011, 7:24 am
Filed under: Humor (If one can laugh at such a serious situation) 
An Illegal Alien, a Muslim and a Communist go into a bar.

The bartender asks:“What can I get you, Mr. President?”
 Comments Off 
 
 Archie Bunker on Democrats September 16, 2011, 12:00 pm
Filed under: Democrats , Humor (If one can laugh at such a serious situation) , US Politics 
This is TIMELY!

http://www.youtube.com/watch_popup?v=cMnSp4qEXNM&amp;NR=1
 Comments Off 
 
 New Candidate for President (sent by Eddie Bailey) September 16, 2011, 5:50 am
Filed under: Humor (If one can laugh at such a serious situation) 
This is the candidate that we’ve been waiting for…he has what it takes to do the job in Washington!

 
 Comments Off 
 «Older Posts 

 Blog at WordPress.com .
Theme: Benevolence by Theron Parlin .
Syndicate entries using RSS and Comments (RSS) .

 Follow 
 Follow“You Wanted Change. You Now Have It! But At What Cost?” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
