<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000950" url="http://malaysiabudgethotel.com/accommodation/sabah/summer-lodge.html" time="2012-07-12-16:19" support="1" score="0.0017209973575643667" bingtitle="Sabah Budget Hotels / Youth Hostels &gt; Summer Lodge" webtitle="Sabah Budget Hotels / Youth Hostels &gt; Summer Lodge">
			<query id="000718" bing-rank="141"/>
	<description>Other Services like Rent-A-Car or Limousine ... pub &amp; disco, saloon, licensed money changer, fast food restaurant ... Terminal 2) make your way to the taxi coupon counter ...</description>
	<body>
		Cheap Accommodation in Malaysia | Malaysia Budget Hotels
   
 
 
 
 Home Budget Hotels 
 &gt;&gt; Malaysia States &gt;&gt; Beaches&amp;Islands &gt;&gt; Hills&amp;Highlands &gt;&gt; Forest Reserve 
 Budget Tours 
 &gt;&gt; All Budget Tours &gt;&gt; Great Offers &gt;&gt; Recent Events/Trips 
 Destinations 
 &gt;&gt; Beaches&amp;Islands &gt;&gt; Hills&amp;Highlands &gt;&gt; National Parks &gt;&gt; Malaysia States 
 Transportation 
 &gt;&gt; Airports &gt;&gt; Airlines &gt;&gt; Coaches / Buses &gt;&gt; Trains &gt;&gt; Taxis 
 Travellers&apos; Tips 
 &gt;&gt; Fast Facts of Malaysia &gt;&gt; Saying it in Malay &gt;&gt; Useful Contacts &gt;&gt; Maps of Malaysia 
 
 
 

 
Summer Lodge
Lot 120 Jalan Gaya
Kota Kinabalu
Sabah 


 

 Are you looking for a spacious and clean room endow with splendid amenities?

Look no further!

Spacious, cleanliness and excellent amenities are all at the tips of your fingers as our objective is to provide you with a pleasant stay with us.

Outstandingly, the convenience of the accessibility to all parts of the city is not a problem at all. Gaya Street is where we are located as well as being known as the heart of the City, where the weekly Sunday bazaar will be held to keep all amused.

We, at Summer Lodge Kota Kinabalu are looking forward to welcomeing you and wishing you a pleasant journey to the West Coast of Borneo.


We provide 24 Hours Reception Service, Security and Computerized Touch Access Door with No Curfew / Lockout.

Spacious Living / Activities Room with Roof-Top Garden&amp;BBQ Area are provided as well.

All Rooms (Bed with Linen Provided) are Air-Conditioned while ALL 10 shower is equip with Hot&amp;Cold Pressure Water Heater plus shampoo&amp;body soap provided.

Towel&amp;Blanket are for Rent for Dormitory and Free use of Towel&amp;Quilt for Single, Double&amp;Twin Room.

We offer many services including: Bar / Convenient Store&amp;Lounge Use of Locker&amp;Luggage Storage Area, Air-Port Pick-Up (Pre-Arrangement required), Cable TV&amp;DVD Movies, Internet Access&amp;WiFi, Tour / Travel Information, Reservation&amp;Arrangement
Comp Coffee, Tea&amp;Drinking Water whole day long

Other Services like Rent-A-Car or Limousine Service can be arranged.


Attractions in the nearby area:

1 minute walk to Sunday Bazaar, Pizza Hut and a locally well-known Japanese Restaurant which serves a-la carte&amp;buffet

2 minutes walk to pub&amp;disco, saloon, licensed money changer, fast food restaurant, library, internet cafe and amusement centre

3 minutes walk to supermarket, taxi station, local food kopitiam (coffee shop), travel agent, Atkinson Clock Tower, police station, budget airline sales office, handicraft centre and clinic

4 minutes walk to post office, major shopping complexes, long-distance coach terminal, Sabah Tourism office, Malaysia Tourism office and banks

Less than 10 minutes walk to cinema, ferry terminal (to/from Labuan, Brunei and Tunku Abdul Rahman Park TAR), Signal Hill Observatory Tower and Waterfront Esplanade 

 ROOMS&amp;RATES 
 
 HOTEL RESERVATION 
 Room Type : Mixed Dormitory Female Dormitory Double Room Twin Room Family Room Check In Date : No of Unit : 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 Check Out Date : 

 To book your your hotel, please enter the above information and click on Book Now icon on the right. If you have any problem doing this online booking, please find out more at our online booking demo . Alternatively, you could drop us an email at info@malaysiabudgethotel.com 
 
 
 BREAKFAST Included 

Do send in your enquiry if you have any queries.

 Room Type Description Rate/Room/Night Normal Mixed Dormitory 6 / 8 / 18 Bedded Dorm Room on allocation Accommodation with Common Bathroom MYR 22
(USD 7.33) Female Dormitory 6 / 8 / 18 Bedded Dorm Room Accommodation with Common Bathroom MYR 25
(USD 8.33) Double Room Queen size Bed / 2 Single Bed with Common Bathroom . Max 2 pax MYR 75
(USD 25.00) Twin Room 2 Single Bed with Common Bathroom . Max 2 pax MYR 75
(USD 25.00) Family Room 1 Queen size Bed + 1 Bunk Bed or 2 Single Bed with Common Bathroom 
. Max 4 pax MYR 115
(USD 38.33) 
 NOTE: 
 Normal : Weekdays&amp;Weekends
	</body>
</document>
