<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000383" url="http://www.kclunchspots.com/2011/02/taco-factory-7439-broadway/" time="2012-07-12-15:35" support="1" score="0.001598928792703569" bingtitle="Taco Factory: 7439 Broadway » Kansas City Lunch Spots" webtitle="Taco Factory: 7439 BroadwayKansas City Lunch Spots">
			<query id="000687" bing-rank="217"/>
	<description>Like a fast food joint, you order at a counter and ... Basically, Taco Factory is a fast food restaurant well-poised to ... aptly-named, since every ingredient in the place ...</description>
	<body>
		Kansas City Lunch Spots 
 It shouldn&apos;t be this hard to find some place to eat lunch. 
 Home About Suggestions? Food and Drink Links Food Truck Feed Contact 
 
 Taco Factory: 7439 Broadway 
   Posted by Dave at 12:20 am Feb 22 2011   
Taco Factory set up shop early this year in the old Sweet Guy spot in the heart of Waldo near 75th and Wornall. I was honestly prepared to never set foot in this place. Everything I had heard and read about Taco Factory made it sound like a middle of the road, cheapish whitey taco place that caters to boring people and drunks.

It turns out I was completely right, but I did enjoy my meal to a reasonable degree. The interior is brightly lit and brightly colored. Like a fast food joint, you order at a counter and pick up your order when your number appears on a monitor mounted high in the dining room.

 

I haven’t seen the number method deployed in this manner before, and I far prefer it to obnoxious shouting via loudspeaker or food runners shouting people’s names in the dining room.

 

The menu is reminiscent of popular fast food chains like Chipotle or Pancheros but I think the quality and flavor are a bit superior at Taco Factory. The shredded beef was succulent and delicious, despite a distinct over-reliance on salt. And the tempura battered fish was great; I would go back just for that.

Unfortunately, there are no corn tortillas to be had, only premade flour ones. They may be softened slightly on a grill, but are a little dense and chewy by the time you take the first bite. Each taco is attractively, if inauthentically adorned with shredded lettuce, red cabbage, feta cheese crumbles, some pale tomato and a generous handful of some tepid“Mexican shredded cheese mix”–probably Monterey Jack and Cheddar.

 

Don’t bother with the rice and beans. The rice is over-seasoned and has the consistency of minute-rice. The beans are too salty and seem to come from a can.

The entree salads are large and attractively presented in metal bowls with multi-colored fried tortilla strips. The finely shredded chicken was likely cooked in-house and was well-seasoned and pleasant in texture. The salad dressing has the appearance of having come from a Sysco gallon jug, but you may prefer the judicious use of salsa instead. You have the choice of hot or mild salsa but I was unable to detect any heat whatsoever in either one.

 

 

A highly publicized Happy Hour from 3-5pm advertises $1 Bud Lite draws and $2 margaritas. The signage is sponsored by none other than Pepe Lopez tequila which, along with the bottles of Hiram Walker triple sec I saw behind the counter probably creates a hell of a cheap-ass wallop in a margarita. By the way, what’s up with happy hours that end at 5pm? Happy Hour used to be a way to compete for after-work business, hasn’t this gotten a little out of hand?

Basically, Taco Factory is a fast food restaurant well-poised to succeed in Waldo, home to some of the city’s oldest and most mediocre restaurants. It is also aptly-named, since every ingredient in the place probably came out of a factory of some sort. It will appeal to college students, people who can’t get in to Waldo Pizza, and drunk people (it’s open very late at night). I’d love to tell you more about their hours and their menu choices, but Taco Factory doesn’t have a website.

 

 


   fast food , mexican , waldo   Add comments 
   7 Responses to“Taco Factory: 7439 Broadway”

 Fred Sanford says: February 22, 2011 at 1:20 am 
pretty funny to think that waldo housed jasper&apos;s for 3 decades, huh? on the other hand I also member old man mirabile taking shots at folks in the parking lot: perhaps a white-bread taco place is more in the spirit of the times….
 Reply succotash says: February 22, 2011 at 5:02 pm 
Spot on.

I&apos;m glad it&apos;s there? Maybe? Yes, in an it-could-be-worse and at-least-it&apos;s-not-a-chain kind of way. But it is nothing special.
 Reply Mike Ekey says: February 22, 2011 at 5:14 pm 
Went in about a week after it opened and was impressed by the fish tacos, too. The rest was just OK.

A friend of mine said she was in love with the salsa…i dunno…maybe give it another month or so to pep up the spice in the food and try again?
 Reply KCNapkins Guy says: February 24, 2011 at 10:00 pm 
Gonna guess that the cheese is actually queso fresco instead of feta, right? Hopefully?
 Reply The DLC says: February 24, 2011 at 10:11 pm 
Nope, it says feta right on the menu.
 Reply kc food guy says: March 30, 2011 at 7:47 pm 
Yes, there was feta on the horrible tacos. This place is perfect for Waldo, plenty of room for strollers and packs of youngsters.
 Reply Chelly’s Cafe: 218 West 85th Street»Kansas City Lunch Spots says: August 4, 2011 at 12:36 am 
[...] good locale for Mexican food, with the supremely mediocre anglocized Cantina del Ray and Taco Factory up north. Paparico’s is the newest addition to Waldo’s Mexican family which has very [...]
 
 
   Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
 Name (required)

 E-mail (required)

 URI 

 Your Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 

 Notify me of followup comments via e-mail 
 
   Lucia’s Restaurant: 641 East Hwy 24, Independence   Chelly’s Cafe: 218 West 85th Street 
 
Sponsors

 Kansas City Self Storage Wisconsin Caterers 
 
Recent Posts

 Dagwoood’s Cafe: 1117 Southwest Blvd, KCK The Big Biscuit: 12276 Shawnee Mission Parkway, Shawnee, KS Friends Sushi&amp;Bento Place: 1808 West 39th St Sama Zama: 425 Westport Rd Anna’s Oven: 1809 W. 39th St 
 
My Tweets
 
Find a Lunch Spot

 2009 (1) 2010 (1) 39th street (4) all over the place (2) asian (10) bar food (5) bars (1) bbq (20) beer (33) Best of (1) bistro (1) breakfast (4) brookside (4) buffet (2) bullshit (1) burnt ends (1) cash only (2) casinos (1) chain (1) cheap (1) cheesesteak (3) chicago (1) Chicago dogs (2) chicken (1) chili (1) chinese (5) classics (1) closed (25) clueless (2) coffee (3) columbus park (3) cookies (1) crossroads (2) deli (6) depressing (3) diner food (8) don&apos;t get the buffet (1) downtown (3) drive-thru (1) dumplings (1) eastside (2) ethiopian (2) family style (1) fast food (4) faux-mexican (2) fish (4) french (1) french fries ain&apos;t pommes frites (1) fried (1) friendly to a fault (1) full bar (22) funny (1) German (1) Get the cabbage soup (1) gluten-free (1) greek (3) Grocery (2) gutbomb (1) hamburgers (13) hawaiian (1) hot dogs (1) huaraches (1) hunting (1) Independence (3) Indian (3) Irish (1) italian (11) italian beef (1) jackasses (1) japanese (6) johnson county (32) kck (8) korean (4) leawood (1) lenexa (9) liquor (1) margaritas (1) mayonnaise sucks (1) merriam (5) mexican (25) middle eastern (8) Mission (4) music venues (1) names (1) new (1) noodles (4) north (1) Northeast KC (2) northland (2) not to be confused with Red Lobster (1) odd (1) Oh sweet Jesus (2) outdoor (1) overland park (17) overpriced (1) pizza (9) plaza (2) polls (1) pork tenderloin (1) Prairie Village (1) pupusas (1) radio (1) reuben (3) river market (12) Russian (1) salads (2) salvadoran (2) sandwiches (17) sausages (2) shawnee (4) should have beer but doesn&apos;t (6) small (1) soda fountain (1) sopes (1) soul food (2) soup (5) South Kansas City (2) spring hill (1) St. Louis pizza (1) suggestions (1) sushi (4) swank (4) tacos (3) terrible (1) umkc (3) Uncategorized (19) video games (2) vietnamese (4) waldo (5) websites (1) West Bottoms (2) westport (7) westside (3) wtf (1) yuppies (1) zzzzzzzzzz (1) 
 
More Info
 
 Map of Lunch Spots KC Free Press Writing 
 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 January 2012 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 June 2007 May 2007 
   Subscribe in a reader 
 
Subscribe via E-Mail
 
Enter your email address:

 
 
Delivered by FeedBurner 
 
 ©2012 Kansas City Lunch Spots Suffusion theme by Sayontan Sinha
	</body>
</document>
