<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000958" url="http://boards.straightdope.com/sdmb/archive/index.php/t-590911.html" time="2012-07-12-16:19" support="1" score="0.0027999933416889902" bingtitle="McDonald&apos;s axes the Big N&apos; Tasty [Archive] - Straight Dope Message ..." webtitle="McDonald&apos;s axes the Big N&apos; Tasty [Archive]  - Straight Dope Message Board">
			<query id="001163" bing-rank="192"/>
	<description>Let me tell you, the only time it seems reasonable to spend $7 on a terrible sandwich from a fast food restaurant is when you&apos;re at ... with ever smaller globs of condiments ...</description>
	<body>
		Straight Dope Message Board &gt; Main &gt; Cafe Society &gt;McDonald&apos;s axes the Big N&apos; Tasty PDA 
View Full Version : McDonald&apos;s axes the Big N&apos; Tasty 
 Stan Shmenge 12-28-2010, 09:48 PM One of the best values on their menu and one of the nicest. Probably costs more than a quarter pounder to make, and costs less. And it was my girlfriend&apos;s favorite sandwich. You can&apos;t get a combo there for less than six bucks any more. First the fried apple pies, now this. Screw you, Ronald, I&apos;ll be over at your direct competitor where they still have a sandwich with tomatoes on it that won&apos;t set you back almost eight bucks for a combo. :mad::mad::mad: Waffle Decider 12-28-2010, 10:14 PM Damn, I actually like the Big N&apos; Tasty. :( Mahaloth 12-28-2010, 10:21 PM Was this their Whopper? MeanOldLady 12-28-2010, 10:24 PM When&apos;d they do this? I was at the airport a couple of days ago, and was going to order one, but didn&apos;t see it on the menu. Let me tell you, the only time it seems reasonable to spend $7 on a terrible sandwich from a fast food restaurant is when you&apos;re at an airport, where you&apos;d otherwise spend $15 on a terrible non fast food sandwich. Hell, I had two drinks at the airport bar, and somehow I ended up paying those people $25. Anyway, I was mildly irritated that the Big N Tasty was nowhere to be found since that&apos;s the best sandwich there, and was cursing the airport for their incomplete menu at the time. Maybe McD&apos;s should have been the subject of my ire. JohnGalt 12-29-2010, 12:26 PM It disappeared around here (Minnesota) in October it seems (and it was my go-to sandwich choice). They have their Angus burgers, which are way too salty for me, so I&apos;ve started going to Hardees for my once-a-week treat. bouv 12-29-2010, 12:31 PM I guess I never saw the big difference between this and a quarter pounder...both were just burgers with lettuce, onion, and cheese, right? And once you added in the Angus 1/3 pounder, they basically had three nearly identical burgers. silenus 12-29-2010, 12:36 PM The Quarter Pounder doesn&apos;t have lettuce. enalzi 12-29-2010, 12:36 PM I guess I never saw the big difference between this and a quarter pounder...both were just burgers with lettuce, onion, and cheese, right? And once you added in the Angus 1/3 pounder, they basically had three nearly identical burgers.

The Quarter Pounder has cheese, ketchup, mustard, onion, and pickle.
The Big n&apos; Tasty has the same patty, but with cheese, ketchup, mayo, lettuce, tomato, and pickle.
The Angus Deluxe has the same ingredients as the Big N&apos; Tasty, but with the bigger patty. The Amazing Hanna 12-29-2010, 12:39 PM I called it T&apos; Big Nasty on Twitter recently. I don&apos;t really like it, but I have been known to order one if I&apos;m really, really hungry and drunk.

It doesn&apos;t really taste like real meat to me, more like meat-flavored... something. A lot of artificial flavoring, or maybe I&apos;m just imagining?

The only good things at McDonalds is still the breakfasts and buying a bunch of little cheeseburgers and a milk shake. RealityChuck 12-29-2010, 01:37 PM The Big &apos;n Tasty was the only actual hamburger on McDonald&apos;s menu (except for their original tiny burger, which is too small and thin to cook properly and is always dried out). I noticed it was gone a few weeks ago. Now they have all these things with that yellow petroleum byproduct vomited onto it. enalzi 12-29-2010, 01:43 PM The Big &apos;n Tasty was the only actual hamburger on McDonald&apos;s menu (except for their original tiny burger, which is too small and thin to cook properly and is always dried out). I noticed it was gone a few weeks ago. Now they have all these things with that yellow petroleum byproduct vomited onto it.

You do realized you can get all the burgers without cheese right? Stoid 12-29-2010, 01:51 PM I agree that the meat is nasty, and breakfast is what Mcd&apos;s is good for. Although the child in me occasionally craves a SugarBurger, aka Big Mac, I find that craving is usually much better satisfied by a Big Carl. SmellMyWort 12-29-2010, 01:51 PM I thought it was good but would really like to see the return of the Arch Delux. Mahaloth 12-29-2010, 02:06 PM Uh, I&apos;ll ask again. Was this their Whopper? I&apos;m trying to remember it. I know they made their own Whopper at one point, but was this it? enalzi 12-29-2010, 03:08 PM Uh, I&apos;ll ask again. Was this their Whopper? I&apos;m trying to remember it. I know they made their own Whopper at one point, but was this it?

It was, in the sense that it had the exact same ingredients. They&apos;ve come out with a lot of similar sandwiches over the years, like the McDLT and the McLean Deluxe. The Angus Deluxe is really the current incarnation. Enuma Elish 12-29-2010, 04:53 PM I haven&apos;t been to McDonalds for a few weeks. There is one a half-mile from my house. I think I&apos;ll take a walk to see if Green Bay is sans Big &apos;N Tasty. And if they don&apos;t have it, liberate a newspaper from the rack and run :D

The burger I really miss is Hardee&apos;s Big and Tasty (pre Carls, of course) and the fat fries Hardees used to have. Sitnam 12-29-2010, 06:12 PM The Big N&apos; Tasty to me always tasted like salt. Enuma Elish 12-29-2010, 06:30 PM The Big N&apos; Tasty to me always tasted like salt.

That could be one of the reasons I liked them. I love a bit of the salty taste.

Carl&apos;s just ruined Hardees. They used to be my favorite fast food spot. Carl&apos;s bought them and they became Bleeech. Now they have improved just enough to be Meh. Roland Orzabal 12-29-2010, 06:39 PM You do realized you can get all the burgers without cheese right?Theoretically, sure. In practice, this has about a 33% success rate at the best locations. You can modify the other toppings with abandon all the live-long day, but deep in their heart of hearts, Micky D&apos;s knows that you want cheese, dammit. RealityChuck 12-29-2010, 06:47 PM You do realized you can get all the burgers without cheese right?Why should I pay for cheese if I don&apos;t want it? Ephemera 12-29-2010, 07:17 PM That is entirely different from stating McDonald&apos;s doesn&apos;t sell hamburgers. Enuma Elish 12-29-2010, 09:05 PM Yup, just got back from Mickey Dee&apos;s. The Big and Tasty is a goner here too. I used to like those, but as time passed, it seemed like they were made with ever smaller globs of condiments and just became dry lettuce burgers with a hint of mayo. Susanann 12-29-2010, 09:16 PM The Quarter Pounder has cheese, ketchup, mustard, onion, and pickle.
The Big n&apos; Tasty has the same patty, but with cheese, ketchup, mayo, lettuce, tomato, and pickle.


If you want to keep getting a big and tasty even though it is off the menu, then all you gotta do,is to order a quarter pounder with ketchup, mayo,lettuce, tomatoe, pickle, and hold the mustard.

Its the Same thing!

This is what i have been doing, its still a big and tastey even though they now usually need the manager to special make it for me, and it is always fresh as a special order. enalzi 12-29-2010, 09:46 PM If you want to keep getting a big and tasty even though it is off the menu, then all you gotta do,is to order a quarter pounder with ketchup, mayo,lettuce, tomatoe, pickle, and hold the mustard.

Its the Same thing!

This is what i have been doing, its still a big and tastey even though they now usually need the manager to special make it for me, and it is always fresh as a special order.

Yep you&apos;ll probably be charged extra though.

I used to work at a McDonald&apos;s restaurant shortly after the Big n&apos; Tasty came out. Back then we never charged for extra condiments, and occasionally we would have the BnT or the Quarter Pounder on sale. So then we would get a bunch of orders for BnTs with only ketchup, mustard, etc. and vice versa. Eventually they wised up and made them the same price.

Also, all McDonald&apos;s sandwiches are made fresh. The only time they would be is if they accidentally made too many of one sandwich, so it might sit there for a couple minutes until someone else orders it. vBulletin®v3.7.3, Copyright©2000-2012, Jelsoft Enterprises Ltd.
	</body>
</document>
