<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000218" url="http://www.care2.com/causes/paleo-take-out-restaurant-to-open-in-denmark.html" time="2012-07-12-15:24" support="2" score="0.0018197591975868082" bingtitle="Paleo Restaurant To Open Soon In Copenhagen, Denmark | Care2 Causes" webtitle="Paleo Restaurant To Open Soon In Copenhagen, Denmark | Care2 Causes">
			<query id="000405" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000311" bing-rank="226"/>
	<description>... is looking back to the Stone Age for his new fast-food restaurant ... “There is room for a glass of red wine once in a ... Minors in Adult Prisons: Sound Punishment or Counter ...</description>
	<body>
		19,747,463 members doing good ! my Care2 
 checking login information 

 Login or Join to earn credits for good causes 

 hi logoff email messages  credits 
 Care2 make a difference 
 Follow @Care2 
   
 care2 home take action causes&amp;news healthy living community ecards butterfly rewards 
 
 CAUSES&amp;amp; NEWS HOME ANIMALS WOMEN POLITICS FOOD LGBT Human Rights more topics 
 
 The Real Food Cause 
 previous 162 
 How to Become a Vegetarian in One Easy Bite 
 193 
 Top 5 GMO Foods To Watch Out For 
 58 
 3 Misleading Food Claims and Why It’s Hard to Eat Right 
 13 
 Food Or Fuel? 
 50 
 Whole Landscape Approach Can Help Feed the World Sustainably 
 294 
 Powerful Anti-Meat Speaker Demands,“Take Animals Off the Menu” 
 37 
 Record Heat Wave Devastates U.S. Corn and Soy Crops, Drives Food Prices Higher 
 24 
 Fast Food Joints Export Poor Health to Singapore 
 55 
 4 Reasons Why Yogurt Is Pudding (Slideshow) 
 44 
 Toxic Tomatoes: What Urban Gardeners Should Know 
 next Address Book Loading... From 
 Your Email 
 To enter multiple email addresses separated by commas (up to 100) 
 Select names from your address book   |    Help 

   
  Add new contacts to Care2 address book Personal message Hello,
 I saw this on Care2 and thought you&apos;d like it as well.

 Care2 is the largest and most trusted information and action site for people who care to make a difference in their lives and the world.     
 We hate spam. We do not sell or share the email addresses you provide.
 
Paleo Take-Out Restaurant To Open In Denmark
 
 by Judy Molland March 17, 2012 6:30 pm 
 93 comments 
 Facebook Tweet Reddit StumbleUpon Digg E-Mail Text Size: A | A | A | A 
 
Chef Thomas Rode Andersen is looking back to the Stone Age for his new fast-food restaurant, Paleo, which will open soon in Copenhagen, Denmark.

What does that mean exactly? No starch, no processed food, no refined sugars, and no dairy products. This is fast food fit for a cave man or woman.

Known as the Paleo Diet, this nutrition plan has been gaining popularity, particularly in the U.S., and celebrities such as Megan Fox are rumored to owe their svelte shapes to this ancient diet plan.

 Primal Gastronomy 

According to proponents of the Paleo Diet , the human body works best (and looks best) when it is fed foods that Stone Age humans originally lived on, such as meat, fish and other game, in addition to plant life such as vegetables and fruits.

Processed foods are a big no-no, as is sugar, dairy, beans, grains and potatoes.

According to Andersen, he is creating“primal gastronomy.”
From The Guardian :

“Bread is the devil,”says Thomas Rode Andersen, 43, who has created the menu for Palo and is head chef at the Michelin-starred Kong Hans in Copenhagen. After divorcing in 2005 he started dating a younger woman and swapped late-night beers and snacks for“paleo”food and exercise.

In the last couple of years he has become something of a poster boy for the paleo movement in Denmark, but he still allows himself the odd break from the diet.

“There is room for a glass of red wine once in a while. If I want to smoke a cigarette I will do that but there might be two months in between,”says Andersen.

Andersen is hoping that his take-out restaurant, which opens in Copenhagen within weeks, will inspire people to try a healthy alternative to standard fast food.

 Europe’s First Paleo Restaurant Opened In Berlin Last Year 

The menu includes“meatza” , essentially a meat pizza turned upside down with a base of organic ground beef topped with baked tomatoes, pickled mushrooms and parsley pesto. For the hot dog, the sausage with wild leeks comes in an egg-based wrapper, while the risotto is made of small kernels of celeriac shaped to look like long-grain rice.

Cutting out refined sugar means that he uses ripe pears to sweeten the puddings.

This is not the first such restaurant: Berlin lays claim to having Europe’s first paleo restaurant, which opened last year.

 President Obama’s Personal Trainer Has His Doubts 

But not everyone is enthusiastic about this diet. Here’s what Cornell McClellan, who is the personal fitness trainer for Barack Obama, has to say, writing in the Chicago Sun-Times :

Not only are these diet choices somewhat questionable, it’s also worth pointing out that our Stone Age ancestors were not eating factory-farmed meat, which is full of chemicals and hormones. Unless you have a spear handy and access to unlimited buffalo, you are going to have a hard time truly eating like a caveman.

Finally, any diet that is as restrictive as the Paleo Diet is problematic because it requires cavemen-sized willpower, which means many people will soon abandon their hunks of meat for a modern-day helping of lasagna.

Still, the idea of doing without processed food, the stuff that crams the shelves of our supermarkets, is admirable. And if the paleo approach makes people think about where their food is coming from, that’s all for the good.

We wish Mr. Andersen all the best in his new venture!

 Related Stories 

 5 More Shocking Reasons To Avoid Fast Food (Infographic) 

 4 Easy Ways To Lose Weight While Loving What You Eat 

 Hold The Meat, Eat Some More Plants 
 
 Read more: Berlin Germany , copenhagen denmark , cornell mcClellan , megan fox , paleo diet , president obama , thomas rode andersen 

 Photo Credit: susanalexx 
 
quick poll
 vote now! thanks for voting! 
Loading poll...
 
 no! leaning no leaning yes yes! 
 
 no! leaning no leaning yes yes! 
 
 0 votes see results take this poll 
 
 Tweet Digg StumbleUpon Reddit Print E-Mail 93 comments 
 
93 comments
 + add your own char l. 12:17 PM PDT
 on
 Jul 3, 2012 
Ah, yes. Carpaccio. Yum! Thanks, Pego, for reminding me of that. Used to go to an Italian place in Heidelberg that had divine carpaccio!

 send a green star 
 Abbe A. 6:09 AM PDT
 on
 Jul 2, 2012 
nice

 send a green star 
 federico b. 9:19 AM PDT
 on
 May 24, 2012 
Grazie per l&apos;articolo.

 send a green star 
 federico b. 9:18 AM PDT
 on
 May 24, 2012 
Grazie per l&apos;articolo.

 send a green star 
 Pego R. 12:52 AM PDT
 on
 Apr 17, 2012 
Steak tartar, Sushi, Carpeche, Ceviche. Raw meat, and very rare, are more digestible than cooked and way more than highly processed meats. We, as a species, have chosen cooking and fermenting as a way of dealing, not with digestibility issues, but with the cycle of parasitism that has built up over the last half-million years of our natural omnivore diet. We have gained the intelligence to figure out how to cut parasitism cycles.

 send a green star 
 Samantha P. 7:47 PM PDT
 on
 Apr 16, 2012 
Awesome to see people raising awareness of the incredible health benefits of paleo, but sad that even a personal trainer as high up as the White House is soooo mis-informed. Paleo is not &quot;restricitve&quot; in fact I eat any vegetable you can think or and any fruit....why isn&apos;t a sweet potato or a banana an acceptable form of carbohydrates? It&apos;s quite easy to find acceptable meats. I eat grassfed pastured meats daily. Paleo people who are doing this as a lifestyle rather than a weight loss trend do place emphasis on eating seasonally as much as possible, but I can say I love bowl of my roasted brussel sprouts any night of the week.
As for whole civilizations being raised from grains...there&apos;s a difference between &quot;surviving&quot; and &quot;thriving&quot;...they merely did what they needed to survive and I have the choice to thrive. Besides that...Paleo&apos;s do not consume immense and grotesque amounts of protein. It&apos;s actually a moderate protein diet with a HUGE emphasis on vegetables, healthy fats, and fruits.

 send a green star 
 colleen p. 5:24 AM PDT
 on
 Apr 16, 2012 
any proof raw meat is toxic to humans? a lot of raw plants are too.

there are Greenland Natives who eat FERMENTED RAW PUFFINS and don&apos;t die. their bodies can handle it.

ahhhh, go chew on a cassava root.

 send a green star 
 Amber M. 11:05 AM PDT
 on
 Apr 13, 2012 
I have to agree with the President&apos;s trainer on this! TOO RESTRICTIVE!

 send a green star 
 rita b. 8:41 PM PDT
 on
 Apr 1, 2012 
What is the natural diet for humans? I have looked at articles from the Weston foundation where a lot of the information on the Paleo diet comes from some of it is just totally unscientific. They say we are more like canids than herbovoires. Well, maybe, but the animals we are really like are other primates. What do they eat? Fruit, shoots, and roots make up the huge majority of their diet. The amount of animal protein they consume is very small and usually low on the evolutionary scale like bugs and shell fish.

There is no way this planet will survive if all seven billion people on it tryed to live on meat based diet. All the great civilizations of world were build on grains corn, wheat, rice barley, amaraeth, quinoa etc. The nick name for the Roman army was - barley crunchers does anyone believe they were weak and unhealthy?

The Paleo people have one thing right - avoid processed food and dairy as much as possible but whole grains and beans -wrong. If you take time to ferment or sprout them they are even healthier and easier to digest.

 send a green star 
 KS G. 5:23 AM PDT
 on
 Mar 25, 2012 
Thanks for the article.

 send a green star 
 
login to add your comment
 
use your care2 login
 username password remember me login help or Log In with Facebook Connect via Facebook . Just click on the icon,&amp;we&apos;ll connect your profile. 
add your comment
 20 20 log in or sign up to start earning Butterfly Credits today! learn more» get comment replies via email 
 Receive Care2 Action Alerts via email! 
 Share my comment on Facebook 
Disclaimer: The views expressed above are solely those of the author and may
 not reflect those of
Care2, Inc., its employees or advertisers.
 
Breaking Stories
 previous 
 Euro Zone Crisis: What More Austerity Means (Video) 
 
 Dispatches From The War On Women: Rape Jokes From Tosh And… 
 
 Wonder Women Blanket Tiny Island With Help for Street Cats… 
 
 In Memory Of Lennox, Dog Put To Death For Resembling A Pit… 
 
 71% of Utah Voters Support Gay Partnerships 
 
 Independent Women Voters Cut Hard For Obama 
 
 Let This Loving Gay Couple Marry in Texas 
 
 On House Floor Tammy Baldwin Shows Why She&apos;s A Serious… 
 
 3 Reasons Marketing High Heels to 6-Year-Olds Is Just Wrong 
 
 3 Ways To Obliterate A Nation&apos;s Healthcare System 
 next ads keep care2 free 
Most Popular

 &lt; 1 of 3 &gt; 
 
 In Memory Of Lennox, Dog Put To Death For Resembling A Pit Bull 
 95 comments 
 Helping Animals Cross the Road, One Overpass at a Time 
 102 comments 
 Dispatches From The War On Women: Rape Jokes From Tosh And We’re Surprised? 
 27 comments 
 Animal Experiments at 25 Year High in the UK 
 52 comments 
 Elderly Bees Discovered The Fountain Of Youth 
 89 comments 
 How to Become a Vegetarian in One Easy Bite 
 162 comments 
 9 Ways To Keep The Global Population Under 9 Billion 
 38 comments 
 83% of Doctors Willing to Quit Because of Obamacare–Except Not Really 
 164 comments 
 5 Endangered National Parks (Slideshow) 
 19 comments 
 Too Much Bloodshed: Thousands Choose Peace for Sudan and South Sudan 
 243 comments 
 Let This Loving Gay Couple Marry in Texas 
 15 comments 
 Record Heat Wave Devastates U.S. Corn and Soy Crops, Drives Food Prices Higher 
 37 comments 
 Gym Class Gets Cut; Obesity Rises in Kids 
 9 comments 
 B Corps Go Global: Ouro Verde Amazonia Becomes the First Brazilian B Corp 
 4 comments 
 Wonder Women Blanket Tiny Island With Help for Street Cats and Dogs 
 28 comments 
Follow Us
 
 facebook twitter rss feeds newsletter 
 
get the causes newsletter
 
Recent Comments from Causes
 
That&apos;s certainly an interesting and cool idea.
 Justin Mullins comments on
 Helping Animals Cross the Road, One Overpass at a Time 
People who have access to good food in good supermarkets in good neighborhoods ought to go out of their…
 Ann Delicath comments on
 Gym Class Gets Cut; Obesity Rises in Kids 
That slavery exists today is shocking enough. That it exists here in the Western World is beyond belief.…
 Suzy D. comments on
 It’s Time to Make Slavery History, Once And For All ads keep care2 free 
meet our writers
 Judy Molland An award-winning writer and teacher, Judy Molland is also an avid hiker, backpacker, and nature lover. Her articles on education, the environment and women&apos;s rights, have appeared in numerous publications, and she is also the author of two books, Get Out! 150 Easy Ways for Kids and Grown-Ups to Get Into Nature and Build a Greener Future, and Straight Talk About Schools Today (both published by Free Spirit). She lives in the San Francisco Bay Area, where she teaches Spanish. less Judy Molland An award-winning writer and teacher, Judy Molland is also an avid hiker, backpacker, and nature... more Cynthia katrina Women&apos;s Media Center see all authors ads keep care2 free 
more from causes

 previous next 
 
 Animal Welfare 
 
 Wonder Women Blanket Tiny Island With Help for Street Cats and Dogs 
 28 comments 
 Causes Canada 
 
 Bev Oda: Where There&apos;s Smoke, There&apos;s Fire 
 28 comments 
 Causes UK 
 
 In Memory Of Lennox, Dog Put To Death For Resembling A Pit Bull 
 95 comments 
 Children 
 
 3 Reasons Marketing High Heels to 6-Year-Olds Is Just Wrong 
 45 comments 
 Civil Rights 
 
 Wikipedia in Russia Shuts Down to Protest Online Censorship 
 4 comments 
 Education 
 
 Gym Class Gets Cut; Obesity Rises in Kids 
 9 comments 
 Environment&amp;Wildlife 
 
 Care2 Success! Leatherback Turtles Protected In Puerto Rico! 
 31 comments 
 Global Development 
 
 9 Ways To Keep The Global Population Under 9 Billion 
 38 comments 
 Global Warming 
 
 Helping Animals Cross the Road, One Overpass at a Time 
 102 comments 
 Health Policy 
 
 Mississippi Abortion Clinic Stays Open For Now 
 7 comments 
 Human Rights 
 
 It&apos;s Time to Make Slavery History, Once And For All 
 9 comments 
 LGBT rights 
 
 71% of Utah Voters Support Gay Partnerships 
 13 comments 
 Politics 
 
 Euro Zone Crisis: What More Austerity Means (Video) 
 12 comments 
 Real Food 
 
 Food Or Fuel? 
 13 comments 
 Trailblazers For Good 
 
 B Corps Go Global: Ouro Verde Amazonia Becomes the First Brazilian B Corp 
 4 comments 
 Women&apos;s Rights 
 
 Dispatches From The War On Women: Rape Jokes From Tosh And We&apos;re Surprised? 
 27 comments 
customize your newsletter
 email address: 
This newsletter will be sent daily and will feature updates on all the causes you care about. Which causes would you like to include?

 Real Food Politics Trailblazers for Good Health Policy Education Human Rights Animal Welfare Women&apos;s Rights Global Warming Children Civil Rights Environment&amp;Wildlife LGBT Rights Global Development Canada UK 
 
 check all uncheck all 
 
 causes&amp;news animal welfare global warming environment&amp;wildlife human rights women&apos;s rights news submit news story 

 healthy living food&amp;recipes health&amp;wellness healthy home family life true beauty pets shopping 

 take action browse petitions create a petition daily action volunteer jobfinder click to donate 

 community&amp;sharing people groups singles photos blogs polls ecards 

 my care2 my account my groups my page my friends my petitionsite my messages join care2 
 
 about us advertise partnerships careers press contact us terms of service privacy subscription center help rss feeds 
 Copyright©2012 Care2.com, inc. and its licensors. All rights reserved 
 CAUSES Animal Welfare Women&apos;s Rights Politics Real Food LGBT Global Development Civil Rights Children Education Environment&amp;Wildlife Health Policy Human Rights Global Warming trailblazers for good Canada UK CARE2 NEWS NETWORK care2 news network home submit a story my news 

 Civil Rights Children Education Environment Health Policy Human Rights Global Warming Trailblazers Canada UK 

 news network home submit a story my news 

 my Care2 main my account my butterfly rewards my click to donate my eCards my friends my groups my kudos my messages my news my page my petitionsite my photos my sharebook my subscriptions
	</body>
</document>
