<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000456" url="http://www.diseaseproof.com/archives/eating-to-live-on-the-outside-eating-to-live-on-the-outside-subway.html" time="2012-07-12-15:42" support="4" score="0.012173340729031507" bingtitle="Eating to Live on the Outside: Subway : Disease Proof" webtitle="Eating to Live on the Outside: Subway : Disease Proof">
			<query id="000286" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="000347" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000649" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="000653" bing-rank="170"/>
	<description>A fast-food restaurant! Have I lost my mind? The answer to that ... onions, olives, pickles, and your choice of condiments. ... Comments (5) Read through and enter the discussion ...</description>
	<body>
		Disease Proof : Disease Proof : Health&amp;Nutrition News&amp;Commentary : Dr. Joel Fuhrman 

The Official Blog of
 Joel Fuhrman, M.D. 
 Search This Site 
Enter keywords:
 Subscribe 
 Add this blog to your feeds or put your e-mail in the box below and hit GO to subscribe by e-mail.
 
 Eat Smart Live Happy 
 
 About Authors Contact Submissions Success Stories DrFuhrman.com Archives 
 Home &gt; Eating to Live on the Outside &gt; Eating to Live on the Outside: Subway 
 Eating to Live on the Outside: Subway 
 Posted on April 20, 2007 by Gerald Pugliese 
 Email This Print Comments (5) Share Link 
 Subway ! A fast-food restaurant! Have I lost my mind? The answer to that question is yes, but that happened a long time ago. And yeah, this week we’ll be taking a look at Subway, a fast-food restaurant. Relax. It’s not the first time we’ve dabbled in fast-food. Just last month we tackled Taco Del Mar and let’s not forget Eating to Live on the Outside favorites Chipotle and Baja Fresh . So of all the mainstream fast-food restaurants, why would I pick Subway?

Well, this week it just so happened that I found myself witness to an unusual amount of Subway commercials and all of them proclaimed“freshness.”This put a bee in my bonnet—and yes, I look very silly in a bonnet. Fresh is a great word, to me it’s the opposite of processed or refined. And when you’re talking about food, fresh is an Eat to Livers best friend. So, what do you say? Let’s see how fresh Subway really is.

Okay, for starters its worth mentioning that we’ve got one across-the-board concession to deal with, bread. If you walk into Subway hell-bent on a sandwich you’ve got to accept the bread, sure, you can order wheat bread, but either way, bread will be your first concession. Personally, I can deal with it.

Let’s see, the first group of sandwiches are called Fresh Fit —there’s that word again. Well the Veggie Delite looks pretty good to me. It’s prepared with lettuce, tomatoes, green peppers, onions, olives, pickles, and your choice of condiments. Now, if I were ordering this, I’d keep everything, get it on wheat bread, and probably garnish with basic yellow mustard. If you get past the bread, you’re left with a pretty phytonutrient-rich meal if you ask me. And, according to the website the Veggie Delite only packs 6 grams of fat or less—a nice little perk.

After the Veggie Delite you basically hit a brick wall. The rest of the Fresh Fit sandwiches include meat, and, there’s really no point ordering them without the meat because you’d just be better off sticking with the Veggie Delite . So let’s just scope out the rest of the menu instead.

Alright, the Fresh Toasted sandwiches are out. I don’t really see any hope here, unless of course Dr. Fuhrman changes his nutritional recommendations to include hearty portions of melted cheese and meat. And you can bet the farm, the beach house, the mansion, and vineyard that that’s not going to happen. Moving on.

Next up are the Local Favorites . Can you hear the sound of screeching tires? Because we’re about to hit a familiar wall again. We’ve got two options, the Cold Cut Combo or the Classic Tuna . The Cold Cut Combo is essentially the Veggie Delite with meat and cheese, and, the Classic Tuna is prepared with mayonnaise—a rancid horrible food in my opinion. Well, let’s see if Subway’s remaining menu selections fair any better.

I’m skipping the Catering Choice —I’m not exactly planning a dinner party here—and the Fresh Fit for Kids doesn’t apply to me, even though I have the mentality of nine-year old. So then, what’s left? Well, not too much. I could try my hand at the Tomato Garden Vegetable with Rotini soup, but it’s loaded with a ton of salt —eighty-six that idea! Or maybe I could just sit and nurse a Fruizle Express . What’s a Fruizle ? It looks like some sort of smoothie, but, I have my suspicions about sugar content, so I wouldn’t order that either. So again, what’s left?

Well, as the cartoon pig says,“That’s all folks!”Subway may be fresh, but they don’t offer very much menu diversity for an Eat to Liver. The Veggie Delite is really your only option, provided you can get over the bread concession. Oh, and this worth mentioning. If the bread concession really aggravates you, you can ditch it all together and just order The Veggie Delite as a salad. And once you omit or limit the salad dressing, you’re in decent shape. Think of it this way, if you HAD to eat at Subway at least it’s not completely hopeless.

And remember, if you’ve got an interesting Eating to Live on the Outside story we’d love to hear from you. Hey, we might even make a post out of it. Check out Subway’s menu and email us at diseaseproof@gmail.com .
 Tags: Eating to Live on the Outside Trackbacks (0) Links to blogs that reference this article Trackback URL 
 Comments (5) Read through and enter the discussion with the form at the end Keith - April 20, 2007 11:57 PM 
Don&apos;t forget to have them replace the lettuce with baby spinach. This has been one of my vegetarian fast food staples for years.
 Joe Fitzpatrick - April 21, 2007 5:37 AM 
Subways in BC stock &apos;Garden Patties&apos; which are supposedly vegetarian but they aren&apos;t on the official menu
 Mason Cooper - April 21, 2007 1:15 PM 
I&apos;m not sure about in other states but in AZ they offer spinach and cucumbers also. The spinach is a much better choice than iceberg.
 Louise - April 24, 2007 2:25 PM 
Hi! Subway breads don&apos;t contain partially-hydrogenated oils - impressive! Gerald, you&apos;re right about the Fruizle - it lists high-fructose corn syrup first after water! Here is where I found the info:
 http://subway.com/subwayroot/MenuNutrition/Nutrition/frmUSIngredients.aspx 

The Veggie Delight would suffice in a pinch, with the addition of spinach - thanx for the posts from Kieth, Joe, and Mason!
 Kyle Key - April 25, 2007 12:06 AM 
Whether it&apos;s called &quot;white&quot; or &quot;wheat,&quot; it&apos;s still refined wheat--one&apos;s just brown. I&apos;ve yet to see a fast food restaurant that has real WHOLE wheat bread; when they do have one, they almost always mean &apos;MADE WITH whole wheat,&apos; which should really be called half and half bread.
 Post A Comment / Question Use this form to add a comment to this entry. Name: 
 
 Email Address: 
 
 URL: (optional) 
 
 Comments: 
 Remember personal info? Yes No Send To A Friend Use this form to send this entry to a friend via email. Email this entry to: 
 

 Your email address: 
 Message: (optional) 
 Categories 
 ADHD Acne Allergies Alzheimer&apos;s Disease Arthritis Asthma Autoimmune Diseases Blood Pressure Cancer 
 Breast Cancer Colon Cancer Lung Cancer Lymphoma Prostate Cancer 
 Cardiovascular Disease Children Cholesterol Cold&amp;Flu Debunking Diet Myths 
 Diet Pills Low Carb / High Protein Portion Control Weight Loss Surgery 
 Depression Diabetes Digestive Health Ear Infections Emily Boller Events Exercise Eye health Food Safety Funny things Green Living Healthcare Healthy Food Healthy Parenting Healthy Pregnancy Holiday Challenge Hurtful Food Interviews&amp;Features 
 Cheap Fruits&amp;Veggies Dr. Fuhrman in the News Eating to Live on the Outside Guest Posts Inspiration 
 Lupus Migraine Headaches News Nutritional Research Project Obesity Osteoarthritis Osteoporosis Podcasts Psoriasis Recipes Research School Food Stress Stroke Success Stories Supplements Toxins Travel Vitamins&amp;Supplements Weight Loss 
 Archives Updates DrFuhrman.com 

 Awards/Recognition Links 
 VeggieGirl Pursue a Healthy You Yummy Plants Healthy Girl&apos;s Kitchen Dr. Fuhrman&apos;s Health Getaways Whole Food Mommies Jana/ Dr. Joel -- Blogging Julie/ Julia Style ParentDish Compassionate Cooks The China Study Nutrient Rich Well Blog Healthy Child Healthy World Slashfood Allies Voice Diet Blog Freakonomics Blog Julie&apos;s Health Club We Like It Raw Aetiology UroStream The Veg Blog Organic Authority AtkinsExposed.org TuDiabetes Lean Plate Club Diet Girl! The Cancer Project Physicians Committee for Responsible Medicine GreenDaily Diabetes Mine ENN Poked&amp;Prodded AllergyKids Environmental Defense Fund That&apos;sFit Wellsphere Health and Men Serious Eats Crazy Sexy Life Ecorazzi HealthDay Peer Trainer Blog Mad Cowboy TreeHugger Vegan Lunch Box DrFuhrman.com 
 Archives 
 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 June 2007 May 2007 April 2007 March 2007 February 2007 January 2007 December 2006 November 2006 October 2006 September 2006 August 2006 July 2006 June 2006 May 2006 April 2006 March 2006 February 2006 January 2006 December 2005 November 2005 October 2005 September 2005 August 2005 
   Disease Proof 
 Dr. Fuhrman&apos;s Executive Offices 4 Walter E. Foran Blvd.
Suite 408 Flemington , NJ 08822 
 Privacy Policy Disclaimer 
 LexBlog Lawyer Blogs and Law Firm Blog Design Copyright©2012, DrFuhrman Online. All Rights Reserved. Nutrition&amp;health news at Disease Proof from Dr. Joel Fuhrman, offering commentary&amp;analysis on cancer, cardiovascular disease, healthy and unhealthy foods, depression, healthy parenting, obesity and other health-related issues.
	</body>
</document>
