<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000993" url="http://www.coolstuffinc.com/main_cardGamesNonCCG.php?viewType=Steve%20Jackson%20Games&amp;info1=Card%20Games&amp;info2=Steve%20Jackson%20Games" time="2012-07-12-16:22" support="1" score="0.0004455895590515311" bingtitle="Steve Jackson Games - Card Games at CoolStuffInc.com" webtitle="Steve Jackson Games - Card Games  at CoolStuffInc.com">
			<query id="000812" bing-rank="199"/>
	<description>Plus a card to go with each pawn, to make it ... You think working in a fast-food restaurant is hell? This place is worse. ... everyone else is between you and the exit! ...</description>
	<body>
		Magic the Gathering Cards     World of Warcraft TCG     VS System     Pokemon     Yu-Gi-Oh!     CardFight Vanguard 

 
 
 Advanced 
 
 Login 
 
        My Cart 

   
 0 Items in my cart.

 
   
      
 

 Magic the Gathering 
   Cards    Box    Pack    Set 
   Special Offers 
   Deck Builder 
   Return to Ravnica 
   Magic 2013 
   Avacyn Restored 
   Dark Ascension 
   Innistrad 
   New Phyrexia 
   Mirrodin Besieged 
   Scars of Mirrodin 

 Board Games 
   Apples to Apples 
   Dominion 
   Axis and Allies 
   The Settlers of Catan 
   Heroscape 
   And many many more! 

 Yu-Gi-Oh! 
   Gold Series Haunted Mine 
   Galactic Overlord 
   Promo 

 CardFight! Vanguard 

 Miniatures 
   Pathfinder Battles 
   Dungeons and Dragons 
   Heroclix 
   Star Wars 

 World of Warcraft 
   WoW TCG Loot Cards 

 Universal Fighting System 

 Legend of the Five Rings 

 RPGs 
   Wizards of the Coast 
   Paizo 

 Supplies 
   Card Sleeves 
   Deck Boxes 
   Card Storage 
   Dice 
   Life Counters 
   Glass Stones 

 Pokemon 

 Other CCGs 
 

 Buy List Gift Certificate Orlando Store South Florida Store   Customer Rewards Shipping Costs Payment Options Pre-Order Policy Grading Policy Privacy Policy Contact Us About Us Jobs   Disc Golf Center 
 
 
 Main  &gt; Non Collectible Card Games 
   

 
 
   

 
 
      Steve Jackson Games 
 
 

 
 
 Wicked Munchkin Bag&amp;Die       more info 

Go down in the dungeon. Kill everything you meet. Backstab your friends and steal their stuff. Grab the treasure and run. Admit it. You love it. And now you can also ROLL SOME WICKED DICE ! 
  Out of Stock   $8.99


 Email me when
back in stock Wicked Munchkin Die       more info 

Go down into the dungeon. Kill everything you meet. Backstab your friends and steal their stuff. Grab the treasure and run. Admit it. You love it. And now you can also... roll some wicked dice!
Crafted for the worldwide acclaimed Munchkin game series from Steve Jackson Games -- this is something...    Read More 
  3 in Stock    $4.99
New  

 Munchkin Deluxe       more info 

What makes this edition &quot;deluxe&quot;? It&apos;s got a big gameboard to keep your cards in place, and six colored pawns that you move on the gameboard as you level up! Plus a card to go with each pawn, to make it easy to remember who is what color and whose sex has changed!

Go down in the dungeon. Kill...    Read More 
  17 in Stock    $19.49
New  

 Cthulhu Plush Dice Bag       more info 

When Cthulhu eats your sanity, you&apos;re in trouble. But when he eats your dice, he&apos;ll give them back.

The Cthulhu Dice Bag is soft plush, with far more eyes, tentacles, and wings than any ordinary dice bag. He&apos;ll hold dozens of ordinary six-siders or non-Euclidean polyhedrons in his zippered po...    Read More 
  2 in Stock    $19.99
New  

 Cthulhu Plush Tentacle       more info 

It&apos;s a 30&quot; long plush posable tentacle. Why did we do it? Because Evil Stevie likes tentacles. And this one is soft, and furry.

Make it a fashion statement, poking out of your shirt. Use the loop in back to hang it from your belt. Put it in your next haunted house . . . or in your cubicle! Th...    Read More 
  2 in Stock    $16.99
New  

 Munchkin       more info 

Go down in the dungeon. Kill everything you meet. Backstab your friends and steal their stuff. Grab the treasure and run.
Admit it. You love it.
Munchkin is the mega-hit card game about dungeon adventure . . . with none of that stupid roleplaying stuff. You and your friends compete to kill mon...    Read More 

 22nd Printing 20+ in Stock    $14.99
New  

 Munchkin +6 Bag O Munchkin Level Counters       more info 

The newest +6 Bag Munchkin game accessory is here!

The +6 Bag o Munchkin Level Counters gives players attractive, easy-to-read level counter dials themed to match six of the most popular Munchkin core sets. 
  7 in Stock    $6.99
New  

 Munchkin +6 Bag O Munchkin Level Counters Set 2       more info 
 
  20+ in Stock    $6.99
New  

 Munchkin +6 Bag of Munchkin Rainbow D6       more info 

This is a set of six 6-sided dice that match the pawns from the +6 Bag o Munchkins and the +6 Bag o Munchkin Babes. The Munchkin head replaces the 1 face on the dice 
  7 in Stock    $3.49
New  

 Munchkin 2: Unnatural Axe       more info 

112 more cards for the game of killing monsters and taking their stuff. Play a new race: Orcs! Face foes like the Hydrant and the Tentacle Demon. Equip yourself with dread armor like the Spiked Codpiece. Recruit allies like the Shoulder Dragon. Wield mighty weapons like Druid Fluid, the Catapult and...    Read More 
  20+ in Stock    $12.99
New  

 Munchkin 3: Clerical Errors       more info 

Another 112 cards for the best-selling game of killing monsters and taking their stuff. Play a new race: Gnomes! Try on the Bard class. Face the Tequila Mockingbird, the Bad Ass, and the dreaded Auntie Paladin! Equip yourself with amazing items like the Chainmail Bikini and the Stab-A-Matic . . . an...    Read More 
  20 in Stock    $12.99
New  

 Munchkin 4: The Need for Steed       more info 

Munchkin 4: The Need for Steed is the latest expansion for the original Munchkin - 112 more John Kovalic-illustrated cards for killing monsters, stealing treasure, and backstabbing your fellow players. This set introduces Steeds, the trusty mounts of legend . . . Oh, wait - this is Munchkin! So thes...    Read More 
  17 in Stock    $12.99
New  

 Munchkin 5: De-ranged       more info 

More of the twisted humor of Steve Jackson and John Kovalic in a 112-card supplement for Munchkin!

Introducing a new class... the Ranger! These munchkins are skilled animal handlers, rescuing Steeds from the discard pile. And with their knowledge of nature (and the creatures that infest it),...    Read More 
  19 in Stock    $12.99
New  

 Munchkin 6: Demented Dungeons       more info 

Munchkin is about kicking down Doors, killing Monsters, and stealing their Treasure. But where are the dank walls of the subterranean labyrinth where our heroes engage in their murderous exploits?

Demented Dungeons introduces a new twist on Munchkin. Now you can enter the Dungeon of Elvish Ex...    Read More 
  17 in Stock    $7.49
New  

 Munchkin 7: Cheat With Both Hands       more info 

Stir Things Up!

Admit it. You really like to combine all your Munchkin sets . . . the stupider things get, the better. Playing Star Munchkin Cthulhu Booty Zombies is really weird and really fun . . . but it can also slow things down.

There are a lot of ways we COULD have addressed this...    Read More 
  19 in Stock    $12.99
New  

 Munchkin 8: Half Horse, Will Travel       more info 

Our fans have been asking for new Races, and were giving them TWO in this set: Centaurs and Lizard Guys! Plus new Race and Class Enhancers: you can be Elite, Legendary, or Elder! Go for all three . . . youll need all the help you can get when you fight That Gecko On The Telly, the horrifying Centa...    Read More 
  20+ in Stock    $12.99
New  

 Munchkin Bites       more info 

 Revised Full Color Edition 

It&apos;s the World of Dorkness!

The Munchkins are now vampires . . . and werewolves . . . and changelings. Bash through the haunted house and slay the monsters. The OTHER monsters. You can&apos;t slay your fellow munchkins, but you can curse them, send foes at...    Read More 
  5 in Stock    $16.49
New  

 Munchkin Bites 2 Pants Macabre       more info 

Aieee! 110 more angsty and overpowered cards (plus two blanks) for Munchkin Bites! Can you face the sonic stylings of Ten Inch Tacks, the face the sonic stylings of Ten Inch Tacks, the annoyance of the Gnat Bats, and the chilling waddle of the Were-Penguin? Will you wield the might of Power Piercing...    Read More 
  5 in Stock    $12.99
New  

 Munchkin Booty       more info 

Munchkin Booty brings the greatest gold-grabbers in history pirates! to the world of Munchkin. Use your Silver Long Johns to beat the Lobster Mobster, drink your Demon Rum to fight off the Viking Kittens, and defend yourself with the Cutlass (or Cutlad, for the gents) against the Prince of Whale...    Read More 
  6 in Stock    $16.49
New  

 Munchkin Booty 2: Jump the Shark       more info 

Jump the Shark . . . or you&apos;re fish food!

Return to the high seas for more Munchkin Booty action. Fight the Hammerhead Shark -- and the Phillips-Head Shark, too. And greatest of all is the terrible Moby Duck!

So kill them and take their stuff.

On the munchkin side, there are lot...    Read More 
  4 in Stock    $12.99
New  

 Munchkin Booty: Fish&amp;Ships       more info 

Avast ye! Fish&amp;Ships be full of Sharks (and other denizens of th&apos; deep) and Ships for yer Munchkin Booty game!
We gots here Fish rangin&apos; from yer pathetic Fish in a Barrel to yer munchkin-mangling Tiger Shark. We gots six new Ships, and all of them be good and most of them be really dumb. We th...    Read More 
  8 in Stock    $3.49
New  

 Munchkin Chibithuhlu Plush - Orange       more info 

This 10&quot;-tall soft and huggable plush figure features huge, adorable eyes, a loving heart on the chest . . . and Cthulhu&apos;s trademark tentacles. It&apos;s made of all-new materials, and is machine washable.
Of course, this toy includes a special rule, which will help you during Munchkin Cthulhu games.&lt;...    Read More 
  1 in Stock    $12.99
New  

 Munchkin Chibithulhu Plush - Green       more info 

This 10&quot;-tall soft and huggable plush figure features huge, adorable eyes, a loving heart on the chest . . . and Cthulhu&apos;s trademark tentacles. It&apos;s made of all-new materials, and is machine washable.
Of course, this toy includes a special rule, which will help you during Munchkin Cthulhu games.&lt;...    Read More 
  2 in Stock    $12.99
New  

 Munchkin Chibithulhu Plush - Zombie Chibithulhu       more info 

This 10&quot;-tall soft and huggable plush figure features huge, adorable eyes, a brain on the chest . . . and Cthulhu&apos;s trademark tentacles. It&apos;s made of all-new materials, and is machine washable.
Of course, this toy includes a special rule, which will help you during Munchkin Cthulhu games.

...    Read More 
  3 in Stock    $15.49
New  

 Munchkin Cthulhu       more info 

Munchkins have hacked their way through dungeons, kung fu temples, starships, haunted houses, and super-foes. Now they face their greatest challenge Cthulhu! Will they survive? Will they retain their sanity? Will they . . . level up?

Munchkin Cthulhu is a stand-alone game that lampoons Love...    Read More 
  8 in Stock    $16.49
New  

 Munchkin Cthulhu 2: Call of Cowthulhu       more info 

Munchkin Cthulhu 2: Call of Cowthulhu puts the Great Old Ones out to pasture, Munchkin-style! In this 56-card supplement you&apos;ll find:

* More monsters! Hog-Sothoth, the Sheep Ones, Shoggoats - even Cowthulhu itself!
* More whackers! Squish unnatural creatures with the Rolling Pin, chop th...    Read More 
  10 in Stock    $7.49
New  

 Munchkin Cthulhu 3: The Unspeakable Vault       more info 

For years, Goomi has been unleashing his own vision of Cthulhu upon the world, in his comic &apos;&apos;The Unspeakable Vault (of Doom)!&apos;&apos; Now his unique take on the Elder Gods comes to Munchkin, in the form of Munchkin Cthulhu 3: The Unspeakable Vault.

This 56-card expansion brings Great Cthulhoo, Dag...    Read More 
  7 in Stock    $7.49
New  

 Munchkin Cthulhu 4: Crazed Caverns       more info 

Subterranean Secrets!

The hunt for forbidden knowledge goes underground! Explore the Midden of the Mi-Go! Dig yourself out of the Dunwich Ditch! Brave the blue light of K&apos;n-Yan! Maybe all at once . . .

Munchkin Cthulhu has already driven you mad, and now it&apos;s even madder! The 16 Portal...    Read More 
  3 in Stock    $7.49
New  

 Munchkin Cthulhu Kill-O-Meter       more info 

Munchkin fans love crazy things, the crazier the better . . . like a Munchkin Cthulhu game when the cards start flying and ichors, monster enhancers, and other bonuses keep the levels bouncing up and down! Now you&apos;ll never have to stop and recount again!

With the Munchkin Cthulhu Kill-O-Meter...    Read More 
  11 in Stock    $4.49
New  

 Munchkin Cthulhu: Crypts of Concealment       more info 

The eldritch secrets of Munchkin Cthulhu deserve a special hiding place! The Munchkin Cthulhu Crypts of Concealment are sturdy cardboard, sized to hold 500 Munchkin cards apiece! One is labeled Doors, and one is for Treasures.

Bonus: Two new Munchkin Cthulhu cards that are unique to this set! 
  4 in Stock    $6.79
New  

 Munchkin Dice Bag       more info 

Be the envy of your friends with the Munchkin Dice Bag, an awesome item with an awesome bonus. Fill it with official Munchkin six-sided dice and watch your friends groan in frustration as your Munchkin-head results turn failure into success. And it comes with two new Munchkin cards, Blind Chance and...    Read More 
  6 in Stock    $6.49
New  

 Munchkin Fairy Dust       more info 

Meet the Sparkly Good Fairy. She wants all the munchkins to play nice, and she&apos;s willing to bash heads to make sure they do. Play her way, and she&apos;ll bribe you with Fairy Dust. Otherwise, you might end up fighting her instead. And if you don&apos;t take her out, she&apos;ll be back again and again . . .
	</body>
</document>
