<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000893" url="http://www.answerbag.com/q_view/1419536" time="2012-07-12-16:15" support="2" score="0.0032375096367780586" bingtitle="Why do people look down on people who work in fast food/ minimum ..." webtitle="Why do people look down on people who work in fast food/ minimum wage jobs? | Answerbag">
			<query id="001035" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="001444" bing-rank="188"/>
	<description>Not everyone has the money to pay for college ... and i respect them so they dont spit in my food. ... Fast food restaurant management looked down on</description>
	<body>
		Ask a Question or Create a Poll 
 Home Categories Questions Forums Blog NEW! 
 
 Arts Autos&amp;Motorcycles Business Computers Diet&amp;Fitness Education Electronics Entertainment Environmentalism Fashion&amp;Beauty Finance Food&amp;Dining Games Health Hobbies Home&amp;Garden Kids Legal Life&amp;Society Pets&amp;Pet Care Real Estate Recreation&amp;Sports Relationship Advice Religion Science Social Sciences Transportation Travel&amp;Places Answerbag Outside the Bag 
 
 Home / Questions / Business / Job Hunting And Career Planning / Careers / Restaurant Careers And Jobs 
 
by broken_beauty17 on April 22nd, 2009
 
Question

Help answer this question below.
 
Why do people look down on people who work in fast food/
minimum wage jobs?
 Share your answer here... Want to attach an image to your answer? Click here. 
 
Only upload an image if you have the rights to it,
and ensure that it complies with our terms of use .
 
 Like Report 
 Share: Facebook Twitter Other Sort answers by: Greatness / Likes Date submitted 
Answers. 19 helpful answers below. 
 
 
by The Chief on April 22nd, 2009
 
 If you know how to fry up the french fries for juuuuuust the right amount of time, then pull them out and salt them IMMEDIATELY so the salt will actually STICK to the fries, and then serve them PIPING HOT...

Then as far as I&apos;m concerned YOU RULE!

Properly prepared french fries are their OWN food group and their importance to humanity cannot POSSIBLY be overstated!

At least not to THIS part of humanity, anyway.

:) 
 
Comments

 
So passionate

 Report 
 
by Kallous on April 22nd, 2009
 
Hey, we&apos;re talking about the french fry, here! Of COURSE I&apos;m passionate!
.
:):)

 Report 
 
by The Chief on April 22nd, 2009
 
I want fries now!

 Report 
 
by Saturnalia on April 22nd, 2009
 
I&apos;m ready to storm a fast food restaurant right now!

 Report 
 
by The Chief on April 22nd, 2009
 
If you do, bring me back something :)

 Report 
 
by Saturnalia on April 22nd, 2009
 
You bet!

 Report 
 
by The Chief on April 22nd, 2009
 
that was awesome :D

 Report 
 
by broken_beauty17 on April 29th, 2009
 
Thanks, broken_beauty17.
.
Good french friers just don&apos;t get paid enough money, in my opinion.
.
:):)

 Report 
 
by The Chief on April 30th, 2009
 
what about curly fries?

 Report 
 
by broken_beauty17 on April 30th, 2009
 
They&apos;re fires, right?
.
Ummmmmmmm....Arby&apos;s curly fries with cheese sauce!

 Report 
 
by The Chief on April 30th, 2009
 
Oops...&quot;fires&quot;=&quot;fries&quot;. My bad!

 Report 
 
by The Chief on May 1st, 2009
 
do the fries make the ketchup or does the ketchup make the fries?? lol

 Report 
 
by broken_beauty17 on May 2nd, 2009
 
Fries are merely a means to move the ketchup from the plate to the mouth...
.
Unless they&apos;re REALLY good fries, then they are merely the means to move the salt to the mouth...

 Report 
 
by The Chief on May 3rd, 2009
 
lol so the fries make the ketchup?

 Report 
 
by broken_beauty17 on May 3rd, 2009
 
Yep!

 Report 
 
by The Chief on May 3rd, 2009
 
i would have to agree

 Report 
 
by broken_beauty17 on May 3rd, 2009
 
but what about fry sauce?

 Report 
 
by broken_beauty17 on May 3rd, 2009
 
Fry sauce?

 Report 
 
by The Chief on May 4th, 2009
 
Well, I&apos;ve looked up fry sauce...Ima gonna have to try it!
.
My wife is a HUGE fan of mayo on her frys, and I have to admit it isn&apos;t bad. So fry sauce ought to be pretty darned good!

 Report 
 
by The Chief on May 6th, 2009
 
yea it doesnt really taste like mayo though

 Report 
 
by broken_beauty17 on May 9th, 2009
 
I should think the ketchup would provide the majority of the flavor, with the mayo providing the more subtle aspects.

 Report 
 
by The Chief on May 11th, 2009
 
it depends if the person who makes it puts in more ketchup or more mayo, but i would have to agree i dont think mayo on fries sounds very good, but then again i hate mayo

 Report 
 
by broken_beauty17 on May 11th, 2009
 
I think the original called for 2/3 ketchup and 1/3 mayo.

 Report 
 
by The Chief on May 11th, 2009
 
lol that makes sense

 Report 
 
by broken_beauty17 on May 11th, 2009
 
:):)

 Report 
 
by The Chief on May 11th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 25 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Doogie on April 22nd, 2009
 
 I don&apos;t think they should cause a lot of us started out that way. 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by Carl_07 on April 22nd, 2009
 
 Some people just think that they are better than the other. 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by Simply99 -- Not a fan favorite. on April 22nd, 2009
 
 I&apos;m just wondering how they got that ability to know someone elses wages just by looking at them. Fast food is a great way to start your career. Personally, I never judge anyone by the wages they make usually because I have no idea how much they make (and it&apos;s none of my business), but will judge by the quality of work and work ethic while performing said job, regardless of the wages. Work hard, make as much as you could, and hope to be rewarded -- not penalized -- for daring to try to make a good living doing whatever it is you choose to do. 
 
Comments

 
Great answer!!

My Granny always told she didn&apos;t care what i&apos;d end up doing as long as i worked hard and enjoyed it.

 Report 
 
by Saturnalia on April 22nd, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by DudeLer 2 on April 22nd, 2009
 
 I work a minimum wage job. no one has looked down on me. I like my job. I have fun doing it. I think it has to do with one&apos;s attitude. That is what people see. That is why they think the person could do better doing something else. 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by nutmegcollector on April 22nd, 2009
 
 You don&apos;t get much money and don&apos;t need much skill. 
 
Comments

 
So life is all about money to them in other words.

 Report 
 
by broken_beauty17 on April 22nd, 2009
 
Unfortunately man needs money to eat, to shelter and to cloth oneself. Unless these 3 basic needs are satisfied, one can&apos;t move beyond life&apos;s other fulfillments. +4

 Report 
 
by nutmegcollector on April 22nd, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 2 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by bandit lets go jets on April 22nd, 2009
 
 if you are under 21 its ok if you are 35 and you were born in the u.s.a. W.T.F 
 
Comments

 
I don&apos;t understand the 21 35 thing?

 Report 
 
by broken_beauty17 on April 22nd, 2009
 
Try to get an education before going to Taco bell is that what you mean, sense we are in one of the Riches Nations in the world?

 Report 
 
by Kallous on April 22nd, 2009
 
So your saying that they should have tried to better themselves by the time they are 35?

 Report 
 
by broken_beauty17 on April 23rd, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 3 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by -NUNYA-- on April 22nd, 2009
 
 NO WAY! I have just as much respect for them then a lawyer, doctor or any other higher paying job. They work hard and are only trying to make ends meet like everyone else. +5 
 
Comments

 
If they respect the work they do I can see it also, but if they don&apos;t its written all over there face generally. Fake it until you make it

 Report 
 
by Kallous on April 22nd, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Aphrodite loves Mentos on April 22nd, 2009
 
 I don&apos;t look down on people who work in fast food. And most fast food employees make more than minimum wage. I do, however, become irritated if an employee in any service industry acts as if their job is sub standard. By that I mean they have no sense of urgency, are rude, or have overall poor customer service. That&apos;s frustrating. Plus, working fast food or minimum wage jobs beats not having a job at all. Sometimes you gotta do what you gotta do to make ends meet. 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by XOXMSperfect on April 22nd, 2009
 
 Personally, i dont look down on people who work in fast food. I worked at taco bell for 2 months, and ill tell you it&apos;s not the funnest job in the world, but alot of times people have to take whatever job they can. Not everyone has the money to pay for college, and the way things are now, jobs are dissapearing. I say a fast food job is better than nothing. 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by Saturnalia on April 22nd, 2009
 
 I imagine a whole number of reasons, ignorance, lack of understanding, fear.

For some working for minimum was never an option as they could have been born into a privileged household.

I for one have grown up working minimum wage jobs, its the reason i was able to move out of my home, attend university and get a degree. Im still in University doing my masters and working part-time, it pays the rent and the bills.

I look at family members who have worked minumum wage jobs all their lives to provide for their families,put kids through school,enjoy life and i am proud and grateful to them.

I see some of my friends who grew up not having to work or even still receiving handouts from their parents while studying and not even looking for a job.
The idea of a minumum wage job repulses them.
Complete ignorance.

If they worked a minimum wage job they would propbably appreciate what they had a bit more.

I hate to say it but in this current economic climate we will see people choosing jobs that before they wouldnt have even considered. 
 
Comments

 
Just an afterthought, i&apos;d rather get by and have a great sense of job satisfaction rather than earn a great salary and be miserable in the process.

 Report 
 
by Saturnalia on April 22nd, 2009
 
Awesome response

 Report 
 
by Kallous on April 22nd, 2009
 
Thanks :)

 Report 
 
by Saturnalia on April 22nd, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 3 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by RosieGHM Jetpacker on April 23rd, 2009
 
 &quot;Some&quot;people..not all people. Those who&quot;look down on&quot;others for their socio-economic status, ethnic background, religious/political beliefs or anything else do it to make themselves feel&quot;better&quot;,&quot;superior&quot;. They don&apos;t have the&quot;right stuff&quot;themselves and they are desperate to feel good about themselves so their only solution is to puff themselves up and look down on others..for whatever reason..it never makes any difference to them..such people will always find something because that is what drives them. Sad. Happy Thursday! :) 
 
Comments

 
wow thanks!

 Report 
 
by broken_beauty17 on April 23rd, 2009
 
You&apos;re welcome. Any honest job that one does to the best of his/her ability should be honored, not dissed. :)

 Report 
 
by RosieGHM Jetpacker on April 23rd, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 2 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Kallous on April 22nd, 2009
 
 We don&apos;t look down at them, because we generally have to look up at them to give them our money :P 
 
Comments

 
I give everyone the same about of respect, and joke about them like an equal :P

 Report 
 
by Kallous on April 22nd, 2009
 
hey i didnt don rate you for that, i put you back up to zero :P

 Report 
 
by broken_beauty17 on April 29th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 2 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Old School on April 22nd, 2009
 
 Perhaps that comes more easily than thinking&quot;There but for the Grace of God go I...&quot;...:-P...
.
.
 http://www.amazon.com/Fooled-Randomness-Hidden-Chance-Markets/dp/1400067936/ 
 
Comments

 
Wow! That&apos;s about the biggest DR I&apos;ve ever had!
.
And I thought my answer was fairly innocuous...:-?...

 Report 
 
by Old School on April 22nd, 2009
 
OS...many fabulously successful people got their start at a fast-food joint. It teaches one many things, not the least of which is the ability to multi-task, not screw things up, get along with their co-workers, please the boss and satisfy the customer. This is not an easy thing. Add to that the fast-pace, the tiring aspects of such a job and on top of it all one is expected to have a happy outlook, pleasant demeanor and never complain. Those who sell such jobs short don&apos;t have a clue about the positive aspects of working successfully in that environment..yes, they are clueless! Happy Thursday! :) ((hugs))I gave you my top +6. Hope someone else with common sense will come along and do likewise!

 Report 
 
by RosieGHM Jetpacker on April 23rd, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 2 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Mr. Bean is a superhero on April 22nd, 2009
 
 lower income? 
 
Comments

 
I think it&apos;s more like some people are so arrogant, rude, spoiled, small-minded, and need to be shown that their not better than any one else.peace.lol

 Report 
 
by broken_beauty17 on April 22nd, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Capital J on April 22nd, 2009
 
 i dont look down on these people. these punk kids and loser adults cook my food at least 5 out of 7 days a week. anyone could do it. but who would want to. i would never do their job but someone has to do it. and i respect them so they dont spit in my food. 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by Mud on May 1st, 2009
 
 because your income determines your worth in a monopolistic world. truth, get some. 
 
Comments

 
fuck the monopolistic world!!

 Report 
 
by broken_beauty17 on May 2nd, 2009
 
audit the fed, and the world will realize what theyve been supporting by silently slaving away for generations. do it not and nothing changes. I want to feel like the life i am living is more benifit than satifying some one elses greed. until then I contmeplate life, while living suicide.

 Report 
 
by Mud on May 6th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 2 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Teresa on May 6th, 2009
 
 Because our economy depends upon the stigmatizing of the lower classes so that the higher classes can sleep at night. 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by 08Busa on May 6th, 2009
 
 I do because the people I see working there don&apos;t care enough to apply themselves and get an education that will help them in their quest in life. They have no respect for others or themselves. 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
 Share your answer... Want to attach an image to your answer? Click here. 
 
Only upload an image if you have the rights to it,
and ensure that it complies with our terms of use .
 
Did this answer your question? If not, then ask a new question or create a poll . 
 
More Questions. Additional questions in this category. 

 
 I am jealous of people who&apos;s job is ____________. 
by Carpe Diem on December 12th, 2011
 
 | 3 people like this
 
 what tree planting company in the US or Canada hires rookie foreign treeplanters?if their is can you gave me info on how to contact them. 
by axerland665 on November 23rd, 2011
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 What is a good night time job for a female college studentt? I&apos;ve been applying to hospitals but no luck yet. No bartending or dancing. 
by Anon522 on May 19th, 2011
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 What can of jobs can a 17 year old do or will be hired? 
by Mr.Bean Mime on July 1st, 2011
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 Did anyone participate in the National Hiring Day for McDonalds? 
by KayyB94 on April 19th, 2011
 
 | 1 person likes this
 More Restaurant Careers and Jobs See only professionally researched Restaurant Careers and Jobs questions 
 
You&apos;re reading Why do people look down on people who work in fast food/ minimum wage jobs?
 
Follow us on Facebook!
 
Related Ads
 
Related Questions

 
 What kind of blue-collar work (Non-fast food and customer service minimum wage jobs) is available in this day and age to high school dropouts? 
 
 Should the government try to reserve jobs for low experience/ low education workers? Why or why not? And are there any ways to help get jobs for teens coming out of highschool, even though so many people are applying for minimum wage jobs? 
 
 How old do you have to be to work a fast food places? Which ones? 
 
 What is the minimum wage for Manhattan, KS? 
 
 I can hire people overseas for $1.50-2.00 per hour. (US minimum wage doesn&apos;t apply, of course). These people speak English, and can do Internet-based work. What can I have them do to earn more than $2/hour? Ideas? Thoughts? Work together? 
 
 
Professionally Researched
 
 
 What percentage of people earn minimum wage? 
 
 Does minimum wage apply to part-time people? 
 
 How much of the work force receives minimum wage? 
 
 What year did the federal minimum wage go into effect&amp;how;much was the minimum wage? 
 
 How many people eat at fast food chains per day? 
 
 
ANSWERBAG BUZZ
 Why do people look down on food service Why do people work fast food Why do some people look down on other people What do people think about their fast food jobs Fast food restaurant management looked down on 
 About Us About Answerbag Sitemap Professionally Researched Questions   Legal Privacy Policy Terms of Use Disclaimer Ad Choices   Follow Us on Facebook 
 Answerbag.com 
Your favorite Q&amp;A site is on Facebook! Become a fan to connect with the ever-growing community of Answerbaggers, share your thoughts and find out what Answerbag&apos;s up to next!

 Latest Tweet 
 Follow Answerbag on Twitter! 
 
 
Answerbag

 AB4Adults Answerbag UK
	</body>
</document>
