<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000974" url="http://www.9kracing.com/shooting-outside-the-carls-jr-in-monterey-park-ca/" time="2012-07-12-16:21" support="1" score="0.0010726946358028025" bingtitle="Shooting Outside The Carl’s Jr In Monterey Park, CA. | 9K Racing" webtitle="Shooting Outside The Carls Jr In Monterey Park, CA. | 9K Racing">
			<query id="000713" bing-rank="220"/>
	<description>“Monterey Park police shot and killed a man outside the Carls Jr. fast food restaurant near East Los Angeles College ... kate upton kim jong mazda nissan r34 Race race car rx7 ...</description>
	<body>
		This text will be replaced All or Nothing since &apos;89 
 LOG IN 
 Shopping
Cart 0 SHOP Search 
 Home News 
 Funny Sports Life Gadgets 
 Babes Freebies 
 Wallpapers Sticker Slap 
 Music Contact 
 
Post navigation
 ← Previous Next → 
Shooting Outside The Carl’s Jr In Monterey Park, CA.
 Spread the Awesome Posted by 9kracing on January 24, 2012 VN:F [1.9.11_1134] 3 1 
 

 

“Monterey Park police shot and killed a man outside the Carls Jr. fast food restaurant near East Los Angeles College Monday morning. Four police officers responded to a call at 9:30 am reporting that an adult male was breaking windows at the fast food restauranton Cesar Chavez Avenue. When police arrived, several patrons ran out of the restaurant, followed by a man brandishing a three foot long lead pipe, according to the Monterey Park Police and the Sheriff’s Department.The man did not listen when officers ordered him several times to drop the pipe, and an attempt to taser him produced no effect, say authorities. The man then approached one of the police officers, swinging the lead pipe twice at him. He was subsequently shot by another police officer, who was “fearing for their safety,” according to a Sheriff’s report. A video posted by a witness on YouTube shows the as-yet unidentified man wielding the lead pipe getting shot eight times by a police officer.”

As many of you know, we are 626 Locals. I have frequented this exact Carl’s Jr several times while living down in that area. You can imagine it is a all too real experience knowing this happened in our community. What do you guys think of this type of situation? It’s pretty shitty all around, but does this justify the use of lethal force? I am not one to point fingers, but my readers can discuss their point of views on the subject in the comment box below.

via Ivy League East 
 
 Tagged ax man carls jr crazy elac epic monterey park mpk shooting Do-Luck R32 Special Best Rap Video Ever Created. Ever. Watch The Chillest Bro Grandpa Ever Heath Frisby Pulls Off Snowmobiling’s First-Ever Frontflip At The 2012 Winter X-Games 
 
9K Racing on Facebook
 
Friends
 Latest Posts Tag Cloud 
 9K Racing x Jimmy Up 4th of July Blackout Party | Car Show Kate Upton Gives You A New Reason To Love America! Swedish Hypercars Are Chill 9K Serious Business. A Day At 9K Racing 
 
 9K Racing x Jimmy Up 4th of July Blackout Party | Car Show Kate Upton Gives You A New Reason To Love America! Swedish Hypercars Are Chill 9K Serious Business. A Day At 9K Racing 
 9K 9K Racing asian ass babe babes best bikini bmw boobs bro carbon fiber college crazy drunk fail fd3s flush funny gtr hellaflush honda hot hot babes hot girls hot import nights hottie import model import models jdm kate upton kim jong mazda nissan party r34 Race race car rx7 sexy skyline stardust tits Track yoga pants 
Friends
 
 Get Involved 
 Contact Us Write for 9K Racing Advertising&amp;Partnerships Send a Tip to the Editors Copyright T&amp;C; 
 Buy online or visit us Monday-Friday 9am-6pm.
 (626) 227-4255 14278 E. Valley Blvd, Unit C
La Puente, CA 91746 USA 9K Racing BUY ONLINE TODAY WITH 100% SECURE PAYMENT TRANSACTIONS
	</body>
</document>
