<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000888" url="http://www.sacsheriff.com/memorial/deffner.cfm" time="2012-07-12-16:14" support="3" score="0.003782532026020459" bingtitle="In the Line of Duty - Richard E. Deffner - Sacramento County ..." webtitle="In the Line of Duty - Richard E. Deffner">
			<query id="001468" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="001462" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000713" bing-rank="95"/>
	<description>Richard E. Deffner - End of Watch: January 21, 1988. The ... On January 20th, a fast food restaurant on Folsom Boulevard had been robbed by a gun ...</description>
	<body>
		Text only   
 Return Home    

 
 Richard 
 E. Deffner - End of Watch: January 21, 1988

The community of Rancho Cordova had experienced 
 several armed robberies in early January. On January 20th, a fast 
 food restaurant on Folsom Boulevard had been robbed by a gun toting 
 suspect. On January 21st. Sergeant Rick Deffner was commanding the 
 elite Special Enforcement. Gold Team in an all day search in an 
 attempt to locate the violent robbery suspect. At approximately 
 2:15 p.m., officers spotted the suspects car and gave chase. The 
 suspect crushed his car into a fence, ran from the vehicle while 
 firing shots at the pursuing officers. He disappeared into the neighborhood. 
 An intensive search began by officers, K-9, and helicopter. An eight-block 
 perimeter was established and a house by house search continued 
 until it was terminated because of darkness. Several hours later 
 a direct confrontation again occurred between the suspect and officers 
 when he was seen hiding in a garage. He again fired at officers 
 and fled to a public storage area near a large apartment complex.

A perimeter was quickly established and the Gold 
 Team was again called and assigned the responsibility to search 
 within the controlled area. Sergeant Deffner realized that if the 
 suspect was on the roof of the apartment complex, he would have 
 a definite advantage over the officers below who where attempting 
 to arrest him. Sergeant Deffner made the decision to search the 
 roof with two of his team members. While on the roof the officers 
 heard noises in a yard below. As Sergeant Deffner peered over the 
 edge of the roof he was shot in the face by the suspect. Sergeant 
 Deffner died that night making the ultimate and final sacrifice 
 for his community and fellow officers.

As the suspect was again trying to escape he was 
 shot and killed by officers. Sergeant Rick Deffner was awarded the 
 Medal of Valor. posthumously. for conspicuous bravery above and 
 beyond the call of duty. The gymnasium at the Sheriff&apos;s Training 
 Academy is dedicated and named for Sergeant Richard E. Deffner. 
 Sergeant Richard Deffner is buried at Mount Vernon Memorial Park 
 on Greenback Lane.

 Return to Memorial 
 


 Return Home ©2012 Sacramento Sheriff&apos;s Department
711 G Street, Sacramento, CA 95814 Privacy
 Policy Conditions of Use Accessibility
 Policy Contact Us
	</body>
</document>
