<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000261" url="http://homeluxuryideas.com/colorful-green-fast-food-design-ideas-wienerwald-restaurant-sweet-tea-restaurant-houston-restaurant-week/" time="2012-07-12-15:27" support="1" score="0.002495358310296739" bingtitle="Colorful Green Fast Food Design Ideas Wienerwald Restaurant ..." webtitle="Colorful Green Fast Food Design Ideas Wienerwald RestaurantHomeLuxuryideas.com">
			<query id="000061" bing-rank="171"/>
	<description>A large, white and compact counter welcomes clients at the entrance, offering food choices on suspended menu ... See all pictures of colorful green fast food restaurant design ...</description>
	<body>
		HomeLuxuryIdeas.com 
 Home Luxury Design,Home Decor&amp;Architecture About Privacy Policy Sitemap Disclaimer Search: 
 Colorful Green Fast Food Design Ideas Wienerwald Restaurant 

August 21st, 2011, Under: Restaurant Luxury Design 
 Advertisement 
 Colorful Green Fast Food Restaurant Design Ideas Wienerwald Restaurant 

Here is fast f ood restaurant with color combination of green, white and brown have transformed this space into a fun and modern restaurant with many great details to take into account. The Wienerwald Restaurant in Munich was designed by German architecture studio Ippolito Fleitz Group and showcases a new brand identity, filled with light, colours and a strong sense of naturalness. Serving fast-food chicken and salads, the Wienerwald restaurant also surprises its visitors with a fresh interior design and bold accents depicting the brand’s strongest points: high quality service, comfort and German cuisine in a contemporary design frame. Wood and leather were used to create a natural setting that was embellished with contemporary graphics and gold intrusions that evoke the crisp skin of its main product, the Wienerwald grilled chicken.

 

A large, white and compact counter welcomes clients at the entrance, offering food choices on suspended menu boards, above the anthracite mosaic stone wall with stainless-steel units for food display. The dining areas are visually delimitated, offering different seating options, from booths to high bar chairs and tables. All around, outlines of trees decorate the walls and mirrors, creating an open, fresh space and a selection of 15 wall plates tell the story of the brand using printed images. See all pictures of colorful green fast food restaurant design ideas wienerwald Restaurant below.
 
Modern Green Fast Food Restaurant Design Ideas Wienerwald
 
Cool Green Fast Food Restaurant Design Ideas Wienerwald
 
Luxury Green Fast Food Restaurant Design Ideas Wienerwald
 
Natural Green Fast Food Restaurant Design Ideas Wienerwald
 
Restaurant Design Ideas Wienerwald Fast Food Plan Design
 
 
 No comments for this entry yet... 
Leave a Reply
 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 

 
 
Populer Design

 Modern Lighting Ideas–La Grelha Restaurant Design in Jalisco Mexico Modern and Elegant Oak Outdoor Furniture Blue Color Design by Scout Regalia 8 Most Popular and Creating Your L-Shape Kitchen Layout Design Ideas Amazing Picturesque Mountain Hotel Was Designed by Jamshyd Sethna Creative Small Yard Garden Design Ideas 
 
Categories
 Select Category Apartment Design Interior Architecture Design Ideas Bar Interior Design Bathroom Design Interior Bathtubs Design Ideas Beach House Luxury Bedroom Unique Design Campus Design Interior Celebrity Home Luxury Chair Design Ideas Children Playground Design Christmas Decorating Ideas Comfortable Home Design Contemporary Home Designs Contemporary Luxury Designs Decorating Ideas Desks Design Ideas Dining Room Design Ideas Doors&amp;Windows Dream House Designs Exterior Home Design Furniture Design Ideas Galleria Modern Interior Garage Design Ideas Garden Design Ideas Green Interiors Packaging Home Luxury Ideas Hotels and Resorts Interior Design Ideas Japanese Interior Design Kids Interior Design Kitchen Design Ideas Lamps Luxury Design Landscape Designs Living Room Luxury Ideas Luxury Dream House Luxury Villas Designs Medical&amp;Garden Ideas Minimalist Home Design Outdoor Design Ideas Palace Interior Designs Penthouse Home Design Restaurant Luxury Design Rug Interior Design Schools&amp;SPA Interior Sofa Design Ideas Studio Luxury Interior Study Rooms&amp;Office Swimming Pool Luxury Swimmingpool Luxury Design Table Design Ideas Theater and Entertainment Tropical Home Luxury Unique Home Design Unusual home designs Villa Trend Designs Wall Stickers Ideas Wallpapers Decorating Ideas Wardrobe Luxury Design Workspace Design Ideas 
©2011 HomeLuxuryIdeas.Com | Theme by Gr8Template .
	</body>
</document>
