<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000605" url="http://www.fishingla.com/local_streams.htm" time="2012-07-12-15:53" support="1" score="0.0006462590431128964" bingtitle="Lake fishing And Local Streams Around Los Angeles, California" webtitle="Lake fishing And Local Streams Around Los Angeles, California">
			<query id="000806" bing-rank="152"/>
	<description>· Take the Santa Anita exit off ... overlooking the golf course, is a neat place to grab a cup of ... convenience store and a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Custom Search 
   
 
 The Big Tujunga Creek    
 
 Big Santa Anita Creek   
 
 Sespe Creek     
 
 Bouquet Canyon Creek    
 
 The San Gabriel River 
 
 East
 Fork of San Gabriel    
 
 West Fork of the San Gabriel 
 
 Piru Creek 
 
 
 
 For a list of Trails check your local book store or library
 for the book, &apos;Trails of the Angeles, 100
 Hikes in the San Gabriel Mountains&apos;, by John W. Robinson. 

 

   

 The Big Tujunga Creek 

          The Big Tujunga offers fishing,
 camping, hunting, target shooting,
 hiking, mountain biking, off- roading, and plain old fashioned Sunday driving. To get to The Big Tujunga, you take the 210 freeway to the community of Sunland. Take the Sunland Blvd off ramp and go north. About a mile or so, you get to
 Oro Vista. There&apos;s a fast food joint and a 7-11 at this intersection. Go left. If you&apos;ve forgotten anything, you might want to get it here.  
       The only place to buy essentials up the
 mountain is Hidden Springs Cafe and General Store. From the 210, (where you
 turned onto Sunland Blvd) it&apos;s 18 miles to the cafe and general store. It&apos;s
 a super little place and it&apos;s owned and run by the Lewis family. You can pick
 up a Wilderness Pass there along with a great bowl of chili.  
       They have the basics: ice, beer, soda,
 canned goods, and some other stuff you might need around the campsite. A lot
 of local history is told in this classic little place.
       Follow Oro Vista Road, and it will become
 (run into) The Big Tujunga Canyon Road. Follow this road and you&apos;ll run along
 side the Big Tujunga Creek. The creek starts on the left side of the road
 and changes sides numerous times the farther up you travel. There are lots
 of places to stop and picnic or fish or whatever.
       The Little Tujunga is included on the
 map. In the Little Tujunga you&apos;ll find The Wildlife Waystation. The
 Waystation saves animals and reintroduces them to the wild and it&apos;s definitely a
 great place to take the kids. Every now and then they need volunteers. For more info on the Waystation please call (818) 899-5201 
       Remember, be safe and please do
 not leave your trash in the mountains 

 Back to top   
 
 Big Santa Anita Creek 
 
 This is a great place
 to visit if youd like a look into the past. There are cabins located along Big
 Santa Anita Creek that go back over a hundred years. Fishing, hiking, camping, and
 even a quickie picnic are what this canyon is all about. 
 
How You Get There 
 
 This canyon is located
 above the community of Arcadia. For reference, Arcadia is found about halfway between
 the communities of Pasadena and Azusa off of Highway 210. 
 
 From Highway 210 
 
 Take the Santa Anita
 exit off Highway 210 and go North. 
 
 Follow Santa Anita
 Avenue six or seven miles up the mountain to the end of the road is Chantry Flats.
 Here youll find plenty of parking, restrooms, and picnic areas with barbeque grills.
 The Chantry Flats Ranger Station is located here also as well as Lonergans Pack
 Station. 
 
 
 
 About Lonergans Pack Station 
 
 Thats right, a pack
 station just like the old days. They have ice cream, sodas, and a small assortment
 of &quot;stuff&quot; like youd find at any out of the way mountain type pack station. There
 are also mules that will carry your supplies for a price. The mules are often used
 to deliver supplies to some of the privately-cabins in the canyon beyond Chantry
 Flats. 
 
 From here on out,
 its hiking or biking. 
 
 As you start to journey
 away from Chantry Flats, youll drop down from the parking area on to a fire road.
 Follow this road. 
 
 There are a couple
 of ways to get down to the creek from this road. The way I like to go is on First
 Water Trail. Its a small trail that youll see on the right of the fire road. It
 has a lot of cutbacks and is a pretty hike down to the water. (If you have a map
 of the area, youll see the trails.) 
 
 Youll be on First
 Water Trail a good 20 minutes before you reach the water. When you reach the creek,
 youll begin seeing some of the privately-owned cabins. These cabins are historic.
 No more can be built. In fact, the existing cabins can only be repaired but not
 altered. These cabins are owned by regular folks who hope you respect their privacy. 
 
 A trail makes its
 way upstream and leads to Sturtevant Falls. These falls are approximately sixty-feet
 high and are only about two miles up the trail or an hours hike from Chantry Flats.
 The falls are named after William M. Sturtevant. He was an early pioneer in the
 canyon and built a beautiful resort that even had a tennis court for his guests. 
 
Sturtevant Resort Was The Place To Play
 
At one time it was &quot;the place&quot; for people like Zane Gray, Humphry Bogart and other
 notables to get away for the weekend and fish, hunt, or whatever tickled their giggle.
 Unfortunately, the resort was washed away by the flood of 1938. But the area is
 still known as the one time famous playground for many Hollywood legends.
 
 The fish at Sturtevant Falls here are
 small rainbows and are plentiful because most of the folks that fish these small
 California streams practice catch and release. I hope you do, too. Fish are more
 fun when you can catch them more than once. 
 
All In All
 
 The Big Santa Anita Canyon is a real forestlike the kind youd expect
 in a Disney film. Big trees, a creek, waterfalls and animals. In fact, dont forget.
 The wildlife here is wild, so dont feed or pet the bears. 
 
 Think
 safety. Stick to the trails. Dont hike alone. And take care of the forest. 
 
 Back to top 
 
 
 
 Sespe Creek 
 
 Probably the only place
 in the world you can enjoy catching and releasing a beautiful little native rainbow
 and glance up and see a giant Condor. Yep, theres still a few up in the mountains
 and canyons in and around Sespe Creek. 

 The Sespe Creek is
 located up above the absolutely beautiful community of Ojai. Its definitely worth
 the drive up to just take a look even if you dont fish. 

 If youre into golf,
 bring your clubs and try the course at the Ojai Valley Inn. Its the same course
 that hosts some of the seniors tour events and when youve been sitting in your
 living room watching those legends whack whitey around and thinking, &quot;Wow, wheres
 that?&quot; Well, now you know. 
 
 How You Get There from LA 
 
 Take Highway 101
 north (or west) to Ventura 
 
 Take Highway 33 east
 towards Ojai 
 
 As you come to the
 community of Ojai, therell be a fork in the road. On the left is Highway 33; the
 right or straight goes into Ojai 
 
 If you continue straight,
 the Ojai Valley Inn is only a minute or so from this intersection. The Inns Oak
 Caf, overlooking the golf course, is a neat place to grab a cup of coffee and a
 muffin. 
 
 At this intersection,
 youll notice a strip mall to your left. If you need anything, get it now. Theres
 not much of anything up the road where youre headed. 
 
 Follow the fork in
 the road left (Highway 33) north and continue about fourteen miles to the Rose Valley
 Rd. 
 
 On the way, youll
 pass a couple of neat little bars, some campgrounds, and the Wheeler Hot Springs. 
 
 If you stop, Id
 recommend staying away from the squirrels. Though it may be okay now, in the past,
 the squirrels have been found to carry a plague which can be transmitted via their
 fleas. 
 
 When you get to Rose
 Valley Road, make a right (east) and go approximately seven miles to Lions Campground. 
 
 Here, youll see a
 couple of fishing ponds off to the left and camp grounds to your right. If you turn
 into the campgrounds and go to the end of the road, youll find a foot path that
 follows the creek for about twelve miles. You might even come across some hot springs
 and want to stop and do a little natural hot tubbing. 
 
 To Reach the Upper Sespe 
 
 Instead of stopping
 at Lions Campground, you could continue on Rose Valley Road. Youll pass a shooting
 range off to your left and a little further up (and down) youll come to Beaver
 campground. 
 
 Fly Tying Anyone? 
 
 Theres an organization
 called the Sespe Flyfishers, and theyve done some great things to help the Sespe
 and make it a good place to fish. Every now and then they have world famous flytyers
 and fly casters visit to share their expertise. If you have an interest in the club
 and would like to know more about it, give Wayne a call at Malibu Fish and Tackle
 in Thousand Oaks. (805- 496-7332.)  
 
 Back to top 
 
 
 
 Bouquet Canyon Creek 
 
 Bouquet Canyon Creek
 is a busy little canyon above Six Flags Magic Mountain and the community of Santa
 Clarita. Ive been told they stock the creek with Rainbows every other week starting
 in April and continue through till September. Once you get up to the creek, youll
 find theres easy access to it along the road. 
 
 How You Get There 
 
 Take Highway 5 to
 Six Flags Magic Mountain 
 
 Go right (East) on
 Magic Mountain Road 
 
 Continue about two
 miles. 
 
 Take a left (go North)
 on Bouquet Canyon Road 
 
 Follow Bouquet Canyon
 Road about ten miles until you get to the creek 
 
 Continue on this
 road (which runs next to the creek) for approximately ten more miles up to the Bouquet
 Reservoir. 
 
 Back to top 
 
 The San Gabriel River 
 
 The San Gabriel River is located in the San Gabriel Mountains
 above the town of Azusa. The river has east, west, and north forks. All are scenic
 and teeming with wildlife. 

 If you look on the
 community map, youll see Azusa is northeast of Los Angeles. It lies in the foothills
 off the 210 Freeway between Pasadena and Glendora. 
 
 How You Get There 
 
 From Highway 210 

 - Take Highway 39 (i.e.,
 the Azusa off ramp) 

 Go north on Highway
 39 
 
 (Highway 39 northbound
 is two lanes one way. Where the one way portion of the road ends, there&apos;s a convenience
 store and a fast food restaurant on your left. Id tell you their names, but theyve
 changed so many times since Ive been going up there I dont want to confuse you.
 This is the intersection of Sierra Madre Avenue and 39 North. Its a good place
 to stop, if theres anything youve forgotten. 
 
 - Continue 3/4 of a
 mile on Highway 39 North 
 
 - Stop at the forest
 service parking permit station and get your permit 
 
 When you get your parking
 permit, grab any maps they may have, too. If no one is at this station, you can
 get a parking permit at either Camp Follows or Camp William&apos;s. 
 
 - From here it&apos;s uphill
 all the way 
 
 Be Very Careful on this Road 
 
 The shoulders off this road quickly become cliffs and are very
 steep. If youre driving too fast and an animal or mountain biker gets in youre
 way, it can be very dangerous. Many times I&apos;ve had to stop because a coyote with
 an attitude was standing in the middle of the road and didn&apos;t feel like moving. 
 
 There are plenty of
 pullouts for sight seeing and parking. If another car follows you too close, use
 these pullouts to let it pass. Its not only the polite thing to do its the safe
 thing to do. This way you can take your time and enjoy the scenic ride. 
 
 - As you make your
 way up the mountain, the first body of water you see on your right is Morris Reservoir. 
 
 - The next body of
 water is the San Gabriel Reservoir. If it&apos;s full, it&apos;s worth stopping to see the
 water coming over the dam. 
 
 - As you get to the
 north end of San Gabriel Reservoir, you&apos;ll be able to see where the west and east
 forks of the river flow into the reservoir. If the water level is down, this is
 a great place to go four-wheeling. 
 
 - Youre now about
 eleven miles from where you turned off the 210 onto Highway 39. You should be at
 the bridge that begins East Fork Road. 
 
 - To go to the East
 Fork , turn right here. 
 
 - To go to the West
 Fork , continue on. Youll find the trail that runs along the West Fork a short
 ways up on the left. 
 
 - First lets cover
 what youll find in the East Fork. 
 
 Back to top 
 
 

 The East Fork of the San Gabriel 
 
 - As you continue on
 East Fork Road, youll cross a bridge, and make your way along the East Fork of
 the river. 
 
 Pull Over and Fish 
 
 I like the East Fork because as you travel along, you can pull
 over any time youd like and fish the river. Small rainbows are abundant in the
 six to eight*-inch size with the trophy being a twelve-incher. You can call the
 Fish and Game Department to check on the last plant. Their phone number is 562-590-5020.  
 
 PERMIT ALERT If You Stop Even Just to Look! 
 
 If you plan on stopping
 and parking your car along the road , you&apos;ll need a Wilderness Pass or parking permit. They only cost a few dollars, and it all goes to the upkeep of our great outdoors.
 I buy mine at Big Five but Im pretty sure you can buy the at most sporting goods
 stores. In a pinch you can probably get one at a local establishment in the mountains. 
 
 If you start spending
 much time in the mountains, you might want to purchase a yearly permit. It costs
 about thirty dollars and is good for not only the San Gabriel National Forest, but also for National Parks
 and Forests in the Los Padre National Forest, San Bernadino National Forest, and
 the Cleveland National Forest in the San Diego area. 
 
 - I should have mentioned
 earlier that I have always stayed on the road that hugs the river. Any left or right
 off of East Fork Road is for you to explore on your own. So enjoy. If you find something
 fun, let me know. 
 
 - About a mile after
 the bridge on your left is the entrance to the Burro Canyon shooting range. This is a safe place to take
 your rifles, pistols, and shotguns if you want to do any plinking. 
 
 - A little ways past
 the shooting range on the right is Fire Camp #19. The fire camp is off limits to
 the public unless youre reporting a fire. 
 
 - Continuing on another
 six tenths of a mile, youll arrive at Follows Camp. A remnant of those glorious
 days of gold mining. You can still pan for gold here. 
 
 Fun at Follows Camp 
 
 I&apos;ve tried my hand at panning and sluicing and had gold flake
 and garnets appear in the bottom of my pan. It was a lot of fun but really hard
 work. A great thing to turn the young kids onto. History and fun all together. 
 
 If youre really lucky,
 you might turn up a good-sized nugget or two. Follows Camp has everything you need to get you started
 and, if you get serious, you can load up on gold mining supplies at Keene Engineering
 in Chatsworth on Bahama Street. Keene Engineering&apos;s phone number is 818-993-0411 .
 They have everything anyone would ever need to pan or mine for gold. 
 
 The fishing at Follows
 Camp is pretty good and the Fish and Game Department stocks here on a regular basis.
 They have approximately 200 campsites and, last time I checked, it was eighteen
 dollars a night per campsite. They also have a restaurant there and serve a wide
 variety of dishes. Follows Camp includes a camp store in case you&apos;ve forgotten something.
 They sell parking permits here, too. Camp Follows phone number is 626-910-1100 . 
 
 Again, any pullout
 that youd like to stop at and fish or pan, feel free to do so. Exploring is the fun part. 
 
 - Continuing up the
 road a little over a mile from Follows Camp is Camp William&apos;s. The camp is on your
 left; there&apos;s mobile home park on your right. 
 
 - Just before you enter
 the camp, there&apos;ll be a restaurant with plenty of parking. You can&apos;t miss it. It
 has a large sign that says &quot;Camp William&apos;s Cafe and General Store.&quot; 
 
 Camp Williams Caf and General Store 
 
 &quot;This is a neat little place to have a cup of coffee or a cold
 beer and
sandwich. The property supervisors are Mark and Jeannie Yelton. If you&apos;d like to
 call ahead their phone number is 626-910-1126. You may purchase parking permits
 here also. 
 
 More About Camp Williams 
 
  If you want to stay at Camp Williams, you&apos;ll need to talk
 to Jeannie Yelton. She runs the campsites up there and tells me there are
 now about fifty campsites, and the campground, cafe and facilities have recently
 been totally redone. If you&apos;d like to call and check on the availability of
 a campsite or to check on stocking days the phone number is 626-910-1126.
 
 
 I prefer nature and
 solitude, so after stopping in for a cup of coffee, a parking pass and a little
 chat about the things that have happened since my last visit, I move on up the river. 
 
 - Up river, about a
 half a mile from Camp Williams, is an old wooden bridge. The bridge crosses
 Cattle Creek (some call it Cow Creek). Where Cattle Creek flows into the East Fork
 is a great place to pan or fish. After heavy rains, you&apos;ll see lots of panners down
 in the river. It&apos;s a pretty cool sight. There is a good fishing hole here,
 and, every now and then, someone pulls out a pretty nice fish. 
 
 - After you pass the old bridge, it&apos;s another half a mile or so to the end
 of the road. 

 - As you arrive at
 the parking area, you&apos;ll see a sign that tells you youre at the Wilderness Fire
 Station (ranger station). The station is up on the right. This also begins the Sheep
 Mountain Wilderness Area. You can usually catch a ranger on duty. Hopefully, youll
 be able to pick up a map of the area at the station. People, who are backpacking
 into the wilderness area, will usually park here overnight. 
 
 To Park or Not To Park 
 
 I personally have never had anything bad happen to a vehicle of
 mine or my friends when parking here overnight. But that&apos;s your call. For an easy
 backpacking trip, you can park here and take the fire road that continues on into
 the mountains. This is a great place to start a child into backpacking. 
 
 Okay. Lets assume
 youre parked and youre geared up. Where do you go? 
 
 Beginners and the Young 
 
 There is a perfect campsite about a half a mile up the road. It&apos;s
 a stand of evergreens, and the area is flat with relatively no stones to dig into
 your back while you sleep. It&apos;s just far enough for a child to think they&apos;ve conquered
 something great and not be to sore or tired to make them dislike it. A perfect way
 to begin a lifetime of enjoying the outdoors with incredible stars and a beautiful
 little stand of trees by the river known as Heaton Flats. 
 
 Who Was Heaton? 
 
 Heaton was a miner in the eighteen hundreds and was known to have
 settled here and panned for gold. He and his place were washed away in the flood
 of 1862. Its a lesson in history to experience the area. 
 
 For the Advanced and More Adventurous 
 
 Up into the narrows, a few miles from the ranger station and parking
 area is a the Bridge from Nowhere. My friend Mike and I have hiked there and camped
 overnight. Its a pretty impressive bridge that seems to hang above the river and
 doesn&apos;t seem to be coming from or going to anywhere. Hence the name. 

 Its a pretty tough
 hike especially in hot weather. Be sure and carry lots of water.* The fishing is
 good up here. I&apos;ve caught a fourteen*-incher in the narrows and in these waters
 that&apos;s a true trophy. 

 When youre up in this
 neck of the woods, you might see some of the mines that have been dug into the mountains.
 If you decide to explore them be very careful. I&apos;ve entered a few of them
 but being somewhat claustrophobic as soon as I couldnt see the light from the end
 of the* tunnel, I stopped. 

 Back to top 
 
 
 
 The West Fork 
 
 Lets back up for a minute. If you had choosen not to turn
 on to East Fork Road off of Highway 39, then you would continue on to the West Fork
 of the San Gabriel. The West Fork has wonderful camping sites, great fishing, and
 waterfalls. Heres how to find these great spots. 
 
 - Continue straight
 up the road to the West Fork. 
 
 - A short ways up on
 your right, youll see the entrance to the off-roading and four-wheeling area. Parking
 permits can also be purchased here. Remember youll need one to park anywhere in the San
 Gabriel National Forest. 
 
 - About a quarter mile
 or so on the left side of the road is a large pullout for parking. Park here if
 youre ready to hike. The hiking on the West Fork can be strenuous, so carry lots
 of water 
 
 - From the parking
 area, walk north a ways until you come to a fire road with a locked gate (cable).
 The road drops down to the river below the south side of the bridge that allows
 the west fork to flow under Highway 39. 
 
 - This fire road follows
 the West Fork for approximately eight miles west to Cogswell Dam and reservoir. 
 
 Fish, Trees, Shade 

 Now, Heres a Good Spot to Camp 
 
 The fishing here is really good. If you have a mountain bike,
 it&apos;s the easiest way to fish the entire West Fork. The camping is also good here
 largely due to the trees providing shade and cooling things down a bit in the summer.
 But remember this is bear country and there have been attacks.. 
 
 - When you get within
 a mile or so of the Cogswell Dam, you&apos;ll find a few picnic tables and campsite stoves. 
 
 Another Good Spot 
 
 It&apos;s a nice place to spend the night. The fish and game folks
 stock this part of the river every now and then so you might want to give them a
 call and see when their scheduled plants are. 
 
 Dont forget to take
 a map of the area so youll know on which of the trails off the fire road, youll
 find water falls. The falls up above Glen Trail Camp in Glen Canyon are beautiful.
 Theyre a short hike from the campsite and are worth seeing. 
 
 Okay, youve parked, hiked, fished and maybe even spent the night. Youre
 ready to continue your drive up Highway 39. 
 
 - Continuing on up
 Highway 39, you&apos;ll see the waters of the North Fork of the San Gabriel River as
 it flows along the side the road. 

 - Highway 39 takes
 you all the way to Angeles Crest Highway (Highway 2) and, if even if you do nothing else, this is a beautiful drive.
 Crystal Lake is up this way also and is known for its fishing and camping. 
 
 
 
 All In All 
 
 What I have shared
 with you so far only scratches the surface of what the San Gabriel Mountains have
 to offer. These wonderful places within the East, West and North Forks are all within
 one to two hours of Los Angeles, Hollywood and the surrounding area. Theyre beautiful
 and can create memories to last forever. Enjoy. 

 Back to top 
 
 Piru Creek 

 (Frenchmans Flat) 
 
 Piru Creek is one of
 my favorite places to fish. The rainbows are pretty aggressive and its close to
 my home. I can be on the water catching fish within an hour of my front door. 

 My favorite spot at
 Piru Creek is about a mile or so above Frenchmans Flat. Ive had some great times
 at Piru in the mornings just before the sun-up. 

 Usually Im the only
 one on the creek and the wildlife hasnt been scared away yet so I get to see deer,
 coyotes, and the occasional Bobcat. I love to watch how animals react to each other. 
 
 How You Get There 
 
 Piru Creek is located
 North of LA, off of Highway 5, about 13 miles north of Six Flags Magic Mountain
 and about seven miles north of Castaic. A good reference point is Magic Mountain. 
 
 From Highway 5 
 
 Take of the Templin
 Highway exit. (Approximately 13 miles after you pass Magic Mountain Six Flags and
 the community of Santa Clarita.) 
 
 Templin Highway is
 the old Highway 99 North and it parallels Highway 5 for about five miles up (and
 down) to Frenchmans Flat. 
 
 Hollywood Alert 
 
 Dont be surprised
 if you see a film crew or two shooting a movie, TV show, or commercial. Some great
 scenes have been shot up here including the scene in &quot;Breakdown&quot; where the conclusion
 takes place. The scene at the bridge where the truck is wrecked and crashes down
 on the bad guy and squishes him. That is one of my best fishing spots. There should
 have been a disclaimer saying &quot;no trout were injured or killed during the filming
 of this movie.&quot; (just kidding) 
 
 At Frenchmans Flat,
 youll find parking. From here on, its all on foot. 
 
 You can either drop
 down west to the creek and fish or follow the road north along the river and pick
 a fishing spot further up. 
 
 Youll want to check
 the current regulations with the Fish and Game Department. 
 
 Good Fishing 
 
 The fishing here is
 good and, if you really want to go for it, take a couple of days and do an overnighter.
 You can camp and then and head downstream to Lake Piru. The pickup spot would be
 Blue Point at the north end of Lake Piru. If you do this little backpacking trip
 remember to tell someone where you are going and when to expect you back. 
 
 All in All 
 
 The area of Piru Creek
 at Frenchmans Flat is great. Ive seen all kinds of animals here, too. Though Im
 still a little bias to the beauty of the North Carolina and Virginia hills where
 I grew up, Ive seen a lot more wildlife in Southern California than back home.
 I think thats because of the lack of trees and foliage here. I carry a small pair
 of binoculars in my vest and have seen wildlife I could not have seen without them.
 They also allow me to see fish in the stream below when Im on the higher trails
 above. 
 
 A Rambling Tale 
 
 Once while standing
 in the Piru creek, I heard a loud noise and looked up to see two coyotes
 attacking or trying to get what I think was a small mule deer. The coyotes had the
 deer backed up to the creek and were spread to either side with their tails and
 heads angled down in a stalking position. The deer had kind of frozen with her head
 cocked to an angle and was trying to keep an eye on both coyotes. 
 
 The coyotes were doing
 a yipping noise and were moving a couple of steps side to side when all of a sudden
 the little deer turned and jumped into and out the other side of the creek. She
 was gone in the blink of an eye. She was so small that when she was moving through
 the water it was up to her chest. 
 
 The coyotes both gave
 chase with one pulling up short of the water and the other barreling into it. The
 one that hit the water freaked and jumped back out as fast as hed gone in. When
 he got back on dry land, he immediately shook to get the water off and the other
 one whimpered around him like he was checking to see if he was OK. Then as I watched
 they both slinked away. If they ever saw me, they didnt act like it. 
 
 

 Ya&apos;ll Come Back
 Now Ya Hear 

 Back To Top 
 Copyright 1999-2010 BornDreamer All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
