<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000694" url="http://ph.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20100216091444AAifM2j" time="2012-07-12-15:59" support="3" score="0.006763826343299109" bingtitle="Yahoo! Answers - What are the duties of a fast food cashier/?" webtitle="Yahoo! Answers - What are the duties of a fast food cashier/?">
			<query id="001134" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000225" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="001008" bing-rank="35"/>
	<description>... need to explain the duties of a cashier at a fast food restaurant. ... fridges/freezers, shake machines, misc. like cups, straws) If you are a drive thru cashier ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Philippines Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Fast Food &gt; Resolved Question 
 ellie Member since: November 17, 2009 Total points: 99 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
What are the duties of a fast food cashier/?
 i need to write a resume and need to explain the duties of a cashier at a fast food restaurant. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Duckie Member since: January 28, 2008 Total points: 2,264 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 you are writing a resume- and need to ask what some of your duties were? They are: ringing up orders, making change, handing out food, cleaning ( counter area, lobby, bathrooms) stocking ( sauces, fridges/freezers, shake machines, misc. like cups, straws) If you are a drive thru cashier : dishes, table prep, preparing salads, towel buckets. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: this really helped me out because i did both front and drive tru cashier 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; What are the duties … &quot;was originally asked on Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (0)
 
No other answers.
 
Discover Questions in Fast Food 

 Interview questions for McDonalds? ? New at working at Sonic Drive-Inn? Any Tips? Will i get hired at McDonald&apos;s ? KFC STRAWBERRY PARFAIT? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
Related Questions

 whats the job duties of a cashier at wendys? what are some duties of a cashier/storefront server at a fast… what are the duties and resposibilities of service crew in… what is the best way to describe my duties as a fast food… How to make these job duties sound better for my resume? 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Asia Pacific Pte Ltd. (Co. Reg. No. 199700735D). All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
