<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000696" url="http://local.toolkit.com/Credit_Card_Equipment_Novi_MI-r1385089-Novi_MI.html" time="2012-07-12-15:59" support="8" score="0.008115170422479553" bingtitle="Credit Card Equipment Novi MI - Novi MI, credit card equipment ..." webtitle="Credit Card Equipment Novi MI - Novi MI, credit card equipment, Novi MI  credit cards planning, Novi MI  credit and collections, Novi MI  managing business finances, Novi MI  small business">
			<query id="001369" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="001495" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000612" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="001304" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="001307" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000303" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="000615" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="000300" bing-rank="176"/>
	<description>Obviously, the receipt you get for your burger and fries at a fast food restaurant isn&apos;t too meaningful. ... company will want to see an itemized bill in order to ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign Up My 
 Toolkit   
 
 
 
 Home Small Business Guide Business Tools Podcast News Toolkit Store Contact 

 Home » MI » Novi MI » Logistics and Fulfillment 
Credit Card Equipment Novi MI
 Choosing credit card equipment has more to do with the interface between what equipment you use at the point of sale to collect and record payment, and the software that you use to perform the accounting required. The days of manually imprinting the numbers directly from the card are just about gone. Today, most merchants simply swipe a credit card through a cash register scanner or a dedicated computer terminal. 
 Local Companies 
 National Ataxia Foundation 
 (313) 736-2827
 20217 wyoming
Detroit, MI Merchant Warehouse 
 866-599-3217
 Flint, MI Merchant Warehouse 
 866-599-3217
 Detroit, MI Merchant Warehouse 
 866-599-3217
 Warren, MI Merchant Warehouse 
 866-599-3217
 Sterling Heights, MI Merchant Warehouse 
 866-599-3217
 Ann Arbor, MI Merchant Warehouse 
 866-599-3217
 Grand Rapids, MI Lowest Rates USA 
 (269) 873-0293
 5138 Stone Brook
Kalamazoo, MI Alegre Merchant Services 
 877-358-5177
 7200 republic
warren, MI Shiawassee County Critter Sitter 
 989-729-7387
 129 E Grand River Rd
Owosso, MI 
 Credit Card Equipment 
 

 
 
 Credit Card Equipment 
Choosing credit card equipment has more to do with the interface between what equipment you use at the point of sale to collect and record payment, and the software that you use to perform the accounting required. The days of manually imprinting the numbers directly from the card are just about gone. In fact, several card issuers no longer have raised numbers on the card - a magnetic strip has replaced the mechanical method.

Today, most merchants simply swipe a credit card through a cash register scanner or a dedicated computer terminal. Some credit card mechanisms interface directly with inventory control software to provide stocking and ordering information on a real-time basis.

Another issue is whether your business is the type that must provide printed receipts to customers. The software that accounts for sales generally will provide the option to create a printed receipt. Obviously, the receipt you get for your burger and fries at a fast food restaurant isn&apos;t too meaningful. In contrast, the receipt that an auto repair shop provides has significance to several parties.

A receipt from an auto repair shop will detail each of the elements that enter into the final cost. Parts, labor, and materials are items that have significance to the customer, who will want to know why it costs so much does to repair a simple fender bender. The insurance company will want to see an itemized bill in order to negotiate how much to pay. And the repair shop can feed the data into inv... 
 
 Click here to read the rest of this article from Business Owner&apos;s Toolkit 
 Related Topics Coupons and Rebates Novi MI Many small businesses use coupons as part of their promotional programs. The more common o... 
 Contact | Terms | Privacy | Copyright | About Us | Advertising | Media Kit 

© 1995- 2011 Toolkit Media Group. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
