<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000820" url="http://www.ehow.com/restaurants/" time="2012-07-12-16:11" support="6" score="0.0078037498437131345" bingtitle="Restaurants - How To Information | eHow.com" webtitle="Restaurants - How To Information  | eHow.com">
			<query id="000798" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000801" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="001084" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000308" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000788" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="001092" bing-rank="30"/>
	<description>... fall, spring and summer provide the option of seating your ... investors is not an easy task--especially in places like ... that allows steam, smoke and pollutants to exit the ...</description>
	<body>
		money section 
 Saving&amp;Spending 
 Budgeting Banking Credit Cards Loans 
 Real Estate 
 Buying a Home Home Loans Selling a Home 
 Careers 
 Career Advice Land the Job Work for Yourself 
 Your Business 
 Starting a Business Managing Employees Running a Business 
 Insurance 
 Insurance Basics Auto Insurance Life Insurance 
 Retirement 
 Get Started Plan Ahead Make It Last 
 
 
 More eHow 
 home mom style food tech money health 
 
 Featured: Allergies eHow Now Blog 
 eHow Business Restaurant, Bar&amp;Nightclub Industries Restaurants 
 
Restaurants

 
 RSS 
 Suggestive Selling Techniques for Restaurants 
Suggestive selling is a big part of running a successful restaurant. Learn about suggestive selling techniques for restaurants with help from a longtime restaurant manager in this free video clip.
 Restaurant Etiquette for Dropped Utensils 
If you drop a utensil at a restaurant, don&apos;t panic. Find out about restaurant etiquette for dropped utensils with help from a published author in this free video clip.
 How to Make the Jump From a Single Operation Restaurant to a Franchise 
Taking your small restaurant business into the world of franchising is one of the most difficult decisions you will ever make as a business owner. Strike too early and you could find yourself without the capital and brand recognition to sell enough franchises quickly. Wait too long and the market could become saturated with restaurants too much like your own. While there is enormous risk in franchising your single restaurant, the rewards, if it works, can be huge. Plan carefully and ensure that the conditions are in place to make your franchising story a success.
 How to Get Unlimited Stoves on Restaurant Story 
&quot;Restaurant Story&quot;is an application video game in which the player operates a virtual restaurant. In the game, the player&apos;s tasks are to cook food, maintain inventory, serve customers, purchase new items for the restaurant and make money in order to advance in the levels. As players level up, they are able to unlock more items, such as stoves. The more stoves the player has the more food he can serve and, in turn, improve the restaurant. A special cheating code is available so that players can unlock the stoves and get an unlimited supply.
 How to Help Toddlers Behave in Restaurants 
You don’t have to skip the convenience of a dinner out just because you have a toddler in tow. Make your dining experience positive by helping encourage good behavior from your 1- to 3-year-old. Your experience may not be as relaxing as it would be had you left your toddler at home with a sitter, but it can still be a good time.
 How to Enclose a Restaurant Patio 
If you run a restaurant, the milder temperatures of early fall, spring and summer provide the option of seating your customers outside on a patio where they can enjoy the fresh air while enjoying a meal from your kitchen. However, the space allotted to a patio does not make you any money during cool or rainy weather. Fortunately, you can choose from a number of enclosure options, depending on the building codes in your area, your budget and aesthetic, and the construction of the patio.
 Restaurant Maketing 101 
For many people, owning or running a restaurant is a lifelong dream. While restaurant ownership can be a difficult and intense endeavor, it can also be a rewarding experience. With six out of 10 newly opened restaurants going out of business within their first year, effective marketing is essential. Without it, it is highly unlikely that a restaurant can be successful.
 Toddlers&amp;Restaurants 
How you prepare yourself and your toddler for restaurant dining makes the difference between an enjoyable evening and battle of complete mayhem and embarrassment. With hectic schedules and less time, American families spend,&quot;roughly half of their families’total food budgets and consuming nearly a third of all calories away from home,&quot;reports the American Academy of Pediatrics. No toddler is going to sit perfectly still and silent for a two-hour, five-course meal, but that doesn&apos;t mean they can&apos;t behave appropriately at the pancake house down the street. With patience and strategy, enjoying restaurants with your toddler can become an…
 How to Sell Homemade Desserts to Restaurants 
If you have a passion for baking and people with a sweet tooth have told you the desserts you make are delectably delicious, then consider marketing your sweet treats to area restaurants. Baking out of the home allows you to keep your overhead low as your business begins. Then, move to a larger commercial kitchen as your business grows.
 How to Keep Floors Dry in a Restaurant 
Wet floors in a restaurant may be unsightly and slippery, but they also create a potential liability for your restaurant should an employee or customer fall on one. To protect yourself, you need to do everything you can to keep your floors dry and safe in both the front and back of the restaurant. Learn some techniques to make sure your restaurant&apos;s floors stay as dry as possible, even when customers and employees are tracking in snow and rain.
 How to Be a Good Restaurant Waitress 
Because waitresses often make less than minimum wage, pleasing your customers is an important factor in your income. If you do a poor job, your tips suffer and you end up with far less pay. Becoming a good waitress requires patience and practice. When you first become a waitress, it can be difficult to keep customers happy while you are learning the ropes; however, once you are more familiar with the job, you can have a positive impact on your earning potential.
 How to Improve Guest Satisfaction in the Restaurant Industry 
There are a number of ways to improve guest satisfaction in the restaurant industry. The key is making sure all guests have a pleasant experience. Restaurant customers like waiters, cashiers and hosts that are helpful and friendly. Therefore, make sure you hire enthusiastic employees who enjoy working at your restaurant. Customers also expect you to deliver what you promised in your Internet, radio or yellow pages advertising. Hence, strive to meet and even exceed your guests&apos; expectations.
 How to Do Bookkeeping for a Restaurant 
Setting up a bookkeeping system for a restaurant can involve a variety of modules, designed to handle the different aspects of the business. While these modules combine to offer a comprehensive view of a restaurant&apos;s financial condition, each requires individual attention. In some cases, bookkeeping for a restaurant can be managed on paper or with the aid of simple spreadsheets. For larger or more complex operations, computer-based accounting software or outsourcing may be necessary to meet the reporting and legal obligations of the restaurant.
 Financial Procedures for a Restaurant Kitchen 
In the heat and flurry of a restaurant kitchen, it can be easy to lose track of the fact that a restaurant is a business, and it must be financially viable to survive. A financially healthy restaurant kitchen must put out a quality product and charge a price that covers costs and still feels fair to the diners who enjoy it. A financially healthy restaurant kitchen must also keep its costs under control by purchasing and staffing shrewdly, and keeping waste to a minimum.
 What Does It Mean When a Restaurant Has High Employee Turnover? 
Businesses of all types hire employees to carry out day-to-day tasks like producing products, maintaining facilities and serving customers. The term&quot;employee turnover&quot;describes the rate at which a business has to replace employees. A restaurant or any other business has high turnover if it tends to constantly hire new employees to replace others who have left the business.
 Legal Breaks for Employees in a Restaurant 
The restaurant business can present a tense and anxious workplace, which is why it&apos;s important to ensure that employees are granted ample time to eat a meal or attend to other small personal matters. Many restaurants are subject to regulations at the state level in regards to how much time an employee should have for a meal break. Federal legislation also protects other rights important to restaurant employees, including overtime pay and workplace safety.
 How to Recover a Restaurant Bench Cushion 
Restaurant cushions get their share of wear and tear, especially if there’s a decent menu attracting hungry customers. Whether you have an ice cream parlor or sandwich shop, durability is as important as the décor. New cushions can enhance the design scheme as they help freshen things up. There are plenty of fabrics available that will satisfy both needs and last until the next time you are ready to redecorate.
 How to Sell a Restaurant Quickly 
You may have many reasons you need to unload your restaurant, from financial troubles to a move into retirement. When financial issues arise, you may have a need to sell your restaurant quickly, thus unloading the expenses associated with it. Whatever the reason, if you must sell your restaurant quickly, keep a few things in mind.
 Tax on Restaurant Gratuity 
Workers in service industries like waiters and waitresses at restaurants often receive income in the form of wages as well as customers in the form of tips or gratuities. The Internal Revenue Service considers gratuities received to be a taxable form of income and restaurant servers are subject to several special tax rules that apply to tip income.
 How to Get to the Restaurant in &quot;Dolphin Olympics&quot; 
Getting to the restaurant in&quot;Dolphin Olympics 2&quot;requires a quick hand and knowledge of which moves will generate the highest jumps. Control over the angle of the dolphin as it emerges and reenters the water is crucial. Obtaining and maintaining a high speed while swimming is important to a successful run as well. Combos, starslides, tailslides and corkscrews are helpful tricks to master and improve your chances of success.
 The Responsibilities at the Front of the House in a Restaurant 
In the restaurant business, jobs are generally divided between two broad categories: front of the house and the back of the house. Harmony between the two is necessary to ensure the restaurant runs smoothly, from serving hot food to busing tables after diners have finished their meals. These responsibilities change and blend depending on the size, composition and needs of the work environment, but are a good rule of thumb to consider when working in the food service industry.
 What Is the Average Pay for a Bartender at a Restaurant? 
Food and beverage industry professionals who prefer a quieter and more relaxed work environment than the nightclub scene might enjoy careers as restaurant bartenders. Working in a restaurant is an ideal situation for bartenders who prefer afternoon and evening schedules rather than the late-night hours required by taverns and nightclubs. Your salary may vary depending on location, position and the type of restaurant you work for.
 How to Make a Career in a Restaurant 
The highest-paying careers in the restaurant industry usually consist of chefs and managers, but servers can earn a full-time living as well, especially in higher-end restaurants. To not only break into the restaurant industry but remain there for the duration of your time in the workforce, you&apos;ll need to meet the requirements of the position you&apos;re after and have an insatiable desire to improve.
 How to Calculate the Break-Even for a Restaurant 
The break-even point, or BE, of a restaurant refers to the amount of total revenue needed to cover expenses. The factors that determine BE include the restaurant’s Fixed Costs, or FC, and its Variable Costs, or VC. FC refers to expenses that do not increase or decrease with sales volume, whereas VC encompasses costs that change with sales volume. Knowing the BE point of a restaurant is imperative when calculating financial projections and forecasting profit. You can calculate your restaurant’s BE within any time frame, such as annually, quarterly and weekly.
 Restaurant Accounting Method 
Like other businesses, if you own a restaurant, you can choose between the cash and accrual methods of accounting for your business. Typically, if your business is small, the cash method is more manageable. Larger businesses might be more interested in the accrual method. A professional accountant can analyze your needs and advise you on which system will work best for you as you start out.
 Accounting 101 for Restaurants 
Owning a restaurant isn&apos;t just a business decision. It&apos;s a lifestyle. It can be tremendously rewarding, but many restaurants fail, and not because the food is bad, but because many restaurant owners have poor financial management skills. They don&apos;t have adequate capital and reserves set aside, and have trouble accounting for overhead, spoilage, taxes and other necessary expenses.
 How to Move a Restaurant Freezer Easily 
Restaurant freezers are typically commercial-grade refrigerating equipment weighing in well more than a ton in many cases, if fully stocked. From time to time, restaurant owners, managers and chefs must move equipment for health code inspections, cleaning and replacement. Trying to move one of these freezers can be an arduous task as the equipment is not only heavy but also sensitive. Moving a freezer on your own may not be possible, but with the help of casters -- wheels attached at the freezer bottoms -- there is a way make the job much easier.
 Disadvantages to Living Upstairs From a Restaurant 
Restaurants make up a substantial amount of storefront properties in the country. In relatively dense areas store fronts are often combined with residential property to maximize the value of the space. However, there are several disadvantages for the tenant. On the positive side, the disadvantage might lead to a lower rent.
 What Three Qualities Are Needed to Work in a Restaurant? 
Restaurant workers typically work long hours under stressful conditions, especially during lunch and dinner rushes while also attending to the guests and their demands. Those who work in fast food, casual dining and finer eateries must be able to handle the rigors of the job, including some occasional lifting. And while restaurant workers&apos; skills can vary according to rank, several common qualities exist that these workers must possess to succeed.
 Restaurant Hostessing Etiquette 
Being hostess at a restaurant carries a number of responsibilities. As hostess, you&apos;re the first person the restaurant patrons encounter, and the interaction they share with you will form their first impressions of the restaurant and influence the entire dining experience. For this reason, it&apos;s important that a restaurant hostess follow some basic rules of etiquette.
 A Restaurant&apos;s Responsibilities With a Bar and Minors Drinking 
Though the federal legal drinking age is 21, exceptions exist on the state level regarding alcohol consumption by minors. Ten states have laws that allow minors to drink on premises that sell alcohol if they are accompanied by a parent or legal guardian. However, restaurants in the 40 states that do not allow minor drinking must observe a few guidelines to prevent minors from obtaining alcohol in their bars.
 Restaurant Tricks You Should Try at Home 
Successful restaurant chefs produce delicious, visually appealing food quickly, often at high volume, sometimes in limited space and always with a tight rein on cost. Many of their tried-and-true methods adapt surprisingly well to home kitchens. You can put their tricks to use to pull off multicourse meals, have everything ready simultaneously, wow your dinner companions with artful presentation and serve a crowd with ease.
 How to Close Your Restaurant in &quot;Restaurant Story&quot; 
&quot;Restaurant Story&quot; is an online game that can be played via any Android phone able to download all 14.2 megabytes of the program. You take on the role of a restaurant owner who opens a small restaurant, cooks dishes and serves up tasty meals to the public. If you want to close your restaurant though, you&apos;re going to have to get a little more creative with the options in the game.
 How to Maintain a Restaurant Grill 
Most restaurants have a commercial charbroiler grill and flat-top grill. Charbroilers use underfired burners to heat ceramic or volcanic-rock briquettes that transfer the heat into the cooking grids or grates above. Flat-top grills, or griddles, have flat metal grilling surfaces that are easy to clean. Maintenance routines are critical to the long-term performance of your grill, and the bulk of grill maintenance consists of regular cleaning. You must keep all kitchen equipment clean in your restaurant to meet food sanitation regulations and local health codes when you are serving food to the public.
 What Type of Expenses Must Be Paid When Operating a Restaurant? 
Opening and operating a restaurant can be gratifying and rewarding, but you must go into the process with realistic expectations and an idea of your major ongoing expenses. All restaurants will have similar expenses in common, regardless of the type or location of your business. A hot dog restaurant must still purchase food, although it will be different in both amount and type of food than a steakhouse. Being aware of your monthly expenses will help you plan your budget.
 Red Seal Chef Salary 
The term Red Seal chef is a Canadian term that implies the chef is an expert because he has earned the Red Seal accreditation by demonstrating superior skills and knowledge as a chef and passing a national exam. While the title is Canadian, Red Seal chefs can also work as chefs in the U.S. or other countries. Red Seal chefs are classified by the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics under the broader career category of chefs. Salaries for chefs vary by restaurant or employer, as well as experience and reputation. Some chefs receive formal training, some learn by experience and…
 How to Determine Star Restaurant Ratings 
As a diner, you have the right to rate the restaurants you go to. Traditionally, only writers from newspapers or specialty publications could pass public judgment on eateries, but now anyone can do it. You can give restaurants a rating on online food publications such as Rate a Restaurant (rate-a-restaurant.com) or Zagat (zagat.com/vote). Restaurants are usually given star ratings based on a series of factors such as service, food and experience. Star ratings typically start at five, which is the highest, and go down to one.
 Uses for a Closed Restaurant 
There are a variety of uses for closed restaurants, whether they&apos;re out of business permanently or just closed for the evening. Some of them require health and business licenses if food is to be served, or money made, but if the restaurant is closed in between normal business hours, the proper licenses are already in place for a number of alternate uses.
 The Salary of Restaurant Cleaners 
Job growth is likely to be slow for all types of building cleaning workers through at least 2018, according to the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics. Nevertheless, opportunities should still be good, because most job openings in this field occur due to turnover. The salary of a restaurant cleaner depends on the type of cleaning he does and the type of establishment in which he works.
 What Are CVV2 and CVC2 Numbers? 
Credit card fraud is a liability for banks, cardholders and merchants. While customers often do not have to pay for fraudulent charges on a credit card, they will have to spend time clearing fraudulent charges from their account. Depending on the circumstance of the fraud, either the merchant or the bank will cover the cost of fraudulent transactions. In order to combat credit card fraud, many banks have begun utilizing countermeasures designed to ensure that transactions are based on a verified card as opposed to a stolen credit card number.
 Employee Tips and Gratuity in Oregon 
The United States Department of Labor defines a tipped employee as one who typically earns at least $30 per month in gratuities. Federal labor laws cover issues such as employer tip credits and the retention of tips by the employee. Oregon labor laws on tips and gratuities coincide with federal statutes in most respects. Whenever Oregon and federal laws differ, the standard that gives the greater benefit to the employee is the one that Oregon employers must follow.
 How to Outline a Feasibility Study 
A feasibility study evaluates the viability of a business venture or idea. A feasibility study for a potential business venture would aim to determine factors such as the necessary start-up capital, how much profit the venture would make, who the target market is, who may invest in the venture and what risks the venture faces. The study aims to draw conclusive evidence that shows whether or not the idea should be implemented. Remember that the outline is not the study itself. You must first draft the outline, a summary of the points you need to research and then research them…
 Restaurant Controller Responsibilities 
Despite a popular misconception that failure rates are even higher than they actually are, research reported by Bloomberg Businessweek shows that about 60 percent of new restaurants fail in the first three years of business. With the odds against you, if you want to open a restaurant, controlling costs and tracking expenses are vitally important tasks -- and these tasks are part of the job of a restaurant controller.
 How to Get Paid for Writing Restaurant Reviews 
Your love of food and restaurants, combined with a little talent for writing, can get you some extra income or even a full-time job. You can take several different paths to get paid for writing restaurant reviews, also known as becoming a food critic. These paths differ primarily in your target venue and time commitment. Regardless of which path you choose, your first steps will be the same.
 How to Reduce Food Costs in Restaurant Management 
One of the most important ratios in restaurant management is food cost. Food cost is calculated by dividing the cost of the food by the food sales and is typically expressed as a percentage. Restaurant owners hold managers responsible for keeping food costs as low as possible. The exact percentage will depend on the restaurant type with upscale restaurants typically having a higher food cost percentage than fast-food or casual theme restaurants. The factors affecting food cost are the cost of ingredients, the amount of inventory that a restaurant must maintain, the amount of food waste and the portion sizes…
 Objectives of the Restaurant Business 
Many people express a desire to get into the restaurant business. According to the National Restaurant Association, in 2011, there were 960,000 restaurants in the U.S. employing 12.8 million people. An October 2006 article in Entrepreneur Magazine states that 90 percent of all restaurants that open &quot;fail within five years.&quot; There are four main objectives to operating a successful restaurant that any potential owner needs to consider.
 How to Get a Market Analysis in Arlington, Texas 
According to the city of Arlington, TX, website, the city has a population of 370,450 as of 2010, the median age being 30.9 years old. It is the third largest city in the Dallas-Forthworth-Arlington Metroplex. This is valuable information for those who need a market analysis of the city. A market analysis is a break-down of a market based on factors such as size, structure, growth prospects, trends and sales potential. Break down Arlington further by geography, and customer attributes, such as age, race, gender, salary or product orientation. You can research Arlington to analyze government and commercial information about…
 How to Project Traffic for a Restaurant 
Starting up a restaurant isn&apos;t an easy thing to do. There are many decisions to be made in developing a good business plan, and the high failure rate of new restaurants demonstrates how many opportunities there are to get them wrong. One of the most important calculations for the budding restaurateur is projecting how much customer traffic to expect. There is no single, simple way to do this.
 Objectives of Restaurant Inspection 
The objective of most restaurant inspections is to ensure that the restaurant is in compliance with all health and safety regulations related to their business. The inspections are usually conducted by a health inspector who often arrives unannounced. Inspectors can shut down restaurants to minimize health risks to patrons and revoke licenses.
 How to Open a Panini Stand 
Paninis started in Italy, where caféguests would nibble on their flavorful grilled sandwiches at lunch or tuck the savory snacks into picnic baskets for afternoon outings. Because the pressed sandwiches are compact and neatly presented (compared with submarine sandwiches dripping with messy toppings and dressings), the panini stand is an ideal business platform for selling on-the-go meals to customers. Although your stand won&apos;t resemble a traditional brick-and-mortar business, you&apos;ll still need to adhere to conventional government regulations and guidelines for opening shop.
 What a Restaurant&amp;Bar Needs to Track Financially 
If you&apos;re in sales of any kind, you know that your product is where the money comes from, and tracking sales and production costs are an essential element in your financial success. The ultimate goal in any business is profit, and bars and restaurants are no different. In fact, when it comes to the food and beverage industry, every single drink, entree or ingredient must be tracked to prevent waste, theft or personal error to affect the financial security of the establishment and generate maximum profit.
 How to Increase Restaurant Covers 
&quot;Covers&quot; refers to the number of people who eat in a restaurant. If a restaurant has more covers, then it sells more food and consequently increases its revenue. This is crucial to pay staff and settle bills. You can increase the covers in a restaurant by implementing techniques designed to stimulate business growth. Essentially, you need to change the marketing strategy, update the menu or have a price review, to encourage more people through the door.
 Restaurant Training Games 
Though it usually doesn&apos;t require any formal education, working in a restaurant requires a significant amount of food service training. One way to enhance the training period for your staff is to incorporate restaurant training games into your instruction program. Successful restaurants nationwide use various types of restaurant training games to provide pleasant and professional instruction to new hires and improve the service skills of senior staff members.
 VeriFone 3730 Restaurant POS Instructions 
VeriFone manufactures point-of-sale, or POS, credit card machines for restaurants and businesses. The VeriFone 3730 model can process both debit and credit card transactions for a customer&apos;s meal in a restaurant. Processing a debit or credit card sale with a VeriFone 3730 varies slightly, but either transaction is still a fairly simple process. Properly charging the customer in the correct manner makes managing your electronic payments for bookkeeping purposes easy to balance.
 How to Figure Parking for Your Restaurant 
When opening a restaurant, your biggest concern is finding patrons to fill the tables. To do this, you must provide adequate parking spaces for all types of vehicles. Depending on where you operate your restaurant, your city regulations may restrict the number of parking spaces allowed on the property. The number of parking spaces is normally determined by the square footage of the restaurant building and the type of restaurant you own.
 What Is a Good Salary for a Dishwasher at a Restaurant? 
In restaurants, dishwashers are responsible for ensuring that all plates, cups, glasses, silverware and cooking utensils are kept clean and free of debris to ensure safe and sanitary food preparation and service. Most dishwashers are paid according to the current state minimum wage laws. The most recent reports by the U.S. Department of Labor Statistics indicate that in 2007, that was about $7.82 to $8.05 per hour. What would be considered a good salary for a restaurant dishwasher depends considerably on where you live.
 Restaurant Safety Inspection Checklist 
Restaurants can be accidents waiting to happen -- burns, falls, and cuts can all cause serious injury. Restaurant safety inspection checklists are a used in an effort to be proactive in preventing such accidents and cover everything from food safety to preventing falls and chemical spills. While there are various items on a safety checklist, many of which are specific to individual restaurants, some are more common than others.
 How to Get Your Restaurant Listed in Restaurant Portals 
There are more than 700,000 restaurants in the United States, according to Manta.com. California alone boasts more than 100,000. With this expanding industry, many restaurant portal Web sites have been developed to help simplify the consumer&apos;s search. However, when you search for your restaurant, you don&apos;t see it listed. Becoming listed is as easy as typing and sending an e-mail to the right person. Be aware however, that some sites require monthly payments.
 California Restaurant Laws&amp;Regulations 
California restaurant laws and regulations govern a variety of categories from the proper training of restaurant staff to wage protections for tipped employees and the sale of alcoholic beverages. These laws are in place with the goal of protecting customers to ensure food is prepared safely and alcoholic beverages are served in moderation.
 How to Overcome Negative Restaurant Reviews 
Criticism is never easy to handle, especially when you own or manage a restaurant. Negative reviews may come as a surprise if you feel your restaurant&apos;s customer service, cleanliness or food preparation is up to par. While some reviews are biased and inaccurate, many are valid. Unfortunately, the public will not always take the time to investigate whether or not an unfavorable review is true. 



Don&apos;t ignore negative reviews; they won&apos;t go away on their own. Address them promptly and take steps to prevent bad reviews from occurring in the future. Your guests are counting on you. Don&apos;t let them…
 How to Make a Layout of a Restaurant 
A restaurant layout should be inviting and functional, directing customers&apos; attention to important areas of the facility while providing ample space for servers to flow through. A successful layout requires careful arrangement and attention to detail, highlighting proper atmosphere for customers and high functionality for employees.
 How to Light a Restaurant 
The way a restaurant is lit makes a considerable difference in the ambiance and guest experience. Proper lighting is also important to ensure the safety of customers and staff. If you&apos;re a restaurant owner who wants to provide the most appropriate atmosphere and comfortable dining experience for guests and keep your employees safe and efficient, knowing how to light a restaurant can get your eatery off to a good start.
 How to Absorb Noise in a Loud Restaurant 
Dining out is a way to escape the madness of the everyday world and a noisy restaurant greatly diminishes the ability to enjoy private moments. Make your restaurant an oasis for your customers by providing a space of refuge. There are simple steps you can take to diminish and absorb noise, but the best way to do it is in the initial planning process of the restaurant. If you have an already established place, you can still take steps to reduce the noise and increase your customers&apos; enjoyment.
 How to Add a Restaurant to Delta Rewards 
Delta offers the SkyMiles Dining program through the Rewards Network as a means for its customers to earn frequent flyer miles without having to fly. Restaurants can participate in this program by signing up with the Rewards Network. The network&apos;s restaurateur program offers marketing options, a cash in-hand facility to help grow your business and detailed customer reports. It also allows customers to provide useful feedback on their dining experience. Restaurateurs can apply to join the program by telephone or by filling out an online form. A customer service representative will subsequently contact you to take you through the joining…
 Different Styles of Restaurant Tables 
A well balanced mix of table styles and sizes will minimize your guests waiting time for seating. If you are serving a fast food or pizzeria type of menu you will need less dining space per person at the table versus a three-course dinner menu. Tables for a coffee house are smaller than tables for a family dining restaurant. The floor space available in your restaurant will also need to be taken into consideration when selecting your tables. Outside dining areas will require weather-resistant furniture.
 Furniture for Bars and Restaurants 
Restaurant and bar decor varies dramatically according to the style, class, ethnicity and overall atmosphere of the establishment. Different types of eateries and watering holes require different types of furnishings. However, all drinking and eating establishments need a few basic types of furniture to comfortably and adequately accommodate their patrons. Furniture for bars and restaurants is available in vast varieties of styles to complement any decor.
 How to Get My Restaurant Booming 
Starting a restaurant can be one of the most enjoyable ways to enter the small business arena, but it can also be risky. According to a study by Michigan State University and Cornell University researchers, just about one in four new restaurants close in the first year, with about half closing after three years. New restaurants open all the time, meaning that your competition to develop a niche will be fierce. Focusing on elements such as location, pricing, marketing presence and employee management can make your restaurant a long-lasting presence in the community.
 How to Get People to Eat at Your Restaurant 
Whether you have a new restaurant or one that has been open for more than a decade, you can always benefit from gaining more customers. Many people in the restaurant business know that their success really depends on having many repeat customers. Of course, to have repeat customers, you have to figure out a way to attract new customers to your restaurant. Fortunately, you can use many effective methods to attract more customers to your restaurant.
 Restaurants at Chase Field 
Chase Field is in the heart of downtown Phoenix, Arizona, and hosts games for the Arizona Diamondbacks, a Major League baseball franchise. Before or after a Diamondbacks game, fans have access to a variety of restaurants within 10 minutes of Chase Field. The baseball season for the Diamondbacks typically runs from April through October, depending on if they play in the postseason.
 How to Find Restaurants for Sale 
Being a restaurant owner is more of a lifestyle choice than a job where you punch in and out. Many people underestimate the number of hours that need to be dedicated to operating the restaurant and overestimate the income-earning potential. However, many also find great satisfaction in being their own boss. There are thousands of restaurants for sale all over the United States, and finding one can be a relatively simple process.
 SWOT Restaurants 
A SWOT analysis is used as an informational tool and typically incorporated into corporate business plans. For example, if I was proposing to build a mall in rural Ohio, in my business plan I would cite a SWOT analysis, highlighting the plan&apos;s Strengths (S), Weaknesses (W), Opportunities (O) and Threats (T).
 Ashton Lane Restaurants 
Ashton Lane, located in the West End of Glasgow, Scotland, is famous for its selection of restaurants and cafés. It is a small, cobbled street adjacent to Byres Road, and during the 1970s was full of dilapidated commercial buildings and empty homes. By the end of the 1970s nearby restaurants began relocating to Ashton Lane, and since then it has grown into a thriving hub of restaurants, cafés and bars.
 How Can I Franchise My Restaurant? 
Franchising your restaurant is an excellent way to expand your customer base. You will be able to increase the profitability of your restaurant and widen your market without the need to acquire additional capital. Franchising can also be a great way to gain popularity for your brand. You will want to follow a few steps to create your franchise.
 How to Organize a Restaurant Storeroom 
Organizing a restaurant storeroom requires organizational skills from someone who either works with the items being stored, or who can follow an outline of which items should be stored together. Placing dry, paper goods on top of frequently used items such as sauces or mixes will only result in a constant shifting of items from on top one another. It&apos;s better to place them into two different areas. In addition, all frequently used goods should be easily accessible.
 How to Decorate a Southern-Food Restaurant 
Southern cooking often has a down-home feel to it and this type of cooking also is known as comfort food by those who love Southern cuisine. When you decorate your Southern-food restaurant, you want to use as many Southern-themed influences as possible but not go overboard with your decorations. You also can get ideas for a Southern-themed decoration by reading magazines such as &quot;Country Living,&quot; &quot;Southern Living&quot; and &quot;Better Homes and Gardens.&quot; If you have some relatives who live in the South but you live in a different region, call them and ask for suggestions.
 The Salary of a Cook or Chef in a Restaurant 
Chefs and head cooks oversee the food service operations in the kitchen of a restaurant or other food service establishment. Restaurant salaries for chefs and head cooks vary by thousands of dollars based on their location and the type of restaurant that employs them. Higher salaries also are paid to chefs and head cooks who understand the business side of restaurant operations. They&apos;re sought after by companies seeking efficient food-preparation services at reasonable costs.
 How to Become a Delta Rewards Restaurant 
SkyMiles is Delta Air Lines frequent flyer program. SkyMiles Dining is a free service in the SkyMiles program, which allows members to earn up to five miles for every $1 spent at participating restaurants. SkyMiles Dining is a member of the Rewards Network. If you own a restaurant and you would like to add your restaurant to the SkyMiles Dining program, you need to contact the Rewards Network.
 How to Decorate a Restaurant 
While the quality of the food and service in a restaurant should always be the most important factors in operating a restaurant, a large reason that many patrons visit restaurant is for the dining experience. A well decorated restaurant that speaks to the type of cuisine and intended atmosphere can make all the difference in determining whether a patron will return to the same restaurant. Regardless of your budget or design needs, decorating your restaurant should be an important concern.
 Restaurant Safety Issues 
By addressing safety issues in your restaurant quickly after you&apos;re alerted to a potential problem, you ensure the overall health and well-being of your patrons and staff. Owning a restaurant is a huge responsibility, and it&apos;s up to the employer to make sure employees are well-versed in safety protocols when on the clock.
 Supplies for a Restaurant 
Restaurants are establishments that cater to customers who order and are served food products. In full-service restaurants, patrons are waited on and eat their food while seated, and then pay after eating. In limited-service eateries such as cafeterias, fast-food restaurants, and nonalcoholic beverage bars, patrons pay at the time of ordering and there may not be table service. Running a successful restaurant requires that you have the right restaurant supplies.
 Salary Scale for Restaurants 
The salary scales for those employed in restaurants differ by occupation, which may range from chefs and head cooks, waiters, dishwashers and restaurant managers. There were approximately 4,495,350 people employed in restaurants in 2009 according to the Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS), with an average salary for all occupations of $21,970 a year.
 How to Find Out Why a Restaurant Closed Down 
Of all commercial businesses, restaurants fail more often than any other type of business. Cornell University researchers found that some 26 percent of restaurants fail in their first year of business, and the rate diminishes to 19 percent in year two and 14 percent in year three. They also found that failure rates are higher for small, independent restaurants. Financial, marketing and management issues are the reasons that cause most restaurant closures. In addition to business failure, there may be other reasons for closure, and it should not be too difficult to find out what they are.
 Restaurant Cleaning Checklist 
Restaurant owners and managers strive to keep their restaurants as clean as possible. Workers must clean numerous items daily to accomplish this. Other items on a restaurant cleaning checklist may be done less frequently, like weekly or monthly. Restaurant cleanliness is important for abiding by state health regulations and helps avoid illness and injury to employees and customers.
 Restaurant Supplies for Kids 
When opening a restaurant, purchase supplies for restaurant patrons with children. Restaurants who make the dining experience pleasant for the whole family will encourage repeat visits. Happy children also makes the dining experience more pleasant for surrounding patrons. Fussy children can be annoying to other restaurant patrons, so order supplies for your restaurant that will facilitate an enjoyable dining experience for children as well adults.
 Cost Analysis for a Restaurant 
According to &quot;Forbes&quot; magazine, restaurants are doing well if they have a five percent profit margin. While some restaurants seem expensive, the costs are often close to the revenues. When thinking about starting a restaurant, the potential owner needs to complete a cost analysis, adding up all costs and determining whether they will exceed predicted profits. If costs are higher than revenues, the restaurant should not open. If costs are lower than revenues, it is a good sign for the restaurant.
 Do I Need a Resume for a Restaurant Job? 
Because the restaurant industry allows employees to work in a social and casual atmosphere, applicants may wonder whether they need a resume to land a restaurant job. Working in a restaurant requires focus, concentration and professionalism that comes with proper training and experience. Whether you need a resume when applying for a restaurant job likely will depend on the position and type of establishment to which you apply.
 Negatives of Restaurant Staff Training 
For restaurant managers, the task of training staff presents a number of challenges. Without resolution, these challenges can impact the delivery of customer service while causing issues regarding retention and repetition of information. In addition, poor techniques used during training alienate the restaurant&apos;s core client base. To avoid this, restaurant managers must remain diligent.
 What Is the Common Wage for a Restaurant GM? 
A restaurant survives because of the people scurrying around to set the table, take orders, cook the food, bring the food and clear the table, but behind all of that work is a hidden layer of staff overseeing everything -- the restaurant general managers. GMs deal with everything from hiring to menu changes to inventory to staff disputes, all in the same fast-paced environment as their workers. Even for general managers&apos; salaries, the customer is always right.
 Subway Restaurant Scholarships 
Many companies offer scholarships to their employees to help further their educations. Subway restaurants are no different. Subway wants its employees to do better in life and be successful. As a way to help, Subway offers scholarships that people can put toward their college educations. Following all the rules and being aware of the requirements could help you raise a little money for school.
 Restaurant Pest Analysis 
A PEST analysis is a business tool that can help determine the macroeconomic factors that will impact a business. Specifically a PEST analysis measures the political, economic, social and technological factors that impact a business. A PEST analysis of a restaurant can be useful for determining if the environment is appropriate for such a business.
 The Cons of Smoking Bans in Restaurants 
Nonsmokers may see a restaurant smoking ban as a positive step that protects the rights of people who want to eat out without suffering the smell and health hazards of secondhand smoke. Yet many people, nonsmokers among them, object to these bans. In many localities the local government has become involved in deciding whether to issue a smoking ban in area restaurants.
 How to Create a Restaurant Blueprint 
A restaurant blueprint has to meet several different types of criteria, including zoning laws for the town the restaurant will be in. The design also has to turn a profit for the restaurant owner, meet the needs of the restaurant&apos;s employees and provide a pleasant atmosphere for patrons. Making the design is thus a tall order, but you can hurdle it by studying existing restaurant plans and getting an objective view of your plan. The primary benefit of a successful blueprint is the personal satisfaction from seeing the profitable restaurant built from your plan.
 Compost Recycling in Restaurants 
According to the Los Angeles Bureau of Sanitation, more than three-quarters of the average restaurant&apos;s trash is compostable. Instead of throwing away vegetable and fruit trimmings, many restaurants are saving this organic waste to be turned into nutrient-rich compost. This compost is recycled back into the earth as a soil amendment and fertilizer for agricultural and landscape purposes such as farms, golf courses and community food gardens. It&apos;s no wonder many restaurants and communities are getting interested in compost recycling.
 Restaurants in&amp;Around Woodstock, Vermont 
Chartered in the 1700s, the village of Woodstock is the capital of Windsor County, Vermont. The village is known for the Taste of Woodstock event and the Woodstock Art Festival. The Woodstock Farmers&apos; Market is open year-round and offers a wide selection of food. Should you wish for alternative dining, Woodstock and its environs are not short on options.
 How to Clean Restaurant Booths 
An important part of running a restaurant is keeping it clean. Just as you need to maintain a clean cooking environment, your dining area should be spotless in order to entice customers to return. The easiest way to keep your restaurant clean is to teach your employees your expectations and methods for achieving a clean restaurant. In the dining area, this should focus on the tables, chairs and booths where customers are most likely to inspect their surroundings. All are cleaned the same way, and because vinyl is often used to make the bench seating in booths, expect cleaning to…
 The Average Salary for Restaurant Jobs in Anchorage, Alaska 
The Alaska Department of Labor and Workforce Development estimates that the need for workers in restaurants statewide will increase by 6 to 9 percent from 2008 through 2018. This growth will create more than 1,300 jobs statewide during that time frame, with the majority of jobs created in large cities like Anchorage. Average annual salaries for restaurant workers in Anchorage vary based upon job duties.
 Restaurants in and around Salix, IA 
Salix, Iowa is a small town in the western portion of the state located within Woodbury County. The population of the city is under 1,000 people and is only a few blocks long, totaling less than one square mile. A town of this size doesn&apos;t have many eatery options. In fact, there is just one restaurant in the town. Salix, however, is sandwiched between two cities with plenty of eatery options, Sergeants Bluff and Sloan, Iowa.
 Information on Financing a Restaurant 
Furnishing and opening a restaurant can be expensive. You will most likely need an outside source of funding to make ends meet while you outfit your operation, advertise its opening and staff it until it begins making a profit. The process of financing a new restaurant involves realistically assessing how much money you will need, and then convincing a lender to advance the funds.
 How to Compare the Usage of Styrofoam Paper Boxes in Restaurants 
Eating on the run depends upon the food packaging. Polystyrene containers --- nicknamed Styrofoam, a trademarked material made by Dow Chemical Corp. --- hold in heat. Common styles help consumers determine how to compare the usage of Styrofoam and paper boxes in restaurants.
 Most Common Restaurant Cleaning Concerns 
Hungry patrons eat out at restaurants each day. Cleaning up after customers and staff require a keen eye, diligence and knowing what to scrub. You always want to clean the entire restaurant from floor to ceiling, but some areas require extra attention. The most common cleaning concerns any restaurant has are the washcloths, potential food contamination, grease trap and kitchen ventilation unit.
 How to Find the Names of the Individual Members of the Massachusetts Restaurant Association 
The Massachusetts Restaurant Association is a non-for-profit trade association for food and beverage businesses across the Commonwealth. Both large and small businesses belong and the membership includes the industries that supply restaurants with everything from equipment to provisions. Finding individual members by name can be accomplished by searching the association&apos;s website to attending a trade show.
 Manheim Township&apos;s Outdoor Table Regulations for Restaurants 
While Manheim Township, Pennsylvania&apos;s code of ordinances does not directly address whether or not restaurants in the township may have outdoor tables, it does contain guidelines relevant to restaurant owners considering placing tables outside.
 The Average Salary of a Four-Star Restaurant Chef 
With the trend of chefs becoming celebrities, it seems likely that chefs would make celebrity-like salaries. But while it&apos;s true that chefs with their own restaurants, shows and books can make a lot of money, that is not the case with most chefs, even those who work for four-star restaurants.
 How to Conduct a Feasibility Study for a New Restaurant 
The majority of new restaurants opened by first-time operators fail within the first year. Even established chain restaurant companies sometimes open new locations that fail. The basic tool for determining the market potential of a proposed restaurant is a thorough feasibility study, also known as a market study. The University of Wisconsin (UW) offers extensive advice and resources for anyone looking at starting a new restaurant, noting, among other things, that a successful feasibility study requires extensive research and analysis, not a superficial glance based on wishful thinking.
 Restaurants in Clearwater, FL 
Clearwater, Florida was named by Native Americans for its abundance of fresh springs along the ocean shoreline. As early as the 1890s, Clearwater had established its reputation as a resort and vacation community. Located near two international airports, Clearwater is an easy-to-access travel destination. Hungry travelers can find many restaurants in Clearwater, with meal options ranging from seafood specialties to Eggs Benedict.
 Romantic Patio Restaurants in Dallas, Texas 
Dallas, Texas is home to many restaurants that offer a variety of cuisines. If you seek a patio restaurant in Dallas, there are a number of options, and with minor exceptions, the weather will usually cooperate for you to eat outside. With decor that includes outdoor sculpture, art, manicured shrubbery, exotic plants, ambient lighting and candles, consider visiting one of many Dallas eateries that provide the perfect backdrop for a romantic dinner.
 How to Support Local Restaurants 
Local restaurant patronage supports local economies in multiple ways, with the majority of restaurant expenditures being spent in the business owners&apos; communities. Chain restaurants, by comparison, funnel the majority of their profits back to an out-of-town corporate headquarters, and have national contracts for supplies, goods, services and advertising. 



Becoming a regular patron at local restaurants also supports and celebrates unique, personalized culinary expressions, which may be steeped in local traditions, rather than supporting homogenized and mass-produced chain outlet fare. Here&apos;s how to support the local restaurant owners who have a vested interest in the communities they live and work in.
 OSHA Restaurant Lighting Levels 
The Occupational Health and Safety Administration (OSHA) sets guidelines for workplace safety. Specific lighting requirements do not address restaurants in particular, but general OSHA rules regarding safe and healthy work environments apply.
 How to Decorate an Indian Restaurant 
While the menu and cuisine are the most important choices when opening an Indian restaurant, the ambiance you create with the restaurant&apos;s decor will also contribute to your success. Because Indian cuisine covers a wide geographical and chronological area, you may wish to focus on a particular region or even a particular era of Indian history when selecting artwork, colors and uniforms. Strive for authenticity in your decor and avoid cheap cliches that your guests might find offensive or disrespectful.
 Restaurant Safety Tips 
Restaurants must follow basic safety principles for the health of their employees and customers. Some of these safety rules are well known, however, some of these measures are not as well known but are still critical to ensuring a safe eating and working environment.
 How to Install a Restaurant Ventilation Hood 
All restaurants, from commercial chain restaurants to family-owned walk-in diners, implement measures to manage airflow better. Commercial kitchen ventilation systems circulate air in and out of cooking areas. Commercial kitchens require proper ventilation of high air volumes in restricted spaces, which presents a challenge when choosing a location, installing the ventilation hood and connecting the duct-work. CaptiveAire, the nation&apos;s leading manufacturer of commercial ventilation systems, offers a wide array of designs hoods perfected for commercial kitchen layouts.
 How to Clean Out Restaurant Exhaust 
By law, restaurants must have an exhaust hood over stovetops and fryers to remove dust and smoke. These exhaust hoods become dirty and must be cleaned a few times a year. If they&apos;re not cleaned, dirt can build up and lead to mold and bacteria problems. Cleaning the hoods is also necessary to avoid kitchen fires. Cleaning the hood and attached duct work is easier to do after business hours because it requires shutting down cooking equipment.
 Reasons for Cleaning a Restaurant 
Operating a restaurant is a never-ending job, with certain tasks repeated daily or weekly. One continual chore is cleaning. Even if you leave the restaurant pristine, it requires thorough cleaning after the next day of business. While not all restaurants clean as well as they should, there are three major reasons to clean, which might encourage a restaurant manager to apply a bit more effort to the chore of cleaning.
 Restaurant Regulations in the State of Oklahoma 
The State Department of Health is responsible for restaurant regulations in Oklahoma. These regulations govern all aspects of opening and running a food business, from inspections to employee hygiene. They are intended to maintain high standards and protect public health.
 How to Install a Restaurant Hood 
One of the most important safety features in any restaurant kitchen is the fume hood. This device rests above the commotion and gives fumes and smoke a way to evacuate. This helps keep the kitchen area from being clouded with smog during busy restaurant hours, which can leave a film on clean utensils, glasses and plates. The flow of oxygen also helps keep fresh air in the restaurant and helps decrease the chance of kitchen fires.
 Gratuity Laws for Florida Restaurants 
Running any business means navigating a web of local, state and federal laws. For restaurateurs, some of these laws involve gratuities. Thankfully for Florida restaurant owners, the state has only a few laws for the business owner.
 What Is the Salary for a Restaurant Chef? 
Working as a chef in a restaurant is an exciting, creative career path that also requires hard work and discipline. The salary a potential restaurant chef can expect to earn will vary depending on his education, experience and skill level, as well as the type of restaurant that employs him and its location.
 What License Do You Need to Own&amp;Operate a Restaurant? 
Starting a business requires the completion of a great deal of paperwork. Some of this paperwork will satisfy application requirements for certain licenses and permits you need to legally operate a food and/or beverage establishment.
 Elements of a Good Receiving System in a Restaurant 
One aspect of running a restaurant that sometimes takes a back seat to more pressing matters is the process for receiving shipments from various vendors. Mistakes, carelessness and inefficient practices in this process alone can make the difference between a thriving restaurant and one that soon will be out of business.
 Breakfast Restaurant Features 
Breakfast is a growing market for restaurants, with the National Restaurant Association reporting that 21 percent of people over 18 eat out for breakfast at least once a week. If you&apos;re thinking of starting a breakfast restaurant or are looking for ideas for your current restaurant&apos;s breakfast menu, there are a few things to consider that may help drive new customers into your establishment.
 Growing Restaurant Chains 
Whether you&apos;re the CEO of an already established restaurant chain, or the nervous first-time owner of a start-up cafe, odds are you share the same vision: you want to have as much success as possible. Stagnancy is not an option; growth is vital. In fact, the same could be said of virtually any business owner, much less a restaurateur. However, in food service, there are a few simple yet crucial steps to take to avoid having your place of business becoming a laundromat that &quot;used to be that so-and-so&quot; eatery.
 Restaurant Investment Information 
While restaurants are considered a high-risk venture, being well informed about your options and preparing carefully can help minimize that risk. There are two main strategies for opening a restaurant for investment.
 How do I Find Financing to Purchase a Restaurant? 
A restaurant represents one of the most difficult businesses for which to obtain financing from a bank. Generally, a bank sees a restaurant as a significantly volatile investment and may ask you to put up personal collateral valued at up to the entire loan amount. Creative and alternative methods of financing do exist however.
 Dinnerware for Restaurants 
Choosing dinnerware for your restaurant is an important decision. The right set can heighten your customers&apos; experience and set the ambiance for your restaurant. Because restaurant dinnerware experiences so much use, durability is a vital factor in your choice. Cost is also a factor, since not only is dinnerware a large expenditure when starting a restaurant, but dishes break and will need to be replaced. Finding a supplier who can meet your financial, practical and aesthetic needs is crucial.
 How to Clean Restaurant Soda Machines 
Researchers at Hollins University in Virginia, have discovered that drinking beverages made from soda fountain machines could contribute to episodic gastric distress. Tests conducted on both self-service and personnel assisted soda machines showed a level of bacteria, including coliform, not allowed in municipal water. A follow up article in Food Safety News suggest the bacteria lies in the tubing of the machine. Regular monthly cleaning of the tubes along with daily cleaning of the nozzles should guard against bacteria.
 Restaurant Daypart Trends 
A daypart is a specific segment of the day. Restaurants have traditionally served breakfast, lunch and dinner at different times of the day and these form distinct dayparts. Market research on consumer behavior during these different mealtime segments helps restaurants better market their offerings. Such research has discerned some trends relating to restaurant dayparts.
 Kosher Restaurants in Hartford, Connecticut 
Finding a kosher meal in and around Hartford, Conn. can be literally as close as the local grocery store. There are a range of options, including a deli that&apos;s been in West Hartford for more than 70 years, a community cafeteria and a cafe located inside the local grocery store.
 Nice Restaurants in Southfield, Michigan 
Southfield, Michigan, is a major commercial center in the Detroit metropolitan area. The Lear Corporation, Sumitomo and Electronic Data Systems all have offices in Southfield. The Southfield Town Center, a collection of five skyscrapers, houses City Hall, a Westin hotel and a 1,000-person conference center. Visitors to Southfield can also take in area attraction like Detroit Tigers baseball games, the zoo and casinos. Southfield has its share of pleasant places to eat, and hungry residents and guests to the city can find a variety of cuisines.
 Restaurant Leasehold Improvements 
Leasehold improvements are investments that are made in a business&apos;s property that add to its value. They are permanent improvements that are not easily removed, such as renovations performed on a physical building.
 Concepts of a Soup Restaurant 
Americans consume more than 10 billion bowls of soup each year, according to the Campbell Soup Company. &quot;Soupreneurs&quot; aim to cash in on our love affair with this versatile food.
 How to Find Investors in Michigan for Restaurants 
Finding investors is not an easy task--especially in places like Michigan, which has been hit hard by several economic downturns after 2000. As of August, 2010, Michigan&apos;s unemployment rate was one of the highest in the nation, at 13.1 percent. Despite these challenges, Michigan has a strong working-class, entrepreneurial population, which is giving rise to many new restaurants. For those looking to open a new restaurant in Michigan, there are several viable options for financing your business.
 American Chain Restaurants in Israel 
A number of American chain restaurants have locations in Israel. Many restaurants follow kosher dietary guidelines, such as no pork products and no cheese served with meat (for example, no bacon cheeseburgers or sausage pizzas). However, some restaurants--possibly recognizing the international population of cities like Tel Aviv and Jerusalem--do offer non-kosher options like cheeseburgers. Some serve both kosher and non-kosher items but from separate counters or booths. Many chain restaurants close on Shabbat, from Friday evening to Saturday morning.
 Star Restaurants in Minneapolis, Minnesota 
The Twin Cities of Minneapolis and St. Paul have a number of fine dining restaurants offering everything from steak to lobster to sushi. Minneapolis features star restaurants to tempt people, whether they are attending a sporting event, visiting the Minnesota Opera or just enjoying a night on the town. The city of Minneapolis offers the best cuisine from Germany, Sweden, Poland, Mexico, Italy and America as well as meals delivered straight from the farm to the table.
 Can a Restaurant Force You to Work in the Smoking Section? 
Refusing to work in a restaurant smoking section is becoming less of an issue as most states have adopted nonsmoking laws. The last holdouts are private clubs and casinos, and smoking remains an issue to people who work in these establishments.
 How do I Obtain Financing for a New Restaurant? 
New restaurant owners buy establishments in a number of different ways, but most do not use their own cash to make their entrepreneurial dreams a reality. The majority of restaurants owners just can&apos;t afford to come up with hundreds of thousands of dollars on their own to fund the costs for a restaurant purchase, advertising expenses and employee salaries. However, if you know how to find a loan, you can open a new restaurant and pay back the money you owe over a period of years.
 Restaurants That Deliver in Tampa, Florida 
Like most big cities, Tampa, Florida, boasts a wide selection of restaurants offering free or cheap home delivery. Whether ordering pizza, Greek food, Indian food or many others, buyers have a variety of foods from which to choose. Most restaurants have menus accessible online. Some offer the ability to order online, although most utilize the traditional telephone method. Delivery times and locations vary based on restaurant policy and location.
 Payroll Software for Restaurants 
Restaurants deal with new employees, tips, payouts and other challenges that requires payroll software designed specifically to manage these types of challenges. The high number of restaurants around the world has spawned a market for restaurant-specific payroll software. Programs commonly offer free trial downloads, which you should use to ensure the software meets your needs.
 Restaurant Training Benefits 
A well-trained staff can make the difference between a successful restaurant and a total failure. Your employees are in charge of every aspect of running your restaurant, from creating the food to cleaning the kitchen. Whether they&apos;re interacting with customers or using expensive equipment, make sure that they&apos;re trained to do things the correct way.
 Appliances for Restaurants 
According to the Food Service Warehouse, it is important for new restaurant owners to carefully evaluate their menus to determine their kitchen equipment needs. When starting out, it is important to limit the equipment needed. Prospective restaurant owners should determine the fewest number of appliances needed to produce all of the dishes on a menu and alter the menu if needed to keep the amount of equipment relatively low. By keeping an equipment list restricted to basic necessities, restaurant owners can start small and add needed items later. Employee training requirements, start up costs and equipment maintenance should be quite…
 How to Make Restaurant Flyers 
Flyers can be a cost-effective way to easily promote your restaurant. Use flyers to introduce your restaurant to the public for the first time, promote specials or new items, or advertise a take-out or delivery menu. Remember that your flyer could be someone&apos;s first impression of your business. Design your flyer to be easy to read, easy to understand and focused, so that prospective patrons can make quick use of it.
 How to Paint Restaurant Interiors 
Whether you are opening a new restaurant or simply want to improve your eating establishment, painting the interior can make all the difference. Creating the right mood for your restaurant involves careful consideration of your target customers, color themes, furniture and the types of cuisine you serve. Diners will remember a restaurant’s atmosphere more than the food, reports Michigan State University. Paint the interior walls to make your restaurant a place customers will return to again and again.
 Restaurant Lighting Tips 
Lighting can have a powerful effect on an interior; this is especially true when it comes to restaurants. Lighting can help set the restaurant&apos;s mood and atmosphere; however, the type of ambiance you want to aim for must be determined by the type of restaurant and the meals served.
 Email Promotions for Restaurants 
Communicating via email is a major part of many restaurants’promotional and marketing campaigns. From major chains to the little guy down the street, eateries offer incentives via email including coupons, discount clubs and weekly specials to loyal customers as incentives for continued patronage and new prospects to gain market share. Strategies used by restaurants are as varied as the type of food served and the type of patron walking through the door.
 How to Value a Restaurant for Sale 
Getting an accurate value for a restaurant for sale is usually the most challenging part of the business purchase process. To value a restaurant for sale is often more like an art rather than a science. There are many established methods that estimate a restaurant’s value but it always depends on the specific situation. Some of the methods include asset valuations, liquidation value, income capitalization, income multiple and comparing prices of similar restaurants. Although not perfect, income multiple seems to be the most effective method for valuing a restaurant for sale.
 Restaurant Host Training 
A restaurant host is the first person the customer interacts with when he enters the restaurant. A host is responsible for making a positive first impression that leaves a customer feeling satisfied with his experience. Her duties normally include customer service, reservations and general supervision of the entire dining room to make sure customers enjoy their experience. Because a restaurant host job can be busy and stressful, proper training is a necessity.
 Restaurant Startup Checklist 
Starting a restaurant can be a challenging but very rewarding and profitable endeavor. There is always room in the industry for another restaurant, especially those that specialize in ethnic or health-conscious cuisine. While restaurants are cited as having a high failure rate, ensuring your restaurant is equipped with all that it needs to thrive will help it succeed.
 Tools for Restaurant Hood Cleaning 
Restaurant exhaust hoods are a necessary, legally regulated part of a professional kitchen. They vent directly to the outside, and help remove a lot of fumes and pollutants from a kitchen. Over time, restaurant hoods become caked with grease and grime and dirt and need to be cleaned. Restaurants will often hire a professional to clean their exhaust hoods. It is possible to do the job yourself if you have the proper tools.
 Restaurant Cooking Appliances 
Restaurant kitchens have appliances similar to those found in the majority of home kitchens, but larger and durable enough to crank out hundreds of meals a day. Professionals do use some appliances, particularly the small wares variety, in the same way home cooks do. The types of appliances found in the restaurant kitchen depend on the style and quantity of food made.
 Fire Safety Tips for Restaurants 
Each year, thousands of businesses literally &quot;go up in flames.&quot; Fires can break a business, causing it to close its doors. Restaurants have additional risks because of the nature of cooking. Kitchens have numerous pieces of cooking equipment such as grills, ovens, stove top burners, and fryers that can cause fires; however, cooking mishaps are not the only way that fires are started--structural issues like faulty wiring can cause a fire. Establishing safety measures is vital in decreasing the chances of fire at a restaurant.
 Restaurant Kitchen Cleaning Checklist 
Restaurant kitchens must be completely cleaned every night. Whether you have an experienced staff or a novice crew, kitchen cleaning is more efficient if you post a list of nightly duties. A list of expected cleaning jobs ensures team members will thoroughly clean all areas without forgetting anything. Your list also can help eliminate health hazards due to food spoilage on surfaces.
 How to Find Restaurant Investors 
Finding an investor for a new restaurant can be a daunting task. Persuading friends, family or strangers to lend you money will be much easier with a business plan that covers all aspects of your proposed venture. If your plan has been thoughtfully researched and includes market demographics, business strategy, marketing plans and realistic financial budgets and projections, it will go a lot further toward securing investors than just pitching an idea.
 How to Become PCI Compliant for a Restaurant 
PCI stands for payment card industry. PCI sets security standards in restaurants and other businesses concerning the processing of credit or debit card information. QSR Magazine reports that while PCI compliance can be a difficult measure to implement at first, it saves restaurant owners from dealing with legal action resulting from compromised credit cards.
 Restaurant Safety Regulations 
Restaurants have a strict set of regulations to which they must abide. These regulations cover the attire and appearance of employees, the cleanliness practices for the facility, the storage of certain types of food such as meat and the safety of the facility. If these regulation are violated, it would pose a serious health and safety risk for both customers and employees. In addition, safety regulations allow restaurants to operate more efficiently. Health inspections occur regularly to ensure compliance with regulations.
 American Food Restaurants in Pittsburgh 
Pittsburgh is a large and diverse city, with places to engage in outdoor activities such as hiking, camping and backpacking or view world-class architecture, museums and performing arts. Visitors can also see professional baseball, football and hockey games. Pittsburgh has almost any kind of restaurant you can imagine, including several which do not employ exotic ingredients or imported spices -- they just make simple, classic American food.
 How to Clean a Restaurant Hood 
Range hoods use a filter to collect pollutants that naturally occur while cooking, including steam, smoke and grease. Daily use of the range will cause an abundance of dirt and grease that may become caked on to the range hood. This dirt and grease can cause an unsightly and unsanitary kitchen environment. Cleaning range hoods is a relatively easy process. However, to keep the build-up of grease to a minimum, regularly wipe the range hood with a damp, soapy cloth.
 Japanese Restaurants in St. Louis, Missouri 
St. Louis is often called the Gateway to the West, and its most recognizable landmark is the enormous Gateway Arch, which is the largest human-made monument in the world. St. Louis has a diverse population and regularly holds festivals celebrating a variety of different cultures. It should come as no surprise that there are a number of Japanese restaurants in St. Louis, with both authentic and creative cuisine.
 Brazilian Restaurants in Tampa Bay, Florida 
The Tampa Bay area in Florida is known for its tourist attractions, including a number of fantastic restaurants from which to choose. If it&apos;s Brazilian that you&apos;re after, you&apos;ll have no trouble finding it in Tampa Bay. There are several restaurants serving authentic Brazilian cuisine in a variety of styles, including steakhouses and Brazilian-American fusion.
 Vietnamese Restaurants in Cleveland, OH 
Vietnamese cuisine is a delicacy that is not always easy to come by in the Western hemisphere. However, those addicted to its distinctive sauce and spice-infused flavors, and its signature offerings such as pho, will go far and wide to track it down. Luckily, for those living in or visiting Cleveland, Ohio, finding a suitable Vietnamese restaurant should be no problem.
 How to Develop a Restaurant Franchise 
A successful restaurant franchise offers a menu with universal appeal using systems that are easy to replicate with high odds of success. Developing a restaurant franchise starts with learning to see the restaurant itself as a product to sell to potential franchisees. The restaurant business tends to involve arduous work and slim profit margins. A restaurant franchise that can help a fledgling entrepreneur beat the difficult odds can be a profitable investment for both franchiser and franchisee.
 Chinese Restaurants Near Lawrenceburg, Kentucky 
Brimming with small-town appeal, Lawrenceburg sits in the middle of Kentucky and offers more dining opportunities than one might expect at first glance. Two Chinese restaurants lie within Lawrenceburg&apos;s city limits, and a third is just a 30-minute drive from town. While visiting or staying in Lawrenceburg, you should check out the Lover&apos;s Leap Winery and Vineyard, as well as the Anderson County History Museum.
 Breakfast Restaurants In Plainwell, Michigan 
Plainwell, Michigan is a small town of 4,500 in southwest Michigan, located midway between Chicago and Detroit. Just 15 minutes north of Kalamazoo and 40 minutes south of Grand Rapids, Plainwell is a small town with all the amenities of metropolitan living nearby. Plainwell is often referred to as &quot;The Island City&quot; as it is surrounded by the Kalamazoo River.
 Italian Restaurants in Dover, Kent 
Dover is a beautiful town in South East England that attracts tourists through the year. Dover offers numerous cultural and recreational attractions and is home to two museums, the Dover Museum and the Dover Transportation Museum. Other points of interest include The Vista Leisure Centre, the famous white cliffs of Dover, the Port of Dover, Dover Castle, St Edmond&apos;s Chapel, Cowgate Nature Reserve and Connaught Park. There are many dining options in Dover as well, including several Italian restaurants.
 Chinese Restaurants in Hendersonville, Tennessee 
Hendersonville is a city in Tennessee that offers many local attractions and a small town feel. Since Hendersonville is located less than 20 miles from Nashville, it is possible to check out that larger city for a day trip. While in Hendersonville, you may want to visit the local skating rink, the Death Valley Haunted Woods and the Historic Rock Castle. There are many dining options, including several Chinese restaurants, to refuel after a day of exploring this quaint little city.
 Restaurants and Diners in Downtown Atlanta 
Atlanta is the largest city in Georgia and has a lot to offer in terms of activities and attractions. There are the sports teams to check out, including the Atlanta Falcons (NFL), Braves (MLB), Thrashers (NHL) and Hawks (NBA), and there are plenty of other fun things to do while in the city. This includes visiting the Alliance Theater, one of the largest regional theaters in the United States, the Atlanta Botanical Garden, the Atlanta Opera and Atlanta Symphony Orchestra. There are also plenty of great little restaurants and diners in Atlanta where you can refuel after a long day…
 Restaurants in Egg Harbor Township, New Jersey 
Egg Harbor Township, New Jersey, is a typically quaint New Jersey township along the road to Atlantic City and close to the Richard Stockton College of New Jersey. This small town has a variety of restaurants to visit whether you need to get out of the dorms, away from the bright city lights, or are simply on your way somewhere else.
 Brazilian Restaurants in Austin, TX 
Austin is the capital of Texas. It&apos;s a unique and diverse city, home to the University of Texas, the Austin Museum of Art, the Texas Natural Science Center and Mexic-Arte Museum. Austin also has a thriving music scene and likes to bill itself as &quot;The Live Music Capital of the World.&quot; You can find many kinds of cuisine in Austin, including some creative and authentic Brazilian food restaurants.
 Brazilian Restaurants in Dallas, Texas 
Dallas, Texas has a great deal more to offer than football, cowboys and rodeo. The city is the home of the Texas Ballet Theater, the Dallas Symphony Orchestra and the Dallas Museum of Art. Much of the local economy depends on high-tech industries, and the area has a diverse and international population. You can find almost any kind of food you would like in Dallas, including several Brazilian restaurants. Whether you prefer a cafe, a steakhouse, or an interesting bit of fusion, Dallas has it.
 Italian Restaurants in Downtown Houston, Texas 
Houston is not only the largest city in the state of Texas, it&apos;s the largest city in the entire Southern United States. It is the home to numerous high-tech companies, and also many foreign banks and consulates, including those of China, Japan, South Korea, Brazil and Mexico. Houston&apos;s population is quite diverse and international, and as a result, visitors and local can find almost any kind of food they could ever want somewhere in the city. There are many creative and authentic Italian restaurants in Houston, several located in the downtown area.
 Restaurants in the West Village Neighborhood of Dallas, Texas 
The West Village neighborhood is an affluent area of downtown Dallas. The West Village tries to upgrade Dallas&apos;s image from one of a conservative, cowboy-filled outback to that of a more progressive, hip, urban center. It&apos;s filled with independent and creative shops, theaters, clubs and restaurants. You can get many types of food, prepared in many ways in the West Village, and almost everything will come with an interesting new twist.
 German Restaurants in Long Island, NY 
Long Island, located in southeast New York, has welcomed many immigrants over the last century and consequently claims quite a diverse population. You can get almost any kind of ethnic cuisine on Long Island, including authentic and creative German food.
 Chinese Restaurants in Denton, Texas 
Denton is a college town located between Dallas and the southern Oklahoma border. Denton is the home to the University of North Texas, a school famous for its excellent Music department, and Texas Woman&apos;s University, which has one of the largest doctoral nursing programs in the world. Many of the residents of Denton are students, and the community is large and diverse. There are a number of restaurants serving hungry and cost-conscious students in Denton, and Chinese food is a perennial favorite.
 Restaurant Supervisor Duties 
Restaurant supervisors have a wide range of responsibilities in day-to-day operations, managing everything from food ordering to employee schedules. It is a fast-paced job and one the requires a wide variety of skills and knowledge. A restaurant supervisor could be planning a sophisticated menu one minute and helping to resolve a simmering dispute between employees another. Besides an extensive knowledge and experience with food, these managers must be organized and capable of handling complex logistics. A knowledge of accounting or the basics of money management is helpful as well, as restaurant supervisors may be required to help monitor the weekly…
 Cajun Restaurants in Arlington, Texas 
Arlington, Texas sits in the center of the sprawling Dallas-Fort Worth Metroplex. Arlington is not just a suburb of Fort Worth, however. The city has its own university, the University of Texas at Arlington, attractions, such as original Six Flags amusement park, and is the home to both the Texas Ranger baseball team and the new Dallas Cowboys stadium. Visitors can get almost any kind of food they want in Arlington, so it should come as no surprise that there are several Cajun restaurants in the city.
 Chinese Restaurants in Richardson, Texas 
Richardson is an affluent North Texas suburb near Dallas. It offers easy access to all the attractions of Big D while still developing its own reputation as a major home of telecommunications companies. Its large size and affluence, along with the overall diversity of North Texas, makes it a haven for numerous kinds of quality restaurants, including many Chinese.
 Chinese Restaurants in North Olmsted, Ohio 
North Olmsted, Ohio, is a western suburb of Cleveland, Ohio. The city of approximately 34,000 is located between interstates I-80 and I-480. The heart of the city centers around Lorain Road, which travels the length of the city east and west. Most businesses in North Olmsted are located on or within a block or two of Lorain Road, which results in a commercial center to an otherwise residential city. There are only a few Chinese Restaurants in North Olmsted, and each is located near Lorain Road.
 Irish Restaurants in Jax, Florida 
Jacksonville is the largest city in Florida, the largest city in area in the continental U.S., and home to the NFL team the Jacksonville Jaguars. It&apos;s a rapidly-growing metropolis due to its business incentives, warm climate and reasonable cost of living. Jacksonville not only emphasizes sports but also supports beaches, parks, and a symphony orchestra. The city also hosts many specialty restaurants, including several authentic Irish pubs and restaurants.
 Japanese Restaurants in Clearwater, Florida 
Clearwater is known for its warm climate and proximity to many activities and attractions, including Busch Gardens, the Tampa Bay Performing Arts Center, and the Florida Botanical Gardens. Clearwater is also the home of several high-quality Japanese restaurants, featuring chefs with decades of experience and both traditional and new Japanese cuisines.
 How to Install a Restaurant Vent Hood 
Starting a new restaurant involves bringing an older restaurant or other building to the specifications you need for your own restaurant. At the cooking range, you will need a vent hood, also called an exhaust hood. You can actually install the hood yourself fairly easily. Before installing the vent hood, check the sturdiness of the area on the wall where the vent will be fixed. If not sturdy enough, the hood might shift or the wall might give. If the location is faulty, the area around the vent will deteriorate.
 How to Install a Restaurant Exhaust Hood 
Installing an exhaust hood is one of the chief ways of outfitting a kitchen for restaurant use. It involves opening your wall to receive the hood&apos;s wiring and then fastening it in place. You will probably find putting the hood in place yourself a simple enough task. The hood should clear the stovetop by at least 25 inches.
 Vegan Restaurants in St. Petersburg, Florida 
There are several different reasons why someone may choose a vegan diet. Vegans eat no animal products of any kind, so many vegans choose it to not contribute to animal cruelty. Other people do it for health reasons. Some are vegan as part of an overall plan to eat and live in more environmentally-friendly ways. Regardless of the reason, vegans often have a hard time finding places to eat. There are several restaurants for vegans and vegetarians in the St. Petersburg area, however.
 Cafe Restaurant Systems and Procedures 
Cafe restaurant systems and procedures should provide a comfortable and enjoyable experience for customers in the restaurant, or the front of the house, and they also should ensure that the kitchen, or back of the house, operates efficiently enough for customers to receive appealing food in a timely fashion. In addition, there should be systems and procedures in place for enabling the front of the house to communicate effectively with the back of the house in order to provide patrons with an optimum dining experience.
 Phoenix Vegan Restaurants 
Veganism is not simply vegetarianism. While vegetarians eat no meat, vegans eat no animal products of any kind, including milk, yogurt or cheese. This can make finding a place for a nice meal out on the town difficult. If you are a vegan or wanna-be vegan living in the warm climate of Phoenix, Arizona, or just want to try some tasty vegan food, there are several local restaurants where you can find animal-free dishes.
 How to Find a Local Delivery Restaurant 
Restaurant delivery options are no longer limited to pizza and Chinese food. A few simple methods can help you track down a local delivery restaurant.
 Vegan Restaurants in Orange County, California 
Vegans often have a difficult time finding suitable restaurants. Vegans are not only vegetarians, but eat no animal products of any kind, so even foods common in vegetarian dishes, such as butter, cream, eggs, and honey, are off-limits. However, if you live in Orange County, Calif., you are fortunate. There are several high-quality restaurants near you that have completely 100 percent vegan menus.
 Regulations for Outdoor Restaurant Seating 
While the addition of outdoor seating may seem merely an extension of the existing restaurant, a special permit or license will most likely be required to operate the outside space. Local laws place separate requirements on outdoor restaurant seating.
 Restaurant Signage Options 
A sign is an important and effective way to call attention to your restaurant. It&apos;s also a tool for conveying information about your restaurant&apos;s ambiance (e.g., using a colorful sign for a restaurant with a party atmosphere or a wooden sign for a rustic restaurant). In addition to a sign bearing your restaurant&apos;s name, every restaurant should have an &quot;open&quot; sign to clearly communicate when it&apos;s open for business.
 How to Grow Fresh Vegetables for Restaurants 
Learning to grow fresh vegetables for restaurants is a great way to make some extra money and contribute to a local food movement. Restaurants are using fresh, local ingredients more than ever. Using locally grown produce not only results in delicious cuisine but also creates a sense of community pride. If you already grow vegetables, or simply have a green thumb and some extra space, start your own vegetable farm. Growing vegetables for restaurants requires commitment to quality, time and a little hard work.
 What Are the Benefits of Restaurant Staff Training? 
Properly training your restaurant staff is crucial to providing a great experience for employees, customers and yourself as a business owner. Training can take various forms. It can be done in a conference setting, with new hires reading employee manuals, or by on-the-job shadowing of established employees.
 How to Price a Restaurant for Sale 
Selling a restaurant can be a tricky process because so many of the variables that give a restaurant value are intangible and difficult to quantify, such as reputation, customer satisfaction and ease of operation. Fortunately, there are some concrete benchmarks you can use to establish the price of a restaurant. Once you calculate a value based on these hard numbers, you can adjust the price higher -- or potential buyers may try to adjust it lower -- by referring to the intangibles that increase or lessen its value.
 How to Create Unique Tabletop Displays in Your Restaurant 
Beautiful, interesting and memorable design is crucial to a restaurant&apos;s success. Restaurant reviews generally make some mention of atmosphere and how restaurants look. Furnishings, color and good design are all important in creating a beautiful restaurant. One area sometimes overlooked is the restaurant tabletop. Restaurant tabletops offer owners a prime opportunity to personalize the dining experience for their guests. Tables become private places for patrons to enjoy the surroundings; a unique tabletop can enhance the dining experience and make it even more memorable.
 How to Obtain Financing for an Established Restaurant 
Even if you own an established restaurant, it can be difficult to obtain financing for expansion and day-to-day operations during slow periods. Although it is certainly easier for an established restaurant to obtain financing, most conventional lenders require a buyer to have sufficient collateral for a secured loan, and lenders usually only consider the depreciated value of fixtures and other tangible assets, rather than reputation and earning potential. You increase your chances of obtaining financing for your established restaurant if you have a good track record, a solid business plan and property to offer as collateral.
 How to Promote a Restaurant 
To promote a restaurant, you&apos;ll need a great knowledge of your customer base. Find out how to best promote your restaurant with advice from a restaurant owner in this free video on the restaurant business.
 How to Determine Restaurant Seating Capacity 
One extremely important decision about opening or owning a restaurant is determining a seating structure and seating capacity. No matter how your restaurant may be set up, determining the capacity of your restaurant is crucial for day-to-day operations, kitchen management and staffing. Whether you go with a large-scale or small-scale restaurant, its capacity could be the single greatest influence on the restaurant as a whole.
 How to Maintain Good Staffing Levels For Your Restaurant 
Thinking everything is under control in your&quot;front of the house&quot;and suddenly you discover there aren&apos;t enough wait staff available to cover all the tables in the dining area! Or, just before opening, you learn that a dish room employee called in sick! This is a problem that will quickly reduce the profitability of any food service operation and possibly result in dramatic consequences. Such a situation in any restaurant, diner, hotel, or assisted living dining service operation can be remedied. In order to learn how to maintain good staffing levels for your restaurant, some very important steps need…
 How Do I Get Pepsi Products in My Restaurant? 
If you are a restaurant owner, you probably know that popular soft drinks have an attractive profit margin. If you have decided that Pepsi is the brand you want to serve, some simple steps will seal the deal.
 How to Develop a Restaurant Comment Card 
If you own or operate a restaurant, customer comment cards can help you discover how your patrons feel about the experience you offer. Distributing and reviewing the cards can be cost-effective; the key is knowing what to ask. If you want to improve operations based on customer feedback, be prepared for an added expense.
 How to Lay Out a Restaurant 
Owning a restaurant can be extremely fun. It can also be extremely overwhelming, especially if you are starting from scratch. If you are, you probably either already have a space picked out or have narrowed down your search. There are several things you need to factor into putting together your restaurant and using your floor space wisely.
 Energy Conservation Tips for Restaurants 
Conserving resources is a restaurant tradition and increasing costs of energy dictates efficiency to remain competitive. Do a preliminary audit to evaluate your practices and energy usages. After review, initiate cost-effective changes and implement a hands-on program to perform periodic audit updates. Announce your program to customers and employees alike by &quot;going green&quot; and making it a part of doing business.
 Restaurant Empire Strategies 
A restaurant empire is new in the business world. Just one successful restaurant used to be seen as a huge success in the world of dining and the focus would be on running that restaurant and making it better for decades. But the achievements of chefs like Wolfgang Puck and Gordon Ramsey have created an entirely new level of success -- the empire.
 Steam Table Tips for Restaurants 
A steam table is a wonderful appliance for a restaurant. It allows the chef to keep food warm and to serve large numbers of guests at any given time. A few precautions will ensure that clients have the best experience possible. Cold food, food that has been sitting out too long and messy steam tables can chase customers away.
 Restaurant Vent Hood Cleaning 
The vent hood is a large venting system in a restaurant that allows steam, smoke and pollutants to exit the kitchen. When grease and oil builds up on this system it can become a fire hazard, so restaurant hoods need to be cleaned regularly.
 Restaurant Safety Guidelines 
Restaurant employees face numerous risks for injuries. If you follow guidelines provided by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, however, these risks can be reduced. When an injury does occur, following the proper guidelines will help you limit your risk for further injury or respond quickly. Being prepared and acting quickly can limit the extent of the injury or the number of people affected.
 Procedure for Making Biodiesel Fuel 
Biodiesel fuel is diesel fuel made from sources other than petroleum. Most biodiesel is made from corn, soybean and animal fat oil. Commercially, farmers grow crops and extract the oils to produce biodiesel. Individuals who make their own fuel commonly purchase vegetable oil or obtain waste vegetable oil (WVO) from others who discard it, such as restaurants. The oil is mixed with alcohol and lye, which helps convert the mixture into burnable fuel.
 Operating a Successful Restaurant 
Operating a successful restaurant requires making enough to pay the bills, pay the staff and earn a modest living. Maintain a consistent style and restaurant atmosphere with information from an executive chef in this free video on the restaurant business.
 How to Make a Restaurant Sign 
When opening a restaurant there are many tasks to complete, such as ordering menus, setting up the kitchen and making a restaurant sign. If the restaurant is located in a shopping center, the center typically has specific rules about what type of sign can be installed. If the restaurant is located where there are no requirements for sign style, then you have the option of choosing a style that bests suits the restaurant&apos;s theme.
 How to Own a Restaurant 
If your dream is to own your own restaurant, you may wonder how you might accomplish your goal. There are several roads to restaurant ownership. Each has its own advantage. For some restaurateurs a franchise is the ideal choice, as the business plan has often been worked out by skilled professionals. But, for those who have their own unique restaurant dreams, they will make other choices.
 Best Restaurant Jobs in Japan 
Looking for the best restaurant jobs in Japan? You can find them -- but only if you&apos;re qualified and know the ropes since this land of culinary diversity is home to the pickled sea slug, horseradish chocolate, hard-to-book sushi restaurants, classic kaiseki dining and fugu houses. Japan is also the place specially trained chefs know exactly how to prepare poisonous puffer fish so their customers don&apos;t keel over and die. If you&apos;d like to join this elite community, you will need to know the ins-and-outs of making perfectly steamed koshihikari rice, and it would be a good idea to know…
 ADA Handicapped Parking Regulations for Restaurants 
Since restaurants are public establishments, when they have a parking lot, they have to provide parking spaces for the more than 54 million Americans who have some physical handicap. The Americans With Disabilities Act (ADA) specifies the details of what accessible parking means in section 4.6 of the law.
 How to Save Money on Restaurant Supplies 
Learning to save money on restaurant supplies can mean the difference between going out of business and early retirement. You can save money, lots of money, and maintain or improve quality at your restaurant easy. Learn how to find the restaurant supply deals that will cut your expenses and help your business make money.
 About Hooters Restaurants 
Admired as being among the best places for chicken wings, the Hooters restaurants have been around for a long time, offering a variety of foods and a festive atmosphere for its patrons to enjoy. At times being criticized for how the &quot;Hooters girls&quot; are presented, the restaurant chain has stood its ground for many years and has been able to expand on its products ans also give back to the community.
 How Does a Restaurant Work? 
A good restaurant team consists of a group of people who help to keep the entire business flowing smoothly. The restaurant owner typically hires a restaurant manager who will oversee the general business aspect of the restaurant such as keeping the restaurant&apos;s finances in order, hiring new employees, ordering restaurant supplies and food, and also making sure the business operation is in good working order with the customers as well as with other restaurant distributors. A marketing consultant may also be hired to assure that the business is getting adequate advertising as well as the proper public relations for the…
 How to Be Successful With a New Restaurant 
Making it through the first 12 months as a restauranteur can be challenging, because about 1/3 of all restaurants in the United States don&apos;t make it past the first year. The biggest reason is that many of them were under-capitalized, while others failed for a variety of problems they could not overcome. You&apos;ll stand a great chance of not only surviving, but prospering, if you have developed a good concept and have a worthwhile location. But that&apos;s not all you need to survive. Here are some other things you should think about to make your restaurant successful.
 How to Get the Highest Price for a Restaurant 
You don&apos;t hear much about a restaurant changing hands, but it happens quite frequently. Maybe the owner wants to sell because he plans to retire. Then again, there may have been the death of an owner or the restaurant lost its lease. There are a number of reasons why someone might want to get out of the restaurant business, but one thing is constant. All owners want to receive the most for their businesses.
 How to Improve Energy Efficiency in a Restaurant 
Restaurants typically run a 32 percent profit margin. To improve the money your restaurant or cafe makes in profit, saving on energy not only makes you money, but saves the environment. Read on to learn how to improve energy efficiency in a restaurant.
 How to Sell a Restaurant 
There are various reasons why you may wish to sell your restaurant. Possibilities could include financial reasons, your inability to operate it any longer or you may just wish to try something new. There are two methods in which you can accomplish your goal. You may sell it yourself or you might want to have help doing so. With simple to follow steps, you may receive a fabulous profit selling your restaurant.
 How to Reduce Spoilage in a Restaurant 
When food spoils, the restaurant has just lost profit. Many restaurant owners find reducing waste one of the most difficult parts of their business because there are so many steps to take. If you isolate those steps and take them one by one true profits can increase while your spoilage decreases. These steps include purchasing, receiving, storage and usage procedures
 How to Promote a Restaurant 
The restaurant business is a difficult venture. You need to take care of three major issues before the business becomes popular. The food, the employees and marketing are all important for success. You may have the best food and service in the world, but if you cannot fill the seats no one will know this is the case. When you promote a restaurant, several things must happen in order to complete your goal.
 How to Operate a Successful Restaurant 
Most restaurants fail within the first few years, mostly because their owners didn&apos;t think the business through before opening their doors. If you want to operate a successful restaurant, it is important that you make plans and execute them according to copious research on your market, location and service.
 How to Name an Upscale Restaurant 
When it comes to launching a business, the name is of supreme importance. And when it comes to launching an upscale restaurant, the name is even more important, as it must sound elite, inviting, appetizing and trendy.
 How to Add Curbside Service to a Restaurant 
Excellent customer service is a vital component of running a successful restaurant. Restaurant owners can expand their services by offering curbside service to their patrons. The information below will help you learn how to add curbside service to a restaurant.
 How to Pick a Restaurant Location 
Selecting the perfect location for your restaurant is critical to the success of your business venture. You want to choose a location that customers can see and can get to easily. These suggestions help the potential restaurant owners in this crucial step in the business start up process.
 How to Promote a New Chain of Restaurants 
Promoting a chain of new restaurants requires extensive marketing, an appropriate budget and proper planning. A consistent effort is required to promote the restaurants and build a customer base. Use the following techniques for maximize results.
 How to Promote Your Restaurant Without Going Broke 
Advertising your restaurant may at times seem unaffordable, but the fact is you can&apos;t afford not to. Many advertising methods are quite expensive when weighed against the rate of return on your investment. To effectively promote your business, you have to develop unique and creative ideas that provide a big return without breaking your budget.
 
 ehow.com 
 About eHow eHow Blog How to by Topic How to Videos Sitemap 
 
Copyright©1999-2012 Demand Media, Inc.
Use of this web site constitutes acceptance of the eHow Terms of Use and Privacy Policy . Ad Choices en-US
	</body>
</document>
