<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000747" url="http://www.pc-calculators.com/articles/calorie-counter-exercise.p2.htm" time="2012-07-12-16:06" support="2" score="0.004353828154949141" bingtitle="Calorie counter exercise - Calculators" webtitle="Calorie counter exercise">
			<query id="001284" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000250" bing-rank="157"/>
	<description>A calorie counter or calculator is where you enter the type ... to work fairly well, which also contains a huge selection of foods including items from fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Thursday, July 12, 2012 
 

 

 
 
 
 Results 9 - 12 of 12 for calorie counter exercise . ( 0.48 seconds) 
 
 
 
 
 Search results 
 Forget All About That Calorie Counting Crap And Learn How To Lose Some Weight! by Gordon Black 
 ... Well, I guess some do have merit but, from what I hear, youd need to be walking around with a calculator and a calorie counter ; its just so time consuming and so fussy, who can sustain that kind of diligence in checking everything they eat? And then I get to the checkout at the supermarket and just about every magazine front page shouts out the answer to all your diet problems. Somebody very good is taking those Oprah cover shots and picking the clothes oh so carefully!! 

 Eating Disorders and the Internet by Dr. Angela Lewis 
 ... Food and Beverage Hints: Glycemic counters , calorie counters , lists of foods that are of negative calorie value, recipes for drinks and foods. In fact, all the things you can buy in the average womens or girls magazine at your local newsagent. A Recovery Room: a discussion forum specifically for recovering eating disorder sufferers. I only found this on a handful of sites. The more militant Pro-Ana websites would typically contain some of these additional attributes:Tips and Tricks: ... 

 Seven Crucial Steps for Long Term Weight Loss by John Tiniakos 
 ... A calorie counter or calculator is where you enter the type of food product, the amount (in grams or ounces) and it calculates the calorie content for you. You can find them at many websites online for free. One that I found to work fairly well, which also contains a huge selection of foods including items from fast food restaurant chains, is at To increase your rate of weight loss even further you can raise your exercise level. One way to accomplish this is by participating in a program ... 

 Dump All That Fat You&apos;re Lugging Around! by Mike Cuggy 
 ... You&apos;ve got a calorie counter and a protein counter . You&apos;ve got a drawer thats bulging with different calculators. Lets see theres a fatcalculator; a carbohydrate calculator; a fiber calculator; a heart rate calculator and a Waist/Hip Ratio calculator. You avoid reading about personal fitness because you know you&apos;re far from fit and you&apos;d rather not think about it thank you. You know all about Weight Watchers, eDiets, Atkins, and South Beach Diets. 



 Previous 1 2 

 
 
 
 
 

 Articles regarding calculators : Links 

 Copyright©2004-2012, PC-Calculators. All rights reserved. All trademarks are the property of their respective owners.
	</body>
</document>
