<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000786" url="http://www.globalbx.com/business/new-jersey/ocean-county-businesses-for-sale.asp" time="2012-07-12-16:07" support="2" score="0.0031942575363076414" bingtitle="Ocean County Businesses For Sale" webtitle="Ocean County NJ Businesses For Sale">
			<query id="001430" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="001436" bing-rank="98"/>
	<description>Buy or sell Ocean County businesses for ... Fast Food Restaurant Busy main street location. Seats 25. ... Oil change, brakes, light repairs. 100&apos; car wash tunnel.</description>
	<body>
		Buy a business in Ocean County. Search our 
 51 Ocean County Businesses for Sale. Buy a business or sell a business for free .

 Login Site Map Lite Edition Help&amp;Faqs 
 
 GlobalBX 
 
Business&amp;Commercial Real Estate Financing
 
 Home Buy a Business Sell your Business Find a Franchise Get a Biz Loan Resource Center Entrepreneur Blog Entrepreneur Forums 
 
 Advanced Search   |   Listings By Email   |   Message Boards   |   Professionals Directory   |   Loans&amp;Financing   |   Business&amp;Mortgage Notes   |   Buyer Resources 
 
 Ocean County Businesses For Sale 
 We have 1950 New Jersey Businesses For Sale , 51 Ocean County Businesses For Sale . You can also View Our Listings By County Or City . 
If you own a business or commercial property and you are considering selling, check out our Sell A Business section for a FREE listing today! 


 


 
 Top Franchises 
 Get Free information on all the top franchises. Find out why franchise owners make ridiculous amounts of money year after year!

Industry: All Industries Array Automotive Business Opportunities Business Services Canadian Cheap Children&apos;s Cleaning&amp;Maintenance Computer&amp;Internet Education Food Franchise Services Health&amp;Fitness Healthcare&amp;Senior Care High Capital Home Based Business Home Services Low Cost Mobile Personnel&amp;Staffing Pet Retail SBA Registry Small Business Sports&amp;Recreation Travel, Cruise&amp;Hotel Veteran&apos;s Women&apos;s Location: All Locations Canada Array Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Puerto Rico Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virgin Islands, U.S. Virginia Washington Washington, D.C. West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming Investment All Levels Array $5,000 $10,000 $20,000 $30,000 $40,000 $50,000 $60,000 $70,000 $80,000 $90,000 $100,000 $150,000 $200,000 $250,000 $300,000 $350,000 $400,000 $450,000 $500,000 $550,000 $600,000 $650,000 $700,000 $750,000 $1,000,000 + 

 
 
 OCEAN COUNTY BUSINESSES FOR SALE
View full details on any business for sale by clicking on the listing title. Refine your search or Start New Search 

   
   1-50 of 51 1-50 of 51  

   Location   Asking Price        Revenue        Cash Flow        Pizza/Rest High Volume NJ 
 I have Pizza/Rest in ocean county nj close to the shore 3,300 sq feet in strip mall.
Gross is 11k-15k week
Cash flow 2,700-3,... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County $250K - $500K $725,000 $190,000 Florist / Flower Shop 
 This is a beautiful flower shop in a large shopping center along a very busy highway. Reputation for superior quality design an... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $150,000 $55,000 Restaurant For Sale - Close To Beach 
 Asking: $169,000. Very nice place, 5 blocks away from the beach in a very upscale town. Do good all year but very busy in summe... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $169,000 $211,000 Quizno&apos;s - Top Location, Big Potential 
 ASKING PRICE: $175,000. Beautiful store located in a major shopping center on a major road surrounded by major anchor stores wi... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $331,100 $46,324 Huge Florist Opportunity 
 This is a beautiful flower shop in a large shopping center along a very busy highway. Reputation for superior quality design an... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County $500K - $1.0M $657,000 $200,000 Wholesale Distributor 
 This wholesale business is ready for the next level. Has substantial amount of steady customers. Distributor of auto, marine, ... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County $250K - $500K $600,000 $101,500 Variety Store 
 Ocean County variety store which sells greeting cards, gift items, cigarettes, cigars tobacco products, candy, soda, magazines,... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $475,717 $78,145 Need money? Click here to get financing for business and commercial real estate. Tanning Salon 
 Professionally Built Out Tanning Salon With All NEW EQUIPMENT. Professionally Operated By Experienced Operator. 3,000 SF will... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $263,685 $71,596 Fast Food Restaurant 
 Busy main street location. Seats 25. Low rent. Long lease. Low down payment. Motivated seller will help qualified buyer with fi... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $280,000 $80,000 Fast Food Restaurant 
 Short hours closed on weekends, Long lease low rent, Busy take out motivated seller has priced this to sell. Will help with fin... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $280,000 $80,000 Full Service Florist 
 Great opportunity to be your own boss ... Located in high traffic plaza on main highway ... 14 retirement communities within 8 ... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $225,000 $106,000 Medical Supply Business 
 Medical Supply did over $500k in 2011 nets over $200k. Partners disagree, brings this highly profitable business on the market.... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County $250K - $500K $575,000 $225,000 Pet Store 
 Established Pet Business for sale, offering a full line of pet products to include live animals. We offer puppies, lizard, bir... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $325,000 $110,000 Roof Cleaning Dealership 
 Central Jerseys biggest and oldest roof cleaning company for sale. Ocean and Monmouth counties (protected territories). This... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $80,000 --- Profitable&amp;Well Established - Chimney Sweep 
 Profitable&amp;Well Established, recession-proof Chimney Sweep Business for sale! -Seller will Train. Fully equipped turn key ho... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $180,000 $78,000 Have a question? Click here to ask our business experts and members. Play N Trade - Established For Sale 
 Play N Trade is a video game sales and service business for sale, located in a small strip mall on a heavily trafficked main th... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $320,000 $35,000 Bagel Business - Profitable And Established 
 No other Bagel Stores are in the immediate area. Currently this absentee owner is not running the business to its full potenti... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $190,000 $75,000 Mexican Puerto Rican Restaurant For Sale 
 EXCEPTIONAL MEXICAN AND PUERTO RICAN RESTAURANT FOR SALE. VERY POPULAR FOR LUNCH AND DINNER. Home style food with everything ... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $133,750 $51,200 Sportsbar / Restaurant 
 New high volume 4,800 sq ft absentee owned sportsbar/restaurant for sale seating for 150 includes the bar. Long lease low rent.... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County $500K - $1.0M $1,700,000 $245,000 Well Established Adult Health Care Practice 
 Well-established Adult Health Care Practice for sale in desirable Ocean County, NJ. Convenient access to all major highways and... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County $250K - $500K $482,360 $285,628 Bakery / Pastry Shop - High Profit - Turn Key 
 You don&apos;t have to be a baker or a pastry chef to operate this turn key operation. Fantastic location in a newer mini strip mal... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County $250K - $500K $500,000 $165,000 Pizzeria - Priced Agressivly - Great Cash Flow 
 Established for nine years, this pizzeria for sale is located in a small strip mall very close to lots of offices, commercial b... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $450,000 $147,000 Fantastic Convenience Store 
 Convenience store for sale located in an affluent neighborhood. Sells cigarettes, Lotto, Money Grams, and deli and convenience... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County $250K - $500K $622,000 $126,800 Need money? Click here to get financing for business and commercial real estate. Dry Cleaning Store - On Site Plant For Sale 
 All new equipment using environmentally safe chemicals. New shirt press. Employees will stay with new owner. New computer syste... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $200,000 $100,000 Tanning Salon - Aggressively Priced For Quick Sale 
 3,200 square foot salon for sale with over 26 tanning pieces of tanning equipment. Profitable and priced extremely aggressive ... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $145,000 $50,720 Gourmet Seafood Store For Sale 
 Seasonal seafood gourmet store offering a variety of seafood, homemade dishes and salads. The location is fantastic with no com... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County $500K - $1.0M $450,000 $135,150 Magazine Publication Opportunity 
 Once in a lifetime MAGAZINE PUBLICATION opportunity, the owner is VERY MOTIVATED to sell this home based business that produces... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $450,000 $280,000 Large Branded Gas Station 
 Great location, large branded station in Ocean County located on Major Highway. Sells gas and diesel and has convenient store ... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $900,000 $53,748 Major Pretzel Franchise Business For Sale 
 Major soft pretzel franchise with room to grow and with a high margin product. Franchise has over 100 locations and is very fin... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County $250K - $500K $275,000 $63,950 Pizzeria Business For Sale 
 Fantastic Pizzeria&amp;Italian Restaurant for Sale situated in a newer strip mall along an extremely heavily trafficked main high... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $400,000 $80,000 Dry Cleaners Located In A Busy Strip Mall 
 Dry cleaners for sale, located in a busy strip mall, surrounded by senior citizen community. Offering a drop off service for 2 ... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $106,000 $36,772 Can&apos;t find a business? Post a FREE business wanted ad on our message boards. Dry Cleaning Store - On Site Plant For Sale 
 All new equipment using environmentally safe chemicals. New shirt press. Employees will stay with new owner. New computer syste... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $250,000 $100,000 Tanning Salon With All New Equipment For Sale 
 Price reduced! Professionally built out tanning salon with all new equipment. Professionally operated by experienced operator. ... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $195,300 $56,000 Car Wash And Auto Service Center For Sale 
 Car wash and auto service center for sale. Oil change, brakes, light repairs. 100&apos; car wash tunnel. All tunnel equipment just 3... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $270,700 $89,550 Ice Cream, Bagel, And Pastry Frachise For Sale 
 Ice cream franchise is well known for its excellent product and brand recognition. The franchise has over 500 retail locations ... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County $250K - $500K $300,000 --- Franchise Eatery For Sale 
 Brand new tri-franchise for sale. Seller put 3 very well known franchise businesses together by investing more than $500,000 to... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County $250K - $500K $262,000 $52,932 Cage Free Boarding&amp;Doggie Day Care For Sale 
 Cage free boarding and doggie day care with grooming capabilties. Great for a couple who is energetic&amp;wants to reinvent thems... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County $500K - $1.0M $150 $6,000 Appliance Repair Business For Sale 
 Appliance repair parts and sales commisions over 7,000 customers and we do insurance work and warranty on some products we have... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $170,000 $100,000 Marina Boat Dealership For Sale 
 Marina, boat dealership protected the only one in N.J VERY, VERY profitable. marine repairs, over 100 loyal customers, great re... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County $500K - $1.0M $1,500,000 $200,000 Have a question? Click here to ask our business experts and members. Coastal Tanning Salon 
 Busy, newer and attractive 1200 sq. ft. tanning salon in Ocean county for sale offering UV and UV free state of the art equipme... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $120,000 $79,000 Optometry Practice For Sale 
 New Jersey Optometry Practice For Sale
Ocean County, New Jersey
Asking $180,000
Ref# OD684

For three years this practice ... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $285,309 --- Gravel Pit For Sale 
 100 acre gravel pit operation. Turn key includes all needed to operate along with customers and permits. Mining permits are no ... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County $2.5M - $5.0M $1,000,000 $500,000 Carpet Cleaning Service 
 State of the art Carpet Cleaning service with two exclusive territories. Rapidly expanding this service is beginning to hit its... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $112,007 $19,975 Children Day Care Center 
 Modern attractive children&apos;s day care center in an active community of Ocean County NJ. This cozy day care facility is licensed... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $160,000 $45,000 Pre School 
 pre school 5,500 sq. ft same owner for 23 years. full high dry basement
for storage. This school is immaculate and is one of t... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County $1.0M - $2.5M $500,000 $150,000 Tanning Salon With All New Equipment 
 PRICE REDUCED! Professionally Built Out Tanning Salon With All NEW EQUIPMENT. Professionally Operated By Experienced Operator. ... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $195,300 $56,000 Tanning Salon With All New Equipment 
 PRICE REDUCED! Professionally Built Out Tanning Salon With All NEW EQUIPMENT. Professionally Operated By Experienced Operator. ... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $195,300 $56,000 Need money? Click here to get financing for business and commercial real estate. Broad C Liquor License For Sale 
 Outstanding opportunity to purchase the LAST Broad &apos;&apos;C&apos;&apos; liquor licenses in one of the most desirable Southern NJ towns. Opport... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County $250K - $500K --- --- Banquet Catering For Sale 
 Highly successful Caterers located in Ocean County, NJ offering on site catering and banquets for all special event. The presen... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County $250K - $500K $799,000 $80,000 Dog Grooming Business For Sale 
 Thriving Pet Grooming business in Ocean County, New Jersey. This successful business is five years old with a solid and loyal c... 
 United States
 -&gt;New Jersey
 -&gt;Ocean County &lt;$250K $120,000 $40,000 

  
   1-50 of 51 1-50 of 51  
 
 
 
 NEW JERSEY BUSINESSES FOR SALE

 Search New Jersey Businesses For Sale 

Find available New Jersey Businesses by county or city.

 
 Absecon Businesses For Sale (2) Asbury Park Businesses For Sale (1) Atlantic City Businesses For Sale (7) Atlantic County Businesses For Sale (24) Atlantic Highlands Businesses For Sale (1) Basking Ridge Businesses For Sale (1) Bayonne Businesses For Sale (9) Bergen County Businesses For Sale (199) Blairstown Businesses For Sale (1) Bloomfield Businesses For Sale (2) Bloomingdale Businesses For Sale (1) Bordentown Businesses For Sale (1) Bradley Beach Businesses For Sale (1) Brick Businesses For Sale (3) Bricktown Businesses For Sale (1) Bridgewater Businesses For Sale (1) Burlington Businesses For Sale (1) Burlington County Businesses For Sale (12) Camden Businesses For Sale (34) Camden County Businesses For Sale (6) Cape May County Businesses For Sale (31) Cape May Court House Businesses For Sale (1) Carlstadt Businesses For Sale (1) Carteret Businesses For Sale (1) Chatham Businesses For Sale (1) Cherry Hill Businesses For Sale (4) Clark Businesses For Sale (2) Cliffside Park Businesses For Sale (1) Clifton Businesses For Sale (5) Clinton Businesses For Sale (1) Cranford Businesses For Sale (1) Cumberland Businesses For Sale (8) Dover Businesses For Sale (1) East Brunswick Businesses For Sale (2) Eatontown Businesses For Sale (1) Edison Businesses For Sale (4) Elizabeth Businesses For Sale (8) Emerson Businesses For Sale (1) Essex County Businesses For Sale (166) Fair Lawn Businesses For Sale (4) Fairfield Businesses For Sale (2) Flanders Businesses For Sale (1) Florham Park Businesses For Sale (1) Fort Lee Businesses For Sale (2) Franklin Businesses For Sale (1) Freehold Businesses For Sale (5) Galloway Township Businesses For Sale (1) Garfield Businesses For Sale (1) Gloucester County Businesses For Sale (10) Hackensack Businesses For Sale (2) Hackettstown Businesses For Sale (1) Haddon Heights Businesses For Sale (1) Haddon Township Businesses For Sale (1) Hamilton Businesses For Sale (3) Harrison Businesses For Sale (1) Hasbrouck Heights Businesses For Sale (1) Hoboken Businesses For Sale (6) Hopatcong Businesses For Sale (1) Howell Businesses For Sale (4) Hudson County Businesses For Sale (104) Hunterdon County Businesses For Sale (17) Irving Businesses For Sale (1) Iselin Businesses For Sale (3) Jackson Businesses For Sale (1) Jersey City Businesses For Sale (11) Jersey Shore Businesses For Sale (3) Kearny Businesses For Sale (3) Kenilworth Businesses For Sale (1) Keyport Businesses For Sale (1) Lakewood Businesses For Sale (1) Laurel Springs Businesses For Sale (1) Lawrenceville Businesses For Sale (2) Lebanon Businesses For Sale (2) Ledgewood Businesses For Sale (1) Linden Businesses For Sale (1) Little Egg Harbor Businesses For Sale (2) Livingston Businesses For Sale (3) Lodi Businesses For Sale (3) Mantua Businesses For Sale (1) Margate Businesses For Sale (1) Marlboro Businesses For Sale (2) Marlton Businesses For Sale (2) Matawan Businesses For Sale (3) Mays Landing Businesses For Sale (1) Mercer County Businesses For Sale (37) 
 
 Middlesex Businesses For Sale (41) Middlesex County Businesses For Sale (117) Middletown Businesses For Sale (1) Millville Businesses For Sale (1) Monmouth County Businesses For Sale (93) Montclair Businesses For Sale (2) Moorestown Businesses For Sale (1) Morris Businesses For Sale (42) Morris County Businesses For Sale (91) Morristown Businesses For Sale (1) Mount Holly Businesses For Sale (1) Mount Laurel Businesses For Sale (1) Netcong Businesses For Sale (1) New Brunswick Businesses For Sale (1) Newark Businesses For Sale (9) Newton Businesses For Sale (2) North Brunswick Businesses For Sale (1) Northfield Businesses For Sale (1) Norwood Businesses For Sale (1) Nutly Businesses For Sale (1) Oakland Businesses For Sale (1) Ocean Businesses For Sale (10) Ocean County Businesses For Sale (51) Old Bridge Businesses For Sale (4) Oradell Businesses For Sale (1) Orange Businesses For Sale (2) Palisades Park Businesses For Sale (1) Palmyra Businesses For Sale (1) Paramus Businesses For Sale (1) Parlin Businesses For Sale (2) Parsippany Businesses For Sale (2) Passaic Businesses For Sale (23) Passaic County Businesses For Sale (105) Paterson Businesses For Sale (1) Pennsauken Businesses For Sale (4) Philadelphia Businesses For Sale (1) Phillipsburg Businesses For Sale (1) Piscataway Businesses For Sale (1) Plainfield Businesses For Sale (4) Princeton Businesses For Sale (1) Rahway Businesses For Sale (3) Randolph Businesses For Sale (2) Ridgefield Businesses For Sale (1) Ridgewood Businesses For Sale (1) River Vale Businesses For Sale (1) Rockaway Businesses For Sale (1) Rockland County Businesses For Sale (1) Roseland Businesses For Sale (1) Roxbury Businesses For Sale (1) Rutherford Businesses For Sale (1) Sayreville Businesses For Sale (3) Seaside Heights Businesses For Sale (1) Secaucus Businesses For Sale (1) Somerdale Businesses For Sale (1) Somers Point Businesses For Sale (2) Somerset Businesses For Sale (12) Somerset County Businesses For Sale (39) Somerville Businesses For Sale (2) South Jersey Businesses For Sale (12) Springfield Businesses For Sale (2) Staten Island Businesses For Sale (1) Sullivan County Businesses For Sale (1) Surf City Businesses For Sale (2) Sussex County Businesses For Sale (23) Tenafly Businesses For Sale (1) Toms River Businesses For Sale (8) Trenton Businesses For Sale (2) Tuckerton Businesses For Sale (1) Union Businesses For Sale (38) Union County Businesses For Sale (75) Vernon Businesses For Sale (2) Vineland Businesses For Sale (2) Voorhees Businesses For Sale (2) Waretown Businesses For Sale (1) Warren County Businesses For Sale (21) Wayne Businesses For Sale (2) West Berlin Businesses For Sale (2) West New York Businesses For Sale (2) Westfield Businesses For Sale (1) Westwood Businesses For Sale (1) Wildwood Businesses For Sale (2) Williamstown Businesses For Sale (1) Woodbury Heights Businesses For Sale (1) Other New Jersey Businesses For Sale (240) Return to all New Jersey Businesses For Sale 
 
 
SELL YOUR BUSINESS
 
 Advertise your Ocean County Business For Sale for free ! 

Reach the largest pool of business buyers and investors anywhere. List your business for sale with a free confidential ad. Whether you want to sell a business, or sell a commercial property, you can post a free ad and upload pictures. We never take any commission or charge fees based on successful sales. All our services are free and have been free since 2001!

 Advertise Ocean County business for sale 

 Advertise Ocean County commercial property for sale 


Can&apos;t find the Business you are looking for?

 Sign up to have new business listings automatically emailed to you 

 Post a Business Wanted listing on our Message Boards 
 
OCEAN COUNTY BUSINESS FINANCING
 
 Get Business Financing for free ! 

We work with some of the top lenders in business and commercial real estate financing. If you are looking to finance a hotel, motel, resort, apartment complex, gas station, manufacturing facilty or any type of business or commercial property, our commercial lenders can help you.

 Get a business loan in Ocean County 

 Search for Ocean County business lenders 

 Apply for Ocean County business financing 
 
BUSINESS NETWORK

 Connecting Business Buyers, Sellers and Lenders ... 

GlobalBX is the leading Ocean County business for sale network, connecting Ocean County business sellers and brokers to buyers, investors and direct lenders. GlobalBX offers a FREE business for sale listing exchange with over 30,000 advertised listings. Whether you want to buy or sell Ocean County businesses for sale, or get a Ocean County commercial loan you have come to the right place. Best of all, our services are FREE!



 
 BUSINESS NEWS

 
 
  Free Industry-Related News on Businesses For Sale


  Opt In, Opt Out Reliability


Email Address    

 
  Sign Me Up     Take Me Off

 
 
 
 BUSINESS BROKERS AND AGENTS

If you are looking to buy or sell a business, we can help you. GlobalBX is a free business for sale exchange with over 6,753 Business Brokers and Agents using our services. Register Now as a GlobalBX Broker to:

 Reach thousands of qualified buyers searching our listings everyday. Post an unlimited number of businesses for sale for free. Track the number of times that your listings have been searched. Have messages from buyers sent to you confidentially via email. Enter your profile into our Professionals Directory, where thousands of buyers and sellers look for assistance. Give your for sale listings greater exposure through our free Multi-Site Distribution, News Print Advertising, and Marketing Programs. 
 
 
 
Find great franchise opportunities that fit your budget!

 Franchises under $10,000 
 Franchises under $20,000 
 Franchises under $50,000 
 Franchises under $70,000 
 Franchises under $100,000 

 

 Popular Links: 
 Franchise Reviews 
 Franchise Information 
 Franchise Opportunities 
 Buy a Business 
 Sell a Business 
 Business Brokers 
 Business for Sale 
 Business Sale Categories 
 Businesses for Sale by Owner 

 Business Tip: 

 If you cannot find the right business for sale, you can use our advanced search feature or check out our popular franchise directory ! 
 
 
 
LOOKING FOR BUSINESSES IN ANOTHER STATE OR PROVINCE?


Search for businesses for sale in other areas:

 
 Alabama Businesses For Sale Alaska Businesses For Sale Arizona Businesses For Sale Arkansas Businesses For Sale California Businesses For Sale Colorado Businesses For Sale Connecticut Businesses For Sale Delaware Businesses For Sale Dist. of Columbia Businesses For Sale Florida Businesses For Sale Georgia Businesses For Sale Hawaii Businesses For Sale Idaho Businesses For Sale Illinois Businesses For Sale Indiana Businesses For Sale Iowa Businesses For Sale Kansas Businesses For Sale Kentucky Businesses For Sale Louisiana Businesses For Sale Maine Businesses For Sale Maryland Businesses For Sale Massachusetts Businesses For Sale Michigan Businesses For Sale 
 
 Minnesota Businesses For Sale Mississippi Businesses For Sale Missouri Businesses For Sale Montana Businesses For Sale Nebraska Businesses For Sale Nevada Businesses For Sale New Hampshire Businesses For Sale New Jersey Businesses For Sale New Mexico Businesses For Sale New York Businesses For Sale North Carolina Businesses For Sale North Dakota Businesses For Sale Ohio Businesses For Sale Oklahoma Businesses For Sale Oregon Businesses For Sale Pennsylvania Businesses For Sale Rhode Island Businesses For Sale South Carolina Businesses For Sale South Dakota Businesses For Sale Tennessee Businesses For Sale Texas Businesses For Sale Utah Businesses For Sale Vermont Businesses For Sale 
 
 Virginia Businesses For Sale Washington Businesses For Sale West Virginia Businesses For Sale Wisconsin Businesses For Sale Wyoming Businesses For Sale 


 Canada: 
 Alberta Businesses For Sale British Columbia Businesses For Sale Manitoba Businesses For Sale New Brunswick Businesses For Sale Newfoundland Businesses For Sale Northwest Territories Businesses For Sale Nova Scotia Businesses For Sale Nunavut Businesses For Sale Ontario Businesses For Sale Prince Edward Island Businesses For Sale Quebec Businesses For Sale Saskatchewan Businesses For Sale Yukon Territory Businesses For Sale 
 
 
 
 
 About Us | Terms | Contact Us | Site Map | FAQ | Businesses For Sale | Franchises | Business Loans | Small Business For Sale ©2001-12. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
