<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000062" url="http://weight-loss.families.com/blog/solving-obesity-food-prices-based-on-calorie-count" time="2012-07-12-15:14" support="3" score="0.005043180425654121" bingtitle="Solving Obesity: Food Prices Based on Calorie Count - Weight Loss ..." webtitle="Solving Obesity:  Food Prices Based on Calorie Count - Weight Loss - Families.com">
			<query id="000467" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="000749" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="001064" bing-rank="237"/>
	<description>What if food prices were based on calorie count? ... to the drive-thru window of the local fast food ... you were low on cash, which would you pick ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign Up for Our Newsletter 
 
  Community  Parenting  Pregnancy Family Entertainment at Home Health Savings 
 
 Health | Fitness | Yoga | Weight Loss | Mental Health 
 
   
 Tweet 
 
Solving Obesity: Food Prices Based on Calorie Count

by Angel Lynn Diamond | More from this Blogger 

I had an interesting thought the other day as I pulled up to the drive-thru window of the local fast food restaurant as I counted my money. What if food prices were based on calorie count ? Not only would we all be thin, but we would be all the wealthier as we are all counting our pennies these days.

Let&apos;s just say that a cheeseburger, which is about calories 340 at one local fast food chain , sold for $3.40 and a Caesar salad, which is about 160 calories at the same place sold for $1.60. Another example would be the fruit parfait at 160 calories for $1.60 or an apple pie at 250 calories for $2.50. If these were your choices for that day and you were low on cash, which would you pick? Well, of course, most of us would opt for the salad and parfait, right? Or not? Are we so addicted to food that we would pay the extra money for that cheeseburger and apple pie? 

This idea would probably eliminate the need to serve unhealthy foods and steer people into eating a more healthy diet . It would also take the guesswork away from those who were actually dieting and thus eliminate the need to study the calorie count of foods as well. On one hand, businesses would lose money selling based on this theory due to the decreased price intake on lower calorie foods, but on the other hand, they might just have more customers because they served healthier, lower calorie foods.

In the long run this would eliminate the need for actual dieting and people would not have to concentrate so hard on keeping their weight at a healthy number. And what&apos;s more, we would have more money in our pockets. They would have to serve more customers; however, to make the same amount of money, but people would live longer so they would have customers for a longer length of time. I finally opted for the salad and parfait because of my pretty bare wallet, but this was good because I am dieting anyway. Crazy idea, I guess, but these are just some of my random thoughts. Go figure.

Angel Lynn writes in weight loss, single parenting, and health
  
 Share and Enjoy: 
 
 Learn more about Angel Lynn Diamond 
I am a mom to my precious one and only, a nurse in a heartwarming adult living facility, and a freelance writer.

 View Full Profile | More from this Blogger 
 
 Relevant weight loss tags 
 Kids | weight loss | christmas | holidays | sex | Food | children | Travel | baby | pregnancy 
 

 
 
Weight Loss categories

 A Type II Diabetes Journey (13) About our Bloggers (69) Becoming the Woman I Want to Be (17) Body-for-Life Challenge 2008 (17) Confessions of a Foodie Mom (7) Counting Calories (13) Dad&apos;s Losing It (32) Diary of an Overweight Mom (51) Diet Beverages (10) Diet Book Info (9) Diet Foods/Beverages (18) Diet News (55) Diet Supplements (40) Dieting on the Go (36) Diets (183) Diets (Fad) (21) Diets (Lifestyle) (10) Diets (Systems) (43) Emotions&amp;Food (16) Energy and Weight Loss Supplements (2) Exercise (69) Exercise Issues (38) Getting My Mind Right (10) Goal Setting (96) Healthy Alternatives (233) Healthy Foods (36) I&apos;ve Lost Weight (1) Looking for My Waist (27) Mission Possible (16) Momma&apos;s on a Diet! (18) Motivation (92) On the Weight Watchers WagonAgain (4) Portion Control (22) Product of the Week (23) Slim Fast (1) Success Stories (11) Television Programs (22) The Best I Have Ever Been (1) The Week in Review (12) Time to Get Moving! (11) Weight a Minute (50) Weight Loss for Breastfeeding Moms (8) Weight Loss for Children (63) Weight Loss for Teens (10) Weight Loss Recipes (96) Weight Loss Surgery (18) Weighting it Out (3) Whole Foods (3) 
 
 
 December 2011 January 2012 February 2012 March 2012 April 2012 May 2012 June 2012 View All 
 
More weight loss tags
 
 Kids | weight loss | christmas | holidays | sex | Food | children | Travel | baby | pregnancy 
 
 
 
 
 
 Relationships Dating Advice Local Date Ideas 
 
 Learn Genealogy Family Tree Research Genealogy Blog 
 
 Ask an Expert Anti-Aging Cosmetic Procedures 
 
 Grocery Coupons Printable Coupons Hot Coupons 
 
 Terms of Service | Privacy Policy | Unsubscribe | Blog For Us! | Be a Moderator! | Advertise with Us | Help 
 ©2012 Families.com, LLC [x] close [x] close
	</body>
</document>
