<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000797" url="http://www.skyscrapercity.com/archive/index.php/t-656824-p-11.html" time="2012-07-12-16:10" support="7" score="0.008543798830592012" bingtitle="Chennai - Malls and Multiplex projects [Archive] - Page 11 ..." webtitle="Chennai - Malls and Multiplex projects [Archive]  - Page 11 - SkyscraperCity">
			<query id="001236" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000797" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000390" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000671" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000265" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="001425" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000451" bing-rank="248"/>
	<description>... best at single screen cinema halls where the throw ... receiving units are similar to Dish &amp; Set Top Boxes ... chain, Country Chicken, a complete turnkey fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		SkyscraperCity &gt; Asian Forums &gt; India &gt; Metropolitan Projects &gt; Chennai &gt;Chennai - Malls and Multiplex projects PDA 
View Full Version : Chennai - Malls and Multiplex projects 
 Pages : 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 [ 11 ] 12 13 14 15 kaja_asif July 20th, 2011, 06:28 AM Ramee mall n mount road does&apos;nt have multiplex.

next mall n chennai with multiplex which s going to open ?

chandra mall food court opend? KFC, PIZZA HUT, MCDONALDS opened r planing 2 open.. kaja_asif July 20th, 2011, 06:33 AM udhaym theater is renovated r still its n same old condition,,,

roopam n sangam cinemas closed they r renovating r permenantly closed...

albert theater any idea r they also renovating... gvijayan July 20th, 2011, 07:53 AM ^^ kaja_asif,

Usage of SMS short forms (n, r, s etc) are not entertained in the forum. Please try to write complete sentences. Indian Sun July 20th, 2011, 09:45 AM Has anyone been to the terrace food court at Chennai Citicenter before ? Yesterday was the first time I noticed it. Nice view from there. mr_madras July 20th, 2011, 12:53 PM Has anyone been to the terrace food court at Chennai Citicenter before ? Yesterday was the first time I noticed it. Nice view from there.

^^nice view of marina, MRTS,santhome wlbkng July 20th, 2011, 07:31 PM Has anyone been to the terrace food court at Chennai Citicenter before ? Yesterday was the first time I noticed it. Nice view from there.

Have u clicked any pics mate? If so, do post it. Indian Sun July 20th, 2011, 07:39 PM ^^ Didn&apos;t take camera, boss. Will go again soon. wlbkng July 20th, 2011, 07:46 PM ^^ Looking forward for it! Cheers :) Anniyan July 21st, 2011, 03:22 PM just now i joined n skyscrapper thats what i am posting now. hereafter i will post all tamil flim release in dubai.

No, Thanks. This thread is only for malls&amp;multiplexes in Chennai

You can post it in Dubai forum if it is of interest to dubai forumers. kaja_asif July 23rd, 2011, 08:17 AM ok. sorry . kaja_asif July 23rd, 2011, 01:15 PM some pvr cinemas chennai photos when i was in chennai these shots taken.

http://img19.imageshack.us/img19/8483/pvr2.jpg
By kaja_asif (http://profile.imageshack.us/user/kaja_asif) at 2011-07-23

http://img855.imageshack.us/img855/913/pvr1.jpg
By kaja_asif (http://profile.imageshack.us/user/kaja_asif) at 2011-07-23

http://img34.imageshack.us/img34/1456/pvr3.jpg
By kaja_asif (http://profile.imageshack.us/user/kaja_asif) at 2011-07-23

http://img219.imageshack.us/img219/7536/pvr4.jpg
By kaja_asif (http://profile.imageshack.us/user/kaja_asif) at 2011-07-23

http://img839.imageshack.us/img839/4264/pvr5.jpg
By kaja_asif (http://profile.imageshack.us/user/kaja_asif) at 2011-07-23

http://img855.imageshack.us/img855/1720/pvr6.jpg
By kaja_asif (http://profile.imageshack.us/user/kaja_asif) at 2011-07-23 kaja_asif July 23rd, 2011, 01:18 PM inox chennai photos during my visit

http://img853.imageshack.us/img853/9081/inox4.jpg
By kaja_asif (http://profile.imageshack.us/user/kaja_asif) at 2011-07-23

http://img813.imageshack.us/img813/6282/inox3.jpg
By kaja_asif (http://profile.imageshack.us/user/kaja_asif) at 2011-07-23

http://img195.imageshack.us/img195/4867/inox2.jpg
By kaja_asif (http://profile.imageshack.us/user/kaja_asif) at 2011-07-23

http://img38.imageshack.us/img38/6043/inox1.jpg
By kaja_asif (http://profile.imageshack.us/user/kaja_asif) at 2011-07-23

http://img29.imageshack.us/img29/1397/inox5.jpg
By kaja_asif (http://profile.imageshack.us/user/kaja_asif) at 2011-07-23

http://img34.imageshack.us/img34/9050/inox6.jpg
By kaja_asif (http://profile.imageshack.us/user/kaja_asif) at 2011-07-23 Dilip joseph July 23rd, 2011, 03:59 PM Multiplex&apos;s in Chennai

Existing::banana:
1. Sathyam Cinemas - Royapettah (6 Screens)
2. Inox Movies- Citi Center, Mylapore (4 Screens)
3. Mayajaal- ECR (14 Screens)-INDIA&apos;S LARGEST MULTIPLEX!!
4.PVR Skywalk- Ampa Skywalk, Aminjikarai (7 Screens)
5.Escape Cinemas- Express Avenue, Royapettah (8 Screens)
6.Abirami Mall - Purasaivakkam (4 screens)
7.Devi Cinemas - Anna Salai (4 screens)
8.Fame National Cinemas- Chandra Mall, Virugambakkam(5 Screens)
9.AGS Cinemas -Villiwalkam[5screens]
10. Sangam Cinemas-Poonamalle High Road (3 screens)
11. Udayam Complex- Ashok Pillar (4 screens) -- under renovation
12. Rakki cinemas-Ambattur(4Screens)
13.Murugan Cinemas-Ambattur(3Screens)
14.AGS Cinemas-Coromandel plaza, Navalur, OMR(2 screens operational)[2 screens soon]
15.SriGanga Cinemas-Kolathur-(3Screens-&gt;Sri Ganga/Sri Yamuna renovation completed; Sri kaveri now renovation started)

In the pipeline: :nuts:
1. Sathyam Cinemas -Prestige Forum Vijaya Mall, Vadapalani (8 Screens)
2. FUN Cinemas - Phoenix Market City, Velachery (12 Screens)
3. Cinemax - The Grand Mall, Velachery (5 Screens)
4. Cinemax - Gold Souk Grande mall, Vandalur (6 Screens)
5. Cinemax - Matrix Mall, Saligramam
6.AGS Cinemas - Coromandel Plaza, Navalur,OMR (2 Screens)
7.Dream cinemas- Grand Venus Mall, Perambur (5 Screens)
8. PVR Cinemas,Marg Junction, Karapakkam, OMR(7 Screens)
9. ???- Ozone Mall, Anna Nagar
10. - Allied Marina Mall, OMR
11.(Fame cinemas)?-Spectrum mall,Saidapet
12.Mayajaal-ECR(2 more coming up)
13.Sangam Cinemas-Poonamalle High road[2screens(1 will be 3D)]
14.Vettri Theatres-Chromepet[ by 2011 end, renovation of Rakesh with dividing Rakesh into 2 which lead to 3rd screen and planned to make Rakesh into 3D by 2012.
15.SriGanga Cinemas-Kolathur-(1Screen renovation started for Sri Kaveri)

You have missed Rohini Movie park @koyambedu,which has got 5screens.........!!!!! balakannan31087 July 24th, 2011, 05:25 AM You have missed Rohini Movie park @koyambedu,which has got 5screens.........!!!!!

is it renovated??if u can pls. post some pics! balakannan31087 July 24th, 2011, 10:21 AM Chennai citi centre holdings Pvt.Ltd today said that they going to construct new mall in Ambattur, which also more bigger than Citi centre!:banana:
See today hindu&apos;s supplementary retail plus.
They also said about roof top hotel in citi centre:cheers:
citi centre also said they also first mall in TN with multiplex, while construction, when they approached licensing authorities, they relunctant to give license for multiple, as before there are only stand alone theatres, hence citi centre group makes them tour to see the mall in mumbai, bangalore, after seen there they given license
Citi centre is pioneer for mall with multiplex in chennai
Sathyam is pioneer for multiplex in TN&amp;chennai mr_madras July 24th, 2011, 01:52 PM You have missed Rohini Movie park @koyambedu,which has got 5screens.........!!!!!
Rohini has 6 screens(Rohini,rahini,rubini,rukmini,rakshini&amp;Ranjani) and all screens are bad conditions till last year. They do charge 80Rs max but viewers spoiled the entire atmosphere and hence rohini lost its family crowd from annanagar&amp;Mugappair. Logesh July 24th, 2011, 07:28 PM COROMANDAL PLAZA
http://img827.imageshack.us/img827/1311/dsc07266c.jpg (http://imageshack.us/photo/my-images/827/dsc07266c.jpg/)

Uploaded with ImageShack.us (http://imageshack.us)

RIVER SIDE MALL , Front views
http://img219.imageshack.us/img219/9301/dsc07276e.jpg (http://imageshack.us/photo/my-images/219/dsc07276e.jpg/)

Uploaded with ImageShack.us (http://imageshack.us)

http://img600.imageshack.us/img600/9459/dsc07277s.jpg (http://imageshack.us/photo/my-images/600/dsc07277s.jpg/)

Uploaded with ImageShack.us (http://imageshack.us)
http://img691.imageshack.us/img691/7131/dsc07278b.jpg (http://imageshack.us/photo/my-images/691/dsc07278b.jpg/)

Uploaded with ImageShack.us (http://imageshack.us)

Rear View
http://img96.imageshack.us/img96/8241/dsc07264a.jpg (http://imageshack.us/photo/my-images/96/dsc07264a.jpg/)

Uploaded with ImageShack.us (http://imageshack.us) Logesh July 24th, 2011, 07:34 PM I had been to the Phoenix market city consturction site too.. Looks like , it would be one heck of a mall , so big . Should come something like the express avenue. By the time I reahced there it was dark. Thought , it would be useless to take a foto at that time murlee July 25th, 2011, 02:07 AM awesome updates Logesh... thanks!! Arul Murugan July 25th, 2011, 02:15 AM Nice updates logesh.

Marg Mall is coming up nicely. I hope by next yr mid it gets opened.

Coromandel mall!! they should do some exterior works to make it attractive. But heard the multiplex there is doing good business!! vinodgopal July 25th, 2011, 03:18 AM Sounds like Chennai really wants to make a point regarding entertainment business. i wish they also open up more night clubs in these malls. Logesh July 25th, 2011, 04:44 AM Nice updates logesh.

Marg Mall is coming up nicely. I hope by next yr mid it gets opened.

Coromandel mall!! they should do some exterior works to make it attractive. But heard the multiplex there is doing good business!!

Yes, Thats right . You could not get tickets for the week end(except for the early morning show) unless u book in advance. The case is the same with fame too Arul Murugan July 25th, 2011, 05:38 AM T nagar walking street :nuts:

http://epaper.dinakaran.com/pdf/2011/07/25/20110725c_013101008.jpg

DKN Indian Sun July 25th, 2011, 06:33 AM ^^ sitting duck :ohno: Raji7373 July 25th, 2011, 06:38 AM :ohno::ohno:Night clubs in malls

Let it be a stand alone one&amp;not mingled with malls..

Sounds like Chennai really wants to make a point regarding entertainment business. i wish they also open up more night clubs in these malls. Raji7373 July 25th, 2011, 06:41 AM I had been to the Phoenix market city consturction site too.. Looks like , it would be one heck of a mall , so big . Should come something like the express avenue. By the time I reahced there it was dark. Thought , it would be useless to take a foto at that time

Yes it would be bigger than Express avenue when you compare the total over all space...

http://www.phoenixmarketcity.in/chennai/chennai_project_breakup.html Vicvin86 July 25th, 2011, 12:14 PM ^^ sitting duck :ohno:
Which one? Indian Sun July 25th, 2011, 01:14 PM ^^ T. Nagar. Arul Murugan July 25th, 2011, 02:39 PM ^^

http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2134/5775920795_e4a1d036d4_b.jpg

Photo owner: seeveeaar-flickr (http://www.flickr.com/photos/seeveeaar/5775920795/sizes/l/in/photostream/) Arul Murugan July 25th, 2011, 02:43 PM ^^ T. Nagar.

Unless economic/budget malls comes at Gudur, Nellore, Gumidipoondi, Sullurpettai, North Chennai, Chengalpattu, Kanchipuram, Arrakonam, Sriperumbudur etc., even Vellore, Chitoor, Tirupati T.nagar&apos;s ranganathan theru would be like this only!! Indian Sun July 25th, 2011, 02:48 PM I meant the safety aspect. All kinds of safety. Vicvin86 July 25th, 2011, 02:52 PM People there are watchful. vinodgopal July 25th, 2011, 02:58 PM Unless economic/budget malls comes at Gudur, Nellore, Gumidipoondi, Sullurpettai, North Chennai, Chengalpattu, Kanchipuram, Arrakonam, Sriperumbudur etc., even Vellore, Chitoor, Tirupati T.nagar&apos;s ranganathan theru would be like this only!!

this is what amazes me and i have often said Chennai&apos;s shopping culture is still old fashioned.

Paris corner for wholesale and houseware items and T Nagar and purasawalkam for clothing and retail items summarizes our shopping culture. Vicvin86 July 25th, 2011, 03:04 PM Unless economic/budget malls comes at Gudur, Nellore, Gumidipoondi, Sullurpettai, North Chennai, Chengalpattu, Kanchipuram, Arrakonam, Sriperumbudur etc., even Vellore, Chitoor, Tirupati T.nagar&apos;s ranganathan theru would be like this only!!

There are shopping places in towns you have mentioned but the way they are connected to the city still makes people to travel to Madras for shopping. And they come here only during festivals. BTW why everyone insisting on malls? In Madras people will do shopping in malls only when T Nagar biggies open shops in quite few of them. kannan infratech July 25th, 2011, 03:11 PM After a very long time, I visited MayaJal complex yesterday.

It is still the same or gone worse than before.

But huge crowds.

Satyam, Escape, Inox are better. I have not visited the new ones yet. vinodgopal July 25th, 2011, 03:15 PM plus we guya like bargaining a lot. in malls no question of bargaining and a fixed price. people think they would end up paying for adverts and AC/rental as a part of merchandise purchased in these places such as malls and ivory towers. And of course who would want to buy a Ralph Lauren T shirt at Rs.3000 in a multi brand showroom in say Spensors plaza when in T Nagar a decent Tirupur export reject can be bought in less than Rs.200 a piece. Arul Murugan July 25th, 2011, 03:20 PM There are shopping places in towns you have mentioned but the way they are connected to the city still makes people to travel to Madras for shopping. And they come here only during festivals. BTW why everyone insisting on malls? In Madras people will do shopping in malls only when T Nagar biggies open shops in quite few of them.

I agree! Thats why I have mentioned those towns in suburban routes. Also T.Nagar has become like another attraction of Chennai for people coming from other parts of the state! After Marina, Anna Samathi, MGR Samathi... they also land up in Chennai&apos;s T.nagar. It has become asculture buying clothing for relatives or families when they visit Chennai.. that too only from T.nagar.. not from express avenue or spencers etc.,

T.Nagar state based retail shops are no way less than those in express avenue or spencer or upcoming malls! Indian Sun July 25th, 2011, 03:36 PM ^^ +1. I realized that while scouting for items for my life abroad (higher studies).

T.Nagar may be a frustrating experience, but it&apos;s got several options and price ranges that EA or Ampa or Spencer&apos;s just do not have.

My mother too prefers the local grocery store (Pazhamudir Solai) to Reliance Fresh, More or Big Bazaar (all 3 of which are close to my residence).

What&apos;s wrong in us having a local identity ? Why can&apos;t malls and shopping districts co-exist ? Same case with food. I wish for a vada-pav today, a pizza tomorrow, and idly-vadai day after. Chennai caters to all 3 wishes. kannan infratech July 25th, 2011, 03:51 PM Chennai - T Nagar / Pursawakkam
Delhi - Sarojini Market
Mumbai - Dadar
Bangalore - Majestic

Far better than malls for shopping.

In Malls, the mark up is very steep.

The differences - AC&amp;clean environment.

I enjoy more in small eateries than the top ones - not because of the cost. For the exclusive taste.

I used to kalai one of my chef friends in a 5 star hotel - they make 5 different types of Masala Currys. They make 150 items from the same. (same taste). They dress it so well and explain for 30 minutes. Gullible clients eat in awe. :lol: Arul Murugan July 25th, 2011, 03:55 PM ^^

Delhi - Chandni Chowk
Bengaluru - Chickpet bonoslack7 July 25th, 2011, 04:00 PM Chennai-Luz, Adyar, T.Nagar, Puraswakkam, khader nawaz khan road, etc.etc wlbkng July 25th, 2011, 06:49 PM ^^


Bengaluru - Chickpet

:lol: kaja_asif July 26th, 2011, 08:16 AM which one these mall will open first

1. Phoneix market city mall at Vellachery
2. Prestige fourm mall at Vadapalni
3. Marg junction mall at OMR
4. PS Grand mall at Vellachery
5. Grande gold souk mall at GST road

I think when all these malls open surely mall standard will improve in chennai also.

I read in article says the metro cities delhi stands first with more than 35 malls, mumbai second with 30 malls,Bangalore third with 19 malls, kolkotta fourth with 13 malls, hyderabad fifth with 7 malls and chennai sixth last with 5 malls.

chennai needs to overcome hyderabad. bangalore its not possible..

chandra metro mall anchors shopper list and food court list please provide any one who visited the mall. kaja_asif July 26th, 2011, 08:19 AM arrange the malls i order of standard, shops, ambiance, crowd and quality

spenzer, citi centre, ampa mal, express avenue, chandra mall, abirami mall. dineshderick July 26th, 2011, 08:22 AM Chennai-Luz, Adyar, T.Nagar, Puraswakkam, khader nawaz khan road, etc.etc

Also G A Road, PondyBazar........ dineshderick July 26th, 2011, 08:24 AM which one these mall will open first


I think first Marg junction mall at OMR
then Prestige fourm mall at Vadapalni dineshderick July 26th, 2011, 08:27 AM arrange the malls i order of standard, shops, ambiance, crowd and quality

spenzer, citi centre, ampa mal, express avenue, chandra mall, abirami mall.

1.Express Avenue
2.Citi Center
3.Ampa Mall
4.Abirami Mall
5.Spenzer
6.Chandra Mall Note: (This will soon over take spenzer and Abirami.) mr_madras July 26th, 2011, 09:07 AM Coromandel mall is missing in the list even though anchor stores yet to open and i guess spectrum (Venus) mall perambur may open early Indian Sun July 26th, 2011, 11:06 AM Chandra Mall looks good from the outside. Didn&apos;t go in.

Something has to be done about the traffic on Arcot Road. It is already becoming a West Chennai shopping district, with Forum Mall, Kamala Multiplex, Raahat Plaza, Doshi Complex, Matrix Mall, Chandra Mall, Shopper&apos;s Stop and Megamart. Besides, there&apos;s the Vadapalani Bus Terminus.

Monorail ? MA Eswaran July 26th, 2011, 11:29 AM If Arcot road is not improved, this part will go the way of north chennai darkprinz July 26th, 2011, 12:45 PM I dont know ,why we people make so much noise about t.nagar being a shopping hub .. As indiansun said, it offers you everything in every price range !

And as told before it has become one of the visiting places for people who are new to our city .. I even knew many people from here,who boast that they shopped in t.nagar when they were to chennai for official visits etc.,

Its a place where both wealthy and poor people get what they want ! It doesnt mean it sells only cheap goods .. Please come out of that idea..

Yes ofcourse ..We need to improve pedestrian infrastructure , improve and integrate transportatin system .. And do some branding exercise .. :) it has good potential to become best shopping district in subcontinent region IMO chennaidesi July 26th, 2011, 04:45 PM Here&apos;s the Complete story about Mall scenario

Existing Malls (This list has already been given by me)
http://img23.imageshack.us/img23/111/unled3bn.jpg
Calculated on GLA (Gross Leasable/Lettable area).

Upcoming Malls (Time Frame 2014)
http://img837.imageshack.us/img837/9928/unled4o.jpg
Calculated on SBA (Total Area). Figures given as per builder&apos;s specification. Please note that actual area may vary after construction as often happens.
The GLA is calculated on approx by reducing 35% of SBA as per existing rule.

For those who has seen the list and thinking of Bangalore as the winner, here&apos;s the caution



I&apos;ve just mentioned the key points from the 33&amp;31 page reports of Bangalore&amp;Kolkata. Since it is getting longer, I&apos;ve omitted details of Hyderabad&amp;Chennai. But the South Indian Cities Report ends like this.

CHENNAI: Still Untapped
Compared to its two competing metros in South India, Chennai, with a total of just 19 malls (existing + new) by 2014, is in a much better position. The 14 new malls under construction in Chennai have a combined GLA of 4.12 million square feet. This will lead to total mall space supply of 6.307 million square feet by 2014, against an estimated demand of 9.13 million square feet, thus leading to 31% undersupply in this Southern metro.

BANGALORE: Certain Disaster
Bangalore may have 55 malls by 2014. As many as 38 new malls are under construction or planning, with a GLA of 12.601 million square feet, to add to the 17 existing malls. According to our research, this will lead to total mall space supply of 16.505 million square feet by 2014, covering only 85% of the cityâ€™s geographical area, against an estimated demand of only 9.698
million square feet, leading to an alarming 42% oversupply.

HYDERABAD: Not Too Bad
Greater Hyderabad may have 26 malls by 2014. Thus, the total
mall space (existing and upcoming) by 2014, covering about 80% of the city by geographical spread, is expected to be 7.655 million square feet, against an estimated demand of only 6.231 million square feet in this area, a case of about 19% oversupply.

Report Courtesy ASIPAC

Nice analysis murlee July 26th, 2011, 05:17 PM A 18 page report on the mall space in Chennai by ASIPAC

http://www.asipac.com/download.php?file=1306931881Asipac%20Study-Mall%20Demand%20Supply%20in%20Chennai%20-%2001%20Jun%202011.pdf&amp;fl=1 Raji7373 July 26th, 2011, 06:12 PM Most of the malls in Bangalore - gopalan mall&amp;total mall are not so good.
Especially Total mall - cannot be called as mall by any standards. Most of the total malls half occupied with vacated stores, very less people.
You can sense the over supply... darkprinz July 26th, 2011, 07:13 PM Most of the malls in Bangalore - gopalan mall&amp;total mall are not so good.
Especially Total mall - cannot be called as mall by any standards. Most of the total malls half occupied with vacated stores, very less people.
You can sense the over supply...

+1 Exactly my thought ...

Total mall in madiwala is worst ... Very less shops ... its nothing like mall ,....There is no lift facility for second floor ... u need to take an escalator to third floor and come down to Ground floor by lift ... Don&apos;t understand the logic behind this arrangement anyway :bash:

Much hyped Central mall looks more like Big Bazaar except that u get costlier brand products ... I also doesn&apos;t give u that feel of a mall ...


IMO Forum mall is the best in most terms.. next comes Mantri ... :) Indian Sun July 26th, 2011, 07:36 PM ^^ I agree with you two on every point, but I think we should shift our discussion 350km east. :) chennaidesi July 26th, 2011, 07:37 PM And never take this discussions to Bgl thread. lexraja July 26th, 2011, 07:42 PM +1 Exactly my thought ...

Total mall in madiwala is worst ... Very less shops ... its nothing like mall ,....There is no lift facility for second floor ... u need to take an escalator to third floor and come down to Ground floor by lift ... Don&apos;t understand the logic behind this arrangement anyway :bash:

Much hyped Central mall looks more like Big Bazaar except that u get costlier brand products ... I also doesn&apos;t give u that feel of a mall ...


IMO Forum mall is the best in most terms.. next comes Mantri ... :)




I think we need to come to a consensus as to what constitutes a mall .:)

Neenga solradha vachu patha then summa kaanum building a katti naalu kadaya vachu Mallunu Hype panra madhiri Theriyudhu Bangalore la . By that logic the malls in the list below also need to figure in the list of malls in Chennai especially Alsa Mall which was one of the earliest malls in Chennai and Prince Plaza .Also there are numerous places with the suffix arcade ,towers and plaza all of which could be counted as malls :) Big Bazaar excluded :lol:

http://www.spiritofchennai.com/shopping/prince.htm

This list does not include Ampa Skywalk and a few others . The current count will be around 30 then . :) Indian Sun July 26th, 2011, 07:44 PM There never really are discussions on the 2 cities there. There are just fights and abuse-counter abuse.

Ispahani Centre and Alsa Mall (as raja said) have been left out. Also, if Central makes the cut, so should Globus, T. Nagar. darkprinz July 26th, 2011, 08:01 PM To be Noted : I didn&apos;t compare Bangalore and Chennai malls anywhere in my previous post ... I just posted my opinion about some malls in Bangalore listed in that article..

:runaway: Yaaru manadhayum punpadutha illai ... Bangalore ppl yaarum enkitte sandai ku varadheenga :P Indian Sun July 26th, 2011, 08:07 PM ^^ Anga post pannala la ? Anga vaayi kuduthu maatina dhaan prachanai. Sondha anubhavam. bonoslack7 July 26th, 2011, 09:01 PM metrozone mall is larger than market city? darkprinz July 26th, 2011, 09:02 PM Indiansun : ya ya... Theriyum ennakum anubhavam irukku ... :nuts: ange lam post panle :lol:

Bono : Where is this Metro zone coming up ... ?? First time am hearing about it bonoslack7 July 26th, 2011, 09:10 PM anna nagar....google it sridhar_n July 27th, 2011, 06:41 AM Chandra Mall looks good from the outside. Didn&apos;t go in.

Something has to be done about the traffic on Arcot Road. It is already becoming a West Chennai shopping district, with Forum Mall, Kamala Multiplex, Raahat Plaza, Doshi Complex, Matrix Mall, Chandra Mall, Shopper&apos;s Stop and Megamart. Besides, there&apos;s the Vadapalani Bus Terminus.

Monorail ?

add to that corp office of Michelin (in Shyamala Towers), AVM studios ; you have got Pizza hut, Dominos, KFC and now I hear that McDonalds is coming up near Megamart.

something has to be done to decongest the place. The vadapalani flyover, when it comes, should help a little bit. But from the junction upto Porur, the road is too narrow, haphazard parking making it very congested and difficult. mr_madras July 27th, 2011, 08:18 AM Bono : Where is this Metro zone coming up ... ?? First time am hearing about it

On IRR between Thirumangalam Jn&amp;Cooum river kaja_asif July 27th, 2011, 08:27 AM 1.Express Avenue
2.Citi Center
3.Ampa Mall
4.Abirami Mall
5.Spenzer
6.Chandra Mall Note: (This will soon over take spenzer and Abirami.)


Citi centre at second place and ampa mall at third place. on what basis u given citi centre second place. can you give details..

i think chandra mall u can give 4th place ... vinodgopal July 27th, 2011, 09:05 AM why the names Chandra mall, Abhirami etc...

all fit for nothing local names. They gotta learn to keep modern trendy international names. Our city thinks local which is why late progression happens. Indian Sun July 27th, 2011, 10:01 AM ^^ How does the name matter, as long as a mall is good ? If Express Avenue is renamed Viraivu Paathai Maaligai tomorrow, will you stop visiting it ?

If a shopping arcade is named Souk Madinat Jumeirah in Dubai, it&apos;s cool.
If Bangkok is called Krung Thep Mahanakhon, it&apos;s cool.
But if a place in Chennai has a Tamil name it&apos;s conservative and un-metropolitan.

It&apos;s already tiring that builders use names like Birchwood, Maplewood, Bollywood for their projects when there are some very sweet Indian names (Ekanta, Aashiana, Svasti, Antariksa - I think Jains and TVH are good at this stuff)

Double standards. vinodgopal July 27th, 2011, 10:08 AM ^^ How does the name matter, as long as a mall is good ? If Express Avenue is renamed Viraivu Paathai Maaligai tomorrow, will you stop visiting it ?

If a shopping arcade is named Souk Madinat Jumeirah in Dubai, it&apos;s cool.
If Bangkok is called Krung Thep Mahanakhon, it&apos;s cool.
But if a place in Chennai has a Tamil name it&apos;s conservative and un-metropolitan.

It&apos;s already tiring that builders use names like Birchwood, Maplewood, Bollywood for their projects when there are some very sweet Indian names (Ekanta, Aashiana, Svasti, Antariksa - I think Jains and TVH are good at this stuff)

Double standards.

^^

andha names ku chandra mall abhirami mall is okay. yeppa what odd sounding oddly spelt words they give in some parts of the world. Indian Sun July 27th, 2011, 10:10 AM ^^ With the japanese investing in Chennai, you might soon see Shinjuku Mall and what not. vinodgopal July 27th, 2011, 10:19 AM ^^ With the japanese investing in Chennai, you might soon see Shinjuku Mall and what not.

and Chennai metro rail will be named&quot;nikkumo nikkadho&quot;perhaps Indian Sun July 27th, 2011, 10:43 AM ^^ :lol:. That would be more appropriate for our buses. Arul Murugan July 27th, 2011, 10:49 AM ^^ :lol:. That would be more appropriate for our buses.

Odummo Odatho. kannan infratech July 27th, 2011, 01:18 PM I think Malls&amp;Multiplexes are used very frequently without actually understanding the true meaning. I think that I had explained a year or two earlier. For the newbies:

MALL:
There are many Shopping Complexes which are also called Malls in the advertisements.
As per the convention&amp;business circle parlance, Malls can be called so only if
The area of occupation is Large or High Value (Gold / Diamond etc) in case of little lesser area.
There should be large Anchor Stores, who individually occupy say 15% or more area of the total (who actually ensure higher footfalls)
There should be a mix of merchandise (Super markets will not qualify).
Vanilla Stores - may be smaller - but sell different merchandise - may not pull footfalls individually - but bask in the reflected footfalls from the Anchors.
There should be ample Car Parking.
There should be Public Amenities. (Many malls abroad are having attached rail stations also. Creches are also there)
There should be entertainment - Movies, Play Areas, Children Play Areas.
There should be Food Courts.
Multiplexes are preferred in the malls mainly to attract repeated Footfalls. We keep going to different movies and so may also buy.

SPENCER PLAZA is not a Mall. Express Avenue is. Spencer could not change over to a mall status.

There are smaller versions (NOT Malls) where the Multiplex / Movie Halls are the Anchors and not Big shops. The Vanilla Stores will depend on the pull of the Multiplexes. In some places, Food Courts&amp;Children Play areas are added. These are called Family Entertainment Centres.

MULTIPLEX:
Multiplex is different from conventional cinema halls. In Multiplexes, same movie can be shown in multiple theatres with few minutes intervals using the same film rolls. There is no fixed movie in fixed hall. Depending on the crowd / pre booking, authorities can change even at the last minute.

SATYAM Complex is not Multiplex. Mayajal is. Mad 4 Madras July 27th, 2011, 02:03 PM Odummo Odatho.
:rofl: vinodgopal July 27th, 2011, 03:17 PM Alsa mall is called a mall then. Why is it so? kannan infratech July 27th, 2011, 03:18 PM Alsa mall is called a mall then. Why is it so?

named so by its developer Alsa Properties. Raji7373 July 27th, 2011, 06:47 PM And never take this discussions to Bgl thread.

I had to quote it becuase - useless malls have been posted as one among malls and raised the numbers to show or maintain city&apos;s hype..

Central mall, total malls are total waste...okey I am jumping :nuts: 350 km east now...forget it. Raji7373 July 27th, 2011, 06:51 PM I think we need to come to a consensus as to what constitutes a mall .:)

Neenga solradha vachu patha then summa kaanum building a katti naalu kadaya vachu Mallunu Hype panra madhiri Theriyudhu Bangalore la . http://www.spiritofchennai.com/shopping/prince.htm



yes exactly...alsa mall is way better than this...don&apos;t compare alsa mall thooku potukum..:lol:
(I have not gone to alsa for ages..but it was good place to shop those days..when I was in college)
Even in wiki list you can see Chennai has more number of malls... balakannan31087 July 28th, 2011, 04:30 AM I think Malls&amp;Multiplexes are used very frequently without actually understanding the true meaning. I think that I had explained a year or two earlier. For the newbies:

MALL:
There are many Shopping Complexes which are also called Malls in the advertisements.
As per the convention&amp;business circle parlance, Malls can be called so only if
The area of occupation is Large or High Value (Gold / Diamond etc) in case of little lesser area.
There should be large Anchor Stores, who individually occupy say 15% or more area of the total (who actually ensure higher footfalls)
There should be a mix of merchandise (Super markets will not qualify).
Vanilla Stores - may be smaller - but sell different merchandise - may not pull footfalls individually - but bask in the reflected footfalls from the Anchors.
There should be ample Car Parking.
There should be Public Amenities. (Many malls abroad are having attached rail stations also. Creches are also there)
There should be entertainment - Movies, Play Areas, Children Play Areas.
There should be Food Courts.
Multiplexes are preferred in the malls mainly to attract repeated Footfalls. We keep going to different movies and so may also buy.

SPENCER PLAZA is not a Mall. Express Avenue is. Spencer could not change over to a mall status.

There are smaller versions (NOT Malls) where the Multiplex / Movie Halls are the Anchors and not Big shops. The Vanilla Stores will depend on the pull of the Multiplexes. In some places, Food Courts&amp;Children Play areas are added. These are called Family Entertainment Centres.

MULTIPLEX:
Multiplex is different from conventional cinema halls. In Multiplexes, same movie can be shown in multiple theatres with few minutes intervals using the same film rolls. There is no fixed movie in fixed hall. Depending on the crowd / pre booking, authorities can change even at the last minute.

SATYAM Complex is not Multiplex. Mayajal is.


For multiplex,the definition said by u above is correct, in addition there is another definition -cinema halls with more than 3 screens is also known as multiplex-which may also referred to as cineplex.
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiplex_(movie_theater)
Hence Satyam is too multiplex, even in sathyam same film is screened more than one screen(most of times)[tomorrow vappam films is screening in both Studio-5 and 6 degrees on sathyam complex]
cinema halls with more than 10 halls is known as Megaplex vinodgopal July 28th, 2011, 09:28 AM For multiplex,the definition said by u above is correct, in addition there is another definition -cinema halls with more than 3 screens is also known as multiplex-which may also referred to as cineplex.
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiplex_(movie_theater)
Hence Satyam is too multiplex, even in sathyam same film is screened more than one screen(most of times)[tomorrow vappam films is screening in both Studio-5 and 6 degrees on sathyam complex]
cinema halls with more than 10 halls is known as Megaplex

oh so mayajaal is a megaplex. am i right kaja_asif July 28th, 2011, 10:14 AM multtiplex will have common projector room in bio-level. because of that they can show the film in more than single screen with 10 to 15 min interval.

i think in chennai INOX, PVR,Fame, mayajaal, AGS having bio-level projector room, so they can possible to screen movies in multiple screen 10 - 15 minutes interval.

Escape there is no projector room, it has automatic projector which is hanged in high-level u can see from the lobby. flims are automatically run with comments from computer. here also possible to screen single flim in multiple screen.

In sathyam there is no common projector room for sathyam and santham. apart from these subham and seasons have common projector room, sutido 5 and six degree has common projector room. any way here all the flims are screend in digital format so flim projector not required only digital projector required which receives the signal from satellite and prject to screen. so its possible to screen single flim in multiple screens. kannan infratech July 28th, 2011, 10:39 AM Satellite Feed is not yet implemented commercially in India.

Even digital format screening happens only in few theatres.

We still use film rolls but using a Spl projector system in a multiplex.

Multiple Theatres is not Multiplex (Wiki is wrong). purapagal July 28th, 2011, 01:59 PM Satellite Feed is not yet implemented commercially in India.

Even digital format screening happens only in few theatres.

We still use film rolls but using a Spl projector system in a multiplex.

Multiple Theatres is not Multiplex (Wiki is wrong).

India has moved on from the&quot;film roll&quot;delivery model specially Mumbai, Chennai, Andhra film industries to digital. That is why now a days even tier II and III cities have screening of latest movies withing the same opening weeks as in metros. Also if you see when viewing a movies in the multiplexes you will not see the sudden roll change on screen which you could have seen earlier. kannan infratech July 28th, 2011, 02:30 PM India has moved on from the&quot;film roll&quot;delivery model specially Mumbai, Chennai, Andhra film industries to digital. That is why now a days even tier II and III cities have screening of latest movies withing the same opening weeks as in metros. Also if you see when viewing a movies in the multiplexes you will not see the sudden roll change on screen which you could have seen earlier.

In multiplexes, film reels are fed into one projector and with a time delay the same reels are fed into the next projector or second projection unit of the same system and so on. This is totally automated system. (No change of reels etc)

The word Digital is used loosely be the industry. If the operation is computer controlled, it does not mean&quot;Digital&quot;. Only of late, movies are taken in the digital format by not using film roles.

New Multiplexes may also have Satellite fed flicks depending on the customer demand. Anniyan July 28th, 2011, 02:42 PM India has moved on from the&quot;film roll&quot;delivery model specially Mumbai, Chennai, Andhra film industries to digital. That is why now a days even tier II and III cities have screening of latest movies withing the same opening weeks as in metros. Also if you see when viewing a movies in the multiplexes you will not see the sudden roll change on screen which you could have seen earlier.

Thats nothing new. Anniyan July 28th, 2011, 02:45 PM In multiplexes, film reels are fed into one projector and with a time delay the same reels are fed into the next projector or second projection unit of the same system and so on. This is totally automated system. (No change of reels etc)

The word Digital is used loosely be the industry. If the operation is computer controlled, it does not mean&quot;Digital&quot;. Only of late, movies are taken in the digital format by not using film roles.

New Multiplexes may also have Satellite fed flicks depending on the customer demand.

All tamil films released in the UK are delivered on a hard drive.

Perhaps there is a technology to convert the video from reel to digital format. kannan infratech July 28th, 2011, 02:53 PM Tamil films released in the UK are delivered on a hard drive.

For overseas market, they are converted into digital to match the theatre system abroad.

Actually the piracy happens only in those labs where this conversion work is being done.

Though I am not into the tech part of the film making, my friends have been telling that it is much cheaper to shoot in digital format and it may catch big time in Kollywood.

In a recent Directors meeting, KS Ravikumar has suggested to release overseas digital format also in India on the first day. There seem to be some issue on payments etc, which is based on the first copy. So the financiers / producers insist on film roles.

I am not well versed in this and may be wrong or not accurate. vinodgopal July 28th, 2011, 03:04 PM In multiplexes, film reels are fed into one projector and with a time delay the same reels are fed into the next projector or second projection unit of the same system and so on. This is totally automated system. (No change of reels etc)

The word Digital is used loosely be the industry. If the operation is computer controlled, it does not mean&quot;Digital&quot;. Only of late, movies are taken in the digital format by not using film roles.

New Multiplexes may also have Satellite fed flicks depending on the customer demand.


See sir, 35 mm reel is not digital at all. Usually they take movies in 35 mm film camera and convert them into digital and are shown in theaters supporting Qube or UFO digital. The satellite option is still in the child crawling stages where across theaters from a common harddrive they transmit and so the shows are predetermined in advance. This technology is common in Hollywood and other advanced countries however in India it is at a low percentage.

Most film producers in hollywood and other forward thinking film industries have started using digital cameras (first Full HD was used and now it supports Red One which can go upto 4K resolutions) in film production itself eliminating costs in conversion and post production film editing. And secondly it can be aired in Satellite or can be easily transported to theaters supporting digital projectors.

Mumbai Express had a production cost of just 2 crores as a result of it while for the same Virumandi had about 20 crores production cost. Why because of digital camera used in Mumbai Express. (But a very poor resolution HD DV Cam) purapagal July 28th, 2011, 04:32 PM Multiplex owners face technology pangs (http://www.boxofficeindia.co.in/one-two-ka-4k/)


If you thought that 3D screens were the ultimate innovation in the exhibition space. Then you need to rethink. With newer technology knocking at our doors almost every second, it is now the 4K digital projection systems that are creating a buzz across the cinema industry these days.

It all happened when the latest action 3D franchise from Paramount Pictures, Transformers: Dark Of The Moon was released on June 29. Urvashi Cinema chain, a single screen cinema in Bangalore screened the film with its newly installed 4K digital projection systems by U.S based visual technology company Christie Digital Systems USA, Inc. The installation was done by Scrabble which is Christies deployment partner in India.

Urvashi cinema is Bangalores biggest 3D cinema, which is equipped with a capacity of 1,161 seats and Transformers had a run for two weeks there. Using two Christie CP4230, this dual projection with an xpand active 3D system on screen of 60ft by 26 ft, it is the first ever 4 K digital cinema projection in a commercial cinema in India.

Amit R Gowda, CEO, Urvashi Cinema says that, 4K is a premium experience even going by worldwide standards. We always want to give our patrons the best viewing quality, which is why we made the bold move of installing Christie CP4230 digital cinema projector, another reason being our belief in pursuing excellence.

The multiplex industry is slated to grow at a steady pace. At a recently held Cinema India Expo, in Mumbai, global experts in digital cinema have forecasted that the E-cinema services across India would touch a figure of 6000 and around 700 DCI compliant projection (2K) cinema screens would be installed in India, by the end of 2011. By the global standards in the digital cinema industry, this is a significant number for the Indian digital cinema space.

What is 4K?
So what exactly is 4K? For the uninitiated, traditional 35mm, 2K digital projection, 4K digital projection, IMAX, digital IMAX, and digital 3D are among the cinema formats that are commonly used across the world. The important question remains that which format is the best to watch a film on? Movie fans may wonder whether it makes much difference if a film is witnessed in 2K projection instead of 4K projection. And cinema owners might ask themselves if its really worth it to update their projection equipment.

Higher image quality
A projector that has a 2K resolution means that it projects 2,000 pixels in an image at a time. A 4K projector puts out 4,000 pixels of an image onto the same size screen. If you sit very close to a screen that is using a 2K projector you are more likely to notice the pixels. The more pixels per screen, better is the quality of image. With 4K it is a lot harder to notice pixels as the image is more sharper and well defined, and more subtle details can come through that would be lost with a 2K projector.

Visual Difference
A 2K projection is at a slightly higher resolution than 1080p HD. To most eyes, this difference is not noticeable. This is also true of 4K resolution despite 4K projection having twice the resolution as 2K projection. The only way this really becomes noticeable is if you are watching a movie on a really big screen such as an IMAX screen. A small screen with twice the resolution wont be that noticeable.

The Future of 2K, 4K, and beyond
As of 2010, 6K projectors are already starting to roll out at movie theaters that wish to upgrade them. Three-dimensional cinema is starting to take off. Most 3D projectors are at 2K resolution, but 4K and 6K projectors exist. As of 2010, 3D projectors require the viewers to wear special glasses. This may change to where no glasses are needed.
Amitabh Vardhan, CEO, My Cinemas says that, 4K is the future of the Indian cinema industry and makes the viewing experience for the audience much better. The image quality gets enhanced with 4K digital projectors.

Most multiplexes are currently using 2K digital projectors which can be easily upgraded to 4K. However, none of the multiplexes have ventured into this space yet as they feel there is a lack of 4K content. It is quite similar to what happened with 3D films. The cinemas started upgrading to 3D only when 3D films flooded the country.

According to Anil Chopra, MD of Diversified Comm India, It is estimated that over USD 200 million would be invested by the Indian digital cinema industry in equipments.
But while 4K may be the swankiest technology for cinema owners, there are a few theatre owners who feel that it is too nascent a technology to invest in. The costs involved in upgrading a existing 2K screen to a 4K screen can range anywhere between Rs 25 lakhs to 40 lakhs and this is an investment that most multiplex owners are hesitant to make at the moment.

Vardhan also mentioned that, We need to have content that is shot in 4K in order to upgrade our screens. It is a useless expenditure for us if there are no 4K films, and we would be making dead investments by doing these technology upgradations.

At multiplexes like Cinemax, PVR, Fun and Inox, all screens are 4K upgradable but none of the projectors have been upgraded to 4K yet. Sunil Punjabi, CEO, Cinemax India says that, I dont see 4K as the future of the cinema space yet as the content needs to be customised to be shown on 4K. This technology works best at single screen cinema halls where the throw length is large otherwise in small theatres the image might get pixilated. He further adds that, I dont think it is wise to invest in 4K yet as 2K is already generating quite good results.

However, just like with 3D technology, this potential of 4K projections is something every theatre owner must take into account when trying to find the ideal projection system according to the seating capacity and length of the theatre.

Devang Sampat, Head of Strategy, Cinepolis India says that, The audience doesnt mind paying extra for picture clarity and good quality cinema. A few years ago all multiplexes were debating whether we should install 2K projectors or not. And the installation of 2K has generated such huge revenue for us. 4K will also have a similar impact in the coming years.


As seen from the report most multiplexes uses digital projection systems. I do not have the details whether the content is also available in digital format or not. But I have noticed pixelation when watching some movies. Anniyan July 28th, 2011, 04:37 PM The companies, which set up their equipment to facilitate beaming of the film without any physical film reel, are currently charging Rs. 7,000 per week from theatres for digital projection of films. The South Indian Film Chamber of Commerce asked the AP Film Chamber of Commerce recently to take steps to reduce the high rentals. The members at the meeting decided to bring down the rental to Rs 3,000 per week

http://www.galatta.com/entertainment/telugu/livewire/id/Digital_projection_Filmmakers_cut_rent_49685.html bonoslack7 July 28th, 2011, 11:32 PM which one these mall will open first

1. Phoneix market city mall at Vellachery
2. Prestige fourm mall at Vadapalni
3. Marg junction mall at OMR
4. PS Grand mall at Vellachery
5. Grande gold souk mall at GST road



you forgot spectrum/grand venus mall in perambur....thats going to open soon. balakannan31087 July 29th, 2011, 04:07 AM Satellite Feed is not yet implemented commercially in India.

Even digital format screening happens only in few theatres.

We still use film rolls but using a Spl projector system in a multiplex.

Multiple Theatres is not Multiplex (Wiki is wrong).

Satellite feed is available in India thru qube cinemas and UFO cinemas! which is getting used by most of the multiplex&apos;s even in local vettri theatre/varadharaja theatres in chromepet also using satellite feed balakannan31087 July 29th, 2011, 04:11 AM Multiplex owners face technology pangs (http://www.boxofficeindia.co.in/one-two-ka-4k/)



As seen from the report most multiplexes uses digital projection systems. I do not have the details whether the content is also available in digital format or not. But I have noticed pixelation when watching some movies.

u may seen it in some theatres in chennai INOX are not 100%digital, but PVR?SAthyam/escape are 100% digital. In INOX u can see scratches/pixellations in Screen1&amp;2 which are not digital, but same u cant see in INOX3&amp;4, Sathyam/escape/PVR.(i dont know about fame) balakannan31087 July 29th, 2011, 04:12 AM Satellite Feed is not yet implemented commercially in India.

Even digital format screening happens only in few theatres.

We still use film rolls but using a Spl projector system in a multiplex.

Multiple Theatres is not Multiplex (Wiki is wrong).

not only wiki, dictioneries too referring same wiki tells, then i am right:ohno:
http://dictionary.reference.com/browse/multiplex balakannan31087 July 29th, 2011, 04:14 AM Satellite Feed is not yet implemented commercially in India.

Even digital format screening happens only in few theatres.

We still use film rolls but using a Spl projector system in a multiplex.

Multiple Theatres is not Multiplex (Wiki is wrong).

Satellite feed is available in India thru qube cinemas and UFO cinemas! which is getting used by most of the multiplex&apos;s even in local vettri theatre/varadharaja theatres in chromepet also using satellite feed purapagal July 29th, 2011, 08:50 AM Satellite feed is available in India thru qube cinemas and UFO cinemas! which is getting used by most of the multiplex&apos;s even in local vettri theatre/varadharaja theatres in chromepet also using satellite feed

State-wise installation of UFO Cinema&apos;s digital platform (http://www.ufomoviez.com/UFO_Presence.aspx?mode=state)

They seem to have a good presence. And this is just 1 company. vinodgopal July 29th, 2011, 11:52 PM The companies, which set up their equipment to facilitate beaming of the film without any physical film reel, are currently charging Rs. 7,000 per week from theatres for digital projection of films. The South Indian Film Chamber of Commerce asked the AP Film Chamber of Commerce recently to take steps to reduce the high rentals. The members at the meeting decided to bring down the rental to Rs 3,000 per week

http://www.galatta.com/entertainment/telugu/livewire/id/Digital_projection_Filmmakers_cut_rent_49685.html


Mister Qube was charging Rs.50000 per show initially. Did you know?(back in 2005/6) Now 7000 per week looks too expensive huh? vinodgopal July 29th, 2011, 11:59 PM Satellite feed is available in India thru qube cinemas and UFO cinemas! which is getting used by most of the multiplex&apos;s even in local vettri theatre/varadharaja theatres in chromepet also using satellite feed

Please read my post replied to Kannan Infratech(who said digital is a mis used term by the market for each and every thing). Qube and UFO pioneered digital cinema projectors and different from satellite transmission because they started much before satellite feed technology. Sat feeds are used by Qube and Digital too these days but they are just players in the market. So dont automatically conclude that they only satellite transmit movies(It is as ambiguous as saying xerox means photocopy and photocopy means xerox. xerox is a company name and Cannon, HP can also photocopy. They have a myriad of products to offer including digital projection(through digital projectors supporting hard drives as well as optical discs(DVD&apos;s). Satellite telecast in theaters were found much later than Qube and UFO were pioneers in digital film auditoriums.

Forget Vetri theater and varadharaja theater which uses just a projector thats digital which is different from a 35 mm projector, Maayajaal itself does not use sat feed and they use DVD&apos;s projected into screens. Are you aware of it? (DVD projector which is one of the forms of digital projector) vinodgopal July 30th, 2011, 12:10 AM See sir, 35 mm reel is not digital at all. Usually they take movies in 35 mm film camera and convert them into digital and are shown in theaters supporting Qube or UFO digital. The satellite option is still in the child crawling stages where across theaters from a common harddrive they transmit and so the shows are predetermined in advance. This technology is common in Hollywood and other advanced countries however in India it is at a low percentage.

Most film producers in hollywood and other forward thinking film industries have started using digital cameras (first Full HD was used and now it supports Red One which can go upto 4K resolutions) in film production itself eliminating costs in conversion and post production film editing. And secondly it can be aired in Satellite or can be easily transported to theaters supporting digital projectors.

Mumbai Express had a production cost of just 2 crores as a result of it while for the same Virumandi had about 20 crores production cost. Why because of digital camera used in Mumbai Express. (But a very poor resolution HD DV Cam)

for your convenience i am quoting it one more time. balakannan31087 July 30th, 2011, 08:41 AM Please read my post replied to Kannan Infratech(who said digital is a mis used term by the market for each and every thing). Qube and UFO pioneered digital cinema projectors and different from satellite transmission because they started much before satellite feed technology. Sat feeds are used by Qube and Digital too these days but they are just players in the market. So dont automatically conclude that they only satellite transmit movies(It is as ambiguous as saying xerox means photocopy and photocopy means xerox. xerox is a company name and Cannon, HP can also photocopy. They have a myriad of products to offer including digital projection(through digital projectors supporting hard drives as well as optical discs(DVD&apos;s). Satellite telecast in theaters were found much later than Qube and UFO were pioneers in digital film auditoriums.

Forget Vetri theater and varadharaja theater which uses just a projector thats digital which is different from a 35 mm projector, Maayajaal itself does not use sat feed and they use DVD&apos;s projected into screens. Are you aware of it? (DVD projector which is one of the forms of digital projector)


In vettri theatre i am sure that they using satellite feed, i even seen dish above theatre and when i enquired about this in their facebook page they confirmed that they using satellite feed for more than three years. Mostly Qube cinemas is using satellite feed, hence only recently in pongal Kaavalan film released as much quickly at aroung 11a..m itself due to satellite feed and released late in some theates as there is no satellite feed kaja_asif July 30th, 2011, 12:14 PM which is better qube or UFO.

bangalore urvashi cinema single screen theater has installed 4K projector first in india. most of the chennai guys who visited says its much more better than sathyam cinemas. sathyam has to over come this. someone pass this message to sathyam. kannan infratech July 30th, 2011, 01:45 PM I checked up with my friends in Real Image who are into HD Advts&amp;movies.

What I understand

In India, most of the films are still taken by using films and only recently, movies are taken directly as digital. If you take directly in digital, the quality will be far superior.

The films taken by using film is converted into DVDs in the labs. In the process, the mistakes like scratches&amp;noises can be removed.

These DVDs are the projected in select theatres who have permanent facility with DVD Projectors.

For those theatres who do not have these projectors, some companies hire them out. There are various models. If they are allowed advt times in between, they do this for free. Or they share a %age on the collection. Or they charge a fixed price per show.

Many Corporate companies, who are into film distribution / exhibition are promoting this concept as it is cheaper for them to handle. But piracy also happens here and they lose heavily.

Satellite Feed at present is actually fixed time broadcast from a remote server. The receiving units are similar to Dish&amp;Set Top Boxes for DTH.

But the future will have multiple flicks available at the same time from a satellite and depending on the viewers / clients&apos; choices, any movie can be selected. Browsing may also be possible.

The screens of the theatres are also in for a change. Instead of front or back projection, that will also become HD screens.

Even outdoor advts with huge HD screens are expected. bonoslack7 July 31st, 2011, 05:51 AM http://www.deccanchronicle.com/channels/cities/chennai/chennai-mall-growth-set-explode-178

Shopping this Deepavali could be a completely new experience for Chennaiites if high-end retailers and real estate developers in the city make good on their plans to open a slew of swanky new air-conditioned malls.

Chennai added over 3.25 lakh sq. ft of mall space in the past three months. Six months from now, the city will have over 3 lakh sq. ft more mall space, paving way for a high-end shopping experience in almost every part of the city.

With the economy bouncing back, retail mall space supply across the country witnessed a growth of over 65 per cent in the second quarter, with Chennai contributing significantly to this, says realty research firm Cushman&amp;Wakefield (C&amp;W). The second half of 2011 will see an increase of mall room by approximately 3.1 lakh sq. ft, it adds.

Chandra Mall in Virugambakkam and Coromandel Mall on OMR fuelled mall growth during the quarter and also led to a surge in overall mall vacancy rate to 6.6 per cent. But this is expected to be sorted out in the next two months with retailers hankering for space ahead of the festival season.

Of the 2 lakh sq. ft in Coromandel Mall, only 40,000 sq. ft has been firmed up while the rest is the under negotiation. But we will have full occupancy before Deepavali, says Suryavardhan Estates director Mitu Sadarangani.

Confirming queries from big brands, Pon Ravichandran, director-projects of Ten Square Realty, says, We have already leased out 60 per cent of the 1.5 lakh sq. ft retail space in Ten Square Mall in Koyambedu, scheduled to open in two months. Other mall projects coming up in the city are the 1.5 lakh sq. ft Ramee Mall on Anna Salai and the 1.6 lakh sq. ft Spectrum Mall in Perambur.

The market is awaiting Parliaments decision on FDI in retail. If it is implemented, the supply side for retail will have more to look forward to, says Jaideep Wahi of C&amp;W. kaja_asif July 31st, 2011, 06:49 AM coramental mall outer interior must be taken care otherwise it looks like hotel in tirunelveli. people will not impressed... H Factor July 31st, 2011, 08:07 PM BIG BAZAAR has taken space in Coramandal mall, OMR. They are the anchor store. The 40K sq feet mentioned in the above news must be for Big Bazaar only. But i heard they ll be opening it in Dec only ceeznic pirate August 1st, 2011, 05:56 AM Dancers at b-boying finals make heads spin
Mumbai Team Wins Event Being Held In India For First Time

Even for a Sunday afternoon Express Avenue mall in Royapettah was rather more crowded than usual. Shoppers forgot the sale signs and stood entranced by boys who spun on their heads, turned, twisted and contorted themselves into unbelievable positions while a DJ kept playing hip-hop tracks. It was the India finals of the worlds biggest b-boying competition, Battle Of The Year (BOTY).

.......

TOI (http://epaper.timesofindia.com/Default/Scripting/ArticleWin.asp?From=Archive&amp;Source=Page&amp;Skin=TOINEW&amp;BaseHref=TOICH/2011/08/01&amp;PageLabel=3&amp;EntityId=Ar00300&amp;ViewMode=HTML) vinodgopal August 1st, 2011, 01:05 PM which is better qube or UFO.

bangalore urvashi cinema single screen theater has installed 4K projector first in india. most of the chennai guys who visited says its much more better than sathyam cinemas. sathyam has to over come this. someone pass this message to sathyam.

Qube is better but is more expensive. UFO is cheaper and usually considered only if budget constraints are there in a cineplex. 4K projectors need not necessarily project in 4K resolution. And also 4K resolution is supported by Red One does not mean it is going to give a 4K resolution always.

It all depends on the exposure and cinematographer skills and lighting effect. Similarly for those who think Digital camera is better than 35 mm, i am afraid they are wrong. Digital camera is just a rough equivalent to a 35 mm camera and clearly 35 mm cameras do not need much color correction while digital cameras need color corrections. Arul Murugan August 2nd, 2011, 07:22 AM Big mega mart!

http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6139/5993150239_f516c6f8b4_b.jpg

Anirudh2792, Flickr (http://www.flickr.com/photos/anirudh2792/5993150239/sizes/l/in/photostream/) Indian Sun August 2nd, 2011, 08:56 AM ^^ Arcot Road, Virugambakkam. It&apos;s a pretty good store. vinodgopal August 2nd, 2011, 02:35 PM ^^ Arcot Road, Virugambakkam. It&apos;s a pretty good store.

my wife hates this megamart. I dont know why. Arul Murugan August 2nd, 2011, 02:50 PM my wife hates this megamart. I dont know why.

nanga(i guess few more thought like me) unga post vechi, neenga ippo thaan college mudichitu company la senthirikinga nenaichom. j.k :) murlee August 2nd, 2011, 02:57 PM LOL yeah.. I was surprised on hearin that our Vinod Sir is married.. :lol: wlbkng August 2nd, 2011, 02:57 PM nanga(i guess few more thought like me) unga post vechi, neenga ippo thaan college mudichitu company la senthirikinga nenaichom. j.k :)

Arul, u r better.. I thought schooling.. :jk: satishanu August 2nd, 2011, 03:40 PM -del- Indian Sun August 2nd, 2011, 04:11 PM Cha Cha. We ilaygnars are not so critical.



You should hear my dad. He thinks Chennai (and India in general) is a lost cause. kannan infratech August 2nd, 2011, 05:03 PM Cha Cha. We ilaygnars are not so critical.



You should hear my dad. He thinks Chennai (and India in general) is a lost cause.

There are so many positives.

The only major negative about the most of the GenY is lack of physical activity. (too much time in front of Lappy / Telly&amp;Junk Food). kongutamizhan August 2nd, 2011, 05:22 PM The only major negative about the most of the GenY is lack of physical activity. (too much time in front of Lappy / Telly&amp;Junk Food).

che!! engalla madiri youth-a kora sollurathae sila perusungalukku velaaya pochi :)

Lappy, TV (electronic stores), food court illatha mall sollunga parpom? Naanga lappy, TV, Junk foodnu illanna innikku neenga Malls and Multiplex thread start senji inga pesikittu iruka mudiyuma? :lol: kannan infratech August 2nd, 2011, 05:24 PM che!! engalla madiri youth-a kora sollurathae sila perusungalukku velaaya pochi :)

Lappy, TV (electronic stores), food court illatha mall sollunga parpom? Naanga lappy, TV, Junk foodnu illanna innikku neenga Malls and Multiplex thread start senji inga pesikittu iruka mudiyuma? :lol:

Katchi maratheenga KT. Naan Youtha patthithan Sonnen. Ungalai Illa. murlee August 2nd, 2011, 05:29 PM Katchi maratheenga KT. Naan Youtha patthithan Sonnen. Ungalai Illa.

:hilarious: kongutamizhan August 2nd, 2011, 05:39 PM Katchi maratheenga KT. Naan Youtha patthithan Sonnen. Ungalai Illa.

:hilarious:

Inga check (http://www.skyscrapercity.com/showpost.php?p=82476467&amp;postcount=9557) pannunga. Youngest member of SSCI calls me Anna. Youth-a than appadi koopiduvanga. Uncle-skku ellam poramai :) Anniyan August 2nd, 2011, 05:42 PM nanga(i guess few more thought like me) unga post vechi, neenga ippo thaan college mudichitu company la senthirikinga nenaichom. j.k :)

thats possible too! if got married while in college. krishnaswamy August 2nd, 2011, 05:49 PM nanga(i guess few more thought like me) unga post vechi, neenga ippo thaan college mudichitu company la senthirikinga nenaichom. j.k :)
+1.. ila ratham kothikathunu nenaichom :lol::lol: Indian Sun August 2nd, 2011, 06:17 PM Inga check (http://www.skyscrapercity.com/showpost.php?p=82476467&amp;postcount=9557) pannunga. Youngest member of SSCI calls me Anna. Youth-a than appadi koopiduvanga. Uncle-skku ellam poramai :)

Neenga youth naa nanga kai-kuzhandaigal. :lol: kannan infratech August 2nd, 2011, 06:23 PM Neenga youth naa nanga kai-kuzhandaigal. :lol:

KT Pozhachu Pogattum.

We will make him the President of the Youth Wing of Namitha Rasigar Mandram.

(Stalin kooda DMK Youth wing President illa ?) Indian Sun August 2nd, 2011, 06:48 PM KT Pozhachu Pogattum.

We will make him the President of the Youth Wing of Namitha Rasigar Mandram.

(Stalin kooda DMK Youth wing President illa ?)

http://youtu.be/SgDjRDHzbrw?t=58s (watch from 0:58) ChennaiIndian August 3rd, 2011, 01:56 AM Inga check (http://www.skyscrapercity.com/showpost.php?p=82476467&amp;postcount=9557) pannunga. Youngest member of SSCI calls me Anna. Youth-a than appadi koopiduvanga. Uncle-skku ellam poramai :)
Summa anna ginnanu sonneengana, ootla vandhu adipom! :D ChennaiIndian August 3rd, 2011, 01:58 AM ^^ Arcot Road, Virugambakkam. It&apos;s a pretty good store.
Virugambakathulla mall-a? Kaalam romba maari pochu pa! vinodgopal August 3rd, 2011, 02:24 AM nanga(i guess few more thought like me) unga post vechi, neenga ippo thaan college mudichitu company la senthirikinga nenaichom. j.k :)

i am just 32 years young. And dont go by posts to judge a person&apos;s age. wlbkng August 3rd, 2011, 08:30 AM Virugambakathulla mall-a? Kaalam romba maari pochu pa!

vandalur, chengalpattu la ellam varum podhu en sir virugambakkathukku vara kudadhu? Indian Sun August 3rd, 2011, 08:49 AM ^^ Add to that Chandra Metro Mall in Vgm. Arul Murugan August 3rd, 2011, 08:52 AM vandalur, chengalpattu la ellam varum podhu en sir virugambakkathukku vara kudadhu?

Gold souk in Vandalur!

whats that coming up in Chengalpattu? wlbkng August 3rd, 2011, 09:11 AM Gold souk in Vandalur!

whats that coming up in Chengalpattu?

I was indirectly referring to the shopping mall called &apos;The Canopy&apos; at Mahindra world city just before chengalpattu..

Also there are malls coming up at Estancia SEZ near Guduvanchery and Shriram SEZ Mall at Perungalathur.

I wish someone constructs a shopping mall in Tambaram. Its one of the biggest junctions of city but it doesn&apos;t even have one mall (though Shanmugam road is like Tnagar Ranganathan st). It will have footfalls from residents across GST road, Mudhichur road, Camp road, Velachery road and nearby localities. Arul Murugan August 3rd, 2011, 09:40 AM I was indirectly referring to the shopping mall called &apos;The Canopy&apos; at Mahindra world city just before chengalpattu..

Also there are malls coming up at Estancia SEZ near Guduvanchery and Shriram SEZ Mall at Perungalathur.

I wish someone constructs a shopping mall in Tambaram. Its one of the biggest junctions of city but it doesn&apos;t even have one mall (though Shanmugam road is like Tnagar Ranganathan st). It will have footfalls from residents across GST road, Mudhichur road, Camp road, Velachery road and nearby localities.

Yes!

When retails went down on OMR till Navallur, I wonder why not at Tambaram, Chromepet etc!

Tambaram mall can attract even Pallavaram, Chromepet crowds. Once malls at Vels open up, Alandur, Nangallur people will go to Vels rather than going to central Chennai. wlbkng August 3rd, 2011, 09:45 AM ^^ I think cost and land availability are the biggest problems for one to start constructing a mall at Tambaram.. kannan infratech August 3rd, 2011, 10:19 AM A mall in Tambaram may come up in between GST Road&amp;Railway line (near the Byepass Flyover Junction). Very initial stage. wlbkng August 3rd, 2011, 10:42 AM A mall in Tambaram may come up in between GST Road&amp;Railway line (near the Byepass Flyover Junction). Very initial stage.

Kannan sir,

Are u mentioning about this area marked in yellow border?

http://i.imgur.com/T9uKZ.jpg

Could you tell us who is the developer? Arul Murugan August 3rd, 2011, 10:48 AM ^^

Looks to be compound wall already built.... Hope they leave space for 4th railway line between Tambaram and Chengalpattu. Vicvin86 August 3rd, 2011, 10:53 AM Is it the pentagonish area? wlbkng August 3rd, 2011, 10:54 AM ^^

Looks to be compound wall already built.... Hope they leave space for 4th railway line between Tambaram and Chengalpattu.
Entry and exit is going to be the problem. The same GST road arm from TBM towards Chengalpattu will be both entry and exit road. They have to complete Perungalathur ROB, Vandalur ROB to escape traffic congestion.

To go back towards tambaram they have to join gst road, take underpass to chennai bypass, make a U-turn there and then join the gst road on the opposite once again. :nuts:

Nevertheless mall will take atleast 5 yrs to be opened from now on.


Is it the pentagonish area?

No its on the other side of railway track.. May be some 200m away.

I am still wondering how IAF allowed them to construct such a high structure near their air base. Indian Sun August 3rd, 2011, 01:58 PM Shanmugam Street, Tambaram, has more hope than Ranganathan Street.

The market between GST Road and Shanmugam Street can also be re-modelled on the lines of a souk. ChennaiIndian August 3rd, 2011, 04:15 PM vandalur, chengalpattu la ellam varum podhu en sir virugambakkathukku vara kudadhu?
Varalaam sir varalaam. kaja_asif August 4th, 2011, 06:50 AM Grande gold souk mall is comming up near cresent eng colleage in vandalur. it&apos;s close to tambaram area.

Saidapet is getting a mall i read in a article. please update that.

coromental plaza extirior work started or still it looks like old one.. vivekajithfan August 4th, 2011, 10:20 AM A mall in Chrompet would definitely cater the crowds of chrompet,pallavaram,chitlapakkam,sanatorium,tambaram........And Peru-chengalpet area desperately in need of a full fledged mall.....I hope Gold souk would definitely cater the needs....And any mall proposed in Shriram gateway in perungalathur?????? wlbkng August 4th, 2011, 10:42 AM And any mall proposed in Shriram gateway in perungalathur??????

Their website (http://www.shriramgateway.com/html/campus.htm)says:

Retail mall is under planning stages and is being designed for a capacity of 3,00,000 sq.ft. vinodgopal August 4th, 2011, 12:21 PM perungalathur a? aamam sandhu bundhu kulla yellam mall katranga. vutta kaatangalathur la asia&apos;s biggest mall nu katti ee otta poranga. wlbkng August 4th, 2011, 12:25 PM ^^ have u visited gst road recently? just take a drive tambaram to chengalpattu, u will change ur mind.. its the next anna salai.. fyi, anna nagar was almost non existent in the 60s&amp;was considered far away from the city in the 60s.. the places in gst road exist from the time one knew mylapore, triplicane, pallavaram etc.. vinodgopal August 4th, 2011, 12:32 PM ^^ have u visited gst road recently? just take a drive tambaram to chengalpattu, u will change ur mind.. its the next anna salai.. fyi, anna nagar was almost non existent in the 60s&amp;was considered far away from the city in the 60s.. the places in gst road exist from the time one knew mylapore, triplicane, pallavaram etc..

GST main road is good. But Perungalathur is underdeveloped in my humble opinion. There is a lake over there and my uncle&apos;s flat is right opposite the lake. But rainy season can get nasty. wlbkng August 4th, 2011, 12:39 PM ^^ Most of the places in the city are like that.. during monsoon, velachery gets drowned.. so what.. except areas like boat club, anna nagar, mrc nagar, besant nagar all areas of chennai are still lacking basic infra facilities..
Underdeveloped means there are still lots of scope for planning and growth.. vinodgopal August 4th, 2011, 12:41 PM ^^ Most of the places in the city are like that.. during monsoon, velachery gets drowned.. so what.. except areas like boat club, anna nagar, mrc nagar, besant nagar all areas of chennai are still lacking basic infra facilities..
Underdeveloped means there are still lots of scope for planning and growth..

Velacheri atleast has drainage system. Perungalathur does not have one and will not get one in the near future. My uncle is vexed with that regard. Logesh August 8th, 2011, 09:16 AM yesterday i have been to the planet of the apes movie at AGS-OMR for a 7:10 screening . There was a big ruckus created because of the less number of counters , people started getting irritated because of their clause that we need to collect the ticktes even if we had done an online booking . many missed their shows and started demanding that they need a refund of 30 rs convenience charge. The people @ AGS were not able to handle the issue. I would suggest anyone who goes there for a week end show to arrive little early . I am facing this issue for the 3rd time. This time it was too bad,:bash: roadracer August 8th, 2011, 01:59 PM yesterday i have been to the planet of the apes movie at AGS-OMR for a 7:10 screening . There was a big ruckus created because of the less number of counters , people started getting irritated because of their clause that we need to collect the ticktes even if we had done an online booking . many missed their shows and started demanding that they need a refund of 30 rs convenience charge. The people @ AGS were not able to handle the issue. I would suggest anyone who goes there for a week end show to arrive little early . I am facing this issue for the 3rd time. This time it was too bad,:bash:

Bit surprised by this. Is AGS-OMR as well getting filled now-a-days? I last went there some 2 months back and it was empty but agree that the place where they distribute ticket is a small area. If the screens there get full, then certainly ticket collection would be a bit of a problem. braveman August 8th, 2011, 03:34 PM Proposed Gold Souk Grande Mall (Vandalur) is not going to come up in the near future.
Heard that it is almost dropped. kannan infratech August 8th, 2011, 03:42 PM Proposed Gold Souk Grande Mall (Vandalur) is not going to come up in the near future.
Heard that it is almost dropped.

May be due to the differences between VGP&amp;Arenes. madrasi7777 August 9th, 2011, 09:03 AM I had always felt that Gold Souk was doomed. It was too far a little remote for a mall to be successful. Now with this acrimony, things will only go from bad to worse. ceeznic pirate August 9th, 2011, 09:26 AM Not far as malls like Coromandel plaza. Gold souke is surrounded by high densely suburbs. Crescent and vandalur Zoo are very near. Lot of Educational institutions are surrounding it. It can attract crouds from Tambaram/Chrompet/Guduvancherry/MM nagar as well.

Anyhow I dont see any work going on it. Cant expect it to open for a year if all it is not doomed. Arul Murugan August 9th, 2011, 09:28 AM I had always felt that Gold Souk was doomed. It was too far a little remote for a mall to be successful. Now with this acrimony, things will only go from bad to worse.

faaaar for Chennai city... not for Tambaram, Maraimalai nagar, Vandalur, Guduvancherri etc.,

but the interior work is under progress in gold souk??? i could see no work in outside. madrasi7777 August 9th, 2011, 10:16 AM Pirate and Murugan, You guys are partially right but read my lines. I wrote&quot;for a mall to be successful&quot;.To be successful People will come to the mall to absorb the ambience but how many will translate to spending customer will decide the fate of a mall. For that you need high earning individuals and only Tambaram may have these people. Skywalk is a success not just because it is the only mall in the area but because of its proximity to Anna Nagar, Kilpauk, Arumbakkam, Chetpet which is chock a block of high spending people. One may not get this kind of spenders in maraimalar nagar and guduvancherry though you may find a few but they need not translate into customers.

faaaar for Chennai city... not for Tambaram, Maraimalai nagar, Vandalur, Guduvancherri etc.,

but the interior work is under progress in gold souk??? I could see no work in outside. Arul Murugan August 9th, 2011, 10:26 AM ^^

Food court and Multiplex, even if it is built in Chengalpattu.. there will be crowd.

None of the malls in Chennai is high end malls to attract the real high end spenders, even express avenue looks to be average one like a combo of devi theater, saravana bhavan, aanachi kadai and t.nagar in one complex. Gold souk will be successful for sure!

If we go to GST thread, wlbkng has explained already how this road is booming in apartments, residential. In coming days salaried people living in suburban will be higher than the core city like Anna nagar, arumbakkam, royapet, mylapore etc., bonoslack7 August 9th, 2011, 11:31 AM ^^
None of the malls in Chennai is high end malls to attract the real high end spenders, even express avenue looks to be average one like a combo of devi theater, saravana bhavan, aanachi kadai and t.nagar in one complex. Gold souk will be successful for sure!


lol...are you joking? express avenue has high end stores like hamleys, aldo, sisley, burberry, many watch shops, etc. madrasi7777 August 9th, 2011, 12:48 PM Hi Murugan,

I agree that multiplexes and food court brings in the crowd but these crowds will spend about 120 for a ticket and other 100 rs for food that is all.The success of a mall lies in their ability to bring in shoppers and to keep them in for at least a couple of hours. Food court and multiplex alone does not comprise a good mall.A mall must have good shops catering to varied products to bring in the true crowd. These are the crowd the malls pull into their food court and multiplexes.

I have been to many malls all around Delhi NCR, Mumbai, B&apos;lore, asia and europe and I must say that Express Avenue has hit the bulls eye in terms of success and ambience.I feel this mall and citi centre ( though it is small) is almost up the other malls that I have seen. The other malls which I see will hit the bulls eye will be the Forum in vadapalani and mount road, Phoenix mall and Marg.

I agree that GST in another 10 years will have many high spenders but until then gold souk has to hang in there.

^^

Food court and Multiplex, even if it is built in Chengalpattu.. there will be crowd.

None of the malls in Chennai is high end malls to attract the real high end spenders, even express avenue looks to be average one like a combo of devi theater, saravana bhavan, aanachi kadai and t.nagar in one complex. Gold souk will be successful for sure!

If we go to GST thread, wlbkng has explained already how this road is booming in apartments, residential. In coming days salaried people living in suburban will be higher than the core city like Anna nagar, arumbakkam, royapet, mylapore etc., ranga August 9th, 2011, 02:01 PM ^^
It will take a decade for chennai to attain the present levels of spending power atleast of Bangaluru.That will only sustain the growth of Mall and Multiplexes in Chennai.Mere more foot falls but lesser spenings will not bring top notch stores to chennai. kannan infratech August 9th, 2011, 02:44 PM What you guys think about this ?

Destination Mall with huge Car Park

Specialised in Jewellery - Diamond - Platinum - Gold - Silver

Wedding Mall - each wing caters to single line of products - chappals, male / female / children dresses - traditional / modern, Accessories and all needed for a family

Leisure Lounge for males / old people with satellite pick the flick / music, Play area for children (indoor / outdoor)

Drive In Restaurant, Multi Cuisine Fine Dining Restaurant, Food Court, Bar

Pick up&amp;Drop from Airport, City important points, Exclusive Pick up&amp;Drop by Benz

Welcome Drinks - Liquor, Juices&amp;Soda

Bank, ATM, Money Changers

Packing&amp;Forwarding sections (to any destination) murlee August 9th, 2011, 02:52 PM ^^ Are u planning on opening such a mall, kannan Sir?? Arul Murugan August 9th, 2011, 02:59 PM I agree that GST in another 10 years will have many high spenders but until then gold souk has to hang in there.

In same Asean countries, I hope you might even seen malls - with local brand retails, cineplex, supermarket, food courts doing good business even in small size town like Villupuram. I don&apos;t think gold souk will be any highend shopping mall like the one in European countries and Asean countries metro cities high end mall.

It will be very ordinary like Ampa mall or Ambirami mall or like the TOTAL mall in Bengaluru... surely gold souk can statisfy those customers.

GRT, Naaiha like retails have opened outlets at Tambaram to attract the suburban crowd, they are doing very good. Do you think these outlets at Tambaram are attracting people from Velacherry, Saidpet, Anna nagar? Definetly not!

note: I dont think gold souk will host international brands there... it should be locally made some international brand, national brand, jewllery, retails like pantaloon, megastore etc., this are common stores and coming up in every dt HQ! I don&apos;t think gold souk need to wait for 10yrs for this! braveman August 9th, 2011, 03:38 PM GRT at Tambaram !!
Where is it located exactly? braveman August 9th, 2011, 03:44 PM Please don&apos;t compare chennai and bangalore. Even chennaites have equal Spending capacity, but they are very smart enough to just spend on the worthy stuff. They don&apos;t show off, they are very real.

^^
It will take a decade for chennai to attain the present levels of spending power atleast of Bangaluru.That will only sustain the growth of Mall and Multiplexes in Chennai.Mere more foot falls but lesser spenings will not bring top notch stores to chennai. chennaidesi August 9th, 2011, 03:58 PM I feel US style outlet malls will be a big hit in Chennai. There is one planned called Neo mall for Bgl something like that.
I feel in the new upcoming malls Forum , Phoenix and Marg will do good considering the location and the spending power of surrounding areas, but gold souk not sure. ceeznic pirate August 9th, 2011, 04:18 PM GRT at Tambaram !!
Where is it located exactly?

Tambaram Sanatorium. Near to Mepz Signal right on the GST. Arul Murugan August 9th, 2011, 04:24 PM huge phoenix market city u/c status as on 3rd august

http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6062/6025198724_529443a4ea_b.jpg

CR:Flickr Madhangopal (http://www.flickr.com/photos/mgfotografia/6025198724/) braveman August 9th, 2011, 04:28 PM Thank you
Tambaram Sanatorium. Near to Mepz Signal right on the GST. kannan infratech August 9th, 2011, 04:48 PM ^^ Are u planning on opening such a mall, kannan Sir??

This what Arenes Gold Souk planned. ranga August 9th, 2011, 06:00 PM Please don&apos;t compare chennai and bangalore. Even chennaites have equal Spending capacity, but they are very smart enough to just spend on the worthy stuff. They don&apos;t show off, they are very real.

IC Anniyan August 9th, 2011, 06:28 PM Originally Posted by braveman
Please don&apos;t compare chennai and bangalore. Even chennaites have equal Spending capacity, but they are very smart enough to just spend on the worthy stuff. They don&apos;t show off, they are very real.
IC

:lol: vinodgopal August 9th, 2011, 11:10 PM hopeless comparison between Chennai and Bangalore. Compare Chennai to Singapore/KL/European cities, American cities, Chinese cities or even some of the other Asian tiger countries (South Korea, Taiwan, Hongkong etc...) then we will see where we stand. By comparing to another crappy indian city like bangalore where you dont have a f&apos;ing place to fart in peace leave alone place to sit, it becomes really silly. Its like comparing the devil with the deep blue sea. Chennai2020 August 10th, 2011, 02:18 AM This what Arenes Gold Souk planned.

I agree with Kannan.

Arenes is a mall operator. They operate malls in NCR, Kochi, Jaipur etc., Other mall owners/operators in chennai including Express avenue owns and operate only that specific mall. With Arenes profile, they are expert in this space and know how to get crowd&amp;convert that into business.

Calling the Chennai Gold Souk is doomed / failed etc., shows the individual&apos;s lack of understanding in this specific area. kaja_asif August 10th, 2011, 06:27 AM finally, gold souk status?.

apart from spectrum mall, forum mall, phoneix market city, marg junction, ps grand mall which one will open first.... bonoslack7 August 10th, 2011, 06:43 AM Either spectrum mall or ramee mall is going to open first. ceeznic pirate August 10th, 2011, 08:11 AM finally, gold souk status?.

http://img41.imageshack.us/img41/2112/dsc00379ti.jpg murlee August 10th, 2011, 08:32 AM Is the project stalled??

I see a few people standing in the upper floor.. ceeznic pirate August 10th, 2011, 09:00 AM Not sure whether the project is stalled. But everyday I see some workers there. ceeznic pirate August 10th, 2011, 09:22 AM A mall in Tambaram may come up in between GST Road&amp;Railway line (near the Byepass Flyover Junction). Very initial stage.

http://img684.imageshack.us/img684/5343/dsc00376pk.jpg

This one? Looks like the width is too small saysenthil August 10th, 2011, 09:54 AM Not sure whether the project is stalled. But everyday I see some workers there.

Even i have been asking it so many times.....

I never saw improvement for almost 1 year at least.....

Has someone got more idea about this? madrasi7777 August 10th, 2011, 10:38 AM The superstructure of the 4 square mall in Koyambedu is completed. It is coming on well. bharathkasthuri August 10th, 2011, 01:10 PM ^^Do we have pictures of Ten Square mall under construction? Please post if you do have. If i travel next time to Koyambedu, i will try to get one. Anniyan August 10th, 2011, 01:21 PM What is the status of the high-end mall u/c in Nungambakkam? coolmukund August 10th, 2011, 02:09 PM What is the status of the high-end mall u/c in Nungambakkam?

It is called Bergamo.

It&apos;s structure is complete. Interior works are going on. lexraja August 11th, 2011, 01:53 AM The superstructure of the 4 square mall in Koyambedu is completed. It is coming on well.

^^Do we have pictures of Ten Square mall under construction? Please post if you do have. If i travel next time to Koyambedu, i will try to get one.


Are 4 square and Ten square 2 different malls coming up in Koyambedu ?

:) Arul Murugan August 11th, 2011, 03:58 AM MAARG mall on OMR status.......

14th April 2011

http://www.margjunction.com/images/Pictures/sitepics/preview/PartIIAtriumArea3rdFloorUnderProgress_Mar11.JPG

http://www.margjunction.com/images/Pictures/sitepics/preview/PartIIAtriumArea1stFloor_Dec10.jpg Arul Murugan August 11th, 2011, 04:02 AM http://www.margjunction.com/images/Pictures/sitepics/preview/6Part2viewfromTJarch.jpg

http://www.margjunction.com/images/Pictures/sitepics/preview/4Part3viewfromhotelentry.jpg Arul Murugan August 11th, 2011, 04:03 AM ^^

copyrights: http://www.margjunction.com/site_pics.php greatshankar August 11th, 2011, 10:34 AM Thanks Arul. Seems old pics... rakeshasoka August 16th, 2011, 02:06 PM On August 14th i came across this mall on OMR..There were huge banners put up saying

&quot;PVR just got junctioned here&quot;
&quot;Shopper stop just got junctioned here&quot;
&quot;Hypercity just got junctioned here&quot;

Looks like the mall might open in 2012 for sure anekho August 16th, 2011, 05:09 PM What is the Forum mall status? gvijayan August 17th, 2011, 09:00 PM MAARG mall on OMR status.......

14th April 2011

http://www.margjunction.com/images/Pictures/sitepics/preview/PartIIAtriumArea3rdFloorUnderProgress_Mar11.JPG

http://www.margjunction.com/images/Pictures/sitepics/preview/PartIIAtriumArea1stFloor_Dec10.jpg

Walking distance from my office!!! We will all have good time to hang out when we are over-done or under-done by work! :) kongutamizhan August 17th, 2011, 11:50 PM ^^ BTW did you move back to India? illa wisconsin-lendhu daily nadanthu poreengala? Logesh August 18th, 2011, 03:29 AM Even i have been asking it so many times.....

I never saw improvement for almost 1 year at least.....

Has someone got more idea about this?

I dont think so this project is stalled. I saw an recruitment ad in chennai times ascent from gold souk for the post of marketing manager in commercial properties for chennai.(though , they might need a manager here to market their non chennai properties too). I feel the project is still on. gvijayan August 18th, 2011, 06:31 PM ^^ BTW did you move back to India? illa wisconsin-lendhu daily nadanthu poreengala?

Intha mall open aagarathukulla, I will move back! :) krishnaswamy August 18th, 2011, 06:37 PM Intha mall open aagarathukulla
your kid will go to u.s and come back.:lol::lol: gvijayan August 18th, 2011, 06:52 PM ^^ Did Indian Railways acquire MARG by any chance? ;) kannan infratech August 19th, 2011, 02:36 PM Vijayanukkum Arulukkum IR mela Romba Kovam :lol: bonoslack7 August 20th, 2011, 12:03 PM http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/news-by-industry/services/retailing/future-group-plans-to-synergise-its-products-for-greater-reach-kishore-biyani/articleshow/9672863.cms

History and retail come together as the Future group, owners of the Amar Chitra Katha brand, grow the property through its retail outlets,group CEO Kishore Biyani said.

&quot;We will open the first of the Amar Chitra Katha theme parks in Chennai. We also have plans for Imagninariums, which will come up at Big Bazar outlets and we are creating a new series in Amar Chitra Katha with more recent events,&quot;Biyani said.

While the Imaginariums are still on the drawing board, the first could open in the another three-four months, Biyani said.&quot;We need to restore awareness about our traditional values and we can do it through Amar Chitra Katha, where we hold a 56% stake,&quot;he said. He pointed out that a whole generation of readers grew up reading Amar Chitra Katha and are thus familiar with our great traditions.

Biyani was in Pune to inaugurate the first phase of a 1.1 million sq ft shopping, leisure and commercial development, Amanora Town Centre. The Rs. 635 crore project is being developed in an equal joint venture between City Corporation Ltd and Horizon Realty Fund of the Future group.

Responding to questions on the chances of the group forming strategic alliances with overseas retailers once the organised retail sector is opened for foreign directo investment, Biyani said,&quot;We have many options since we have multiple formats. The bride is ready in several formats but FDI is still to happen.&quot;

He added that they plan to add another 8-9 million sq ft of retail space over the next three years, with Big Bazar accounting for about 60% of that space. The other brands will take up the rest.&quot;We will invest Rs. 700-800 crore for this over the next three years, raising the funds through internal accruals,&quot;he said.

With Indian consumption expected to rise multifold in the next decade to US $1 trillion, from the current level of $400 billion, Biyani was confident that Indian retailers could become the size of Walmart, the US retail giant.&quot;There will be consolidation in the next two- three years in organised retail space, leading to three-four players per segment and a lot of regional players,&quot;he said. bonoslack7 August 21st, 2011, 10:26 AM 40,000 sqft Shoppers stop to be anchor tenant. Shyam_India August 21st, 2011, 11:30 PM Can anyone provide the list of malls coming in Chennai for SURE (in the next 1-2 yrs) ???

Apart from the 4 existing malls
CitiCenter
EA
Spencers
AMPA,, kaja_asif August 22nd, 2011, 06:52 AM Can anyone provide the list of malls coming in Chennai for SURE (in the next 1-2 yrs) ???

Apart from the 4 existing malls
CitiCenter
EA
Spencers
AMPA,,


1. coromendal plaza already AGS cinemas opened
2. spectrum mall
3. marg junction
4. forum mall
5. ps grand mall
6. phoneix market city Raji7373 August 22nd, 2011, 01:01 PM Can anyone provide the list of malls coming in Chennai for SURE (in the next 1-2 yrs) ???

Apart from the 4 existing malls
CitiCenter
EA
Spencers
AMPA,,

Okey Add these also

Chandra Mall
Abirami mall
Isphani Center (No multiplex)
Alsa Mall : (No multiplex) http://www.spiritofchennai.com/shopping/alsa.htm
Kasi arcade ( No multiplex)
Challa mall (No Multiplex)
Prince plaza ( No Multiplex) MA Eswaran August 22nd, 2011, 01:09 PM Alsa mall!!!

No AC. With bad smell,dirts all over mr_madras August 22nd, 2011, 01:11 PM my friend told that venus mall going to open next week in perambur with big bazar as anchor and most of the brands as vannila store along with food court and also fame cinemas 5 screen. Raji7373 August 22nd, 2011, 01:18 PM Alsa mall!!!

No AC. With bad smell,dirts all over

Neat and clean mall kekala...mall nu than ketaru.

Moreover this is according to what we call as mall in our country ....:nuts::nuts:

Okey i have never visited Alsa mall after 90&apos;s. I don&apos;t know the present condition at all. Arul Murugan August 22nd, 2011, 01:23 PM venus mall a.k.a spectrum mall a.k.a perambur mall..

how does the mall looks now? the one below or quoted one!?

http://www.gangafoundations.com/images/banner_retail.jpg

Grand Venus Mall

http://img519.imageshack.us/img519/1962/peramburmall.jpg


The mall will set the benchmark in planningâ€“with ample car parking, open spaces and driveways set amidst natural surroundings, fountains and landscaping
A multiscreen theatre operated by one of the top names in the field Fame Cinemas
food court that will have counters by leading restaurant chains
Sophisticated childrenâ€™s play area
A shopperâ€™s paradise with lifestyle products and international brands
Construction already underway, for the first mall in this chainâ€“coming up over 4 acres of prime property in Perumbur


http://www.gangafoundations.com/projects.html

Though the name of the mall chain is spectrum, it is coming under the name,&quot;Grand Venus Mall&quot;.Construction is going on for more than a year albeit at a slower pace. Visible improvements can be seen with the pace of development. Will try to post the U/C pics soon. Arul Murugan August 22nd, 2011, 01:25 PM ^^

multiplex ellamey oru mall a... but spencer was sucessful w.o multiplex or theatre. But satyam cinemas was just opp and walkable distance so it was not an issue! Raji7373 August 22nd, 2011, 01:44 PM ^^

multiplex ellamey oru mall a... but spencer was sucessful w.o multiplex or theatre. But satyam cinemas was just opp and walkable distance so it was not an issue!

Me too - did not like the concept of a mall w/o multiplex. Even ten square mall is of the same category. No multiplex. kannan infratech August 22nd, 2011, 04:35 PM Getting permission for a multiplex in a mall is tough and its associated conditions are stiff.

But Eppadi Chennai Citi Centre la Inox vanthathu ? Not even a fire escape staircase for such huge crowd ? krishnaswamy August 22nd, 2011, 06:08 PM AGS to build 100 theatres in next 5 yrs..
They are going to start multiplex in GN Chetty Road by next year..

http://cinema.dinamalar.com/tamil-news/3986/cinema/Kollywood/AGS-plans-to-open-100-screens-over-next-five-years-in-TN.htm

100à®ªà¯à®¤à®¿à®¯à®¤à®¿à®¯à¯‡à®Ÿà¯à®Ÿà®°à¯à®•à®³à¯!à®à®œà®¿à®Žà®¸à¯à®ªà¯à®¤à®¿à®¯à®¤à®¿à®Ÿà¯à®Ÿà®®à¯!!
AGS plans to open 100 screens over next five years in TN
à®…à®Ÿà¯à®¤à¯à®¤5à®†à®£à¯à®Ÿà¯à®•à®³à®¿à®²à¯à®¤à®®à®¿à®´à®•à®®à¯à®®à¯à®´à¯à®µà®¤à¯à®®à¯100à®ªà¯à®¤à®¿à®¯à®¤à®¿à®¯à¯‡à®Ÿà¯à®Ÿà®°à¯à®•à®³à¯ˆà®¤à®¿à®±à®•à¯à®•à®ªà®¿à®°à®ªà®²à®¤à®¯à®¾à®°à®¿à®ªà¯à®ªà¯à®¨à®¿à®±à¯à®µà®©à®®à®¾à®©à®à®œà®¿à®Žà®¸à¯à®¤à®¿à®Ÿà¯à®Ÿà®®à®¿à®Ÿà¯à®Ÿà¯à®³à¯à®³à®¤à¯.à®šà¯†à®©à¯à®©à¯ˆà®ªà®´à¯ˆà®¯à®®à®•à®¾à®ªà®²à®¿à®ªà¯à®°à®®à¯à®šà®¾à®²à¯ˆà®¯à®¿à®²à¯à®¨à®¾à®µà®²à¯‚à®°à¯à®…à®°à¯à®•à¯‡à®°à¯‚.50à®•à¯‹à®Ÿà®¿à®šà¯†à®²à®µà®¿à®²à¯5à®¤à®¿à®¯à¯‡à®Ÿà¯à®Ÿà®°à¯à®•à®³à¯à®…à®Ÿà®™à¯à®•à®¿à®¯à®®à®²à¯à®Ÿà®¿à®ªà®¿*à®³à®•à¯à®¸à¯à®µà®³à®¾à®•à®¤à¯à®¤à¯ˆà®à®œà®¿à®Žà®¸à¯à®¨à®¿à®±à¯à®µà®©à®®à¯à®¤à®¿à®±à®¨à¯à®¤à¯à®³à¯à®³à®¤à¯.à®‡à®¤à®±à¯à®•à®¾à®©à®µà®¿à®´à®¾à®µà®¿à®²à¯à®à®œà®¿à®Žà®¸à¯à®¨à®¿à®°à¯à®µà®¾à®•à®‡à®¯à®•à¯à®•à¯à®©à®°à¯à®…à®°à¯à®šà¯à®šà®©à®¾à®•à®²à®¨à¯à®¤à¯à®•à¯†à®¾à®£à¯à®Ÿà¯à®ªà¯‡à®šà¯à®•à¯ˆà®¯à®¿à®²à¯,à®à®œà®¿à®Žà®¸à¯à®šà®¿à®©à®¿à®®à®¾à®®à¯à®¤à®²à®¿à®²à¯à®µà®¿à®²à¯à®²à®¿à®µà®¾à®•à¯à®•à®¤à¯à®¤à®¿à®²à¯à®•à®Ÿà®¨à¯à®¤à®†à®£à¯à®Ÿà¯à®°à¯‚.60à®•à¯‹à®Ÿà®¿à®¯à®¿à®²à¯à®®à®²à¯à®Ÿà®¿à®ªà®¿à®³à®•à¯à®¸à¯à®¤à®¿à®¯à¯‡à®Ÿà¯à®Ÿà®°à¯ˆà®¤à®¿à®±à®¨à¯à®¤à¯‹à®®à¯.à®°à®šà®¿à®•à®°à¯à®•à®³à¯à®•à¯†à®¾à®Ÿà¯à®¤à¯à®¤à®†à®¤à®°à®µà¯ˆà®¤à¯à®¤à¯†à®¾à®Ÿà®°à¯à®¨à¯à®¤à¯à®‡à®ªà¯à®ªà¯‹à®¤à¯à®ªà¯à®¤à®¿à®¯à®®à®²à¯à®Ÿà®¿à®ªà®¿à®³à®•à¯à®¸à¯à®¤à®¿à®¯à¯‡à®Ÿà¯à®Ÿà®°à¯ˆà®¤à®¿à®±à®¨à¯à®¤à®¿à®°à¯à®•à¯à®•à®¿à®±à¯‡à®¾à®®à¯.à®®à¯‚à®©à¯à®±à®¾à®µà®¤à®¾à®•à®šà¯†à®©à¯à®©à¯ˆà®œà®¿.à®Žà®©à¯.à®šà¯†à®Ÿà¯à®Ÿà®¿à®šà®¾à®²à¯ˆà®¯à®¿à®²à¯6à®¤à®¿à®¯à¯‡à®Ÿà¯à®Ÿà®°à¯à®•à®³à¯à®…à®Ÿà®™à¯à®•à®¿à®’à®°à¯à®®à®²à¯à®Ÿà®¿à®ªà®¿à®³à®•à¯à®¸à¯à®•à®Ÿà¯à®Ÿà®µà®¿à®°à¯à®•à¯à®•à®¿à®±à¯‹à®®à¯.à®…à®¤à®©à¯ˆà®¤à¯à®¤à¯†à®¾à®Ÿà®°à¯à®¨à¯à®¤à¯à®‡à®°à®£à¯à®Ÿà®¾à®®à¯à®•à®Ÿà¯à®Ÿà®¨à®•à®°à®™à¯à®•à®³à®¿à®²à¯à®¤à®¿à®¯à¯‡à®Ÿà¯à®Ÿà®°à¯à®•à®³à¯ˆà®•à®Ÿà¯à®Ÿà®¤à®¿à®Ÿà¯à®Ÿà®®à®¿à®Ÿà¯à®Ÿà¯à®³à¯à®³à¯‹à®®à¯.à®…à®Ÿà¯à®¤à¯à®¤5à®†à®£à¯à®Ÿà¯à®•à¯à®•à¯à®³à¯à®¤à®®à®¿à®´à®•à®®à¯à®®à¯à®´à¯à®µà®¤à¯à®®à¯100à®ªà¯à®¤à®¿à®¯à®¤à®¿à®¯à¯‡à®Ÿà¯à®Ÿà®°à¯à®•à®³à¯à®¤à®¿à®±à®•à¯à®•à®ªà¯à®ªà®Ÿà¯à®®à¯,à®Žà®©à¯à®±à®¾à®°à¯. kaja_asif August 26th, 2011, 11:51 AM fame cinemas chennai has 3d facilites. mostly all the flims are screening in 2d format. only harry potter screened in 3d faormat. any body confirm this. die4chennai August 27th, 2011, 04:12 AM venus mall a.k.a spectrum mall a.k.a perambur mall..

how does the mall looks now? the one below or quoted one!?

http://www.gangafoundations.com/images/banner_retail.jpg

It looks like this. But its visibilty from the main road is a problem... The developers were unable to buy out a residential complex in front of the mall. Access is through two narrow corridors on either side of that residential complex... murlee August 29th, 2011, 04:14 PM Chennai retail Report - 2Q11

http://img801.imageshack.us/img801/1362/retailreport.jpg

SRC;http://www.cushwake.com/cwmbs2q11/pdf/chennai_retail_2q11.pdf Anniyan August 30th, 2011, 12:13 PM I heard there are some designer outlet shops in beseant nagar that sell diesel jeans, armani, etc.. any one got the address? kumarsubbiah August 31st, 2011, 04:53 PM Big Bazaar Perambur will be opened to public from 01.09.2011 (Ganesh Chathurthy) @ spectrum mall. indiatraveller September 1st, 2011, 05:50 AM Visited KNK Road yesterday. Bergamo is at the far end of the road near Evoluzione. It looks small when compared to Palladium and DLF Emporio. Looks like it has one level + a roof top for some restaurants.

The structure is complete. The facade is white; the final paint is yet to be given. Seems like they are doing up the interiors now. Guess it&apos;ll take 6-8 months to complete it even if work is done at brisk pace. murlee September 2nd, 2011, 07:12 PM Food helps Sathyam dish out a better movie experience

You&apos;re watching a particularly riveting scene from a blockbuster movie. Eyes transfixed, you reach for another fistful of caramelised popcorn. To wash that down, a long glug of cold beverage and maybe a rich chocolate doughnut after.

Feeding oneself and family well is all part of the movie experience, says Mr Tan Ngaronga, Chief Operating Officer of the Chennai-based Sathyam Cinemas, which runs a chain of multiplexes. That insight led Sathyam, a few years ago, to enhance its offers at its food counters. With its own bakeries dishing out rolls, pastries, muffins and other freshly baked stuff, Sathyam Cinemas earns as much as 25 to 35 per cent of its revenues from food and beverage, depending on the theatre location.

Says Mr Ngaronga, a New Zealander,â€œToday people want a quality cinema experience and food is an integral part of that experience. And, they are willing to pay. We changed a lot of our F&amp;B concepts along the way.â€

Sathyam Cinemas&apos; frenetic expansion in the next year or two will also see this carried forward.â€œWe will have bakery facilities in-house to service all of our locations. Chennai locations will be supplied by our central kitchen / bakery. Other city sites will have their own in-house facilities,â€he explains. With many multiplex chains coming up in various cities, Mr Ngaronga says F&amp;B can be a differentiator. At its landmark Sathyam Cinemas it runs a premium eatery, Ecstasy, as well as a restaurant, ID (idli-dosa) which dishes out South Indian fast food. Ms Monica Umesh, a software professional, who frequents Sathyam, says the theatre has created its ownâ€˜brand&apos; of food which is not available elsewhere. And, for the convenience of ordering food online (which is delivered to the seats at the interval) along with the tickets, she says she&apos;s willing to pay a premium.

REVAMPED MULTIPLEX

The Sathyam chain will shortly open its revamped three-screen, 1,500-seater multiplex in Nellore. Opening soon will be a six-screen 1,566 seater multiplex at Brookefields, a new mall in Coimbatore. In Chennai too it has ambitious plans. The cinema company recently took over two old theatres, Theagaraya, and once a city landmark, Casino, which, Mr Ngaronga says, will retain its old art deco style and be revamped to make it contemporary while retaining its old world flavour.

By next year it will also have a nine-screen multiplex at Vadapalani, a Chennai suburb, with 3,500 seats in all. Also, at the Sathyam Cinemas complex, it is awaiting permission to put up two 350-seater theatres based on Imax&apos;sâ€œimmersiveâ€motion picture technology. The overall expenditure for these expansions, says Mr Ngaronga, would be between Rs 50 crore and Rs 80 crore. A modern multiplex screen costs approximately Rs 2.5-Rs 3 crore a screen

http://www.thehindubusinessline.com/industry-and-economy/marketing/article2418691.ece sshivakumar September 2nd, 2011, 08:08 PM Food helps Sathyam dish out a better movie experience

The cinema company recently took over two old theatres, Theagaraya...

I guess its Thiyagaraja theater in Thiruvanmiyur, if so its a great news. I watched most of the movies in this theater, this was during my college days. This part of the city lacked good theaters and restaurants for a long time. I guess its still true wrt theaters, am glad Sathyam is going to revamp this place. coolmukund September 2nd, 2011, 08:12 PM ^^

That was a good read. I thought a 7 screen multiplex was only coming up at Forum in Vadapalani. From this report, I understand it is a 9 screen multiplex. wlbkng September 2nd, 2011, 08:18 PM Wow IMax is coming too :) vinodgopal September 3rd, 2011, 10:20 AM i want a dome theater in Chennai like the Bombay IMAX Wadala. Raji7373 September 3rd, 2011, 08:05 PM i want a dome theater in Chennai like the Bombay IMAX Wadala.

Okey build. We welcome.:lol: vinodgopal September 3rd, 2011, 09:51 PM Okey build. We welcome.:lol:

i&apos;ll build and you give me the money. :lol: Indian Sun September 4th, 2011, 03:15 AM ^^ Actually Mr. Gopal CM sir, please make it like the IMAX in Valencia.

Can you ensure it&apos;s built in the middle of a huge public park ? We can call it Poonganagaram.

Thanks. kaja_asif September 4th, 2011, 07:36 AM from last few years hearing about IMAX in chennai. still they didn&apos;t get permission for that. it will take another couple of years after getting permission then starting construction, interior work, final finishing etc... process will long time.

they can propose IMAX in upcoming forum mall.

finally Kovai get sathyam multiplex. before in brookefeild first choice is bigcinemas second is fun republic and final sathyam. surely it will give fine entertainment for Kovai people...Let&apos;s enjoy.. kaja_asif September 4th, 2011, 07:38 AM I heard big bazzar opened in spectrum mall. it&apos;s true mall opened. what are anchors coming there. what about cinemas.post some picture of spectrum mall PLZZZZ. vinodgopal September 4th, 2011, 08:17 PM ^^ Actually Mr. Gopal CM sir, please make it like the IMAX in Valencia.

Can you ensure it&apos;s built in the middle of a huge public park ? We can call it Poonganagaram.

Thanks.

Unnai Pol Oruvan intha CM aka common man. but thanks for the thought :) ceeznic pirate September 7th, 2011, 12:28 PM Gold souk Grande, vandalur. Some work is going on..

http://img163.imageshack.us/img163/9664/dsc00466zn.jpg reach.tharan September 11th, 2011, 04:23 AM If Any body visited Metro and Spectrum Mall !!!! Post your experience and also some images of the same.. darkprinz September 11th, 2011, 06:23 AM http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6161/6135149112_2873641cf3_z.jpg (http://www.flickr.com/photos/67191309@N02/6135149112/)
I2753 (http://www.flickr.com/photos/67191309@N02/6135149112/) by Venks_DarkPrinz (http://www.flickr.com/people/67191309@N02/), on Flickr

http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6209/6135149114_936dbf3a92_z.jpg (http://www.flickr.com/photos/67191309@N02/6135149114/)
I2754 (http://www.flickr.com/photos/67191309@N02/6135149114/) by Venks_DarkPrinz (http://www.flickr.com/people/67191309@N02/), on Flickr

http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6086/6135149104_9394a9f4aa_z.jpg (http://www.flickr.com/photos/67191309@N02/6135149104/)
I2752 (http://www.flickr.com/photos/67191309@N02/6135149104/) by Venks_DarkPrinz (http://www.flickr.com/people/67191309@N02/), on Flickr

- No A/C in Fame ticket counter since it is placed outside mall entrance ...So u will be sweating like hell by the time u get your ticket:bash:
- Photography not allowed inside Fame lounge , unlike Escape ..
- Food court is small but decent for the mall size ...
- Mall as many know is smaller , may i say minuscule compared to other big retail properties in chennai ...
- But the Toilets were maintained well .. And the Staff were behaving well..
- Another point to be noted is the mismanagement i found in Fame cinemas refreshment counter ... They themselves were not sure whether the particular food stuff is available or not ... Eg. I was told that coffee was not available in counter 1 but in the next counter they were issuing coffee from another coffee machine on the other side ... :nuts:
- Another nutty concept is that u have to go to second floor by lift and then move to Fame(third floor) through escalator only ... This i found very much irritating because old people even in case of my family are not usually comfortable with Escalators ..!!!I had to persuade them to use the same !! I found this as a letdown !! Murali Bala September 11th, 2011, 06:45 AM The Srijan Grand mall in Velacher is showing some real good improvement after a slow down. Hope this will be ready in another year and will be a Welcome change to the southern coridor. bonoslack7 September 11th, 2011, 07:26 AM Big Bazaar
Gini&amp;Jony
Bata
Archies
Denizen from Levis
Music World
Health&amp;Glow

Food Court

http://i.imgur.com/HTv4p.jpg reach.tharan September 12th, 2011, 03:03 AM Thanks for your update.... Anyway new mall forum will satisfy all our concern Arul Murugan September 13th, 2011, 05:19 AM http://i.imgur.com/HTv4p.jpg

:drool: Dilip joseph September 13th, 2011, 06:32 PM Wen is the Fame cinemas gets opened in spectrum mall......??????? mr_madras September 14th, 2011, 07:22 PM Wen is the Fame cinemas gets opened in spectrum mall......???????
minimum it wil take 3months. this mall becomes popular already for tvk nagar,periyar ngr kolathur locality darkprinz September 14th, 2011, 08:00 PM http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6186/6147874760_ff8586b107_z.jpg (http://www.flickr.com/photos/67191309@N02/6147874760/)
I2841 (http://www.flickr.com/photos/67191309@N02/6147874760/) by Venks_DarkPrinz (http://www.flickr.com/people/67191309@N02/), on Flickr

http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6189/6147874522_7a839884f8_z.jpg (http://www.flickr.com/photos/67191309@N02/6147874522/)
I2844 (http://www.flickr.com/photos/67191309@N02/6147874522/) by Venks_DarkPrinz (http://www.flickr.com/people/67191309@N02/), on Flickr

http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6193/6147324843_58c06ca8ff_z.jpg (http://www.flickr.com/photos/67191309@N02/6147324843/)
I2843 (http://www.flickr.com/photos/67191309@N02/6147324843/) by Venks_DarkPrinz (http://www.flickr.com/people/67191309@N02/), on Flickr

http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6153/6147324555_a74721d862_z.jpg (http://www.flickr.com/photos/67191309@N02/6147324555/)
I2842 (http://www.flickr.com/photos/67191309@N02/6147324555/) by Venks_DarkPrinz (http://www.flickr.com/people/67191309@N02/), on Flickr Arul Murugan September 15th, 2011, 02:46 AM ^^

Good updates DP, but enna 10 square paka chinna shopping complex mathiri irrukku? darkprinz September 15th, 2011, 02:51 AM :) Dont know arul... Indha mall oru angle le perusa theridhu ... Indha angle le Chandra mall madri irukku ... ore confusion :nuts: sridhar_n September 15th, 2011, 05:44 AM ^^+ pakkathula neriya potti kadais...i hope the main entrace will be devoid of potti kadais... Sathisht77 September 15th, 2011, 10:38 AM Australias premier food chain, Country Chicken, a complete turnkey fast-food restaurant, is set to make its India foray. Besides eyeing 300 outlet-strong chain in three years through the franchisee route, it is also planning to set up a processing unit near Vellore in Tamil Nadu.

As for the food chain, the company through its master franchisee, will start off with four outlets in Chennai alone by December this year. In two years, this will grow to 35 units in Tamil Nadu and 120 across the south

http://www.mydigitalfc.com/news/country-chicken-plans-300-outlets-india-foray-766 darkprinz September 15th, 2011, 12:38 PM ^^ Dont know whether posted earlier ...
http://i54.tinypic.com/2hol11l.jpg
KFC near Poonamalee - Nazarathpet kannan infratech September 15th, 2011, 12:48 PM DarkPrinze adikkadi Jelebi oorukku poittu varappala irukku.

or Weekly (Week End) visit to Chennai ? bharathkasthuri September 15th, 2011, 02:25 PM eppadi kannan sir, serious&apos;a comedy panringa? murlee September 15th, 2011, 02:35 PM kannan Sir konja naalave kushi mood le irukaru!! 
 vBulletinÂ®v3.8.7, CopyrightÂ©2000-2012, vBulletin Solutions, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
