<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000201" url="http://eatingsa.blogspot.com/2009/02/bill-miller-bar-b-q.html" time="2012-07-12-15:23" support="22" score="0.04871543953996999" bingtitle="Eating San Antonio: Bill Miller Bar-B-Q" webtitle="Eating San Antonio: Bill Miller Bar-B-Q">
			<query id="001311" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="001296" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="001287" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="001103" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="000311" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="001292" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000029" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="001286" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="001503" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="001377" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000560" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="001035" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="001293" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000123" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="000623" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="000002" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="001188" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="001310" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000006" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="001289" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="001315" bing-rank="16"/>
	<description>Bill Miller started his business ... in to the counter, order, pay, and then wait for your number to be called. It’s just like any other fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		skip to main | skip to sidebar Eating San Antonio 
A restaurant review site about places that real people actual eat.
 
Do you know saté from sauté? Semifreddo from spoom? Well neither do I! I&apos;m a real person reviewing real food for real people. Join me as I find the best, and worst, restaurants in San Antonio, Texas.
 
 
Follow by Email
 
 
 or follow me on Twitter @EatingSA 
 
Scoring
 1 Jalapeno = Suckola! Crappy food, crappy service! Run for your life!

2 Jalapenos = Meh, not that good. Needs improvement. Enter at your own risk.

3 Jalapenos = Good food and service. Go eat there.

4 Jalapenos = Yum! Great food and service! Definitely eat here.

5 Jalapenos = Zowie! Unbelievable food and service! You gotta go here!
 
Categories
 
 1 Jalapeno (1) 2 Jalapenos (1) 2½Jalapenos (4) 3 Jalapenos (29) 3½Jalapenos (32) 4 Jalapenos (17) American (1) Asian (6) BBQ (4) Burgers (3) Cajun (2) Chinese (8) Continental (1) Diner (1) European (1) Fast Food (4) French (1) Greek (3) Hamburgers (7) Ice Cream (2) Italian (6) Japanese (1) Mediterranean (4) Mexican (21) Middle Eastern (1) Multi Category (18) Pizza (4) Salad (2) Sandwich (7) Seafood (9) Spirits (1) Steak (4) Tex-Mex (1) TexMex (1) Thai (3) Vegetarian (2) Vietnamese (1) Wine (1) 
 
Alphabetical Listing
 
 410 Diner Acadiana Café Acenar Mexican Restaurant Ajuua! Apple Annie&apos;s Restaurant AT&amp;T;Center versus the Nelson W. Wolff Municipal Stadium Augie’s Barbed Wire Smokehouse Babe&apos;s Old Fashion Hamburgers Baskin Robbins Bei Fang Chinese Restaurant Beijing Chinese Restaurant Beto&apos;s Comida Latina Big Easy Café Big&apos;z Burger Joint Bill Miller Bar-B-Q Black-eyed Pea Blanco Cafe #1 Boardwalk Bistro Canyon Café Cappy&apos;s Restaurant Cappyccino&apos;s Carrabba&apos;s Italian Grill Cerroni&apos;s Purple Garlic Champps Americana Chester&apos;s Hamburgers Chili&apos;s Chris Madrid&apos;s Citrus Clear Springs Texas Seafood Cold Stone Creamery Cool Café Cosi Crumpets Restaurant and Bakery Del Sol Mexican Restaurant Demo’s Greek Food Ding How Chinese Restaurant Dough Pizzeria Napoletana El Chaparral El Mirasol Far East Café Flour Power Café&amp;Bakery Fralo&apos;s Art of Pizza Frederick’s Bistro Green Vegetarian Cuisine&amp;Coffee Hungry Farmer Steakhouse and Seafood Jacala La Focaccia Italian Grill La Fogata La Fonda Oak Hills La Tune Grill La Vie Cafe Lisa’s Mexican Restaurant Little Itlay Restaurant Long John Silver’s and A&amp;W; Mamacita’s Restaurant and Cantina Marianito&apos;s Extreme TexMex Grill Marie Callender&apos;s Mimi&apos;s Café Old Smokehouse P.F. Chang’s China Bistro Paloma Blanca Panera Bread Café Pappasito&apos;s Cantina Pei Wei Asian Diner Petra Café Picante Grill Picnikins Patio Cafe Pizza Hut Red Lobster Rock San Thai Restaurant Romano&apos;s Macaroni Grill Skipper&apos;s Galley Soleil Bistro&amp;Wine Bar Sompong’s Thai and Chinese Cuisine Sonic Drive In Spanky’s Smokehouse and Saloon Sushihana Japanese Restaurant T.G.I. Friday’s Taipei Restaurant Taqueria El Rodeo Texas Land and Cattle Steak House The Barn Door Restaurant&amp;Meat Market Water Street Oyster Bar Wetmore Smokehouse and Saloon Which Wich? Z&apos;Tejas Zinc Bistro and Bar Zorbas Greek Mediterranean Cuisine 
 
 
 Bill Miller Bar-B-Q 
 Labels: 3½Jalapenos , BBQ 
13151 NW Military Hwy
San Antonio, TX 78231
(210) 492-7385

Bill Miller started his business in 1950 as a small poultry and egg place. It’s grown a little over the past 59 years; now there are 68 Bill Miller Bar-B-Q restaurants in Texas. And if that doesn’t tell you that they know what they’re doing, then maybe the fact that they sell over 2,000,000 sausage links a year will tell you something…it’s good BBQ!

The concept of their restaurant is simple…walk in to the counter, order, pay, and then wait for your number to be called. It’s just like any other fast food restaurant; accept for the fact that the food is way better than any fast food joint.

I stopped by this franchise for dinner one night, and there wasn’t a long line. The person behind the counter was very helpful and patient. She made ordering easy.

I ordered a #1. It’s a Brisket Po-Boy sandwich with fries and a large tea. I like that you can order the meat extra lean if you want. I personally don’t go for that“healthy”stuff…I want cow fat on my cow meat! I know, it’s not healthy. All I can say is…SO WHAT! IT’S REALLY GOOD!

Since I ordered the full-fat meat, I decided to raise the bar on having a heart attack before I’m 50 and ordered a big slice of Coconut Cream Pie. Yum, yum!

After placing my order I hit the condiment buffet which you can find at every Bill Miller’s. This thing has it all, from pickles to onions, the buffet has everything you need to eat BBQ.

My food was ready in just a few minutes, and I really enjoyed it. The sandwich was good, with nice, tender meat, and fresh hoagie style bread. I would have liked a little more BBQ sauce though. You can ask for more, but I’d rather get it upfront.

The fries are great. Big, fat fries that are hot and tasty. A perfect match for the sandwich. The pie was good also. Very tasty without being overly coconut-ie. A great desert.

Overall, Bill Miller really got it right when he started making BBQ meat products in a fast food setting. It’s not the best BBQ in the city, but it’s the most popular. Why? Because their food and service are consistently good!

Facility:
 

Service:
 

Food:
 

Overall Experience:
 
 
 
 
1 comments:
 Anonymous
said... 
Bill Millers is good quality all around...but could be better in a few minor places.
The BBQ sauce is a bit weak (something like Rudy&apos;s sauce would be better for those who like sauce).
THe brisket, while it is always tender and juicy...needs more flavor, like a spice rub before it is cooked.
THe potato salad is horrible...tastes like the deli stuff from HEB...yuck.

I give them high ratings for having consistant good food, fast and affordable.
 August 20, 2009 12:46 PM 
 Post a Comment 
 Newer Post Older Post Home Subscribe to: Post Comments (Atom) Copyright 2010 Eating San Antonio.All rights reserved. Powered by Blogger 
Presented by Cargo , Boston Hotels , SharePoint Services , Designed by Dedicated Server .
	</body>
</document>
