<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000225" url="http://www.fathead-movie.com/index.php/2010/12/06/restaurants-arent-making-us-fat/" time="2012-07-12-15:25" support="1" score="0.00019316685534360558" bingtitle="Fat Head » Restaurants Aren’t Making Us Fat" webtitle="Fat Head » Restaurants Arent Making Us Fat">
			<query id="000861" bing-rank="250"/>
	<description>... average 127 daily fast-food meals per 1000 people. In towns without a fast-food restaurant ... and buzz, then finally take a seat ... over time, whether or not they eat meals ...</description>
	<body>
		Home About the Film No-Bologna Facts Recommended Reading Meet the Experts Contact 
 
 «  Fat Head is on Hulu! Gary Taubes Is Blogging  » Dec 06 2010 
 Restaurants Aren’t Making Us Fat 
 Posted by Tom Naughton in Good Science , The Food Evangelists 
A friend of mine sent me a PDF of an academic paper that will soon be published in the Am erican Economic Journal . The paper, titled Restaurants, Regulation and the Super-sizing of America asks the question:  Are restaurants to blame for the rise in obesity? The answer, not surprisingly, is No.  Or as the authors wrote in their conclusions:

 Our findings indicate that the causal link between the consumption of restaurant foods and obesity is minimal at best. 

 Restaurants have become a convenient whipping-boy for government busybodies who are driven by the urge to do something! whenever they see a problem. San Francisco banned Happy Meals. Los Angeles banned the opening of new fast-food restaurants on the city’s south side. The health-care“reform”bill will require all restaurants with more than 20 outlets to put calorie counts on menus…never mind the fact that we got fatter after nutrition information was mandated on all packaged foods. Some government goofs in Mississippi even proposed barring people with a BMI of over 30 from eating in restaurants. (I sure wish they’d try that right around the time some big fellas from All-Star Wrestling come to town. The violence would be real for a change.)

The trouble with all of these attempts at leanness-through-legislation (besides the shredding of individual freedom in a supposedly free country) is that there’s no evidence they’ll actually work. If restaurants aren’t the problem, then we’re shooting at the wrong target. If restaurants are the problem, then someone should be able to prove that restaurants induce overeating long-term, as opposed to during a single meal.

To examine the effects of restaurants on over-eating and obesity, the authors of this study compared food-intake and BMI data among rural communities with either a relatively high or relatively low availability of restaurants. The BMI curve for both kinds of communities was virtually identical. Apparently having a bit of fun with math, the authors calculated that for each extra mile to the nearest restaurant, the average BMI decreased by a whopping 0.0013 points.

Well, there you have it. If the government do-gooders could simply require that all restaurants be located at least 3,846 miles from the nearest town, our average BMI would drop by five points and the obesity crisis would be solved…although those“Let’s go to White Castle and get some sliders!”inspirations at three in the morning would require a passport in some states.

Of course, you could argue that distance doesn’t have much to do with how often people eat in restaurants. (In which case, the old adage about“Location, location, location!”doesn’t hold water…or soda.) However, using a series of surveys, the authors calculated that people who live near restaurants do, in fact, eat out more often. In towns located within five miles of a restaurant, residents average 128 daily restaurant visits per 1000 people. In towns located between five and 10 miles from the nearest restaurant, the rate drops by half.

Having a restaurant located within the same town makes an even bigger difference: In towns with at least one fast-food restaurant, residents average 127 daily fast-food meals per 1000 people. In towns without a fast-food restaurant, residents average just 39 daily fast-food meals per 1000 people.

If restaurants are making people obese, then the populations who live near restaurants and therefore eat in restaurants more frequently should be fatter. But they’re not. As I pointed out when the Los Angeles city council banned new fast-food restaurants on the south side—a poor area with a high rate of obesity—it apparently didn’t occur to the do-gooders to check out other areas of the city. If they had, they would’ve found that there are more fast-food restaurants per square mile on the oh-so-stylish west side. Since the rate of obesity is also much lower there, nobody dared suggest all those burger and taco joints might be making people fat.

The do-gooders blame restaurants for obesity because of a simple observation: restaurant meals are usually bigger than the meals we eat at home. Duh…that’s one of the reasons I eat in restaurants. I’m not going to dress up, stand by the door tapping my foot while my wife finishes dressing and applying makeup, pay a baby-sitter $30, drive several miles, park, give the hostess my name, take a little buzzy-blinking-light thing from her, stand outside and wait for it to blink and buzz, then finally take a seat at a table…all for the sheer joy of eating a small piece of steamed fish and a salad with lemon juice. When I go out, I eat a big meal.

But then I do the same thing that most people do, according to the study’s authors: I eat less later. I don’t eat less later because I’m disciplined; I eat less because my body tells me it really doesn’t care for another big meal right now, thank you very much. Now, that may be partly because when I eat in a restaurant, I don’t stuff myself with sugar and starch. But I don’t stuff myself with sugar and starch at home, either. By the same token, people who go carb-crazy in restaurants probably go carb-crazy at home too.

The point is, our appetites are controlled by our metabolisms, not by McDonald’s. The authors found that within individual communities, people who eat frequently in restaurants do, in fact, consume more daily calories on average and are fatter on average. But they don’t have big appetites because they eat at restaurants more often; they eat at restaurants more often because they have big appetites.

When the authors looked at data on how many calories individuals consume day-to-day, they found almost no difference between the days that included a restaurant meal and the days that didn’t—just 35 extra calories on days that included a restaurant meal, whether we’re talking about fat people or thin people. In other words, yes, when there are restaurants nearby, the obese are more likely to eat in those restaurants and stuff themselves—but take away the restaurants, and they just stuff themselves at home:

 When eating at home, obese individuals consume almost 30 percent of their calories in the form of“junk food”(ice cream, processed cheese, bacon, baked sweets, crackers, potato chips and fries, candies, soft drinks, and beer). Because obese individuals consume so many calories from nutritionally deficient sources at home, it may not be surprising that replacing restaurant consumption with home consumption does not improve health, as measured by BMI. 

(Take the word“bacon”out of that paragraph, and it would be perfect.)

So as usual, the government do-gooders (not to mention Morgan Spurlock) have the cause and effect backwards. We didn’t develop perverted appetites because of super-sized restaurant meals. Our appetites were perverted first, and then super-sized meals came along to match them. Order the restaurants to serve lower-calorie meals—as some government goofs in the U.K. proposed—and the fat people will just go home afterwards and open the pint of Chunky Monkey.

Picking on the restaurants is a waste of time and effort. The do-gooders can pass every law their little fascist hearts desire, and it won’t solve the obesity problem. There’s just no evidence that restaurants are the cause—not that I’d expect the do-gooders to care one way or another.  As the study authors noted:

 Many policymakers and public-health advocates design policies intended to reduce the impact of restaurants on obesity, even while they acknowledge that convincing evidence of such a link has proven to be elusive. For example, the Food and Drug Administration recently organized a forum in which participants proposed solutions to the challenge of obesity in the context of away-from-home foods, even while the organizers cautioned that“there does not exist a conclusive body of evidence establishing a causal link between the availability or consumption of away-from-home foods and obesity.” 

Anyone want to bet me that the lack of a“conclusive body of evidence”will convince those public-health advocates to stop proposing stupid laws to save us from ourselves?
 
 
 
 This entry was posted on Monday, December 6th, 2010 at 11:32 pm and is filed under Good Science , The Food Evangelists . You can follow any responses to this entry through the RSS 2.0 feed. You can leave a response , or trackback from your own site. 
 35 Responses to“Restaurants Aren’t Making Us Fat” 
 Grok says: December 6, 2010 at 11:41 pm 
The real problem is…what to do with all the lawyers?

 I would say feed them to sharks, but I’m told sharks don’t attack their kin. 
 Amy Alkon says: December 6, 2010 at 11:55 pm 
As a low-carb eater, I love those big restaurant portions people complain about. My boyfriend started a tradition that when he leaves town for work every few weeks he takes me to a certain nice restaurant near my house. I usually get the $36 steak—which perhaps sounds pricey, except that for me, it’s usually three $12 steaks, because it takes me three meals to finish it.

 You must be like my wife. Take her to a nice restaurant, and I know she’ll get at least two meals out of it. 
 Ginger says: December 7, 2010 at 12:13 am 
There’s another point that needs to be understood here, as well. Not all fat people are lazy gluttons stuffing themselves with ice cream all day. I know a lot of extremely large people because of my 25+ years as a size rights activist. This is one of the greatest myths we’ve had to battle and it won’t go away. While there are many people who are very fat and who do eat a lot, there are also many more extremely large people who have yo-yo dieted their whole lives, who have messed up metabolisms, who do not eat like stuffed hogs and who restrict calories and follow a“healthy”low-fat diet. These people are doing what they’re told by so-called experts is right, yet they can’t seem to get thin. I think it goes back to what you explained in Big Fat Fiasco, and let’s face it, what the body does with 100-calorie snack pack of cookies offered by Big Food, is NOT what the body is going to do with 100 calories of steak (thank you Mr. Taubes).

I’ve lived with very large people who’s house you could starve in because they only kept vegetables, chicken breasts and low-fat, low-cal snacks (loaded with carbs and chemicals) and were (and I assume still are) PETRIFIED to have things like half-n-half or red meat or ice cream in their house. They had a stationary bike, walking machine and free weights that they used regularly. They’ve been the same size year, after year, after year. They’re large, but not growing larger and they’re also not getting thin, but they’re doing“everything right”.

Now, I hate eating in restaurants and rarely do, but when I do, I notice how very often people order low-fat meals, avoid meat and fish dishes that are expensive and order sugar free sodas and ice tea regardless of whether or not they’re fat or thin. Usually, at big family gatherings, my husband and I are the only ones who eat high fat/low carbohydrate meals (and are looked at with both envy and disgust, by the way).

Also, I’d love to know what kind of“obese”people this study is talking about. By“obese”are we talking about people who pass for“normal”on the street but are labeled“obese”by the anti-fat, skinny white women committee (example, George Clooney is“obese”and Tom Cruise is“overweight”) or are we actually talking about 400, 500, 600lbs people, (who tend to be fairly rare and rarely seen in restaurants)?

 Metabolism of course has a lot to do with it. The point the study’s authors wanted to make is that both fat people and thin people tend to keep their caloric intake pretty level over time, whether or not they eat meals in restaurants. 
 js290 says: December 7, 2010 at 12:20 am 
 People fail to understand that the [US Government] doesn’t represent them, or care about them… 

“Fighting obesity, terrorists, whatever”is just a cover used bureaucrats who would otherwise bring no redeeming value to a peaceful and free society.
 Sarah says: December 7, 2010 at 3:02 am 
I hate how when people look at“unhealthy high fat”restaurant food, they always point at something starchy 9/10 times.“These mashed potatoes and corn have BUTTER! These fries are fried in OIL! This mac and cheese has CHEESE!”It’s really frustrating…

Quick personal question, when you look at the carb content of food, do you count total carbs, or net carbs (meaning subtracting the fiber grams I believe?)

Because I was getting all excited to eat sweet potatoes with their glycemic load of 17, until I saw they average at about 40g of carbs a piece. What do you think? Do they count as a food that doesn’t spike insulin even with the high carbs?

 I go with net carbs. The idea is to keep the carb count low, but that doesn’t mean zero. If you eat low-carb meals and toss one sweet potato in there, it’s still a low-carb day. I’d recommend testing your reaction to various foods with a glucose meter, then making your dietary decisions based on the results. Pasta is supposed to be a relatively low-glyemic food, but a little bit of if sends my blood sugar through the roof. 
 Dave Fish says: December 7, 2010 at 4:04 am 
I’m in Japan this week and eating all of my meals in restaurants. Here are some observations on restaurants here, and Japanese health and dietary habits in general:

The portion sizes are no smaller here than in the US. They are however much more nicely presented.

The ingredients are mainly fresh vegetables, meat, and ubiquitous sticky rice. Not a processed food item to be found.

Americans don’t eat faster than people in other countries. I’m usually the last one to finish my meal. Some of that is probably because I’m not as adept at using chop sticks as my Japanese colleagues, but they do seem to be ravenously devouring their food. I bring up this point because you often hear that Americans are fat because they eat too fast and the stomach doesn’t have time to send a signal to the brain that it is full.

Many Japanese suffer from cold and flu. OK, this isn’t scientific, but because most of them wear a mask when they have a cold, it is easy to see how many are sick. Sitting here in the office I hear people all around me coughing and sneezing. They are fastidious about hygiene but I suspect the illness is due in part to diet (too much rice and possibly soy suppressing the immune system) and to the fact that 11 million people are packed into Tokyo making it easy for viruses to spread. Cold and flu incidence is probably not any higher than in the US, but it is more obvious here.

Most Japanese are not overweight. Interestingly enough, of the overweight people I see, most are young people, as in teenagers. I wonder if they have adopted a more processed food, western type diet?

Unsweetened tea seems to be the non-alcoholic beverage of choice. Soft drinks are available everywhere but I see few people drinking them. Almost every restaurant I’ve been in serves hot tea with the meal. They don’t ask if you want a beverage (unless they sell alcohol).

Much of the conventional wisdom explaining our obesity problem in the US doesn’t hold up under real world observations. But that never stopped the experts from spouting their theories.

 Their anti-obesity plans aren’t about evidence and results; they’re about control. 
 Liz Downunder says: December 7, 2010 at 7:22 am 
Recently here in Australia:“…the Queensland Health Minister said that it’s time to develop a national plan to cut the amounts of energy, fat, sugar and salt in fast food, which he believes will help tackle Australia’s obesity problem. He also urged the nation’s health ministers to agree on standards for the display of nutritional information on product packaging, and on menu boards. Mr Lucas says the fast food habit is having a devastating effect on the nation’s health…”

I’ve paraphrased the above from an online news article I read last month, which was accompanied by a photo of the clearly overweight Queensland Health Minister.

Wonder if anyone else saw the irony…

 Same here. We have an obese surgeon general planning anti-obesity programs, and a First Lady promoting fitness programs while her husband (the president) continues to smoke. 
 Gracie says: December 7, 2010 at 9:37 am 
The fast food ban in LA and the proposed barring of 30+ bmi people from restaurants puts me in mind of a paper from the Hoover Institute that I read last year.

It’s a discussion of our culture’s reversal of sex and food in our moral calculations. This link is to a precis of the piece in a George Will column, he links to the paper itself. http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2009/02/25/AR2009022503123.html 

I can’t commend this paper to people enough.

 Very good essay, thanks. 
 Ailu says: December 7, 2010 at 10:09 am 
I dunno, I don’t know how I could possibly stay healthy if I ate out all the time. Up here in the mountains all we have to choose from is diners, drive-ins and dives. All the food is loaded with rancid seed oils, trans fats and MSG. Bleh. Can’t say that many people in the city could afford to eat at the higher-end restaurants all the time, either. True, many people don’t make the best choices on their at-home food. But eating at home, I’d say a person has a much better control over what goes inside of them, and as a result, staying far healthier than their daily dine-out counterparts.

 It’s definitely easier to control your diet at home. The point the study’s authors were making is that restaurants have little effect on how much junk people eat. The junk addicts eat junk at home too. 
 Ned Kock says: December 7, 2010 at 10:52 am 
One thing that is problematic about restaurants in the USA in general is that they often use copious amounts of industrial seed oils and/or hydrogenated oils for cooking. I sometimes watch TV food channels that show footage of chefs preparing dishes, and it is appalling. The other day I saw a chef pouring a large amount of margarine into a mix, because it was“much healthier than butter”. And this is becoming a trend in Europe, including France, as well.

 Oh, no…tell me the French aren’t switching to margarine! 
 Paul Eilers says: December 7, 2010 at 11:41 am 
Restaurants only supply what consumers demand. Otherwise, the eateries would go out of business.

Why is that so hard for some people to comprehend?

P.S. My mother owns a family restaurant that serves southern country cooking with cafeteria style service. No low-fat fare available there. And she can hardly keep up with all business.

 Does she serve chicken-fried steaks cooked in lard? With all the nasty vegetable oils restaurants use these days, I can’t remember my last good chicken-fried steak. 
 Holly J. says: December 7, 2010 at 11:53 am 
“But then I do the same thing that most people do, according to the study’s authors: I eat less later.”

That whole paragraph sums it up. Saturday mornings my boyfriend and I go to IHOP. I can get my steak and eggs with broccoli and a water and he can get whatever he wants–usually 3 or 4 eggs, sausage, bacon and ham, and toast maybe some hashbrowns or pancakes–with water and a coffee. (He’s less disciplined about the carbs. He’s also the same size he was in high school.) We usually do this around noon, so it’s more of a brunch, and aren’t hungry again until 6 or 7pm. We only eat about 2 meals that day. Then again, like your paragraph suggested, we don’t normally stuff ourselves on carbs. If there was no restaurant in our town, I would end up making more dishes and miss out on our relaxing morning to sit and talk. I doubt we would change what we eat or the portion sizes if IHOP wasn’t there. I always remember Gary Taubes saying that EVERYONE eats until they’re full; deranged metabolisms or not.

 Exactly. Metabolism determines appetite. When I eat a big restaurant meal at night, I usually skip breakfast the next day because I’m just not hungry yet. 
 Godzilla says: December 7, 2010 at 12:09 pm 
A brief statement from Godzilla:

“I agree that restaurants aren’t making us fat. The restaurants in Tokyo I have eaten were fairly light fair. There was one sushi bar I wish I would I would’ve spared.

New York City has some restaurants to die for, but I managed to survive it without putting on nary a kilogram.

I have yet to eat a Parisien restaurant.

I would do London just for kicks.

A few places in Italy, too.

I was hoping someday Amazon would put together a“restaurants of the world”sampler pack.

I just don’t have time to travel like I used to.

And that wasn’t really me in Mexico City.”

As reported by R Dunn
 Lori says: December 7, 2010 at 1:03 pm 
You know who sells a lot more junk than fast food joints and panders to kids even more? Grocery stores. But then, people depend on grocery stores, and you can get nutritious, non-fattening food there.

Oh wait–that applies to fast food joints, too.

When unskilled people in South Central LA have an even harder time finding a job because there’s fewer fast food restaurants for them to get a start in the job market, I suppose government will come up with a great solution for that, too, like, encourage people to open a family restaurant! I’ve actually seen that suggested, as if people with little work experience can snap their fingers and make it happen.

 The job-killing aspect of it really p$$$ed me off, too. I’m usually horrified when I stand in grocery-store lines and see what people buy. Take away the restaurants, they’ll still indulge their carb cravings. 
 Mallory says: December 7, 2010 at 3:28 pm 
**Some government goofs in Mississippi even proposed barring people with a BMI of over 30 from eating in restaurants**

haha my state is representing well! but on a serious note that’s the most ridiculous thing i have ever heard…restaurants make us fat??? i think i eat more at home lol but i rarely eat out.

there’s like 2 groups of fatties down here…one group is living on food stamps and my paycheck and buy 20oz sodas, hoho’s and doritos with their food stamps…the other set of fatties are good-ol-folk. these people pass on the family traditions and food legends, and some do it well(cooking food in lard etc) but some morph a not so bad meal of gumbo into a starch laden, veggie oil induced carb fest with biscuits, cornbread, and deep fried everything.

 Yup, people eat according to their tastes, whether at home or in restaurant. 
 The Cheap Vegetable Gardener says: December 7, 2010 at 3:29 pm 
It is frustrating when I do go out and look for something with reasonable number of calories. With even a typical salad coming in at 1000+ calories though as I am sure you know take any meat and skip the fries, pasta, bread, etc and they magically become“reasonable”Guess I should get used to taking apart my burger or skipping the potato with my steak…
 mezzo says: December 7, 2010 at 4:14 pm 
Order the restaurants to serve REAL FOOD. That appears to be the most difficult commodity–in Europe too. Very many restaurants are not what they purport to be–a place where you can restore your strength. That is what the name implies–restoration of the weary traveller. Many do not even bother to cook–they just dish up microwaved stuff. That is not my idea of a place where to take a rest and receive proper refreshment and rest-au-ration.

 I presume you’re kidding about ordering the restaurants to serve real food. We shouldn’t order them to serve anything. 
 Richard Tamesis, M.D. says: December 7, 2010 at 6:14 pm 
These regulations affecting restaurants are all about self-promotion on the part of these government officials, who want to give the appearance that they are actually doing something while in office to their constituents.

 Bingo. 
 Nancy says: December 7, 2010 at 8:43 pm 
AS a BBW myself I do think big is beautiful. I am very proud of my size. I also have met many plus size friends on a BBW dating club [seekingbbw dot com]. The blog was updated very often. Lots of guys joined my friend circle. We are very popular here because we know size is only a number.
 Wanda says: December 7, 2010 at 8:49 pm 
Any low carber in my little hick town would probably share my frustration in that there isn’t really any good restaurant to get a decent sized low carb meal. Sault Ste. Marie, Ontario is predominantly italian, which means LOTS of handmade pizza and pasta, and not much else. We don’t even have a seafood restaurant. All meals are pretty much your standard 6-8 oz of meat or fish, with pasta, potato or rice sides and bread on the table.

The biggest problem is that when we do go out, I usually end up disappointed, knowing that I would have done a much better job of the meal at home, portion AND flavour wise. Maybe i should open a low carb restaurant–if I did you can be sure that it would be a whole lot more than just bunless burgers, and bacon would not be considered junk food!

 That would be frustrating. I’m glad there are plenty of steak and seafood restaurants around here. 
 Ben_P says: December 8, 2010 at 1:44 am 
This doesn’t surprise me at all. Working in a restaurant, I can tell you that the packaged wholesale ingredients restaurants get are the exact same packaged food as what you buy in a grocery store. Powdered gravy mixed with trans fat and lots of other junk. Soybean oil in everything, like the deep fryer and salad dressings. HFCS in places it shouldn’t be. One pound sticks of margarine because it’s a third of the cost of butter. In America, you have to go to a really expensive restaurant to get‘real’food, and even then it’s a gamble. Soybean oil has pretty much completely replaced animal fats and saturated tropical oils in the American diet. Politically Correct nutrition has almost removed the choice of fat for us. Along with the HFCS in sodas and every packaged food and you have a perfect storm, IMO.

I really want to open a restaurant just so I can sell sweet potato fries deep fried in coconut oil, or maybe tallow. Screw the Guy from the CSPI!

 He’d be picketing you within a week. My wife makes sweet potato fries in bacon grease. They’re awesome. 
 Jason Sandeman says: December 8, 2010 at 11:36 am 
Well, by golly-gee…we need MORE laws to make them stupid people stop eating out, and buying more of our crap that is“good for them.”Once we have driven those evil chefs out of business, then we will look at attacking the farming people. By golly, them vittles shouldn’t be so fat at slaughter, right? All that saturated fat! It’s making us obese!
Better still, those lazy diabetics need to get their act together! They are disgrace to the health care system, and they are even more scary than…. terrorism!

Those words SHOULD read like they are out of a nuthouse, but sadly, they are the norm thought about people.
My favorite part is when people assume that I“got diabetes”from my diet. See, if I just stayed away from all those saturated fats, I would have been okay.

Problem is, I am a TYPE 1 diabetic. Meaning, DIET HAD NOTHING TO DO WITH IT! It is genetic.

More and more, people are getting“obese,”and more and more the government will have to step in and“help.”Sounds like a make-work project to me?

 As Eric Oliver pointed out in the film, a lot of these government initiatives are about keeping government officials employed. 
 Marilyn says: December 8, 2010 at 4:07 pm 
Ben_P wrote:

“In America, you have to go to a really expensive restaurant to get ‘real’ food, and even then it’s a gamble.”

Alas,’tis true! I’ve enjoyed one of the better restaurants in town for many years, but I noticed a few years ago–since the son took over the business–that the gravy now tastes like they dissolved a bouillon cube in some water and thickened it with something. Ugh.
 Levi says: December 9, 2010 at 1:34 am 
I’m still trying to figure out why bacon always makes the junk food list. I’m convinced its because they need a confounding factor so they can implicate fat. So when they do a study to demonize fat they use donuts, cupcakes, cheesecakes, and bacon. Must be the fat that’s killing us!

 That’s why they usually do. You’d think fat and sugar were the same substance. 
 TimInUkraine says: December 16, 2010 at 1:18 am 
I live in Ukraine, where going out to restaurants is for the privileged few. The problem with restaurants here is that the portions, especially of meat, are dreadfully small. So my friends and I went to the old drawing board an came up with a plan. It’s being fine tuned and copyrighted at the moment, so all I can say is that the gist of the plan involves ordering more than one portion.

I don’t see too many fat people at the restaurants, but I see plenty lumbering home from the market with bags full of bread, sunflower oil, potatoes, and cakes…

 That’s what I see in grocery stores here. 
 Marcus says: March 18, 2011 at 12:11 pm 
Some contrary evidence: http://www.ajcn.org/content/91/2/465.short 

“Consumption of restaurant foods and incidence of type 2 diabetes in African American women”

Worth taking a look at. Turns out eating hamburgers and fried chicken from restaurants is associated with higher diabetes levels.

 It’s not contrary evidence. It’s confirming evidence. People who eat a lot of fast food consume more sugar than the population as a whole. You’ll notice the study says nothing about controlling for sugar consumption independently. Blaming the diabetes on hamburgers and fried chicken was their bias manifesting. Nothing in the data points specifically to burgers and chicken, only to an association between fast food consumption and diabetes.

Other studies have shown that sugar addicts consume just as much sugar whether fast food restaurants are nearby or not. But if those restaurants are nearby, the sugar addicts will patronize them more than the population as a whole.

Since you’re a PhD and all, I’m sure you realize correlations are just that: correlations. They don’t prove cause and effect. A and B are often correlated simply because they’re both caused by C. There’s a correlation between baldness and heart disease, but I’m pretty sure baldness doesn’t cause heart disease. If A is correlated with B and we want to blame A for causing B, we need to describe a plausible mechanism by which A causes B. There’s a very plausible mechanism for sugar causing type 2 diabetes. There is no plausible mechanism for hamburger and chicken causing diabetes. 
 Marcus says: March 18, 2011 at 2:19 pm 
@ Tom:

p. 469–they controlled for sugar consumption. Did you even read the study before you denounced it? Do you really think that the researchers are that stupid? That they couldn’t of thought of a confounding factor that a comedian came up with? LOL

re: correlation vs. causation. You do realize, Tom, that your comments (and documentary) are absolutely fraught with the very type of correlation that you decry here, right? You have no causal story for how you lost weight independent of the correlations that also occurred with exercise and reduced caloric intake. Yet, you privilege the correlation of the diet, mistakingly believing that it had some causal power. That’s poor science.

 Ditto your belief that exercise produces weight loss because you lost weight by running. As for the weak association study you linked:

“Participants were asked to mark how often they had consumed each food in the past year and the portion size.”

Ah, one of those“how many burgers did you consume in the last year”surveys. Yes, those are notorious for their amazing precision. I had to fill out one of those once, along with my co-workers. It was a joke. Nobody could remember what he or she ate last week, much less during the past year. We started randomly checking boxes and had a good laugh about it as we all headed out to Happy Hour.

Now show me a controlled clinical trial in which burgers and chicken—with all other variables controlled—were found to produce a higher level of diabetes or loss of glucose control. Here’s a clinical trial (the kind that matters) demonstrating greater glucose control on a low-carb diet:

 http://diabetes.diabetesjournals.org/content/53/9/2375.long 
 Marcus says: March 18, 2011 at 2:23 pm 
“There is no plausible mechanism for hamburger and chicken causing diabetes.”

Please see:

 http://diabetes.diabetesjournals.org/content/40/11/1397.short 

“Abstract

Muscle and hepatic insulin resistance are two major defects of non-insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus. Dietary factors may be important in the etiology of insulin resistance. We studied progressive changes in the development of high-fat-diet-induced insulin resistance in tissues of the adult male Wistar rat. In vivo insulin action was compared 3 days and 3 wk after isocaloric synthetic high-fat or high-starch feeding (59 and 10% cal as fat, respectively). Basal and insulin-stimulated glucose metabolism were assessed in the conscious 5- to 7-h fasted state with the euglycemic clamp (600 pM insulin) with a [3-3H]-glucose infusion. Fat feeding significantly reduced suppressibility of hepatic glucose output by insulin after both 3 days and 3 wk of diet (P less than 0.01). However, a significant impairment of insulin-mediated peripheral glucose disposal was only present after 3 wk of diet. Further in vivo [3H]-2-deoxyglucose uptake studies supported this finding and demonstrated adipose but not muscle insulin resistance after 3 days of high-fat feeding. Muscle triglyceride accumulation due to fat feeding was not significant at 3 days but had doubled by 3 wk in red muscle (P less than 0.001) compared with starch-fed controls. By 3 wk, high-fat-fed animals had developed significant glucose intolerance. We conclude that fat feeding induces insulin resistance in liver and adipose tissue before skeletal muscle with early metabolic changes favoring an oversupply of energy substrate to skeletal muscle relative to metabolic needs. This may generate later muscle insulin resistance.”

Next falsehood you want to try and propagate, Tom?

 Where’s the full text? There’s no specifics on the high-fat diet. Last rat study I saw proving the evils of dietary fats (for rats at least) used corn oil for fat. I’d expect all hell to break loose if you force an animal to live on corn oil. 
 Marcus says: March 18, 2011 at 7:00 pm 
@ Tom:

I *know* that exercise leads to weight loss. The only time it doesn’t is if you stuff your face after you exercise, thereby consuming more calories than you burn. This is why you need more nuance in your arguments. It’s not that exercise doesn’t lead to weight loss–it certainly can be a great tool for that purpose. But you’re right, gorging at McDonald’s after the gym likely won’t have the desired effect. Do we really need a bunch of studies to tell us that?

re: survey research. I know you’ll look for ways to discredit any information that doesn’t confirm your prior-held beliefs (see that confirmation bias link I sent you), but you really should at least be open to the possibility that you may be wrong. That’s what science is all about. At the very least you could admit that the science has produced mixed results with respect to eating at restaurants and gaining weight.

On another note, how do you feel about New York restaurants being“forced”by big bad government to show caloric information on menus?

 I’ve expressed my opinion about the worthlessness of calorie-count menu laws in several posts. Look them up.

I don’t dispute research that doesn’t match my preconceived notions. I dispute research that 1) proves nothing about causality, since it’s a weak association study and 2) is based on a food survey that required people to accurately remember what they’ve eaten for the past year. The inability of those surveys to accurately reflect actual food consumption is notorious.

Marcus, here’s where we’re at: I’ve let you waste large chunks of my day by debating you, even though your method of debate consists entirely of repeating, in one form or another, some variation of“I’m right because I know I’m right”or linking to some lousy association study. If you truly understand science (I have my doubts), you know association studies aren’t proof (they are intended merely to produce a hypothesis to test in a clinical setting) and the conclusions drawn from them are often completely contradicted by clinical studies—the type that matter. For an idea of what a real scientist thinks of those studies, see this article:

 http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2010/11/lies-damned-lies-and-medical-science/8269/ 

I reached my conclusions about the biochemistry of hunger and insulin resistance after reading extensively and conducting interviews with researchers in the field. I’m still in touch with with some of them. One even calls me at home now and then to discuss research and make suggestions for blog topics. (He likes my writing style, especially the humor.)

Before that extensive reading, I believed exactly what you believe. I was ignorant of the biochemistry and thought fat people (myself included) simply needed to eat less and exercise more. When people I interviewed for the film told me I was wrong, I at first resisted. But unlike you, I was open-minded and examined the evidence. Presented with the evidence, I changed several beliefs I’d held for most of my life. Since making the film, I’ve also changed my previous opinion that high-GI foods like rice and potatoes induce insulin resistance. I saw evidence that while those foods spike blood sugar, which can certainly be bad, it’s far more likely that fructose is the prime mover in insulin resistance.

So I’m not the one who isn’t open to changing my mind. You are. You have declared that weight loss is a matter of willpower, and you will obviously hang onto that belief for dear life rather than consider that you might be wrong. I listed the biochemistry involved in a series of points and asked you to tell me which points were wrong and why. You didn’t. You simply repeated that you’re right because you know you’re right. I asked why obese mice who were forced to eat 5% less ended up fatter and with less muscle mass as a result, since you just by gosh KNOW that“of course”they would burn fatty acids when hunger set in. You never answered. I asked why, if it’s all about willpower, people on low-carb diets spontaneously eat less and lose more weight than people on low-fat/low calorie diets, even though the low-carb dieters had no calorie restrictions whatsoever. You never answered. I asked how, given the known biological fact that elevated insulin inhibits lipolysis, your statement that“of course”people with elevated insulin will burn fatty acids instead of muscle mass if they don’t eat when their glucose levels drop could possibly be true. You never answered.

So in all seriousness, Marcus, you’re not actually debating. You’re simply arguing endlessly and pointlessly without offering any evidence to dispute what I’ve said about the metabolic process involved. Why, I can only guess. Apparently you believe that if you simply repeat yourself over and over and over and over and over and over, I’ll forget everything I’ve learned about the biochemistry of hunger, insulin and weight loss and decide your uninformed opinions must be correct, since you believe in them so strongly. Then, of course, I’ll rename this blog to“Dietary Wisdom Based On The Uninformed And Unsubstantiated Opinions of Marcus.”

Not going to happen. And I’m certainly not going to waste any more of my busy days talking to a wall. Instead (if you choose to waste your own time with pointless and endless arguing), I’ll simply agree with absolutely everything you say and bid you good-day. I explained why in this post:

 http://www.fathead-movie.com/index.php/2010/12/13/arguing-with-idiots/ 
 Marcus says: March 19, 2011 at 9:33 am 
@ Tom:

Well fortunately for all of us you’ve shown your true colors. You’re not interested in debate, either. You interested in ad hominem attack and calling those who disagree with you“idiots.”That may fly in the comedy world, but in the intellectual world it just exposes your insecurities. You’ll note that *I* have never called you an idiot, a moron, uneducated. You might want to think about why you feel the need to call those you disagree with names.

If you’re not interested in debate, that’s fine. I’ll happily claim victory and note, like many of the low-carb folks, you’ve given up when presented with evidence that doesn’t fit your pre-conceived notions. It’s a shame, really. You set out to create a documentary that heightens the discussion…in the end you only lowered it.

 You’re 100% correct, Marcus. Your tactic of repeating yourself over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over and over without actually providing evidence to dispute the metabolic process I described or answering any of the challenging questions I asked proves your intellectual superiority, and was an absolutely, positively stunning rhetorical performance. You win. Declare victory and enjoy. I shall henceforth base all of my posts on your uninformed and unsubstantiated opinions. 
 Marcus says: March 19, 2011 at 12:34 pm 
@ Tom

This reply just illustrates that you haven’t been reading what I have been writing. I have not, ever, disputed any of the metabolic process studies you have cited. What I have done, and this is important Tom, is debated what those studies *mean*. As a simple example vis-a-vis exercise, you seem to think that exercise increasing appetite MEANS that exercise isn’t a particularly useful tool for many people when it comes to weight loss. I don’t share that view. What I think the studies MEAN is that we need to educate people on *how* they should be incorporating exercise into their weight-loss strategy.

So when you say things like“I don’t believe [exercise] is much of a weight-loss treatment.”I can’t help but point out that this is silly, as it’s not the exercise that is the problem.. it’s the eating afterward. It’s similar to suggesting that going to the gym isn’t good for exercise. Sure, that’s true. Because walking into the gym doesn’t nothing for you–it’s what you do there. Going to the gym is a tool that can be useful in become fitter and losing weight. Same thing with exercise. It won’t do you any good if you end up consuming more calories than you burn.

Finally, in addition to what these studies mean, I also question to what extent they’re important. Remember, my original claim is that hormones matter on the margins. You still haven’t provided any evidence that hormones are the most significant causal factor in weight loss. It could be character. It could be genes. It could be environment. It could be any number of things. The way I look at it is that researchers have now provided us with yet one more piece to a very complicated and large puzzle. You’re acting like it is THE piece that solves the puzzle. I’m suggesting it is only one piece among many.

 Thank you for sharing your superior knowledge on the causes of weight gain and weight loss. If only someone with your extensive background in endocrinology had informed me that in spite of the amazing complexities of human metabolism, weight loss is a really just a simple matter of eating less and moving more, I could’ve saved myself untold hours reading up on the amazing complexities of human metabolism. 
 Marcus says: March 19, 2011 at 12:35 pm 
And you still haven’t explained why you feel the need to resort to terms like idiot and moron. Do you really feel that this is a good way to debate and argue?
 
That will depend entirely on your opinion of those terms. What do you think I should think? I don’t want to disagree with you on anything, because that would prove I’m incapable of changing my mind. 
 Marcus says: March 19, 2011 at 4:45 pm 
@ Tom:

I encourage you to continue learning about the human metabolism. Indeed for those unwilling to exercise or reduce their food intake, the metabolism studies may indeed be pretty important. For those of us who can control what we put in our bodies, however, don’t really need the intricate knowledge as it’s mostly irrelevant.

 You are 100% correct as usual, Marcus. The problem with the 98% percent of people who fail to lose weight on“eat less / move more”programs is that they lack your superior intellect, discipline, and willpower. Biochemistry has nothing to do with their failure to lose weight, and of course knowledge of metabolism is completely irrelevant for superior human beings such as yourself. Therefore, biochemistry need not be considered when designing weight-loss programs. If only everyone was just like you, there would be no obesity problem today. I thank you for explaining it to me. 
 Marcus says: March 19, 2011 at 6:29 pm 
@ Tom

Well that’s certainly true by definition. I’m not obese, so if everyone was like me, we wouldn’t have an obesity problem. See, you *are* learning.

Now, as for my diet (which we know works), here is what I do: I make sure that I burn more calories than I eat. It’s hard sometimes. Having that 4th beer is fun. Eating at McDonald’s can be a joy. A nice slice of seared foie gras is delic. But hey, who said diets were easy?

The great thing about my diet is that you can eat whatever you want. Carbs, fat, whatever. Just don’t eat more of it than you burn. Pretty simple philosophy, really. Difficult in our society since we’re used to overconsuming and huge portion sizes, but it can be done.

But it does take willpower. You got that absolutely right.

My suggestion for you would be to relax. Maybe have a beer. (Oops, you can’t.. too many carbs–I forgot). In any event, try to calm down and realize that you don’t have all the answers. Some of us with old ideas might actually have a point. 

 You are 100% correct, Marcus. The mere fact that I’ve spent so much time showing up on your blog and arguing endlessly and pointlessly with you without actually offering any evidence that your views on metabolism are wrong speaks volumes about my need to relax. I will try to stop obsessing on you, get a life, and cease being an annoying jackass with a weird compulsion to endlessly repeat my uninformed but nonetheless strong opinions. This will be difficult for me, since I’m not blessed with the superior willpower, intellect and discipline that keeps you thin, but I’ll do my best. 
 Marcus says: March 19, 2011 at 8:22 pm 
@ Tom:

Just doing my part in educating your audience on some, *ahem*, more scientifically sound viewpoints. 

 I appreciate you sharing your deep understanding of metabolism and fat accumulation with my audience, Marcus. Most of them were completely unaware of the theory that losing weight is simple matter of eating less, moving more, and exerting superior willpower. I suspect they’ll all try that method now—most of them for the first time ever.

If only someone could get your message across to the population as a whole, I’m sure the obesity problem would soon be a distant memory. 
   
 Leave a Reply Click here to cancel reply 
 Name (required) 

 E-mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 

 

 

 

 
 
Recent Posts

 Low-Carb = Ketosis? Not Necessarily. The Farm Report: Visitors, Part Two The Farm Report: Visitors A Possible Metabolic Advantage…But It Will Kill You Order Delay 
 
Search
 
Archives

 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 
 
Blogroll

 Brian Sekula Bye Bye Carbs (Dr. Gregory Ellis) CarbSmart Dave Dixon/Spark of Reason Diet Doctor (Dr. Andreas Eenfeldt) Dr. John Briffa Dr. Mike Eades/Protein Power Dr. Richard Feinman Fred Hahn Free The Animal Gary Taubes Gnolls (paleo-science site) Healthy Diets and Science (hundreds of studies cited) Heart Scan Blog (Dr. William Davis) Hyperlipid Livin’La Vida Low Carb Low Carb Pediatrician (Dr. Brad Hoopingarner) Maria&apos;s Nutrition Counseling Mark’s Daily Apple N=1 Health The Thrifty Dieter’s Blog Vin Miller/Natural Bias War on Insulin–Dr. Peter Attia Your Health Is On Your Plate (Dr. Roxanne Sukol) Your Lighter Side 
 
Fast Food Nutrition Info

 Boston Market Carl’s Jr. In-N-Out Burger Jack in the Box KFC McDonald’s Popeye’s Chicken Restaurant Guide Taco Bell Wendy’s 
 
Fat Head News/Reviews

 2Blowhards interview (pre-release) pt. 1 2Blowhards interview (pre-release) pt. 2 2Blowhards interview with Tom (new) Amazon Reviews Associated Content’s review Bionic Broad’s review Box Office Magazine Review David Mendosa’s review Freethunk Review HealthyFixx.com Review Houston Chronicle article Jimmy Moore’s podcast interview LewRockwell.com review Mike Eades’interview Noodle Food’s reviews Unfashionably Economic review Video Business Magazine review 
 
Helpful Links

 Carbs Info–Glycemic Index Diabetes.Net–Glycemic Index Dr. Scott Moore (good list of articles and studies) Healthy Eating Politics Healthy Nation Coalition International Network of Cholesterol Skeptics Low-Carb Cooking (New Zealand) Natural Remedies–Al Sears, M.D. NZ Low Carb Info and Recipes Tom’s Food Log Well Done Chef! Weston A. Price Foundation 
 
Other Blogs

 My Brother&apos;s Blog TomNaughton.com 
 
Recommended Reading

 Cholesterol Does Not Cause Heart Disease Dr. Malcolm Kendrick on the Cholesterol Myths Gary Taubes: The Soft Science of Dietary Fat Gary Taubes: What If It’s All Been A Big Fat Lie? High Insulin Dangers (lecture transcript) Jacob Sullum on the Food Police Jacob Sullum’s review of Super Size Me Low-Fat Diet Myths Malcolm Kendrick on Cholesterol (YouTube) Review of Dr. Ravnskov’s“The Cholesterol Myths” Review of Eric Oliver’s book“Fat Politics” Sally Fallon and Dr. Mary Enig on The Truth About Saturated Fat The Cholesterol Crock Vegetarian Myths What if“bad”fat is really good for you? 
 
Categories

 Bad Diets Bad Medicine Bad Science Good Science Government Foolishness Low-Carb Experts Low-Fat Nonsense Media Misinformation News and Reviews Random Musings Real Food The Food Evangelists 
 
 
 Donate (PayPal)
 
 Big Fat Fiasco 
 How the misguided fear of saturated fat created a nation of obese diabetics. 

 Science For
Smart People 
 Learn to tell good science from bad science ... and laugh while you learn. 

 Order the DVDs 
 
Fat Head DVD

 Order the DVD 
&quot;This movie is funny and entertaining and amazingly informative.&quot;

&quot;Contradicts everything you&apos;ve ever been told about diet and heart disease with true science to back it up.&quot;

&quot;Funny and smart, you&apos;ll be hard pressed to spend a more enlightening 100 minutes, and you&apos;ll come away with more practical knowledge than a whole college course in &apos;convential&apos; nutrition.&quot;

-- Amazon reviewers 
 WHEAT IS MURDER t-shirts! 
 
 
 
Powered by WordPress , Mandigo theme by tom.
 Entries (RSS) and Comments (RSS) .
	</body>
</document>
