<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000229" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Milwaukee/Cousins-Subs_24" time="2012-07-12-15:25" support="1" score="0.0021597366115733794" bingtitle="Cousins Subs - Fast Food Restaurant Milwaukee, WI 53220" webtitle="Cousins Subs - Fast Food Restaurant  Milwaukee, WI 53220">
			<query id="001449" bing-rank="12"/>
	<description>Cousins Subs is a Fast Food restaurant located at 5121 W Howard ... and lost 2/3 of my lunch! 2 people after my order got ... build a new Fairfield ... reign at the east end ...</description>
	<body>
		0 Friend Requests Friend Requests 0 Messages Send a New Message Messages 0 Notifications Notifications 
 
 Find Friends Login 
 or login with: User Pages Photos Events Videos Polls Forum Threads Restaurant Search Results For User Search Results For Pages Search Results For Photos Search Results For Events Search Results For Videos Search Results For Polls Search Results For Forum Threads Search Results For Restaurant 
 Places Deals Recipes Photos Members Blog 
 
 Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Cousins Subs
 
Average User Rating
 
5
 
Average
 
Sponsored Link


 
(414) 321-4650

 http://www.cousinssubs.com/ 
 WI &gt; Milwaukee &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Cousins Subs listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Cousins Subs to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Social 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Cousins Subs
 Cousins Subs is a Fast Food restaurant located at 5121 W Howard Ave in Milwaukee, WI 53220. Cousins Subs has been described as an Good Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 5 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Cousins Subs
 
 
 
All Reviews for Cousins Subs


 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Cousins Subs:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   0

 
Comments
 
 
Cousins Subs Tips
 Call in order even for 1 sub. Waited 20 minutes and lost 2/3 of my lunch! 2 people after my order got there&apos;s first. Wtf!!!
 
John G. eat here trice!!!
 
Rilest C. eat here twice
 
Ryan Eat here
 
S.R.K. 
Cousins Subs News
 Kirk Cousins&apos; Michigan Moments: Q&amp;A;with winningest Michigan State quarterback It’s the week leading into the new year ... what food/restaurant would you miss the most? A: Every time I get home I always go back to a sub shop in downtown Holland (NCAA eligibility rules prohibit Cousins from naming/promoting a restaurant ... A year on the move for area businesses The owners of Cousin’s Country Inn and Restaurant announced plans to build a new Fairfield ... reign at the east end of downtown The Dalles in June.      The New York City Sub Shop folded its tent in December, as did the Pastime Restaurant and ... 10 Great American Regional Foods You Should Taste In 2012 For instance, you can now get deep dish pizza in a chain restaurant at your local mall or from ... Greek-style pastrami is leaner, moister, and less salty than its New York-style deli cousin, and very wet, stored in a vat of warm, paprika ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing Cousins Subs Sandwich Shops | Better Bread. Better Subs.™ Cousins Subs is a gourmet sandwich shop serving the Midwest and Arizona. Find a Cousins restaurant location, look up sandwich nutritional information or check out ... Pizza Restaurant, New York-Style Pizza | Bloomfield Hills, MI Indulge your taste buds with New York-style pizza and subs from our pizzeria restaurant in Bloomfield Hills, Michigan. My Cousin&apos;s New York Pizzeria is a family-owned ... Gourmet, New York Style Pizza, Pasta&amp;Subs - Streets of New York Streets of New York Restaurants - The Passion Is In The Details! Serving Pizza, Pasta and Subs in Arizona for more than 30 years! Cousin&apos;s Pizza, Norwood, NJ New Jersey Restaurant Guide - Norwood ... Cousin&apos;s Pizza - View the menu for Cousin&apos;s Pizza as well as maps, restaurant reviews for Cousin&apos;s Pizza and other restaurants in Norwood, NJ and Norwood. Cousins Subs (Official) - Sandwich Restaurant, Food&amp;Grocery ... Cousins Subs (Official) - Thanks for visiting Better Bread Better Subs! We&apos;re on Twitter, too! | Facebook 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 72° 
Fri
 
 73° - 86° 
Sat
 
 72° - 84° 
Sun
 
 75° - 91° 
 
Address
 
Cousins Subs

5121 W Howard Ave

Milwaukee, WI 
 
53220
 
Telephone
 (414) 321-4650 
Cousins Subs
 
 Rating :  5 out of 10 based on 5 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Cousins Subs Photos
 
 Fast Food 
 
 Local Places
 
 McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Hardee&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food S&amp;P Thai Cuisine 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Cousins Subs 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Redds Snapperseafoods II 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food A&amp;W Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Taco Bell 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Tams Chop Suey 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Arby&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Arby&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Tastee Twist 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Popeye&apos;s Chicken&amp;Biscuits 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Ann M MoryWydeven Ceramic Std 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Brooks Barrow Gallery 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Cultural Alliance 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Fusion 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Gallery H20 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries 
 

See all Milwaukee Art Museums Galleries 
See all Milwaukee Bars and Pubs 
See all Milwaukee ATMs 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Cousins Subs Coupons 

 Cousins Subs Milwaukee 

 Cousins Subs Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Milwaukee Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P Q | R | S | T | U | V | W | Y Z 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
