<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000602" url="http://www.gardenguides.com/video-57011-compost-kitchen-garbage-part-2.html" time="2012-07-12-15:53" support="6" score="0.02670409541951152" bingtitle="Compost Kitchen Garbage: Part 2 | Garden Guides" webtitle="Compost Kitchen Garbage: Part 2 |  Garden Guides">
			<query id="001222" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000557" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="001238" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="001250" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="001246" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="001229" bing-rank="72"/>
	<description>Container Gardens; Greenhouses; Urban Gardens; Small Space ... Usually anything that comes from a fast food restaurant ... have chemicals added to them, I am going to throw away ...</description>
	<body>
		go to my profile 
 All Articles Videos Plants Recipes Members 
 Follow Us! 
 Plants 
 Plant Taxonomy 100 Most Popular Plants About Plants Annual Plants&amp;Flowers Perennial Plants&amp;Flowers Biennial Plants&amp;Flowers Flowers Flower Bulbs Roses Trees&amp;Shrubs Vegetables Herbs Fruits&amp;Nuts Fruits&amp;Vegetables Grasses Grass - Ornamental Grass - Lawn Vines&amp;Climbers Cacti&amp;Succulents Ferns&amp;Mosses Fungi&amp;Lichens Other Plants 
 Garden Design 
 Landscape Design Dry Gardens Edible Gardens Flower Gardens Garden Styles Wet Gardens Wildlife Gardens Gardens by Color Gardens by Light Gardens by Season Gardens by Type of Space 
 Gardening Spaces 
 Indoor Gardens Container Gardens Greenhouses Urban Gardens Small Space Gardens Yards&amp;Lawns 
 Pests&amp;Diseases 
 Animal Control Disease Control Insect Control Weeds Weed Control 
 Gardening Phases 
 Garden Preparation Beginning a Garden Maintenance&amp;Improvement Harvesting Cutting&amp;Preserving Flowers Cooking from the Garden Garden Crafts&amp;Activities 
 Organic Gardening 
 Organic Gardening Tips Organic Edibles Organic Gardening Troubleshooting 
 Resources 
 Regional Gardening Tools&amp;Elements Plant Dictionary Garden Walks Gardening Calendar Local Business Directory Off Season 
 
 
 Gardening Gardening Phases Cooking from the Garden Meat&amp;Entree Recipes Compost Kitchen Garbage: Part 2 
 
Compost Kitchen Garbage: Part 2
 Comments ( )  |  Share:    |  Email  |  Link: Embed: Views : 10140 | Last Update: 2008-07-31 Compost Kitchen Garbage: Part 2 - Provided by eHow Add kitchen garbage to compost heaps or compost bins and learn what foods and materials are not good for compost in this free gardening video. View Video Transcript 
 About this Author 

Yolanda Vanveen


 
 Video Transcript 
 Hi. This is Yolanda Vanveen on behalf of Expert Village. In this series, we&apos;ve learned all about compost and how to start your own compost pile. In this section, we will continue on kitchen garbage and what goes in and what does not go in the compost pile. So we all have fast food as Americans sometimes, and especially when you have kids (it seems hard to get around it as a treat). Usually anything that comes from a fast food restaurant...I could probably compost these buns because they are made from wheat. But, because they probably have chemicals added to them, I am going to throw away the meat and I&apos;m going to throw away the French fries too. If they were home made fries that I made from potatoes and baked them not using oil (because I try not to put any oil in my compost heap, as well), I would probably throw them in the compost heap. But because I know these have been cooked in oil, and you don&apos;t want any types of oil in your compost pile, I&apos;m going to throw them away. And instead of throwing away my bags, I&apos;m actually going to save them and use them to start my fire in my fireplace next time. So, anything that you can recycle out of your refrigerator, whether it be glass, or plastic or paper or paper bags, there are many recycling centers that you can bring them to. But, these bags, I&apos;m actually going to save because I use them to start my fire in my fireplace. Here I have some egg shells remaining. When I was growing up, everyone said to use egg shells in your compost, it was really important for your garden. A lot of people use egg shells in their garden and in their compost. But I usually throw them away because it still goes against my policy that I don&apos;t want any animal products, oils or bodily fluids in my garden (and then, the Styrofoam, I try to recycle as well). Here&apos;s some extra Alfredo noodles and really, they are made of wheat. So, if it were noodles alone, I would probably compost them but because they&apos;ve been mixed with cheese and I don&apos;t want any type of milk products in my compost heap, unfortunately, I&apos;m going to have to throw them away. So, now that we&apos;ve decided what can and can not go in a compost heap, let&apos;s go outside and start our compost heap.
	</body>
</document>
