<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000445" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/23/1570764/restaurant/Aspinwall-Blawnox/Burgatory-Bar-Pittsburgh" time="2012-07-12-15:41" support="1" score="0.0016611716279470341" bingtitle="Burgatory Bar - Aspinwall/Blawnox - Pittsburgh | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Burgatory Bar - Aspinwall/Blawnox - Pittsburgh | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="001289" bing-rank="99"/>
	<description>... Chef Bill ... Shmelvin, If you want a &quot;cheap lunch&quot; go to a fast food restaurant. I prefer to pay a bit more ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Pittsburgh » North » Aspinwall&amp;Blawnox » Burgatory Bar 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Buffalo Cleveland Columbus Los Angeles New York Toronto Washington DC More... 
 
Burgatory Bar
 
(412) 781-1456
 Aspinwall/Blawnox 932 Freeport Rd 
 Pittsburgh , PA 15238 
 burgatorybar.com 
 on facebook.com 

Added by Mallory Lambert 
 See all 199 reviews Cuisine American , Burgers Features Happy Hour , Outdoor Dining Menu $$ $10-15 per entree Create Your Own Burger, Nutella Nestle Milkshake , Prantl Burnt Almond... View menu 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Dinner ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Late ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ 
   1624 people have voted 89 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 India Garden 80% $$ Oakland - Indian, Buffet 328 Atwood St 
 
 Mineo&apos;s Pizza House... 83% $$ Squirrel Hill/CMU - Pizza, Italian 2128 Murray Ave 
 
Critic reviews

 June 30, 2011 City Paper Burgatory&apos;s burgers are unquestionably in the running for best in town More from City Paper June 24, 2011 Pittsburgh Magazine Most fun is the “custom creation” offering, which allows you to build your own burger, starting with your choice of... More from Pittsburgh Magazine March 30, 2011 Pittsburgh Tribune-Review Burgatory sends some mouths to food heaven More from Pittsburgh Tribune-Review February 10, 2011 Pittsburgh Post Gazette The menu promises&quot;Helluva Burger and Heavenly Shakes&quot;and does not disappoint. More from Pittsburgh Post Gazette 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews

 May 4, 2012 Likes it Pitts-Burgers The Jalapeños slightly overpowered the flavor, and unfortunately the Beef, and Cheese were slightly masked. Overall this was a good burger, and I wouldn&apos;t hesitate to come back and try it... More from Pitts-Burgers February 12, 2012 A Dash of Spectacular Our shake was a chocolate base with graham crackers blended in. The grainy texture might sound terrible to some {and I thought I&apos;d agree!}, but it went so well with the whipped cream and... More from A Dash of Spectacular February 6, 2012 Likes it Fast Food Geek The quest for the ultimate burger has been an ongoing process that has passed through generation after generation, lifetime after lifetime, animal byproduct by animal byproduct. But one... More from Fast Food Geek November 4, 2011 Likes it The Steel Trap In August, I started to explore the Burgh&apos;s burger phenomenon in this post . Not too long ago, I went for round 2 at Burgatory , located in the Waterworks Mall (which is in the City of... More from The Steel Trap October 19, 2011 Pittsburgh Eats Burgatory, while having the actual best burger I have tried yet, failed in some other key aspects of my visit. The service needs to be improved. The chips are almost comically bad... More from Pittsburgh Eats 
 Show 15 more 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 May 25, 2012 Really likes it Where&apos;s the BEEF? by Ken P. ( 84 reviews ) It&apos;s Here! I like Burgatory better than BRGR and believe it or not, better than Tessaro&apos;s. And forget about Pittsburgh Burger Company! The Lowdown: It&apos;s casual, it&apos;s good for families, it&apos;s loud, it&apos;s open and airy, and it&apos;s tucked into a corner of waterworks mall. I think it used to be a Chinese restaurant. The food is burgers.. you can order a few choices off the menu or you can build your own...from bun to beef to cheese to toppings, etc...you order a&quot;build your own&quot;via a checklist ala Bahama Mama (a restaurant in the Bank Center downtown - who remembers THAT??) I opted for the hormone free beef (vs. the more expensive wagyu beef), angel dust rub (salt pepper garlic), cracked peppercorn rub, cheddar horseradish cheese and some type of aioli sauce. SHAZAM! You can also choose RED, PINK or Medium for cooking style. I choose RED of course! My kid Meg ordered hers pink. Girl after my own heart. The burger was awesome. The beef was high quality, the rubs were... more» It&apos;s Here! I like Burgatory better than BRGR and believe it or not, better than Tessaro&apos;s. And forget about Pittsburgh Burger Company! The Lowdown: It&apos;s casual, it&apos;s good for families, it&apos;s loud, it&apos;s open and airy, and it&apos;s tucked into a corner of waterworks mall. I think it used to be a Chinese restaurant. The food is burgers.. you can order a few choices off the menu or you can build your own...from bun to beef to cheese to toppings, etc...you order a&quot;build your own&quot;via a checklist ala Bahama Mama (a restaurant in the Bank Center downtown - who remembers THAT??) I opted for the hormone free beef (vs. the more expensive wagyu beef), angel dust rub (salt pepper garlic), cracked peppercorn rub, cheddar horseradish cheese and some type of aioli sauce. SHAZAM! You can also choose RED, PINK or Medium for cooking style. I choose RED of course! My kid Meg ordered hers pink. Girl after my own heart. The burger was awesome. The beef was high quality, the rubs were perfect, and the whole thing was a great, fresh, juicy, scrumptious mess! The bugers came with chips - both tater and sweet tater. They were good - no better or no worse than others. The fries were good... salted and herbed. Shoestrings...run of the mill. As far as I&apos;m concerned 5 Guys has the best fries around - these don&apos;t even come close. The onion rings were good, and huge and almost as $$ as the burger. I don&apos;t get that, but they were good. For dessert Meg and I had one of their shakes. Whatever. It was good. Mine was Salted Nutella and hers was S&apos;mores.. Let&apos;s be honest..I don&apos;t believe there is any way to really elevate a shake by using chocolate and vanilla ice cream. Mine had nutella - so what. Hers had chunks of ground up graham crackers. They were as good as any Dairy Queen Blizzard. They were 5 bucks for a large. Keep in mind Blizzards are 5 bucks too - so they are not all they expensive. They were good...to die for?? Na. I should mention, in addition to burgers, they also have a chix sandwich, a lump crab sandwich (which is hard to believe since it&apos;s only $10) - Backfin crab meat is probable...but lump?? They also had a few appetizers ($9 for wings???). And they have a kids menu. I would absolutely go back! 2 out of 2 found this review helpful July 11, 2012 Likes it One word - EXPAND ! by RCase ( 34 reviews ) And I don&apos;t just mean the physical size of this restaurant, but expand into other parts of the city. Please!! It&apos;s been 18 months since my first review...... and this place has not let me down in numerous visits. Better than ever, and the ownership group needs to capitalize on this success now! McKnight Road needs one, the Waterfront needs one, the Galleria needs one, Shadyside needs one. I&apos;d truly love to be an investor in their expansion plans. This concept could be taken anywhere. But they need to move NOW! +1 more review from RCase February 4, 2011 Off to a good start, but... Let me first say that I do like the burgers here. I&apos;ve now eaten here twice, and think they do a very nice job in providing quality food; prepared, dressed, and cooked the way you want it. I do like that you can order your burger with a specialty rub (peppercorn, kona, salt/pepper/garlic salt combination, etc.). It seems to keep the meat juicy and tasty. I really hope they keep up this quality as time progresses. I also hope they try to refine some of the rougher edges that currently exist:... more» Let me first say that I do like the burgers here. I&apos;ve now eaten here twice, and think they do a very nice job in providing quality food; prepared, dressed, and cooked the way you want it. I do like that you can order your burger with a specialty rub (peppercorn, kona, salt/pepper/garlic salt combination, etc.). It seems to keep the meat juicy and tasty. I really hope they keep up this quality as time progresses. I also hope they try to refine some of the rougher edges that currently exist: It sure seems like they could have made better use of the space in the restaurant for seating. This needs to be a restaurant first and a bar second. The amount of open floor space seems to indicate they&apos;re anticipating a larger population of standing drinkers in the establishment. As well, the seats at the high top tables are ridiculously small and tremendously uncomfortable (and I&apos;m a guy with a small waist/butt). Right now, in fairness, the service staff is still feeling itself out... but I&apos;m not seeing a whole lot of quality servers just yet. One last note, the pricing of toppings for the burgers is somewhat inconsistent - in that some of the things that are free, I&apos;d expect to pay extra for - and some of the things that are an additional charge, I&apos;d expect to be free.. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful May 28, 2012 My favorite burger joint by sjw23 ( 23 reviews ) This is my favorite burger place in this city! Unfortunately, I very recently found out I have a gluten intolerance, which means I will not be at Burgatory any time soon -- how can I go and not order a delicious burger?? I probably would do it, and then be sick for days and days. I&apos;ll jump for joy (and over the river right to you!!) if I ever find out you offer gluten free buns!!!!! +1 more review from sjw23 March 1, 2012 Not much they can screw up here Yesterday was my fourth visit to Burgatory since they opened. The first time I went I was put off by the hostess who was wearing bright pink sweat pants (I&apos;m not joking) ... thankfully never to be seen again. We got a nacho appetizer which is a better fit for 3+ diners, it was too much for just the two of us. We took it home and only half the chips were soggy. We created our burgers and we both enjoyed them immensely! Our server, Sarah, was wonderful! She checked on us often and refilled our... more» Yesterday was my fourth visit to Burgatory since they opened. The first time I went I was put off by the hostess who was wearing bright pink sweat pants (I&apos;m not joking) ... thankfully never to be seen again. We got a nacho appetizer which is a better fit for 3+ diners, it was too much for just the two of us. We took it home and only half the chips were soggy. We created our burgers and we both enjoyed them immensely! Our server, Sarah, was wonderful! She checked on us often and refilled our iced teas without us asking. Brought the check without us having to ask. She was just great! The wait for the burgers was a long, but we went during the lunch rush and as soon as a table emptied it was wiped off and resat. Worth the wait. April 27, 2012 Likes it Love these upscale burgers by Angela B ( 47 reviews ) I love these make-your-own burger places and to be able to pick your own combination of toppings. The burgers are really big, I only had half. I ordered it cooked to medium but it was cooked to probably medium-well/well. Not too big of a deal, I&apos;m pretty easy to please. The milkshake was delicious, I got the salted caramel one. The flavors complimented each other very well and it was extremely rich and thick. The wait is a killer, with the app they have I believe you can put a place in line and not have to wait around for hours (don&apos;t quote me on that though). The seats aren&apos;t very comfortable either, and we were placed in a high traffic area and I kept getting bumped. Oh well. Overall, I think its worth the wait if you love burgers. May 28, 2012 Really likes it by jerry walbach ( 6 reviews ) this place is awesome and i hope they open more around Pittsburgh because its a haul to get here some times. burgers are cooked perfect every time and you cant blame slow service when its always packed. the food might take a few minutes longer than you like but its worth it. add a milkshake and its nap time! March 1, 2012 Likes it @eater...your review by Effort ( 205 reviews ) Your review must be for BRGR since Burgatory does not have a roof. 4 out of 5 found this review helpful +2 more review from Effort September 19, 2011 Beef or not to Beef Most people order burgers, build you own or one of the specialties. Well, for some reason the crab looked good to me. So I had a delicious Crab Shack that came with a sauce and tart slaw. It was very good. Went early and beat the crowd. We were sitted immediately and had good service. 3 out of 3 found this review helpful November 20, 2011 Beef or Not to Beef? Stopped back at Burgatory with a friend and decided to try the Beef. Had a Custom Creation with a rub and some of my favorite condiments that usually do not get on a burger. It turned out to be really good. Nice and juicy, flavorful and cooked perfectly. 3 out of 3 found this review helpful June 15, 2012 Likes it Mobile review by H24 ( 3 reviews ) Excellent food and atmosphere. Lump Crab Burger was very good. Prime Dip good but prefer the prior. Service good but didn&apos;t care much for unsweetened tea. June 12, 2012 Likes it I will dream about this Burger... by Aspen ( 2 reviews ) Create Your Own Burger, Nutella Nestle Milkshake -
WOW! I have always been in search of the best burger, and I think I may have found it... I did the create your own with the basic ground beef, wheat bun, cracked peppercorn, roasted garlic mayo, white american cheese, guacamole, onion strings, red onions, and lettuce. This was a fabulous meal, you can really taste the fresh, quality ingredients. It is an expensive dinner for a burger, but totally worth the price (the portions are huge!). I think the only way this place could get a bad review is if you just picked a bad combination on the create your own; with so many choices, it can be a little overwhelming to narrow down and be sure you have ingredients that will taste well together. I also got the Nutella Nestle Crunch milkshake and was pretty convinced I died and went to Nutella heaven. If you are in Pttt, I HIGHLY recommend putting this on your places to visit! July 6, 2012 WOW What A Burger by Hubert Powers ( 1 review ) I visited Pittsburgh for a business meeting and my colleagues suggested suggested the Burgatory Bar. I am so glad I took their advice because it was one hell of a burger. I had mine topped with Gruyere cheese and smoked ham and it was gorgeous. I also tried one of their famous Nutella shakes and yum. Check them out for yourself and see. January 22, 2012 Likes it Hip and Tasty by Marcus Carcus ( 14 reviews ) Surprisingly hip, especially since it&apos;s part of a strip mall, you usually find places this trendy in tucked away, older neighborhoods of Pittsburgh, It&apos;s a little pricy for burgers and shakes, but you&apos;re compensated by the atmosphere. I have a feeling that people either love it and are regulars or tend to visit once and find it a little overrated. I have no complaints with my burger, except that they forgot to put something that I ordered on my burger (you can custom-order a burger by filling out a paper sort of scorecard in the center of your table) and I was too timid to mention it to my waiter. I would return here, it&apos;s also conveniently located by the cinema, with a little walkway that cuts through the strip mall, so if carefully scheduled, dinner here and then a movie would be a good night out. 2 out of 2 found this review helpful May 1, 2012 Likes it Awesome by ericdicenzo ( 3 reviews ) Caramel Pretzel shake -
I have raved about Burgatory since it opened. The burgers are delicious--- expecially the chicken burger. And the Caramel Pretzel Shake is my guilty pleaure. This place is going to continue to do well. They use great ingredients to make delicious food. The servers are always friendly and I love the drinks. Now if I could only convince them to take reservations! April 27, 2012 Likes it Great milkshakes... by Kelly ( 9 reviews ) We came here on a Saturday night, hungry and excited for a delicious burger. When we got there, the young hostess casually said there was a 2 hour wait, at 9pm. Shocked, we asked her to repeat herself and she rudely said it again. Luckily, there were 4 seats together at the bar so enjoyed dinner there. The bartender seemed annoyed that we sat there and didn&apos;t offer menus, the specials, or to clean up the area where we sat. Trying to shake it off, we started with the caramel pretzel milkshake. This was the best thing I have ever tasted and negated the service for the time being. Then for our main course, we ordered the Bison burger and Meat your maker, medium rare. Expected to be the best cooked and best tasting burgers of our lives, we were both mildly disappointed. They both came out almost well done and they were just ok. Overall, I would go back just for another milkshake, but the service and the quality of the burgers weren&apos;t up to par. January 29, 2012 my review and rebuttal by shmelvin ( 182 reviews ) Obviously food lover has a hard time grasping the English language, nowhere in my review did I say I wanted a&quot;Cheap lunch&quot;But! As a responsible reviewer I was just pointing out that this place is not inexpensive, and some people may find the price a little steep (especially in this economy). After reading food lovers reviews he/she like so many equates price with quality, sometimes they are parallel and sometimes they are not. Good but $$$$ I really have no complaints but! 3 burgers, 3 iced teas, and 1 order of fries with a tip $60.00 not exactly a cheap lunch. Don&apos;t get me wrong it was good, but not fabulous. 6 out of 8 found this review helpful February 9, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by Anthony Tomasic ( 2 reviews ) Last year we had a great meal - filet and ribs. Both items are gone now. A classic management mistake in thinking that your lesser selling items can be cut. This place was a good restaurant and bar. Now it is a burger place. 4 out of 4 found this review helpful March 24, 2012 Likes it Best burger by far by Kitty and wolf ( 42 reviews ) We ate here twice now. The menu is wonderful with a nice mix of options from salads to build your own burger. All the food is extremely fresh. The bison burger is a great healthier option. If you have not tried bison, try it here. The chicken chili is amazing with just the right amount of a kick of spicy. If you like nachos, Burgatory does a nice spin on a nacho platter...advice....ask for the sauce on the side so the mushiness does not set in. Many posts complain about the price for a burger. All we can say is you pay for what you get. Want quality, then be willing to pay a small premium. Also, do yourself a favor and sit at the bar and then you won&apos;t have a long wait. The wait staff is top notch. We must also comment on a similar restaurant Brgr. If Burgatory opened a location in the Shadyside surrounding area, Brgr would be put out of business. February 9, 2012 Good for Burgers and Shakes by Nisha ( 3 reviews ) My boyfriend and I went there this afternoon for the 3rd or 4th time since it opened. I was initially disappointed that there was no mac and cheese AND they got rid of the organic bison in the bison burger. It wasn&apos;t very busy at all being the afternoon on a weekday but it seemed to take the waiter forever to actually ask us if we were ready to order. Service overall wasn&apos;t that great and the only foods that were great were the burgers and the shakes. I ordered fries since they got rid of their mac and cheese and they were probably the worst fries I&apos;ve ever had in my life, I wish that were an exaggeration, they were barely warm, not well seasoned and also overcooked. The chips that came with my BF&apos;s burger were also inedible and again barely warm and overcooked. After eating his burger and shake he was still hungry so he ordered chili which looked amazing but was also lukewarm which is not appetizing no matter how good it is. Maybe since it was the afternoon on a weekday we got the... more» My boyfriend and I went there this afternoon for the 3rd or 4th time since it opened. I was initially disappointed that there was no mac and cheese AND they got rid of the organic bison in the bison burger. It wasn&apos;t very busy at all being the afternoon on a weekday but it seemed to take the waiter forever to actually ask us if we were ready to order. Service overall wasn&apos;t that great and the only foods that were great were the burgers and the shakes. I ordered fries since they got rid of their mac and cheese and they were probably the worst fries I&apos;ve ever had in my life, I wish that were an exaggeration, they were barely warm, not well seasoned and also overcooked. The chips that came with my BF&apos;s burger were also inedible and again barely warm and overcooked. After eating his burger and shake he was still hungry so he ordered chili which looked amazing but was also lukewarm which is not appetizing no matter how good it is. Maybe since it was the afternoon on a weekday we got the cook who only knew how to make burgers idk but everything we ordered other than shakes and burgers wasn&apos;t worth the trip and definitely not worth the money. Unfortunate experience at a restaurant I actually do like a lot. 3 out of 3 found this review helpful March 17, 2012 Likes it Mobile review by Chef Bill ( 34 reviews ) Best burger in Pittsburgh! In my opinion fatheads held the title for at least ten years but this burger is better. The hamburger competition in the area has really multiplied. Bad news for the burger makers......Good news for us!!! April 30, 2012 Atmosphere a plus, burgers, not so much by Elin ( 1 review ) The first trip I made to Burgatory was shortly after they had opened and I hadn&apos;t been impressed. My burger was just okay, but I loved everything else they had to offer. Upon going back again, I have to say I&apos;m left with the same thoughts. If I lived closer to the area, this would be a place I&apos;d go to hang out, watch the game, and have an amazing hard milkshake. However, it wouldn&apos;t be one that I&apos;d probably ever be left craving their burgers. The staff is very knowledgeable though and extremely helpful. If only every place in the city had this to offer. Plus the decor is really cool, featuring a warm industrial vibe, with plenty of TVs to watch various games on. So try it out for yourself, because it is a fun place, although you might have a long wait, and get a milkshake no matter what. December 13, 2011 Likes it Worth the wait and Great for a Date by The Ad Minister ( 27 reviews ) This place is run well, has best burger and Shake in town and is a cool but non-pretentious place to hang out. I&apos;d invest my life savings in Burgatory Stock if I could. 2 out of 3 found this review helpful January 21, 2012 Dericioush. by CL ( 15 reviews ) I went to Burgatory, then went straight to Heaven. To begin with, great atmosphere- loud, a bit tight in terms of space, but HOPPIN. Boyfriend and I waited for about 45 minutes, which was not a huge deal since A.) I wasn&apos;t famished and B.) we went to the Barnes&amp;Noble next door (fun times). They used an iPad that texted us when our table was ready, which was v cool. Now, the FOOD....bf got the steak burger (forget the name of it- it was the one with the peppercorn steak), and he said it was prettty much the best burger he&apos;d ever had. I made my own creation- beef on brioche + jalapenos, shallot truffle aioli, and lettuce. Uh, YUM. Our burgers were gone in about 5 minutes. Chips were dec. We also got the Apple Pancake Bacon Shake- I only have one word for it: INTENSE. SO: make sure you go when you&apos;re not starving (yet)- the burgers are derish. 2 out of 2 found this review helpful 
 Show 151 more 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by Clara Morty Steakhouse... by ForkedPgh Milk&amp;Cereal... 
 All 39 photos View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Uncle Sam&apos;s Submarines 93% $$ Aspinwall/Blawnox - American Walnut Grove Restaurant&amp;... 69% $$$ Aspinwall/Blawnox - American, Seafood, Steakhouse Kings Family Restaurant 35% $ Aspinwall/Blawnox - American Ichiban Hibachi Steakhouse&amp;... 81% $$$ Aspinwall/Blawnox - Sushi, Japanese, Steakhouse Aladdin&apos;s Eatery 93% $ Aspinwall/Blawnox - Middle Eastern, Mediterranean 
 More nearby restaurants People reached this page by searching for: 
 burgatory burgatory aspinwall menu burgatory restaurant burgatory pittsburgh burgatory bar 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
