<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000041" url="http://www.2knowmyself.com/miscellaneous/Restaurant_color_psychology" time="2012-07-12-15:13" support="1" score="0.0013319779216200453" bingtitle="Restaurant color psychology | 2KnowMySelf" webtitle="Restaurant color psychology | 2KnowMySelf">
			<query id="000307" bing-rank="205"/>
	<description>In case you are running a restaurant or you are planning to open a restaurant soon then ... Enter your search terms</description>
	<body>
		The Ultimate Source for Understanding Yourself and others
 Home | All Articles | Books | About | Free Videos | Newsletter | Affiliates | Contact | Testimonials | Coaching 
 
31 Million can&apos;t be wrong

 
 Staples Coupons 
Overcome depression now
 

 

The Ultimate guide to Getting over depression, mood swings&amp;bad moods Based on psychology
 
Latest Articles
 
 2008-2010 Articles 2011 Articles 3 ways fears affect people&apos;s lives Aggressive people psychology Different strategies for attracting people to you Does money attract women does our personality affect our level of attractiveness Does smiling make you more attractive? do people get attracted to those who are as physically attractive as them Do short men have any chance do women care about looks How incorrect perception affects self confidence How to attract someone who is not interested in you how to become financially successful How to stop worrying about the first impression Understanding Anxiety and depression from a different angle What attracts men (the psychology of attraction of males) why do people like certain facial features Why do people see the world differently (perception psychology) Why extra attention can attract some people and not others Becoming rich online How can i love my husband again (Based on the psychology of love) How To Get Over Someone how to get over someone you can&apos;t have how to have a healthy relationship How to know if someone likes me(Based on the psychology of love) How to know if someone likes you How to make anyone fall in love with you How to use reverse psychology on people I broke up with my boyfriend/girlfriend Inferiority complex songs to get over someone Stages of getting over someone Why do people cheat in relationships? 
 
My Problem:
 
 Dealing with Rejection Dealing with Narcissism Dumped by my Boyfriend/Girlfriend Feeling Insecure Feeling Jealous Dealing with Loneliness Dealing with Mood swings Dealing With Breakups Feeling Inferior Emotionally sensitive 
 

 
 
 
 
 
Restaurant color psychology
 Written by M.Farouk Radwan , MSc. Color psychology 
Psychology is everywhere

Whether you are a business man who wants to motivate your employees or whether you are an ordinary person who wants to have a good relationship with your wife you are going to definitely need psychology somewhere in your life.

Color psychology is the science that explains the connection between colors and the psychology of people. Certain colors can affects people&apos;s moods. Some colors can affect the way people perceive you while some other colors can help you sell more food at your own restaurant!

Restaurant color psychology

In case you are running a restaurant or you are planning to open a restaurant soon then the following few color psychology tips will help you make the best out of it.

 Blue and purple can result in loss of appetite: usually the subconscious mind connects blue or purple to toxins. Yes, I know there are some healthy Chinese food that is blue yet studies has shown that they can decrease the appetite.
If you want lots of customers to visit your restaurant and to eat more then avoid the blue color. Yellow would make people stay less at your restaurant: yellow is an irritating color. People tend to feel more irritated in yellow rooms. Some fast food restaurants paint their walls in yellow in order to motivate people to leave as soon as they order their food so that they free more space for new customers . Green is relaxing: Green is a relaxing color and can improve vision. People associate green with nature and that&apos;s why they feel more comfortable in rooms painted in green. Painting your restaurant&apos;s wall with a green color is a good idea Red is an appetite stimulator&amp;eye catching color: red is a very eye catching color and this makes it useful in case you want to draw some attention to your restaurant. but take care, do not over use the red color because it&apos;s still an irritating color just like yellow .It might be a good idea to use some red on the outer walls to direct some attention to your restaurant. Red stimulates the appetite and it was found that a red table would make people eat more. 

Other factors that can help you make your restaurant more profitable

It was found that the music played while people are sitting at a restaurant can affect their mood and as result let them consume more food.

This doesn&apos;t only stop at music but it extends to include smells as well! Certain smells can put people into buying mood and motivate them to buy more goods.

Finally the way waiters or the restaurant owners treat their customers can have a significant impact on their spending habits. One study has found that people tend to visit the shops with friendly shop owners more often!

A tip as simple as being more friendly with your customers can help you sell more.

2knowmysef is not a complicated medical website nor it’s a boring online encyclopedia but it’s a place where you will find simple, to the point and effective information that is presented in an uncomplicated and clear way. If you think that this is some kind of marketing hype then see what other visitors say about 2knowmyself .The book How to make someone fall in love with you was released by 2knowmyself.com; the book will dramatically increase your chance of letting someone fall in love with you.

Want to know more?

 How music affects people moods 

 Yes but I want to know more about psychology of colors? 

 Yes but what is an anchor? 
 How to make someone fall in love with me? (book) 

 How to get over anyone in few days? (book) 

 How to become rich while working from home (book) 

 Click here to see all 2knowmyself&apos;s books 

 Share 

 
 
 
2knowmyself Books
 

 

How to get over anyone in few days Breakups will never hurt like before.


 

How to make someone fall in love with you. Based on the psychology of falling in love


 

How i did it. The ultimate guide to making money from the internet


 

 

The Ultimate guide to Breaking habits Break any unwanted habit tonight
 
 

The Ultimate Guide To Maintaining A Healthy Relationship Reduce fights, avoid breakups and live happily.
 
Audio
 
 How to make someone fall in love with you. 
 How to get over someone 
 Making money from the internet 
 
Most Popular
 
 What is Real Love? Signs that Shows that He likes you Does Love at First Sight Really Exist? Free Face reading How to Stop Loving Someone Who Doesn&apos;t Love you Love body Language Psychology Of Love&amp;Relationships Reading Body language (Male&amp;Female) 
 
The Best of Farouk
 
 How to make someone fall in love with you Signs that shows that someone Likes You How To Get Over Someone How to know if someone is lying to you
	</body>
</document>
