<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000572" url="http://wiki.answers.com/Q/Fast_food_restaurant_do_more_harm_than_good_food" time="2012-07-12-15:51" support="1" score="0.0007004212749038185" bingtitle="Fast food restaurant do more harm than good food" webtitle="Fast food restaurant do more harm than good foodFast food restaurant do more harm than good food">
			<query id="000738" bing-rank="212"/>
	<description>... Restaurants and Dining Establishments &gt; Fast food restaurant do more ... Why would your car volt amps drop while you stop ... Find Cell Phone Numbers Online; Are Debt Consolidation ...</description>
	<body>
		Unanswered Questions New Answers Q&amp;A;Categories Coupons Guides 

 Sign In | Sign Up Home Search Settings Top Contributors Help Center English▼ 
 English Français Deutsch Italiano Español Tagalog 
 
 Home Answers.com &gt; Wiki Answers &gt; Categories &gt; Food&amp;Cooking &gt; Restaurants and Dining Establishments &gt; Fast food restaurant do more harm than good food? 
Fast food restaurant do more harm than good food?
 In: Restaurants and Dining Establishments [ Edit categories ] 

 Answer: 
 No they are good for you and they are healthy you should eat at fast food resturants. :] 


 I&apos;m just kidding they are bad for you did you watch that guy who ate it only for one whole month? He made 30 pounds and it took him 3 months to get skinny again. ` 
 

 First answer by ID1207940313 . Last edit by Xoverly sarcasticx . Contributor trust : 0 
 [ recommend contributor recommended ]. Question popularity : 1 [ recommend question ]. [ report abuse ] 
Can you answer these Restaurants and Dining Establishments questions?
 
 How much does it cost to go to studio movie grill? Answer it! What do people call waitress? Answer it! What are the types of restaurant according to concept? Answer it! Is there agency in Cyprus to send to Canada for working? Answer it! What are the top 8 foods in Costa Rica? Answer it! 
 
Relevant answers:
 
 Fast food restaurants do more good than harm ? 
 YESs 
 Do fast foods do more harm than good ? 
 My take is that they do much more harm than good. 
 Fast food does more harm than good ? 
 Yes the food is fast but has tons of grease in it causing your artier to be clogged with bad. 
 Do fast food restaurants do more harm then good ? 
 my it would seem that fast food does do more harm than good. because it could cause some deises 
 Fast food resturants do more harms than goods ? 
 It depends. If you eat it everyday then you will get fat and unhealthy, but if you eat it every other weekend or so it won&apos;t affect you as much. The blame for obesity is the individual person not the... 
 
 
Shopping for Restaurants and Dining Establishments deals?

Find Coupons and Promo Codes on Coupons by Answers.com

 Cafe Britt Coupons CafeFit Coupons Burger King Coupons Chilis Coupons 
 FIND MORE COUPONS AND PROMO CODES Sign in using: Answers members: Username Lost password? Password Remember me Sign in 
Home
 
 Recent site activity Browse categories 
 Animal Life Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Vehicles Entertainment&amp;Arts Food&amp;Cooking Health History, Politics&amp;Society Hobbies&amp;Collectibles Home&amp;Garden Humor&amp;Amusement Jobs&amp;Education Law&amp;Legal Issues Literature&amp;Language Relationships Religion&amp;Spirituality Science Shopping Sports Technology Travel&amp;Places WikiAnswers Local 
 Random question Promoted questions Community forum Unanswered questions Advanced search Top contributors Q&amp;A;categories Coupons Guides Settings 
 
 Answer these 
 What is a pathway of blood flow from the dorsal venous arch of the foot to the right atrium? In: Human Anatomy Answer it! Would a mouse eat a dead moth? In: Mice and Rats Answer it! How do you register Pandora? In: Intel 8085 Answer it! What are some games that are like warlords 2? In: Video Games Answer it! » more 
Featured guides
 
 Science Diet Coupons Online Choosing An ATV How to Install a Kitchen Faucet How to Install an Amplifier Male Genital Warts 
 » More 
Answers Properties
 
 Answers Wiki Answers Video Answers Guides Coupons 

 Local Answers Online Answers Shop Answers Blog Sitemap 
 
Company
 
 About Terms of Use Privacy Policy IP Issues Disclaimer 
 
Community
 
 Guidelines Reputation Roles Help 
 
Updates
 
 Email Watchlist RSS 
 
 
International sites
 English | Deutsch | Español | Français | Italiano | Tagalog 
 
 Copyright©2012 Answers Corporation facebook twitter youtube blog
	</body>
</document>
