<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000321" url="http://intelliwiser.com/" time="2012-07-12-15:30" support="1" score="0.0007520182512029194" bingtitle="Intelliwiser" webtitle="Intelliwiser">
			<query id="000057" bing-rank="241"/>
	<description>It’s quick, easy, and convenient for many people to stop by a fast food restaurant on ... Coconut water also acts as a natural diuretic helping excess waste to pass through ...</description>
	<body>
		About 
 
 Intelliwiser 
 Information to help you make better choices to lead a healthier life. July 9, 2012 0 Comments 
 Natural Ways to Help You Look Younger 
 
Almost everyone is familiar with the phrase, “The Fountain of Youth”, and nearly everyone would be happy if they could find it. Unfortunately, that’s not the case, and if you are among the… Read More → 
 July 2, 2012 0 Comments 
 Are GMO’S Bad for You? 
 
There are many food products today that you may not know are genetically modified since food manufacturers in the United States and Canada are not required to disclose this fact on their labels.… Read More → 
 June 25, 2012 3 Comments 
 Five of the Foods that are Healthiest for You 
 
You may have started a new diet regimen to include eating only healthy foods to lose, maintain weight, or if you’re among the select few, gain weight. Whatever the case may be, proper… Read More → 
 June 18, 2012 0 Comments 
 Healthy and Delicious Chicken-Apple Salad 
 
Healthy eating habits should include planning a wide array of nutritious meals to help you maintain a balanced diet. Salads may be the perfect complement to several meals, or serve as the main… Read More → 
 June 11, 2012 0 Comments 
 Tips to Help Improve Lasting Weight Loss 
 
You should be proud when you’ve met your weight loss goal, and motivated and challenged to keep it off. It can be difficult for many people, however, when so many aspects of our… Read More → 
 June 4, 2012 0 Comments 
 Eight Tips for a Healthy Summer Picnic 
 
Almost everyone loves the fun, and frolic, of summer picnics. There are, however, summer picnic safety tips to keep in mind for adults and children, to keep the summer picnic activities healthy. What… Read More → 
 May 28, 2012 0 Comments 
 Best Exercises for Flatter Abs 
 
Some people who are diligent with exercise and a healthy diet find they may still have a problem with a bulge in their midsection. It’s difficult for most individuals to obtain the so-called… Read More → 
 May 21, 2012 0 Comments 
 Healthy Benefits of Whole Wheat Flour versus Enriched Flour 
 
If you’re one of the many health conscious individuals who now read the ingredient labels more closely before buying food products, you may be aware that many products contain the ingredient labeled enriched… Read More → 
 May 14, 2012 1 Comment 
 Seven Ways to Curb Your Appetite Naturally 
 
Anyone who has tried unsuccessfully to shed a few pounds or even a considerable amount of weight may find it difficult if you’re always hungry. There are ways to curb your appetite naturally,… Read More → 
 May 7, 2012 1 Comment 
 Positive Thinking for a Longer Life 
 
You probably have heard the familiar phrase, laughter is the best medicine, or is the glass half empty or half full? What you may not have realized is the importance of those phrases,… Read More → 
 
Post navigation
 1 2 3 4 5 … 7 8 
 
Links
 


 Blog Directory Top Blog Sites 
 
 
 
 Blogs Blog Tools Promote Blog 



 
 Top Stories 

 

 pc-review.net 
 
 Blog at WordPress.com .
 Theme: Triton Lite by Towfiq I . Follow 
 Follow“Intelliwiser” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
