<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000126" url="http://www.supertopo.com/climbing/thread.php?topic_id=454584&amp;tn=0&amp;mr=0" time="2012-07-12-15:19" support="1" score="0.0022117758376323723" bingtitle="Shawangunks - Cornerstone of Eastern Traditional Climbing ..." webtitle="Shawangunks - Cornerstone of Eastern Traditional  Climbing :: SuperTopo Rock Climbing Discussion Topic">
			<query id="000789" bing-rank="66"/>
	<description>Geno-I think you were on Exit Stage Left in those ... roof, I couldn&apos;t imagine it going at anywhere near 5.9. ... Is a book actually in the works? If so, I&apos;ll place my order now!!!!!</description>
	<body>
		Welcome Guest!
 Join SuperTopo 
 Sign In 

 View Cart 
 
 Home Climbing Areas 
 Alaska Bay Area Bouldering Desert Towers, Utah High Sierra Red Rocks, Nevada South Lake Tahoe Yosemite Big Walls Yosemite Valley Tuolumne Meadows Zion National Park 
 Climbing Routes 
 Route Search Boulder Search Trad Climbing Routes 
 Alaska Desert Towers, Utah High Sierra Red Rocks, Nevada South Lake Tahoe Yosemite Valley Tuolumne Meadows 
 Big Wall Routes 
 Yosemite Big Walls Zion National Park, Utah 
 Bouldering Routes 
 Bay Area Bouldering Northern California Bouldering Yosemite Valley Bouldering Lake Tahoe Bouldering Tuolumne Bouldering 
 
 Guidebooks 
 Traditional Climbing 
 Alaska Climbing Desert Towers Select High Sierra Climbing Red Rocks Climbing South Lake Tahoe Climbing Yosemite Valley Free Climbs Tuolumne Free Climbs 
 Big Wall Climbing 
 Yosemite Big Walls The Road to the Nose Zion Climbing: Free and Clean 
 Bouldering 
 Bay Area Bouldering Lake Tahoe Bouldering Northern California Bouldering Yosemite Valley Bouldering Tuolumne Bouldering 
 DVDs 
 Learning to Fly DVD The Sharp End DVD 
 
 Free Topos Photos 
 Featured Photos Pro Photo Gallery Climber Slideshows Upload a Photo My Photos Search Photos 
 Gear 
 Gear Reviews 
 Belay Devices Climbing Harnesses Climbing Helmets Rock Protection Big Wall Gear Bouldering Gear Snow and Ice Carabiners Rock Climbing Shoes Gear Slings and Runners View All Gear Categories 
 Best-in-Class Awards Search Gear Reviews Best Price Finder 
 Forum 
 Climber&apos;s Discussion Forum Recent Route Beta Postings Recent Trip Reports Recent Articles Recent Gear Reviews 
 
   
 Home &gt; Climber&apos;s Discussion Forum &gt;Topic Thursday, July 12, 2012 
 
 
Shawangunks - Cornerstone of Eastern Traditional Climbing
 
 Search Routes Bouldering Forum Gear Price Finder Gear Reviews Photos Articles Trip Reports Entire Site 
 Go 
 
 
 
 Climber&apos;s Forum Recent Route Beta Trip Reports Articles Gear Reviews 
 
 
 
Discussion Topic
 
 Return to Forum List 
 
 Post a Reply 
 

 Messages 1 - 459 of total 459 in this topic 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Original Post - Sep 23, 2007 - 01:40pm PT 
Long before I laid eyes on the place, Hugh Herr would fill many a lull in conversation with a grin and an enthusiastic &quot;Steve, you will love the Gunks!&quot; He was sooooo right. I love the Gunks!

So did the rather large (6&apos;4&quot;) Richard Muhe, once he tagged the jug on Foops. I believe he was one of Wolfgang Gullich&apos;s cohorts.
 
Bob D - Don&apos;t say I never did nuthin&apos; for ya! Harvey Arnold&apos;s excellent 1980 survey.
 

 

 

 

 

Gotta have a little Henry Barber, of course. FA of True Grip (5.10). I took a real hard look at this striking line and decided to get a better feel for the place first. Big roofs to finish!

 
 

 
 

 Gunkie 

 climber East Coast US 
 Sep 23, 2007 - 01:54pm PT 
I&apos;ve been in every spot except for the roof on Mohonk Lake. That&apos;s not saying I pulled the roof on Foops totally free. I just got to the jug after pulling on a sling :) 5.10 A0.

Thanks for posting that article. I think I still have that issue of Mountain. 
 

 
 

 Crimpergirl 

 Social climber St. Looney 
 Sep 23, 2007 - 02:00pm PT 
Super cool. I see my friend Laura Chaten (now Smith) in the article. Sweet! 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Sep 25, 2007 - 08:31am PT 
Also pictured (next to Bob) is David Rosenfeld, now an architect/builder here in Seattle. 
 

 
 

 The Schmutzvink 

 climber The WAY past 
 Sep 25, 2007 - 08:34am PT 
How &apos;bout that shot of Spider Dan Goodwin on Short Climb with the belayer sitting on the bench... 
 

 
 

 TradIsGood 

 Happy and Healthy climber the Gunks end of the country 
 Sep 25, 2007 - 08:42am PT 
$1.50 a day!

Annual $20! 
 

 
 

 klk 

 Trad climber cali 
 Sep 25, 2007 - 08:54am PT 
Not to mention the gratuitous snide comment about the use of chalk, presumably added by the editor, for the caption to the cover shot. Ah, for the days when folks thought the Gunks were insufficiently traditional . . . . 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Sep 25, 2007 - 09:06am PT 
klk- can&apos;t find the snide chalk comment for either cover shot. I think the man&apos;s reach is the &quot;unethical&quot; part of his Foops experience. 
 

 
 

 locker 

 Trad climber Joshua Tree Ca 
 Sep 25, 2007 - 09:30am PT 
I love and miss the Gunks...

Can&apos;t wait to get back that way again...

I have told many &quot;HARD CLIMBERS&quot; to head there and TEST their skills on the &quot;EASIER&quot; rated routes... LOL!!!...

and of course...

mentioned that they MIGHT want to take some TRICAMS along for the ride... 
 

 
 

 klk 

 Trad climber cali 
 Sep 25, 2007 - 09:33am PT 
steve-- i can&apos;t recall it precisely, but i believe the caption was, &quot;Unethical? Perhaps. Impressive? Certainly,&quot; or something similar. then something about whether or not it was difficult and how that depended on the &quot;body dates&quot; of the climber. mountain had been running an anti-chalk debate in those years so many of us read it as a comment on his dipping. i think having a chalk bag almost dead center on the cover was considered a bit of a provocation, at least in some british circles. 
 

 
 

 Tomcat 

 Trad climber Chatham N.H. 
 Sep 25, 2007 - 09:51am PT 
My first 5.9 was Never Never Land.Fresh on the heals of that we went to Mohonk and got on Ringwraith.Clueless about jamming I made it 2/3rd&apos;s or so to the worst of the butt crack and rattled in a nine hex,turned to talk to my belayer and gasp at the sight of the Mohonk Mountain House.Later sent the Ringwraith after servitude in NH.

A frigid day on Krapp&apos;s Last tape with Mel Hamel stands out....numb hands....EB&apos;s....Red Swami....all set !! 
 

 
 

 Ed Hartouni 

 Trad climber Livermore, CA 
 Sep 25, 2007 - 09:54am PT 
I love the &apos;Gunks, it is wonderful to go back and climb there whenever I get a chance... there are many changes but I think much is still a matter of personal choice. It is unfortunate in this time of impatience that climbers don&apos;t climb off the top and hike back to the Uberfall and solo down that bit of cliff above the spring&apos;s pipe. Then back out to collect the gear and get on another climb. Eating blueberries in the early summer.

Playing the game of accumulating pitch-points... add the rating of each of the pitches you did that day, 7 for a 5.7, 10 for a 5.10 (hey, no letter grades then), trying to get to 100. That was a &apos;Gunks game... and getting to 100 was an accomplishment, but not one compromised by rushing. 
 

 
 

 BadInfluence 

 Mountain climber Dak side 
 Sep 25, 2007 - 09:57am PT 
 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Sep 25, 2007 - 10:04am PT 
klk- the context is right but I have a feeling that Harvey simply watched Richard reach around the aerial moves and pulled out the gaff for the West German.

Jstan on Foops from Shawangunks Rock Climbs by Richard Dumais

 
 

 
 

 GOclimb 

 Trad climber Boston, MA 
 Sep 25, 2007 - 10:14am PT 
That first post contains the best photo of the Foops roof I&apos;ve ever seen. Thanks so much for that!

GO 
 

 
 

 TKingsbury 

 Trad climber MT 
 Sep 25, 2007 - 12:39pm PT 
Cool post.

I actually almost bought the #73 issue today...but I&apos;m broke. So at least I got to read the article.

Cheers


 
 

 
 

 ChoochCharlie 

 Trad climber South East PA 
 Sep 25, 2007 - 01:20pm PT 
Free Skytop ! 
 

 
 

 BadInfluence 

 Mountain climber Dak side 
 Sep 25, 2007 - 01:36pm PT 
did someone say Krapps Last Tape a Hot Henry route
 

being that i was busted up at skytop last weekend so yeah free skytop
 

 
 

 
 

 Chiloe 

 Trad climber Lee, NH 
 Sep 25, 2007 - 01:39pm PT 
I recall Henry once joking about Steve Wunsch, who had a boulder problem he called his &quot;Psycho simulator&quot; as training for the FFA of Psycho in Eldorado.

&quot;That&apos;s just crazy!&quot; Henry remarked, but then someone reminded him that Henry himself had a &quot;Foops Machine.&quot;

Any of you gunkies got a photo of that? 
 

 
 

 Curt 

 Boulder climber Gilbert, AZ 
 Sep 25, 2007 - 10:59pm PT 
I like how Richie is demonstrating the world&apos;s most difficult way to do the Gill variation to the Brat.

Curt
 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Sep 26, 2007 - 09:07am PT 
I wonder if Henry was trying to train for a free solo of Foops with his device? Getting up the thing wouldn&apos;t seem to have been a problem for a man of his abilities. Some pretty stiff routes have been done unroped at the Gunks including Kansas City and Supercrack! 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Sep 26, 2007 - 09:22am PT 
Steve...that&apos;s a really funny shot of me in that article. My time in the Gunks was a wonderful period in my life. Lot&apos;s of life long friends and great memories.

That picture of John Bragg (climber) with Russ Raffa (belayer) and Mark Robinson (onlooker) on top of Skytop is really what the Gunks are all about. I remember that day like yesterday...beautiful fall day, vibrant colors on the trees and rolling farm land to east and south.

Larry wrote: Any of you gunkies got a photo of that?

Larry...do you mean the Andrew boulder problem? I have it somewhere.

 


The Gunks...it&apos;s all about love.

 
Can&apos;t wait to get back...13 days and counting. 
 

 
 

 Chiloe 

 Trad climber Lee, NH 
 Sep 26, 2007 - 09:31am PT 
I meant a photo of Henry&apos;s Foops Machine. I&apos;ve heard of it a few times but don&apos;t know what it was. 
 

 
 

 klk 

 Trad climber cali 
 Sep 26, 2007 - 09:34am PT 
That&apos;s how I did the Gill variation to The Brat. It worked great-- a heel-toe to avoid all those greasy crimps. The only Gill problem I managed to do that day. 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Sep 27, 2007 - 07:59am PT 
That looks to be The Gunks Wedding. Is it? 
 

 
 

 Curt 

 Boulder climber Gilbert, AZ 
 Sep 27, 2007 - 09:54pm PT 
 &quot;...That&apos;s how I did the Gill variation to The Brat. It worked great-- a heel-toe to avoid all those greasy crimps. The only Gill problem I managed to do that day...&quot; 

Probably only because you couldn&apos;t find some way to press it out as a mantle...

Curt
 
 

 
 

 Delhi Dog 

 Trad climber Good Question... 
 Sep 27, 2007 - 10:12pm PT 
Steve thanks for posting, trip down memory lane for many of us seeing that cover and article!

Though the West is the Best ( slam me if you want but there you have it) there is so much of the East that remains special. From crisp fall days at the Gunks with colors radiating to the horizan to the whicked humdity that encourages the chalk to run in streams down the arms... its all good.

DD 
 

 
 

 phillip mike revis 

 climber snowbird, ut 
 Sep 27, 2007 - 10:24pm PT 
the gunks kick ass
MF is the best 5.9 in america
you get sh#t for even thinking about hangdoggin fall off or go home
today i soloed little face at sky top best 5.2+ ever tonite is the nite after the full moon maybe a pilgrim&apos;s progress is next i love the gunks
i have climbed all over the north america and i come back to the gunks every summer and nyc is so close
how could you not like it americas premier trad climbing area right next door to the most famous city on earth
if you haven&apos;t climbed there you are loosing money 
 

 
 

 yo 

 climber The Eye of the Snail 
 Sep 28, 2007 - 07:35am PT 
I&apos;m gonna need a little more background on the Gunks wedding please.

hahaha 
 

 
 

 Chiloe 

 Trad climber Lee, NH 
 Sep 28, 2007 - 07:50am PT 
The happy couple in that picture are Lynn Hill and Russ Raffa, who were married in the Gunks in 1989. Perhaps somebody who was there can tell more about the story? 
 

 
 

 klk 

 Trad climber cali 
 Sep 28, 2007 - 08:14am PT 
So Curt, where&apos;s The Egg pix?

I went to the Gunks on a summer weekend in the early 1980s and it was my first experience of what could only be called an urban climbing experience. I had never seen so many people packed into a climbing area. Gumbies anchored to trees on one side of the path, their ropes running across the road like slack lines to the leader&apos;s first piece, four feet off the ground, with the leader suspended helplessly twenty feet out on a 5.2. fixed in place by fear and rope drag as the rest of us casually walked over and under the belay rope; people fighting like junkyard dogs over the prime parking spaces or any space at all; huge swarms of outing groups huddled around their lost leader, trying to make sense out of the guidebook; teams of women climbers in flat-tops and dog collars; and the occasional wasp&apos;s nest to keep things fun. I was actually quite horrified. In retrospect, I appreciate the place a bit more, for the ability of the locals and the landowners to keep it open and usable under an incredible amount of pressure. Most of all, I&apos;d really like to go back on a cool off-day for miles of fun 5.2 + soloing.
 
 

 
 

 tinman 

 Trad climber 
 Sep 28, 2007 - 08:41am PT 
&quot;The happy couple in that picture are Lynn Hill and Russ Raffa, who were married in the Gunks in 1989. Perhaps somebody who was there can tell more about the story?&quot;

Didn&apos;t Bob D take this photo? He should be able to supply all the info necessary. 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Sep 28, 2007 - 09:21am PT 
I was a usher in the wedding. Nice wedding and great times.

The photo is from my camera and I set the lighting and angle. I think Russ Clune took the shot.

I am on the far right next to Jim McCarthy (preacher). With Mark Robinson and his wife and a guy who name slip from my mind.

I am going to the Gunks in a little more than a week for a reunion with a most of the folks (and more) in the photo.

As we all know Russ and Lynn parted ways and Russ is married to a wonderful lady (Holly) and has a 2-year boy.

I also have a photo of Russ Clune and Chris Bonnington who were out at the cliff the same day as the shoot.

Really looking forward to it.

 
 

 
 

 Curt 

 Boulder climber Gilbert, AZ 
 Sep 29, 2007 - 09:24am PT 
k.l.k. Egg pix for you...

 

...from 1981, I think.

Curt
 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Sep 29, 2007 - 09:30am PT 
Nice shorts Curt! 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Sep 29, 2007 - 12:19pm PT 
Most dramatic shot of a 5.2+ ever! Nice! Some more air for ya. From Richard DuMais&apos; exquisite Shawangunk Rock Climbing 1985. All of the photos from the initial posted article appear in color within!

 

Jimmy Surette on Swing Time.
 

 
Just wouldn&apos;t be a Gunks thread without my main man Fritz. Rock solid....
 
 

 
 

 TwistedCrank 

 climber Caution: Filling may be hot. 
 Sep 29, 2007 - 12:59pm PT 
Nice slippers, Fritz! 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Sep 29, 2007 - 02:02pm PT 
Original School, all the way! 
 

 
 

 tradcragrat 

 Trad climber 
 Sep 29, 2007 - 03:36pm PT 
Ha! the dangler used to be rated 5.8?! 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Sep 29, 2007 - 04:42pm PT 
Steve...that is Jeff Achey on Fat City and Bill Shanaman on Three Pines Direct. 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Sep 29, 2007 - 08:55pm PT 
The picture of Fritz is on Never-Never Land (5.10a). The crux is just above. Fritz was, I think, in his mid-seventies at the time, and was climbing in his K2 slippers, as you can see. The belayer up out of sight is me. I did not wear mountaineering boots.

Fritz was really something else. 
 

 
 

 healyje 

 Trad climber Portland, Oregon 
 Sep 30, 2007 - 01:47am PT 
What, no early Hardy Truesdale shots? Hmmm. Will have to dig around. 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Sep 30, 2007 - 10:46am PT 
This would be you on the sharp end then, Rich?

 

How about the personnel in this shot?

 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Sep 30, 2007 - 11:16am PT 
Steve Jones, Kevin Bein, John Bragg, Dave Rosenfeld with Bob Murray climbing out of picture. 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Sep 30, 2007 - 11:25am PT 
I have seen pictures of Bob Murray leading at the Gunks before he became a dedicated boulderer. How much roped climbing did you guys do with Bob? 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Sep 30, 2007 - 01:51pm PT 
 &quot;This would be you on the sharp end then, Rich? 

Yup. The piton hammer, knickers, and swami place it pre-seventies, probably late sixties. Looks like I&apos;m wearing Robbins shoes, which weren&apos;t that different from the mountaineering boots I just claimed to be avoiding.

Climbed a summer or two in the Bugaboos in Robbins Shoes. Smeared &apos;em in SnoSeal each the morning for the glacier.
 
 

 
 

 Tan Slacks 

 Social climber Joshua Tree 
 Sep 30, 2007 - 05:34pm PT 
Hey, I remember that place...

 
 

 
 

 BadInfluence 

 Mountain climber Dak side 
 Oct 1, 2007 - 07:48pm PT 
&quot;What, no early Hardie Truesdale shots?&quot;

Hardie does have a website. Amazing Photographer!

 http://www.hardietruesdale.com/ 

 
 

 
 

 TwistedCrank 

 climber Caution: Filling may be hot. 
 Oct 1, 2007 - 08:13pm PT 
Who here has done Directidelic Times? 
 

 
 

 Peter Haan 

 Trad climber San Francisco, CA 
 Oct 1, 2007 - 08:17pm PT 
What a wonderful lthread!!! 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Oct 1, 2007 - 08:23pm PT 
Hardie was one of first climbing partners in the Gunks...he also caught one of the longest falls I ever took in the Gunks...close to 50-60 feet off Birdie Party.


How and why I took the fall is another story.

He is a wonderful person and a great artist. 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Oct 1, 2007 - 10:57pm PT 
Somewhere I have a print of a photo Fritz took of Horseman
around the time of the Second War. I really do have to find it.
It is in one of my &quot;nostalgia drawers&quot;.

I understand we all are primarily interested in climbing, but
there is much interesting stuff going on.. Had he been less
focused on making sure the &quot;Shongums&quot; were protected
and yet remain available to benefit people, I suspect Dan
Smiley would have had the time, himself, to become an
excellent climber. I believe it was no accident he was so
interested inhaving Hans and Fritz climb in the area. Most of
us are mere shooting stars lasting but a moment compared
to Dan.

Early on in the period when I had begun to make a nuisance
of myself I got an invitation to visit LaVerne Thompson down
in NYC. She was most gracious but I thought it probable the
Smiley&apos;s had tasked her to find out if there was anything
there. There was not of course. But they chanced it anyway.

Just this evening I am back from Facelift 4 at which the
spokesperson for the National Park Service stated that the
Superintendent views Ken Yager as a &quot;resource&quot; critical to
the success of the Park and to the success of all the Park&apos;s
users. (Don&apos;t miss the fact Yosemite is arguably the lead
National Park in the US.) An opportunity for very big
advances for all the parks and for all users may now be
forming.

Think about it.


 
 

 
 

 BadInfluence 

 Mountain climber Dak side 
 Oct 2, 2007 - 04:56am PT 
Fat City Direct
 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Oct 2, 2007 - 07:40am PT 
John S...I think a number of climbing areas in the US have a huge impact (good) from climbers who volunteer their time and efforts.

Check out...

 http://www.slvguide.com/DelNorte/Penitente.htm 

and

 http://travel.howstuffworks.com/scenic-drive-in-colorado-gold-belt-tour-scenic-and-historic-byway-ga.htm 

Both these area that welcome climbers with open arms is from the effort of volunteers and their relationship with BLM. 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Oct 2, 2007 - 08:25am PT 
Welcome back from Ken&apos;s wonderful service gathering, Jstan. I hope that finding this thread was a pleasant surprise. Any tales from battling with this one?

 

 

Out of curiousity, what were some other contenders for the 5.11 title at the time or was Persistent a clear cut above the existing standards? 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Oct 2, 2007 - 11:03am PT 
Bob:
I am sorry if I implied other organizations have not been active. For that matter the Appies were an important organization in the Gunks beginning, I believe in the 50s but had seriously weakened by the sixties. About 1970 or so when the effort in the Gunks was beginning to gain momentum I was invited down to the mountains north of Atlanta to talk to the group forming what is called the Southeastern Climbers Coalition.

Organizations wax and wane but the modern ideas appear to involve inclusion independent of diversity of thought, creativity in regards to developing projects that immediately help the land and the land management, and getting people of all kinds working side by side in the field. I used trash collection back then and it works as well or better still today. It is so immediate.

Steve:
Oh, yes there were many facets to that one. It was my first attempt at a half-way decent first ascent. On my honeymoon in 1969 I had my new wife getting flipped around catching me on it. This may even have contributed to later unfortunate developments. I already knew pitons had to go but the peck crackers I put in the overhung rock kept sliding to the front and out. Feeling as I did, I was wrong to use pitons and leaving fixed pins in place did not right the wrong. What can I say? Once I knew pitons had to go, the fact others were using pins actively in no way excused me.

When a person has just started climbing they go at it in a particular frame of mind. Later, for one reason or another, that mindset changes. Having never really learned how to do cracks( the Gunks dont have very many) this climb took too long to figure out. I did not learn fast enough to suit me. I wanted to do roped climbing not roped bouldering. On the successful try when I got to the wide knee jam I stopped, knowing I had arrived at an end. I knew I was through and wanted to enjoy the moment of completion. It had been a fun four years. Lets face it. At 30 I was already no spring chicken.

When I got down I wondered, What now? I thought, Maybe I can do something helpful? I did climb afterward. But everything was done for a reason. Without doubt I had less talent for being helpful than I had for climbing. But I thought I might be able to make up for it by being persistent.

You will have to ask others about ratings. As long as a climb is fun and if to do it I have to be better this weekend than I was last weekend, I know everything I need to know.
 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Oct 2, 2007 - 03:54pm PT 
John wrote: Organizations wax and wane but the modern ideas appear to involve inclusion independent of diversity of thought, creativity in regards to developing projects that immediately help the land and the land management, and getting people of all kinds working side by side in the field. I used trash collection back then and it works as well or better still today. It is so immediate.

John...the problem with climbers is their lack of vision to keep area opens and access for all users. They are so splintered...they worry more about where a bolt is place while areas are getting shut down or have limited access.

All the work I done on trails and such at certain climbing areas...you rarely see an &quot;elite climber&quot; lending a hand. It&apos;s the middle range climbers who have no problem giving time and sweat.

 
 

 
 

 happiegrrrl 

 Trad climber New York, NY 
 Oct 2, 2007 - 05:18pm PT 
Dick Williams heads the trail crew at the Gunks and is there every Sunday; if there&apos;s volunteers, he&apos;s there.

He told me that back in the day, one day someone who was quite a known name - was it you, JStan? - started the trail work ethic at the Gunks by moving a big boulder to ease a trail, and then someone stopped to lend a hand,and then another did, and so on...

When we had a recent bouldering cleanup day, Joe Iurto(spelled wrong, I&apos;m sure), the editor for Urban climber magazine was there.

 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Oct 2, 2007 - 05:30pm PT 
happie...thanks for making my point.

I said rarely... 
 

 
 

 BadInfluence 

 Mountain climber Dak side 
 Oct 2, 2007 - 05:56pm PT 
I was told JStan had Saturday morning clean up crew.

Happie too bad the next day the trapps boulders were all chalked up 
 

 
 

 ghand 

 Sport climber Golden,Colorado 
 Oct 2, 2007 - 08:24pm PT 
Go get em jstan!
 
 

 
 

 &apos;Pass the Pitons&apos; Pete 

 Big Wall climber like Oakville, Ontario, Canada, eh? 
 Oct 2, 2007 - 09:52pm PT 
I remember that caption regarding the chalk bag on the front cover of Mountain - I think klk has it more or less correct.

Is that variation to Three Pines Modern Times? I remember doing that one, pretty rad indeed!

And there is only one &quot;n&quot; in the first part of &quot;Bonington&quot;! Sheesh. 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Oct 3, 2007 - 03:05pm PT 
So much to which to respond I dont know where to start:

TRAILS:
When I unilaterally put the ribbons up to see where trails might possibly go and which Richie P. quite rightly took down immediately, I learned no individual should attempt to change in any way the lands we share. All trail work in which I was involved was done under the supervision of Thom Scheuer and a couple of his people. There were a number of very important salutary effects.

First, the work was done with the Preserves knowledge and direction. I am confident Dick has this all prearranged in his work.

Second, we wanted trails that would not unnecessarily impact the area visually. There is a natural tendency for a person to build a visible trail so people can appreciate what they have done. We wanted trails that work as trails but leave you feeling you were the one who decided where to step. Thom and the rangers had much better knowledge of such things than did we. Better than did I at least.

Third, it got climbers digging and moving rock side by side with Preserve people. Cooperative physical work is the surest and best way to strengthen the relationship between people. It is quite simply invaluable.
As an aside, we saw something like this working at Facelift4 for building relationships. Ken had provided for liquid refreshments at the final party but he was worried that people would have trouble getting back to their campsites. Now listen up to what the terribly bureaucratic and horrible National Park Service suggested. They suggested their park rangers use the paddy wagon to take people wherever they needed to go. I heard that some of the climbers also wanted hand cuffs used but I dont know what all came out of that. Pretty funny.

Another thread is currently and unproductively (I think) addressing the issue of relationships of this sort. Once relationships have been established people on both sides can come down off their reactive pedestals and become real people. Ken and Jesse have done wonderfully creative work on this critical area.

THE ROCK
Ah yes, there is a story with regard to the rock near Handy Andy.

We needed to move this big flat boulder up the slope so that people belaying would have a place other than beaten down dirt on which to stand. Something natural. Mind you, I had been working really hard on this for several years; I was wearing down, and may have even discovered that I was pregnant. In any event I was coming, once more to an end. I had to know whether we had managed to help people or whether we had just caused problems. You can never tell this by the way. The moment to find out came. I got down with my face and shoulder into the rock and said to my friend who had spent many Sundays picking up trash with me, &quot;Lets see if we can move this.&quot; He gave me an incredulous look but got down beside me anyway. The boulder, weighing a ton or more, was still half buried and I knew we had no chance of moving it. I could see nothing from my position but I immediately heard racks hitting the ground all up and down the carriage road. Soon there was not room left for even one more finger under that rock. The rock rose up as if by magic and was settled into the hole prepared for it.

By this we learned all of the work by so many people had created something that would live on after we were gone. The people had come together. For me that moment when the rock rose up was like no other. It is with me even today.

LEADERSHIP
I will admit I originally thought the fact a number of people thought well of me, for some unknown reason, might help me in my effort. But I dont think so now. It was just my ego talking. You dont have to be a leading climber at all to make a contribution. It can even be a hindrance because people will then imagine reasons to explain what you are doing.

You really need only three things.
You need always to be willing to give of yourself.
You need always to be willing to listen to people.
You need always to be willing to include people who do not agree with you.
Most critically, you can never have a moment when you are unwilling.
NEVER.

The goal is to engage people and to include them. So projects have to be created, supported, and publicized. Getting a thing done is not the goal. Getting people involved in doing the thing is the goal.

When you succeed, you will receive a moment like no other, and you will hold it close the rest of your life.
 
 

 
 

 TradIsGood 

 Half fast climber the Gunks end of the country 
 Oct 3, 2007 - 03:20pm PT 
Nice, JStan. Excellent points.

Now are you really sure there aren&apos;t that many cracks to climb at the Gunks.

I said that once here, and Aya K disagreed. LOL. 
 

 
 

 bvb 

 Social climber flagstaff arizona 
 Oct 3, 2007 - 04:47pm PT 
DAMMIT!!!

don&apos;t.

make.

me.

warm.

up.

my.

SCANNER!!!! 
 

 
 

 happiegrrrl 

 Trad climber New York, NY 
 Oct 3, 2007 - 05:34pm PT 
Thanks JStan. Pretty cool story about the rock. You are right that the projects Dick works on are with the Preserve knowledge and no doubt there&apos;s more that goes on behind the scenes than one realizes. There are some things only the rangers are allowed to do, like cut down dead trees with the chainsaw.

You might not have heard, and BVB - maybe this will get you out back to the Gunks.... But there is, in the works, the acquisition for a parcel of land(Rosendale Water Works) which will become a part of the Preserve. It is purported to have world class bouldering, and if all goes well, should be opened sometime in 2008. The Open Space Institute is to buy the land, and then give it to MP.

I don&apos;t know anything at all about the land, but am assuming that there will be big amounts of volunteerism needed to develop trails fairly quickly(in order to preserve ground plants and lessen impact of foot traffic).
 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Oct 4, 2007 - 08:17am PT 
Jstan- Thanks for the recollections of Persistence and your well considered perspective on group activism and land use issues. I couldn&apos;t agree more strongly that we are entering an exciting and potentially very productive period as a user group. Ken&apos;s inclusive approach in Yosemite is a great indication of what may be possible on a much broader scale once the adversarial nature of past interaction is let go. Too much anarchistic self image can be a difficult habit to break but we all need to question the character of the actual freedom that ultimately results from habitually throwing off or avoiding cooperation or external constraints. Attitude in isolation will not open a closed crag or further our collective position. Thanks again for sharing your mind and process. You do a lot of good with your contributions to the ST and I always enjoy your thoughts and reflections.

And now a little more eyecandy.....from DuMais.
 
 
Wish I was turning a roof right now! 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Oct 4, 2007 - 08:31am PT 
I always thought the freeing of Coexistence never caused the stir it merited. After getting over the supposed crux you still had only those little damn things with which to work. And knowing Richard as I do, I would bet money he was merrily humming the whole time. 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Oct 4, 2007 - 10:30am PT 
The humming you heard was my clothes flapping in the breeze caused by falling. I fell off two or three times (which seemed really radical in 1967, at least to me) before making it. I also contrived to miss the best hold, just for added adventure. Wow, that was forty years ago, pretty much to the day.

By the way, the posted picture of Coex is of Barbara Devine, our beloved Kevin Bein&apos;s wife. She was one of the first women in the country to lead 5.11. (She&apos;s still around in the Hudson Valley area...not climbing as far as I know.)

The climber on Retribution is Joe Bridges.

Retribution was my first 5.10. I climbed it around 1964, give or take a year or two, seconded by none other than Yvon Chouinard, who was East for a visit.

 
 

 
 

 Harv 

 Trad climber Nederland, CO 
 Oct 4, 2007 - 11:45am PT 
Hi fellow Gunkies; Laura (Chaiten) Smith turned me onto this site and the display of some of my photos and story. First Richard was not a friend (maybe he was but they came to the Gunks at different timres) of Wolfgang. Richard came with the Editor of Alpinismus Magazine out of Austria and I was taking photos for his article on the Gunks. Second, that was Hardie Truesdale belaying off the bench at the Mohonk lake. And lastly, if any of you are coming out to the Boulder area that I knew back in the 70s in the Gunks, be sure to look me up. I now live in Nederland after 20 some odd years in Boulder.
Harv Arnold 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Oct 4, 2007 - 01:23pm PT 
Welcome Harvey,
I hope that you enjoy revisiting past work as much as the rest of us! Lots of tales and images from direct participants make the ST a living history treasure. Perhaps you can quell the dispute over the meaning of &quot;unethical&quot; in the Foops cover caption. Some say chalk, but I think reach was clearly at the heart of the humor.

&quot;Unethical? Maybe. Impressive? Certainly. Richard Muhe (West German) who is 6ft4ins high and weighs 180lbs, prepares to finish Foops (5.11). Shawangunks. Muhe says,&quot;the climb is 5.11 if not harder; that depends very strongly on the individual &apos;body dates&apos; of the climber.&quot; 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Oct 4, 2007 - 07:24pm PT 
More classic shots from Richard DuMais&apos; Shawangunk Rock Climbing, 1985.

 

 

 

Any stories about climbing with Fritz, Harvey? Great shot of him up there with a chest harness, same as when I had a chance to get out with him and John Rupley in Tucson in the early seventies. He is the only one I ever saw in one of those items. 
 

 
 

 Crimpergirl 

 Social climber St. Looney 
 Oct 4, 2007 - 07:28pm PT 
Welcome Harv. I think you are going to like it here. 
 

 
 

 redpt 

 Trad climber nj 
 Oct 5, 2007 - 09:31am PT 

Can some of the locals from the era comment on the accuracy of the following, this description was given to me by a local Gunks climber. Disclaimer: I don&apos;t know what period in Gunks development (my guess is somewhere 70&apos;s-80&apos;s) he was talking about exactly AND it&apos;s also possible that I misunderstood his description - it is a bit hard to believe.
I&apos;m not trying to start any dispute here, just get things clarified.


Supposedly the &quot;tactic&quot; for getting the FA of a route was that the first member of the team started up the route, on lead, placing whatever pro they could, if they fell/hung they were lowered and the next person got their chance - but the gear and rope were left up so they were TR&apos;ing some of it, this &quot;process&quot; would continue in rotation and the person to reach the top (and I suppose they could decide where that is on an FA) without a fall, who may have only lead/placed pro on a small section of the route would be named as having the FA.

Thanks



 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Oct 5, 2007 - 09:59am PT 
I cant speak with regards to any climb other than those I was a party to. Some of this will be background to better define the answer.

Any FA I was on caused me to write a name in my guide. But no one ever looked at my guide. I have no idea how the name going into the next guide was selected. On Fat City I put Gary Brown as first because putting the pin in was harder than doing the move. He did a superb job. I dont know how it is listed in the guides. I have not looked at any of them. The truth is none of us were hung up on FA credits. The fun lay in figuring out the problems.

First and foremost we need to understand that most Gunks climbs involve a short section substantially harder than the rest. That illuminates several aspects of your question.

Typically the first person would go up until encountering difficulty. If there was a fall we got back on the rock at the earliest opportunity no matter how tired we were. No resting on the rope or on any protection. Part of the fun was learning how to rest on the rock enough to make the next try. We did not pull the rope down and start over. In the context of the Gunks I thought that was kind of synthetic. Other places it may be needed to produce whatever satisfaction one is seeking.

When the leader got tired they were lowered off or down climbed and the second would have a go. I usually noted the name of the person who first surmounted the main problem. But as I said, no one ever looked at my guide.

Bottom line? We really didnt care who got any credits. They have nothing to do with climbing.
 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Oct 5, 2007 - 11:43am PT 
 &quot;Supposedly the &quot;tactic&quot; for getting the FA of a route was that the first member of the team started up the route, on lead, placing whatever pro they could, if they fell/hung they were lowered and the next person got their chance - but the gear and rope were left up so they were TR&apos;ing some of it, this &quot;process&quot; would continue in rotation and the person to reach the top (and I suppose they could decide where that is on an FA) without a fall, who may have only lead/placed pro on a small section of the route would be named as having the FA.&quot; 

This practice certainly occurred in the era following the tremendous achievements of Barber, Bragg, Stannard, and Wunsch, none of whom used this tactic. In fact, there was a time when Henry used to pull his rope and all but the top piece if he fell, so that the next attempt required not only reclimbing the moves up to the high point but also replacing all the gear. This never caught on. 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Oct 23, 2007 - 09:43am PT 
I am a little surprised that Henry didn&apos;t make it to the Gunks reunion to join the other luminaries. Great to see a picture of John Reppy, who did. 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Oct 27, 2007 - 11:55pm PT 
Speaking of Rich Romano in his prime... The first issue of N A Climber circa 1975 showing Rich on the left and Spaff Ackerly on the right on Persistent, rated 5.10+ at the time.

 
 

 
 

 TwistedCrank 

 climber Caution: Filling may be hot. 
 Oct 28, 2007 - 08:20am PT 
Spaff Ackerly - there&apos;s a name I haven&apos;t heard in a while. Last I heard he was teaching at an outdoor prep school in Carbondale after he finished a paleontoloty PhD. 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Feb 6, 2008 - 09:11pm PT 
Old Gunks bump for Roy K! 
 

 
 

 SteveW 

 Trad climber Denver, CO 
 Feb 7, 2008 - 08:16am PT 
Mr. Grossman
You&apos;ve just got to stop these historical links. . .
my work is suffering whilst I&apos;m browsing and dreaming. . .
But thanks anyway! 
 

 
 

 Chiloe 

 Trad climber Lee, NH 
 Feb 7, 2008 - 08:37am PT 
Any week now, the weather window could open just enough for a Gunks trip. Not today, crampons advisable on our driveway. 
 

 
 

 AbeFrohman 

 Trad climber new york, NY 
 Feb 7, 2008 - 08:50am PT 
Yay Gunks.
YAY!

yes parking can be an issue.
yes, the first 1/4 mile of 1 of the 4 (trapps, near trapps, millbrook, and peters kill) cliffs gets a bit crowded with gumbies.
but beyond that 1/4 mile there is PLENTY of good climbing.
just walk.
you can handle an &quot;approach&quot;, can&apos;t you?

 
 

 
 

 TradIsGood 

 Chalkless climber the Gunks end of the country 
 Feb 7, 2008 - 08:55am PT 
A buddy was up there last week.

He said that not only was there no waterfall at Ken&apos;s Crack, but that the crack was dry!

 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Feb 7, 2008 - 10:26am PT 
Me on Kama Sutra...some upstart named Scott Franklin belaying back in 1982.

 
 

 
 

 SteveW 

 Trad climber Denver, CO 
 Feb 7, 2008 - 10:31am PT 
Lookit that head of hair. Boy, those were the good ole
days! :-)
(Bob, I&apos;m hair challenged, just like you, pun intended).
 
 

 
 

 Wormly81 

 Trad climber 
 Mar 25, 2008 - 09:22am PT 
Bump to celebrate March at the Gunks....

The forecast is for a high of 45 degrees, partly cloudy, and a significant wind. Your in the car early.

As you wander down the carraige road the cliffs major features take on whole new perspectives as your view is unencumbered by leaves. At the first belay you throw your feet over the ledge and relax. The sky is perfect blue and the sun feels close; like it has detoured closer to New Paltz just to make your day. If you were to drop a feather, it would flutter straight down as there isnt a breeze to speak of. The long winter of water ice climbing has made you strong and you are flooded with the unbridled optimism that starts another rock season in one of the most sacred of places this world has to offer.

 
 

 
 

 Harv 

 Trad climber Nederland, CO 
 Apr 26, 2008 - 02:32pm PT 
I will be returning to the Gunks in September of 2008 for a long awaited visit (27 years). As to unethical, I don&apos;t recall what that refered to as chalk was in everyone&apos;s bag (and some had the chalk mouse that John Stannard had suggested - chalk in an old sock tip that was tied into a ball). But hight had a definte effect on how one could get out to the bucket on Foops. Richard could do one movw under the roof and it was in his reach, but Kevin and Barbara would have to do a dance including a layback on the back of their thumbs to finally get within reach. 
 

 
 

 LittlePinkTricam 

 Trad climber Providence, RI 
 Apr 26, 2008 - 02:59pm PT 
Despite living in NJ/RI, I&apos;ve tried very hard to make the Gunks my local crag because, as a young climber, I&apos;m in desperate need of a place with strong ethics and a deep history. As one of my many attempts to get closer to the roots of climbing, I did a recent all-nude ascent of Shockley&apos;s Ceiling (the first time I&apos;d done the route). You have to love a location with a history like that... 
 

 
 

 TradIsGood 

 Chalkless climber the Gunks end of the country 
 Apr 26, 2008 - 05:11pm PT 
LPT - Was that a daylight ascent? 
 

 
 

 LittlePinkTricam 

 Trad climber Providence, RI 
 Apr 26, 2008 - 09:32pm PT 
TradIsGood-
It was indeed, on a weekday when very few people were around. I think we only ran into two parties--one before we got off the ground, and one we shared a rap station with at the top. 
 

 
 

 TradIsGood 

 Chalkless climber the Gunks end of the country 
 Apr 27, 2008 - 04:57am PT 
Ah, in the style of the FNA! Excellent. TR worthy.

I saw a TR once of a headlamp ascent of Shockley&apos;s. That seemed a little weak - the whole point being that Shockley&apos;s is above the hairpin turn where all the cars have to slow down. Hardly matters which climb if it is done covertly.

 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Apr 27, 2008 - 10:24am PT 
There is a great shot of Mr Shockley at his shockleyest in Climbing in North America. My copy is at large. A couple of size sensitive shots of Foops from States of the Art.

 

 
 

 
 

 TrundleBum 

 Trad climber Las Vegas 
 Apr 27, 2008 - 10:46am PT 
Not the Gunks so maybe OT but...
I always loved that image of Bard on Slipstream.
A big dude playing Baryshnikov. The left foot back step and could he put his right foot any higher please ? 
 

 
 

 the idle rich 

 climber Estes Park, CO 
 Apr 28, 2008 - 02:57pm PT 
rgold

I really hate to correct my elders, but there are fewer and fewer of them left so I can&apos;t pass up the opportunity. The photo of Coexistence isn&apos;t of Barb Devine...it&apos;s Spaff Ackerly. (I took the pic from the crux of Star Action) If you&apos;re in need of stronger eyeglasses, I think I have an old set that you&apos;re welcome to have. Just have to sign the obligatory liability waiver. Better men than you have lost their eyesight looking through these things.

rich 
 

 
 

 Tarbuster 

 climber right here, right now 
 Apr 29, 2008 - 06:43am PT 
Ditto on that photo of Bard.
One of the better sequence of photos from that time. 
 

 
 

 Harv 

 Trad climber Nederland, CO 
 Jul 13, 2008 - 10:29pm PT 
Ah, climbing with Fritz. Only once. I was with a new girl friend and we ran into Fritz on the carriage road and he (always having an eye for the girls) suggested we partner up for a climb. He suggested he lead so I gave him my rack which he hardly used. He would use the trees sticking out of the cliff as his saftey points and made every pitch very short so he could look down at the girl between us.
Once, where there was a sharp left traverse in the climb after a straight up section, he tried to place a nut with a long sling to cut down on the rope drag. When I got up to it, the nut almost fell out into my hand. Bottom line, I got to climb with the original discoverer of climbing in the Gunks and still got to retain my girlfriend no matter how much he flirted. LOL 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Jul 13, 2008 - 10:51pm PT 
A point possibly of interest. I still have the original chalk sock. This shows a single pair of worn out socks can give between 100 and 150 years of service inside a chalk bag. It was not knotted however. I used a wire tie from a loaf of Wonder Bread. The tie is also the original.

The day I thought that up was probably one of my better moments. 
 

 
 

 horst 

 Trad climber Lancaster, PA 
 Jul 14, 2008 - 05:38am PT 
I learned to lead climb at the Gunks in the late 70s...modeling after my heroes of that era...Goldstone, Bragg, D&apos;Antonio, et al...the classic outfit of white painter pants and red swami belt. Here&apos;s a pic of me (back then, I was the scrawny teenager with a big fro moving hyperactively from one climb to the next) leading Foops in 1981.

 

Here&apos;s to all my Gunks heroes of the 1970s! 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 16, 2008 - 01:00pm PT 
Thanks Eric...Quite the group you put me in with. Hope all is well.

Kevin Bein...Skytop...

 

The Throne

 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Jul 16, 2008 - 06:48pm PT 
After a good bicycle ride and some wine I see a photo of Kevin. There is no alternative but to think.

I have never met a person who lived so completely in each moment as did Kevin. 
 

 
 

 Jeremy Handren 

 climber NV 
 Jul 16, 2008 - 06:52pm PT 
Or more accurately...
&quot;The Gunks - Cornerstone of Eastern Traditional Frigging&quot;

 
 

 
 

 Griff 

 Social climber Felton, PA 
 Jul 16, 2008 - 08:45pm PT 
The number of horizontal cracks makes placing pro an added mental challenge for the leader new to the area.

They do some different stuff there.

It&apos;s a beautiful place to climb. 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 16, 2008 - 09:49pm PT 
Jstan...here is another one for you.

Kevin on Open Cockpit...1977

 


Jstan wrote: I have never met a person who lived so completely in each moment as did Kevin.

To this day and over 30 years later I can honestly say that some of my best days ever climbing were spend with Kevin and Barbara in the Gunks and SD.

I miss him dearly. 
 

 
 

 Curt 

 Boulder climber Gilbert, AZ 
 Jul 16, 2008 - 10:19pm PT 
Best thread here, for sure.

Curt

 
 

 
 

 Rokrover 

 Trad climber SB, CA 
 Jul 17, 2008 - 08:43am PT 
Heres Ivan Rezucha airing his pits on Matinee back in 1975. This was my first year at the Gunks after specializing in crack climbing at Frog Buttress in Queensland, Australia. I had to relearn face climbing quickly and leading this traverse onsight in clunky stiff Chouinard boots was quite stimulating. Ivan was quite active at the Gunks over the ensuing years - I wonder where he is now?
 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 17, 2008 - 08:58am PT 
Ivan lives in Boulder and still climbing a lot.

Here is another shot of Kevin...

 
 

 
 

 bvb 

 Social climber flagstaff arizona 
 Jul 17, 2008 - 10:28am PT 
that pic of skytop in full color way, way upthread. brings back so many bittersweet memories. there is something so tangible across the decades, the gunks in the fall, memories you can practically reach out and touch. the smell of autumn and the cool crisp sunlight. so much sweet melancholy. more than the climbing, i remember the people, so many years ago. 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Jul 19, 2008 - 02:02pm PT 
Great stuff guys!

Wasn&apos;t Kevin known as the Mayor of the Gunks? 
 

 
 

 hobo_dan 

 Social climber Minnesota 
 Jul 19, 2008 - 06:10pm PT 
Thanks everyone for the great stories and photos. This really captures the spirit of how it felt back in the day- I never went East but I can recall many of these photos from Mountain and Climbing. I can smeel the lichen and the rock when I read the story.
I used to to sign summit registers with the joke that I thought the route was easier than Open Cockpit- this came from a humorous article on one upmanship- I forget the title
Really really great
murf 
 

 
 

 N0_ONE 

 Social climber Utah 
 Jul 19, 2008 - 07:16pm PT 
Good Stuff!!!

Thanks for the pics and stories. 
 

 
 

 Ed Hartouni 

 Trad climber Livermore, CA 
 Jul 19, 2008 - 07:55pm PT 
I&apos;m trying to figure out how to get back there this fall... I miss climbing there, it&apos;s been too long 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Jul 19, 2008 - 08:50pm PT 
Miscellaneous Gunks pictures, some old, some new...

Todd Mummert on Beatle Brow Bulge

 

Bragg on Coex

 

Feast of Fools

 

Alphonse

 

Oblique Twique

 

Sound and Fury

 

Arrow

 

Tim Keenan on Trapped Like a Rat

 

Joe Bridges on Westward Ha!

 

Laura Kosbar on Groovy

 

Myriam Bouchard on CCK

 

...and on Hans&apos; Puss

 

Kevin Bein on Matinee

 

Yellow Wall

 

Bragg on link-up to Yellow Ridge

 

Todd Mummert on Cruise Contol

 

Top of Annie O

 

Mellow Yellow

 

Added in edit: High Exposure

 



 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 19, 2008 - 09:10pm PT 
Wonderful shots Rich..looking forward to seeing everyone again in the fall.

PS...what are you doing hanging out with Romano woman??? :)

Mark Robinson on some roof.

 

Rich G on PR
 

Bob D on Land of Milk and Honey 

That Romano Guy 

Bob D on the Throne 

John M on Fissure Ramins
 

Gary Garrit bouldering 
 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Jul 19, 2008 - 09:22pm PT 
Thanks Bob.

Romano woman sometimes is climb with beta males. 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 19, 2008 - 09:44pm PT 
Perch...is that you lurking out there??

RGold...what happened to Bragg&apos;s blonde hair?? 
 

 
 

 the idle rich 

 climber Estes Park, CO 
 Jul 19, 2008 - 10:16pm PT 
Bob...Just trying to figure out how to post photos, but with limited success. Here goes another attempt. Here&apos;s Henry&apos;s answer to climbing Matinee in the clunky green Shoenards. He was just back from his trip to Dresden.
Rich

 

 

That pic of Land of Milk and Honey looks suspiciously like Frustration Syndrome? 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Jul 20, 2008 - 02:41am PT 
Fellahs,

Those are some great, great pics. Laura and I just got a decent scanner so we are going to post some new old stuff soon. Out of a box of 3000, I don&apos;t think we have any photos of the quality that TIR, Rgold and BobbyD just submitted though.

RichP those pics of Barber are incredible.
Rgold:
-classic photo of you on Yellow Wall!
-we love that shot of you climbing with with the lightning bolt head scarf.
Bob D-thanks for kick starting this. So what year was that shot of you on the Throne? That&apos;s a tough one for sure. Great photos Bob. I don&apos;t know how you caught Romano relaxing.

RichP your screen name is hilarious. It fits too.

Look forward to October. 
 

 
 

 Chiloe 

 Trad climber Lee, NH 
 Jul 20, 2008 - 06:31am PT 
These photos convey how dynamic and character-ful the climbs are, across all the grades.
They especially make me want to come back in the fall. 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 20, 2008 - 07:13am PT 
Oakie...you are right...I was on my second vodka lemonade by that time.
Perch...cool shots of Henry.
Geno..funny about Richie...all the years I have know him he seems like he is always in motion.

How is Laura??

Russ Raffa on Scary Area 

Bob Jahn on Wishbone Overhang 1977 

One of the 20 people sieging the route that day..No Comment 

Nick Morrel on Resistance
 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 20, 2008 - 08:24am PT 
A really handsome fella on &quot;The Fall&quot;.

 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Jul 20, 2008 - 08:26am PT 
 RGold...what happened to Bragg&apos;s blonde hair?? 

Uh, Bob, if we&apos;re gonna start down the &quot;what happened to&quot; road, we&apos;re gonna need a whole new thread...


Meanwhile, this just in (from 7/19/08)

Recently septegeneric Dick Williams leading one of his many new routes in the Near Trapps (protection so far consists of a micronut in a vertical seam and a pair of Ballnuts in a horizontal fracture).

 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 20, 2008 - 01:11pm PT 
Howie Doyle...one of us (Gunkie) and always will be.

In the Black Canyon just before heading down to do the Scenic Cruise.

 
 

 
 

 the idle rich 

 climber Estes Park, CO 
 Jul 20, 2008 - 02:48pm PT 
Everything I knew about rangering, I learned from this man...a very scary thought! Thom Scheuer was a friend to many, many climbers in the east and was as much a part of the Gunks as the rocks and lichen.

 

And who could forget the bus that tried to shortcut the switchback at the hairpin turn. The caption in the local paper was titled, &quot;The Precarious Perch&quot;.

 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 20, 2008 - 02:53pm PT 
Rich P ...nice shot of Tom...Kevin was the first person I met in the Gunks and believe Tom was the second. Sunday morning at the Uberfall is not the same without Tom, his NY times and doughnuts. 
 

 
 

 the idle rich 

 climber Estes Park, CO 
 Jul 20, 2008 - 03:01pm PT 
Yeah Bob...I don&apos;t think a day goes by that I don&apos;t think about Thom and Kevin. Hope to see you this fall in the Gunks. 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Jul 22, 2008 - 02:52am PT 
Shots of the Trapps from Eagle Cliff. Some from the early 1970s. Some recent. All taken by Laura Chaiten Smith.

 

 

 

 

 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Jul 22, 2008 - 03:04am PT 
Skytop from Lenape lane.

 

 

 

 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Jul 22, 2008 - 03:06am PT 
Another picture of Tom for everyone.

 
 

 
 

 horst 

 Trad climber Lancaster, PA 
 Jul 22, 2008 - 06:19am PT 
Jim Ewing on Ridiculissima...

 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 22, 2008 - 06:57am PT 
Geno and laura...nice shots.

Good shot Eric...almost looks like he is ropeless. 
 

 
 

 Crimpergirl 

 Social climber Boulder, Colorado! 
 Jul 22, 2008 - 08:51am PT 
I&apos;m glad this thread is still thriving. Can&apos;t wait to see the next photos! 
 

 
 

 the idle rich 

 climber Estes Park, CO 
 Jul 22, 2008 - 11:06am PT 
This isn&apos;t nearly as cool a shot of Ridiculissima as Eric&apos;s but it is more historic. Kevin Bein and Vern Clevinger on the first ascent in 1977?

 

Dana Bartlett and Bill Ravitch on Jack Sh#t,

 

and Open Cockpit

 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Jul 22, 2008 - 04:46pm PT 
Superb and inspiring photos! Go Dick Williams!
Who was called the &quot;mayor of the Gunks?&quot; 
 

 
 

 scuffy b 

 climber Sartre&apos;s No Exit 1/32 mile 
 Jul 22, 2008 - 05:09pm PT 
Kevin 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Jul 22, 2008 - 05:36pm PT 
Bobby, I loved that shot of you on the Fall. What&apos;s it like at that point?

Here is a scan of Kevin on the cover of CLIMBING.
 

BobbyD, Kevin and Elrod at the Uberfall.
 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Jul 22, 2008 - 05:41pm PT 
Maury pouring for one and all.
 

A young Clune. The Idle Rich.

 

Jeff Gruenberg and me.

 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Jul 22, 2008 - 05:44pm PT 
Rich thanks for mentioning Dana Bartlett. I forgot his last name until you did. Here are a couple shots from Summer of 81.

 

 
 

 
 

 Double D 

 climber 
 Jul 22, 2008 - 05:47pm PT 
The East Coast...Climbing??? Dude, isn&apos;t that like past the 395 or something? 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Jul 22, 2008 - 05:50pm PT 
Retribution in Summer of 80.
 
 
 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 22, 2008 - 09:16pm PT 
Geno...it get easier as you go higher...I think you get in a good 4 RP...fecking Gunks...what a place.

The cover photo of kevin looks just like the one I took...I think the whole crew was out there that day.

 

Bob Jahn (he freed Doug&apos;s Roof) on Comedy in Three Acts.

 

Mike Freeman on the Sting.

 

Three months and counting...Eric H...you coming to the reunion?? 
 

 
 

 Curt 

 Boulder climber Gilbert, AZ 
 Jul 22, 2008 - 10:27pm PT 
That&apos;s how I remember Open Cockpit, Bob--lots of good face holds off to the right side of the crack. I think I first did it with Mike Freeman in &apos;82 or &apos;83. Great pic.

Curt

 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Jul 23, 2008 - 03:59am PT 
Bob, Nice shots from your archives. Great to see them. It&apos;s amazing the memories old pictures invoke.

Here are a couple of Dan McMillan. We climbed Crack&apos;n Up that day. Dan fought hard and did it. I can&apos;t remember where we are in these pics. I think we are nearby on another climb.

 

 

 
 

 
 

 veryveryoldman 

 Social climber The Bronx 
 Jul 23, 2008 - 12:02pm PT 
Geno-

I think you were on Exit Stage Left in those pics, a 5.9 next to Modern Times.

Jstan-

Do you have any recollections you would share about Stannard&apos;s Roof? It&apos;s one of my favorites, although I find it intimidating and difficult.

When did you first climb it? Who were you with? What did you use to protect it?

Here are two shots of it:

 
 

-Denis 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Jul 23, 2008 - 06:42pm PT 
Denis, Roger. You are right. Gene 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Jul 23, 2008 - 07:05pm PT 
Roof:
Must have been early 70&apos;s or there abouts. I remember getting a good
nut well out there, most probably a large stopper. No risk of cratering
against the wall. Absolutely best part came when I got to the lip. Reached
up for the its-over-hold and grabbed onto a 150# loose block. Could not
use it so you had to find an alternative. I was told someone trundled it.
So it&apos;s not the climb it was originally. Didn&apos;t give it a name. Since no
marks were left on it, it was there undamaged ready to be discovered again.

Best laid plans gang aft aglae.

Edit
The nut was in that good place. The reach to the block was blind so it
must have been sitting in what you see as a V at the skyline. The roof
used to be a bit longer. Must be an awful route to follow. Fall off and
you finish up in the trees. 
 

 
 

 veryveryoldman 

 Social climber The Bronx 
 Jul 24, 2008 - 07:23am PT 
Thanks, John. That&apos;s interesting. I can&apos;t imagine where that block was resting--but I&apos;m sort of happy I don&apos;t have to deal with it.

One day I&apos;ll try doing it with only stoppers for the full experience, but it&apos;ll be tough forgoing that perfect #2 camalot in the rail before the lip. That placement always fills me with a sense of joy and contentment.

Here&apos;s the roof as it looks before you get horizontal, and a view of Clove Valley from the top of the route in late October:
 
 
 

 
 

 steveA 

 Trad climber bedford,massachusetts 
 Jul 24, 2008 - 07:39am PT 
First time posting on Supertopo. I sprained my ankle a few days, ago (bouldering), and am killing time on the Web. I am enjoying this thread. Kevin Bein was a good friend of mine-brings back fond memories. Looking forward to the Oct. reunion, (HenryB invited me). JohnS-nice to see you here. It will be fun seeing many old faces.
Cheers Steve Arsenault 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Jul 24, 2008 - 07:55am PT 
Steve:
I am still using that same junk sling. Shall I bring it or mail it?

John

I&apos;m kidding. I&apos;m kidding.
No. As a matter of fact I do still have it. 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 24, 2008 - 08:33am PT 
Barbara Devine on Open Cockpit...1977

 

Hardie Truedale on On Any Monday...I think.

 

Mike Freeman on Wasp Stop.

 

Bob D on Climb and Punishment.

 

I hope I not boring you guys with these photos? 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Jul 24, 2008 - 08:40am PT 
Welcome Steve Arsenault!

 
Then and now on the VMC Direct. From Mark Kroese Fifty Favorite Climbs 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 24, 2008 - 08:42am PT 
Lynn on Iron Curtain...Skytop

 

She lead it... wasn&apos;t pumped enough so she did another run. 
 

 
 

 veryveryoldman 

 Social climber The Bronx 
 Jul 24, 2008 - 08:44am PT 
You&apos;re certainly not boring me.

I think Hardie Truesdale is on Never Never Land. 
 

 
 

 emac 

 climber New Hampshire 
 Jul 24, 2008 - 08:48am PT 
I&apos;ve not been down to the Gunks in a couple of years, but it&apos;s one of my favorite place for sure.

 
 

 
 

 veryveryoldman 

 Social climber The Bronx 
 Jul 24, 2008 - 08:52am PT 
Here is how Never Never Land looked last week:

 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 24, 2008 - 09:13am PT 
My son Jeremy (just getting done doing his duty) and me at the Gunks in 1978.

 


This shot also shows how pitiful and defective my left arm (bicep) is. LOL 
 

 
 

 the idle rich 

 climber Estes Park, CO 
 Jul 24, 2008 - 10:14am PT 
jstan...you used to be just eccentric but at least your memory was intact. I&apos;m not so sure anymore. Here&apos;s my story and I&apos;m sticking to it!

In the fall of 1975 I made plans to climb at Lost City with Steve Wunsch. Steve talked about a roof that he was interested in checking out and related this story. He and John Stannard were walking along the base of Lost City one day when they noticed a huge roof at the top of the cliff. Steve wondered aloud if the thing would possibly go free and John answered, &quot;Oh, sure, it looks like it&apos;s about 5.9.&quot; John later climbed it with Pete Ramins (I think) and called it &quot;Surprise Overhang&quot;. When Wunsch asked him how hard the roof was, Stannard answered, &quot;Oh...about 5.9&quot;. Wunsch assumed that the surprise was that the roof was so much easier than it looked.

It was a stellar day in October when Steve and I made the hike to Lost City with Lucy Greenberg and her young children, Ted and Emily. Lucy sunbathed topless (at least that&apos;s how I like to remember it and it&apos;s my story) and prepared a picnic lunch. The kids played in the talus at the base of the cliff.

I haven&apos;t climbed there in years, but at that time the local ethic was not to advertise or even report routes that had been done at Lost City. Any route information was passed on word of mouth and most climbers were loathe to ask for any beta. The intent was to have an area where everyone was free to have the adventure of a first ascent even if the climb had been done many times before. The running joke was that Stannard had climbed all of these routes at some time in the past...hence the phrase Done By Stannard Years Ago (DBSYA).

After looking at the roof, I couldn&apos;t imagine it going at anywhere near 5.9. Wunsch allowed me to have the roof lead which immediately raised a red flag. Upon reflection, I think his plan was to have me place the pro, work the moves and then take the free ride to the lip after I blew out. This was not the first time he used that ploy (rather effectively I might add) which made me all the more determined to lead it without falling. You had to respect the man&apos;s strategy but it wouldn&apos;t work this time.

I was able to place gear and then somehow reverse the moves each time and climb back to a rest at the belay. This involved much swinging and circus-like maneuvers in order to place the feet back on the holds. I endured a constant stream of heckling from Wunsch until I reminded him that he would only have one chance to clean the roof when he followed. Though not very speedy, all went well until I reached the lip and saw a large block that didn&apos;t quite look attached to the cliff. As I reached out to gently test the block, it came loose and began to fall off of its perch. That&apos;s when I remembered that Ted and Emily were playing in the talus somewhere below. I was able to hold the block in place, at the same time screaming for Lucy to get the kids to a safe place. Steve had finally ceased his heckling, probably more interested in the drama that was enfolding. After what seemed like an eternity, they told me that the children were safe. I relaxed slightly and the block sailed through my arms and smashed into the rocks below. On the positive side, it left a good hold in its wake that allowed me to finish the last moves to the top.

I couldn&apos;t imagine any way to climb past the death block other than doing a series of one-arm pullups. The next time I saw Stannard, I told him about the near-disaster and asked why he left the block on the climb. He gave his silly laugh and complained, &quot;Oh no...you ruined the surprise!&quot; He then demanded that I return to the climb and replace the rock. John wandered off down the carriage road shaking his head and mourning the loss. If the intent was to preserve the sense of adventure for future climbers, the goal was well met. 
 

 
 

 veryveryoldman 

 Social climber The Bronx 
 Jul 24, 2008 - 11:56am PT 
That&apos;s a great story, Rich--thank you.

Here&apos;s the lip (with no loose block in sight):

 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 30, 2008 - 07:36am PT 
Oakie wrote: Bob D, i mentioned to Barb that I thought you posted a couple photos of her on Supertopo. She had the biggest smile on her face when when she heard your name.


She is by far one the sweetest people that I know. I had so many wonderful times with her and Kevin....I miss seeing both of them...they added so much sunshine to my life.

I saw he last year at for the first time in 20 years and tears came to both our eyes. 
 

 
 

 mongrel 

 Trad climber Truckee, CA 
 Jul 30, 2008 - 09:02am PT 
With the name of this post, along with all the great photos that have turned up already, we ought to have one anyway of trad climbing the way it was: hammer in the back pocket, rack of 3 slings/biners, hiking boots with no friction at all, maybe a swami of 2 or 3 wraps of 1 inch.

(First try at posting an image; will it work?)

High E, a few years back
 
 
 

 
 

 horst 

 Trad climber Lancaster, PA 
 Jul 30, 2008 - 01:01pm PT 
OK Bobby D....here&apos;s a classic for you to name...

 


 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 30, 2008 - 01:54pm PT 
Sling Time 5.11+


or


Kansas City 5.12

Nice shots Eric.

 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Jul 30, 2008 - 02:00pm PT 
You can&apos;t be serious. 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Jul 30, 2008 - 03:05pm PT 
Eric, Incredible shots! Geno 
 

 
 

 horst 

 Trad climber Lancaster, PA 
 Jul 30, 2008 - 04:02pm PT 
DaDing! BobbyD wins...

Sling Time - One of the many stout roof routes at the gunks, though very unique in that the crux is managing your way through funky, sharp jams. I was psyched to onsight the route a number of years ago...only to have a photog show up as I&apos;m turning the lip onto easy rock. So, of course, I was talked into leading it again...thus, the pix you see above. 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 30, 2008 - 04:35pm PT 
Eric...I first did it in 79 and then again with Mike McGill in the late 80&apos;s.

Great route.

Are you coming to the reunion?? 
 

 
 

 horst 

 Trad climber Lancaster, PA 
 Jul 30, 2008 - 05:25pm PT 
Is the reunion the weekend of Oct 11 or 18?

I was just out climbing with Mark Robinson in Mammoth a few weeks back, and I believe he&apos;ll be coming in for the event.

Sounds like a good time!

 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 30, 2008 - 06:16pm PT 
Jstan wrote: You can&apos;t be serious.


About what??


Eric...it is on the weekend of the 18...it&apos;s going to be a blast. We need a young ropegun. 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Jul 30, 2008 - 06:58pm PT 
Slingtime 5.10+

or

Kansas City 5.10+


Slingtime is the Gunks equivalent of an overlap but on the vertical. It is the only one. You can&apos;t confuse it with any other climb. Not any other climb that existed in 1974 certainly.

&quot;Surely you are joking, Mr. Feynman?&quot;

That&apos;s a great read by the by.

Still trying to decide on the reunion. Will entail six(6) days of train travel. That&apos;s a bunch.

Do transcontinental trains provide wireless service? Anybody?

Airplanes are not going to be part of our future. They no longer exist. 
 

 
 

 TradIsGood 

 Chalkless climber the Gunks end of the country 
 Jul 30, 2008 - 08:21pm PT 
Slingtime.
:-)

Good guess!

Shows up in the picture properties.

Could it be in the Nears?

Looks a little stiff. I know a guy who blew a bicep not far from there. Inverted Layback. Just a plain old Gunks 10, mostly easier except for a couple moves.

Edit: jstan, AT&amp;T;provides wireless - 3G - iPhone. Will you be repeating some of your FA&apos;s? Been on a couple of them lately. 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Jul 30, 2008 - 10:00pm PT 
TIG:
Slingtime is in the Nears right near an easy climb which I can&apos;t remember. I really have to bring one of my books out of JT. Not something to which I refer often.

There is one repeat I really would like to do, if I come. I used to pick up trash early in the morning and then climb with whomever jumped in to help. We did that every weekend more than thirty years ago. Much of the climbing is a bit faded in my memory. The trash picking is still as clear as a bell. People got the place so clean there was not one cigarette butt to be found on the carriage road between the steel bridge and Skytop. 5.19
Take that back. 5.19d

If the trains are internet cafe type hot spots I could get an old Apple laptop and while away the time on the train. Have to be doing something. You&apos;ve watched Rich Romano? He&apos;s much more able but the disease is the same. 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Jul 31, 2008 - 02:56am PT 
Jstan,

This is from Gene Smith. I was one of those guys hanging in the Uberfall that you hooked up with to climb back in 1980. I don&apos;t remember that we picked up litter. Maybe there wasn&apos;t any that morning or you had already done it. Anyway, you led Nose Dive and set only a single nut at the crux. I led Never Never Land (you soloed up a ways on Never Say Never and gave me some encouragement). Then you led us up Balrog. On another day we walked to Sky Top and did No Exit. I really appreciated that you&apos;d climb with us. Thank you. I learned a lot from you on just those few climbs.

We really hope you come to the Gunks II Reunion. A number of people are combing through their archives (closets, garages and storage bins)to find long lost pictures for the event on Saturday evening 18 October at the Preserve. A lot of folks will also be in the Gunks climbing, hiking and hanging out the week before.


 
 

 
 

 redpt 

 Trad climber nj 
 Jul 31, 2008 - 06:28am PT 
&gt;jstan: near an easy climb

Sling Time is just right of Swing Time (11a?) and just left of Disneyland (5.5/6). I&apos;ve got to get on it some day.



 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Jul 31, 2008 - 08:06am PT 
Gene:

I certainly do remember you. At the time you were teaching at the Point.
Except for the traffic I expect you find the capitol a very interesting
place. Great museums.

We usually tried to do the roads like 299 right after dawn on Sunday
morning. The hairpins got a bit exciting once traffic had picked up.

Red:
To give you an idea of how memorable I found Slingtime I remember it in
some detail. I can&apos;t seem to pull up even an image of Swingtime. Slingtime
must have taken stoppers as that was about all I was using. It was a
little hard on the fingers too.

This brings up my all time favorite made up but true story. Mac was
sitting under April Showers tieing has shoes when he looked up. He said
to Claude, &quot;Do you suppose that roof has gone? Thumbing through the
guide Claude says, &quot;Yeah, Jim. It has gone. Jim says, &quot;Who did it?&quot; Claude
replies after a pause, &quot;Jim. You did it.&quot; After a somewhat longer pause
Jim says, &quot;Does it say how hard it is?&quot; 
 

 
 

 Smike 

 Ice climber Gunks, NY 
 Jul 31, 2008 - 09:03am PT 
Ah the Gunks: (From left to Right: Millbrook, Bayards, Near Trapps, Trapps, Sky Top)


 

View large: http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2201/1795309207_0862a848ac_o.jpg 

 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 31, 2008 - 09:07am PT 
Bob D on Maria Redirect....1977

 

The blond god on Sling Time....1978.

 

One of the other gods (Stewe Wunsch) on Kligfield&apos;s Follies...1978

 

Sorry about the quality of the slides. 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Jul 31, 2008 - 10:53am PT 
Part way up Kliegfields you encounter a cramped belay below a roof going
into an inside corner with no protection for awhile. When Bragg and I did
the route we considered a plan to get Steve belaying below that roof and
then have the leader smile and wave as they fall past the belay and go
down below yet another roof. I don&apos;t know whether Bragg ever put that
plan into action. I certainly did not.

At least among the routes known in 1974, Kliegfield&apos;s Follies holds a very
special place. It has ambiance up the wing wang, IMO. 
 

 
 

 cliffmama 

 Trad climber Noo Jerzee 
 Jul 31, 2008 - 10:57am PT 
&quot;I met Barbara at the Long Distance swimming area in Minnewaska. Barbara is in incredible shape and I mentioned that it would be great to get her back out climbing. Barb&apos;s answer was maybe.
...

I hope to see Barbara back out climbing again.&quot;

About 3 or 4 years ago, I did a little climbing with Barbara after she moved back to the area. We brought our kids out to climb one day and she did a little top roping. Despite not climbing in many years she still could gracefully tiptoe up a 5.10a. Then we got out for an afternoon without the kids and she followed me up Classic. Haven&apos;t climbed with her since, but I heard she climbed during last year&apos;s reunion.

So how do I get myself an invitation to the reunion? I have no &quot;Gunks legend&quot; credentials, I just like to hang out with them. Jstan - it was great to climb and hike with you at JTree in March - will you be coming to the Gunks this fall?

I did my first climb at the Gunks the weekend the bus went over the hairpin turn (Feb 1981). Remembering the sound of the people in the bus screaming still sends chills down my spine. Seems like no one walks down anymore, everyone raps and so many people carelessly throw their ropes down on other climbers. I miss the cow-bell sound of hexes clinking down the carriage road as climbers walked back to their packs.

Recently, there have been efforts to maintain good relations and get climbers to participate. We started the Gunks Climbers&apos; Coalition back in 2002 (I&apos;m the secretary and webmaster). We&apos;re working on opening more areas to climbing, fund raising for rescue equipment, annual clean-ups, and we put on climber events (slideshows by Henry Barber, Eric Horst, John Bragg, Russ Clune, Al DeMaria, and others). We are currently organizing a letter-writing campaign to open climbing up in Minnewaska, beyond the Peter&apos;s Kill area. See our website http://gunksclimbers.org for information about who to write to (they are accepting comments until August 11th), and send me a message if you&apos;d like to get on our mailing list.

Great thread, fun pictures!

Jannette 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Jul 31, 2008 - 11:02am PT 
J:
You guys are plenty gnarly. You don&apos;t need no stinking credentials. 
 

 
 

 SteveW 

 Trad climber The state of confusion 
 Jul 31, 2008 - 11:10am PT 
I remember picking trash up on the road back
in the early to mid 70&apos;s. (I think Jstan lured us
poor climbers by dropping change on the road--
I always picked up at least a dollar&apos;s worth doing
trash duty)! 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Jul 31, 2008 - 11:48am PT 
Steve:
Weren&apos;t you the one who got the ten spot? I remember that.

Two of us picked up $20 apiece on Route 120 at the last Facelift. Well that is not strictly correct. Hollywood found the twenty but the TV crew gave me twenty for some reason. We stuck both bills in the wallet I had just found and gave it to Ed to give to Ken. That same day I found the bungee cord I am still using on my bicycle. 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Jul 31, 2008 - 09:57pm PT 
Geno...start posting pictures.

Russ Raffa On Scary Aria.

 

Rich G on first pitch of Endro Man.

 
 
 

 
 

 TomMc 

 Trad climber Massachusetts 
 Aug 1, 2008 - 06:17am PT 
My oh my, what a wonderful thread. The Gunks hold a very special place in my heart, as do all the friends and climbing partners from those days. Both the rock and the people are the very best, it was good to see pictures of both.

My favorite &quot;good old days&quot; story of the Gunks comes from my first visit, Labor Day weekend 1967. I have a photo of us eating lunch down below the Uberfall along the road. There were 6 cars there! Thats all! The fee was 50 cents a day, and Joe Donahue (remember him?) was the Mohonk ranger before Tom Scheuer.

The names and photos urged me to dig out my old guidebooks (Art Gran &apos;64 and Dick Williams &apos;72) to recall some of my past. I was fortunate to have climbed lots of 5.9&apos;s and 10&apos;s in the early/mid-1970&apos;s with some of the best; Kevin and Barbara Bien, John Bragg, Steve Arsenault, Steve Wunsch, Bob Jahn, Spaff Ackerly, Howie Doyle, and others. What a pleasure to see their names and pictures.

Does anyone know what happened to Bob Richardson or Harvey Goldstein? I see Al Rubin occasionally here in western Mass., and actually got to the Gunks to climb last summer for the first time in 12 years.

I&apos;d love to come down for the reunion in October. Can anyone provide me with any details? E-mail me direct at: tom@southfacefarm.com.

John Stannard: You were a very important integral part of the the Gunks climbing history, not only for pushing the limits but also for your clean climbing ethics and community work spirit. Train or plane or flying carpet, y&apos;gotta come east in October for the reunion.

 
 

 
 

 wombat 

 Trad climber NY, NY 
 Aug 1, 2008 - 06:48am PT 
wow - the tree at the base of enduro man has grown quite alot!

we were over there a little while back (on TR) and discussing the merits and tactics for protecting the pitch on lead. plan 1 was to jump for the tree, plan 2 was to pre-sling the tree with a stick to hold out the sling towards the rock to make it easier to reach. barring that, solo seemed to be the most likely option. we have not yet availed ourselves of any of those yet. great moves, proud lead. 
 

 
 

 DanaB 

 climber 
 Aug 2, 2008 - 04:48am PT 
I&apos;m pretty sure in that group photo with Bragg, Rosenfeld, et al, it&apos;s actually Bill Ravitch that&apos;s hiding behind the tree. Rick Cronk is also in the picture, and I believe it&apos;s Barbara Devine who is being belayed on To Have or Have Not. 
 

 
 

 Rickster 

 Trad climber Pine Bush,NY 
 Aug 2, 2008 - 05:46am PT 
Thank you Dana, we&apos;ve been trying to fathom who was behind the tree. I&apos;m pretty sure this was a day spent on and around &quot;To Have and Have Not&quot;. At some time while Barb was up top, a toaster sized rock came off and slammed in not few feet from the belay. Everyone goes diving left and right and all David can do is stand there tied short to the tree. Being a good man on a rope, he stayed the course and held on. RC 
 

 
 

 DanaB 

 climber 
 Aug 2, 2008 - 06:09am PT 
Gene,

Thanks for posting those photos. At last, there is some photographic evidence that I really do climb. I had a lot of fun climbing with you that summer, and I still haunt the &apos;Gunks - I was up there yesterday. Remember Roger&apos;s Rock with Todd and Patty? I just went back there a week ago, the paddle out and the climbing are still a blast. Take care.

Dana Bartlett 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Aug 2, 2008 - 08:27am PT 
Hey Dana, I just top-roped evidence that you really do climb---Night Fall. Holy crap, I thought 5.10 X would be a fair grade. How the hell did you protect that thing? 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Aug 2, 2008 - 09:00am PT 
Bob Jahn on April Showers...I think....1977.

 

Rich G again on Endro Man


 
 
 

 
 

 DanaB 

 climber 
 Aug 2, 2008 - 11:11am PT 
Hi Rich,

There was no protection, and I thought that it was solid to hard 5.10; I&apos;ve climbed enough at the &apos;Gunks to know that. I have no idea why Dick downrated it to 5.9. It&apos;s definitely much harder. 
 

 
 

 DanaB 

 climber 
 Aug 2, 2008 - 11:16am PT 
Gene,

Those photos of Balrog made me think of something else we did in that area. Remember doing Nurdland?

Dana 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Aug 2, 2008 - 12:08pm PT 
Dana...you in Philly? 
 

 
 

 DanaB 

 climber 
 Aug 2, 2008 - 12:16pm PT 
Someone has to live here . . .

Dana 
 

 
 

 Todd Eastman 

 climber Bellingham, WA 
 Aug 2, 2008 - 02:54pm PT 
Wow! What a trip down the memory carriage road. Thanks to all for the pics and comments. 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Aug 2, 2008 - 08:19pm PT 
Dana...you dissing my hometown?? Look me up if you make it out this way.

Todd...long time no see. Hope all is well? 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Aug 3, 2008 - 04:39am PT 
Dana,
Great to hear from you.

Of course I remember that June of 81. I just got out of an Army school and had 30 days off. I was so psyched to climb! I met up you and we climbed a bunch of B-side and other classics:
Nerdland
Nemisis
Welcome to the Gunks
Midnight Cowboy
October Country
Shake and Bake
Jean
Maria Direct
No existence
This Petty Pace

and we also climbed Two Bits on Rogers Rock with Todd Swain and Patty Lanzetta.

I picked up a lot watching you climb thin face. I remember you had this minimalist rack: all hollow biners and couple wires. You didn&apos;t waste time putting in much of it either! I searched for more pics of you, but those were the only ones I had.

Look forward to climbing with you this October at the Reunion! Also Laura and I will be climbing in the Gunks 10-12 Aug and 16-23 Aug if you&apos;d like to meet us. PM me.

Geno
 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Aug 3, 2008 - 12:03pm PT 
Here are a couple scans:

Mike Freeman on No Exit:
 

A climber moving out on Modern Times:
 

 

Rosie Andrews on No Comment:
 
[img]
Rosie on Fissure Ramin:
 
Jeff Gruenberg on Square Meal:
 

Jeff on Welcome to the Gunks:
 



 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Aug 3, 2008 - 12:10pm PT 
A few shots of my struggles on Foops back in 82:

 

I always thought it would be easy once I got the bucket at the lip but it wasn&apos;t for me. I fell pretty far at this point.
 

Here is another climber trying:
 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Aug 3, 2008 - 12:41pm PT 
Here are a few shots of people from the late 70s/early 80s:

Rick Cronk:
 

Rick who is the guy to the right?
 

Harvey Arnold:
 

Manny on the left. Mike Sawicky on the right.
 

Bobby do you know this guy?
 

Gary Garret and Steve Jones.

 

 
 

 
 

 Todd Eastman 

 climber Bellingham, WA 
 Aug 3, 2008 - 12:43pm PT 
Bobby D, I just snapped my achilles while bouldering last week and am now perfecting my armchair routine. I&apos;m living in Bellingham and doing well though not climbing much due to the crazy long ski seasons. I&apos;ll be back! 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Aug 3, 2008 - 01:28pm PT 
If asked why that climb gets so much attention I would have to guess it
is because of the bucket at the lip. You can see where you have to get
to. The roof I really regret our doing was all slopey and roundy out there.
Once on the face it was most definitely not all over.

If no one had done it people could still look up and wonder. Answers don&apos;t
keep you awake at night wondering.

Only questions do that. 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Aug 3, 2008 - 02:00pm PT 
Great shots everyone. Keep them flowing.

Geno...the guy with Gary is Steve Jones...his brother Cory use to a ranger.

This is me trying my best to break my neck on Generation Gap...maybe the biggest sandbag in the Gunks.

 

Todd...sorry about the ankle...weren&apos;t you just in town climbing with Dan? 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Aug 3, 2008 - 02:21pm PT 
Bones (AKA as Jersey Jeff) on Lotus Flower...1982?

 

Mike Freeman on...

 
 
 

 
 

 Mighty Hiker 

 Social climber Vancouver, B.C. 
 Aug 3, 2008 - 02:31pm PT 
What does the word Foops mean, and/or how was it derived? Is it just a play on &quot;Oops!&quot;? 
 

 
 

 Rickster 

 Trad climber Pine Bush,NY 
 Aug 3, 2008 - 05:32pm PT 
Geno, I haven&apos;t a clue who the first fellow is . I&apos;m pretty sure that is Manny with Sawicky. RC 
 

 
 

 divad 

 Trad climber wmass 
 Aug 3, 2008 - 06:38pm PT 
From Swain:
Legend has it that John Salathe was rappeling in Yosemite and found his rope too short to reach a ledge. The disgruntled Salathe was heard to exclaim in a heavy Swiss accent &quot;Foops (whoops), no more rope!&quot; He then cut off the ends of his rope and prussiked back up to the anchor. 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Aug 4, 2008 - 06:03pm PT 
Our dear Kevin on Supercrack.

 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Aug 4, 2008 - 07:12pm PT 
Divad, if Swain repeated that story about Foops, he ought to have used it with attribution, because it comes from Art Gran&apos;s original 1964 guide to the Gunks. 
 

 
 

 Kligfield 

 Mountain climber Boulder, CO 
 Aug 5, 2008 - 06:56pm PT 
And the &quot;Foops&quot; story is initially discussed in the 1959 (?) cover article on the Gunks in Sports Illustrated--the one in which Jim McCarthy is shown aiding across the Foops roof on the second ascent. 
 

 
 

 Curt 

 Boulder climber Gilbert, AZ 
 Aug 5, 2008 - 09:35pm PT 
Yes, &quot;Up Against the Wall&quot; is the route Mike is on.

Curt

 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Aug 7, 2008 - 10:40pm PT 
Well, it just wouldn&apos;t a proper Gunks thread without a Vulgarian gross-out! Got my Jones back and had to post this shot of Dick Williams on Shockley&apos;s Cieling. Art Gran photo courtesy of Ed Cooper in Climbing in North America, 1976.

 
 

 
 

 david r 

 climber WA now NY then 
 Aug 8, 2008 - 11:22am PT 
Hello All,
Hi Steve! Hi Bob D, Hello Rick, stay seated Idle Rich...
This will be my first post..
I thought that some of you might find this interesting...
 The cover of Vulgarian Digest (Spring 1972): 
 

 
 

 
 

 david r 

 climber WA now NY then 
 Aug 8, 2008 - 11:36am PT 
and another...
Kevin And Barbara in a classic pose from a memorable trip to Boulder in the summer of &apos;77
Many Gunks climbers were there including Romano, The Idle Rich, and many others...
Many of us slept in the (vacated for summer) rooms of a very animal house-like
CU fraternity where jumping off the roof and out of windows into the swimming pool
was a frequent occurance...
 
 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Aug 10, 2008 - 05:12pm PT 
Welcome maestro Rosenfeld!

Now I actually have a way to contact you! Where is the other pair for the Milton Boulder chicken fight?!? 
 

 
 

 LCS 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Aug 11, 2008 - 04:13am PT 
David R, Remember our hike out to Lost City and our trip &quot;out west&quot; in 1975??

From left to right are Russ Raffa, Rich Ross, Mike Robbins, David Feinberg and David Rosenfeld
 

Here&apos;s a young David R and Feinberg
 

Rich Ross
 

Harvey Arnold, David R and Matt Munchnik in Eldorado 1975
 
 

 
 

 david r 

 climber Seattle now NY then 
 Aug 11, 2008 - 08:32am PT 
L,

Great to see those photos... Though it is sometimes a bit difficult to separate
out which trip was which!
Still feeling a huge impact from last fall and looking forward to Gunks II

 an attempt at Crack of Bizarre Delights, late 70s... in the end Kevin led and others followed: 
 

note: original image which was backward has been flipped 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Aug 11, 2008 - 08:47am PT 
Not shots of climbers back in the day but rather shots of back-in-the-day climbers climbing (still). This post just ain&apos;t gettin&apos; any love---almost off page 2 without even a heckle, so I thought I&apos;d give it a chance at life here.

 Septuagenarians on Parade 

 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Aug 11, 2008 - 08:47am PT 
Not shots of climbers back in the day but rather shots of back-in-the-day climbers climbing (still). This post just ain&apos;t gettin&apos; any love---almost off page 2 without even a heckle, so I thought I&apos;d give it a chance at life here.

 Septuagenarians on Parade 

 
 

 
 

 david r 

 climber Seattle now NY then 
 Aug 11, 2008 - 09:46am PT 
RIch,

The pics of Williams are great...
Having turned 50 last year and thinking about climbing and aging, his example is truly inspiring... 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Aug 12, 2008 - 07:29am PT 
Sweeeeeeeeet Shot! 
 

 
 

 scuffy b 

 climber Zeno&apos;s Paradise 
 Aug 12, 2008 - 09:31am PT 
This must be the first sighting of Munchnik on ST 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Aug 12, 2008 - 09:56am PT 
Lovely shot, John! 
 

 
 

 david r 

 climber Seattle now NY then 
 Aug 12, 2008 - 02:22pm PT 
guys, it is Matt Muchnick (only one &quot;n&quot;)


cheers... 
 

 
 

 Rickster 

 Trad climber Pine Bush,NY 
 Aug 13, 2008 - 04:50am PT 
Davey, The shot of CBD is backwards dude! I&apos;ve got the last in the series of you at the lip. I think Joan was on camera that day. Good to see you&apos;ve been scanning. We had a scanning frenzy going on last evening. There will be big surprises going way, way, way back. And, more to come for Gunks II. LCS is in dyno mode.
On a related note, 2010 will be the 75th anniversary of Gunks climbing. RC 
 

 
 

 david r 

 climber Seattle now NY then 
 Aug 13, 2008 - 07:02am PT 
rick,
ok.. image has been flipped..


 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Aug 18, 2008 - 01:43pm PT 
Skytop and Open Cockpit....simply beautiful. If my memory serve me well that is Mark Robinson leading.

 


Oakie...love that image of your at Skytop. 
 

 
 

 Gunksgoer 

 Trad climber nj 
 Aug 18, 2008 - 06:07pm PT 
Skytop probably has the best rock ive seen anywhere. 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Aug 19, 2008 - 04:37pm PT 
Welcome to the Gunks...1977

 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Aug 19, 2008 - 08:28pm PT 
Good morning Geno and Laura....two months and counting.

Skytop...again.

 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Aug 20, 2008 - 07:00am PT 
Sandy Stewart...PR...1978 

 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Aug 25, 2008 - 08:00pm PT 
Richie Romano on the Winter...

 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Aug 26, 2008 - 08:50am PT 
Geno on Simple Suff

 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Aug 28, 2008 - 07:38am PT 
Stemming through Simple Suff is not the best way for a 50 year old to wake up. Thanks Bob 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Sep 1, 2008 - 03:20am PT 
This is a photo of Rosie Andrews, one of the great Gunks climbers from the 70s-early 80s. I learned a lot climbing with her. She had incredible technique and nerves of steel. Rosie is climbing Kevin Bein&apos;s test piece: No Comment 5.11+ PG in this photo:

 
 

 
 

 Harv 

 Trad climber Nederland, CO 
 Sep 7, 2008 - 04:14pm PT 
For those of you who have asked about the &quot;reunion&quot; at the Gunks this fall, the main day is going to be October 18th where I will be giving a slide show centering on the people and climbing in the seventies. There will be a lot of people coming early to recapture the feeling on being on good rock and Bob D told me that there would be some top ropes in the Slime area for those who have lost the penchant of leading hard climbs. 
 

 
 

 Don Lauria 

 Trad climber Bishop, CA 
 Sep 21, 2008 - 09:08am PT 
To me &quot;Gunks&quot; and &quot;Vulgarians&quot; are inseparable. For a little history I refer you to www.bardini.org and the anecdote &quot;Who created the Vulgarians?&quot; 
 

 
 

 Rickster 

 Trad climber Pine Bush,NY 
 Oct 14, 2008 - 03:17pm PT 
Keeping the thread alive. Gunks II has begun. Folks are slowly arriving in town. This past weekend the place was packed out as usual. Parking lots were near full by 9 am with normal climbing traffic as well as leaf peepers, dog walkers, runners, bikers, and many others. Many climbs had continuous activity from sunrise to sunset and beyond. It looks to be a great week of memories revisited and some new ones to come. RC 
 

 
 

 Jim E 

 climber 
 Oct 15, 2008 - 08:49am PT 
mega bump! 
 

 
 

 Rickster 

 Trad climber Pine Bush,NY 
 Oct 15, 2008 - 01:54pm PT 
Sorry, but someone had to do it. RC 
 

 
 

 Ed Hartouni 

 Trad climber Livermore, CA 
 Oct 15, 2008 - 09:36pm PT 
more nostalgia 
 

 
 

 Anastasia 

 climber Not there 
 Oct 15, 2008 - 11:03pm PT 
Bumping 
 

 
 

 cliffmama 

 Trad climber Noo Jerzee 
 Oct 17, 2008 - 08:26am PT 
Does anyone know if the party starts some time before the slide show, or at the same time as the slide show on Saturday? Don&apos;t know what time to arrive...

Jannette 
 

 
 

 Rickster 

 Trad climber Pine Bush,NY 
 Oct 17, 2008 - 08:12pm PT 
7pm. Slides are a side show in adjacent room.RC 
 

 
 

 cliffmama 

 Trad climber Noo Jerzee 
 Oct 22, 2008 - 10:34am PT 
Anyone have pictures to post from the events this weekend? I have a few, will post in a day or two.

Jannette 
 

 
 

 SteveW 

 Trad climber The state of confusion 
 Oct 22, 2008 - 10:39am PT 
Nice pix, Oakie! 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Oct 22, 2008 - 01:55pm PT 
Note shots on Gunks Reunion 2008 thread .

Keep &apos;em comin&apos; (and leave a comment to keep the thread alive...)
 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Oct 23, 2008 - 07:07am PT 
The guy in the fifth photo is Doug Fosdick. In the 201-220 section with the caption &quot;Bobby D do you know this guy?&quot; 
 

 
 

 socialclimber 

 Mountain climber CA 
 Oct 23, 2008 - 11:14am PT 
bump 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Oct 25, 2008 - 06:35am PT 
Rich Ross, Thanks for input on the Fosdick photo. Laura had a that slide. We couldn&apos;t figure who it was. Geno 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Oct 25, 2008 - 06:37am PT 
Oakie, You take brilliant photos. Can you provide some information on that last one? Geno 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Oct 25, 2008 - 09:27am PT 
 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Oct 25, 2008 - 09:28am PT 
 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Oct 26, 2008 - 06:24am PT 
Damn, Oakie, that photo with the ink colored sky is superb.



Bobby D, Your shots are awesome too. Did you get a good one of the sky from the parking overlook after it was raining in the Nears last Thursday? 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Oct 27, 2008 - 06:11pm PT 
Anyone know who these guys are? This is one of earliest pictures of a group that would make a name for themselves first in the Shawangunks and then in American Mountaineering. There&apos;s a lot of clues in the photo.

 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Oct 27, 2008 - 07:34pm PT 
I&apos;m guessing here. The guy leaning on the car looks like he could be the young McCarthy. Next from L to R is, I think, Roman Sadowy, then Dick Williams. I&apos;m not sure who the next guy is, and then last on the right is Al DeMaria.

If any stills can be extracted from Steve&apos;s video of the visit with the Vulgarians on that day during the reunion that they let them out of the Bide-a-Wee Old Climbers Rest Home, you can see just what age has done to some of these studs.

On the other hand, the fact that they&apos;re all still pullin&apos; down (ever so much more gently) fifty plus years later oughta count fer somethin&apos;. 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Oct 27, 2008 - 10:00pm PT 
Them studs may be old but they sure ain&apos;t rusty or unreliable! Must be that they are solid gold on the inside. 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Oct 29, 2008 - 03:15am PT 
The photo I posted above was given to me last summer by Claude Suhl, one of the great Gunks climbers and a central Vulgarian figure. Claude provided introductory remarks as a member of the Vulgarian panel at Rock and Snow last Friday couched in what calls mega-mystical cosmology. Claude has a unique sense of humor that he uses to poke fun at science, psychology, and politics. He and his wife Alice have been strong supporters of the last two Gunks Reunions. They also have a son who is a U.S. Army Ranger. Getting to know them both has been one of the great experiences of attending the reunions these last couple years.

Anyway, I called Claude yesterday and he provided details on the picture.

These guys were members of the NY City College Outing Club (CCOC). It is March 1958 and they are in West Virginia looking for adventure (it is likely their School House Cave trip). The guy leaning on the car is Horst something (Claude couldn&apos;t remember his last name). But the rest of the gang will form the core of the Vulgarians in a few years:
-Roman Sadowy is tying the knot.
  The guy holding red licorice is Claude Suhl himself.
-Pete Geiser is wearing the red hat.
-Al DeMaria is wearing the red sweat shirt.

Rgold may have to advise us on a few details I may miss but from what Claude tells me at this point in time (1958):

-Dick Williams is in the US Navy in the Submarine Service (Claude reckons Dick may even be under the artic ice cap). Dick had been to the Gunks in 1957 but he won&apos;t link up with these guys until 1961.

-Jim McCarthy is already a leading Gunks activist. He started climbing in 1951.

-Art Gran is also a top Gunks climber who has met the CCOC guys and will put them under his wing at the Gunks and on trips out West.

-Dave Craft comes into the picture in Summer 1958 and is a very important catalyst in the eventual formation of the Vulgarians.

-Jim Andress is another important mentor to the CCOC guys. Jim served in WWII in the 10th Mountain Division and starts climbing in the Gunks in 1950.

-Rich Goldstone is 14 years old and starts climbing in the Summer of 1958 by climbing the Grand Teton.

Claude Suhl gave me a rough draft of the early Vulgarian history and what follows is an excerpt of what the CCOC boys did in their first few years. Its important to realize that these climbs were being accomplished in boots/sneakers using Army ropes, slings and a few pitons. This is learning to climb during the Iron Age.

Vulgarian Chronicals jugernaught
[author unknown but it could be Al DeMaria]

1957
Sept. - Oct : First meetings of CCOC. Attended by Suhl and Geiser meet Sadowy, [George] Bloom, Al D, others?. Suhl and Geiser excited to learn that CCOC members doing rock climbing, an area that both have serious interest in. See learning opportunity also possibilities of getting to &quot;the mtns.&quot;, the ultimate goal.
Nov. - Dec?

1958
March? First rock climbing trip to Breakneck Ridge, with Art [Gran]?. Gunks seen in distance.
First time to Gunks. Climbing with Gran. Yellow Belly [5.7] free is maximum climb.

April (Al D)
School house cave trip. Rappeling climbing in cave requires prior knowledge of climbing therefore climbing already begun. &quot;Terse Wiry&quot; term coined from &quot;terse wiry leader&quot; reference in climbing book.

June (Al D)
Crag Camp/White Mtns trip followed by climbing at Pocomoonshine, 2nd ascent of Catharsis.

Summer:
Every weekends climbing at cliffs independent of AMC. Probably up to and including 5.7 (Yellow Belly). Craft goes to Bugaboos with Dave Isles and party do East Ridge of Bugaboo. Meet [Jim] Craft,[Jim] Andress, {Jim] McCarthy; Gran &quot;adopts&quot; CCOC climbers. Craft, Andress become regular partners with CCOC climbers. CCOC climbers leading probably including 5.7 (Yellow Belly). An &quot;Independent&quot; group starts to form.

September (Al D)
Kathadin trip. Suhl and Geiser do first alpine type climb of new route on Kathadin headwall. Bushwack to base was hardest part.

Fall
Birdland [5.9] put in [by Mccarthy, Andress and Ruppley]. climbing breakthrough. Some friction developing between &quot;independents&quot; and AMC for not following AMC climbing guidelines.re leading and following (i.e. all the 4&apos;s before the 5&apos;s, etc.). A number of the CCOC&apos;ers who had started climbing that spring begin leading. This particularly aggravates the AMC.

Al DeMaria leading in the Gunks with hammer and pitons:
 

 

 
 

 
 

 Alan Rubin 

 climber Amherst,MA. 
 Oct 29, 2008 - 06:43am PT 
Great photo!!!!! Rich&apos;s mis-ID of the fellow leaning against the car as the &quot;young McCarthy&quot;, made me realize that I don&apos;t recall ever seeing a picture of &quot;the young Mac&quot;, or the young Art Gran, either. So if anyone has such photos, or similar ones of other local characters in their younger days, please post &apos;em. As for the VMC chronology---more great stuff. Is a book actually in the works? If so, I&apos;ll place my order now!!!!! 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Oct 31, 2008 - 06:06am PT 
Al and all,

There is a guy writing a book about Gunks climbing that will no doubt include previously unpublished stories about the Vulgarians. I am sure it&apos;ll be a great read. In the meantime, here are a few more details and pictures from Claude Suhl&apos;s archives.

The year is 1959. The City College Outing Club guys have met Dave Craft and others. They are climbing with Jim Mccarthy, Art Gran as well as coming in contact with other great climbers of this era. The pictures and text that follows is mostly of climbing in the Bugaboos. Claude tells me they took few pictures of themselves climbing in the Gunks. Although they were Gunks climbers what they really wanted to do was climb mountains.

&quot;Vulgarian Chronicals jugernaught[unknown author-could be Al DeMaria] (continued).

1959
Spring: Weekend climbing trips to Gunks

Birth of the Vulgarians
Sometime in June at an early proto-rave, Dick Williams good buddy Jack Hansen, looking around a firelit circle of carousing Independent climbers exclaimed &quot;why you guys are a bunch of Vulgarians&quot;. The name seemed somehow appropriate and began to be used by the independents to describe themselves. It also became used by the AMC but with very different intent. The &quot;boys&quot; were becoming a problem for the tightly structured AMC climbing environment that had become the unofficial &quot;controlling authority&quot; for climbing in the Gunks. The independents discovered that their outlandish and irreverent behavior on the rocks was a potent weapon in keeping the AMC at bay. After all, how to handle a bunch of young, loud, foul mouthed hooligans who were also excellent climbers was a daunting problem for the rather strait-laced Appies.

July:
Begining of &quot;sport&quot; climbing - First placement of bolt while on top rope: McCarthy and Suhl on Turdland.


August:
The Vulgarians meet the Bugaboos
and
the Bugaboos meet the Vulgarians

This particular adventure was probably really Dave Crafts fault.
Picture of Dave Craft:
 

The previous summer Dave had disappeared from the Gunks to purportedly visit a fabled range of real mountains that the Vulgarians had never heard of; the Bugaboos. Dave returned with great tales of gleaming granite spires, rising gloriously out of glaciers. Most of the peaks had only a single route and were therefore virtually unclimbed; tales of Snowpatch Spire, the mountain with the hardest normal route in North America climbed only a handful of times; of Bugaboo Spire and the of the even more challenging Howsers with its South Tower which had only been climbed once. What was even more enticing was that this climbing Shangri-La was a mere 2500 miles away and on the same continent!
By the time the summer of 59 rolled around a Vulgarian raiding party had formed with plans for an assault on this fabulous treasure. The fact that this would be the first time that any of them except for Craft had even been in an alpine environment was considered a mere bagatelle.


Anyway with all the overweening overconfidence of youth, plans were made, gear assembled and an assault team consisting of Gran, Craft, Geiser, Sadowy and Suhl formed. The only thing that now stood in their way was a little problem of money.
Only two people in this group, Craft and Gran, had regular paying jobs. Geiser, Sadowy and Suhl consequently had to spend the first part of the summer working in the south Bronx for Senator Frozen Products, a tiny mom and pop ice cream manufacturer that was coincidently about to give rise to an ice cream revolution.
Because Senator was a Teamster union shop, and because manual labor actually got a living wage in those days, they managed to accumulate sufficient boodle to finance their planned venture. Not only did they get the boodle, but they also intersected with an historic moment in the ice cream business, the birth of Hagen-Dazs. At the time, Senator Frozen Products, a family affair, was under a lot of rather hard ball pressure from its much larger competitors, so in the summer of 1959, in a last ditch effort to stave off bankruptcy they decided to create a product that they were pretty sure their competitors couldnt match, namely the first commercially available super-premium ice cream. Boy did they get that one right!
Although the boys didnt know that they were witness to ice cream history, they did know when theyd accumulated the necessary funds for the western adventure. Consequently, towards the end of July, the necessary $ in hand, the five man assault team with all its gear, squeezed into Art&apos;s 57 Olds and headed west.
NY, NY to Spilamacheen, BC; two and a half 24 hour days of driving across pre-interstate America. Eternal 2 lane arrow straight blacktops leading to the tiny town of Spilamacheen and Jim Pauls(?) gas station. $25/person got you a place in his jeep/trailer combo. 3 or 4 hours of four wheeling in the long Canadian evening through the still, semi-virginal BC wilderness, got you to the so-called trailhead; an abandoned lumber camp.

There the party met John Rupley and Hans Krause already climbing for a week or so and come out for more supplies. Morning comes and staggeringly heavy packs are mounted for the 4.5 mile ascent to Boulder camp. A network of game trails leads to the foot of the moraine along which there&apos;s a fairly well beaten path which unfortunately dissolves into a maze of boulders, scree and shrubbery protecting the final (steep, really MF&apos;ing steep) hump into Boulder camp:
 
Boulder Camp is pretty crowded, Ed Cooper is camped under the &quot;Boulder&quot;, Fred Becky and his climbing partner are hacking away at the first ascent of Snowpatch East face, while off away from all the hurly burly of Boulder Camp, Krause and Rupley have pitched camp up in the Pigeon - Hauser col.
A day or so of &quot;acclimatization&quot; and the Vulgarian party makes the 32nd ascent of Snowpatch; feels great, running around these hills. Various day ascents are made of Anniversary and Pigeon peaks, and a visit to the Krause - Rupley camp while Gran and Cooper start to work on the East face of Bugaboo.
Pictured from left to right is Claude Suhl, Art Gran and possibly Ed Cooper:
 


Geiser and Sadowy join forces with Becky and under Fred&apos;s tutelage, and a long day, knock off the first ascent of the west face of Bugaboo.

Picture of Roman Sadowy:
 

Picture of Al DeMaria:
 
Picture of Claude Suhl:
 
At the end of the first week there are a few more arrivals, Bill Kemsley(?), following the directions left with Jim Paul to &quot; Don&apos;t bring food, bring beer &quot; actually packs in two cases of beer instead of food and declares himself a ward of the camp. About this same time Roger Chorley of Himalayan fame, where he also contracted polio leaving him with only one fully functioning leg, showed up as well.

After about two weeks of escapading about the Bugs,with the weather deteriorating, the VMC party departed for the Tetons. Without knowing it many US climbers had fallen in the ways of the old trapper parties who used to rendezvous annually in Jackson Hole at summers end. So the &quot;boys&quot;, although initially side tracked into the Jenny Lake camp ground, soon discovered that the party was in full swing at the old CCOC camp. There, a bunch of hard core California climbers including Yvon Chouinard and Ken Weeks were living in the old abandoned ovens and pushing the envelope with new difficult rock routes. In fact Chouinard was just recovering from a rather nasty fall off a new line he and Weeks (?) had been pushing on the Broken thumb. He&apos;d zippered a bunch of pins on an overhanging section of the route kissing the rock with his knee when he swung into the wall as Weeks caught him off the last pin. They then proceeded to self rescue, bushwacking down in the dark, a particularly painful experience for Yvon when the occasional branch would whack him on his newly insulted knee. Needless to say the Vulgarians were impressed.
Although there wasn&apos;t a lot of climbing that got done, a couple of rock climbs on Disappointment and Black Tail Butte, the Climbers camp was great. There, there was much partying and palavering as well as trips into Jackson Hole. Jackson in those days of yore was still a sleepy western town. A place where at noon you could practically go to sleep on Main street and not have to worry about getting hit by a car; old dogs moseying along, the occasional cowboy, the odd citizen and almost no tourists.

Art Gran leading in the Tetons:
 

In addition to the Yosemite crew, the Vulgarians also met the climbing Rangers who manned the Jenny Lake ranger station and saved the odd climber and/or lost hiker. Pete Sinclair, Dave Dornan, Sterling Neal, etc. were a bunch of very decent guys and outstanding climbers with a &quot;live and let live&quot; attitude towards the goings on at Climbers camp. Ultimately it was time to leave. Time to get back to school.&quot;

 
 

 
 

 Bill Hutchins 

 Trad climber Maryland 
 Oct 31, 2008 - 06:57am PT 
This thread is just wonderful! Geno, please post more of the Vulgarian notes. I started climbing in the Gunks back in the 60s and find the notes a treat to read. How cool it must have been for a bunch of kids from NYC to climb in a car, drive to the Bugaboos and encounter Becky and Kraus and then meet up with Chouinard in the Tetons. 
 

 
 

 bob d&apos;antonio 

 Trad climber Taos, NM 
 Oct 31, 2008 - 07:16am PT 
Amazing Geno....way to go. 
 

 
 

 GOclimb 

 Trad climber Boston, MA 
 Oct 31, 2008 - 07:45am PT 
Very cool!

Geno (or others who know) - would Kraus have been on friendly terms with the Vulgarian crew by then, after they&apos;d been climbing in the Gunks for a full season or two?

Would they even likely have known the other party was going to be a the Bugaboos?

GO 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Oct 31, 2008 - 09:50am PT 
I&apos;m reading Claude&apos;s wonderful account of the early Vulgarian days with interest and delight. I was still a teenager just getting into climbing as the Vulgarians were forming and was certainly not a part of the group. My first encounter with them occurred in the old climber&apos;s camp in the Tetons, a place that used to be at the epicenter of Americian climbing, not so much because of the Teton climbs themselves but because over the course of a summer, nearly every active climber in the country seemed to pass through the climber&apos;s camp on the way to or from adventures in other ranges.

Except for what one would nowadays call minimal instruction from a few Exum-guided climbs, I learned about climbing on my own, primarily from books. (And hoo boy, there were some doosies back then. The AAC published a handbook by Kenneth Henderson that recommended such bombproof techniques as the knee belay---don&apos;t ask...and the there was Charles Wilts&apos; book called, I think, &quot;On Climbing,&quot; that expounded still on the virtues of nailed boots over &quot;rubbers&quot; and included such tie-in esoterica as the Tarbuck Knot.) Anyway, my impressionable adolescent psyche had been deeply influenced by the purple pro---uh, the lyrical writing---of Gaston Rebuffat. From his books I learned about the beauty of the mountaineering experience, the brotherhood of the rope, the necessity of being fashionably attired at all times, and the imperative that under no circumstances was the leader ever to allow the perfect geometrically vertical lines of his rope to be broken by pictorially distracting protection points.

Thusly stuffed to the gills with matching-patterned-sweater-and-knicker-socks idealism, I made my way to the climbers&apos; camp. Oh, the horror! The place was infested with badly dressed, apparently unwashed, and thoroughly unkempt vermin, drinking, copulating, disrupting Teton Tea parties, roaring around the loop road in their Triumphs, sounding the Vulgaraphone, and indulging in all manner of activities impossible to carry out in woolen knickers. I feverishly consulted my copies of Neige et Roc and Etoiles et Tempetes (you don&apos;t think I would deign to read bad English translations of The Master, do you?) for protective incantations against these alpine demons, no doubt the same ones feared by the early peasants venturing into the heights for the first time, now somehow transplanted from Chamonix to Jackson, screaming like the hounds of hell in the throes of the feverish blood lust stimulated by the scent of my dry-cleaned climbing outfits.

As I cowered behind Orrin Bonney&apos;s teepee, watching the End of Days in progress before me, I realized that the apocalypse had arrived, probably during my AP Calculus class, and that from now on Fire and Brimstone would be replacing Starlight and Storm. Still, I managed to cling to one eternal verity: these were not Real Climbers.

No way. 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Oct 31, 2008 - 10:11am PT 
We all choose different things that we allow to affect us. Many were much affected by the &quot;White Spider&quot;, a book I never encountered. The French ascent of Annapurna alpine style affected me.

When you get into marginal situations, invariably the dangers begin to roll up and multiply. When your fingers get too cold to button your coat you have to choose to let core temperature drop long enough to get your hands working. When you have not got the strength to remove your crampons, you know you are sacrificing your feet to frostbite.

If you choose to visualize it this way, climbing can be nothing other than you and your relationship with a rock. The rock has no feelings. It is neutral. You own it all. if you manage it properly and think ahead things don&apos;t tend to roll up.

The rock and you both come out ahead. 
 

 
 

 rbob 

 climber 
 Oct 31, 2008 - 10:13am PT 
wow! makes the bugaboos these days seem like a a fully-furnished alpine crag... oh wait...

 
 

 
 

 Alan Rubin 

 climber Amherst,MA. 
 Oct 31, 2008 - 10:25am PT 
It should be noted that rgold&apos;s incantations to The Master had little long term effect, as soon enough he too was &quot;corrupted&quot; by the Vulgarian ethos---and spread it to Devil&apos;s Lake where he infected a yet newer generation of innocents---such as myself----must&apos;ve been the Teton Tea!!!! 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Oct 31, 2008 - 01:09pm PT 
Yes, as Al mentions, only a few years later I went over to the Dark Side. But it should be noted that, as was the case with so many of the 60&apos;s revolutionaries, the Vulgarians almost universally ended up as conventionally successful members of society. I remember Dave Craft, owner-manager of The North Light restaurant, shaking his head incredulously and saying, &quot;I just threw out a bunch of guys acting just the way we used to act!&quot;

One can&apos;t help wondering whether the Vulgarians weren&apos;t, in some sense, the creation of the conservative forces that fueled their rebellion, and that when they eventually ``won,&apos;&apos; they extinguished the foil required for their outlaw identities and so simultaneously lost both the context and pretext for their activities.

A few historical observations about Claude&apos;s account. I&apos;m fairly sure it was Bob Kamps, not Ken Weeks, who caught Chouinard&apos;s 160&apos; fall on the North Face of the Crooked Thumb. It was many years before the route was completed, I think by Pete Cleveland and Don Storjohann. Ken Weeks was, I think, hiding out from the FBI in the climbers&apos; campground. He was AWOL from the US Army and had no intention of going back. The climbing rangers knew about this and looked the other way, but the FBI tracked him to the climbers&apos; camp anyway and Weeks was arrested by supervisory ranger personnel.

 
 

 
 

 Alan Rubin 

 climber Amherst,MA. 
 Oct 31, 2008 - 01:33pm PT 
It was Cleveland and Storjohn who finally finished the Crooked Thumb route in 1966. One other factoid about Chouinard&apos;s fall is that he was wearing a swami belt (a few wraps of 1&quot; tubular webbing around the waist usually knotted with a bowline on a coil--with no leg-loops--the rope was then either tied -in directly to the swami or clipped on with a locking biner), which was at the time an avant garde technique--most climbers simply tied-in by wrapping the rope directly around the waist. Chouinard attributed his lack of internal injuries to this system--appropriately, it seems--so that this eventually became the normal method of tying-in for a number of years (with various modifications to add leg-loops to the system for some)until decent harnesses became available in the early &apos;70s. 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Oct 31, 2008 - 01:39pm PT 
Now I never heard of tying a swami with a bowline on a coil. The rope yes, not the swami. After we started using a swami we used what looked like a follow-thru fisherman&apos;s.

Still do. 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Oct 31, 2008 - 04:57pm PT 
Glad you all enjoyed Claude&apos;s stash of pictures and the journal. It may be a rough draft but it&apos;s enjoyable to read what those college boys dared to do. Thanks to Rgold, Al Rubin and Jstan for filling in some of the blanks. Here&apos;s another couple pages:

&quot;Vulgarian Chronicles jugernaught [continued]

Fall: The fall of 59 saw the first climbing death in the Shawangunks. A fall on High Corner. It was pretty shocking, but even more shocking was the use that the AMC attempted to make of it. Apparently increasingly unhappy with the activities of the &quot;independents (e.g. Vulgarians primarily)&quot;, the AMC saw this as an opportunity to regain the power that they seemed to feel slipping away. On the other hand the Vulgarians were feeling rather feisty as they now included many of the best climbers and they had also survived their first encounter with &quot;serious&quot; climbing, i.e. the &quot;mountains&quot;.

Here&apos;s an early bouldering photo.
 

Claude Suhl
 

Uberfall crowd.
 

In addition to ignoring the strictures that the AMC attempted to place on them, a new weapon now emerged, the &quot;Rave&quot;. The Rave, a term probably coined by Craft who sort of used it as his &quot;War cry&quot; at the very loud drunken Saturday night parties that began to take place. These parties, often accompanied by makeshift musical instruments, such as metal guard railing, logs and an assortment of plumbing remnants, were used to drive the AMC crazy and out of their traditional nesting ground at the Wickie -Wackie camping area, which the Vulgarians then took over as a sort of war trophy. Not content with driving the AMC from Wickie-Wackie, the Vulgarians continued to occasionally harass the poor buggers at whatever place they chose to camp. It was unconventional and asymmetric warfare at its best.


December: Winter attempt on Wall Face Al D, Gran, Geiser, Suhl. Packing in on snow shoes to sleep in a lean-to in the artic cold. Upon awakening in the morning with the temperature about -10F and a snow covered wall in front of them, discretion seemed the better part of valor, so they backed off and spent the remainder of the day in the New Paltz bars.

1960
Craft moves to California
1961
Summer:
Yosemite Climbing Camp 4, Arches, Washington Column. Lost Arrow with Chouinard.
Suhl on Lost Arrow:
 
[note: This photo may actually be Dick Williams who was known for his gymnastic athleticism and for doing handstands in improbable places. I will ask Claude].
 
Suhl and Geiser go to tetons via Rail (Death) and Preacher Jim. Climbers camp and return.

Fall: Chouinard makes the eastern scene. Arriving without any visible means of support other than a chest full of his new chromoly pins, Yvon sells them like hot-cakes to the local climbers. Holy cow! And Great Gugamuga! A piton that you can use more than 2 or 3 times and that doesnt take 15 minutes of pounding to remove! It was a whole new world. Whoever said the East is the east and the West is the west and never the twain shall meet. Couldnt have had it more wrong. The west bringing high technology to the east and the east recriprocating with some classically steep climbs, Vulgarianism and several great Raves including one that that culminated with one of the most spectacular Auroras that anyone had seen, and Yvon was made an ex-officio member of the VMC. &quot;

More to follow...



 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Nov 1, 2008 - 03:29am PT 
All,

The &quot;Vulgarian Chronology jugernaught&quot; from Claude Suhl I have been posting is slightly different than Dick Williams&apos; Climbing History that is published in his: The Climber&apos;s Guide to The Shawangunks. One must really read Dick&apos;s history along side this rough draft. Dick Williams does a fabulous job describing the Vulgarian Era in the context of climbing in the Gunks and in American mountaineering.
So if you can, review: The Cimber&apos;s Guide to The Shawangunks, The Trapps, by Dick Williams, p 15-22. 2004.

 

The best price I found is at the Rock and Snow site:
 http://www.rockandsnow.com/store/product/2987/THE-CLIMBER%27S-GUIDE-TO-THE-SHAWANGUNKS%3A-THE-TRAPPS/ 


It is also contained in his earlier guides.
 
 

 
 

 wack-N-dangle 

 Gym climber the ground up 
 Nov 1, 2008 - 04:45am PT 
amazing thread 
 

 
 

 Don Lauria 

 Trad climber Bishop, CA 
 Nov 1, 2008 - 08:20am PT 
The Original Vulgarian
John Hansen
1937-2005

By Don Lauria

I met John Hansen in the fall of 1961. We were both working as engineers at North American Aviation in El Segundo, California. I had just returned from vacation and my first excursion to the summit of a Sierra peak. The traditional routine was to pass around any photos from ones trip for all to see. One of my colleagues, upon returning my box of slides, mentioned he knew a guy in the Computer Department who was an avid mountaineer and asked if he could show the slides to him. I said okay and a little later he returned with John Hansen.

Hansen was not too tall, maybe 5 9, but very wide, very fit, built like an ape. He had a New York accent, a cauliflower ear, a mischievous laugh, and a great gift of gab. He immediately needed to know of my entire personal mountaineering history (which at that moment involved a single non-technical Sierra peak). He asked if I was interested in learning to climb. I asked if he meant with ropes and stuff. He answered that, of course, ropes, pitons, ice axes, crampons - all that stuff! I replied that he must be kidding I was definitely not interested. He insisted I go with him to Stoney Point and do some bouldering. Bouldering? I politely said no. He insisted. I said no again. He questioned my sense of adventure and suggested the coming weekend would be ideal for my introduction to rock climbing. For more than 15 minutes he parried my refusals. His persistence won out. That weekend would change my life.

I drove 35 miles to the San Fernando Valley where John lived with his wife and infant son and arrived at 7:00 AM, as agreed, to find him still in bed. He came to the door naked. Oh man, sorry. I overslept. Come on in. Ill be ready in a minute. He returned to the bedroom. I could hear an infant crying and his wifes complaining. He had obviously forgotten to tell her of his plans. He immerged from the bedroom wearing a beige wool sweater, brown corduroy knickers, mountain boots, and a navy blue beret. Come on, lets get something to eat.

We stopped at an IHOP for pancakes. Johns beret and knickers got a few looks as we entered, but I was so absorbed in interesting and enthusiastic conversation about rock climbing, I soon forgot the stares.

I spent the entire Saturday climbing at Stoney in a pair of Johns mountain boots two sizes too small for me. He took me around the entire area, climbing everything in sight. By the end of the day I could barely lift my arms. I was exhausted - but was I stoked!

That evening at Johns apartment, he found a not-so-dear-John note from his wife she had packed up and left with child. Seemingly unperturbed, John filled me with Gerwurztraminer and tales from his Vulgarian Shawangunks days. Well into the evening he talked about mountaineering famous European and American climbers and climbing history. He pulled six mountaineering books off his shelf and insisted I take them home and read them. By the time I got home I was already planning my next weekend at Stoney Point.

I climbed four more times with John at Stoney Point, and then, on New Years Day 1962, he took me out to the Devils Backbone on Mt. San Antonio with my brand-new boots, brand-new ice axe, and brand-new crampons. He tied me into a 9mm rope and told me to take a running leap off the ridge down the steep north face to practice a self-arrest. My first attempt ended abruptly at the end of the rope. I had not only failed to slow my descent, I had forgotten to put on my brand-new leather gloves which left all the knuckles on both my hands bereft of skin. My second descent, with gloves, was successful and I figured that I had mastered the art no need to do that again. My life as a mountaineer had begun.

John was a gregarious sort and he introduced me to many well known climbers including Yvon Chouinard, Bob Kamps, and several of his Vulgarian buddies like Jim McCarthy and Art Gran.

One November evening in 1961, we visited Chouinard in his little room in back of his parents home in Burbank. It was Yvons 23rd birthday. The evening could have been a bit more cheerful, but Yvon was due to report for his pre-induction physical the next morning and was not happy about it. However, Yvon had a plan. He heard that a sufficient amount of soy sauce consumed prior to a physical exam could raise ones blood pressure to 4F levels. So John and I went out and bought a six pack of eight-ounce bottles of soy sauce and returned to watch Chouinard down as many as he could stand. The birthday party ended and later that week a very sick Yvon was inducted into the U.S. Army. The experiment had failed and Yvon ended up in Korea for two years. Yvon mentions this happening in his new book Let My People Go Surfing.

John and I climbed together just a few more times at Tahquitz Rock and in Yosemite through 1964 and then saw each other on mostly social occasions, some of which were memorable - and somewhat Vulgarian. Like the night he and Dave Huntsman went out in Daves VW to try out Johns new small caliber pistol. After attempting to shoot out a few street lights, John accidentally fired a round into his calf and refused to go to the emergency hospital fearing the required police report. Later, Dave forced him to seek treatment. Then there was the night at a small gathering in Daves home. John was challenged to an arm wrestling contest with a complete stranger at the kitchen table. After many seated minutes of stress and strain without an apparent winner, the two adversaries, still locked in combat, rose to their feet and fell across the kitchen table breaking the tables legs and careened into the matching chairs doing irreparable damage to them also. It took three of us to pry them apart and three years for Mary Huntsman to forgive him.

It was in the early 70s that Johns profession became more important than his passion and after his second marriage to an assistant district attorney, he quit engineering and the sciences to become lawyer himself. A few years of individual practice tending to needy clientele and he realized he could not afford the profession. He quit law and returned to science. We remained distant friends for the next 41 years until his death in 2005.

Though not an exceptional climber, John was an exceptional person. He was an engineering physics graduate from Columbia University, a champion collegiate Greco-Roman wrestler, and a fierce liberal - politically and socially. He had the strength of an ox and intelligence bordering on genius. He could overhaul automobile engines as casually as he discussed celestial mechanics. He was conversant in the calculus of variations, a connoisseur of fine wines, and generous to a fault.

Im relating this to you because, although few people have heard the name John (Jack) Hansen in connection with climbing or mountaineering, after all these years, I discovered something about John that he never shared with me something that should be known. Something that should be part of climbing history.

Most of us that climb, or have climbed, have heard of the Vulgarians the outrageous Shawangunk climbing cabal of the late 50s and early 60s. Heres a little history from the gunks.com website - an excerpt from a conversation in August of 2004 with Dick Williams, one of the early Vulgarians and one of the many reputable climbers to come out of the Gunks:

Dick Williams - So, that particular morning we were all at the base of Never Never Land and [Jim] McCarthy is trying to do the direct finish. So anyway hes up there - I dont think Id ever belayed anybody before - it was my first time, so Id been watching some people belay and theyd belay over the shoulder with the rope under your armpit, like this, you know.

Interviewer - Wow.

Dick Williams - And Jims about to do this final bit and he looks down and he sees how Im belaying. And he says, You dont belay someone my weight like that. I said, Ok. and just dropped the rope. If you dont like it, get somebody else to do it. Everyone goes racing to the rope. Jack Hansen gets a hold of the rope and puts him on belay. Jack Hansen was the guy who coined the phrase, the Vulgarians - he gave us that name.

Interviewer- He puts him on hip belay, right?

Dick Williams - Body belay, yeah. So Jim goes up, sure enough he falls and that big tree thats there now was just a little sapling and the rope was behind it and it really broke the thing. John didnt let any rope go through his hand - he probably [held] about a 30-footer.

So now you know what it took me 41 years to find out. Not only was Hansen a Vulgarian, John Hansen was the original Vulgarian.




 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Nov 2, 2008 - 09:40am PT 
Don, Thanks very much for your post! It is a really fine contribution to this thread and to our understanding of the history of the Vulgarians. Jack Hansen was quite a unique and interesting individual. Geno 
 

 
 

 Steven Amter 

 climber Washington, DC 
 Nov 2, 2008 - 12:03pm PT 
Wow, its really great, and important, that the pieces of the early gunks history/Vulgarians are being perserved and posted. Facinating! Hats off to Grossman for starting the thread, and all the great posters, particularly those who lived it. Big thanks to Geno for keeping it going.

way to go! 
 

 
 

 Mighty Hiker 

 Social climber Vancouver, B.C. 
 Nov 2, 2008 - 06:08pm PT 
More Shawangunks stories and photos, please! 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Nov 2, 2008 - 08:08pm PT 
For THE IDLE RICH, In earlier sections of this thread is a photo you took of a climber leading Coexistence scanned from the Dick Dumais Shawangunk Rock Climbing book. Everyone thinks the person is Barbara Devine. For twenty plus years I have wondered if that was correct. I always thought it could be Spaff Ackerly? Can you shed any light on the subject? From another Rich. 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Nov 2, 2008 - 10:10pm PT 
Uh, Rich, Rich has already said it was Ackerly.

---Rich

The Gunks has, for some time, had an embarrassment of Riches. 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Nov 2, 2008 - 10:45pm PT 
One year, McCarthy went out on a 90 degree 90% humidity windless summer day to do what anyone seeking a break from the oven-like conditions would do: burn the brush around his house. So he takes a can of gasoline, saturates a large area of brush, waits a bit for the fumes to fully envelop the area, and then, standing in the middle of it, lights a match.

Measurements taken later of the take-off footprints and landing butt-print suggest that Jim was then and probably still is the world&apos;s record-holder for the standing backwards broad jump.

After weeks of non-stop celebration of this feat of athletic prowess, hosted by the Columbia Presbyterian burn unit, Jim emerged, somewhat pinker than before, and also, thanks to enforced incactivity and hospital cuisine, just a tad on the heavy side. For his rehabilitation activity, he decided to join a group of us in the Needles in South Dakota.

Unfortunately, the Great Designer had not considered, when drawing up the Needles nubbin-load specifications, that anyone of Jim&apos;s post burn-unit avoirdupois would be entrusting their considerable heft to those tiny crystals. And so it was that the pine forests of Custer echoed with the snap, crackle, and pop of nubbins giving way under Jim&apos;s attempts at upward progress. Entire faces were left glassy smooth by his repeated efforts, mostly in vain, to find something to stand on that would hold him up long enough to take the next step.

And let us now speak of those who undertook to belay Jim on these forays into the realm of pinnacle-polishing. Imagine them seated on top of the spire du jour, sitting on a cushion of ever-so-unpolished Needles granite, like mystics on their bed of nails, awaiting that hemorroidal impact as Jim&apos;s footholds sheared, eyes beseeching the heavens for a quick end to the suffering they were about to endure.

Both the Needles and his partners were saved from extinction by the fact that the rehabilitation effort was successful, Jim&apos;s weight melted away, the nubbins stayed under foot, Jim rose up as in the days before, and all was right with the world again.

And yes, his brush problem was, at least for a while, solved. 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Nov 3, 2008 - 02:59am PT 
Rgold, you are a master of visual imagery in telling the story of Jim McCarthy burning bush around his house. Jim was certainly a survivor of many harrowing adventures, some of which as you confirm were of his own doing.

Those who know Jim McCarthy will attest that he has many admirable traits that are revealed in his climbing as well as in his relations with others. Jim McCarthy was at the fore front of free climbing and mountaineering in America. He actually started climbing years earlier than the independents. Although he embraced them and is widely known as a member of the Vulgarians, Jim McCarthys climbing career actually spans from his association with Hans Kraus in the early 1950s to his present day leadership in access and other climbing causes. Here are a few notes that Art Gran wrote about Jim McCarthy in the first Climbing Guide to the Shawangunks, American Alpine Club Press, 1964, pages 17-18.

The year was 1951, and a small group from Princeton arrived at the cliffs. One of the beginners mistakenly got paired with a much better climber; they set out to do Baby and, of course, the beginner would had to be hauled up. The leader never realized that the beginner would take this as a personal challenge. Jim McCarthy was there to stay. Jim worked his way up the scale with his close friend, Jim Ewing. While climbing at Sleeping Giant in Connecticut, Ewing took a leader fall, dislodging a rock which struck and killed him as the second was checking his fall. Jim was on another climb and did not see the accident. Crushed by the death of his close friend, he was forced to decide just how much climbing meant to him. The news of this reached Hans Kraus, and it reminded him so much of a similar catastrophe which had happened to his closest friend when they were climbing together in Austria, that he went out of his way to befriend Jim.

Jim, who had little, if any, equipment, started using the best, which Hans readily supplied. But Hans gave him much more than pitons and Karabiners; he taught him climbing lessons gained from years of climbing in the mountains under all conditions. This was the start of the golden age in the Shawangunks. In the a relatively short time, Jim became the best climber in the area and, together with Hans and their small group of friends he put in many of the prettiest routes on the cliffs. His small band made him a legend by convincing the AMCs best climbers that he was climbing at a much higher level than they could ever reach. Actually his climbing was a shade higher; however, he was putting in the bulk of new routes.

The fall of 1958 saw the next major milestone: Retribution was put in on lead, using one stirrup., and a new higher standard was reached, heralding in the modern age of the Shawangunks. Never Never Land advanced the standard even further. Then Jim McCarthy put in his greatest classic, M.F. which achieved the top of the scale and stood at the dawn of a still higher standard. This new higher standard was reached in 1962 with the climbing of Retribution [5.10] without aid, and soon after that other very difficult climbs were done free.
 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Nov 3, 2008 - 05:30am PT 
Thanks RGOLD, That info from THE IDLE RICH must be on some other page. (Coexistence photo)
 
 

 
 

 the idle rich 

 climber Estes Park, CO 
 Nov 3, 2008 - 09:03am PT 
Good eyes rich...you&apos;re probably the first person that picked out that climber as spaff ackerly and not barb devine. 
 

 
 

 Alan Rubin 

 climber Amherst,MA. 
 Nov 3, 2008 - 01:18pm PT 
I&apos;d just like to add a few additional comments on Jim McCarthy&apos;s significant role in US climbing. For us old-timers it is often easy to forget that newer generations of climbers, or even those from other regions, might not be aware of the contributions of those figures who played important roles in the history and development of our sport. In the Gunks, Mac played a (and often &quot;the&quot;) key role in the advance in standards of every grade from 5.8 to 5.10+(read would be 5.11 in alot of areas). And much of this was done during a time and in a place, where even the idea of advancing standards was viewed by many in the then local climbing establishment as almost subversive. He was also one of the first to train in the gym specifically for climbing. His climbing achievements weren&apos;t limited to the Gunks as he claimed important new routes in other east coast areas such as the Adirondacks and Seneca Rocks. In the west, relatively early in his career he made the first ascents (with aid) of the North and West Faces of Devil&apos;s Tower, and with Hans Kraus and John Rupley made the first ascent of the West Face of the then legendary Snowpatch Spire amongst other significant climbs. At a later stage of his career he organized an expedition, at the behest of the American Alpine Club, to bring the then-new Yosemite bigwall techniques to a remote alpine area resulting in the first ascent of the East Face of Mt. Proboscis in the Cirque of the Unclimbables in Canada, following this up a few years later with the first ascent of the classic line on Lotus Flower Tower in the same area. During the same time period he participated in the now much-discussed, but then top-secret, CIA expedition to Nanda Devi in India. He has long been very active in the American Alpine Club, serving as its president during an important period of transition, and always working to make the club to be truely representative of and of service to American mountaineers. Existing alongside these (and other) accomplishments, he also has somewhat of a reputation for being accident-prone. In addition to the fire &quot;mishap&quot; described by Rich, he is well-known for certain dramatic leader falls. The most famous occurred in the Gunks, when he was caught by the rope just as he touched the ground at the feet of a newly-arrived, for his first visit to the Gunks, Yvon Chouinard. Mac&apos;s first comment upon regaining his breath was to say to Yvon &quot;Welcome to the Gunks&quot;. Oh, and with all this he had a highly successful career as a civil trial attorney in Manhattan. For those of us climbing in the Gunks in the 60s and early 70s (and those of the 50s generation as well)Mac was The Man. It was great to see and chat with him during the reunion last month and I look forward to seeing him at future gatherings. 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Nov 5, 2008 - 02:08am PT 

Al,

Thanks much for the eloquent summary of Jim McCarthy&apos;s climbing career. He was and is a leader in every way. As you said, besides his accomplishments in climbing, he also had a very successful professional life as a trial lawyer in New York. He was a great example to all of us of how to balance a career with climbing. Jim was a significant mentor to several generations of Gunks climbers. And Jim is a giver. He is always willing to help a friend (or a friend of a friend). He is still very active in the American Alpine Club giving his time. He has committed his life to climbing.

I wish I had a few pictures of Jim McCarthy from the 1950s and 60s. Here is one I like from the late 1970s showing a very fit McCarthy in the Sawtooths. From left to right:
John Ross, Unkown, Laura McCarthy and Jim McCarthy:

 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Nov 5, 2008 - 02:22am PT 
Art Gran authored a Climbing Guide in 1964. It was the first guide book for the Shawangunks. Imagine climbing in the 1950s and early 1960s at this rather large climbing area and the names and descriptions of climbs were passed around mostly through word of mouth. There were likely some notebooks that were passed back and forth among Appalacian Mountain Club and college mountaineering club members. But in those early days, being able to find your way around and to lead climb in the Gunks must have been a big deal indeed.

Art Gran was the first mentor to the CCOC climbers (Claude Suhl, Roman Sadowy, Pete Geiser, and Al DeMaria). He had an important influence on the group and early on Art helped them buck prevailing AMC certification requirements. Before I continue with Claude&apos;s manuscript, I thought I&apos;d insert a couple more paragraphs from Art Gran&apos;s, A Climber&apos;s Guide to the Shawangunks, Published by the American Alpine Club, 1964, pp 18.

&quot;When I started climbing in the Shawangunks, the AMC had reached the high point of its training program by the introduction of qualified seconds training. At this time, the AMC would have sixty people registered on a weekend, the colleges would have about eight and there would be three independents. These figures soon rose to 100 AMC, fifteen college and four independents. Although I had experience, I started from the bottom working my way up the scale with the Club. However, the Club did not have enough leaders who were willing to participate in its elaborate training program, the whole thing was starting to bog down, and my progress was so slow that I decided to come up in the late winter on my own. I first came with Lester Germer and later with my new friend, Howard Friedman. Although I continued on the Club&apos;s program and eventually became an unlimited leader (which meant I could pass other people as leaders for the Club).

In 1957 I started bringing up a number of beginners from the City College Outdoor Club. When we climbed together, we did not do so as part of the AMC trip; this more or less started the growth of the independent movement, and it soon mushroomed to gigantic proportions. The original group, known as The Vulgarians, did not discourage outsiders from participating, but welcomed anyone who could take it. Thus, the independent climbers eventually became the largest single group in the area, which very much changed the entire atmosphere.

Here is a picture of Art Gran from Shawangunk Rock Climbing, Richard Dumais, Chockstone Press, Denver, CO, 1985, page 54


 

The Gran guide published in 1964:

 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Nov 5, 2008 - 03:00am PT 
The Vulgarians are legendary for more than just their climbing prowess. They were committed to having fun at night. From the accounts shared with us by the members of the Vulgarian Panel at Rock and Snow last month, most evenings at the &apos;Wickie Wackie&apos; Campsite ended in the wee morning hours. The Vulgarians also had a fascination with cars and driving them fast. Here is another account from Claude Suhl&apos;s material:

&quot;The Vulgarian Chronicles jugernaught [continued]

[Summer 1959]

Another element that got introduced here was night time &quot;tower climbing&quot;. The most exciting tower climbing was at Minnewaska as this would involve running the gate (which was generally unmanned at night) with a car containing the climbing party. The party would be dropped off in the general vicinity of Minnewaska water tower and then the driver would speed back down the mountain before the guards could get themselves organized. Meanwhile the climbing party, often with a sixpack or two as supplies, would whisk themselves up the metal ladder of the tower.

Typically this could all be done with little fear of detection as Minnewaska and Mohonk had fallen on hard times and there were very few guests, particularly at Minnewaska. The first couple of times this was done, simply getting up and out undetected was satisfying enough. However after a while it began to seem that being completely undetected was taking much of the sport out the venture. Consequently after everyone was on the catwalk at the top of the tower it would become irresistible not to make some sort of noise that would bring out the gendarmes. This produced even better entertainment as from the ground it was quite difficult to tell where these strange seemingly inhuman sounds were coming from. The result was that the watchers on the tower got to see the confused wandering lights of the guards futilely looking for someone or something on the ground. It seemed to beggar the imagination that these night noises might be coming from the top of the tower, but they were.

Tower climbing was becoming a regular source of nightime fun until one fine night one of guards did figure out from whence the noise came and lo and behold found a bunch of strange people hanging out on the top of the water tower. This might have had something to do with the presence of Gary Hemming among the tower party. Hemming liked to keep his life as exciting as possible and as I recall was in particularly fine fettle that night. When the tower climbers heard that the state police had been called, it was decided that now was a good time to be leaving. Despite the kind invitation extended by the Minnewaska guards to hang with them until the police arrived, the climbing party of some 7 or 8 semi-drunken individuals figured that the cops weren&apos;t going to see all the humor in the situation that they did and so they bid a fond adieu to the tower guardians. Actually it wasn&apos;t too fond as the carbinieri made some minor physical attempts to detain the miscreants.

A rapid descent of the mountain now seemed to be in order. There was also the matter of the pickup car as no one wanted to walk the 4 or 5 miles back to Wickie-Wackie. The pick-up car would be cruising around looking for us within the next 20 to 30 minutes. To further add to the fun, the tower guardians had gotten into their guard-mobile and taken off after the tower climbing party. This seemed to make the hotel access road a poor descent choice. So it was into the woods for some night time bush wacking. Eventually the party reached the highway, now all that they had to do was somehow remain undetected by their pursuers, who by this time included the state police, and hail the pick-up car whose driver of course had no knowledge of how entertaining the evening had become.

As walking along the highway was no longer an option due to the presence of both the Statz Polizei and the Minnewaska gendarmes, it was decided to take to the woods. This seemed to be working out alright as the ascent party managed to elude the searchers initial passes along the road. Then salvation suddenly appeared imminent with the arrival of the pick up vehicle. There was a quick dash from the bush to the road to hail the car and then a quick dash back into the woods when the law suddenly appeared, still cruising to locate the miscreants. The stopped pick up car was a dead giveaway of course. And while the ascent party had made it back to the woody shelter, they hadn&apos;t made it very far back. So that when the searchers started sweeping the woods with search lights, the jig was up despite some attempts by one or two of party members to try and convince the investigators that we were just fagged out party goers resting innocently in the woods on the way home. The affair actually ended fairly amicably, the driver of the get away car who was of course unlicensed, got a ticket and everyone else got some sort of warning. Then on the other hand what was a State Cop going to do with eight or nine guys that he found in the woods at one o-clock in the morning? Tower? What tower?&quot;
 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Nov 5, 2008 - 08:16am PT 
This is THE STUFF!!!!! Thanks for posting it, Geno. I was going to post the material from Chris Jones Climbing in North America on the Vulgarians but I have been buried lately. This is the history that makes the ST a magical place and Duke Geno has the wizard&apos;s touch! Awesome work everyone! I can&apos;t wait to soak it all in! 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Nov 5, 2008 - 08:34am PT 
The climbing environment in an area can be created or changed in an instant. One
moment that helped form my perception of the Gunks was a comment by a climbing
lawyer, whom I will not name, just after winning a tort case.

He said, &quot;Once more, justice has been defeated.&quot; 
 

 
 

 Alan Rubin 

 climber Amherst,MA. 
 Nov 5, 2008 - 10:02am PT 
I feel like I&apos;m doing a history tag-team with Geno and Rich G., but it is worth supplementing the info Geno posted on Art Gran. Gran was another very significant Gunks character during the 50s and 60s, but always seemed to be something of an &quot;also-ran&quot; to more famous contemporaries. He was very much a stereotypical New Yorker--complete with heavy accent and a pushy perhaps somewhat abrasive personality. He established numerous new routes in the Gunks, many of them of considerable difficulty and quality but not quite at the same level as those being established by McCarthy and, later, Williams.Like most climbers of that era Gran still viewed the Gunks as training for the &quot;real mountains&quot;, and focused considerable energy into establishing new routes in mountain environments. He was the driving force in the first ascent of the VMC Direct on Cannon Mountain in New Hampshire (the first &quot;big-wall&quot; route in the east), and also made significant climbs in the west and in Canada. Routes such as the North Face of Monolith in the Wind Rivers, the East Face of Bugaboo Spire, and the West Face of Mt. Brussels and his route (Mt. Geike?)in the Ramparts, both in the Canadian Rockies, were early examples of difficult technical climbs in alpine environments, but as in the Gunks, these routes were unfortunately overshadowed by those established during the same time period by contemporaries such as Becky and Chouinard.What is particularly interesting about Gran&apos;s mountain routes is that he established most of them with various Vulgarian partners (particularly the youthful John Hudson, sadly lost much too young in the Andes), basically weekend climbers from New York climbing during vacations from work and school, in contrast to his &apos;rivals&quot; who were then virtually full-time climbers living within easy reach of the mountains. Gran had an interesting relationship with the Vulgarians, as he was to some extent one of their early mentors but was also often the butt of their jokes(find,if you can, some of Joe Kelsey&apos;s classic satires--accident reports, Gunks guide, Vulgarian Digest--for examples of this). Perhaps Gran&apos;s most significant accomplishment, as Geno stated, was the first published guidebook to the Gunks. This slim red book is now a collector&apos;s item, full of idiosyncratic writing, poor puns, transparently disguised Vulgarian route names (the book was published by the American Alpine Club, so proper decorum had to be observed), as well as essential information for the onslaught of new climbers who arrived at the cliffs in the mid-60s. Gran abruptly dropped out of the climbing scene in the late 60s or early 70s, rumor had it that he became the guru of a hippy commune someplace in the Catskills. Someone I spoke to at the Reunion, I think it was Barb Devine, reported running into Gran in a supermarket a number of years ago, and that he reported that he was doing carpentry at that time. I&apos;d love to hear if anyone has more up-to-date information. He surely deserves more recognition by the climbing-community at large than he has received to date. 
 

 
 

 Don Lauria 

 Trad climber Bishop, CA 
 Nov 5, 2008 - 02:48pm PT 
Yes, Art Gran took his share of kidding about his famous descriptions of hard moves on his latest climbs. Always with animation and total re-enactment , sans rock.

I first met Art at Stoney Point in Southern California - a bright Sunday afternoon with a large Sierra Club contingent in attendance. I was there with Jack Hansen (the original Vulgarian) and Yvon Chouinard.

We were bouldering at Boulder #2 and Gran and I had just climbed a steep route on the west side. We dropped the rope to Yvon and he tied in. For whatever reason (it was a very nice day), Yvon was wearing a full length heavy wool overcoat a thrift store bargain. It was buttoned closed from bottom to top. When he signaled that he was ready to climb, Gran whispered to me, Grab the rope. Lets pull him up. So, the second Yvon yelled, Climbing, the two of us hauled. In a matter of seconds Chouinard was on top gasping for breath and laughing nervously. He literally had not used any of his extremities in the ascent. His overcoat had spared his body from abrasion, but in the dynamic contact with the sandstone the coat had lost all of its buttons.

Gran was in stitches. Yvon had stopped his nervous chuckling. He was untying and seriously inspecting his damaged coat. I quickly explained that it was all Grans idea sorry about the buttons, Yvon. Chouinard was no longer amused, but Art, still laughing uncontrollably, had dropped to his knees and began rolling around the top of the boulder. Yvon and I left Art with his rope and downclimbed to the road.

As we trudged toward our next objective, Chouinard was mumbling and staring down at the front of his coat, feeling the texture of the abraded material. Glancing back at Boulder #2 - Art was still on top coiling the rope and still laughing. Chouinard looked back and mumbled something about hyenas and burros or was it jackasses?
 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Nov 5, 2008 - 04:23pm PT 
Probably a prank that, in the long term, had unintended consequences. 
 

 
 

 TradIsGood 

 Chalkless climber the Gunks end of the country 
 Nov 5, 2008 - 04:29pm PT 
Don, that is too funny! 
 

 
 

 Alan Rubin 

 climber Amherst,MA. 
 Nov 6, 2008 - 06:21am PT 
I&apos;d described Gran&apos;s personality as &quot;somewhat abrasive&quot;, Don&apos;s story shows that it was literally so!!!!! 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Nov 9, 2008 - 03:46am PT 
Here is a contribution from Claude Suhl on Art Gran:


&quot;As Al DeMaria stated @ R&amp;S;[Rock and Snow Panel Discussion on 17 Oct 08], Art was instrumental and our fearless leader and mentor- not only because he had a car but because he really relished and honored that role.
In fact he used to call us his &quot;boys&quot; - like as if he was Jesse James and we were his &quot;boys&quot; - his gang. He liked being referred to as &quot;dad&quot; - in what was then a prevalent kind of Jazz hip formalism.
There existed in those times a bunch from Pittsburgh - the Pittsburgh climbers aka &quot;Gebhardt and his boys&quot;. One of them was a girl (actually a woman who was an MD - I think - Kay was her name) who was quite possibly the most adept climber of them. The &quot;boys&quot; from Pittsburgh, an explosive and competent bunch, whom we frequently met at Seneca Rocks were a unique and rowdy clan who favored using dynamite in their 4th of July celebrations! Now that was a real treat - dear to my heart - but that is another story for some other time.

I still, to this day , when faced with some fearful consternation in the midst of a climb will find some of his [Grans] sound byte admonitions running through my mind - such as &quot;always have at least 3 points of support&quot; or &quot;the leader never falls &quot; or others that are more appropriate and effective, and not passe - even to this day and that are not easily verbalized but are more of an attitude that is always valid.
My first western trip and also that of Roman, and Pete Geiser was in Art&apos;s light-green and white Rocket 88 Oldsmobile with western veterans Art and Dave Craft.
No Interstates yet - we switched off driving - gear filled part of the back seat and all of the trunk - three sat abreast up front -one of the two in the back had to sit on the floor part of the time. As we Rocketed down two lane empty highways towards the setting sun at 85 mph we could actually observe the gas gauge needle dropping!
7 miles to the gallon. The tank was big AND the car felt like a tank - but high speed. As each &apos;newbie&apos; took the wheel a tirade of harassment, directions to follow and &apos;advice&apos; was leveled by those still able to stay awake. After a brief stop to repair some minor thing in a sleepy South Dakota town , where we waited and rested in the parking lot of a garage until it opened at 8AM - we headed out to the prairie. We were very tired all so decided to pull off the road and catch an hour or two of sleep. As we spilled out of the car and tossed our sleeping bags on the edge of an infinite grassland some local cops pulled up in their black and white. They rolled down the window and slowly, in the manner of the west, prepared to elicit some signals from us that might aid their comprehension-or perhaps to inquire were we OK.
Art quickly moved into his position as diplomat, negotiator and maker of all things well:
he walked over to the cop car and earnestly petitioned in his Brooklyn accent &quot;hey, is it alright if we sleep on YOUR LAWN ?&quot;.

He had a need to inflate or promote himself when in the presence of others whom I guess he felt the need to impress such that he was a setup fall guy for all kinds of mockery BUT whenever anyone actually climbed with him, particularly if it became serious , Art was just the greatest - he was right there - proving himself in a low key manner with his actions and being self effacingly exuberant when things went well - and always super supportive of anyone having difficulty keeping up with him.
Art and I once tackled the North Ridge of the Grand Teton { I now refer to this route as the North Ridge of THE GRAN } We got caught in a freezing sleeze storm that coated the rock with a thin layer of frozen snow and ice - right at the crux-which is just a few hundred feet from the top. He lead up comfortably and competently - I managed to follow over a bulging chockstone in a big chimney by hanging on some old pins - the pins had sharp burrs from many eons of ball peen hammering (Art was a tool and die maker machinist mechanical engineer ). The burrs cut my hands and blood was freezing to the rocks. Frozen hands stop bleeding real quickly and we groveled on happily to the summit and down.
Later when we exhorted to climbing ranger Pete Sinclair he said &quot;you had a REAL alpine adventure, eh?&quot;. Yeah, we were proud.

Eventually , I think, Art felt ostracized and drifted away from climbing concurrently with those feelings. He started an ultimately very successful high end contracting company.
He lives and has lived for many years on Ashokan Road in the town of Olive Bridge or Marbletown, within 10 miles of the Gunks. I frequently ride my bike past his house. I last saw him and spoke to him perhaps 15 years ago. If he re-emerged now, I am sure he would find himself very comfortable with all of his old acquaintances but then again- I don&apos;t know.&quot;

Claude Suhl with Art Gran in the Bugaboos, 1959. [Suhl collection]
 

Photo as the boys approached the Tetons in 1960.
 

 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Nov 9, 2008 - 04:54am PT 
Here is another email from Claude that adds some color to the City College Outing Club (proto Vulgarians) first forays to West Virginia in 1958:

&quot;last night Pete Geiser called , we are going over to one of his famous dinners at his New Paltz house tonight- he is here from Boulder.
I told him about those West Va pictures that look like a movie from the &apos;30s.
Turns out Pete recalls that we were with that car in a WVa junkyard because:
as we started our trip in NYC and began to drive to various neighborhoods and accumulate our personnel, at one stop we all jumped out the door to greet the latest person being picked up. Unfortunately, Horst, the driver and car owner , did not realize the doors were open. (In those days cars did not have those dashboard lights indicating such things) He commenced to backup AND
he tore one of the doors OFF !!!!!!
So we drove to WesT VA , I guess with the door tied on with clothes line or something.
After Pete reminded me of this factor , I began to reformulate an image of us driving around WVa with a dark dusty blue car with one prominent light TAN door.&quot;

CCOC members (Suhl, Horst, Sadowy, DeMaria) looking for a new door in WV in 1958 [Suhl Collection].
 

Making a deal with the Man at the Junkyard [Suhl collection].
 
 

 
 

 neebee 

 Social climber calif/texas 
 Nov 9, 2008 - 05:18am PT 
hey there geno... say, i thought this was a post with lots of pics, which it may well be--and that being wonderful, in itself... but 
i started at the back this time, and found these great shares you just did... (the article on art, first off, and the rest)...

i really appreciate hearing stuff on climbers of the past, as they are such inspirations and mentors, the likes of which we will not see again---being that climbing was not as common then, or perhaps accepted? and yet, they pressed onward, going by their heart, and fed many, in the process... as with any great mentor, they did HAVE to... it was just part of their passion, and who they were... 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Nov 9, 2008 - 05:21am PT 
Claude Suhl pens his take on The Vulgarians:


&quot;The Vulgarians, even prior to naming ourselves in New York street gang fashion [ name supplied by Jack Hansen - now deceased who brought Dick Williams up to the Gunks first in 1957 and drove a Triumph and moved to California in the late 60&apos;s]

the vulgarians were ULTRA-ALL-INCLUSIVE !!! our stated and enacted mission was to provide a safe haven for all and any Fraternity(or Sorority) rejects in particular-
although one could also be welcome if one had such affiliations [for example succesful lawyer McCarthy of Princeton - but McCarthy publically rejected membership in a Princeton eating club because a good friend of his who was Jewish was denied membership. Apparently at Princeton these &quot;eating clubs&quot; - I believe that is what they were called - were much more important than frats at other schools because if you didn&apos;t belong you had to cook your own food on a candle lantern in your dorm I guess] so we had nerdiest geeks like Bill Goldner from RPI and Yonkers, charismatic local natural baseball athlete descended from the former producer of the Hudson Valley&apos;s best apples - Dave Craft, local Gardiner lady Lynn Tosti , many visitors from Britain-Mike and Judy Yeats, Nick Pott,....- we had grade school dropouts - a person who earned his PhD in math from MIT before he was 21 [Jim Geiser]- future multi-millionaires and guy who skied with Jean-Claude Killy and sold a bikini to Joan Baez&apos; sister from his North Face store in north Beach, CA- Doug Tompkins,
too many eternal dirt bags to count - many veterans of scarfing food from the Yosemite Lodge cafeteria as a way of life and sustenance- Army veterans like Ralph Worsfold- West Point grad Army drop-outs like Garry Garret- communist sympathizers, civil rights activists, anti-Vietnam war protesters who after burning all their draft cards tried to lead a brigade to burn down a draft board, an arch traditional conservative who was an MIT Civil Engineer then Lawyer-Bill Ryan( although he originally was a very curious anti-Vulgarian - we co-opted him eventually I think he would confess) ...................................

to earn membership one merely had to be able to survive in the environment - if you kept coming back, why you were still there-thus you were one of us

the Vulgarians were and still are Egalitarians [i hope] - egalitarians with dirt bag roots [or dirt bag wannabe rub off patina] and a grubby grumpy edge
who had a lot of fun and have made a commitment to keep it up, eh? [perhaps some having had occasional lapses into seriosity and conformity]

why , Vulgarians pioneered stone UN-washed jeans
with holes in the ass and knees
way before Ralph Lauren was born
Vulgarians prowled the lower east side streets in big puffy orange down jackets beneath the towering walls of the steaming, huffing and puffing ConEdison powerplant on east 14th street
before Vulgarian protoge Doug Tompkins pioneered the North Face and now wealthy ghetto chic -lettes board the subways in their prominently North Face labelled down accoutrements.

some - like Bill Goldner and much later Don Whillans - tried to extend the Ultra-All -Inclusive aspect to cadging FREE drinks. At the recent dinner at the Mountain Brauhaus, Joe Kelsey at our table was having a little problem with the check, because of some mix up about that Mark Robinson had payed for him but from another table - joe earnestly stated that &quot;hey, I&apos;ll just pay for it again - I don&apos;t want to be a Bill Goldner&quot; - it all worked out fine BUT note the Goldner reference - Goldner&apos;s fame survives - he has a bill paying avoidance mechanism named after him with people still using this appellation to describe such behavior to this day.
Now Whillans is a whole other order of magnitude - he liked to be a bar fighter- he would face people down and gruffly insist they buy him beers - BUT Dave Craft - master of corrective coercion- stood Whillans down - [so did Gerd Thuestad, while naked, about some wool socks - but you will have to ask Burt about that story]-
anyway Whillans had to buy his share of beer - at least when craft was around.

Quite frequently besides night gatherings there were collective engagements at the base of climbs - lots of harrassment was manifested at times - whereby as someone was leading - particularly if they were starting to have trouble - those on the ground might start chanting and beating their piton hammers on the rocks in unison - it was frequently not a very quiet time. But there was also often a rope of two or three going off to just do a climb but , as you mentioned recently, there was always a huge gathering at the Uberfall to come back to.

..... what does it all mean?
I dunno - but it sure was fun&quot;

VMC Gathering in the 1960s [Suhl Collection]
 

VMC at Pocomoonshine. Left to Right: Claude Suhl, John Weichsel, Dick Williams, Al DeMaria, Brian Carey, and Roman Sadowy. [Suhl Collection]
 
 
 

 
 

 neebee 

 Social climber calif/texas 
 Nov 9, 2008 - 05:21am PT 
hey there geno.. say, as to one of your share bits here:
&quot;Art Gran authored a Climbing Guide in 1964. It was the first guide book for the Shawangunks. Imagine climbing in the 1950s and early 1960s at this rather large climbing area and the names and descriptions of climbs were passed around mostly through word of mouth. There were likely some notebooks that were passed back and forth among Appalacian Mountain Club and college mountaineering club members. But in those early days, being able to find your way around and to lead climb in the Gunks must have been a big deal indeed.&quot;

i just learned some more... will come back and do far more reading, when i can...

god bless to all, thanks for all the neat shares... 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Nov 9, 2008 - 05:38am PT 
Neebee,

As always, you appreciate the guiding spirit and wisdom of those who came first. These mentors like Kraus, Gran, and McCarthy led the way. There&apos;s a lot of stories that must be shared around the camp fire while they still can be. Someone may make sense out of it all someday, but for now they should be told.

I love what you write on ST. God bless you too Neebee.

Geno 
 

 
 

 MH2 

 climber 
 Nov 9, 2008 - 10:27am PT 
 


 
 

 
 

 hossjulia 

 Trad climber Eastside 
 Nov 9, 2008 - 10:48am PT 
I scanned through this and saw no mention of Dick Shockley (sr.)
can anyone tell us of his role in the Gunks scene, if at all.
I worked for Paul Ramer for a bit in the 90&apos;s. He came from the east and did some climbing there. Unless my memory is way off, he indicated he was part of the Vulgarians, probably in the mid to late 60&apos;s. By the time I knew him, he had quit climbing, focusing on his ski gear and family.
Anyway, does anyone have any good stories about Shockley&apos;s Lunge?

If I missed it in this thread, I&apos;ll look harder, thanks. 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Nov 9, 2008 - 01:59pm PT 
My apologies: HJ&apos;s question about Bill Shockley somehow got transposed to a question about Lester Germer in my mind. That shows how huge an effect Lester had on us. Since my post is out of context I deleted it. But yes, I had been climbing with Goldstone that morning and he was there on the ground also.

I think our loss has helped us to value the life we have even more.

Each day is a gift. 
 

 
 

 MH2 

 climber 
 Nov 9, 2008 - 06:39pm PT 
&quot;MH2, Nice old photo of climber on CCK. There is no caption of who it is? If the climber is MH2 I will take a wild guess at Matt Hale? If Matt took the photo my second guess is Dave Roberts.&quot;

The climb is Moonlight. The year is 1969. The photographer is Mike Warburton.

The climber was once mistaken for John Dill at an AAC affair in Manhattan, a talk by Doug Scott and Ken Wilson.

The climber also once house-sat for a Vassar Brothers Hosp ob-gyn whose wife remembered climbing with Roman Sadowy and he, the climber, drove a gravel road one day and the next morning entered the MD&apos;s garage to a smell of gasoline and discovered that the gas tank of his car had acquired a small hole. Rather than make McCarthy&apos;s blow-up look minor, the climber carefully hoisted the garage door and rolled his car out on to the driveway to await the dissipation of the spill.

I wonder why I never got an answer to those letters addressed to: Rich Perch, tent?

 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Nov 9, 2008 - 06:51pm PT 
Dick Williams on the back cover of North American Climber on the summit of Devil&apos;s Tower.The sign reads &quot;No climbing above this point&quot;.

 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Nov 10, 2008 - 04:44am PT 
Kevin Bein on the bottom and me on top. Uberfall. 1975.
 
Rich Romano, 1975.

 
Dave Rosenfeld and Matt Muchnick 1975.
 
Rich Ross 1975.
 
Rich Romano at Lake Awosting in 1976.

 
Mike Sawicky and Geoff Ohland at the Mohonk Mountain House, Late 70&apos;s.
 
Gunks crew in Eldorado Canyon 1977. Gary Garret,Kevin Bein,Dave Rosenfeld,Barbara Devine and Mike Sawicky.
 
 
Rich Romano bouldering mid 80&apos;s.
 
The same spot this year.
 
Rich Ross on Adair by the Sea. Acadia National Park,Maine 1985.
 
Another back cover of North American Climber.
 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Nov 10, 2008 - 10:39am PT 
The handstand on the Gnomon is by (of course) Dick Williams. 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Nov 11, 2008 - 04:02am PT 
Rich Ross,

Those are fabulous scans from the great 1975-80 era. You, and the other top Gunks climbers in your generation (Kevin Bein, Rich Romano, Bob D&apos;Antonio, Russ Raffa, Mark Robinson, Mike Sawicky,...and others)were again pushing the limits of difficulty and risk. Amazing how young you guys look! The other great thing is that you actually took some pictures! Thanks to Harvey Arnold, Bobby D and others there is a photographic record. Some of these photos as you revealed were published in Mountain and other magazines. I know when I started climbing in 1980 I was inspired by those early pictures of Henry Barber, Rich Romano and others climbing hard rock. 
 

 
 

 GOclimb 

 Trad climber Boston, MA 
 Nov 11, 2008 - 07:32am PT 
Regarding this pic: 

&gt;&gt;&quot;MH2, Nice old photo of climber on CCK. There is no caption of
&gt;&gt;who it is? If the climber is MH2 I will take a wild guess at
&gt;&gt;Matt Hale? If Matt took the photo my second guess is Dave Roberts.&quot;

&gt;The climb is Moonlight.

You&apos;re certain of that? It looks a hell of a lot like the middle of the flake on CCK.

GO 
 

 
 

 divad 

 Trad climber wmass 
 Nov 11, 2008 - 08:15am PT 
I also think it&apos;s CCK, especially with the roof above. I also matched some features with another picture. Sorry, I don&apos;t have a scanner. 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Nov 11, 2008 - 09:23am PT 
CCK 1975. Climber is me.
 
 

 
 

 scuffy b 

 climber On the dock in the dark 
 Nov 11, 2008 - 10:54am PT 
But MH2 has already been outed!

 Mighty Hoax from tiny A. Cairns grow 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Nov 11, 2008 - 11:25am PT 


 
 
 

 
 

 divad 

 Trad climber wmass 
 Nov 11, 2008 - 12:01pm PT 
That little bushy thing shows up in all the CCK pics as it does in MH2s&apos;. 
 

 
 

 Mighty Hiker 

 Social climber Vancouver, B.C. 
 Nov 11, 2008 - 12:49pm PT 
MH2 = Andy C. All clear? He lives in Vancouver, and no doubt can tell you himself about his connection with the Gowannashunks. 
 

 
 

 MH2 

 climber 
 Nov 11, 2008 - 02:32pm PT 
&gt;&gt;The climb is Moonlight.

&gt;You&apos;re certain of that? It looks a hell of a lot like the middle&gt;of the flake on CCK.

&gt;GO


The thing at the top of the photo is a tree, perhaps no longer there.

Thanks to Rich Ross for a great series of pictures. 
 

 
 

 divad 

 Trad climber wmass 
 Nov 11, 2008 - 03:25pm PT 
OK, if that is a tree, Moonlight it is. There are remains of a tree there, or was a couple of years ago. 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Nov 15, 2008 - 12:29am PT 
A little Gunks history compliments of Chris Jones Climbing in North America, 1976.

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

I had the pleasure of meeting Chris at the Nose reunion and what a fine man and lover of climbing history he is. 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Nov 15, 2008 - 01:48pm PT 
Mark Robinson on Red Tape 1979. Climbing number 54.
 
Rich Ross on Red Tape 1980. Photos by Rich Romano.

 
 
 
 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Nov 16, 2008 - 05:48pm PT 
Bump 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Nov 16, 2008 - 05:56pm PT 
Rich Ross just posted some heirloom shots of Red Tape. For those who didnt climb in the Gunks back in the mid to late 1970s, Rich Ross was one of the top Gunks climbers and personalities from that era. He is not as widely known as Russ Raffa or Rich Romano, but he is another guy with RR initials who could and did climb shoulder to shoulder with those stars. Rich Ross had a natural strength and grace. And, he had what we called back then a good head. Rich was one of those top 1% climbers who was able to keep it together when the moves were hard and protection difficult or absent.

Rich Ross in 1978:
 

Anyway Red Tape is a fabled hard route located on Mohonk land near Eagle Cliff. It is unusual for a Shawangunk Grit climb being it is an overhanging crack. At the time of the first ascent in 1978, Red Tape was one of the hardest, most pumping routes in the Gunks. A while back I asked Rich Ross about the first ascent of Red Tape. Here is what Ross wrote:

Geno, I think you asked in one of your emails about the first ascent of Red Tape. It is a climb that I discovered in 1978. I brought Rich Romano there. We did not know the first time there that we required a lot adhesive tape to keep our hands from getting torn up. The climb starts as laybacks leading to finger jams leading to hand jams, leading to fist jams that go up this offset crack. There are quartz pebbles in the crack the whole way up. It is very painful. Richie got up to the hand jams on the first day and would have done it then if he had taped up. We both had bleeding hands. The next weekend we planned to meet there. I was supposed to bring the tape and he was supposed to bring the tincture of benzine. I brought this not so big roll of tape. We did not have enough to do a good job and ended up opening the scabs we had had acquired the week before. The next week we came fully prepared and Rich cruised it. I got two thirds the way out but could not do it then. I learned how to crack climb on Red Tape. I thought of the name. This was in the fall of 78. I did not do it until the following spring. A few other people did it before me. I have a few slides of me trying do it the first day. Our friend Fred Yaculic was there taking pictures. I also have slides of me and other people doing it. I think I have done it 8 or 9 times. I call it meat-grinder 5.11+ or harder. That is the short history of Red Tape.

Rich Ross on Red Tape, 5.11d/5.12a
 

Vern Clevinger on an early ascent sans mechanical friends of Red Tape, 5.11d/12a:

 

Rich Ross ranged far and wide on the Shawangunk Ridge and was always looking around in obscure places for fine lines like Red Tape. Many of his first ascents were off the grid in hidden areas where the ethic was and still is to keep things quiet. Rich Romano often climbed with Rich Ross then. Romano told me that Rich Ross was one of the few people who was always motivated to make the hour hike out to climb at Millbrook. Ross-Romano Incorporated did dozens of first ascents together. At Millbrook, the pair put up several adventure routes which at their time were state of the art for difficulty and risk. Here are a just a few:
Artistry in Rhythm, 5.10 R
Danger UXB, 5.10 PG
Brown Bomber, 5.10 G
Asteroid Belt, 5.10 X
Diaper Man, 5.10 X

(Note that at Millbrook the grades are only comparable to places like Seneca Rocks).

Rich Ross also established some well known Gunks routes during the late 1970s. One is Land of Milk and Honey, a three star 5.11- at Sky Top. He also climbed The V, 5.12 which is an amazing route that goes through a series of improbable overhangs also at Sky Top.

Rich Ross on The V, 5.12:
 

But one of the very best routes Rich Ross did was Grave Yard Shift, 5.11, PG. Grave Yard Shift is not an obscure line, but a mega classic that is front and center on the McCarthy Wall. Here again in the words of Rich Ross is how the first ascent went down:

The funny thing about Graveyard Shift is that nobody knows how it got it&apos;s name. I was awake for over 24 hours when Russ Raffa and I climbed it. I was working for Cohen&apos;s Bakery in Ellenville at the time. I had worked the 12 midnight till 8 am (graveyard) shift. And then I drove straight to the cliffs that morning. I showed up at the Trapps and immediately ran into Russ. He said that he had tried a new route the day before on the McCarthy wall with Sandy Stewart. They had gotten up the first bulge and were working on the crux but had not done it. I don&apos;t know why Sandy was gone that day but Russ recruited me. I led the bulge and set up a belay below the crux. Me and Russ took turns trying the crux. We played around trying to get the nerve to go for it. At one point we got thirsty and took a break and went to the Brauhaus for some cold glasses of Pepsi. After that we returned and Russ did the lead of the crux overhang. I remember we had some other name we were considering for the route. But a few days later the name Graveyard Shift came to me. Raffa liked it too so we kept it.

Some other Rich Ross FA&apos;s at the Gunks:

Skytop (all left of the crevass):
Inflatable Girl (right of Mechanical Boy) actually just right of Strawberry Yogurt.
Juggernaut
Tor and feathered
Blockparty
Kashmir
Mystery Woman
Amazon

Trapps:
Dogs in Heat (Nerdie Gerdie) most people call it Nerdie Gerdie.
Nevermore
High Times
Daydream
Dat Mantle
Kernmantle

Rich Ross in 1979 style attire with Bob D&apos;Antonio after a session on Super Crack:
 


 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Nov 18, 2008 - 06:27am PT 
Here is a photo of me on the very first attempt at climbing Red Tape in 1978. It was taken by Fred Yaculic.

 
Rich Romano leading Rhumba Mama, 1980 gunks hinterlands.


 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Nov 19, 2008 - 11:17am PT 
Oakie, My memory is fuzzy but I think that is Fail Safe in the very upper right of this picture. The corner leading through hangs.

 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Nov 19, 2008 - 04:32pm PT 
Rich,

That&apos;s a great pic of you on Red Tape from 1978.

The best so far.

 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Nov 20, 2008 - 08:13am PT 
Sams Point, Shawangunk Ridge above Ellenville.
 
 

 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Nov 22, 2008 - 12:55pm PT 
Ron Kauk on Supercrack, 1976. Photo by Paul Baird.
 
Rich Goldstone inside cover of North American Climber.
 
Neil Pothier, North American Climber ad.

 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Nov 22, 2008 - 07:00pm PT 
Nice shot a few posts back of a dip into Enchantment Lake! And, arguably, the oldest artificial climbing wall in the USA.

Nice historical shots too, Richross. Where did you get them? 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Nov 23, 2008 - 04:51am PT 
Steve, I got the historical Gunks photos from my dad. He was into nature and the local history. Glad you liked them. Here are a few more.

 
 

 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Nov 23, 2008 - 09:24am PT 
Harvey Arnold whose excellent photos started this thread allowed me to put up a few of Rich Ross in my previous post (see above). 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Nov 23, 2008 - 10:06am PT 
Geno, Can you photoshop out that hat I am wearing in that one photo? I am afraid the fashion police might see it. That must be why Bobby D is smiling. Thanks to Harvey Arnold for the photos. 
 

 
 

 MH2 

 climber 
 Nov 23, 2008 - 10:08am PT 

Thanks to oakie and Steve. I didn&apos;t notice first time through that Prussik and UW Rock are the scenery for the photos of Fred Y. Fred is doing either Left Hand Face or maybe Timson&apos;s Problem. Just to his right is the hand and fist crack that was a big part of my jamming education after all that face climbing at the Gunks and Devils&apos; Lake. I&apos;ll have to put that learning to use if I ever end up in the vicinity of Red Tape, again.

Depending on when that Practice Rock picture was taken, about 30% of those foot impressions in the gravel could be mine. 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Nov 24, 2008 - 09:42am PT 
Vern Clevenger on Mellow Yellow in 1980.
 
Vern Clevenger on Red Tape 1980.
 
Jim Damon on Supercrack early 90&apos;s.
 

Owen Silver leading Amazon and Michael Peters, right on top of Scare City. Early 90&apos;s.
 
Marco Fedrizzi on Blockparty, Mid 80&apos;s.
 

 
Rich Goldstone inside cover North American Climber.
 
Chuck Calef on Arms for the Poor, early 80&apos;s.
 


Rich Romano on Flashpoint. 80&apos;s.
 
Barbara Devine on Foops Trap. Mountain issue no. 97 Photo Harvey Arnold.

 
Jim Munson on Tuff Lady, FA late 80&apos;s.

 
 


 

 
My turn on Tuff Lady, 3rd. Photos Rich Romano.
 
 
Climb just left of Tuff Lady.
)
 
 
 



 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Nov 30, 2008 - 09:31am PT 
This is the first photo of the fabled Supercrack that I can recall seeing in North American Climber November 1975.

 

The caption reads &quot;Looks like a hand eating jam crack, but Mohonk&apos;s Super Crack, Shawangunks, New York rates out at 5.11 and has ahd only one free ascent by Steve Wuncsh last fall. Photo: Paul Baird.&quot; 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Dec 3, 2008 - 09:42pm PT 
A little historical nugget from Mountain 21, May 1972. Bring back any memories? This was likely the first Gunks survey that saw international coverage. Any major magazine article on the Gunks come out earlier?

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 
Rich, DUDE!

 
 

 
 

 Alan Rubin 

 climber Amherst,MA. 
 Dec 4, 2008 - 09:20am PT 
Steve, There was really no major magazine to do international coverage before Mountain appeared in the late &apos;60s. It was the first climbing magazine that really sought the international market. Alpinismus (Germany) and Montage et Alpinisme (France)had somewhat earlier started a &quot;glossy&quot; modern-style format, but they were primarily focused on their national audiences. Mountain editor Ken Wilson very aggressively (and largely sussessfully) tried to establish it as the &quot;magazine of record&quot; in the climbing world. Ken was, and still is, very opinionated and out-spoken, viewing himself as the guardian of the purist British traditional approach to the sport. I remember him visiting the Gunks a few years after the article appeared and being very sarcastically critical of the number of fixed pitons then present on the cliff----though that didn&apos;t stop him from clipping each one he encountered!!!!!As for earlier articles about the Gunks, I presume that there must have been something in Summit---the only US magazine of the pre-Mountain era. It is also likely that one of the relatively frequent visitors from the UK wrote up something for one of the annual club journals that were/are a part of the climbing culture over there. But I agree that the posted Mountain articles were the first real international coverage of the Gunks and other New England areas. As a footnote, &quot;my&quot; article was actually written (and later published) as the historical introduction to Paul Ross&apos;s New Hampshire guidebook, which Paul then submitted to Mountain on his own without consulting me (not that I really minded). 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Dec 4, 2008 - 04:02pm PT 
Edifying as it is to be the encaptioned one, a respect for the truth obliges me to report that the Rich Goldstone in the photo soloing High E is not the Rich Goldstone I have known for now a bit more than 65 years. In fact, the intrepid soloist is Matt Hale, and the faux Rich Goldstone is not the soloist, but rather the fully-grounded photographer.

Just to keep my street cred intact (as if soloing an exposed 5.6 entitled one to any kind of cred in todays climbing world) the real Rich Goldstone had just finished soloing High E and took up his position as photographer in order to immortalize Matt Hale.

And now that I&apos;ve revealed this much, I might as well go all the way and mention that this particular conga line of soloists had at its head that Fall day the venerable Jim McCarthy, whose lustre is cetrtainly not dimmed by the fact that he is neither in the picture nor is entitled to any credit for taking it.

Finally, if all this unencumbered romping seems perhaps a bit too carefree, let&apos;s tip a glass to another frequent High E soloinst and dyed-in-the wool gunkie, Chuch Loucks, who, on the Southwest Ridge of Symmetry Spire, paid the ultimate price for his love of ropeless mountain travel. 
 

 
 

 MH2 

 climber 
 Dec 4, 2008 - 07:42pm PT 

Are you sure Chuck was ropeless? I was told, &quot;He ran it out 80 feet and then did a very un-Chuck-like thing. He fell.&quot; 
 

 
 

 Tarbuster 

 climber right here, right now 
 Dec 4, 2008 - 07:52pm PT 
&quot;let&apos;s tip a glass to another frequent High E soloinst and dyed-in-the wool gunkie, Chuck Loucks&quot;

Glass tipped!
In this case, an &apos;89 Chateau Meyney Saint-Estephe.
Hopefully worthy of the man. 
 

 
 

 TradIsGood 

 Chalkless climber the Gunks end of the country 
 Dec 4, 2008 - 07:56pm PT 
Hmm. Interesting history.

Inverted Layback shot is especially interesting. I followed that once and the rope went to the right, not up and left. I wonder if that is just a question of where gear got placed or actually a difference of where the route is currently climbed.

I remember it being strenuous, but not exceedingly so, given the grade. But a buddy of mine blew out a bicep at that spot. 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Dec 4, 2008 - 08:11pm PT 
 http://www.americanalpineclub.org/AAJO/pdfs/1977/inmemoriam1977_306-315.pdf 

CHARLES LOUCKS
1932-1976
Chuck was born in China, the son of American medical missionaries,
educated in the United States and taught in a Long Island school. For
the past fifteen years, climbing was his real vocation. Spring and fall
his habitat was the Shawangunks, though on long weekends he could be
found at Poco-Moonshine or the White Mountain cliffs. Come summer
he climbed mountains. He ranged from the Alps to the Brooks Range,
the Canadian Rockies to the Wind Rivers. He fed on gorp and glop and
could cook a one-pot feast under any conditions. He climbed gracefully,
smoothly, with a rhythm and balance always admired by onlookers. He
brought enthusiasm and puckish humor to every climb. On Easter he
was known to have climbed Bunny in the Gunks to distribute jelly beans
and a plastic rabbit. He shared his enthusiasm by introducing young
people to the sport and teaching them the wonder of the classic routes.

Essentially a private person, few people could say they knew him
well. Yet he was highly prized as a climbing, tenting, traveling or
bivouacking companion.
For several years he served as the New York representative of the
AAC and was a past member of the house committee. He was a serious
collector of Alpine literature and spent many evenings at the Club library
sharing his knowledge of the books and photographs.
Charles Loucks died of injuries sustained in a fall while climbing with
friends in the Tetons on August 27, 1976.
EARLYN CHURCH

 
 

 
 

 Tarbuster 

 climber right here, right now 
 Dec 4, 2008 - 08:15pm PT 
Thanks for that JStan.
He sounds like an outstanding fellow and now I know a little more about the man to whom I&apos;ve raised a glass. 
 

 
 

 cowpoke 

 climber 
 Dec 5, 2008 - 06:06am PT 
In the very cool article posted from Mountain, there are references to &quot;artificial&quot; climbs, e.g., for Cathedral it notes that there are both free and artificial climbs. Is this a synonym for aid climbs that is no longer used? As someone who didn&apos;t start climbing until the early 90&apos;s, the term conjures up images of glued holds and the like, but it can&apos;t be that...can it? If it is a synonym, i would love to know why it was dropped from the lexicon? Sorry for my ignorance, but I&apos;d never heard/read this term before. 
 

 
 

 Tarbuster 

 climber right here, right now 
 Dec 5, 2008 - 07:44am PT 
Yes: artificial = direct aid.
It&apos;s natural to climb directly upon the rock using your hands and feet!
And a woeful unnatural act to bang in pitons and stand on them using wrunged ladders and stuff.
Unless you were Kor and those of like ilk, for whom the real climbing only started when it got nasty, steep and artificial.

I don&apos;t know why it was dropped; aid also used to rank as sixth class, fifth being free climbing.
But this is mostly inference on my part, based on some of the prevailing knowledge when I started in the 70s, so we&apos;ll get some good historically accurate detail from the real guys in a few more posts perhaps.
 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Dec 5, 2008 - 10:53am PT 
The term comes from French for &quot;artificial climbing,&quot; escalde artificielle. Probably in use since the 1930&apos;s, and still the common term today in France, ``artif&apos;&apos; for short. 
 

 
 

 MH2 

 climber 
 Dec 5, 2008 - 11:20am PT 

Yes, I do remember Mountain 21. It was the first climbing magazine I bought though I got a few earlier issues later on. Number 15 did not list Al Rubin among the contributors (United States) as many later issues did.

I also remeber Denny Merritt&apos;s modest reference to being the centerfold of Mountain Magazine. Good job including the staples in your image.

And wasn&apos;t Chuck Loucks the one who carried a record-player to the base of Cakewalk to climb it to the music?

I only had one interaction with Chuck but it was an intense one and his quiet strength came across clearly.

&quot;an &apos;89 Chateau Meyney Saint-Estephe.
Hopefully worthy of the man.&quot;

Cheers


 
 

 
 

 Alan Rubin 

 climber Amherst,MA. 
 Dec 5, 2008 - 11:23am PT 
Chuck Loucks was one of the all-time nice guys in climbing----a gentle soul with a dry but excellent sense of humor. He was missing several fingers on one hand (don&apos;t know the reason), but climbed smoothly and solidly. My recollection is that he died in an unexplained, roped, but unprotected, fall on the Jensen Ridge of Symmetry Spire, a climb well within his ability.It was, and remains to those of us who knew him, a very sad loss. 
 

 
 

 klk 

 Trad climber cali 
 Dec 5, 2008 - 11:38am PT 
TB: &quot;Glass tipped!
In this case, an &apos;89 Chateau Meyney Saint-Estephe.&quot;


You&apos;re posting online while drinking that?

The French will be outraged. You&apos;ll be lucky to get them to sell you a jug of plonk after that admission. 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Dec 5, 2008 - 11:41am PT 
I stand corrected: Chuck died in a very long (80-100 ft) roped fall on easy ground on Symmetry Spire in 1976. Still not sure whether it was the Jensen Ridge or the SW Ridge. 
 

 
 

 the idle rich 

 climber Estes Park, CO 
 Dec 5, 2008 - 12:15pm PT 
Though before I worked in the Tetons, I&apos;m pretty sure Chuck fell while leading on the Jensen Ridge on Symmetry Spire...well within his abilities. I think he was climbing with the Westmacott&apos;s (don&apos;t quote me on this) and was not feeling well before they began the climb. I recall that there was speculation that he had some sort of episode that caused him to fall. I didn&apos;t know Chuck well but I remember that he had quite a repertoire of old climbing songs and wasn&apos;t hesitant to perform. I also recall the jelly beans on climbs and the time it rained, leaving a sticky residue on all of the holds. 
 

 
 

 Alan Rubin 

 climber Amherst,MA. 
 Dec 5, 2008 - 12:17pm PT 
Rich, Thinking about that solo of High E pic, wasn&apos;t there an &quot;almost&quot; on that or a similar occasion that brought an end to that period of group soloing in the Gunks? 
 

 
 

 Mighty Hiker 

 Social climber Vancouver, B.C. 
 Dec 5, 2008 - 01:15pm PT 
This thread - the whole thing, that is - currently takes me 4:18 to load, pictures included. Worth every second. 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Dec 5, 2008 - 03:16pm PT 
Vulgarian Steve Larsen right. Building stone circle with Gunks stone at his farm. We could have used a few more druids that day.
 
The end result.
 
 

 
 

 sween345 

 climber back east 
 Dec 5, 2008 - 04:34pm PT 
So...

These Gunks stone circles work as some kinda equestrian chick magnet? 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Dec 5, 2008 - 04:53pm PT 
Al, I&apos;m not aware of anything bringing an end to group soloing in the Gunks beyond the fading of the Vulgarians who used to practice it. It seems to be a tradition that passed as its practicioners left the scene---subsequent generations never took it up.

I certainly went on soloing for many years, but that day with Jim and Matt may have been one of the last times I went off for a group excursion, perhaps because I graduated to harder and harder stuff and such things are best done in isolation.

The group solos used to be a regular feature of the Vulgarian spring training, in which a large number of the easy routes were done in a day by a large and typically very jovial group who, the times being what they were, were not exactly buff from a winter in the climbing gym---there being no such thing. 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Dec 5, 2008 - 07:36pm PT 
The old lug a jug to offset the chug a lug in the off season, eh! Perfect place to solo. 
 

 
 

 Sewellymon 

 climber .....in a single wide...... 
 Dec 5, 2008 - 10:29pm PT 
rgold write, &quot;group soloing in the Gunks ....Vulgarians .... used to practice it. ... a tradition that passed as its practicioners left the scene---subsequent generations never took it up. &quot;

John Long and his So Cali cohorts brought the tradition to Joshua Tree and elsewhere in the early/ mid 70&apos;s

I&apos;d written B4 about the day (&apos;80ish) where Dave Evans, DT and others Pied-Pipered about 20 of us up Lower Zig Zag and Upper Ski Track to a summit party atop Intersection Rcok. Quite the Conga Line.. 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Dec 6, 2008 - 11:24am PT 
Vulgarians, all in a line
Eschewed ropes to get fit, double time
I may wind up shorter
Eighth or a quarter
But climbing round here, Ill be fine.
 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Dec 6, 2008 - 01:11pm PT 
A little Gunks piece from Wolkgang Gullich&apos;s bio, A Life in the Vertical, 1994.

 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Dec 8, 2008 - 03:50pm PT 
Mohonk scenes from 12/8.
 
 
 
 
Red Tape.
 

Here is a link to some Rich Romano related pics and story.
 http://mammutathleteteam.blogspot.com/2008/11/there-are-no-cracks-in-gunks.html 
 
 

 
 

 Rickster 

 Trad climber Pine Bush,NY 
 Dec 14, 2008 - 05:10pm PT 
RR, do you need to book a room and procure a guide to take photos of the rock while on hotel grounds? RC 
 

 
 

 TradIsGood 

 Chalkless climber the Gunks end of the country 
 Dec 14, 2008 - 07:08pm PT 
Nice photos, Rich! 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Jan 8, 2009 - 04:03pm PT 
Bumpity Bumpity Bump, this thread&apos;s been in a bit of a slump.

1983.

 

Mid 70&apos;s

 
 
 
 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Jan 8, 2009 - 05:47pm PT 
The ones I didn&apos;t lose.
 
 
 

Old Rock and Snow tee shirt after the fire.

 

.

 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Jan 9, 2009 - 06:05am PT 
Old Gunks pins.
 


 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Jan 9, 2009 - 04:53pm PT 
Rich Ross,

Great job keeping the fire burning! I will try to post some stuff this weekend.

Geno 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Jan 9, 2009 - 06:22pm PT 
Great job of threadstoking! Is that Clune in the top shot?

Edit: How many fixed pins have outright snapped or had the eye fail in the Gunks? 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Jan 9, 2009 - 06:40pm PT 
It&apos;s Richie belaying me. I&apos;m in the next three and then a young Romano age 17.

Who&apos;s this Clune?


 
 
 

 
 

 Mighty Hiker 

 Social climber Vancouver, B.C. 
 Jan 9, 2009 - 06:44pm PT 
There was an article in the New York Times on the Mohonk House as a weather station. Originally posted to http://www.supertopo.com/climbing/thread.html?topic_id=677446 , including similar stuff about Thoreau and Walden.

The station has been in exactly the same place since January 1st, 1896, and since then only five volunteer observers have been responsible for taking all 41,152 daily readings. The current volunteer is in his 34th year.

The station and its environs are virtually unchanged since 1896, and many of the original instruments are still being used. That, and the stability and consistency of the observers, makes it very valuable in terms of climate change.

Added to that, an extraordinary collection of phenological observations - essentially observations of natural history in the area. First birds, first snow, etc.

 http://www.nytimes.com/2008/09/16/science/earth/16moho.html 

Someday I hope to visit the Gunks, and will add a visit to the weather station to my list of things to do there. 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Jan 9, 2009 - 07:21pm PT 
 
 

 
 

 Tarbuster 

 climber right here, right now 
 Jan 9, 2009 - 07:40pm PT 
That&apos;s very nice RichRoss!
Your three photos upthread really showcase the elegance of Mohonk. 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Jan 11, 2009 - 03:06pm PT 
Out biking.

Kevin Bein and Rich Romano. Mid 80&apos;s

 

 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Jan 11, 2009 - 06:13pm PT 
 
Foops,1976.
 
 
 

 
 

 Alan Rubin 

 climber Amherst,MA. 
 Jan 12, 2009 - 08:53am PT 
Rich, Great photos----keep it up. I really like the photo of Kevin and Rich with their bikes. Even as fairly distant silouettes they are each recognizable!!!! Wish I knew more about some of the &quot;off the grid&quot; routes that you posted photos of. Guess I&apos;ll have to get back down to the Gunks some more next year and nose around a bit. 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Jan 12, 2009 - 09:40am PT 
THE IDLE RICH and Bobby D. Gunks reunion,Rock and Snow.
 
 
 

 
 

 Alan Rubin 

 climber Amherst,MA. 
 Jan 12, 2009 - 09:43am PT 
We all do still miss Kevin. One of the high points of the Gunks Reunion last Oct. for me was the chance to see and chat with Barb---it had been much too long. I wish I had the know-how and equipment to scan in old slides as I have some decent ones of Kevin from the &apos;60s and very early &apos;70s. 
 

 
 

 Alan Rubin 

 climber Amherst,MA. 
 Jan 12, 2009 - 09:46am PT 
You were posting the Idle Rich and Bobby D&apos; photo as I was posting my last comment. It is my balding head that also appears in that photo!!!! 
 

 
 

 MH2 

 climber 
 Jan 12, 2009 - 09:53am PT 
Looks the same as he did 30 odd years ago, around the eyes.


(Al, why not take some slides to a photo processor and let them do it?) 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber gunks,ny 
 Jan 12, 2009 - 02:40pm PT 
Harvey Arnold who took many great Gunks photos.Thanks Harv. Late 70&apos;s
 




 
 

 
 

 geiger 

 Trad climber Doylestown pa 
 Jan 12, 2009 - 05:59pm PT 
As an &quot;old time climber&quot; I started following this thread. I also remember climbing Ringwraith and looking over my shoulder to see the Mohonk house. Never finished the climb, but had my honeymoon there! Still wish I finished the climb! 
 

 
 

 Tomcat 

 Trad climber Chatham N.H. 
 Feb 17, 2009 - 05:10am PT 
I remember that day Geiger.Did your nipple recover fully?

We had no idea how to crack climb.After a year in New Hampshire I went back and sailed up it.The cams didn&apos;t hurt either.It&apos;s sad to think others can only enjoy that climb by being guided there now. 
 

 
 

 MH2 

 climber 
 Feb 17, 2009 - 12:22pm PT 
Good pictures, oakie. I very much liked Mohonk in the evening when the sun was low. I fooled myself one time into thinking that Goethe&apos;s last words were &quot;last light.&quot; A German-speaking woman from Poughkeepsie set me straight when she said that the pronounciation of that would be something like, &apos;leastest licht&apos;, whereas Goethe&apos;s supposed last words or word were/was, &apos;merlicht&apos;, or &quot;more light&quot;, if I remember rightly. Probably could be a bit of debate over which last words would be more appropriate.


Roughly 1970

 

 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Mar 21, 2009 - 09:47pm PT 
A few Gunks tidbits from Climbing December 1988.

 

 

 
 

 
 

 Wayno 

 Big Wall climber Seattle, WA 
 Mar 21, 2009 - 11:28pm PT 
Great thread! That is the Harvey Arnold that I met in the Tetons in &apos;79. Nice guy. We did the Exum together. I ran into him in Tuolumne years later. Anyone know how to drop him a line? 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Mar 21, 2009 - 11:33pm PT 
He posts as Harv here on the ST if I remember correctly. Go back a few hundred posts on this thread! LOL 
 

 
 

 Wayno 

 Big Wall climber Seattle, WA 
 Mar 22, 2009 - 12:42am PT 
You&apos;re right, Steve. I sent him a message. That is funny.Thanks. 
 

 
 

 SteveW 

 Trad climber The state of confusion 
 Mar 29, 2009 - 04:28pm PT 
Bump this ! 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Aug 31, 2009 - 08:28am PT 
The leaves are turning and I am given to pondering the Eternal Question. Where would you rather be on a balmy fall day than right here, dreaming along the carriage road?!? 
 

 
 

 MH2 

 climber 
 Aug 31, 2009 - 09:09am PT 
 Where would you rather be on a balmy fall day than right here, dreaming along the carriage road?!? 

Carriage road? Dreamy.

Shawangunk quartzite? Crystalline purity.

Getting from the one to the other? Deer ticks GAAAAAAAHH!!!!! 
 

 
 

 Chiloe 

 Trad climber Lee, NH 
 Aug 31, 2009 - 09:28am PT 
I got to the Gunks just a couple of times this year, less than I&apos;d hoped.
I&apos;m &apos;sposed to be back Oct 24 for a slide show at Rock&amp;Snow, plz save a few leaves.

 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Nov 14, 2009 - 10:08pm PT 
I hate the little suckers too! Fortunately there is very little brush between the road and the crags for them to hang in.

 
 

 
 

 T H 

 climber . . . not ! 
 Nov 14, 2009 - 10:57pm PT 
I wonder if Jimmy S saw this . 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Nov 14, 2009 - 11:14pm PT 
This Jimmy S?

 
On Swingtime. 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Nov 26, 2009 - 09:03pm PT 
A couple of Gunks articles from 1960. The first was written by Michael Borgoff (MisterE&apos;s dad)from Summit September 1960.

 

 

From Summit December 1960.

 

 
 

 
 

 Pate 

 Trad climber The Lost Highway 
 Nov 26, 2009 - 09:06pm PT 
&quot;Practicing&quot; 
 

 
 

 Alan Rubin 

 climber Amherst,MA. 
 Nov 27, 2009 - 06:40am PT 
Those articles are a wonderful snap-shot of the attitudes of the times--that climbing at places like the Gunks was merely &quot;practice&quot; for the &quot;real thing&quot; in the mountains. One major error in Borgoff&apos;s article, it wasn&apos;t Kraus who opened the Gunks to climbing but Wiessner half a decade earlier. 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Nov 27, 2009 - 01:55pm PT 
Ira Spring? Who let that glacier-slogging, view-camera-toting snow bunny loose on our quartzite? 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Nov 27, 2009 - 03:35pm PT 
Something to celebrate! The ultra precise, terribly careful, and oh so darned excellent rgold just loosened up a notch. Just a notch mind you.

Grab your socks! The ride of our lives has just become a prospect. 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Nov 27, 2009 - 03:46pm PT 
The giddiness of 66 is upon him! 
 

 
 

 Mighty Hiker 

 climber Vancouver, B.C. 
 Nov 27, 2009 - 04:47pm PT 
 Who let that glacier-slogging, view-camera-toting snow bunny loose on our quartzite? Shouldn&apos;t there be a &quot;volcano-plodding&quot; in there somewhere? :-) 
 

 
 

 Alan Rubin 

 climber Amherst,MA. 
 Nov 30, 2009 - 06:44am PT 
John, you are doing rgold--and yourself, less than justice. I remember evenings in New Paltz and Yosemite when the 2 of you had a number of us literally rolling on the ground in hysterics with your comedic exchanges.So maybe the &quot;ride&quot; is actually about to resume. 
 

 
 

 Pate 

 Trad climber The Lost Highway 
 Nov 30, 2009 - 09:50am PT 
400 posts on a single area- on par with the Arizona Appreciation thread, and that&apos;s a whole STATE that&apos;s FULL of rock!

This thread is a treasure chest. 
 

 
 

 Evel 

 Trad climber Slartibartfasts Newest Fjiord 
 Nov 30, 2009 - 11:30am PT 
Just got back to CO after spending all of November at the Gunks. First time there in 16 years! Fantastic weather all month long, sunny days and low sixtys. Still the same scene, friendly folks [mucho thanks to Mark and staff at the Brauhaus] awesome routes in every grade. Soon as I figure out how to post photos I&apos;ll do a TR Berg heil! 
 

 
 

 Geno 

 Trad climber Reston, VA 
 Nov 30, 2009 - 04:34pm PT 
Here is a photo of a few folks eating dinner in late Sep 09 at the Mountain Brauhaus. Lot of fun.

 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Dec 6, 2009 - 02:25pm PT 
Nice shot, Geno.
How long has the Brauhaus been in business at that location?

Cheers 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Dec 6, 2009 - 04:13pm PT 
Not a good sign. Jean and Trudy used to let climbers into the bar area only.

To what is this world coming? 
 

 
 

 hagerty 

 Social climber A Sandy Area South of a Salty Lake 
 Dec 6, 2009 - 04:40pm PT 
jstan wrote:
&quot;Not a good sign. Jean and Trudy used to let climbers into the bar area only.

To what is this world coming?&quot;

The descent into madness started some time ago. My partners and I ate in the main dining room many times from the late 80&apos;s onward.

 
 

 
 

 Pate 

 Trad climber 
 Jan 25, 2010 - 06:10pm PT 
jstan on Foops bump. 
 

 
 

 Curt 

 Boulder climber Gilbert, AZ 
 Jan 25, 2010 - 06:17pm PT 
Damn. I wish I did Foops before Skytop was closed to climbing. Oh well, at least I had a couple spectacular failures on it.

Curt
 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Jan 25, 2010 - 06:53pm PT 
A pointless reminiscence. Getting old I guess.

The Eastern Trade and all took many hundreds of times the effort that I put into the climbing itself.

My priorities must have been all screwed up. 
 

 
 

 Curt 

 Boulder climber Gilbert, AZ 
 Jan 25, 2010 - 07:57pm PT 
I think priorities have little to do with it, John. You, like Lisa, will always find a couple hours of work to fit into 15 minutes of spare time.

Curt
 
 

 
 

 happiegrrrl 

 Trad climber New York, NY 
 Feb 2, 2010 - 09:00pm PT 
Can&apos;t wait for spring to come..... and get back climbing again.(bump) 
 

 
 

 seth kovar 

 climber Bay Area 
 Apr 1, 2010 - 06:03pm PT 
 some - like Bill Goldner and much later Don Whillans - tried to extend the Ultra-All -Inclusive aspect to cadging FREE drinks. At the recent dinner at the Mountain Brauhaus, Joe Kelsey at our table was having a little problem with the check, because of some mix up about that Mark Robinson had payed for him but from another table - joe earnestly stated that &quot;hey, I&apos;ll just pay for it again - I don&apos;t want to be a Bill Goldner&quot; - it all worked out fine BUT note the Goldner reference - Goldner&apos;s fame survives - he has a bill paying avoidance mechanism named after him with people still using this appellation to describe such behavior to this day.
Now Whillans is a whole other order of magnitude - he liked to be a bar fighter- he would face people down and gruffly insist they buy him beers - BUT Dave Craft - master of corrective coercion- stood Whillans down - [so did Gerd Thuestad, while naked, about some wool socks - but you will have to ask Burt about that story]-
anyway Whillans had to buy his share of beer - at least when craft was around. 

bump for Dave, love that guy... 
 

 
 

 handsomegran 

 Trad climber Stone Ridge, NY 
 Jun 5, 2010 - 06:24pm PT 
Dear all who are interested in Art Gran. My name is Josh Gran. I am Art&apos;s son. I have been reading some of the information that is posted above, and I must say that there is much to clarify. I grew up on my father&apos;s climbing stories. I know all of them like the back of my hand.

First off, somebody mentioned that my father was a bit of an &quot;also ran,&quot; when compared to McCarthy and Williams. But if you look at the list of first ascents, Art Gran and Jim McCarthy are undoubtedly on the same level. Add to that my father&apos;s amazing contributions out west, especially in the Canadian Rockies, and I think the term &quot;also ran&quot; becomes not merely hyperbolic, but grossly incorrect, dare I even say slanderous. As far as Williams is concerned, he was the next generation, and indeed passed my father and McCarthy in Gunks climbing. My father had nothing but respect for Williams&apos; abilities, as well as McCarthy&apos;s, on the cliffs, and I KNOW he would be the first to say that both of them were incredible. As far as Yvon Choinard is concerned, he and my father were friends. Choinard&apos;s reactions to a prank are no reason to make gross generalizations about the man.

Furthermore, Art Gran never became a guru of a hippie commune. He is far too much of a loner for that. Why did he stop hanging out with the climbing community? If you have to ask that question, you do not know my father very well. He prefers the solace of a peaceful evening with his dog Fergus. What ultimately became of him? He created a successful construction company --Gran Custom Builders, raised an amazing family, and because of his &quot;somewhat abrasive&quot; personality, I am proud to truly know what it means to be dedicated to pursuing what matters most in life. I think people who base their opinions of others on secondhand accounts ought to seek out instead the person in question; go to the source. Art will talk about climbing until the seventh seal is opened. 
 

 
 

 MH2 

 climber 
 Jun 6, 2010 - 01:11am PT 
Thanks for your perspective, Josh.

The Art Gran Gunk&apos;s guide seemed perfect for the time. It added a lot of value to the climbs, giving them a personality, perhaps. Those were great days in the late 60s and the Gran guide was vital to them, at least for me. 
 

 
 

 Seth 

 Trad climber New York, NY 
 Jun 15, 2010 - 09:17pm PT 
Hey, I never post here at supertopo, but I climb in the Gunks and this is my favorite thread ever-- so many legends in one place. I also love looking at Gunks climbing photos so I hope if I bump the thread maybe we&apos;ll get some more!

Here are a few of mine:

 
 
Climbers on Horseman, a 5.5 that introduces new leaders to everything the Gunks is about: overhangs, traverses, and steep face climbing!
 Credit: Seth 
 
 
 
A nice couple I met named Saranne&amp;Jeff on the first pitch of Arrow.
 Credit: Seth 
 
 
 
A climber working through the wild crux of the second pitch of Nurse&apos;s Aid.
 Credit: Seth 
 
 
 
Climbers on the first pitch of High Exposure.
 Credit: Seth 
 
 
 
Me leading the second pitch of Airy Aria.
 Credit: Seth 
 
 

 
 

 lucander 

 Trad climber New England 
 Jun 16, 2010 - 04:33am PT 
Art Gran was present at a panel discussion about Gunks climbing in the 1960s and 1970s held at Rock and Snow in 2008. Jim McCarthy introduced Art as the oldest living person who has climbed at the Shawangunks. It seemed to me that his peers hold him in high regard as a climber and I am surprised that his groundbreaking use of aerial photography in a guidebook is not widely recognized.

D. Lucander 
 

 
 

 steveA 

 Trad climber bedford,massachusetts 
 Jun 16, 2010 - 05:06am PT 
Josh
I&apos;m glad to say I climbed with your father for a week, back in 1967. He cooked the supper and I did the dishes. For some reason I still remember how much he spiced up the eggs with some hot stuff.
I often wondered what happened to him. 
 

 
 

 Seth 

 Trad climber New York, NY 
 Jun 16, 2010 - 05:17am PT 
Art Gran put up a ton of climbs, many of which are among the most popular Gunks routes today: Strictly From Nowhere, Thin Slabs Direct... if his son is still reading I think he can stop worrying about his father&apos;s place in history. It is secure.

A few more pics:

 
 
The Fall
 Credit: Seth 
 
 
 Credit: Seth 
 
 
 Credit: Seth 
 
 
 
I don&apos;t know this guy, but he was super smooth.
 Credit: Seth 
 
 

 
 

 John cameron 

 Trad climber Denver 
 Jun 16, 2010 - 05:56am PT 
 
 
The Grand Traverse
 Credit: John cameron 
 
 
 
Belay
 Credit: John cameron 
 
 

 
 

 Seth 

 Trad climber New York, NY 
 Jun 16, 2010 - 07:34am PT 
Pointing at the roofs atop Modern Times, of course. 
 

 
 

 jstan 

 climber 
 Jun 16, 2010 - 08:02am PT 
Art&apos;s guide was unusual not only for the photography. The book was an interesting read.

With regards to the possibility of being an also-ran. I have climbed with any number of people each of whom made tremendous long term contributions. All were out there for the joy you get from simply running. 
 

 
 

 426 

 climber Buzzard Point, TN 
 Jun 16, 2010 - 08:14am PT 
Neat stuff. Anyone have details about DanO soloing Yellow Wall? I remember vaguely after he&apos;d come back from the east telling us about it but his tales of the Gun Club at NRG held us in a deeper rapture... 
 

 
 

 seth kovar 

 climber Bay Area 
 Jun 18, 2010 - 10:02am PT 
 
 Credit: seth kovar 
 


 
 

 
 

 Les 

 Trad climber Bahston 
 Jun 18, 2010 - 01:18pm PT 
Late to this thread, but what an amazing one it is! SO many amazing memories from my many days there. Can&apos;t wait to get there again soon. Thanks for all the amazing contributions to this thread! 
 

 
 

 sween345 

 climber back east 
 Jun 18, 2010 - 02:46pm PT 
Steve,

There&apos;s a couple of older pictures in the entry foyer to the Brauhaus which it says it was their 50th anniversary in 2005.
There is also a picture (likely from the 2008 reunion) there with head shots of about 100 of the attendees, all squeezed into the frame. 
 

 
 

 jogill 

 climber Colorado 
 Jun 19, 2010 - 06:40pm PT 
Josh, I remember your dad with affection and admiration. Great sense of humor. Please say hello for me.

John 
 

 
 

 handsomegran 

 Trad climber Stone Ridge, NY 
 Jul 4, 2010 - 04:33pm PT 
For some reason, I keep thinking about the hilarious concept of my father being the supposed leader of a hippie commune in the late 60s and early 70s! He definitely took a far different route in life. He ended up marrying Linda, my mother, who already had a son, my brother Liam. He built us a beautiful house over near Stone Ridge, which served as a great place to grow up, as well as a large museum for my mother&apos;s paintings. My father is a guru, but his lessons were and are always taught by example. 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Jul 4, 2010 - 06:31pm PT 
The first time I met Art Gran was in the Gunks in, I think, 1960. I had come up with another kid (Bud Lustenberger---what a name for a climbing enthusiast) who told me that there was climbing in the East; at that point I done a few climbs in the Tetons and thought that was the only place in America to climb.

The Gunks looked 1000 feet tall as we made our way along the base looking for someplace to climb up. It was a hot humid summer weekday and there appeared to be no one else there. Eventually we made our way to Three Pines (of course we had no idea what it was called), climbed it, and somehow found our way back to the Uberfall. There we encountered Art, who stunned us with a display of bouldering beyond our wildest imaginations at the time.

Then he offered to take us up a climb---Squiggles, as it turned out. Again, we were stunned by his smoothness and technique. This was a peek into a world of competence we had barely imagined.

A year later, I saw Art in the climber&apos;s campground at Jenny Lake. He was surrounded by Vulgarians who, to my high-school senior&apos;s eyes, were behaving scandalously. (I wrote about that encounter in this upthread post .) When I greeted him, his only reaction was, &quot;who are you?&quot;

Well, I had no idea who I was at that point. But a day later, I happened to have on the same clothes I had been climbing in at the Gunks a year earlier, and I approached Art one more time and stupidly asked, &quot;do you know who I am now?&quot; To which he replied, &quot;You put on some knickers and you&apos;re walking around.&quot; Having now been thoroughly squashed, I crept off to my tent, embarrassed that I had even imagined that a pair of knickers would have made me recognizable to a man of his stature and accomplishment.

I returned to the Gunks for good a few years later. My experience with Art notwithstanding, the Vulgarians were an inclusive group and welcomed me into the fold. By the mid-sixties, the original hard-drinking culture had been replaced by sex, drugs, and rock &apos;n roll, and Art was already really not part of that scene. Many of the original CCNY group were around but had already started to retreat from climbing.

There was never anything remotely like a hippie commune, with or without Art. For a while, Dave Craft, Claude Suhl, Elaine Mathews, myself and my wife at the time, Evy, shared a house in Tilson. The 1968 album by The Band, Music from Big Pink, was out and we called our house Big White. Evy and I had the third floor attic bedroom which we used on weekends. Claude and Elaine lived on the second floor and Dave on the first. The first two floors had their own kitchens. That&apos;s as close to a commune as things ever got, and Art had nothing to do with it.

Josh, my regards to your dad. I think I may have finally hung around long enough for him to remember me.

Richard Goldstone 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Aug 1, 2010 - 10:10am PT 
A curious blip on the radar screen...with guitars! From Climbing July/August 1982.

 

 
 

 
 

 Rick A 

 climber Boulder, Colorado 
 Aug 1, 2010 - 10:28am PT 
Great stories, great thread. 
 

 
 

 seth kovar 

 climber Bay Area 
 Aug 1, 2010 - 10:39am PT 
 
 
the long way around...
 Credit: seth kovar 
 

 
 Credit: seth kovar 
 
 

 
 

 seth kovar 

 climber Bay Area 
 Aug 1, 2010 - 10:44am PT 
 
 
on the way to the giants workshop
 Credit: seth kovar 
 
 

 
 

 seth kovar 

 climber Bay Area 
 Aug 1, 2010 - 10:46am PT 
 
 Credit: seth kovar 
 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Sep 4, 2010 - 09:39am PT 
Would someone please scan Art Gran&apos;s guide and post the history section? 
 

 
 

 seth kovar 

 climber Bay Area 
 Sep 4, 2010 - 11:56am PT 
 
 Credit: seth kovar 
 
 
 Credit: seth kovar 
 
 
 Credit: seth kovar 
 
 
 Credit: seth kovar 
 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Sep 11, 2010 - 12:22pm PT 
Thanks to Jim Phillips I can post this classic Paul Baird cover shot of Kauk working Super Crack.

 
Californian Ron Kauk on Super Crack, Shawangunks,N.Y. An area known more for its overhangs than for any other climbing feature, the Gunks has come up with quite possibly one of the hardest crack climbs in the country. Ron completed the second ascent of the route this past October.

As well as the news from Vern and Ron&apos;s excellent adventure!

 

 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Sep 13, 2010 - 07:44pm PT 
Phew! The humidity finally died down a bit. Here, some members of the Medicaid Climbing Team in enjoying one of those Gunks obscurities that they missed out on in their younger days.

 
 Credit: rgold 
 
 

 
 

 donini 

 Trad climber Ouray, Colorado 
 Sep 13, 2010 - 07:46pm PT 
Is that Bragg? 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Sep 13, 2010 - 09:21pm PT 
Yup. I&apos;m afraid I lied---they won&apos;t let him on the Medicaid Climbing Team just yet. It&apos;s up to me to carry the flag. 
 

 
 

 Alan Rubin 

 climber Amherst,MA. 
 Sep 14, 2010 - 06:39am PT 
Rich, What &quot;obscurity&quot; are you and John on? It looks somewhat familiar but I can&apos;t quite place it. Alan 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Sep 14, 2010 - 11:26am PT 
Day Tripper. A very full-value 5.8 in the Nears just to the left of Eastertime Too.

Bring yer small gear... 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Sep 24, 2010 - 05:28pm PT 
Since we have Mike Sawicky around, now maybe I can get a response as to what a &quot;Sawicky&quot; is with regard to specialized technique?!? 
 

 
 

 oldfattradguy 

 climber 
 Sep 28, 2010 - 01:07pm PT 
great old pics, here&apos;s some more from the &apos;80s, enjoy, todd:


more here:
 http://toddeo.smugmug.com/History/80s-in-the-Gunks/ 

skiing gunks style:

 
 
There was skiing too
 Credit: oldfattradguy 
 
cybernetic wall:

 
 
cybernetic wall
 Credit: oldfattradguy 
 
open cockpit:

 
 
Open Cockpit
 Credit: oldfattradguy 
 
down and out:

 
 
Down and Out
 Credit: oldfattradguy 
 
cybernetic wall:

 
 
Cybernetic wall, mid 80&apos;s
 Credit: oldfattradguy 
 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Sep 28, 2010 - 06:13pm PT 
Thanks to DanaB here is the history section of the 1964 Art Gran guidebook.

 

 

 

 

Of particular relevance is the discovery of the Gunks. 2010 marks the 75th anniversary of the Old Climb and the first season of Gunks climbing! We will be raising a glass to Fritz in short order!

...&quot;The Vulgarians&quot; did not discourage outsiders from participating, but welcomed anyone who could take it.&quot; Priceless! 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber 
 Sep 28, 2010 - 06:50pm PT 
Mike Sawicky.

Foops, 1976.

 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Sep 28, 2010 - 07:24pm PT 
The Soon-To-Be-Eatin&apos; Crows Nest or the Raptor&apos;s Perch?

Great shot! Really makes that roof look BIG! 
 

 
 

 richross 

 Trad climber 
 Sep 28, 2010 - 07:55pm PT 
Better luck a few weeks later.

 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Oct 21, 2010 - 08:22am PT 
Some shots of the 2010 Brauhaus dinner are posted on the 2008 Gunks Reunion thread!

 http://www.supertopo.com/climbers-forum/697229/Gunks-Reunion-2008 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - Jan 29, 2011 - 02:02pm PT 
Gunks bump looking for the Bob Murray shot on Slingtime if I remember correctly?

Anyone climb in the Gunks with Murray BITD? 
 

 
 

 Curt 

 Boulder climber Gilbert, AZ 
 Jan 29, 2011 - 07:39pm PT 
I think BobD did.

Curt
 
 

 
 

 howlostami 

 Trad climber Southern Tier, NY 
 Apr 6, 2011 - 06:34am PT 
Spring fever bump. 
 

 
 

 Steve Grossman 

 Trad climber Seattle, WA 
 Topic Author&apos;s Reply - May 13, 2011 - 06:54pm PT 
Gunks Bump! 
 

 
 

 Wei-Ming 

 Trad climber Atlanta, GA 
 Sep 18, 2011 - 10:19am PT 
These photos and history are awesome... Glad I stumbled upon it.

I&apos;m currently in New Paltz, working on a Gunks climbing documentary and am looking for archival film and photos! If any of you are willing to help out please let me know. Also, any tips or folks I should talk to, that is also a tremendous help.

Cheers,
Wei-Ming
WML230@gmail.com 
 

 
 

 Auto-X Fil 

 Mountain climber 
 Nov 26, 2011 - 11:58am PT 
Bumping political garbage off the main page. 
 

 
 

 A5scott 

 Trad climber Chicago 
 Nov 26, 2011 - 01:42pm PT 
great thread! love all the info and pics!

I love all the classic moderates at the gunks.

 
 
my climbing buddy/best friend self portrait on High E crux, me belaying
 Credit: A5scott 
 
 
 
Son of Easy O
 Credit: A5scott 
 
 
 
Climbers on Modern Times
 Credit: A5scott 
 
 
 
Me on Something Interesting
 Credit: A5scott 
 
 
 
Me on Retribution
 Credit: A5scott 
 
 
 
my climbing buddy on Slightly Roddey
 Credit: A5scott 
 
 
 
With my cousin... near or on Belly Roll
 Credit: A5scott 
 
 
 
Rap from Easy O
 Credit: A5scott 
 
 
 
winter climbing, back in the mid 90&apos;s
 Credit: A5scott 
 
 
 
top of Jackie
 Credit: A5scott 
 
 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Nov 26, 2011 - 11:24pm PT 
 
 
Millbrook Rap, Gunks
 Credit: rgold 
 
 
 
Cruise Control, Millbrook, Gunks
 Credit: rgold 
 
 
Cruise Control, Millbrook, Gunks
 Credit: rgold 
 

 
 
Westward Ha!, Millbrook, Gunks
 Credit: rgold 
 
 
Westward Ha! Millbrook, Gunks
 Credit: rgold 
 
 

 
 

 rgold 

 Trad climber Poughkeepsie, NY 
 Nov 27, 2011 - 05:22pm PT 
Bump for some new Millbrook photos I just added. 
 

 
 

 MH2 

 climber 
 Nov 27, 2011 - 07:36pm PT 
^^^^ Glad I saw them. 
 

 
 

 adam d 

 climber 
 Nov 27, 2011 - 07:59pm PT 
I love Millbrook! 
 

 
 

 seth kovar 

 climber Reno, NV 
 Dec 27, 2011 - 09:43am PT 
 
 Credit: seth kovar 
 
 
 
 Messages 1 - 459 of total 459 in this topic 

 
 Return to Forum List 
 
 Post a Reply 
   
 Our Guidebooks Check 
 &apos;em out!
SuperTopo Guidebooks 
 
Try a free sample topo! 
  
 
 Go 
 
 
 
 SuperTopo on the Web 

 
 
 
 Review Categories 
 
 Climbing Shoes Technical Backpacks Climbing Harnesses Climbing Helmets Belay&amp;Rappel Carabiners Quickdraws Rock Protection Gear Slings&amp;Runners Big Wall Gear Bouldering Gear Snow&amp;Ice Gear Approach Shoes Climbing Ropes Slacklines Avalanche Beacons 
 View All Categories 

 
 
 
 Recent Trip Report and Articles 
 The Psych Must Flow 
 Jul 10, 2012; 10:13pm Chossapalloza. Sedona Rocks! on Tour. (w/pics) 
 Jul 09, 2012; 6:30pm Steck-Salath photo TR, captions in 10 words or less 
 Jun 22, 2010; 4:49pm Thunderbolt to Sill: Palisades Scramble Redux 
 Jul 09, 2012; 5:52pm Keeler Needle- Blood of the Monkey VI, 5.12 -16 pitches F.A. Moser, Ness: May 28, 2012-June 6, 2012 
 Jun 08, 2012; 10:25am View more trip reports &gt; 
 Recent Route Beta 
 Bay Area Bouldering, California, USA, Rocklin (Deer Creek Park) 
 Bay Area Bouldering, California, USA, Jul 11, 2012 Incredible Hulk, Red Dihedral 
 High Sierra, California USA, Jul 11, 2012 Sentinel Rock, Steck Salathe 
 Yosemite Valley, California USA, Jul 10, 2012 Glacier Point Apron, The Grack, Left 
 Yosemite Valley, California USA, Jul 10, 2012 Sentinel Rock, Steck Salathe 
 Yosemite Valley, California USA, Jul 9, 2012 View more route beta &gt; 
 Recent Gear Reviews 
 Rab Stretch Neo - Hardshell Jacket
 Jul 12, 2012; 4:30am Totem Cam - Camming Device
 Jul 11, 2012; 7:39pm Montane Mohawk - Hardshell Jacket
 Jul 06, 2012; 10:43am Black Diamond Axiom 30 - Mountaineering Backpack
 Jul 05, 2012; 11:19pm La Sportiva TC Pro - Climbing Shoe
 Jul 05, 2012; 10:45pm View more gear reviews &gt; 
 
 
 Home | Climbing Areas | Free 
 Topos | Guidebooks | Route 
 Beta | Forum | Trip Reports | Photos | Articles | Gear Reviews 
 Gear Best Price Finder | Links | FAQ | Contact | About Us 

Climbing Areas
 Rock Climbing Yosemite | Big Wall Rock Climbing Yosemite | Rock Climbing Tuolumne | Rock Climbing Sierra 
 Rock Climbing Red Rocks | Rock Climbing Southwest | Rock Climbing Zion | Rock Climbing Tahoe | Climbing Alaska 
Copyright©2012 SuperTopo LLC
All trademarks property of their respective owners


How can we improve SuperTopo? Got feedback?
 Let us know! 
Time to generate this page: 7.85 secs.

 Climbing is dangerous. Climb at your own risk.
	</body>
</document>
