<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000778" url="http://www.visitnorthwest.com/crewe/grand-junction.htm" time="2012-07-12-16:07" support="6" score="0.0061994268312465335" bingtitle="Grand Junction Retail Park Crewe | Currys, Comet" webtitle="Grand Junction Retail Park Crewe | Currys, Comet">
			<query id="000716" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="000709" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="001210" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="000699" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001275" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000713" bing-rank="105"/>
	<description>The park also offers a KFC fast food restaurant. Focus DIY closed in 2010 and has now been replaced ... So for a car park where you can park free for 2 hours, they would ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Crewe 
 Hotels Map Nantwich 
 Blackpool Chester Lake District Liverpool Manchester Barrow Birkenhead Blackburn Bolton Burnley Bury Carlisle Kendal Lancaster Macclesfield Morecambe Oldham Penrith Preston Ribble Valley Rochdale Rossendale Southport Stockport Warrington Wigan News 
 
Grand Junction Retail Park

The Grand Junction Retail Park is located just east of Crewe town centre. It opened in the mid-90s on the site of the old Crewe Kings speedway stadium.

Shops here include Next, Brantano, SCS, Poundstretcher, Comet, Halfords, M&amp;S Simply Food, Currys and PC World, Carpetright, Pets at Home, Dreams, Laura Ashley, Aldi, CSL, Harveys, Bathstore, and Carphone Warehouse. The park also offers a KFC fast food restaurant.

Focus DIY closed in 2010 and has now been replaced with a TK Maxx Store, Costa coffee shop, and Boots. Rosebys closed in 2008, followed by Allied Carpets in 2009.

Opening times vary by store, but all are open seven days a week. For example Next is open 9 am to 8 pm Monday to Friday, 9 am to 7 pm Saturday, and 10.30 am to 5 pm on Sunday.

Currys, PC World, Pets at Home, and Comet are open 9 am to 8 pm Monday to Friday, 9 am to 6 pm on Saturday, and 10.30 am to 4.30 pm on Sunday.
 
Reviews / Comments / Additional Information
 air jordan concords [url= ... ... buyrealjordanscheap ... /30-air-jordan-2010]air jordan 2010 out door[/url]encyclopedia[url= ... ... buyrealjordanscheap ... /31-air-j ordan-2011]air jordan 2011 releasedates [/url]EastbayBlog[url= ... ... buyrealjordanscheap ... /32-air-jordan -spizikes]michael jordan spizikes[/url]Spizikes[url= ... ... buyrealjordanscheap ... /76-LeBro n-James-9]lebron james 9 shoes for sale[/url]Shoes For Sale[url= ... ... buyrealjordanscheap ... /40-air-jordan-pro-classic] air jordan pro classic black[/url]Black Hot Sale Val I am expecting a£75 fine, after parking at the retail park today. I only spotted the signs on my return and reckon I was about 15 minutes over. The
&apos;signs&apos; look like flimsy pieces of card displayed quite highly on the odd lamp post. I thought this practice was now regulated, and that notices had to be prominently displayed, which was not the case where I was parked- near Hobby craft. Marie Just recieved a fine for£75 from these scammers too. Absolutely outraged as I didn&apos;t see or expect such a curfew on parking at a retail park. that was my first and last visit to Crewe having just moved locally to the area.
Will in future go back to Leicester&apos;s Fosse park where you can park all day for free.
Will check the legality of the fine, but doubt they&apos;ll get any money off me. Taylor We have always done our Christmas shopping in Hanley. Seeing so many shops closing down in my home town Crewe, this year decided to support our local retailers and shop at the retail park. Christmas shopping is not a five minute job and we overstayed the parking allowance which we incidentally didn&apos;t know existed. We have now been served with a£75 parking fine by G4 which is extortionate. The retailers say it&apos;s not their fault, but are they trying to do anything to stop this rip-off. We spent a lot of money that day in various outlets and there was not a single mention of the parking limit and extortionate fine by any off the shop workers. We could have parked in Hanley all day for around£8 so how can G4 warrant a parking fine of£75 for a fraction of the time. I don&apos;t intend to pay£75 but I am prepared to pay a realistic fine in accordance with local parking charges of around 40p an hour if G4 want to accept that rather than nothing. Get this thieving company off the site and lets have pay and display so we all no where we stand. Until that happens I&apos;m sorry retail park but from now on we shall do our shopping elsewhere. Rip-off Britain - Rip-off retail park. The site owners deserve nothing but failure for employing a mob like G4. Heather I am disabled and went to the retail park yesterday. I have a blue badge as I have a false leg and have to have door wide as possible to get out. Tried to park outside Sportsworld/next but all disabled bays were full. That&apos;s no problem and it&apos;s fair enough if disabled people got thee before me but 5 of the cars did not have blue badges displayed!! Sorry , but I hope all the morons who illegally park get tickets....and pay them! Manager on retail park Just to clarify you are all so ignorant! You think the retail shops have anything to do with the parking fines? We are in the same position as you all are if we overstay, and are under the thumb of savills and the parking company! More to the point, if any of you bothered to think sensibly in taking massive offence at an automated ticket, you just need to ask the stores you have shopped at and they will get the ticket cancelled, just like we do for our staff. But I definitely wanted to clarify, the shops have NOTHING to do with the parking restrictions or tickets so stop blaming us! Victoria Went Christmas shopping recently on a Thursday and spent quite a bit of time in Hobby Craft and then visited other shops. Then walked into town and met my husband for lunch as he works near by. When I got back to the car I found I had lost my car keys. My friend and I retraced our stops and spoke to various security people asking if any keys had been handed in. Even reported it to Police as street cleaner said that was where they notify if they find anything. Took husbands car to get kids from school and then get home. Husband got call from Police just before 5 pm - Royal Mail had keys, so eventually all sorted and car returned home. Have just received a &apos;letter&apos; requesting£75 for overstaying my welcome in car park. Am really wondering whether I want to go back. Crewe resident Whatever you do dont pay the fines! I have had numerous and I have ignored every single one. They are just out to make money on unsuspecting visitors. DO NOT answer or even acknowledge you have been fined. You will probably get about 5-7 letters and threats but they give up every time! its a private park and they have absolutely no authority over it. Keep coming to Crewe and dont let these idiots get you down. Crewe worker AGAIN I HAVE TO SAY - DO NOT PAY THESE FINES. LOOK AT MONEY SAVING EXPERT AS MABEL SAYS - I TOO HAVE HAD A FINE AND WILL NOT BE PAYING - I HAVE HAD SEVERAL LETTERS NOW AND JUST IGNORE THE LOT OF THEM. I DON&apos;T ANSWER THEM - I JUST BIN THEM! I SUGGEST YOU ALL DO THE SAME, OTHERWISE YOU ARE WASTING YOUR MONEY PAYING THE FINES!! Sue During a recent visit to the UK, I also visited the retail park. With a teenage daughter who likes sport, we of course made a bee-line for Sports Direct; this is not the kind of shop that you are in and out of in 5 minutes! We looked in some others and then finished up with lunch at KFC. I certainly didn&apos;t see the warning signs for the 3 hour parking limit. Now back in France, I was surprised to open a letter from the car-hire company that I used, informing me of a parking fine of£50, plus£35 admin. fees, plus VAT brings me to a hefty£92. An expensive shopping trip!
I understand the reasons that parking charges need to be applied in certain places. However, I was there during the day on a Tuesday, outside of the school holiday period etc. and the car park was by no means full. Why are there no parking meters in place? At least that would be clear and alert people to the fact that they need to watch the time. I will certainly not be going back to this retail park, which is a shame, as there are some good shops. I am now faced with the challenge of trying to sort this out from another country! goods returner I visited one of the stores to return an item. When I returned to my car I had a ticket for apparently parking in a disabled space.This space is a double plot but with only one disabled badge painted on the floor, very unusual as it should have two or one large sign in the middle so as it covers both spaces.This is the first fine I have ever received. It will be my last time on there (it was midweek at dinner time with probably 20 cars on site). Oh well there are plenty of other local places to go shopping. I really feel sorry for those people that could lose there jobs thanks to g24. Hope they sleep well at night. Alan First Cheshire East Council hike the parking fees in the town and then Grand Junction Retail Park levy parking fines on people to dare to spend their hard-earned money in the shops there! Why oh why are the council and traders of Crewe doing their level best to persuade potential shoppers to do their shopping in neighbouring towns? The retailers in Northwich, Macclesfield and Hanley must be rubbing their hands in delight! dorian Crewe has for years been losing trade to Hanley and Chester. Whilst people will go to Chester for the range of shops and the experience, it is very easy to skip Crewe and go to Hanley rather than be mugged at Grand Junction.
It&apos;s not as though the car park is ever full. Do the retailers realise how much trade they will lose if this continues? another disgruntled x customer Really would not want to see anyone out of a job but shop assistant and retailers just put a 3 hour warning notice up at the entrance of your store better a visit cut short than a customer who will NEVER return! another disgruntled x customer I too have received one of these official looking parking&quot;invoices&quot;after&quot;overstaying&quot;the 3 hour limit whilst spending a considerable sum on this retail park . Luckily I was warned to read this site and Money Saving Expert before paying.I am surprised that the individual retailers have not seen fit to warn their customers of the&quot;3 hour limit&quot;- they may have a fear of shortening a potential customers shopping trip but surely that would be better than allowing them to be charged£75 after which they will never return! I personally have warned everyone I have come into contact with. shop assistant PLEASE don&apos;t stop coming to the retail park, we need you guys to keep us open. I also think the &apos;invoices&apos; are ridiculous, however to avoid the fine just let one of the shops managers know you have been on the park for over 3 hours and they can email g24 with your reg plate so you are exempt for that day. WE NEED YOU!!! Andy I too have just received my£75 demand for parking for 15 minutes too long. This on a visit where I spent over£2000.00 with the retailers on that site. Choosing a new 3 piece suite and bed and visiting the 4 different retailers on there to compare prices on a sale weekend takes time. We did not leave the site, also visiting sportsworld, brantanos and the bargain shop and even had lunch at KFC which pushed me over the 3 hours!
I came away happy with what I had bought; what a strange rip off world this is! I now do not have any intention of ever going back there again. (no doubt I soon will see the Crewe councillors bleating on about the loss of trade to other towns - little wonder!). Law What they issue are invoices based on contract law. They do NOT issue fines. They do everything they can to make their letters look official but they are still just invoices. As with any invoice - if you don&apos;t agree with it, don&apos;t pay. Let them prove you have to.
To claim for damages under contract law they would have to show &apos;offer, consideration and acceptance&apos; of the contract - very doubtful that driving past a sign would be seen as &apos;consideration and acceptance&apos;. Importantly though the only damages they can claim have to be proportionate to any loss incurred. So for a car park where you can park free for 2 hours, they would really struggle to explain why the extra half an hour has caused actual financial loss of£60.
Essentially what these scammers do is play a numbers game. Enough people are fooled by their official looking letters (and just pop a cheque in the post to them) to make it worth their while. Shopper I recently visited the retail park&amp;have been INVOICED for #75 for staying 10 mins over the 3hrs. Please look at the Money Saving Expert website,&amp;do not pay G24 ltd. There charges are only enforcable if they take you to court&amp;win their case. To do this they must prove that the invoice (not fine)represents the a financial
loss to the retailers. I will not be going back ever again. Holland I&apos;m disabled and parked on the site with my wife to do some shopping. My condition makes it very awkward for my wife to get me in and out of the car, and can take some time. As with the other people we also find ourselves with a£75 FINE just for overstaying by a few minutes. Mabel Do not pay the parking fines sent by G24 Ltd for parking at Grand Junction in Crewe. They are a scam. If you ignore the letters they eventually go away. Look on Money Saving Expert website for more details about this. I spent£1200 in Currys on Grand Junction - needless to say I won&apos;t be shopping there again! Neil Barraclough We used to frequent the Grand Junction Retail Park in Crewe for most of our shopping needs. Last Saturday (27th of March) we stayed a little longer than usual, 3 hours and 25 minutes, and promptly received a parking fine in the post of£75 (£50 for prompt payment). We live nearby but will no longer go to Grand Junction Retail Park to do any of our shopping. It is unbelievable in these economic times to be fined for shopping too long. None of those stores will have our business any more, Next, Comet, M&amp;S Food, Focus, Pets at Home, Currys, Carphone Warehouse. ball We visited the retail park on the 16th March and found the collection of shops really good. We spent well over£850 but were shopping for 3hrs 15 mins! We are now in receipt of a£75 fine and are trying to appeal against it. We too shall not be repeating the experience. There is another retail park with a great selection of shops and free parking at Festival Park in neighbouring Stoke on Trent and I will be going there from now on. Beardmore We visited your retail park on the 13th of March which at the time was a good experience. However we are now in receipt of a car park charge notice of£75 (£50 for prompt payment) for parking in excess of 3 hours. This is bordering on daylight robbery. Needless to say it is unlikely we shall be repeating the experience. 
Add Review
 Your name: 

 Image verification: 
 

 Message: 
 
 
Info

Grand Junction Retail Park

Address and postcode: Grand Junction Way , Crewe , Cheshire CW1 2RP 
 
 [View Map] 
 
Search For Accommodation
 
 1 Where would you like to stay? Barrow Blackburn Blackpool Birkenhead Bolton Burnley Bury Carlisle Chester Crewe Kendal Lake District Lancaster Liverpool Macclesfield Manchester Morecambe Oldham Penrith Preston Ribble Valley Rochdale Rossendale Southport Stockport Warrington Wigan 2 When would you like to arrive? 3 How many nights do you want to stay? 1 night 2 nights 3 nights 4 nights 5 nights 6 nights 7 nights 4 How many people in the room? 1 person 2 people 2 + 1 child 2 + 2 children 2 + 3 children 3 people 4 people 5 people 6 people 7 people   
 
Popular hotels in Crewe

 De Vere Venues Wychwood Park 4*£49.00 The Quality Hotel Crewe 3*£45.00 Crewe Hall - QHotels 4*£70.00 Ramada Crewe Hotel 4*£60.00 Ramada Encore Crewe 3*£55.00 
 
 About Us | Free Advertising Submit Press Releases Privacy Policy Blog
	</body>
</document>
