<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000544" url="http://www.bison.com/Taco_Bell_franchise" time="2012-07-12-15:50" support="2" score="0.0028529630484235152" bingtitle="Taco Bell Franchise - Fast Food Restaurant Franchise" webtitle="Taco Bell Franchise| Taco Bell Franchises, Taco Franchises">
			<query id="000178" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000427" bing-rank="142"/>
	<description>Taco Bell Franchise - Fast Food Restaurant Franchise ... can only be made through the delivery and receipt of a ... Taco Bell Franchisees Receive Financial Assistance From ...</description>
	<body>
		Franchise Industries - Food Franchises - Taco Bell 
 
Taco Bell Franchise - Fast Food Restaurant Franchise
 
 


 

 At Yum! Brands, we connect successful professionals like you to brands people crave! We leverage your experience by helping you become a multi-unit franchisee with some of the biggest brands in the business. Our proven process supports you every step of the way with development experts, business coaches and a peer network of more than 1,200 experienced franchisees, all part of the Yum! Value Network. It’s a way to set yourself apart. 

 Do You Have What It Takes? Capability. Commitment. Capital.
 While Yum! franchising is a fantastic opportunity for many, it may not be for everyone. Have a look at the following criteria to see if Yum! is right for you:  

 Do you have a passion for operations?
 The restaurant business is a hands on business  Are you committed to building people capability?
 Multi-unit ownership requires you to be a team builder Do you have capital to grow? 
You and your partners must have at least $360,000 in liquid assets 

 Taco Bell
 Taco Bell Corp., based in Irvine, California, is a subsidiary of Yum! Brands, Inc. (NYSE: YUM), and the nation’s leading Mexican-style quick service restaurant chain. Taco Bell®serves tacos, burritos, signature Quesadillas, Grilled Stuft Burritos, nachos, and other specialty items such as the Crunchwrap Supreme™, in addition to a wide variety of Big Bell Value Menu®items. Taco Bell®serves more than 2 billion consumers each year in more than 5,800 restaurants in the U.S. In 2005, Taco Bell®generated sales of $1.8 billion in company restaurants and $4.4 billion in franchise restaurants. More than 80 percent of our restaurants are owned and operated by independent franchisees. 

 Multibranding The Power of Two! 
Yum! Brands is the worldwide leader in Multibranding, offering consumers more choice, convenience and value at one restaurant location by combining two of our great brands under one roof. 

 Multibranding is changing the landscape of the quick-service food industry in the United States. Yum! Brands has more than 3,900 company and franchise-owned multibrand restaurants worldwide (Q4 2007).
For example, the power of KFC + Taco Bell= 

 Two National Media Budgets  Two Category Leading Brands  Two Menus can broaden the customer appeal and have the potential to increase average check size.  Complementary dayparts can bring more customers to the restaurant throughout the day. 

 Multibrand opportunities exist across America and offer you a real competitive advantage. We are actively looking for new franchisees to bring our big brands to more customers. 

 

 Yum! Value Network
 We recognize there are many franchising choices out there and you need real value. You need strong brands that have demonstrated economic stability over time, that offer growth opportunity and that give back to the community. Yum! offers all of this and more. It’s what we call the Yum! Value Network.  

 The Yum! Value Network consists of many programs and support staff all focused on enabling you to compete, including:  

 Brand Recognition Customer Attraction Competitive Advantage Franchise Value System Multi-Unit Growth Economic Stability Brands that Give Back to the Community Development Expertise Access to Financing Solid Business Support Quality On-boarding&amp;Training Reliable Supply Chain Return on Investment 

 Your drive. Your Team. Our Brands. It can be a powerful combination! 

 Interested?  
 Fill out the form below and we&apos;ll be in touch. 



This web site and the information contained herein does not constitute the offer or sale of a franchise. There are certain states that require the registration of a FDD before the franchisor can advertise or offer the franchise in that state. This franchise may not be registered in all registration states and may not offer franchises to residents of those states or to persons wishing to locate a franchise in those states. The offer and sale of a franchise can only be made through the delivery and receipt of a Franchise Disclosure Document (FDD).
 
Related Information on Taco Bell
 

 Related Franchise Industries 
 Food Franchises Restaurant Franchises Casual Dining Franchises Fast Food Franchises Fast-Casual Franchises Quick Service Restaurant Franchises Food Franchises 
 Taco Bell News 
 Taco Bell Hires Joe Millionaire Butler To Promote Steak Quesadilla 
 3/2003
  Taco Bell Motors To A Top Spot On the Best Drive-Thru in America 2002 Survey 
 10/2002
  Yeah Baby! Taco Bell and Mini-Me `Power&apos;Up for the Summer 
 7/2002
  Taco Bell Breaks Through Original Reality Show&apos;Murder in Small Town X&apos; 
 6/2001
  Taco Bell Franchisees Receive Financial Assistance From Taco Shell Suppliers 
 6/2001
  
 2/1999
  
 


 

 Home - About Us - Contact Us - Site Map - Advertising Info - Copyright - Privacy Policy 
 

Bison.com - Offering the best franchise opportunities and businesses for sale since 1995.
 
 
 
 Franchise For Sale Search:
 Location International Canada Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware District Of Columbia Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming Industry Franchise Consultants International Franchising Advertising Franchises Home Services Franchises Automotive Franchises Business Opportunities Business Franchises Children&apos;s Franchise Cleaning Franchises Coffee Franchises Computer Franchises Consulting Franchises Education Franchises Entertainment Franchises Financial Services Franchises Fitness Franchises Food Franchises Franchise Information - Financing Green Franchises Health and Beauty Franchises Health Care Franchises Home Based Franchises Home Improvement Franchises Home Inspection Franchises Low Cost Franchises Master Franchises Medical Franchises Multi-unit Franchises Pet Franchises Photography Franchises Printing Franchises Real Estate Franchises Repair Franchises Residential Franchises Restaurant Franchises Restoration Franchises Retail Franchises Security Franchises Senior Franchises Shipping Franchises Sign Franchises Specialty Franchises Sports Franchises Staffing Franchises Internet Franchises Travel Franchises Transportation Franchises Vending Franchises Video Franchises Womens Franchises 
 
 July 12, 2012 Home Franchise List Top Franchises Franchise Consultation Franchise News Franchise Categories My Request List    
 
 

 0 companies selected 
 Selection 1 EMPTY Selection 2 EMPTY Selection 3 EMPTY Selection 4 EMPTY
	</body>
</document>
