<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000604" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/61/1560252/restaurant/Peninsular-Charleston/Husk-Charleston" time="2012-07-12-15:53" support="1" score="0.0018636815992342643" bingtitle="Husk - Peninsular Charleston - Charleston | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Husk - Peninsular Charleston - Charleston | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000690" bing-rank="69"/>
	<description>About midway through I found a hair in my food. Told myself that I would not be ... divided by soil, while an important part of terrior, it is like offering cars ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Charleston » Charleston » Peninsular Charleston » Husk 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Atlanta Charlotte Jacksonville Los Angeles New York Orlando Research Triangle More... 
 
Husk
 
(843) 577-2500
 Peninsular Charleston 76 Queen Street 
 Charleston , SC 29401 
 huskrestaurant.com 
 See all 100 reviews Cuisine Southern/Soul , American , Breakfast/Brunch Features Outdoor Dining , Romantic Menu $$$ $15-25 per entree Fried chicken skins, Pappy van winkle 20 year old bourbon, warm yeast roll w/... View menu 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast ✓ Lunch ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Dinner ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ ✓ Late 
   502 people have voted 72 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 82 Queen 83% $$$$ Peninsular Charleston - Seafood, American, Southern/Soul 82 Queen St 
 
 Charleston Grill 87% $$$$ Peninsular Charleston - American, Seafood, French 224 King St 
 
Critic reviews

 February 22, 2012 Charleston City Paper Looking for Charleston&apos;s iconic seafood sandwich...the catfish BLT at Husk ranks as a wonderful fish sandwich. More from Charleston City Paper 
 16/20 Gayot Sean Brock&apos;s raucous celebration of Southern ingredients leaves even the most civilized guest pining for more. More from Gayot 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews

 July 3, 2012 eatsouthern Husk is just one of the many reasons we look forward to returning to Charleston. We fell in love with the city, and fortunately there is so much more we need to explore, like the famed... More from eatsouthern April 26, 2012 Burgers, Barbecue and Everything Else They said their cornbread was the best that they had ever eaten. More from Burgers, Barbecue and Everything Else March 18, 2012 Likes it Hungry In London This article described the incredibly cooking of Sean Brock , a Virginian born chef in his early thirties covered in tattoos, who is executive chef at the Charleston restaurants Husk and... More from Hungry In London February 7, 2012 Capital City Eatz The atmosphere was tasteful! The service was impeccable! Glasses of water were refilled with only slightest notice of the waiter! Allow me to take this opportunity to advise waiters on a... More from Capital City Eatz January 26, 2012 Likes it EAT: King Street So did Husk meet our expectations? More like they took our expectations, shoved them back in our faces, telling us we didn’t set the bar high enough and then delivered on a whole other... More from EAT: King Street 
 Show 11 more 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 July 1, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by Meandorene ( 26 reviews ) Disappointing. Enuf said. May 25, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it Not worth the $$$$$ by Joanne ( 7 reviews ) VERY small portions.....Hubby had credit card sized grouper with peas, I had catfish smaller than a small filet with sweet corn.....both delicious, but at $26/ea. I&apos;m still hungry. I live in Charleston, I know Southern Foods, and although the flavors are there, they are not giving southern&quot;bountiful portions&quot;which is what the south is all about. Don&apos;t get the pig&apos;s ears unless you have good teeth, Carmelized bits of pork (?) wrapped in bibb lettuce. Couldn&apos;t eat it and after 3 people asked how it was? No one offered to take it off the menu nor give me another option.....I&apos;m done with this overblown restaurant... May 15, 2012 Really likes it Mobile review by C Chester Reed ( 4 reviews ) Happy hour at the bar, grab a ham&amp;cheese plate...absurdly knowledgeable bar tenders July 9, 2012 Likes it Been there twice, can&apos;t wait to go back. by GatorDave ( 7 reviews ) We found Husk last summer on vacation and I think it is the main reason we came back to Charleston this summer. The cornbread is out of this world good (my 8 year old adds honey and hot sauce to hers) and the burger is what a burger was meant to be. I actually think the cow would be happy to have given itself to be this burger. This year the newest addition to the list of heavenly food was a Fried Chicken BLT. I don&apos;t have words to do it justice but the kid now says she has a&quot;food crush&quot;on the chef at Husk. May 19, 2012 NOT UP TO THE HYPE by John F ( 2 reviews ) For all the hype about this being the best new restaurant for 2011 you would think that the food would be spectacular. My wife and had lunch last week and we were disappointed. I had the TX sirloin which was supposed to be like Kobe beef. Frankly I found it tough. My wife had the pork shoulder which was indeed tender but bland.. Don&apos;t order the cornbread because its rather dry. We did have the grouper fritters and they were very good. Overall the service was excellent. There are many other restaurants in Charleston that we have eaten in that are just as good if not better. June 14, 2012 Menu is what it is.... by Sank ( 2 reviews ) My husband saw the chef of Husk interviewed on the Charlie Rose show and thought that we should add it to our itinerary when we make our annual visit to Charleston. We went with my parents and our son. Our son does not eat a large variety of food, but we have never not been able to find something on the menu or have the kitchen make him something for dinner. I asked if they make pizza. They don&apos;t. I understand. No problem. I was told that they only make things that are from the south. That is fine too. We love Charleston and southern food. I was told that it had to be something on the menu. I asked if they could take bacon and cheddar cheese and make a sandwich for him. She said that they could only use what was sourced locally to make something. Both bacon and cheddar were on the menu, so it seemed like that would fit the requirement, but our waitress really did not think that the kitchen would do it, but she never checked. There was no interest in helping us make something work... more» My husband saw the chef of Husk interviewed on the Charlie Rose show and thought that we should add it to our itinerary when we make our annual visit to Charleston. We went with my parents and our son. Our son does not eat a large variety of food, but we have never not been able to find something on the menu or have the kitchen make him something for dinner. I asked if they make pizza. They don&apos;t. I understand. No problem. I was told that they only make things that are from the south. That is fine too. We love Charleston and southern food. I was told that it had to be something on the menu. I asked if they could take bacon and cheddar cheese and make a sandwich for him. She said that they could only use what was sourced locally to make something. Both bacon and cheddar were on the menu, so it seemed like that would fit the requirement, but our waitress really did not think that the kitchen would do it, but she never checked. There was no interest in helping us make something work, so my son and I walked across the street, sat on a bench and had a pizza delivered for dinner. It is difficult to know whether what happened to us was an issue with that particular waitress or whether that is an issue with all the service there. We will never know.... May 15, 2012 Decent Enough by SouthernEats ( 1 review ) Husk is good...don&apos;t get me wrong. However, it didn&apos;t live up to the hype. Small portions, average flavors, nothing really creative, etc. The chicken skins tasted like greasy left over batter. The pig ear lettuce wraps were unremarkable and the steak was average at best. A nice time, nice atmosphere and a nice dinner. The bar next door is much better. April 14, 2012 Likes it &lt;3 Husk! by Meg ( 13 reviews ) I absolutely love Husk. Now, if we can actually eat there again. We used to be able to go in easily on the weekends for brunch. Due to the popularity, and rave reviews, however, a reservation is months out. Great prices, excellent food. Sometimes, we felt the service needed to be kicked up a notch, and the hostesses can be snooty, but food-wise, Husk absolutely kills it. December 9, 2010 Likes it Nearly NYC Tier 1 Execution by myverismo ( 322 reviews ) This might be the nearest thing to a One Star Michelin restaurant in the south. The food was spot on, perfect. Servce was great. My server, Katlyn, understood the menu perfectly well. While the whole&quot;all from the South&quot;shtick is clever, but nothing more than an extension of locally grown as is the daily menu a trend seen more and more like Passion8 Bistron in CHarlotte.&quot;South only&quot;hurts the menu in some areas, like the corn and sausage. Locality does not equal the best product. Strangely, there were zero southern wines on their list. Further more, the list is divided by soil, while an important part of terrior, it is like offering cars by base metal. Still Husk is a must vist. This just replace FIG for me as Chucktown&apos;s best groceries. 4 out of 4 found this review helpful April 15, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by Rachael ( 6 reviews ) Good food for sure. if I order a ten dollar glass of wine I want it to be filled more than I was served. The service was so so. I think overall neat concept but I think there&apos;s room for improvement November 15, 2011 Likes it Imaginative by Chance ( 68 reviews ) Living in Charleston over the past 5 years I am fortunate enough to have tried most of its great downtown restaurants and Husk ranks as one of my favorite places. The charming ambience both outdoors and in is 100% Charleston. It&apos;s a fine dining experience with a casual atmosphere. The funnest part of the dinner was the pumpkin soup -- a sweet combination that includes a pork rillette, a marshmallow, and chestnut granola. It is nearly a meal in itself. The entrees were superb including my pork chop. The service was excellent and there didn&apos;t appear to be a bad table in the place. Securing a reservation on short notice is difficult else I would be back in a few weeks. The menu is chockfull of interesting dishes giving so many reasons to return. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful April 16, 2012 Very Disappointed by lindab ( 1 review ) The first time I visited Husk was for Sunday brunch. Ordered a breakfast item with steak. The meat was so tough I couldn&apos;t eat it. About midway through I found a hair in my food. Told myself that I would not be back. Decided I would give it another try. My husband, daughter and son-in-law and I went to Husk Bar. We were sitting upstairs. My daughter asked for a drink from the menu she had at her last visit. Our server went downstairs, came back up and told us that they couldn&apos;t make the drink. Period! Drinks were ordered along with two appetizers. We then wanted to order burgers. My daughter ordered hers first asking for a burger without the bun. Our server said there would be no modifications bur went downstairs anyway to check. Came back upstairs and we were told she had to have the bun with her burger. So okay she just wouldn&apos;t eat the bun. My daughter asked to substitute slaw for the fries. Our server went downstairs again to check, came back up and said no modifications. She... more» The first time I visited Husk was for Sunday brunch. Ordered a breakfast item with steak. The meat was so tough I couldn&apos;t eat it. About midway through I found a hair in my food. Told myself that I would not be back. Decided I would give it another try. My husband, daughter and son-in-law and I went to Husk Bar. We were sitting upstairs. My daughter asked for a drink from the menu she had at her last visit. Our server went downstairs, came back up and told us that they couldn&apos;t make the drink. Period! Drinks were ordered along with two appetizers. We then wanted to order burgers. My daughter ordered hers first asking for a burger without the bun. Our server said there would be no modifications bur went downstairs anyway to check. Came back upstairs and we were told she had to have the bun with her burger. So okay she just wouldn&apos;t eat the bun. My daughter asked to substitute slaw for the fries. Our server went downstairs again to check, came back up and said no modifications. She had to take the fries. My daughter had ordered the same burger with no bun and slaw instead of fries her last visit. No questions asked. I then ordered my burger well done and again the server went downstairs to see if I could have it well done, came back upstairs and told us they would make no modifications - I would have to have my burger cooked medium. I said I can&apos;t eat my burger medium. Again was told no modifications. At this point, I had had enough! My husband asked to see the manager who said he would take care of our food and drinks. My husband refused and paid our bill including a tip. We really don&apos;t know what was going on here but suspect it was the chef! I will never go back to Husk and will not recommend it. By the way left Husk and went to High Cotton where our requests were met 100% by a wondeful server, delicious food and awesome live jazz combo. June 13, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it Uninspired by Nicole Pearce ( 53 reviews ) I&apos;m still not really sure what I thought of HUSK. It is really highly rated and they do use all fresh local produce. I couldn&apos;t help feeling something was missing. Part of me felt like they were trying to hard to be west coast. Also, in a place as expensive as HUSK I expect the servers to know a little about the food and beverage they are serving. I&apos;m not even sure that my waiter was so much not knowledgeable as he was uninterested. That said, my beet salad with whipped goat cheese was the best salad I had on the trip, and I had quite a few. Sitting out on the deck was really nice. They have quite an impressive cocktail list. I would recommend HUSK as a place to go an have a drink outside and then have dinner elsewhere. 2 out of 3 found this review helpful October 10, 2011 Really likes it This was great by jsw ( 149 reviews ) Had read a piece about Husk in the New York Times and was determined to put it on our to do list for annual Charleston trip. Two previous experiences at Chef Brock&apos;s McCradys were OK (&apos;09)and very good (&apos;10). Spoke with three locals in the food biz -2 said good, the other comment was&quot;overrated/dissapointing&quot;. The lady smoking outside before we went in said&quot;not worth the $&quot;. Needless to say we were ambigous going in, dining here was a conversion experience.. Pork belly startter was excellent, as were the duck and pork shoulder entrees. Service was good, with some minor hiccoughs entrees seemed a bit delayed, but we were treated to complimentary fried chicken skins with a great dipping sauce. This is comfort food all the way- no wimpy health conscious options on this night!! The decor in the dining room was among the most innovative we&apos;ve experienced in quite a while. Pricing is on par with upscale Charleston, we&apos;ve paid more for dinners that were not on this level. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful February 28, 2012 Likes it Everything was Great! by John S ( 8 reviews ) Great (and original) Food, Great Service, Great Bar! When can I return? and did I mention the prices were reasonable compared to many of the finer downtown establishments. April 11, 2011 Doesn&apos;t like it run....run away by FeedingFrenzy ( 33 reviews ) While in Charleston for a conference we were told that we HAD to visit Husk, so we managed to snag a 5:45 reservation on a Friday night and canceled our previous reservation. we arrived and were greeted brusquely, like our hostess had so many more important things to do in the empty restaurants. were taken upstairs where there were 2 other tables occupied. took some time for the waiter to come greet us and was unhelpful with drink suggestions...in fact, he seemed like he had somewhere else to go....but there were only 2 other tables. dining companion is gluten intolerant so needed to ask questions about menu items. took forever for waiter to come back from kitchen with answers. wine and beer finally came and we started with the bread (the best part of the meal). well, okay I ate all the bread... the sweet potato soup was outstanding...bit salty but creamy and rich. very enjoyable. the&quot;tasting of hams&quot;was huge disappointment. Yes, we realized we would be eating... more» While in Charleston for a conference we were told that we HAD to visit Husk, so we managed to snag a 5:45 reservation on a Friday night and canceled our previous reservation. we arrived and were greeted brusquely, like our hostess had so many more important things to do in the empty restaurants. were taken upstairs where there were 2 other tables occupied. took some time for the waiter to come greet us and was unhelpful with drink suggestions...in fact, he seemed like he had somewhere else to go....but there were only 2 other tables. dining companion is gluten intolerant so needed to ask questions about menu items. took forever for waiter to come back from kitchen with answers. wine and beer finally came and we started with the bread (the best part of the meal). well, okay I ate all the bread... the sweet potato soup was outstanding...bit salty but creamy and rich. very enjoyable. the&quot;tasting of hams&quot;was huge disappointment. Yes, we realized we would be eating salt-cured hams, but does the chef not try them before he puts them on the plate? 3 were so salty we could not finish. the dirty rice with mushrooms was quite fine, again on the salty side. by this time, the waiter had disappeared or spent all his time fawning on the table of older southern couples who were obviously of old money. when finally we asked about dessert, we were told about a great cookies and ice cream dessert where the&quot;cookie&quot;was separate from three types of ice cream -- bourbon brown sugar, chocolate and one other. after waiting 15 minutes, a manager brought the dessert. nothing like what we expected. we got vanilla, strawberry and sweet potato. when we asked the manager what the flavors were and he told us, we let him know that was not what our waiter described...the entire reason we ordered was for the chocolate and bourbon brown sugar. he informed us that they&apos;d run out of those flavors (it was barely 7 p.m. and the restaurant was just starting to fill up). he then walked away. walked away! he knew he had dissatisfied customer yet he walked away. when the waiter came by 10 minutes later to see puddles of uneaten ice cream, he didn&apos;t even ask. he took the board away and still charged us. i have many friends headed to Charleston in a few weeks for a conference and my main recommendation to them -- eat anywhere but Husk. 2 out of 3 found this review helpful January 20, 2011 Likes it Get Food Drunk at Husk! by tpoolei ( 18 reviews ) My wife and I just returned from our dinner at Husk. It was one of the most wonderful dinning experiences we have ever had! Once we entered the establishment we new that we were in for a treat. Everything is so methodically thought out. The oak floors and tables coupled with the décor and artwork fit in perfectly with the rustic southern charm they were going for. We were greeted by a friendly hostess and general manager on the way in and our server was just superb. She had great taste in wine and carefully described each menu item as we questioned her. My wife and I both ordered the Shrimp&amp;Grits for the 1st course. I am from the south and have had this dish many of times…but this was the pinnacle. It was very flavorful, with fresh ingredients and a little extra genius. Who would have thought that adding crispy pork ear as a garnish would pair so well? For our 2nd course, my wife ordered the duck and I the triggerfish. You could tell each dish was carefully prepared and made... more» My wife and I just returned from our dinner at Husk. It was one of the most wonderful dinning experiences we have ever had! Once we entered the establishment we new that we were in for a treat. Everything is so methodically thought out. The oak floors and tables coupled with the décor and artwork fit in perfectly with the rustic southern charm they were going for. We were greeted by a friendly hostess and general manager on the way in and our server was just superb. She had great taste in wine and carefully described each menu item as we questioned her. My wife and I both ordered the Shrimp&amp;Grits for the 1st course. I am from the south and have had this dish many of times…but this was the pinnacle. It was very flavorful, with fresh ingredients and a little extra genius. Who would have thought that adding crispy pork ear as a garnish would pair so well? For our 2nd course, my wife ordered the duck and I the triggerfish. You could tell each dish was carefully prepared and made with love. The duck fell right off the bone and my fish was excellent, especially adding the fresh steamed clams as a garnish. It was yet another step towards the extra mile. Finally, our 3rd and final course was desert. My wife ordered the sweet potato bread pudding with a roasted marshmallow and pecans and I could not resist the&quot;coffee and donuts,&quot;a coffee flavored donut-cake with ice cream made out of Krispy Kreme donuts. Afterwards we made our way home, both food drunk and already thinking of when we will pay Husk another visit. 2 out of 2 found this review helpful March 13, 2011 by willIambl ( 47 reviews ) A group of six of us had the opportunity to check out The Bar at Husk. It&apos;s nice inside and offers a quiet open upstairs where you can relax and talk, order drinks w/limited appetizers, etc. The downstairs is a little busier and more noisy. Specialty drafts we&apos;re 7.50 and the mixed drinks 10. Apps we&apos;re okay - reserving judgement for opportunity to eat at the restaurant next. There&apos;s a small driveway between the bar and restaurant that leads to limited free parking but check first and pull in your rear-view mirrors; there&apos;s room but just barely. 2 out of 3 found this review helpful March 22, 2012 Likes it Delectable... by sujomo3 ( 15 reviews ) We ate here for lunch and were seated on the balcony outside - absolutely charming! My husband enjoyed the cheeseburger with bacon - a definite winner. I had the cornbread stuffed quail which was equally delicious. You definitely want reservations here! This is a place I will highly recommend to anyone visiting Charleston! April 6, 2012 Doesn&apos;t like it Poor service by M.westphal ( 2 reviews ) Pork Belly Sandwich -
Had kids w us decided to eat at loft over the bar. Service was horrible. Two waitresses were serving tables together and we couldn t tell which one was the trainee. Food was delicious everything else horrible. We ordered a bottle of white wine for the table. The bottle was not deivered to our table until our meal was almost over. The waitress couldn t get the cork out of the bottle so my husband opened the wine at our table. Kids asked for bread to go with the ham plate and the waitress said dinners don t get bread at the loft area. I gave the kids bread from my sandwich. Returning to Charleston in May will not be returning to this establishment 
 Show 62 more 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by Chance Bev Eggleston&apos;s... by AkAttack Pimento cheese... 
 All 57 photos View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Poogan&apos;s Porch 86% $$$ Peninsular Charleston - Southern/Soul, American 82 Queen 83% $$$$ Peninsular Charleston - Seafood, American, Southern/Soul Eli&apos;s Table 78% $$$ Peninsular Charleston - American, Breakfast/Brunch, Coffee Barbadoes Room 79% Peninsular Charleston Bin 152 98% $ Peninsular Charleston - Wine Bar, French 
 More nearby restaurants 
Nearby Places

 Circular Congregational Church -
150 Meeting St Days Inn - Historic District -
155 Meeting St Gibbes Museum of Art -
135 Meeting St St. John&apos;s Lutheran Church -
5 Clifford St Trott&apos;s Cottage -
83 Cumberland St 
 People reached this page by searching for: 
 husk charleston rusk charleston sc husk charleston sc husk reviews husk charleston menu 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
