<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000448" url="http://www.freesamplesite.com/ydf/showthread.php/243097-Need-Help-Zoompanel-Telephone-Number!!!" time="2012-07-12-15:41" support="1" score="0.0006524818846508772" bingtitle="Need Help Zoompanel Telephone Number!!! - Welcome to Your Daily ..." webtitle="Need Help Zoompanel Telephone Number!!!">
			<query id="001453" bing-rank="167"/>
	<description>Cause Every End Of Dec. They Up The Point Level ... I called the toll free number above and was able to ... Fast Food &amp; Restaurant Coupons; Drug Store &amp; Pharmacy Coupons</description>
	<body>
		Register Help Remember Me? 
 
 Home Forum 
 FAQ Calendar Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 

 
 Blogs What&apos;s New? 
 
 Advanced Search 
 
 Forum YDF Freebies - Discounts - Deals Surveys / Mystery Shopping / Product Testing Need Help Zoompanel Telephone Number!!! 
 
 If this is your first visit, be sure to
 check out the FAQ by clicking the
 link above. You may have to register before you can post: click the register link above to proceed. To start viewing messages,
 select the forum that you want to visit from the selection below. 
 + Reply to Thread Page 1 of 2 1 2 Last 
 Jump to page: 
 Results 1 to 10 of 14 
Thread: Need Help Zoompanel Telephone Number!!! 
 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Search Thread 
 
   Advanced Search 
 
 
 09-26-2008,  11:31 AM #1 Bushelon 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Jan 2003 Location NY Posts 168 
Need Help Zoompanel Telephone Number!!!
 Hi all!

I just went to check my Zoompanel.com/zoomreward account and was really frustrated to see that my account points were cancelled!!!

I had 26,165 of unredeemed points that were cancelled on August 26, 2008 for reasons cited as expiration via disable. I don&apos;t understand that because I have been consistently doing zoompanel surveys for years! I read in the rules that your account can be cancelled if you do not do their surveys for at least 90 days, which isn&apos;t the case for me!!!

I would appreciate a telephone number for Zoompanel if anyone has it!!

TIA!! I would like to hear from anyone who has had this done to them and the resolution if any.

Bushelon (Jean)
 AMcn166742@aol.com Reply With Quote 09-26-2008,  12:18 PM #2 heyABLE 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 1/2007 Join Date Feb 2006 Location Go Saints!! Posts 946 I am very sorry to hear that. 

I did a google search but only found an address:

Corporate Headquarters:
ZoomPanel
150 Spear Street Suite 600
San Francisco, CA 94105


May be someone else can help. Reply With Quote 09-26-2008,  12:23 PM #3 myccbb 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Jul 2008 Posts 39 Click the link and it tells you information about how to contact Zoom Panel:

 http://www.surveypolice.com/zoom-panel Reply With Quote 09-26-2008,  12:46 PM #4 hipfan 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Jan 2007 Location Michigan Posts 1,017 
Hope this helps...
 MarketTools, Inc.
150 Spear Street
Suite 600
San Francisco, CA 94105

Phone: 415.957.2200
Fax: 415.957.2180
Toll-free in the U.S.: 888.396.6014

 sales@markettools.com 
 www.markettools.com Reply With Quote 09-26-2008,  07:14 PM #5 Bushelon 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Jan 2003 Location NY Posts 168 Originally Posted by hipfan MarketTools, Inc.
150 Spear Street
Suite 600
San Francisco, CA 94105

Phone: 415.957.2200
Fax: 415.957.2180
Toll-free in the U.S.: 888.396.6014

 sales@markettools.com 
 www.markettools.com Thanks so much!!; 

Bushelon Reply With Quote 09-27-2008,  05:23 PM #6 bacicat 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Jun 2006 Location NYC - West Village Posts 1,033 I wish you luck. I&apos;ve had luck w/them when I didn&apos;t get a survey credit. Took some time/emails but I eventually got my small pts.
WOW over 26K in pts. where you saving for something special? Reply With Quote 09-28-2008,  02:28 PM #7 Bushelon 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Jan 2003 Location NY Posts 168 Originally Posted by bacicat I wish you luck. I&apos;ve had luck w/them when I didn&apos;t get a survey credit. Took some time/emails but I eventually got my small pts.
WOW over 26K in pts. where you saving for something special? I really didn&apos;t like anything offered and was waiting for something new! I didn&apos;t think they would cancel my points because I didn&apos;t use them since I have been consistently doing surveys for them! I am so upset with myself that I didn&apos;t just get anything with the points even if I didn&apos;t like what they offered!

If anyone else has had their account points wiped out from zoompanel, please let me know. I would like to know how they handled it. TIA!!

Bushelon Reply With Quote 09-28-2008,  02:33 PM #8 Bushelon 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Jan 2003 Location NY Posts 168 Originally Posted by myccbb Click the link and it tells you information about how to contact Zoom Panel:

 http://www.surveypolice.com/zoom-panel Thanks so much! I couldn&apos;t remember this site and was racking my brain to remember who to contact. Have a great day!


Bushelon (Jean) Reply With Quote 09-29-2008,  06:18 PM #9 KARATE 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Mar 2001 Location louisiana Posts 2,052 Yep But U Gotta Redeem Every Yr If U Really Want To Get Good Stuff. Cause Every End Of Dec. They Up The Point Level Amts Per Item Getting. Making It Harder To Cash Out For Something.
Also Some Places Expire Points Or Say You Are Inactive. Been Doing This For Twenty Yrs Now. Good Luck. Oh If U Pester The Hell Out Of Them, They Will Answer U. Like Send Fifteen Emails Every Day To Them . Trust Me. Haha Reply With Quote 09-30-2008,  01:56 PM #10 Bushelon 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Jan 2003 Location NY Posts 168 Originally Posted by hipfan MarketTools, Inc.
150 Spear Street
Suite 600
San Francisco, CA 94105

Phone: 415.957.2200
Fax: 415.957.2180
Toll-free in the U.S.: 888.396.6014

 sales@markettools.com 
 www.markettools.com I called the toll free number above and was able to get transferred to a live customer service rep. who credited all my points back to my account!!
He was very apologetic and said that since I hadn&apos;t redeemed any points in six months, my points were deleted. He said they were going to work on changing that. Thanks for everyones help!!

Bushelon (Jean) Reply With Quote
	</body>
</document>
