<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000309" url="http://www2.ed.gov/offices/OSFAP/training/regions/boston.html" time="2012-07-12-15:29" support="1" score="0.001570190569015864" bingtitle="Boston Regional Training Facility - U.S. Department of Education" webtitle="Boston Regional Training Facility">
			<query id="000744" bing-rank="198"/>
	<description>The closest stop to the building is the State Street stop on the Blue &amp; Orange lines. ... Due to the large number of participant requests for lodging information, we are ...</description>
	<body>
		Local Transportation Information 
 John W. McCormack Federal Building 
U.S. Department of Education—Federal Student Aid
Boston (Region I) Training Facility
5 Post Office Square, 9th Floor, Suite 900
Boston, MA 02109-2931
Hours: Monday–Friday 6:00am to 6:00pm
RTF Coordinator: 617-289-0133
Boston Fundamentals of Title IV Coordinators:
617-289-0130 and 617-289-0022 
The public entrance to the John W. McCormack Federal Building is on Congress Street. Visitors entering the building must pass through security systems. All belongings will be x-rayed. Employees with a federal ID card may enter either on Congress or Devonshire Streets.
 

 Car
   Air, Subway, and Bus
   Hotels and Services
 
 From Logan Airport: 

Exit the airport and merge onto I-90 W/Mass Pike/Massachusetts Turnpike/Ted Williams Tunnel. Take Exit 24 toward I-93. Merge onto I-93 N/US-1N/MA-3N/Thomas P. O&apos;Neill Jr. Tunnel. Take Exit 23 toward Government Center. Turn slight left to take the Government Center ramp toward Faneuil Hall/Financial District/Aquarium. Turn slight right onto North Street, turn left onto Congress Street and continue straight to 5 Post Office Square. The John W. McCormack building will be on your right across from the small park.

 From Back Bay: 

Turn right onto Beacon Street. Beacon Street becomes School Street. Turn left onto Washington Street. Turn right onto Water Street. Turn right onto Congress Street/Post Office Square. The John W. McCormack building is on your immediate right with a small park across the street.

 From the West: 

Take Mass Pike (1-90) East. Go through the Weston tolls, take Exit 24 A-B-C on the left toward I-93S/Quincy/South Station/I-93 N/Concord NH. Take the 24C-B exit on the left. Merge onto I-93 N/US-1 N/MA-3 N/Thomas P. O&apos;Neill Jr. Tunnel via Exit 24B toward Concord NH. Inside the O&apos;Neill Tunnel take Exit 23 toward Government Center. Turn slight left to take the Government Center ramp toward Faneuil Hall/Financial District/Aquarium. Turn slight right onto North Street. Turn left onto Congress Street and continue straight to 5 Post Office Square. The John W. McCormack Building will be on your right across from the small park.

 From Rhode Island and South: 

Take Interstate 95N to Interstate 93N to Boston. Enter Thomas P. O&apos;Neill Tunnel. Take Exit 23 toward Government Center. Turn slight left to take the Government Center ramp toward Faneuil Hall/Financial District/Aquarium. Turn slight right onto North Street. Turn left onto Congress Street and continue straight to 5 Post Office Square. The John W. McCormack Building will be on your right across from the small park.

 From New Hampshire and North: 

Take Interstate 93S across the Leonard Zakim Bridge and into the Thomas P. O&apos;Neill Tunnel. Inside the tunnel, take the RT-1A exit, Exit 24B-A toward Airport/Government Center. Stay right taking Exit 24-A toward Government Center and right onto Clinton Street. Turn left onto North Street. Turn left onto Congress Street and continue straight to 5 Post Office Square. The John W. McCormack building will be on your right across from the small park.

 From Eastern New Hampshire and Northeastern Massachusetts: 

Take Interstate 95S to Route 1 South. Follow Route 1 across the Tobin Bridge and merge onto I-93 S/US-1 S into the Thomas P. O&apos;Neill Tunnel. Inside the tunnel, take the RT-1A exit, Exit 24B-A toward Airport/Government Center. Stay right taking Exit 24-A toward Government Center and turn right onto Clinton Street. Turn left onto North Street. Turn left onto Congress Street and continue straight to 5 Post Office Square. The John W. McCormack Building will be on your right across from the small park.

 Parking 

There is NO parking in the John W. McCormack Federal Building. However, you may park at the following locations that are just within walking distance of the Federal Student Aid office.

 Garage at Post Office Square 
Zero Post Office Square
Boston, MA 02109
Tel. 617-423-1430

 From Points South : From I-93 North, take Exit 23 (Government Center). Take an immediate left off the exit onto John F. Fitzgerald Surface Rd/Purchase Street. Continue on Purchase Street. Take a right onto Pearl Street. (Pearl Street is clearly marked with a street sign.) After the second set of lights/Franklin Street intersection, the entrance to the garage will be immediately on the left.

 From Points North : From I-93 South, take Exit 23, bearing right off the exit onto Purchase Street. At the second light, make a right onto Pearl Street. (Pearl Street is clearly marked with a street sign.) After the second set of lights/Franklin Street intersection, the entrance to the garage will be immediately on the left.

 From Points West/Mass Pike (Interstate 90) : Follow the Massachusetts Turnpike (I-90 East) into Boston. Take Exit 24B to I-93 North to Exit 23, (Government Center). Take immediate left off the exit onto John F. Fitzgerald Surface Rd/Surface Road/Purchase Street. Continue on Purchase Street. Take a right onto Pearl Street. (Pearl Street is clearly marked with a street sign.) After the second set of lights/Franklin Street intersection, the entrance to the Garage will be immediately on the left.

 From Logan Airport via Ted Williams Tunnel : Take the I-90 West/The Ted Williams Tunnel and take Exit 24 onto I-93 North. From I-93 North, take Exit 23 (Government Center). Take immediate left off the exit onto John F. Fitzgerald Surface Rd/Purchase Street. Continue on Purchase Street. Take a right onto Pearl Street. (Pearl Street is clearly marked with a street sign.) After the second set of lights/Franklin Street intersection, the entrance to the Garage will be immediately on the left.

 33 Arch Street Parking Garage 
33 Arch Street
Boston, MA 02110
Tel. 617-204-9268

 

 

Much of the information on this page is available in Word or PDF .
   
 Air 

 Logan International Airport serves the Boston area. You can reach the RTF from Logan Airport by public transportation or by car. See the left side of this page for the driving directions from the airport.

 Transportation Services 

 Taxi 
 Red White Cab (617) 536-5010
 Town Taxi (617) 536-5000 

 Limousine / chauffeur 
 Boston Chauffeur (617) 927-5466
 Ultimate (800) 439-4390

 Airport transportation 
 Knights Airport Limo Service 800-822-5456

 Subway 

The John W. McCormack Federal Building is just a short walk from all four MBTA www.mbta.com subway lines. It&apos;s centrally located in Post Office Square in downtown Boston. Access is within walking distance from numerous MBTA stops. The Red (Park Street or Downtown Crossing) , Orange (Downtown Crossing or State Street) , Green (Park or Gov Center) and Blue (State Street) lines all have stops within the vicinity of the building.

 The closest stop to the building is the State Street stop on the Blue&amp;Orange lines. Exit on Devonshire Street. 

South Station is less than half a mile away. North Station is less than a mile away. A bicycle storage room is also available for your convenience.

 Bus 

Please visit the MBTA Website for complete schedules and station information.

Bus routes #92, 93, 459, 7, 504, 553, and 558, among others, are easily accessible from the John W. McCormack Federal Building. Also, South Station is less than half a mile away, offering long distance bus service to Cape Cod, New Hampshire, New York and points beyond.

Bus stops are located on Franklin Street, Milk Street, Devonshire Street, Washington Street, Federal Street, Otis Street, and Summer Street, all of which are within easy walking distance from the John W. McCormack Federal Building.

For additional resources, you may wish to check the following links:

 Massachusetts Bay Area Transit Authority (MBTA) web site:
 MBTA Home Page 


 HotelGuide Boston: 
 boston.hotelguide.net 

 Citywide Reservation Services, Inc.: 
 www.cityres.com 
   
 Federal Building Amenities :
Cafeteria—3rd floor (McCormack Café)
Hours: Monday to Friday 6:45am–2:45pm
Hot Breakfast: 7:00 am–10:30 am
Lunch: 11:00am–2:30 pm
Telephone: 617-292-4646

Health Unit—3rd Floor
Hours: Monday to Friday 7:30 am–4:00 pm
Telephone: 617-412-4456

Fitness Center—3rd Floor
Hours: Monday to Friday 6:00 am–7:00 pm
Telephone: 617-918-1744

Hanscom Federal Credit Union—3rd Floor
Hours: Monday to Friday 7:30 am–3:30pm
Telephone: 617-412-4869

 Local Hotels 

 Near the Airport: 

 Hilton Logan
(617) 569-9300 Harborside Hyatt
(617) 568-1234 Ramada Inn Logan Airport
(617) 569-9300 

 Within walking distance of the RTF: 

 Holiday Inn Government Center
(617) 742-7630 Omni Parker House
(617) 227-8600 Shawmut Inn
(617) 720-5544 

 Important Note: 

Due to the large number of participant requests for lodging information, we are offering the names and phone numbers of local hotel and motel sites to assist you in making your travel arrangements while staying in the Boston area. Our listings are not all-inclusive, and no endorsement by the U.S. Department of Education should be inferred.

 Local Services 

 Restaurants 
 Cosi
 14 Milk Street (617) 426-7565
 J. Pace&amp;Son
 One Federal Street (617) 556-8253
 Elephant&amp;Castle
 161 Devonshire Street (617) 350-9977
 Archie&apos;s New York Deli
 101 Arch Street (617) 330-5145
 Pizzeria Rico
 32 Bromfield Street (617) 423-7426
 Sam LaGrassa&apos;s
 44 Province Street (617) 357-6861
 Qdoba Mexican Grille
 62 Summer Street (617) 357-0791

 Other Nearby Amenities 

 Angell Memorial Park is immediately opposite the front doors on Congress Street. Across the street from the John W. McCormack building is a Dunkin Donuts on Milk Street and next to it, on the corner of Congress and Milk Street, is a CVS drugstore. The post office is on Milk Street on the right of the building. Faneuil Hall Marketplace is to the left and down a few blocks from the building. Shopping at Downtown Crossing is just out the doors on Devonshire Street; turn left and go right onto Milk Street and up a few blocks. 

 Map 
 Top   
   Main Locator Page
	</body>
</document>
