<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000927" url="http://www.familycorner.com/homegarden/desrep/drinking_glasses.shtml" time="2012-07-12-16:17" support="3" score="0.0022363741934431315" bingtitle="Kitchen &amp; Home | Decor | It&apos;s the Little Things: Drinking Glasses" webtitle="KitchenHome | Decor | It&apos;s the Little Things: Drinking Glasses">
			<query id="001025" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="000246" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000243" bing-rank="61"/>
	<description>... hallmarks from a lost time: One free 32-ounce plastic cup with neon lettering from a fast-food restaurant, a ... toddler’s sippy cup, somehow all end up gracing your table.</description>
	<body>
		join | what&apos;s new | site map 
 
 a
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
   
 It&apos;s the Little Things: Drinking Glasses 
 by Lauren Ragland 
 Over the years, many of us have acquired a collection of differently-shaped and sized drinking glasses as if they were hallmarks from a lost time: One free 32-ounce plastic cup with neon lettering from a fast-food restaurant, a set of pint-sized glasses for lemonade on sale from a discount retailer, and perhaps even your toddlers sippy cup, somehow all end up gracing your table. Before you know it, your kitchen has enough drinking glasses to quench the thirst of the American League baseball teams and as much style as the nearest football stadium! Now, perhaps you can&apos;t bear to part with your collection of mismatched glasses. Well, thats fine, just relegate them to backyard barbecues, your kids birthday parties or any other casual dining experience. But at least have a decent set of glasses around when company comes. Interior decorators will tell you that a set of inexpensive glasses can detract from the dcor of the room.
Consider just how much drinking glasses can add to the aesthetics of a kitchen. A complete set of glasses that complement the color scheme of the kitchen can help create a distinct mood. Using similar styles, colors, or patterns will bring harmony to the rooms design. As a result, the entire space will look infinitely more pleasing to the eye. Not only can a beautiful set of glasses brighten up a table setting, but they can also serve as display pieces even when theyre not being used.
In a kitchen setting, attractive glassware can divert focus away from items that are, while functional, an eyesore. Decorative drinkware is definitely available, and comes in large quantities to fit a wide range of tastes.
First, let&apos;s look at some of the many styles in drink glasses. Of course, we all know that they come in materials ranging from clay and wood to plastic and other synthetic materials. For the sake of simplicity, let&apos;s stick with the glass products. While some are pricier than you might be willing to pay, these are items that could last a lifetime. Consider glasses that are very distinctive and colorful, which makes them perfect to put on display. Imagine how they would look placed in glass-fronted white cabinets in a kitchen. The colors of your glasses should be found elsewhere in the kitchen, even if it is in the designs on a dishtowel. Matching colors will create cohesion within the space.
Sometimes drinking glasses can be expensive, which will keep many from placing them in the hands of their three-year-olds. But for those with small children who will somehow get to the glasses anyway, there are more reasonably priced items. Retro-looking glasses are affordable and yet create a distinctive mood. Tinted drinkware is another option that can add a more traditional style to a table setting. Consider matching them to plates and dishes, or even pots and pans to complete the rooms color scheme.

 

Another way to add color to a kitchen space without changing the color of your wallet from green to black (as in empty) is to color coordinate your glasses with one another. Choose a rainbow of colors that work together and also pick up tones and colors from other objects in the space. Decorating with accent pieces, such as this art glass pitcher and matching tumbler is an excellent way to create a fun and an attractive setting. Otherwise, a mix-match of same sized glasses is a nice touch.
For a more elegant look, some etched glasses will do the trick. They have been popular for many years. When using a set that has the same design to accent a room, add some variety by mixing up the size of the glasses. Notice in the photo above, the background is black. Clear glasses will work best when there are some dramatic colors in the room to add contrast. For instance, these glasses would look striking on a dark blue or mahogany-colored shelf. Theyll look great in a dining room with walls painted a deep rich red or burgundy too.
Much of choosing which glasses are appropriate depends on your personal tastes. Attractive glasses are a small thing but taking the time to attend to all of the little details will infinitely improve the aesthetic quality of a home.
 EDITOR&apos;S NOTE: A special report for consumers. Please be careful when choosing your drinking glasses. According to this special report, some manufacturers are still allowed to use lead based paint for their designs. Please click here for the full story from KCBS Channel 2 in Los Angeles . 
 About the Author: 
 Reprinted with permission from the Sheffield School of Design 
 Did you enjoy this article? Rate
 It! | Tell A Friend 

 
 
 


  
 
 
 
 FamilyCorner.com Magazine on Facebook 

 
 Name: E-mail:   
 
 New Stuff 
 Missed the last couple of newsletters? Haven&apos;t visited for a while? This section highlights articles and crafts that have recently been added to FC...


 50 Summer Crafts, Recipes and Games 
 Rice Krispies Treat Birthday Balloons 
 10 Fun Crafts and Recipes for July 4th 
 10 Ways to Utilize Your Space Effectively 
 Dealing with Separation Anxiety 
 Disney Visa: Are the Savings Worth It For You? 
 Cardboard Tube Bracelet for a Princess 
 Tips to Get Your Picky Eater to Try Something New 
 Pampering Your Older Dog 
 Traveling with Toddlers 
 Cookie Crumb Cheesecake Caterpillars 

 
 
 Win Fun Stuff! 
 Check out all the fun goodies we are giving away here at FC...

 Check out all of our contests here! Giveaways change every couple of weeks, so be sure to check back often. Several giveaways going on at once!

 
 
 
 Summer Fun! 

 Summer heat is here. Whether you are looking for fun crafts, great recipes, fun family activities or travel tips, you&apos;ll find it all here. Here are a few examples to get you started...

 Craft: Ice Cream - 5 Cents! Building a Basic Backyard Sandbox Fantastic Family Reunions Fun Outdoor Play Heading Off Summer Boredom Teach Your Dog to Play Frisbee 

 More Holidays... 
 Camping Crafts, Recipes&amp;Tips Back to School Crafts, Recipes,&amp;Tips Labor Day 
 
Subscribe to RSS headline updates from: 
Powered by FeedBurner
 
 
 
 
 
 Flower Wand 
 
 Easy Bird Treats 
 
 Strawberry Pin 
 
 Litterbug Craft 
 
 

 
 
 
   

 OUR FRIENDS 
 Craft Supplies 
 Family Stickers 
 Children&apos;s Halloween Costumes 
 Letter Stencils 
 Family Costume Ideas 
 FamilyCorner The Blog 
 Amanda&apos;s Cooking Blog 
 Amanda&apos;s Craft Blog 
 MORE GOOD STUFF 
 Newsletters 
 Advertising 
 Services 
 Submissions 
 Media Opportunities 
 Link To Us 
 Shop 
 Feedback 
 Staff 
 POPULAR AREAS 
 Family FunBook 
 Forums 
 Kid&apos;s Crafts 
 Coloring Pages 
 Household Hints&amp;Tips 
 Photo Gallery 
 Blogs 
 e-Cards 
 Reminder Service 
 
 Contact Us | Copyright Notice | Privacy Policy | Terms of Use/Disclaimer 

Copyright© 1997-2012 FamilyCorner.com FamilyCorner.com®is a registered trademark of FamilyCorner.com, an Internet Brands Company
	</body>
</document>
