<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000340" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20090112183738AAxTbMG" time="2012-07-12-15:32" support="5" score="0.01601798831724349" bingtitle="What does accounting do in a fast food restaurant? - Yahoo! Answers" webtitle="What does accounting do in a fast food restaurant? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="001214" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="001191" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="001207" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="001218" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="001210" bing-rank="34"/>
	<description>Best Answer: You should be able to handle it. You will probably keep track of receipts and deposits. Maybe do payroll records, etc. I did that kind of work ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Business&amp;Finance &gt; Small Business &gt; Resolved Question 
 Tung L Member since: September 06, 2008 Total points: 100 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
What does accounting do in a fast food restaurant?
 I applied for a job in Del Taco and they ask me if i can do the accounting, I am a junior highschool student, Math is my favorite subject, I always get an A in math class and my computer skill is expert so should i get this job or it is too high for me? 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by stevepit... Member since: March 11, 2006 Total points: 16,597 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 You should be able to handle it. You will probably keep track of receipts and deposits. Maybe do payroll records, etc. I did that kind of work when I was in High School. If you are good with math, it should be easy. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 100% 1 Vote 
 1 person rated this as good 
 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (0)
 
No other answers.
 
Discover Questions in Small Business 

 Can I start an online business at the age of 13? What is the best bank for a small corporation and why? Why does my father not respect what I do for a living? Setting up a computer business? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Related Questions

 Where can I get a standard chart of accounts for a restaurant? where can you find restaurant accounting software? What does an account manager do? What all do you do in Accounting? What do accountants do on a daily basis? 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Business&amp;Finance 
 Advertising&amp;Marketing Careers&amp;Employment Corporations Credit Insurance Investing Other - Business&amp;Finance Personal Finance Renting&amp;Real Estate Small Business Taxes 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
