<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000879" url="http://www.usatoday.com/money/industries/food/2011-06-30-fast-food-restaurants-offering-alcohol_n.htm" time="2012-07-12-16:14" support="44" score="0.33238380505840237" bingtitle="Sonic, Burger King, other fast-food chains selling alcohol ..." webtitle="Sonic, Burger King, other fast-food chains selling alcohol - USATODAY.com">
			<query id="001512" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000532" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001104" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000118" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="001116" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000104" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000372" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="001521" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000351" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000360" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="001372" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000550" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000383" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="001121" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="001524" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="001475" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000547" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="001348" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000095" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="001113" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="000227" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="001490" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000363" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000901" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000884" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="000893" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="001533" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="001500" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="000368" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000220" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="001376" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="000896" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000905" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000110" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000120" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="001493" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="001498" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000113" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="001529" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001125" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="001484" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="001364" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="001502" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000122" bing-rank="73"/>
	<description>Beer or wine sold at fast-food outlets might give young folks the wrong message, adds Christopher Muller, dean at Boston University&apos;s School of Hospitality ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Main Content 
 USA TODAY 



 Subscribe Mobile 
 
 Home News Travel Money Sports Life Your Life Tech Weather 
 
Sonic, Burger King, other fast-food chains selling alcohol
 
 By Bruce Horovitz, USA TODAY 
 
Updated |
    |    Share Reprints&amp;Permissions 
The trip to the fast-food joint that was once all about burgers and fries is increasingly about something that could require you to flash your ID: beer and wine.
 
 
Sonic

 The grand opening of a Sonic in Homestead, Fla., that will be one of two Florida Sonics to begin serving beer and wine later this summer. 
 
 Enlarge Close 
Sonic

The grand opening of a Sonic in Homestead, Fla., that will be one of two Florida Sonics to begin serving beer and wine later this summer.
 
In a bid to boost business, two Sonic restaurants in South Florida soon will sell beer and wine. The move follows Burger King &quot;Whopper Bars&quot; recently opened in Miami, Las Vegas and Kansas City that sell beer. Starbucks recently began to serve local beer and wine in a handful of Seattle stores.

In a tough economy, the move towards alcohol is a way to compete with casual dining—and can help boost typically slow evening business, says Ron Paul , president at Technomic, a restaurant consulting firm. &quot;For consumers, it&apos;s basically about having it your way—even if it&apos;s having a beer with your burger.&quot;

But the trend has critics .

&quot;Fast food plus fast alcohol equals fast drunks,&quot; warns Michele Simon, research and policy director at the Marin Institute , an alcohol industry watchdog group.

 
STORY: Starbucks remakes its future with eye on beer and wine 
 
VIDEO: Take a behind-the-scenes tour of a new Starbucks 
 
STORY: Burger King plans beer-selling Whopper Bar in South Beach 
 

Beer or wine sold at fast-food outlets might give young folks the wrong message, adds Christopher Muller, dean at Boston University&apos;s School of Hospitality Administration. &quot;You don&apos;t want someone downing a quick beer, then getting into their cars and driving off. It&apos;s a delicate balance of risk and reward.&quot;

Several fast-food chains clearly consider the reward worth the risk:

 •Sonic. Later this summer, the chain plans its first attempt to sell alcohol at two new locations: one in Miami and one in Fort Lauderdale . The Miami unit will sell three types of draft beer, 25 kinds of bottled beer and 10 varieties of wine to customers who eat on its patio—but not to folks in cars, says Drew Ritger, SVP of business analysis. The Fort Lauderdale location will only sell beer and wine inside.

&quot;We look at this as an opportunity to drive evening business in this market,&quot; says Ritger, who says there are no plans to expand alcohol sales outside of South Florida.

 •Burger King. Besides the three domestic Whopper Bars that serve beer, there are three others that also serve brews in Singapore, Venezuela and Spain, says spokeswoman Lauren Kuzniar. A cold brew at a domestic Whopper Bar fetches about $4.25.

 •Starbucks. Four Starbucks coffee shops in the Seattle area now sell beer and wine, and a fifth will begin selling alcoholic beverages in September, says spokeswoman Lisa Passe. Beer goes for $5 a bottle, and a glass of wine for up to $9.

 • Pizza Hut . The chain has sold beer for decades in many dine-in locations, and a handful of delivery/carry-out locations offer it, says spokesman Chris Fuller. A brew sells for up to $3.

 
 For more information about reprints&amp;permissions , visit our FAQ&apos;s. To report corrections and clarifications, contact Standards Editor Brent Jones . For publication consideration in the newspaper, send comments to letters@usatoday.com . Include name, phone number, city and state for verification. To view our corrections, go to corrections.usatoday.com . 
Posted | Updated 
 Share We&apos;ve updated the Conversation Guidelines. Changes include a brief review of the moderation process and an explanation on how to use the &quot;Report Abuse&quot; button. Read more . 
Advertisement
 
Most Popular E-mail Newsletter
 
Sign up to get:

Top viewed stories, photo galleries and community posts of the day

 Most popular right now: 
 
USA TODAY Digital Services

 Mobile E-Newsletters RSS Twitter Podcasts Widgets e-Edition USA TODAY for iPad Kindle Edition Subscribe to Home Delivery 

 Reprints&amp;Permissions USA TODAY Topics Reporter Index Corrections/Clarifications Contact Us Archives 
 
 Home News Travel Money Sports Life Tech Weather 

 Visit our Partners: USA WEEKEND Sports Weekly Education Space.com Travel Tips 
 
 Contact us Advertise Pressroom Jobs FAQ Reprints/Permissions Privacy Notice/Your California Privacy Rights Ad Choices Terms of Service Site Index 

©2012 USA TODAY, a division of Gannett Co. Inc.
	</body>
</document>
