<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000320" url="http://www.simplybusinessesforsale.com/spain/valencia/valencia/undisclosed/fast-food-restaurant-take-away-shop-in-undisclosed-sp1026c-1701/" time="2012-07-12-15:30" support="11" score="0.04089105099534582" bingtitle="Buy a Subway Fast Food Restaurant, Take Away Shop in Undisclosed ..." webtitle="Buy a Subway Fast Food Restaurant, Take Away Shop in Undisclosed SP1026C in Valencia, Spain business for sale. EUR95,000.00">
			<query id="001278" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="000727" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="001261" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000059" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="001264" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000743" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="000687" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="001282" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000047" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000747" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000749" bing-rank="68"/>
	<description>Subway Fast Food Restaurant, Take Away Shop in Undisclosed SP1026C ... SUBWAY &apos;Sandwich Artists&apos; begin making customers&apos; sandwiches on varied selection of daily baked ...</description>
	<body>
		Homepage Buy a Business Sell a Business Broker Search For Brokers Log-in Register    
Buy a Business
 
Search businesses for sale in over 180 countries worldwide.
 Keywords: 
 Country (optional): 
 Any Country United Kingdom United States Canada Australia New Zealand South Africa Spain ------------------------ Afghanistan Albania Algeria Andorra Angola Antigua and Barbuda Argentina Armenia Australia Austria Azerbaijan Bahamas, The Bahrain Bangladesh Barbados Belarus Belgium Belize Benin Bermuda Bhutan Bolivia Bosnia and Herzegovina Botswana Brazil Bulgaria Burkina Faso Burma Burundi Cambodia Cameroon Canada Cape Verde Central African Republic Chad Chile China Colombia Comoros Congo, Democratic Republic of the Congo, Republic of the Costa Rica Cote d&apos;Ivoire Croatia Cuba Cyprus Czech Republic Denmark Djibouti Dominica Dominican Republic Ecuador Egypt El Salvador Equatorial Guinea Eritrea Estonia Ethiopia Falkland Islands Fiji Finland France Gabon Gambia, The Georgia Germany Ghana Gibraltar Greece Greenland Grenada Guatemala Guinea Guinea-Bissau Guyana Haiti Honduras Hungary Iceland India Indonesia Iran Iraq Ireland Israel Italy Jamaica Japan Jordan Kazakhstan Kenya Korea, North Korea, South Kuwait Kyrgyzstan Laos Latvia Lebanon Lesotho Liberia Libya Liechtenstein Lithuania Luxembourg Macedonia Madagascar Malawi Malaysia Maldives Mali Malta Mauritania Mauritius Mexico Micronesia, Federated States of Moldova Monaco Mongolia Montenegro Montserrat Morocco Mozambique Namibia Nepal Netherlands New Zealand Nicaragua Niger Nigeria Norway Oman Pakistan Panama Papua New Guinea Paraguay Peru Philippines Poland Portugal Qatar Republic of Singapore Romania Russia Rwanda Saint Kitts and Nevis Saint Lucia Saint Vincent and the Grenadines San Marino Sao Tome and Principe Saudi Arabia Senegal Serbia Seychelles Sierra Leone Slovakia Slovenia Solomon Islands Somalia South Africa Spain Sri Lanka Sudan Suriname Swaziland Sweden Switzerland Syria Taiwan Tajikistan Tanzania Thailand Togo Tonga Trinidad and Tobago Tunisia Turkey Turkmenistan Uganda Ukraine United Arab Emirates United Kingdom United States Uruguay Uzbekistan Vanuatu Venezuela Vietnam Virgin Islands Yemen Zambia Zimbabwe Sector (optional): 
 Any Sector Agriculture Engineering Food Franchise Resales Leisure Manufacturing Real Estate Retail Services Tech, I.T&amp;Media Wholesale&amp;Distribution Industry (optional): 
 Any Industry 
 
Subway Fast Food Restaurant, Take Away Shop in Undisclosed SP1026C - Business For Sale

 Undisclosed, Valencia, Spain 
 Contact Seller Printable View Send To A Friend Agents Profile Listing: 1701 | 
 Ref: Unspecified | 
 Agent: 98 
 Asking Price: EUR€95,000.00 Gross Income: Undisclosed Cash Flow: Undisclosed Fixtures&amp;Fittings: Undisclosed Stock&amp;Inventory: Undisclosed Owner Financing: No Terms of Sale: Unspecified 
 
Business Description

The SUBWAY Franchise system places a focus on making great sandwiches. It is so great, in fact, that many SUBWAY custoemrs have become franchise owners simply because they believe in the product.

SUBWAY Franchise offers
24 hour potential with hot menu items
Flexible floor plans
Simple operations, no frying or grease
Trusted brand recognition
Well trained team of people striving to exceed customers needs
Dedicated headquarters personnel and local support network

Customers want
A quick, tasty and portable meal
Attentive customer service
A meal prepared just the way they want
Nutritious Choices to eat right
Affordable, value focused menu

SUBWAY food includes
Nutritious menu choices
Flexible food options for mutiple day-parts
Gourmet breads, sauces and toppings
Hot meals and subs toasted to perfection
Fresh subs, salads and wraps made to order

The SUBWAY franchise was named the #1 Global Franchising Opportunity by Entrepeneur Magazine in 2008.

The SUBWAY business goal is to be the number one restaurant/store chain in both consumer ranking and location count in every market it serves.

In most years about 70% of SUBWAY franchises are purchased by exisiting franchisees.

Exceptional growth
With the SUBWAY franchise system&apos;s outstanding support structure and operational history, it&apos;s no surprise that its growth continues to break global records.

Great food
SUBWAY &apos;Sandwich Artists&apos; begin making customers&apos; sandwiches on varied selection of daily baked gourmet breads. With the option of many ingredients, the sandwiches are customized with an array of meats, cheeses and vegetables and topped off with unique select sauces. In addition, many food flavours are brought out by toasting the sandwiches to perfection, just the way a customer wants.

Décor
Tuscany décor integrates the look of natural building materials - brick, clay, stone - into the stores and conveys to customers that SUBWAY locations are warm and inviting family dining destinations.

Products you will be proud to serve
The SUBWAY franchise offers your cstomers man great options to eat a fresh meal, fast. Think about your customer base and all the potential consumers who patronize your business. Wouldn&apos;t the quality of the SUBWAY products appeal to those consumers

SUBWAY FRESH FIT Menu
Caring about the health of customers shows with the SUBWAY FRESH FIT menu that is low in sturated fat and cholesterol and is trans fat free.

The franchisee is responsible for:
Initial franchise fee
Finding locations
Leasehold improvements and equipment
Hiring employees and operating restaurants

The company provides:
Access to formulas and operational systems
Store design and equipment ordering guidance
Training program
Operations manual
Representative on-site during opening
Periodic evaluations and ongoing support
Informative publications

Investment
A SUBWAY franchise has some of the lowest start-up costs in the industry. Your complete investment will depend on your location, size and the extent of renovations required. Enquire now for a detailed investment Capital Requirements worksheet.

 
Detailed Information

 Website: http://rta-europe.com/?q=Property/PropertyDetail&amp;refno;=SP1026C 
 Additional Media 
 Video Presentation No Videos Uploads Available 
 
 Download Files 
 Download Files No Download Files Available 
 Welcome | Register an account  |  Log into my account Key Info: Marketed by: Business Broker Spain 
 Contact: Click here 
 Rating: 
 
 Location: 
 Spain » Valencia » Valencia » Undisclosed 
 Categories: 
 Franchise Resales » Food Franchises » Fast Food Franchises 
 Food » Restaurants » Take Aways 
 Food » Cafés » Sandwich Shops&amp;Delivery 

 Type: Franchise | 
Didn&apos;t find what you were looking for?

 Find more businesses for sale located in: 

 Undisclosed, Valencia, Spain Valencia, Spain Spain 

 Find businesses for sale by industry: 

 Franchise Resales | Food Franchises | Fast Food Franchises Food | Restaurants | Take Aways Food | Cafés | Sandwich Shops&amp;Delivery 
 
 All information in this listing has been submitted by the business seller or representative stated above. SimplyBusinessesForSale.com has no stakehold in the sale of this business, has not independently verified any of the information about the business or the listing and assumes no responsibility for its accuracy or completeness. Please read our Terms&amp;Conditions before responding to any business for sale advertisement. 
 
 Advice for Sellers | Advice for Buyers | Help&amp;FAQs | Link To Us | Get Email Updates | Website Design 
 Businesses Wanted | Press Room | Follow Our Blog | Terms&amp;Conditions | Privacy Policy | Contact Us | Site Map 
 UK | USA | Canada | Australia | New Zealand | South Africa | Spain 

Copyright©2009 - 2012 Simply.Biz Internet Limited. v2.1.2 |  Get RSS Feeds

 
 
By using this site, you agree to the use of cookies. More Info... Accept
	</body>
</document>
