<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000036" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/article/5428802/how_to_place_an_order_at_a_fast_food.html" time="2012-07-12-15:13" support="25" score="0.15656506796733716" bingtitle="How to Place an Order at a Fast Food Restaurant Drive-Thru Window ..." webtitle="How to Place an Order at a Fast Food Restaurant Drive-Thru Window - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="000802" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000807" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000905" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000113" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000865" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="000101" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000789" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000813" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="001355" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="001418" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="001367" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000783" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="001376" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000790" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000799" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000443" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000893" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000811" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000970" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="001189" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="001504" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000122" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000110" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000456" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="001364" bing-rank="89"/>
	<description>How to Place an Order at a Fast Food Restaurant Drive-Thru ... meal order at a fast food restaurant drive-thru: Step 1 - Drive your car or other ... Step 8 - Exit the drive ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 
 
How to Place an Order at a Fast Food Restaurant Drive-Thru Window

Getting You from Fast Food Drive-Thru Approach to Exit in 8 Simple Steps
 LIVIN , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
Jun 4, 2010 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: Fast Food Fast Food Restaurants Worst Fast Food Best Fast Food 
 Flag Close Post a comment The first four steps to successfully placing a meal order at a fast food restaurant drive-thru: 
Step 1 - Drive your car or other automobile up to the first billboard menu of the drive-thru lane.

Step 2 - Honk your horn. This will alert everyone that you are &quot;on deck&quot; to place your fast food order.

Step 3 - When you pull up to the fast food drive thru teller, honk once again. This will alert the teller that you are ready to place your fast food order.

Step 4 - Place a typical order for everything you might desire in a given fast food meal. Then, order an additional item that is not on the menu. When you are told the last item is not available, simply respond by saying, &quot;In that case, can I change my order?&quot;

 The last four steps to successfully placing a meal order at a fast food restaurant drive thru: 

Step 5 - Place an entirely new drive-thru order. Be creative.

Step 6 - Honk once again. This will signify that you have successfully ordered your meal from a fast food drive-thru.

Step 7 - When you pull up to the last drive-thru teller to pay, ask the teller if she can hold your order. Tell her you left your money at home.

Step 8 - Exit the drive-thru lane and drive away. Congratulations, you have successfully placed an order at a fast food drive-thru.
 
Published by LIVIN 

Writer of extraordinary tales, elaborate yarns and perfectly poetic prose, LIVIN has travelled the globe in search of the poopiest stories and terrifically tall tales. LIVIN has written in every realm of th...  View profile 
 
 Fast Food Restaurants The growing problem of Fast Food Restaurants lacking when it comes to good customer service and following instructions. How to Find Healthier Fast Food Fast food options with the lowest combination of calories, fat, and sodium. It is Possible to Order Healthy Items at a Fast Food Restaurant Think you have to order 1,000 calorie meals just because you are eating at a Fast Food Restaurant ? Think Again , there are ways to work the menu to your advantage. Fast Food Failures What if someone put together a list of all the really bad fast food restaurants? What if that someone was me? Breaking the Fast Food Habit Fast food is bad for you. Here&apos;s how to break the habit of eating it. 

 Make Your Own Fast Food with No... Health To Go: How To Order Wisel... The Drive-In Cafe Commercial 
 
 Healthy Choices at Fast Food Restaurants Beat the High Cost of Food: Make Your Own Fast Food Consumers Taking a Legal Stand Against Fast Food Can You Really Eat Healthy Fast Food? Is Fast Food Too Fast? Eat Fast Food and Still Be Healthy What Kind of Fast Food Tonight? 
 
 
 
18 Comments
 Post a Comment 
 LIVIN 3/27/2012 
For those that do not realize this is a joke - this is a joke.
 OLD NURSE 3/4/2011 
This is very rude. Theses folks at Mc&apos;ds work very hard. Bless them -don&apos;t trouble them!
 Michael Segers 9/17/2010 
Great fun!
 Jeanne Baney 8/10/2010 
This was hilarious! Loved it!
 Lynn Mason 7/31/2010 
Haha, good thing you didn&apos;t pick up the food because the kids behinde the counter were spitting in it by this time! I always say McThank-you at McDonalds :o)
 Kristen Wilkerson 6/7/2010 
Great! lol
 Delicia Powers 6/5/2010 
Funny.
 Victoria Lucas 6/5/2010 
Oh my goodness, lol ! I was thinking that the person who wrote this is very rude at the drive-thru, then it hit me ;-) hehe. Very nice! (Particularly being on-deck, hahaha)
 Linda Louise Johnson 6/4/2010 
This is a hoot, but I know you don&apos;t really do it, funny as it may be.
 Randy Inman 6/4/2010 
My uncles used to get drunk and make their wives drive them to Burger King to order Big Macs. When the poor sap at the drive through said they didn&apos;t sell Big Macs there, my uncles would scream insults at them. Yes I may be kin to Rednecks.
 
 Displaying Comments «Prev 1 2 Next» 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Shine and Lifestyles Network. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
