<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000669" url="http://www.swordbrother.com/ramblings/fastfood/" time="2012-07-12-15:58" support="4" score="0.006910534063704673" bingtitle="Swordbrother.com : Rambling : Carl&apos;s Junior League" webtitle="Swordbrother.com : Rambling : Carl&apos;s Junior League">
			<query id="000221" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="000721" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="001130" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="000250" bing-rank="153"/>
	<description>People have given me the wrong size drink, and ... of frustration I have ever had at a fast food restaurant this ... I went up to the counter, ordered my food, got my drink, and ...</description>
	<body>
		New | Comics 
 
comics
 Bee Police 
 What have I done for you lately 
 Next-Genned 
 Cats: Kilah in heat 
 Bees: Pancakes for Dinner 
 Mall Santa 
 Bees: Tik Tak Pow! 
 Bees: Retail Therapy 
 Naval Camo 
 Bees: Down the tubes 
 Bees: Negotiating a hostage release 
 Bee in a Jar 
 Out with the Old in with the Pew 
 Thanksgiving Cats 
 Waking the Lion 
 Cats In Space 
 Cats to the moon 
 Chicken-Cat 
 Getting Her Number(s) 
 Cats: Getting the run-around 
 
 | Home 
 
home
 shooting a pole 
 Carl&apos;s Junior League 
 Ancient Older Stories 
 Ron&apos;s Restaurant Reviews 
 Narnia Revisited 
 Bacterial Marketing 
 Goblet of Fire 
 Weddings 
 Evolution by Design 
 Photography 
 World Perspective 
 The Good, The Bad, and The Kitten 
 Happy Festivus 
 Resumé 
 High School Recipes 
 Contact Me 

Photos
 R&amp;A;wedding photos 
 Damning photos 
 David&amp;Melissa Rehersal Dinner 
 Kathie&amp;Clayton&apos;s Wedding 

Restaurant Reviews
 Denny&apos;s Debacle 
 El Azteca 
 King Buffet 
 Zack&apos;s 
 Pepe&apos;s Fine Mexican Food 
 Los Caballos 
 Marie Callender&apos;s 
 
 | S.C.A. 
 
S.C.A.
 Leohtulf and Gillian Investiture 
 New Shoes 
 SCA Limericks 
 Torvald&apos;s Knees 
 Local Branch Search Engine 
 Hardened Leather 
 Fighting 
 Fall Investure 2004 

Fighting
 October Coronet 2009 
 Wolfscairn Fighting videos 
 Older Wolfscairn Fighting videos 
 Tarnmist Practice 
 San Jose Practice 
 Fighting videos 
 June Crown 2009 
 Fixing Leather Armor 
 Making a Fishbat 
 Tourney Fighting 
 More Tourney Fighting 
 Fighting for Consorts 
 War Fighting 
 
 | Art&amp;Design 
 
 
Analog Art
 Arthur, Guenevier,&amp;Lancelot 
 Princess Muriel sketch 
 Paper Waterfall 
 Ron SD 
 Climber 
 Shell 
 Gorget and Pauldrons 
 Connect 
 Owl 
 Mermaid 
 Watercolor Portrait 
 Hammer 
 Horse 
 Vampire Princess Miyu 

Design
 Sable Wolf 
 Modern Maya 
 E&apos;s 
 T is for Turtle 
 Website 2.0 
 Big Blue 
 Jamaica Red Ale 
 SF Jazz Festival 
 Mill Valley Film Festival 
 Percussion 
 Seattle 
 
Digital Art
 Dragon Art 
 Cybervision 
 Face 
 Vampire Princess Miyu 2 
 Bubblegum Dinosaurs 
 View Down 
 Wasp 
 Buildings 
 Coffee Cup 
 Mermaid 2 
 Alien 
 ET TV 
 Fat Man 
 Rocks of Despair 
 Run 
 Sitting 
 Typewriter 
 What 
 Wheel and Reel 

Photography
 Leon and Muriel Photo Edit 
 Achmere and Leohtulf 
 Queen and Knight 
 Self Portrait 
 Gauntlets 
 
 
 | Scripting 
 
Coding Stories
 Old printer meet windows 7 
 CSS and Printing 
 Bricolage on Linux 
 Hating the Gnome 
 Javascript 
 HTML 
 Installing Bricolage 
 Perl: Make XML for Image Import 

JavaScript Stories
 Image Loaded Script 
 Nav scripts 
 Image Popup windows 
 
 | Gaming 
 
Miniatures
 Barbarian Leader 
 Barbarian 
 Sword Maiden 
 Fighter 

Roleplaying
 Warcraft 
 Stephen R. Donaldson-itis 
 Glory Days and D&amp;D; 
 Miniatures 
 Making Characters 
 
 | Ramblings 
 
Ramblings
 Hamas&amp;Fatah 
 Fear the Mighty DVR 
 Leftovers 
 Anime Meaningless? 
 Stonehenge Hijinks 
 21st century flop 
 Cellphone Manners 
 Iran&amp;Nuclear Power 

Politics
 Voting day stress 
 Angry White Woman 
 The Fourth Branch 
 
 | SCA Search 
 
 
Carl&apos;s Junior League
 Search Swordbrother.com 
 

 Rambling Stories 
 Hamas&amp;Fatah 
 Fear the Mighty DVR 
 Leftovers 
 Anime Meaningless? 
 Stonehenge Hijinks 
 21st century flop 
 Cellphone Manners 
 Iran&amp;Nuclear Power 
 
At some point, the people at fast food joints stopped speaking the same language as you and I. I stopped being able to say &quot;6 dollar burger, no cheese, make it large.&quot; without the counter help immediately asking me If I wanted cheese.

Over the last few months, I&apos;ve regularly had to take burgers back to get one without cheese. People have given me the wrong size drink, and theres innumerable times I&apos;ve orderd a double burger and got a single. At some establishments, I&apos;ve even had to take various chicken burgers, fish burgers and random other things I did not order back to the counter.

I think I reached the highest level of frustration I have ever had at a fast food restaurant this Last Monday at Carl&apos;s Junior. Yes, I&apos;m going to point the finger at this particular restaurant. It&apos;s the one on Industrial, right off of Cleveland, across from K-mart.

I&apos;ve had my share of little problems at this Carl&apos;s, but they pale compared to what happened on Monday. I decided to get a burger to go between repair stops. I figured it would be quicker to order at the counter and eat at the red lights on my way to my next stop.

I went up to the counter, ordered my food, got my drink, and realized I needed to wash my hands. I left my drink on the counter along with the &quot;to-go&quot; tag. Knowing I didn&apos;t have much time, I dashed to the rest room and got back as fast as possible. It must have taken a minute or two at the most.

I got back to the counter, picked up my drink and number, and watched as two or three large groups of people came and went. As I waited some more, various burgers were made, and taken to the customers. A truck in the drive-through got a burger. All this time, I was standing at the counter, holding my tag, looking at the counter help and the manager, waiting for my burger.

About ten minutes into my waiting, I noticed that there was a burger-box sitting on the counter in front of the kitchen window. The Manager was busy counting money, and would not meet my gaze. The cashier rang up people, and would not look at me. The girl delivering food to customers ignored my now fuming glare as I stood there, holding my big yellow &quot;to-go&quot; number at arms length and shoulder height, looking at each of them in turn.

Finally, I bellowed at the three of them &quot;Excuse me, could ONE of you give me my burger? It&apos;s been sitting there for the last ten minutes! By the way, HERE&apos;S MY NUMBER!&quot; I then stood there and quietly waited for another minute while they searched their video screen, then got me my fries.

At this point, you would think they would just ask me if I ordered fries, and perhaps throw in a complimentary slice of pie as a mea culpa, but none of them even said anything like &quot;Oh, I&apos;m sorry, we didn&apos;t mean to ignore you for an inexcusable amount of time while we gave food to a bunch of other people, and counted our money.&quot; I don&apos;t think any of them are capable of forming such a complicated sentence.

Finally, as I stormed to my work van, a dark thought occurred to me. I popped open the black and white box, pealed back the paper diaper, and pulled off the top half of the bun. Well, at least they didn&apos;t put CHEESE on it.

 

 © 2012 Ronald K. Neal

 What&apos;s New | Contact Me | Overview
	</body>
</document>
