<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000329" url="http://www.customersatisfactionsurveyguide.com/old-navy-customer-experience-survey-www-survey4on-com/" time="2012-07-12-15:31" support="5" score="0.004430718525942538" bingtitle="Old Navy Customer Experience Survey – www.Survey4on.com ..." webtitle="www.Survey4on.com - Old Navy Customer Experience Survey">
			<query id="000397" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="000740" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="000930" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000992" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="001405" bing-rank="104"/>
	<description>A few of them are based on details on your receipt. ... Old Navy does not expect their customers to waste ... Fast Food Restaurant customer satisfaction surveys</description>
	<body>
		Home 
 You are here : Survey Beat » Fashion Retail Surveys »www.Survey4on.com–Old Navy Customer Experience Survey 
www.Survey4on.com–Old Navy Customer Experience Survey
 Posted By admin On Monday, February 20, 2012 05:25 AM. Under  Fashion Retail Surveys    
The Old Navy Customer Experience Survey, found at www.Survey4on.com, is an online survey designed by Old Navy that gives customers a chance to leave feedback on services and products. The company uses this information to work harder to meet consumer needs. This is an online survey, which means you can take it whenever you want.

By participating in this survey, you give valuable, important feedback to the company. They then use your information to improve customer service as well as products. As a reward for participating, you will receive a code word to get 15 percent off your next purchase from Old Navy. You can leave feedback without receiving the coupon by simply closing the browser.

You will not have to give any personal information in order to fill out this survey or to recent the discount.

 About Old Navy Company 

Old Navy is a clothing brand. Their store sells their brand exclusively, as well as other specialty brands affiliated with Old Navy. This is an upscale store, but has affordable prices. They were founded in 1994 and have many stores across the US.

They offer clothing for women, men, and children. They also have shoes and accessories.

 How to Participate in the Old Navy Customer Experience Survey ? 

 You Will Need:
 

 Have a computer with Internet access. Be able to read English, Spanish, or French. Have a recent receipt from an Old Navy store. 

 Steps To Do Survey: 
 

 Go to www.Survey4on.com . Select the language you prefer to take the survey in. Click Begin Survey. Answer the demographic questions asked, such as age and gender. You will be asked to enter the store number. There is a diagram above the text box so you know where to find this information. You will be asked questions based on your most recent experiences. Please answer these questions thoroughly and honestly. You have to answer all questions on the page before moving on. At the end of the survey, you will receive a special code that entitles you to a 15 percent discount on your next purchase. Please write this code down and present next time you shop at Old Navy. 
 
30 Responses to “www.Survey4on.com–Old Navy Customer Experience Survey” 
 
 Elicia says: March 22, 2012 at 6:51 am 
Old navy the people are really nice and helpful.
 Reply 
 Rhonda Harding says: April 12, 2012 at 1:01 am 
I agree…Amy was a great employee…
 Reply 
 Cavelline says: April 2, 2012 at 10:17 pm 
Shopping at Old Navy has always been a pleasant experience. Customer service is top priority and the staff put out a lot of effort to assist.
 Reply tania garcia says: April 5, 2012 at 4:40 am 
Great experience
 Reply 
 tania garcia says: April 5, 2012 at 4:41 am 
Friendly staff and inexpensive items
 Reply 
 connie says: April 9, 2012 at 12:31 am 
Enjoy Tyrone Sq. location in St. Pete Fl for children’a clothing—
 Reply Rhonda Harding says: April 12, 2012 at 1:02 am 
Amy was the best employee…..
 Reply Alejandra garibay says: April 13, 2012 at 12:43 am 
Mi experiencia en la tienda fue muy impresionada por que habia muchas ofertas que me quede con el ojo cuadrado,me gusta este tipo de ropa es muy durable,tienen el personal muy amable esa fue mi experiencia gracias.
 Reply nisreen says: April 16, 2012 at 1:34 am 
I love shopping from old navy great quality and the people realy nice
 Reply Sharece Gallon says: April 18, 2012 at 2:59 pm 
The survey was to long and I had to sign up for things I didn’t want. I love old navy and I spend alot of money every time I go. Please send me coupons online thank you for your time. Sharece Gallon
 Reply Pam says: April 18, 2012 at 9:42 pm 
I just wanted to say how very much I love the old navy @ 4th&amp;market in s.f., I am in the store always at least once a wk, sometimes 2-3 times a wk,&amp;very rarely leave empty handed. The staff is amazing…so helpful, so friendly…always greeting me with a smile…always ready to help. Yesterday, I met a wonderful lady, her name is Wanda Felix&amp;she has worked there for a number of years..we had a nice conversation&amp;will probably run into each other on one of my many shopping trips., I feel like I have made a bunch of new friends…some of the staff there recognize me now…its a good feeling. Thank you to the awesome staff at o.n. s.f.
 Reply Francine Biddle says: April 18, 2012 at 11:58 pm 
love the store and everything about it.
 Reply Magzie says: April 19, 2012 at 11:27 pm 
I shopped on 4/18/2012 at the Methuen Loop Old Navy. Valerie was my check out lady. She was terrific. There was a pregant women that fainted in front of me in line. I was able to help her to a gentle landing.. But Valerie the lady at the checkout got on her phone an in seconds things started happening.. She was in full emergency mode.. She should be commended.
 Reply Ora Hardy says: April 20, 2012 at 12:51 pm 
on April 16,2012 I was at Old Navy looking for two bright colored outfits for my 8 year old son whose size is a 10 and my 7 year old daughter whose size is also a 10. I must say the floor runners/ employees were very helpful. They took out the time to help me find and match up two beautiful outfits for my kids. The cashier whom name i managed to get Janise was extremely helpful also. I had some jeans that was not on the Price Lock Sale and she took out the time to show me each and every pair pants that were on the Price Lock Sale and even considered nice tops that would go with da pants. Old Navy has the best employees that i know. Thank you guys for all your help. Signed: A VERY HAPPY AND LOYAL CUSTOMER
 Reply michele silcock says: April 27, 2012 at 4:44 pm 
I love shopping at old navy, because they always have what I need!
 Reply terry leinum says: April 30, 2012 at 11:47 pm 
service was great-love the fashion
 Reply Colleen Pryce says: May 7, 2012 at 12:21 am 
I love shopping at Old Navy, because they always have good stuff for myself and grand-daughter.Customer Service is excellent.
 Reply lisa perry says: May 9, 2012 at 2:53 pm 
lorna was very pleasent.every store need someone as plesant and joyfull as she was.had a great day at old navy.
 Reply roddie mils says: May 10, 2012 at 8:58 pm 
old navy is the best
 Reply Vanessa says: May 12, 2012 at 9:03 pm 
I went through the entire survey and was not given a code!!! WTF?
 Reply tanika love says: May 13, 2012 at 12:26 am 
I love old navy and the sales
 Reply Marianela says: May 13, 2012 at 9:15 pm 
I love old navy because they have good sale .
 Reply marie says: May 17, 2012 at 6:04 am 
I vote for Makoya in Fargo ND to get an award for great customer service From Marie , todays customer (16th May)
 Reply angeli says: May 17, 2012 at 6:07 am 
staff are friendly and accommodating…
 Reply R. Zimmerman says: May 19, 2012 at 3:46 am 
At the end of the survey I was not given a code . Was that because I had a bad experience?
 Reply Sarah says: May 22, 2012 at 6:28 pm 
Friendly staff
 Reply carolina luna says: May 23, 2012 at 1:22 am 
i like the store, the clothes and the employees.
 Reply Rebecca drews says: May 25, 2012 at 7:59 pm 
Monica Helped me today a lot. both in the fitting room and on the floor while shopping for my son. she is extremely enthusiastic about her job.
 Reply 
 
Leave a Reply
 Click here to cancel reply. 
 Name (required) 

 E-Mail (required) 

 Website (Optional) 

 

 
 «  www.Talktosonic.com–Sonic Drive-In Guest Satisfaction Survey www.Placesurvey.com–The Children’s Place Customer Satisfaction Survey  » 
 
Survey Categories

 Automotive Surveys Bar Surveys Coffee Surveys Computer Electronics Surveys Department Store Surveys Fashion Retail Surveys Fast Food Restaurant Surveys Footwear Surveys Grocery Store Surveys Hardware Store Surveys Home Furnishings Surveys Office Supply Surveys Pet Store Surveys Pharmacy Surveys Pizza Surveys Restaurant Surveys Retail Surveys Smoothie Juice Surveys 
 
 
 
Pages

 About Us Privacy Policy SiteMap Terms of Use Why Do Companies Give Out Customer Satisfaction Surveys? 
 
 Lorama WordPress Theme By Printer Ink Thanks to Classifieds and Cheap Laptops Copyright©2012. All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
