<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000854" url="http://www.personalpowertraining.net/Articles/Why_is_Fast_Food_so_Bad.htm" time="2012-07-12-16:13" support="8" score="0.05441747749834408" bingtitle="Why is Fast Food so Bad - Personal Trainer Scottsdale | Fitness ..." webtitle="Why is Fast Food so Bad">
			<query id="001122" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000907" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000369" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000887" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="001535" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="001127" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000902" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="001160" bing-rank="44"/>
	<description>Why is Fast Food so Bad, learn why fast food is so teribble for you and your body and ... So if we are given an extra large fry, we should be thankful and eat the whole ...</description>
	<body>
		Personal Trainer, 
 Personal Training Arizona, Phoenix, Scottsdale Scott White. Hire a Certified personal Trainer 
   Scott 
 White 
 
 
 Personal Training 

   

 Results 
 Today!! 
     
 Web PersonalPowerTraining.net 
 
 
 
 Sign up for Fitness Facts, 
 get personal training secrets Name:   Email: 
 
 Private Personal Training Studio Call Now: 
 480-628-1607 Personal Training 
 in Arizona, Phoenix, Scottsdale, Paradise Valley 
 
 

 
   
 Personal Trainer AZ Trainers Scott White Programs Fit Equipment Fitness Models Fitness Books Fit Articles Online Trainer Supplements Fitness VIdeo Fitness Q&amp;A training facts Testimonials Contact Us Fitness Forums phone trainer Fitness Store Photos Site Map Studio Resources Hire a 
 Trainer Fitness BootCamp Female Fit 
 Model Male Fitness Model Female 
 Bodybuilder Male 
 Bodybuilder FAQ&apos;s Fitness Model 
 Book 
 Figure Competition Guide 
 Link to us 
 Arizona 
 Massage 
 Media 
 Personal Trainer Blog 

 Subscribe Now! Newsletter Weight loss Calculators   
 

  
 
 
 
 
 Why is Fast Food so Bad 

 

 

Fast food is very tempting to consumers because of its 
convenience. Its so easy to swing through the drive thru on your way home from 
work, starving, and order a super size extra value meal for yourself, spouse, 
and kids. The food is fairly cheap and you usually wont spend more than five 
minutes in line. If the food that fast food companies are serving were actually 
good for you this would be an ideal situation. However this is not the case. 
Instead, fast food companies are profiting off of clogging your arteries 
resulting in heart disease.

 

The first problem with fast food is that over the decades 
they have been increasing the serving size available. Now when you order a small 
fries, you actually get what would have been a medium just five years ago. The 
larger serving size you are served the harder it is for you to know when to 
stop. From the time we are children our parents teach us to clean our plates 
because there are those less fortunate who have no food. So if we are given an 
extra large fry, we should be thankful and eat the whole thing.

 

Fries, burgers, nuggets, shakes, sodas, and other items you 
can find at fast food establishments are usually three times larger than the 
amount you should be consuming. This means that you could easily be consuming 
1,000+ calories per meal when you super size it. If you are trying to stick to a 
healthy 2,000 per day calorie diet, you will have consumed over of your entire 
daily food allowance.

 

Another problem with the foods you are served at fast food 
restaurants is that these foods are not nutritious. The foods that you are 
served at fast food restaurants are high in fat and high in sugar. By regularly 
consuming these high calorie meals that do not have any nutritious value is 
basically poisoning your body.

 

There are even some studies that have shown fast food may 
be addictive. The high levels of salt and sugar content found in most fast food 
items cause the brain to seek them out. This stems back thousands of years when 
salt and sugar were hard to come by so people would stock up on their supply 
when they could.

 

People will continue to frequent fast food restaurants as 
long as they continue to see ads on television for Big Macs and super size 
fries. One solution to this problem would be to limit the number of ads fast 
food companies can have at any one time.

 

While we cannot blame fast food companies entirely for our 
increasingly expanding waist lines, it is their food that is making us this way. 
If they increased the cost of a burger and lowered the cost of a salad there may 
be more incentive for consumers to choose the salad over the burger.

 

As long as fast food companies are making money off of 
their 1,000 calorie burgers, they will continue to sell them. The best way to 
prevent weight gain associated with a fast food diet is to completely cut fast 
food out of your diet. Drive right by those golden arches and hurry home where 
you can make a healthy meal. Completely removing fast food from your diet is 
similar to detox; it removes the addictive properties found in fast food.

 

Also, exercise is a vital aspect that is missing in most 
peoples daily lives. This is an essential piece of the puzzle to reverse the 
effects of high calorie fast food diets. Incorporating some type of a daily 
exercise routine will decrease your risk of heart disease ten fold.

 

Exercise does not have to be a very strenuous endeavor 
either. Simply going for a half hour power walk with your dog after a healthy 
meal is enough for starters.
 
 order organic meat 

 

 Get a Great Food Delivery Service 

  
 
 
 
 Personal Trainer  
 Personal Trainers Marketing 
 Personal Trainer Web Design 
 Fitness Consulting 
 Health&amp;Fitness Kettlebells Clubbells Sauna&apos;s Detox, Cleanse Super Detox 
 program 
 Food Delivery 
 Air 
 Purification Water Filters Liquid vitamin Fat Loss Diet Internet 
 Marketing Directories Personal Trainers Physical Therapists Massage Therapists Chiropractors   Design Your Own Fitness Program 
 

 SEO Program   
 Hiring Personal Trainers Fitness Video Company Life Coach 
 Hiring Massage Therapists   
 Professional Fitness Photographer   
 Affiliate Program   
 
 
  
 

    
 Internet 
 Marketing Program 
 

 
 
 Site Map   Link 
 to us   Policies Fitness 
 equipment personal 
 trainer directory    massage 
 directory Chiropractor 
 directory Fitness Models Burn fat Kettlebells Q and A Liquid vitamin 2 vemma 1 Fitness info product Arizona California calorie counter Physical 
 Therapy directory Female Male clubbells Kettlestack: Links Air 
 Purification Link Water 
 Filters Calander listings Oxy- powder Sauna Personal 
 Training Misspelled 
 
 
 
 
 

 Personal Power Training 

 14362 N. Frank Lloyd Wright Blvd., Suite 2138
Scottsdale AZ 85260 

 Phone: 480-628-1607 

Email: info@personalpowertraining.net 

 

 

 Personal Trainer  |  Personal Trainer 
 Certification   |  Online Personal 
 Trainer  |   Personal Fitness 
 Trainer
	</body>
</document>
