<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000132" url="http://orangecounty.citysearch.com/profile/32826323/irvine_ca/marie_callender_s.html" time="2012-07-12-15:19" support="2" score="0.0024069731852724113" bingtitle="Marie Callender&apos;s - Irvine, CA, 92604 - Citysearch" webtitle="Marie Callender&apos;s - Irvine, CA, 92604 - Citysearch">
			<query id="001424" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="001426" bing-rank="123"/>
	<description>In Short – Marie Callender&apos;s began in the 1940s in Orange County, Calif., as a ... Tokyo Table. 2710 Alton Pkwy, Irvine, CA</description>
	<body>
		Deals Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Hotels Shopping Best Of Citysearch 

 Mobile Login / Join 
 More More Go! Advertise With Us 
 Citysearch has shed its old skin! In addition to our new look, there&apos;s a boatload of new features. Poke around! Tell us what you think! 
 Orange County, CA Metro &gt; Irvine &gt; Restaurants &gt; Marie Callender&apos;s 
Marie Callender&apos;s
 (949) 552-2101 
 15363 Culver Dr , Irvine , CA | Directions  
 92604 33.695100 -117.797701 View Website 
 Menu Share Save 
   Own this Business? Recommend this business? Thumbs Up Thumbs Down ? 50 % 100 8 2 Votes Add a Photo Neighborhoods: Walnut Cuisine: New American , Traditional American Categories: Dessert Shops , Restaurants Price: $ 
 View More 
 Restaurant Special Features: Carry Out , Group Dining , Family Style Dining , Family-Friendly Dining , Lunch Spot , Breakfast Bakery Products: Pies 
 View Less 
 Site Feedback 
 Overview Tips (8) Photos (0) 
 Write a Tip for Marie Callender&apos;s 
 Sign in to Write a Tip 
 Write a Tip... optional 
 
 
Tips for Marie Callender&apos;s
 Contributor Joined 9 years ago June 22, 2008 
 Down-home, Midwest-style cooking and a straightforward menu to please the whole family.. In Short 
Marie Callender&apos;s began in the 1940s in Orange County, Calif., as a bakery that specialized in pies. Now, pie is only a slice of this nationwide franchise&apos;s offerings. Family-style comfort foods like pot roast, pot pie, tuna melt and country-fried steak as well as pasta, burgers, salads and sandwiches dominate the menu. But, the big draw is still pie: More than 31 freshly-baked varieties are available daily. Whole pies also can be purchased to go. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends oclocal714 Joined 7 years ago 5.0 October 03, 2005 
 Marie Calendar&apos;s at Anaheim Plaza. One of the best bartenders in OC is located at Marie Calendar&apos;s at the Anaheim Plaza. Sara has been there for almost 15 yrs, maybe more. I usually start my Friday nights off at MC&apos;s. Her great smile along with her awesome mix drinks makes your visit to the restaurant extra special!!!! Of course the food is great. There is a big screen t.v. to watch sports on. Monday night football is a happening night so be sure to check that out also. There is an outside patio for those smokers. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart 
 See more tips for Marie Callender&apos;s 
 Write a Tip for Marie Callender&apos;s 
 Sign in to Write a Tip 
 Write a Tip... optional 
 
 
People who viewed this also viewed…
 
 KFC - Kentucky Fried Ch… 15463 Culver Dr 
 Irvine, CA 
0.1 mi away Denny&apos;s 14962 Sand Canyon Drive 
 Irvine, CA 
2.6 mi away 75 % Ruby&apos;s Diner 4602 Barranca Pkwy 
 Irvine, CA 
1.2 mi away 
 
Things to do near Marie Callender&apos;s
 
 Restaurants Movie Theaters Banks 

 Bars Shopping&amp;Malls Hotels 
 
 About Apps Careers Privacy Policy Terms of Use Contact Us Blog FAQs 
 
Partner Sites:

 Ask Kids     Bloglines     Expedia     Hotels     Hotwire     Insider Pages     MerchantCircle     Reference     The Daily Beast     Thesaurus     Urbanspoon 
 ©2011. Citysearch is a registered trademark of CityGrid Media. Data provided by Infogroup. All rights reserved. 
 Popular Categories Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Shopping Hotels Deals Sports&amp;Recreation Cafes Movie Theaters Directory&amp;Services 

 Change City New York City Los Angeles Houston Chicago Atlanta Seattle Portland Philadelphia Austin San Francisco More…
	</body>
</document>
