<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000255" url="http://srwestend.com/tag/white-water-rodeo-on-santa-rosa-creek/" time="2012-07-12-15:27" support="1" score="0.0008954361601576543" bingtitle="White Water Rodeo On Santa Rosa Creek | West End Neighborhood and ..." webtitle="White Water Rodeo On Santa Rosa Creek | West End Neighborhood and Historic District">
			<query id="001469" bing-rank="86"/>
	<description>The West End Bicycle Parade and Yearly Potluck BBQ on ... clean up late afternoon (stack hay bales, pick up trash ... Location: Meet at the Pierson Street bridge (near # 5 ...</description>
	<body>
		West End Neighborhood and Historic District A Classic American Neighborhood — Community, History, Art, Culture, and Downtown Living 
 
 Updates Gallery Calendar Arts Video 
 

 
 About Us Preservation Walking Map Archive Resources 
 
 
 Search for: 
Slideshow
 Get the Flash Player to see the slideshow. 
Updates Sign Up
 
Receive West End news&amp;events updates via email:
 
 
 
Local Sponsors
 We would like to thank our local sponsors that generously help us to produce this website and print the Newsletters. 


 Assistance League Carol Haseltine-Ernst D&apos;Argenzio Wines Don Taylor&apos;s Omelette Express EPIC Design Build Franco-American Bakery Betsy Hall, Ph.D., MFT Heritage Public House Lakeside Pet Hospital The Last Day Saloon Murnane Floors Risling Electric Stark&apos;s Steak&amp;Seafood Tangram Landscape Architecture Teevax Time Travelers Tours Western Farm Center The Wineyard Richard Gary Wong, DC 
 
Membership Dues
 
 $10 suggested but other amounts available. Option 1 $10.00 Option 2 $20.00 Option 3 $30.00 Option 4 $40.00 Option 5 $50.00 
 
 
Tag-Archive for◊White Water Rodeo on Santa Rosa Creek◊
 Whitewater Rodeo, Bocce,Movie Author: Lea Barron-Thomas •Tuesday, June 26th, 2012 
 Bocce, Movies, BBQs- all in the West End. This Saturday, the Upper West End will have a neighborhood cookout AND the White Water Rodeo promises lots of fun at the creek right at Pierson Street Bridge. If that doesn’t suit- there’s other choices a mere walk away. Lucky us! 

 West End Summer Bocce- Every Friday at DeMeo Park . Bring a dish to share. Family and dog friendly. Location: DeMeo Park 810 Polk Street Time: 6 p.m.

 June 29th, Friday- James and the Giant Peach. West End Summer Movie Nights . All movies start at dark. Bring a blanket, warm clothes and friends. Free popcorn! Location: DeTurk Round Barn Park 819 Donahue Street Time: At Dark approx. 8:30- 9 p.m.
 
2012 W E Summer Movie Nights
 
 June 29 th , Friday- Invasion Tribute to an Era (60’s&amp;70’s music. Rock and Roll) A tribute band to the 60′s British invasion which in turn inspired American bands  starting with The Beatles, Dave Clark five, The Animals, The Zombies, The Kinks Location: Last Day Saloon 120 5 th Street $10 21 yrs+ Time: Door 9 p.m. Show 9:30 p.m.

 June 30 th , Saturday. Upper West End Neighborhood cookout this Saturday . We’re going to take over the sidewalks at 10 th &amp;Ripley. It’s a gathering for Upper West neighbors to meet, eat, and have fun! What to Bring: You and your family (kid and pet-friendly), a dish to share or something to grill (we’ll have a few grills going, tables and chairs. We’ll have some, but bring along if it’s easy). What will we do? Musical entertainment from some talented neighbors, sidewalk chalk art contest for the younger set or anyone who feels like it, catch up with friends and meet new ones. Questions? Email Jennifer Watson When&amp;Where: This Saturday (June 30), 12-4 pm at 10 th &amp;Ripley Streets
 
UWE Neighborhood Cookout
 
 

 June 30 th , Saturday- Whitewater Rodeo on Santa Rosa Creek. Build a toy boat and race it down S. R. Creek’s shallow rapids. Don’t have time to build a boat? Build a boat that morning. Materials and assistance will be available. Boy Scouts and Lifeguards on hand to demonstrate their skills and provide water safety. Children of all ages welcome. Wear shoes that can get wet. For more info contact Alistair Bleifuss 543-3845 Location: Meet at the Pierson St. bridge. Time: 10:30- Noon

 
 
Whitewater Rodeo
 
 June 29 – 8:00 PM; June 30 – 2:00 PM&amp;8:00 PM; July 1 – 2:00 PM Redwood Writers 10-Minute Play Festival You will see 9 plays, by 9 different local playwrights with 16 actors taking on 24 characters directed by 6 directors: a ferocious endeavor for the 2012,“2nd Annual 10-minute Play Festival”–a collaboration between Redwood Writers and the 6th Street Playhouse. All Tickets $16.00 Location: 6 th Street Playhouse Studio Theatre Time: See website for more info

 June 30th, Saturday- Read to a Summer Dog . Put a kid, a dog and a book together in the library and watch wonderful things happen. Location: Sonoma County Library, Central Branch 211 E. Street Time: 11 a.m – 12 p.m.

 Railroad Square Office for rent- Anyone in walking to their own well lit pretty downtown office? Mezzanine office for $600/month, includes utilities and wifi located in Cast Away Yarn 111 4 th Street. It’s big and private! Plus it’s super fun to be in Railroad Square during your work day. Contact Justine 707-546-YARN (9276) justine@castawayyarn.com 
 
Railroad Square Office for rent
 
 Do you smell a burning rubber odor lately? That’s from the BoDean Asphalt Plant located near College and Dutton Avenues. You can make a report to the Bay Area Air Quality Management District at 1-800-334-6367 (mention Plant #13584). Many neighbors have had to call this number on a daily basis. For more information on their concerns, visit the Facebook Page “Parents Concerned About the BoDean Asphalt Plant”: https://www.facebook.com/groups/251867121552910 
 
Burning Rubber Smell?
 
 Announcement Guidelines: The West End Neighborhood Association website is a tool that gives out information that is West End related or of West End interest.  Announcements are subject to our West End Neighborhood Association guidelines. turned. Do you have a West End or Railroad Square related announcement? Announcements can be emailed ( 1 week lead time required) to Lea Barron-Thomas westend@sonic.net 
 
The Assistance League is a West End Sponsor
 
 The West End Neighborhood where urbanism, preservation, art and people come together! For the latest updates, crime alerts, full calendar of events and photos- go the West End Neighborhood website . Click Here! 
 Category: Bocce , Entertainment , Events , Miscellany , Neighbor News  |  Tags: 6th Street Playhouse , Alistair Bleifuss , Bocce , BoDean Asphalt , Cast Away yarn shop , DeTurk Round Barn , downtown santa rosa , Jennifer Watson , Last Day Saloon , Lea Barron-Thomas , Parents Concerned About BoDean Asphalt , Round Barn , Upper West End , West End , West End neighborhood , West End Summer Movie Night at DeTurk Park , White Water Rodeo on Santa Rosa Creek  |  Comments off We welcome June! Author: Lea Barron-Thomas •Wednesday, May 30th, 2012 
 If you haven’t been to Bocce yet, the weather has been marvelous, the company excellent and the food divine! Last Friday we were surprised by a performance from the Church Marching Band. Join us every Friday night. Bring a dish to share. It is a family friendly event and well-behaved dogs are welcomed too. Bocce Photos A rundown of events for the beginning of June: 

 
 
You never know what to expect at Bocce!
 
 

 June 2nd, Saturday- First SATURDAY Cleanup (ages 6 and up welcome). Next Saturday is first Saturday Cleanup. We’ll meet at Olive Park at 10 AM near the south end of the footbridge. Come join us. Anyone who would like to paint over graffiti, please let me know. I’m going to try to have equipment there for graffiti removal. Join us at 12 noon for pizza. It should be a lovely day, come spend a couple hours cleaning the creek and enjoying pizza. Hope to see you there,  Stan Stan@firstSaturdaycleanup For more info go to http://firstsaturdaycleanup.org Time: 10 a.m. Location: Meet at Olive Park near south end of footbridge.

 June 2, Saturday- Chop’s Open House . Teens are invited to go for BBQ, Karaoke and the climbing wall. Activities will be provided in the art studio, tech lounge, gym and recording studio. Parent consent is needed for the climbing wall. Go to chopsonline.com to download form. Location: Chop’s Teen Club 509 Adams Street Time: 1–3 p.m.

 

 June 2 nd , Saturday- Last Day Saloon 11 th Anniversary Party . Pride and Joy- Rhythm and Blues, Motown. 21 years + $15 Location: Last Day Saloon Time: 8:30 p.m. door, 9 p.m. show
 
Last Day Saloon
 
 June 6th- June 27th- New Qigong Class - Flying Crane Qigong- utilize movement, breath and visualization to train one’s energy or Qi. This 4 week class is held every Wednesday at 10 a.m. DeTurk Class Cost is $46. To register call 543-3737 or santarosarec.com 

 
 Put these events on your Summer calendar: 2012 West End Summer Movie Nights starting June 15th. All movies start at dark on Friday nights at the DeTurk Round Barn. Questions? Email Paul&amp;Veronica 
2012 W E Summer Movie Nights
 June 30 th , Saturday- Whitewater Rodeo on Santa Rosa Creek. Build a toy boat and race it down S. R. Creek’s shallow rapids. Don’t have time to build a boat? Build a boat that morning. Materials and assistance will be available. Boy Scouts and Lifeguards on hand to demonstrate their skills and provide water safety. Children of all ages welcome. Wear shoes that can get wet. For more info contact Alistair Bleifuss 543-3845 Location: Meet at the Pierson St. bridge. Time: 10:30- Noon 
Whitewater Rodeo
 
 July 21 st , Saturday- The Annual West End neighborhood BBQ and Bike Parade. Friends and neighbors join together to dine, dish and delight in our beautiful park. The Bike Parade is routed throughout the neighborhood. Bring your decorated bike and join in. Under 18 yrs. must wear a helmet. Location: Parade starts and ends at DeMeo Park, BBQ at DeMeo Park. Time: TBA See last year’s photo .
 
West End Bike Parade
 
 

Do you have any Pet Friendly news? a photo of your West End dog? or something else that will delight animal lovers? Email Lea Barron-Thomas 
 
Time Travelers Tours is a West End Sponsor
 
 

 The West End Neighborhood where urbanism, preservation, art and people come together! For the latest updates, crime alerts, full calendar of events and photos- go the West End Neighborhood website. Click Here! 
 Category: Bocce , Entertainment , Events , Miscellany , Neighbor News  |  Tags: Alistair Bleifuss , Bocce , CHOPS Teen Club , Church Marching Band , DeMeo Park , DeTurk Round Barn , First Saturday Creek Cleanup , Flying Crane Qigong , Last Day Saloon , Paul Poling , Stan Gow , Veronica Jordan , West End , West End neighborhood , West End Summer Movie Nights , White Water Rodeo on Santa Rosa Creek  |  Comments off Movie night, Poodles and W. E. BBQ&amp;Bike Parade Author: Lea Barron-Thomas •Wednesday, July 06th, 2011 
 West Enders always have many events, happenings and entertainment to choose from. You can socialize with your neighbors, hang out with your favorite dogs, play on the creek or listen to music. 

 Don’t forget! The West End Bicycle Parade and Yearly Potluck BBQ on July 16th, Saturday is almost here!, . Volunteers are requested to set up in the morning (move hay bales, set up tables etc.) and to break down and clean up late afternoon (stack hay bales, pick up trash, clean up etc.) Are you good with kids? Volunteer to coordinate kid’s activities like a hula hoop contest, water balloon toss or egg and spoon race. Lend your empty recycle bin and trash can that day- just roll it to DeMeo Park. Bicycle Parade safety marshals and decoration assistants would also be appreciated. Contact Allen (707) 477-8422 to volunteer. 

 
 
Join us for the bike parade!
 
 July 8 th - Movie Night at DeTurk Round Barn How to Train Your Dragon Watch movies under the stars.  Movie schedule posted on DeTurk Park Bulletin Board (by dog park) Bring a blanket, warm clothes and friends. Free Popcorn. Location: DeTurk Round Barn Park 819 Donahue Street Time: Movies start at dark- 8:30 to 9 p.m. As soon as it is dark enough to project.  If it rains, the event is canceled. Questions? Email Paul or Veronica at jordanpoling@gmail.com 

 July 9 th Roots Americana #1 One Saturday a month, S. R.’s Courthouse Square will turn into a folk music paradise! These events are free to the public.  The idea behind Roots: Americana (and other North Bay Hootenanny events) is community building—to encourage people of all ages to pick up instruments and play music together while also promoting local folk/Americana artists. http://srcity.org/roots On July 9th  performances by…    - Old Jawbone ( www.jawbonemusic.com )    - The Tequila Mockingbird Orchestra  ( www.thetequilamockingbirdorchestra.com )    - The Blushin’Roulettes  ( www.blushinroulettes.com ) . Location: Courthouse Square Time: 4 p.m.

 July 10 th - West End Poodle Party Time for Poodles to canoodle at the park! All Poodles, Poodle fusions and Poodle friendly dogs are invited. The West End Poodle Party is on the second Sunday of every month at the same time- 11 a.m. Limited shade and seating available. Don’t forget your sunblock! Location: DeTurk Round Barn Dog Park 819 Donahue Street Time: 11 a.m.
 
June 2011 Poodle Party
 
 July 10 th , July 17 th , July 24 th , July 31st, August 7 th &amp;August 14 th . Live at Juilliard. Free Sunday Concert Series. Enjoy listening to music in a lovely park setting. Great event for the whole family- including the dog. Location: Juilliard Park 227 S. R. Ave. Time: 5- 7 p.m. Live at Julliard info 

 Sunday, July 10th ,  5th Street Share Fair The 5th Street Share Fair will bring 5th Street merchants and restaurants out into the streets along with artists, musicians, inventors, and mad tinkerers.  Share Exchange, is an incubator of ideas for a new local economy with the goal to share, reuse and exchange resources amongst neighbors to promote a friendlier world. It will be a fun day filled with live music, performing arts, sculpture exhibits, juried arts and craft vendors, food and beer. Location: On 5th Street in Downtown Santa Rosa between B and D Streets Time: 11am-4pm Click here for participating vendors and more info!

 July 13 th – FREE monthly workshop from the Clean Energy Advocates! Speaker is Armando Novarro from PG&amp;E.   Come learn about available PG&amp;E residential customer rebates, efficiency and solar rebates for your home. RSVP to CEA@srcity.org or call 707-543-3886. Location: 35 Stony Point Road, UFO Building, Room M Time: 6-7 p.m. For more info. visit: www.srcity.org/CEA 

 July 15 th , 16 th &amp;17 th - Big River: The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn. Mark Twain’s classic performed by the 6th Street Playhouse School of Drama students. Location: 6th Street Playhouse Time: See website for show times and tickets

 July 16 th WNA Annual BBQ and Bicycle Parade. Location: DeMeo Park W. 7th&amp;Polk Streets Time: 1 p.m. Bicycle Parade; 3 p.m. BBQ
 
Ice Cream Sundae table
 
 July 16 th - Whitewater Rodeo on Santa Rosa Creek (children of all ages welcome) Build a toy boat and race it down Santa Rosa Creek’s shallow rapids that test stability, speed, accuracy, and durability. Wear shoes that can get wet. Laughs and prizes, everyone is a winner! No Boat! You can build a boat that morning on the creek. Materials and assistance will be available to craft your own vessel. Sea Scouts will be on hand to demonstrate their skills and provide water safety. Come out and enjoy your creek!  Location: Meet at the Pierson Street bridge (near # 5 Pierson Street between W. 3rd and W. 6th Streets). Time: 10:30 AM–noon. Contact : Alistair Bleifuss at 543-3845 or ableifuss@ci.santa-rosa.ca.us .

 July 17 th Pug Play Day. Perky Pugs gather to socialize and snort. Very cute! Pug Play Day is held on the 3rd Sunday of every month. Location: DeTurk Round Barn Dog Park Time: 10 a.m. Contact Lisa Howard for more info 

 The West End Neighborhood where urbanism, preservation, art and people come together! For the latest updates, crime alerts, full calendar of events and photos- go the West End Neighborhood website. Click Here! 
 Category: Animals, Lost Pet , Entertainment , Events , Miscellany , Neighbor News  |  Tags: 5th Street Share Fair , 6th Street Playhouse , Dog friendly neighborhood , Dog Park , downtown santa rosa , Live at Julliard Park , Paul Poling , pugs , Veronica Jordan , West End , West End Bicycle Parade , West End neighborhood , West End Neighborhood BBQ , West End Poodle Party , West End Summer Movie Night at DeTurk Park , White Water Rodeo on Santa Rosa Creek  |  Comments off ©2012 West End Neighborhood and Historic District 
 Sassy Monkey Media : Theme Customization&amp;Site Maintenance | Site Powered by WordPress 
Original Free Wordpress Theme by TemplateLite.com | Theme Originally Coded by Web Hosting Refer
	</body>
</document>
