<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000560" url="http://www.gaithersburgmd.gov/poi/easy_print.asp?POI_ID=1011&amp;POI_TYPE=17" time="2012-07-12-15:51" support="2" score="0.001958620490854876" bingtitle="Planning Commission Meeting, 2/4/2004 - The City of Gaithersburg" webtitle="The City of Gaithersburg">
			<query id="000602" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="000102" bing-rank="196"/>
	<description>Chair Blanche Keller called the meeting to order at ... to come back to the Commission as a consent item. ... Kentlands and about the larger tenant being a fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Planning Commission Meeting, 2/4/2004 

 
 CITY OF GAITHERSBURG
31 South Summit Avenue
Gaithersburg, Maryland 20877
Telephone: 301-258-6330

MINUTES OF A REGULAR MEETING OF THE PLANNING COMMISSION
 FEBRUARY 4, 2004
 
 
Chair Blanche Keller called the meeting to order at 7:30 p.m. Present at the meeting were Vice Chair John Bauer, Commissioners Victor Hicks, Lenny Levy, and Danny Winborne, City Attorney Cathy Borten, Acting Planning and Code Administration Director Greg Ossont, Community Planning Director Trudy Schwarz, Planners Dan Janousek and Caroline Seiden, Associate Planner Jacqueline Marsh, and Recording Secretary Myriam Gonzalez.



 I. APPROVAL OF MINUTES
 
 
 January 21, 2004, Planning Commission Meeting
 
 
Commissioner Levy moved, seconded by Commissioner Bauer, to APPROVE the Minutes of the January 21, 2004, Planning Commission Meeting, as submitted this evening.


Vote: 3-0-2 (Abstained: Hicks and Winborne)


 
 II. CONSENT - APPROVAL
 
 
 AFP-04-002 -- Lamichane Property
 MXD Zone
121 Englefield Drive in Washingtonian Woods
Sunroom Addition to Existing Deck
AMENDMENT TO FINAL PLAN REVIEW

 
Commissioner Bauer moved, seconded by Commissioner Hicks, to APPROVE the Consent Agenda.


Vote: 5-0


 
 III. RECOMMENDATION TO MAYOR AND COUNCIL
 
 
 T-363 -- Request for amendment of Chapter 24 of the City Code (City Zoning Ordinance), Article III, Division 19, entitled,&quot;MXD Zone, Mixed Use Development,&quot;§24-160D.3(a), entitled,&quot;Uses Permitted, Residential,&quot;§24-160D.3(b), entitled,&quot;Uses Permitted, Commercial/Employment/ Industrial,&quot;and repeal and reenactment of§24-160D.3(d), entitled,&quot;Uses Permitted, Special Exception Uses,&quot;to specify individually each special exception use for the MXD Zone.
 
Planner Seiden stated that the above-referenced application was the subject of a joint public hearing with the City Council on January 5, 2004, adding that the Commission&apos;s record closed on January 25 without any public testimony. She referenced Text Amendment T-351, adopted in November 2002, and noted that the ordinance under consideration this evening excludes from the special exception process uses that are desirable in the MXD Zone.

Chair Keller noted the housekeeping nature of this application and, inviting comments from the Commission, who had no objections, called for a motion:

 
Commissioner Bauer moved, seconded by Commissioner Winborne, to recommend to the City Council ADOPTION of Text Amendment T-363.


Vote: 5-0


 
 IV. SITE PLANS
 

 AFP-03-042 -- Quince Orchard Park - Phase 2
 MXD Zone
135-175 (Odd Nos.) Painted Post Lane
Removal of White Picket Fencing
AMENDMENT TO FINAL PLAN REVIEW

Community Planning Director Schwarz stated the Commission reviewed this application in November 2003, and deferred its decision to allow staff to work with the Homeowners Association (HOA) and property owners of 135-175 Painted Post Lane to obtain a consensus on an appropriate fence type. She presented the site plan and a rendering of a scalloped picket fence style suggested by staff consisting of six-foot high, 3.5-inch wide white vinyl pickets, one inch apart, and reported that all parties had agreed on it. She stated that if the Commission&apos;s decision is to approve this proposal, four conditions are suggested by staff, which she listed.
 
Applicant representative Mark Carroll, Quadrangle Development Corporation, voiced concerns over liability with having to perform the fence replacement work on private property and being responsible for the fence after completion as part of the developer&apos;s bond requirement.

Chair Keller pointed out the reason for the developer&apos;s responsibility in making the modification work is the fact that the developer approved a fence that was not in accordance with the approved site plan. Mr. Carroll noted the existing fence was in accordance, however, with the architectural guidelines. Chair Keller reminded Mr. Carroll that the approved site plan is the prevailing document. Mrs. Schwarz noted staff&apos;s suggested Condition 3 and stated that staff would work with the individual homeowners that would be affected. Commissioner Levy suggested amending Condition 3 to include Mrs. Schwarz&apos;s comment.

 Quince Orchard Park HOA President Troy Kennedy stated that the general consensus of the community is favorable for the staff&apos;s suggested fence design. He inquired as to the possibility of obtaining one-foot easements from the properties involved. Mrs. Schwarz noted that the cost of the legal processes would be excessive.

 William Turner, 135 Painted Post Lane, noting that his is one of the affected properties, favored the staff-suggested fence design and thanked staff for their assistance in resolving the issues with this proposal.

In response to Commissioner Winborne, Mrs. Schwarz stated that the applicant&apos;s responsibility is for installation of the new fence. Commissioner Bauer reiterated his previous suggestion that the HOA review the approved site plan for inconsistencies with their architectural guidelines for fences and use the subject style as the standard. Mr. Kennedy reported the HOA is in fact presently reviewing the documents for that purpose. The Commission concurred on directing staff to prepare an opinion resolution of approval upon finding that the plan is in conformance with Zoning Ordinance§24-170, as the modified fence design does not adversely affect the health of persons residing in or working on the land in question or in the neighborhood thereof, or the use or development of surrounding property; that it does not constitute a violation of any provisions of this chapter or any other applicable law or regulation ordinance; that the proposed fence is compatible and harmonious with other existing uses or proposed development; and that it is consistent with the City environmental standards.

 Commissioner Bauer moved, seconded by Commissioner Levy, to direct staff to prepare an OPINION RESOLUTION granting AFP-03-042 - Quince Orchard Park, Phase 2, AMENDMENT TO FINAL PLAN APPROVAL, with the following conditions:


 Applicant is to amend the site plan and construct a six (6) PVC white scalloped fence with 3.5-inch wide pickets with a one (1) inch maximum gap between pickets and decorative top stabilizing posts;

 Applicant is to amend the landscape plan to remove the Hicks Yews and Chinese Dogwood trees;

 Applicant is to work with individual property owners and staff to obtain permission letters to install the fence; and

 Applicant is to complete the installation of the fence within 90 days.


 Discussion: the Commission directed staff to prepare a letter after the installation is complete stating that the installation of the fence will be considered completion of the streetscape requirements for these lots so as not to interfere with the release of bonds for Phase 2 of Quince Orchard Park.

 Vote: 5-0


 AFP-02-026 -- Kentland Square (Saul Centers)
 MXD Zone
317 Kentlands Boulevard
4,500-Sq.Ft. Retail Center
AMENDMENT TO FINAL PLAN REVIEW

Planner Janousek stated this plan is in compliance with the schematic development plan (SDP-03-005 Phase 1), approved in December 2003, noting that staff would be working with the applicant on the sign package to come back to the Commission as a consent item.

Engineer for the applicant, Gary Unterberg, Rodgers Consulting, identified Chipotle as the largest tenant of the two units in the building proposed on Pad Site B in front of Lowe&apos;s. He presented an overall plan and the site plan, noting two outdoor seating areas, brick sidewalk and brick grates for existing and proposed street trees, freestanding dumpster area, and a request for a waiver of 36 parking spaces. Regarding the latter, he referenced a letter from the applicant explaining the waiver request and reminded the Commission that the waiver request is in conformance with the SDP and that the City Council had actually approved a larger waiver in the context of the entire project.

Architect for the applicant, Chris Cowie, Cowie and Associates, Inc., presented the floor plan and briefly discussed how the proposal evolved with staff&apos;s assistance. He also presented the elevations and sample materials noting a corner tower feature, masonry, trims, awnings, metal cornice and panels. He answered questions of the Commission regarding sidewalk width, screening of mechanical equipment and dumpster, and delivery area. In response to Commissioner Levy, he noted that the plaza discussed during SDP review will be part of the next phase plan.

Speaker from the audience:
 
Richard Arkin, 121 Selby Street, voiced several concerns relating to the absence of input from the Kentlands Community Architect&apos;s Office (CAO) and of a comprehensive plan for infill development. He pointed out that there are no guarantees that the subsequent phases will be developed and in five years the approved SDP would expire. He was also concerned about the absence of architectural design standards for commercial areas in Kentlands and about the larger tenant being a fast food restaurant. He noted that the City had sought in the past courtesy reviews from the CAO for residential developments and asked that the same practice would continue with commercial development. He requested deferral of this plan until development standards for commercial areas in Kentlands are developed. However, he favored the evolution of the plan since its original submittal.

Planner Janousek pointed out that during the schematic development plan review of SDP-03-004 and SDP-03-005 last September, the City Council noted that although courtesy reviews of residential development applications had been sought of the CAO, or other architectural firms hired by applicants, they are not part of the process for approval and would not be carried forward with the subject proposals. In response to Commissioner Bauer regarding the parking waiver, Mr. Janousek stated that staff has no objections to the waiver requested. In response to Commissioner Levy, Mr. Janousek noted that Staff&apos;s Condition 2 should be revised for Planning Commission approval of the sign criteria.

Commissioner Bauer reported he had attended a staff/applicant site plan review meeting and noted that the plan before the Commission this evening is a considerable improvement, in spite of the absence of architectural guidelines or commercial development standards for that area. He commended the applicant for its willingness to meet the City staff&apos;s concerns. Commissioner Levy commented that when the tenant is known, some of the architectural features are expected to reflect the tenant&apos;s identity while observing planning principles of architectural harmony with existing structures. Chair Keller stated that the proposed elevations had addressed her previous concerns with visibility of all four sides of the building and Commissioners Hicks and Winborne agreed that the architectural design has unique features while fitting in with the rest of the center.

Mr. Janousek stated the plan is in conformance with the Mixed Use Development Zone portion of the City Code, subject to conditions that he listed.

 Commissioner Levy moved, seconded by Commissioner Hicks, to grant AFP-02-026 - Kentland Square (Saul Centers), AMENDMENT TO FINAL PLAN APPROVAL, with the following conditions:


 Applicant is to submit a lighting and photometric plan to be approved by the Department of Public Works, Parks, Maintenance and Engineering (DPWPM&amp;E) prior to the issuance of any site or building permits;

 Applicant is to submit building signage criteria to be included in the final elevations. Building signage criteria to be approved by the Planning Commission prior to the issuance of any site or building permits;

 Applicant is to provide a bike rack and include sidewalk and outdoor seating area details to be noted on the final site plan prior to the issuance of any site or building permits;

 Applicant is to submit elevations of the proposed trash enclosure walls to be included on the final site plan, and a note that dumpsters are to be shared by both tenants prior to the issuance of any site or building permits;

 Applicant is to work with staff to participate in the Art in Public Places Program prior to the issuance of any site or building permits; and

 Planning Commission hereby grants a 36-space parking waiver.


 Vote: 5-0


 SP-03-0012 -- Washingtonian Center - Rio
 MXD Zone
100 Boardwalk Place
New Restaurant
FINAL PLAN REVIEW

Associate Planner Marsh introduced this application for a new restaurant, Red Rock Canyon Grill, on Pad Site 1 of the Washingtonian Waterfront parcel.

 Applicant representative, Jeff Parana, Peterson Companies, stated that this proposal is for the first of three restaurants on the Waterfront parcel. He presented and discussed the proposed site plan noting a plaza with fountain, directory and activity table in the front area, and sidewalks that follow the same patterns as the rest of the Washingtonian Center. Along the boardwalk, he noted a walkway and outdoor seating area that will connect with future restaurant sites and a buffered common area, or pocket park, with a hidden trash receptacle in the back.

 Mike Sipes, Red Rock Canyon Grill, described the type of restaurant and presented the architectural elevations and sample materials, noting natural tones in stucco, stone, cedar shake roof, and wood trims. He noted an outdoor fire place, archway entrance, and the possibility of a western mural on the elevation facing the lake. He commented that there would be no external coolers and that the dumpster area and lighting have not yet been resolved.

In response to Commissioner Bauer&apos;s inquiries about the directory and plaza area, Mr. Parana stated that at staff&apos;s suggestion, the directory kiosk location is being reconsidered and that lighting fixture details, though not yet resolved, would probably have poles comparable or matching the style in the center.

Speaker from the audience:

 Richard Arkin, 121 Selby Street, favored the plan.

Chair Keller spoke favorably on this plan, and, in particular, the mural idea, rock material, and archway, noting about the latter that its extended version shown on a photograph of another of their locations was very attractive. Commissioner Bauer recommended a two-sided directory in scale with its surroundings, noting that the plan shows a four-sided directory that may be excessively large for the proposed plaza area. He further recommended that the directory and directional signage placed elsewhere be considered as a whole providing recognizable features in the entire area.

Ms. Marsh stated that the plan complies with the City Zoning Ordinance (§24-170,§24-171,§24-172), subject to conditions that she listed.

 
Commissioner Bauer moved, seconded by Commissioner Hicks, to grant SP-03-0012 - Washingtonian Center - Rio, FINAL PLAN APPROVAL, with the following conditions:


 Applicant is to add a note concerning the use of the trash compactor for both this site and Pad Sites 2 and 3;

 Applicant is to show the location and details of the screen wall, curb and gutter grades, and spot elevations of the service area to be approved by the Department of Public Works, Park Maintenance, and Engineering (DPWPM&amp;E) prior to the issuance of any permits;

 Applicant is to submit a tree protection plan and coordinate it with sediment control to be approved by staff and DPWPM&amp;E prior to issuance of any permits;

 Applicant is to add construction notes including a tree protection schedule and tree relocation schedule to be approved by staff prior to the issuance of any permits;

 Applicant is to add details of the fountain seat wall to the plaza details to be approved by staff and DPWPM&amp;E;

 Applicant is to work with staff on the placement and design of the directory, to be reviewed by the Planning Commission as consent approval prior to the issuance of any permits for the restaurant;

 Applicant is to add a note to the final site plan to exclude construction/details of the second pocket park until development of Pad Sites 2 and 3; and

 Applicant is to work with staff on the design of a mural, to be located on the north elevation of the restaurant, for Planning Commission review as consent approval prior to the issuance of any permits for the restaurant.


Vote: 5-0


 
 V. FROM THE COMMISSION
 
 
 Commissioner Hicks
 
 
Commended the City Department of Public Works on snow/ice removal.


 
 Commissioner Levy
 

 Welcomed Cathy Borten as the future City Attorney.

 Reported that northbound motorists are confused with the new traffic signals at the Shady Grove Road/Md. Rte. 355 intersection for several right-turning movements.



 Vice Chair Bauer
 
 
Commented on news about Governor Ehrlich&apos;s initiative to eliminate the Smart Growth Office and asked staff to investigate how this change might impact the City&apos;s Smart Growth Programs.


 
 VI. FROM STAFF
 
 
 Community Planning Director Schwarz
 
 
Announced a joint public hearing on February 17 and reminded the Commission of the joint dinner meeting with the City Council February 10.


 
 VII. ADJOURNMENT
 
 
There being no further business to come before this session, the meeting was duly adjourned at 9:30 p.m.
	</body>
</document>
