<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000811" url="http://www.courier-journal.com/section/ZONE09/Oldham-County" time="2012-07-12-16:10" support="1" score="0.0009801033812022184" bingtitle="Oldham County | The Courier-Journal | courier-journal.com" webtitle="Oldham County | The Courier-Journal | courier-journal.com">
			<query id="001430" bing-rank="97"/>
	<description>A new study found that Oldham County has the healthiest residents in the state. ... Dick Clark worked hard for his fortune, estimated in hundreds of millions; Rule change ...</description>
	<body>
		Continue Reading » Advertisement 
You will be redirected to the page you want to view in   seconds.
 
 JOBS CARS HOMES APARTMENTS CLASSIFIEDS PLACE AN AD 
 
 Hi, 
 My account Newsletters Log out 
 Log in Subscribe Activate E-Newspaper Help 
   Subscriber Solutions   Advertising Solutions   Reader Solutions   Contact Us   About C-J Media 
 
 
 News Sports Business Features Entertainment Opinion Metromix Obituaries 
 
   Election 2012   Indiana News   Neighborhoods   Nation&amp;World   Databases   Strange News   Kentuckiana Green   Education   Traffic   Special Reports 
 LATEST HEADLINES Competency hearing today for man charged in Sullivan student death A competency hearing is scheduled for Thursday morning for Gregory O&apos;Bryan, who is charged with... - 8:55 am Sheriff&apos;s deputy falls ill, dies while on duty A Jefferson County Sheriff&apos;s deputy died Wednesday afternoon while on duty, after suffering an... - 8:39 am Showers, storms moving into Louisville area Showers and thunderstorms are expected to move into the Louisville area Thursday and stick around... - 7:20 am 
   Blogs&amp;Columns   Scores&amp;Stats   Horse Racing   Recruiting   U of L Cardinals   UK Wildcats   Golf   Motor Sports   Kentucky Highs   Indiana Highs   Buy Tickets 
 LATEST HEADLINES Report: Penn St. officials concealed Jerry Sandusky abuse Hall of Fame coach Joe Paterno and other senior officials &apos;concealed critical facts&apos; about Jerry... - 9:38 am Olympic gold would be the crowning glory for Angel McCoughtry Not even a sprained knee can slow former University of Louisville basketball star Angel McCoughtry... - 2:55 am Kentucky basketball coach John Calipari will put a ribbon on it now These are heady times for University of Kentucky men&apos;s basketball coach John Calipari. - 2:55 am 
   Money&amp;Markets   Business People   Moneyline   Property Transfers   Gas Prices 
 LATEST HEADLINES Clarksville contractor in line for piece of bridges project A Clarksville, Ind. - 12:22 am KFC Yum! Center operator hired The Los Angeles-based entertainment giant that&apos;s been arranging concerts and shows at the KFC Yum!... - 2:55 am Kentucky Derby, Oaks samples clear of potent painkiller Samples from this year&apos;s Kentucky Derby and Oaks were negative for a potent painkiller that has... - 11:54 am 
   Food   Health&amp;Fitness   Home&amp;Garden   Scene   Her Scene Magazine   Travel   Kentuckiana Pets   Celebrations   Books   Comics 
 LATEST HEADLINES Stay Well | How to find doctors, clinics and advice on vacation Getting sick or hurt while on summer vacation is unfortunate enough. - 6:37 pm Eat Well | Another way to use pulled pork Pulled pork is a treat often reserved as an occasional indulgence. - 6:37 pm Autistic teen first in clinical trial She lives in a world no one else can enter, unable to speak or interact with others. - 6:36 pm 
   Metromix   The Buzz   Dining   Television   Movies   Arts   Music   Events   Goof Off   Blogs&amp;Columns 
 LATEST HEADLINES Ask The Incredible Inman | Music for floating weightless What&apos;s the name of the music in the Virgin Mobile commercial where Richard Branson goes from being... - 6:32 pm The Buzz | Local fashion designer is back on &apos;Project Runway&apos; He&apos;s baaaaack! Is the second time the charm for local fashion designer Gunnar Deatherage? The... - 4:39 pm The Buzz | &apos;The Hunger Games&apos; final book will be made into 2 movies The final book in &apos;The Hunger Games&apos; trilogy is coming to the big screen in two parts. - 11:51 am 
   Editorials   Cartoons   Reader Letters   Columnists   Op-Ed   C-J Blogs   502 Blogs 
 LATEST HEADLINES Marc Murphy | Out damn spot! - 5:40 pm Editorial | Free up nurses to provide care Kentucky&apos;s nurse practitioners provide primary care services for thousands of patients across the... - 5:46 pm Editorial | Doctors should stopfighting pill-mill law A basic tenet of medical ethics is to &apos;do no harm,&apos; but the Kentucky Medical Association is... - 5:55 pm 
   Restaurants   Bars&amp;Clubs   Events   Music   Movies&amp;TV   Showclock   Photo Galleries   Deals 
 
   Search obituaries   Guest Books 
 
 FEATURED: Photos Video A Better Life In the Prime DealChicken 
 Search 
Search in
   News
   Archives   Local Deals
   Yellow Pages ADVERTISEMENT 
Oldham County
 
sponsored by
 
 Top Oldham County News 
 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Oldham County teacher wins presidential award and $10,000 

An Oldham County eighth-grade math teacher has won a presidential award and $10,000 from the National Science Foundation.

 Jul 10, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Rotary club to hold bourbon, wine tasting 

The South Oldham Rotary Club will offer tastings of more than 30 bourbons and wines at its inaugural tasting event.

 Jul 10, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Grandparents remembered 

The history center collects artifacts and oral histories to identify the special places and events that make our community unique. The following recollection comes from the history center&apos;s family files and was contributed by Dorothy Oldson Brun.

 Jul 10, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Oldham County Fair Board president Buddy Head dies 

Willie S. &apos;Buddy&apos; Head, who was chosen to be grand marshal of Oldham County Day on July 21, died Saturday. He was 74.

 Jul 9, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Summer programs offer students year-round learning 

With barely enough time to make a dent in the couch this summer, some Oldham County students have quickly returned to school for a mental or physical workout.

 Jul 3, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Oldham schools will use reserves to give employees raises 

Oldham County Schools officials have dipped into reserves so that their employees can receive a raise beyond what is required by the state.

 Jul 3, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Goshen wildlife center denied permit to rehabilitate animals on site 

The Second Chances Wildlife Center lost its request for a permit to rehabilitate animals on its property, but that doesn&apos;t mean it&apos;s shutting down.

 Jul 3, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 School board says goodbye to retiring superintendent 

After starting out as a language arts teacher with Oldham County Schools, Paul Upchurch ascended the ranks to become superintendent.

 Jul 3, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Oldham schools save $2 million on bonds 

Oldham County Schools officials have saved roughly $2million by getting better interest rates on two bonds.

 Jul 3, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Oldham History | New Castle made impression on Confederate general 

The history center collects artifacts and oral histories to identify the special places and events that make our community unique. This article is about Confederate Gen. Edmond Kirby-Smith, who commanded the Trans-Mississippi Department of the Confederacy.

 Jun 30, 2012 
 
 PETS / 
 
 Adopt a Pal | Sleepy 

Meet Sleepy. She&apos;s a special dog. Severely underweight and filthy, she was found at a shelter. We pulled her and, due to her very sweet nature, put her into Camp Canine. Turns out she is older than we thought and really just needs a quiet, loving home.

 Jul 3, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Highlands/Crescent Hill 
 
 Blood Drives 

Upper Highland Swim Club, 2411 Parkdale Ave., 11 a.m. to 3 p.m. Wednesday. Kroger, 4501 Outer Loop, 3 to 7 p.m. Thursday. University of Louisville Medical School, 550 S. Preston St., 11:30 a.m. to 3:30 p.m. Thursday.

 Jul 3, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Officials at &apos;The Quarry&apos; in Oldham put a lid on alcohol 

Playful, brightly colored, hand-painted signs greet visitors at Falling Rock Park, an Oldham swimming hole that&apos;s also known as &apos;the quarry&apos; and that has become a favorite among Louisville-area young adults.

 Jul 3, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Northeast 
 
 Prospect set to fire up full July Fourth &apos;Boomsday&apos; after last year&apos;s cuts 

After having to cut the Independence Day fireworks in Prospect last year because of budgetary constraints, the patriotic display is back on this year.

 Jul 3, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 July Fourth festivities set for Oldham&apos;s Wendell Moore Park 

Oldham Countians can celebrate Independence Day with music, games, a magic show and fireworks at Wendell Moore Park. The entertainment starts at 6 p.m. July 4, with the fireworks kicking off over the lake at 10 p.m.

 Jul 3, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Oldham County PVA violates ethics code, commission finds 

The state Executive Branch Ethics Commission on Monday found Oldham County Property Valuation Administrator Ron Winters violated state government&apos;s ethics code when he promoted his wife.

 Jul 2, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Southwest 
 
 Southeast Christian plans new southwest regional campus 

Southeast Christian Church plans to build a new southwestern Louisville campus on 10 acres adjacent to Christian Academy of Louisville&apos;s campus on St. Andrews Church Road.

 Jul 3, 2012 
 
 NEWS / Local News 
 
 Man dies in Oldham County crash 

A 32-year-old Smithfield man was killed Sunday evening in Oldham County when the pickup truck he was driving left the road and flipped over. Oldham County Police said Darren Ellis was pronounced dead at the scene by the Oldham County coroner.

 Jul 2, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Oldham County issues burn ban 

The high heat and dryness have led Oldham County Judge-Executive David Voegele to issue a total burn ban for the county. The ban began at noon Thursday and prohibits outside burning until it is lifted.

 Jun 28, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Baptist Hospital Northeast to manage Oldham EMS 

On Sunday, Baptist Hospital Northeast will assume management of Oldham County Emergency Medical Services, a public ambulance service that has operated full time in the county for 20 years.

 Jun 27, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Locust Grove Chess Club members hone their skills at summer camp 

In the Locust Grove Elementary School library, students hunch over their desks. Their assignment is centuries old, and even the most knowledgeable masters are still students of the field.

 Jun 26, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Letter to the Editor | Not all in favor of incorporating Brownsboro 

In response to the article in The Courier-Journal Neighborhoods section of today&apos;s paper, June 20, there seems to be a totally one-sided discussion on the incorporation of Brownsboro of a huge area to be called the Village of Brownsboro.

 Jun 26, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Experience Oldham | Shakespeare takes on new meaning behind bars 

Should I begin with the strangeness of passing through a metal detector, forfeiting my driver&apos;s license for a wristband that says &apos;Luther Luckett Correctional Complex&apos; on it and then being handed a theater playbill?

 Jun 26, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Northeast 
 
 Cemetery plans funeral home on Ballardsville Road 

Louisville Memorial Gardens East, a cemetery on Ballardsville Road in northeast Louisville and Oldham County, plans to add a funeral home. A zoning change the cemetery needed was approved last week by the Louisville Mtero Planning Commission.

 Jun 26, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Oldham History | Military policewoman enjoys time in Afghanistan 

Major Bobbi Jo Mayes of the 238th Regiment of the Kentucky Army National Guard is a 20-year veteran and holds 29 decorations, awards and citations as a military policewoman.

 Jun 26, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Oldham Fiscal Court cancels July 3 meeting 

Oldham County Fiscal Court canceled its July 3 meeting because of the Independence Day holiday.

 Jun 26, 2012 
 
 PETS / 
 
 Adopt a Pal | Cami 

Cami is a black and tan border collie mix. She weighs 30 pounds and is about a year old. Cami is a medium energy dog. She appears to still have a lot of puppy in her and loves to play. She is a very sweet and loving little girl.

 Jun 26, 2012 
 
 NEIGHBORHOODS / Oldham County 
 
 Oldham County wreck kills two teens 

Two La Grange teenagers were killed early Saturday after fleeing from Oldham County sheriff&apos;s deputies and crashing their vehicle into a parked car and light pole, authorities said. Michael Tanner Wheat, 15, was driving the vehicle and died at the accident scene. The passenger, 14-year-old Autumn Foree, died at University Hospital.

 Jun 24, 2012 
 
 
 Louisville, Kentucky•Southern Indiana 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
Oldham County Blog
 
 
 Experience Oldham 
 
 The play&apos;s not the thing 
 
 
Get Published
 
 
Submit articles

 Submit stories about your club or organization 
 

 
Submit photos

 Show off your favorite photos in our reader galleries 
 

 
Submit an event

 Add your upcoming event to our calendar 
 

 
Your Business

 Tell us about your business; send us a photo 
 
 See all Photos 
Photo Galleries
 
 Oldham 4th of July celebration 
 
 Oldham 4th of July celebration 
 
 Falling Rock Park 
 
 Locust Grove chess club 
 
 Juneteenth at Oldham History Center 
 
 Greater Louisville Soapbox Derby 
 
Don&apos;t Miss
 MORE 
 
2012 Independe

 ODY Fourth of July 


 
 
 
Click to fix

 Report problems in your neighborhood 
 
 
 
SUMMER CAMPS

 Find a camp in our guide 
 
My Pet Rocks

 Nominate your pet or vote on current nominees 
 
Databases

 School maps and test scores 
 
1937

 The flood that changed Louisville 
 
 MORE 
Follow us anywhere
 
 SUBSCRIBE TWITTER FACEBOOK MOBILE RSS EMAIL SMS 
 
 Sign up for daily delivery!
 
 View today&apos;s print edition of The Courier-Journal! 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
Buy&amp;Sell
 
 JOBS CARS APARTMENTS HOMES 
 
 Find a job Post resume Tools and advice For employers 
 
 Archives 
 
Last seven days

 Yesterday, Jul. 11 Tuesday, Jul. 10 Monday, Jul. 09 Sunday, Jul. 08 Saturday, Jul. 07 Friday, Jul. 06 Thursday, Jul. 05 

 30-day archive 

 Full archive 
 
 Welcome to Louisville 
 
Hello, visitors, guests and newcomers. Louisville is a great place to live, work, play—and celebrate.
 »Check out our guide to the area. 

 
 
 Subscribe 
 
 Where to buy

 Subscribe 
 
 Courier-Journal Datacenter 

Find government salaries, crimes, test scores, and more at the Courier-Journal Datacenter. 

 Politics Kentucky General Assembly expenses Government salaries Law Enforcement Crime reports Jefferson County homicide victims Education Kentucky school test scores University of Louisville donations 
 
 Local Deals 
 
 

Flip, shop and save on specials from your favorite retailers in Louisville.

 This week&apos;s deals Weekly Deals Local Coupons Email deals Grocery Coupons 
 
Investigations with Impact: The heart of The Courier-Journal mission is public service journalism. Daily, we print and put online the watchdog stories that significantly affect you.

See our previous reports :
 Select a special report The face of a serial killer? Deadly tornadoes Overcoming Infertility Changes at MSD Status offenders Olmsted Dam project Sherman Minton Bridge closure 9-11: Ten Years Later Louisville&apos;s vacant-property problem Wounds of War Metro Council discretionary funding Civil War in Kentucky Prescription for Tragedy Preying on seniors Jobs for the future Inside KFC Yum! Center Obesity surgery: A weighty decision Black coaches making their mark Behind the bars at Otter Creek Jockey safety is no sure bet The Legacy of Ann Gotlib Officer&apos;s cases riddled with dismissals Children in Crisis Domestic violence in Kentucky Kentucky&apos;s death-penalty system Trial by fire Medical breakthroughs Troubles at Park DuValle Football player&apos;s death Officer absent, case dismissed Family services audit U of L Foundation Road contractor U of L professor Soldier&apos;s murder case Cervical cancer vaccine The storms Middle-class insurance Tragedy on the track Education commissioner Greg Page Shock probation Black lung Troubled towers Crash of Comair 5191 Punishment doesn&apos;t fit crime Well deals cost investors A hoax most cruel Busing&apos;s legacy 
 FOLLOW US ON TWITTER&amp;FACEBOOK 
 
Get the latest Courier-Journal headlines on facebook and Twitter!
 
 Most Popular 

 100-plus new laws take effect in Kentucky Kentucky basketball coach John Calipari will put a ribbon on it now Sheriff&apos;s deputy falls ill, dies while on duty Snyder reopens after fatal motorcycle crash Showers, storms moving into Louisville area Database | Delinquent Jefferson County property taxes Belly dance instructor shimmies her moves in studio and online 
 Subscribe today for full access Current subscriber? Activate your account 
Reset your password
 Enter your email and we will send you a link to reset your password. Email Reset my password Cancel OK Resend Email Need help? Call 1-800-866-2211 
Log in
 Are you currently a subscriber?
 Set up your digital access now. Email Password Forgot your password ? Log in Keep me signed in on this computer or Learn more about Login with Facebook Need help? Call 1-800-866-2211 
Log in
 Are you currently a subscriber?
 Set up your digital access now. Email Password Forgot your password ? Log in Keep me signed in on this computer or Learn more about Login with Facebook Need help? Call 1-800-866-2211 Need help? Call 1-800-866-2211 
We hope you have enjoyed your complimentary access.
 Become a subscriber today to enjoy these benefits: 
 Unlimited access to our Web site iPad-optimized edition Mobile site&amp;iPhone app 
 View subscription options Log in Are you currently a subscriber? Set up your digital access now. 
You now have full access.

Thank you for subscribing.
 
 View articles, videos, galleries and more–24/7 Access the tablet-optimized site, mobile site and iPhone app Share your access with any friend or family member Subscriber exclusive Top 5 daily email newsletter You will automatically receive the courier-journal.com Top 5 daily email newsletter. If you don&apos;t want to receive this newsletter, you can change your newsletter selections in your account preferences. 
 Continue&gt; 
Register
 Create an account or if you have a digital profile log in . Are you currently a subscriber?
 Set up your digital access now. Name Gender Select Female Male Birth year Zip code Email Password (5-30 characters, no spaces. Letters and numbers only.) Create my account Keep me signed in on this computer or Learn more about Login with Facebook Need help? Call 1-800-866-2211 Users of this site agree to the Terms of Service , Privacy Notice/Your California Privacy Rights , and Ad Choices 
You must have browser cookies enabled to view our site.
 It&apos;s possible that your browser cookies are turned off. Read our FAQ page to find out how to enable cookies in your browser. 
Account issue
 We&apos;re sorry, your shared access privileges have been removed by the subscriber. You can still look at a limited number of articles per month. Subscribe now Continue reading Need help? Call 1-800-866-2211 
Account issue
 We&apos;re sorry, this account no longer has full access. You can still look at a limited number of articles per month. View my account Need help? Call 1-800-866-2211 
Flash is required to continue
 To continue using your current Web browser, Adobe Flash must be installed or upgraded: Download Adobe Flash Player Or you can download any of the following supported modern browsers: Firefox Chrome Safari ADVERTISEMENT Site Map   |   Back to Top   
 
 NEWS 
 Election 2012 Indiana News Neighborhoods Nation&amp;World Databases Strange News Kentuckiana Green Education Traffic Special Reports 
 METROMIX 
 Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Events Music Movies&amp;TV Showclock Photo Galleries Deals 

 
 SPORTS 
 Blogs&amp;Columns Scores&amp;Stats Horse Racing Recruiting U of L Cardinals UK Wildcats Golf Motor Sports Kentucky Highs Indiana Highs 
 OPINION 
 Editorials Cartoons Reader Letters Columnists Op-Ed C-J Blogs 502 Blogs 

 
 BUSINESS 
 Money&amp;Markets Business People Moneyline Property Transfers Gas Prices 
 ENTERTAINMENT 
 Metromix The Buzz Dining Television Movies Arts Music Events Goof Off Blogs&amp;Columns 

 
 FEATURES 
 Food Health&amp;Fitness Home&amp;Garden Scene Her Scene Magazine Travel Kentuckiana Pets
	</body>
</document>
