<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000241" url="http://reportyourcomplaint.com/mcdonalds-employees-review-and-complaint-bad-customer-service-and-rude-behavior-towards-customers/" time="2012-07-12-15:26" support="55" score="0.09727896525680645" bingtitle="McDonalds employees review and complaint - bad customer service ..." webtitle="McDonalds employees review and complaint - bad customer service and rude behavior towards customers. | Report Your Complaint.com">
			<query id="000537" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000992" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000443" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="001385" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000552" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="001353" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000990" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="001165" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001417" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="001495" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000241" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000615" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="001180" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000555" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000961" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="000599" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000678" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="001291" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="001504" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="001307" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="001480" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="000561" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="001408" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="001008" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000225" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000303" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000947" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="001001" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="001386" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="001315" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="001377" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="001000" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="000978" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000663" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="001399" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="001040" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000882" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="001369" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="001396" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="001409" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000946" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="001292" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="001188" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000538" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000288" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="001404" bing-rank="202"/>
			<query id="001403" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000458" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="001166" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="001023" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="000442" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="001387" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="001009" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="001393" bing-rank="166"/>
	<description>... Camino Real in Sunnyvale and had the worst cashier ... I am not going to give my order next time to this guy or ... Here are some super hot fast food restaurant complaints from ...</description>
	<body>
		Log In 
 
 RYC (Home) Companies Complaints Reviews Compliments Helpful tips&amp;info Credit repair About us Site Index Blog 
 

 
Random Posts

 NC Department of Motor Vehicles (DMV) complaint Food Lion Supermarket Complaint - Discriminative Security Guards That Are Rude And Unjust! State Farm Insurance Company - Rude Customer Service Representatives and Claim Adjustors! Ed and Bob&apos;s textbooks review - great way to save big on college textbooks for summer classes by renting! Papa John&apos;s Complaint - They Messed Up My Order Then Delivered Old Pizza! Dunlap Grubb&amp;Weaver, Voltage Pictures and Hurtlocker - a bunch of incompetent moron lawyers that couldn&apos;t find their way out of a paperbag are trying to abuse the legal system to sue illegal downloaders of one of the worst movies of all time - Hurtlocker! True bargains can be found at Real Deals Magic Coat whitening shampoo for dogs - it really works! Proactiv acne solution - a review of an overhyped, 2nd rate benzoyl peroxide skin cleaning system... Kohl’s, A honest review of an amazing department store! 
 
Recent Comments

 skyday on Great Stuff insulating foam sealant review–this stuff works great for sealing and insulating gaps and cracks SCAM on Childhood leukemia Foundation–a review of a shady charity that uses auto dialers and other shady practices to get donations Mike on HomeVestors home buyers is a shady scam and offers you far less than your home is worth! Chris Brady on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? Lee on Stanley Steemer–fraudulant business practices, abusive telemarketing and a bad rug cleaning experience! Lisa Carroll on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? brenda on Walgreen’s pharmacy–incorrectly filled prescription and they refused to fix it! S.K. Thompson on Virginia State Troopers Complaint–Police officers have too much power and get away with breaking laws! 
 Privacy Policy 
McDonalds employees review and complaint–bad customer service and rude behavior towards customers.
 By Aman 
McDonalds has the rudest employees!
 




I went to this McDonald’s restaurant located on El Camino Real in Sunnyvale and had the worst cashier you could possible imagine behind the register. I greeted this McDonald’s sking,“how are you doing?”. No reply from him.“What can I get you?”is what he says. That’s fine. He is doing his duty.

My order was a no. 6 Club Sandwich, crispy and just the sandwich no meal, also 4 McNuggets, just the nuggets. First he can’t find where the nuggets are, he then asks his manager or someone where to find the nuggets in the register. He then asks me, how many, I say 4.

He then talks to his manager and says he can’t give 4 to me. The manager says 6 is the min. I said that’s fine, give me 6. Then he adds it as a meal, instead of just the nuggets. I told him just the nuggets not the meal. He puts his face as if I gave him a wrong order and changes the order and says around $10 is my bill.

I said it is around 4 for the sandwich and 3 for the nuggets how come my bill is $10. I didn’t even pay by that time. The over zealous waiters inside placedmy order out on the counter even before I paid. This guy has added a meal on my sandwich as well and says it is $6 for the sandwich combo, which I have mentioned clearly in the beginning just the sandwich. He is like what and gives me a pretty bad look and starts all over again.


 Your Ad Here 


Mean while the waitress from inside asks him what’s happening, he from out of this world blames everything on me with a single line,“this guy is unable to make up his mind”. I was shocked and so pissed off that I wanted to kick his behind right there or atleast make a scene by complaining about him.

Somethings stopped me from doing that::

1)It was lunch time and there were lots of people waiting.
2)He is one of those employees who is working really hard for peanuts, I didn’t want to get him fired.
3)I tried to understand him dealing with so many crazy customers.

But I was really pissed off, my order was crystal clear, he messed it up and blamed it on me. I am not going to give my order next time to this guy or I will stop going to that particular McDonald’s altogether.



 
Posts Related to McDonalds employees review and complaint - bad customer service and rude behavior towards customers.

 
 Walmart cashier and customer service complaint–customer service at Walmart downright sucks! 

// I went to the Walmart the other day and saw that there was only a very few cash registers open and the lines were ...
 
 McDonalds–rude service and employees that don’t speak English 

// Earlier today I went to the McDonald&apos;s on Harris Blvd. in Charlotte North Carolina. My sons were hungry and wanted a happy meal. So ...
 
 Aldi’s has racist employees that knowingly discriminate against ethnic groups like Spanish Americans! 

// I have always enjoyed shopping at ALDI&apos;s store as they do have very low prices. But that all changed today; the service I had ...
 
 Hot fast food restaurant complaints here on ReportYourComplaint! 

Here are some super hot fast food restaurant complaints from our readers and contributors here on ReportYourComplaint.com! // Here are some of the latest and ...
 
 Walmart Customer Service Complaint–Rude Employees Whom Don’t Know Company Policies and Practices 

// Today I needed to go to Wal-Mart to pick up a couple things before the work week began.  As I was walking through the ...
 
 
 Tags: bad customer service , chain restaurants , complaint , fast food , fast food joint , fast food restaurant , fast food restaurant complaints , food , honest review , horrible customer service , McDonald&apos;s , McDonalds restaurant , Not recommended , restaurant , review , rude , sucks , Terrible 
 
5 Responses to McDonalds employees review and complaint–bad customer service and rude behavior towards customers. 

 Tim Robbins on April 28, 2011 at 12:26 AM 

I ordered a Quarter Pounder, sandwich only, at your drive through window. When the cashier told at the next window told me the total was nearly $5, I said there must be a mistake, this normally runs no more than $3.50 or so. Can you double check the amount for a quarter pounder only? After repeating the phrase“quarter pounder only”about 3-4 times to try to get through to the guy, after repeatedly being told that that was the correct price. He eventually said that they raised the prices. I said by over $1.50, let me see the receipt. After about 5 minutes I finally got the receipt to find it said“double”quarter pounder. Then I told the cashier, thats why, the receipt says double quarter pounder. He still didn’t seem to understand. I repeated for a 4th or 5th time that I ordered a regular quarter pounder. Finally, I got the manager and after another 5-10 minutes I was finally refunded the money and given the correct order. I didn’t even get an apology. I won’t be back to your establishment ever again and I will tell all of my friends, family, and business associates–there’s a Carl’s Jr. next door and they never seem to mix up the orders.

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 Tyson on May 10, 2011 at 4:27 AM 

people shouldnt expect top quality service at a fast food restaurants.He was probly just a nervous 15 year old trainee. The kids that work their are not incompetent or stupid, they are just highly undertrained, thrown into action with hopes they ll learn something from their 2 days of“training”. The employees are never notified about daily species are free promotional items or given any info at all on food that customers tend to ask.

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 june on October 24, 2011 at 11:41 AM 

Dear McDonalds:

These comments are not limited to any specific date/time or location. These comments are for all the McDonalds I go to here in California.

As a veteran customer of over 40 years, I only go to McDonalds for the products, get them&amp;then leave.

I am sick to death of entering any McDonalds up&amp;down California from here in any Sonoma county McD’s to surrounding counties&amp;all around and having to put up with the Spanish speaking of your employees.

Typical scenario: I enter the and already can hear the employees in the background, speaking in Spanish before I am anywhere near the counter , when it is my turn at the counter, they momentarily stop speaking to each other in Spanish because they are interrupted by me, a customer, and have to“serve”me and then go back to the Spanish bantering until I am called for my order. That is mostly the case where they even bother to say “may I take your order” or a similar greeting. There are other bozo’s that just stare at you mute when you come up, and I have to do the first “hello, how are you today”.

The rating for this kind of “customer service”- ZERO. ZERO. ZERO.

Suggestions: 1.McDonalds needs to do some serious customer service satisfaction surveys. Give every 100th customer a survey with their receipt to mail in and concentrate on the customer service questions; we know the product is a winner.

2. Don’t hire people who are unwilling to speak English in the workplace if for no other reason-SAFETY and COMMON MANNERS, then watch your profits go even higher and watch the restaurants tables fill up because it is once again a friendly American atmosphere in which to dine in.

Diversity, where is the “diversity” in the McDonalds workplace? Hire one of everybody who is qualified&amp;all on the same communication page so nobody is left in the cold atmosphere. McDonalds will once again attract quality people because they won’t be so turned off and disheartened, to simply even apply there apply there. Why would someone looking for work in their own country, be motivated to go to work in a place knowing that it acts like it’s in another (failed) country every single day and night?

Thank you for your time, if it were not for the excellent food&amp;drinks, I would not put one toe in any McDonalds anymore. Speak English in one of my favorite American companies that I grew up with, how much is that to ask of people who are lucky enough to have a job here?

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 aut0mat3d on June 9, 2012 at 4:01 PM 

went to store # 6823, they lids were out, everyone on. Break.. manager is screaming at the employees they look lost…. It took us 15 minutes to get oír food, oh yeah that daily double is than worst burger Mcds has put on their menu

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 Jillian on July 2, 2012 at 5:53 PM 

I had my first day at mcdonalds today. I can say it’s not the cashiers fault most of the time. I made sooooo many mistakes today and most customers where quite pacient with me. I think unless the cashier is just super rude then it’s usually just a simple mistake the cah register is weird and you have to learn it by heart I had a slow time with it myself. And I am always grateful for pacient customers who know or can tell I’m new and don’t hassle me. It makes me much more willing to fix the mistakes I make 

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
Search Website
 Most Popular
Complaints, Reviews, and Compliments! Want your company&apos;s product or service reviewed?
 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 Your Ad Here 
Tags
 automotive Awesome bad customer service car car dealer car dealership chain restaurants Charlotte Charlotte NC complaint compliment Customer service disgusting Educational fast food fast food restaurant food fraud health Helpful helpful information highly recommended honest review Horrible horrible customer service horrible service How to illegal Interesting Not recommended rave recommended restaurant review ripoff rude save money scam sucks Terrible unfair business practices unhealthy untrustworthy Walmart website Copyright©2012 Report Your Complaint.com . All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
