<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000829" url="http://fullofdeals.com/Search/Education" time="2012-07-12-16:11" support="11" score="0.017193021784623765" bingtitle="Education Deals - Education Hot Deals ,Education coupons ..." webtitle="Education Deals - Education Hot Deals ,Education coupons, Education printable coupon">
			<query id="000294" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="001327" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000137" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="001108" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="000387" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000511" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000355" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="000417" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000888" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="001485" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="001045" bing-rank="127"/>
	<description>Wu Tang Clan Enter Wu-Tang [Amazon.com] $1.30 Raekwon Only Built 4 Cuban Linx [Amazon.com] $1.30 Mobb Deep Infamous [Amazon.com] $1.30 Nas It Was Written [Amazon.com] $.70</description>
	<body>
		HOME HOT DEALS FREE STUFF FINANCE GROCERY TRAVEL DEALS 
 
Education hot deals , Education coupons results
   1   2   3   4   &gt;   Sponsor Deals JM Cremps Educational Guide&amp;Catalog JM CREMPS said: Information Request Sign up to receive a Free Adventure Catalog and regular savings from JM Cremp&apos;s! You can expect to receive your: Educational Guide in Mid-July!&amp;Huge Adventure Filled Christmas Catalog in Mid-October! Note: We will not Sell, Share or Rent any of your personal information with third parties.https://www.jmcremps.com/inforequest.asp Tags: Cremps   Educational   Guide   Catalog   Apple Education Store : $100 Back to School Gift Card THe new Mac book Air&amp;Pros are 50 dollars cheaper ( Students save $50). Apple is adding a $100 Back to School Gift Card to this. http://store.apple.com/us-k12/findyourschoolDo you qualify for Education Pricing?
Apple offers special education pricing on Apple computers, software and select third party products to college students, parents buying for a college student, or teachers, homeschool teachers, administrators and staff of all grade levels. Students who have been accepted to college are also eligible.
Note: If you are a homeschool teacher, type &quot;homeschool&quot; in the search field below and select &quot;K-12&quot; to find the Homeschool store.&quot;Well add your $100 Back to School Gift Card to your order. Youll see it appear in your cart, but you will not be charged for it at checkout. You can use your gift card on the Mac App Store, the iTunes Store, the iBookstore, or the App Store.&quot;
Apple Store Coupons
 Tags: Apple   Education   Store   100   Back   School   Gift   Card   Useful/Helpful/Educational Finance Video Thread Its been awhile since I have started a thread, but, I havent seen a thread with something like this so I thought it may be useful. I stopped watching TV over a year ago, so anytime I feel like watching something, I typically watch something educational related to business and making money. My favorite is Century of SelfThis should really hit home for a lot of folks on this board, it goes through the history of consumerism and how it was created and essentially how it works, theres a reason you want to buy expensive clothes, cars, houses, ect. Its 4 hours long, but well worth it.Feel free to post your videos. Tags: UsefulHelpfulEducational   Finance   Video   Thread   Robotic 6-in-1 Educational Solar Kit ($4.15 compare at $6.00) @ eBay 
 Tags: Robotic   Educational   Solar   Kit   415   compare   600   eBay   6-in-1 Educational Solar Kit DIY Bulid Your Own Solar Toy $6ac Ship MERITLINE http://www.meritline.com/6-in-1-educational-solar-kit---p-78852.... $5.99 w/Code: MLC507DN For First 300 OrdersMeritline Coupons Tags: Educational   Solar   Kit   DIY   Bulid   Your   Own   Toy   6ac   Ship   MERITLINE   GeoBingo USA - Educational Geography Board Game - $13 eligible for Prime @Amazon GeoBingo USA - Educational Geography Board Game - By GeoToysList Price: $18.95
Deal Price: $12.95
You Save: $6.00 (32%)
Geo Bingo USA - Educational Geography Board Game - by Geotoys : GeoBingo USA is a new twist on a classic game and a new way to make geography fun! The goal of GeoBingo USA is to get 5 states in a row on one of the 8 GeoBingo Boards. 50 state cards show the capital, land area, population, and nickname for every state. High quality, made in Germany, Ages 4 and Up.Amazon Coupons Tags: GeoBingo   USA   Educational   Geography   Board   Game   eligible   for   Prime   Amazon   Samson&apos;s classroom educational software $9 (up to %70 off) HERE!Choose from $9 for a one-year Home Plan for (1) user ($30 Value) OR
$16 for a one-year Family Plan for (4) users ($50 Value) onlyIdeal for ages 5-10 The Company
Based in Schenectady, New York, Samsons Classroom offers high-quality educational software for kids of all ages, as well as a vibrant online learning community. New product releases and upgrades are provided at no additional cost.Mamasource Coupons Tags: Samsons   classroom   educational   software   off   2011 Tax Question - Transition from dependent to independent filing, who claims the education credits? I graduated last May and started working in August. This means that January - May&apos;s education expenses were paid, however I don&apos;t know if I can claim them on my tax returns.I will be filing independent for 2011 if it matters.Any idea where I can find out how this should be treated? Tags: 2011   Tax   Question   Transition   from   dependent   independent   filing   who   claims   the   education   credits   High state tax and education expenses? funnel money through 529 for profit. I live in a state with high state tax. DW is attending college and we are looking at around $5k tuition charges for her this year and $10k/year for the next couple of years.10k/year of 529 contribution in my state&apos;s plan is tax free (savings of $600/yr). So I&apos;m planning to funnel the money through a 529 plan to save some money. I think it is worth it for a couple of hours of my time.For a list of states that offer tax benefits for 529 contribution and decide if this applies to you - go to http://www.finaid.org/savings/state529deductions.phtml.Points to be aware of:
1. Some states have time limits of how long the money has to stay in the plan before you can withdraw it.
2. Even if there is no theoretical time limit - there may be practical one. e.g. in my case the plan administrator takes at least 31 days to disburse funds for the first request.
3. The 529 investment options seem to be very opaque. In my plan - I have not been able to dig out so far something as simple as what are the holdings under the different &quot;mutual fund type&quot; investment options. Tags: High   state   tax   and   education   expenses   funnel   money   through   529   for   profit   Khan Academy - free educational site 60 Minutes had a segment tonight about Khan Academy link . It is a free educational site that Bill Gates said he used to teach his children math. Bill Gates later funded the site to expand the site&apos;s offerings. The site&apos;s founder previously worked at a hedge fund. It was mentioned previously in this archived FW thread
here Tags: Khan   Academy   free   educational   site   FREE Federal Trade Commission Education Materials https://bulkorder.ftc.gov/ Tags: FREE   Federal   Trade   Commission   Education   Materials   Adobe Coupon: Extra 80% off select education software PS $49 Suit $95 Adobe Coupon: Extra 80% off select education software
Adobe cuts an extra 80% off select education software via coupon code &quot;SAVE80EDU&quot;. That&apos;s the best percent-off discount we&apos;ve seen from Adobe in more than a year. (We last saw 10% off $375 or more in August.) Shipping starts at $5.95, or choose download delivery to avoid shipping charges. Deal ends March 3.I bought a Photoshop for $49 shipped.
And also bought a web design suit for $95 shipped.Great deal.Adobe Store Coupons Tags: Adobe   Coupon   Extra   off   select   education   software   Suit   Lauryn Hill &quot;The Miseducation of Lauryn Hill&quot; MP3 Album downloads for $4 Today only, the Amazon MP3 Store offers downloads of Lauryn Hill&apos;s The Miseducation of Lauryn Hill MP3 Album for $3.99. It&apos;s a 16-track, DRM-free R&amp;B;album, released in 1998. (iTunes charges $10.99.) Amazon MP3 Downloader is required.
LINKAmazon Coupons Tags: Lauryn   Hill   The   Miseducation   MP3   Album   downloads   for   $7.98 6-in-1 Solar-Powered Educational Robotic Kit With 6 Models linkProduct InfoLearn about solar energy while having fun. No batteries or tools are required to build the six different models in the Solar-Powered Educational Kit. Easy to build, the kit demonstrates the science of solar power.There&apos;s a solar powered puppy, 2 different planes, an airboat and more that can be created from the kit. The fun assembly is sure to get your child thinking about the various applications of solar energy and what else the sun&apos;s rays can power.SpecsCondition: NEW
Packaging: Retail
Warranty: 1-Year Limited
Manufacturer: Ace
Model: 6-in-1 SolarFeatures Include:Excellent beginner building kit designed to teach how solar power is used
Easy build kit
No tools required
No batteries required
Learn about solar power while having fun
Builds six different working models including a puppy, 2 different planes, an airboat, and a windmill
Only one project can be completed at a time
Recommended for ages 10 and up Tags: 798   Solar   Powered   Educational   Robotic   Kit   With   Models   Taxation of Job Related Education Fringe Benefits I hope this isn&apos;t too much in the weeds, but we have some pretty savvy folks in the area of taxation here that may be able to answer my question. I have 4.5k in reimbursed education costs from my employer which falls under an accountable plan. From what I can tell, this money qualifies as a working condition fringe benefit. I believe I can deduct the costs of tuition, fees, books, parking, one way mileage as job-related expenses. However, I&apos;ve reached the 2% of AGI limit, as AGI is ~70K. Can I only take up to the 2% limit, and apply the rest of the education expenses toward the lifetime learning credit or education deduction? The lifetime learning credit is reduced by the amount of employer education reimbursement, but as far as I can tell, the money received from my employer is not considered &quot;education reimbursement&quot; but a fringe benefit.This sounds like double dipping on the surface, but I honestly don&apos;t think it is. I&apos;m paid with a non-taxable working condition fringe benefit, and I incur education costs related to my job.Relevant links:
IRS Pub 970
IRS Fringe benefit guide
Topic 513 - Education Expenses Tags: Taxation   Job   Related   Education   Fringe   Benefits   A heads-up for those who have received The National Household Education Survey through the mail. Hope this is the correct forum to post. Please move if not.
This post is a heads-up for those who have received (or will receive) The National Household Education Survey through the mail.Do Not Throw Out Before Opening...There is a brand new crisp $5.00 bill included in the survey envelope.survey info:The Department of Education wants to understand the condition of education in the United States. This survey is the only way that the Department of Education can learn about schooling and child care arrangements from your perspective.How was your household chosen? Your address was randomly selected from among all of the home addresses in the nation. It was selected using scientific sampling methods to represent other households in the U.S. The sample is designed so that interviews with only a few thousand people will accurately describe the educational experiences of almost all Americans. Some households will be selected to receive a second survey that asks more specific questions about the educational experience of children in the house.Can I complete the survey on the web?No web option is available for this survey. Please complete the form that was mailed to your address. If you have misplaced your form, call the U.S. Census Bureau toll-free at 1-888-840-8353 to request a replacement survey.More information can be found at nces.ed.gov/nhes. Tags: heads   for   those   who   have   received   The   National   Household   Education   Survey   through   mail   Free Kindle Books 12 Children&apos;s Character Education Books Each Listed at $10 For a Total of $120 JACKSON&apos;S PLAN-Goals, Perseverance Children&apos;s Book
Text
KYLIE&apos;S CONCERT-Goals Children&apos;s Book (Children&apos;s Character Education Books)
TextPLATO&apos;S JOURNEY-Honesty Children&apos;s Book (Children&apos;s Character Education Books)
TextTESSA ON HER OWN-Self-Esteem Children&apos;s Book (Children&apos;s Character Education Books)
TextMOLLY&apos;S MAGIC-Problem Solving Children&apos;s Book (Children&apos;s Character Education Books)
TextFEATHERS AT LAS FLORES-Gossip Children&apos;s Book (Children&apos;s Character Education Books)
TextKIKI AND THE CUCKOO-Competition Children&apos;s Book (Children&apos;s Character Education Books)
TextSTANLEY&apos;S &quot;THIS IS THE LIFE!&quot;-Nutrition Children&apos;s Book (Children&apos;s Character Education Books)
Text
INGER&apos;S PROMISE-Trustworthy Children&apos;s Book (Children&apos;s Character Education Books)
TextBAILEY&apos;S BIRTHDAY-Birthdays Children&apos;s Book
TextHANA&apos;S YEAR-Peer Pressure Children&apos;s Book
TextBEA&apos;S OWN GOOD-Following Rules Children&apos;s Book
Text Tags: Free   Kindle   Books   Childrens   Character   Education   Each   Listed   For   Total   120   Credit Cards with rewards for Education and Dealerships Transactions? Need assistance in pin pointing any CC&apos;s with best rewards for transactions pertaining to college and dealership charges?Thanks Tags: Credit   Cards   with   rewards   for   Education   and   Dealerships   Transactions   Labels for Education Bonus Points in today&apos;s Coupon inserts nationwide! FOR THOSE OF U WHO GET THE SUNDAY PAPER: please don&apos;t throw out the page in the coupon section that has bonus points for the Labels For Education program. Send the sheet to school w/ your child, and if u don&apos;t have a child in school, drop the sheet off at an elementary school. It&apos;s a free program and his is how these companies have chosen to support children around the country...If u have any questions about the program, u an either check their websites or send me a PM and I&apos;d be happy to explain it to you! It&apos;s a lot like the more popular Box Tops for Education program, but instead of the 10 cents (cash) you get per Box Top (which adds up quickly), you get points in a catalog of things from crayons to smart boards and with school budgets hit hard nationwide, these free programs are a help, BUT ONLY IF WE PARTICIPATE. I apologize for putting this on this forum, but I feel strongly about not throwing out something in a free program run nationwide that can help our children and grand-children. moderator: PLEASE don&apos;t delete this message. It&apos;s sunday evening and not many people will be reading it anyway...Thanks for your understanding and support. The children u help, thank u!!!For a list of participating products: http://www.labelsforeducation.com/How-to-Earn/Participating-Prod... Tags: Labels   for   Education   Bonus   Points   todays   Coupon   inserts   nationwide   Educational Insights Geosafari Motorized Solar System $8.47 @Amazon Was $32.99
Now $8.47 Observe the vastness of space in a dramatic light show
Base features planetary longitude marks so the planets can be set up to their correct positions
A/C adapter not included
Includes a Stardome that converts the unit to a planetarium
The central tower and the planetary support rods are black so that they &quot;disappear&quot; in a darkened room for a spectacular effect
The unique stardome converts the unit into a planetariumhttp://www.amazon.com/dp/B00062RV18 Tags: Educational   Insights   Geosafari   Motorized   Solar   System   847   Amazon   Educational Insights Laundry Jumble Game @ Amazon was $29 now $9.09 w/FSSS LINKFind the missing clothes - no peeking allowed! Help the animals get dressed! Reach inside the dryer and explore using only your sense of touch. Players try to match picture cards with articles of clothing they feel inside the dryer. Engaging 3-D game play encourages tactile exploration, fine motor skills, and counting. Great for practicing animal names and clothing words, too. Ages 4+ / Grades PreK+ For 14 playersCHOKING HAZARD [1]. Not for under 3 yrs. Tags: Educational   Insights   Laundry   Jumble   Game   Amazon   was   now   909   wFSSS   Sesame Street Learning Fun with 4 Fun&amp;Educational Activity Books + 4 Silly Song CDs ($4.99 was $39.99) @ 1SaleADay 
 Tags: Sesame   Street   Learning   Fun   with   Educational   Activity   Books   Silly   Song   CDs   499   was   3999   1SaleADay   Sesame Street Learning Fun With 4 Fun&amp;Educational Activity Books + 4 Silly Song CDs $10 Shipped @ 1 Sale http://1saleaday.com/family/ Tags: Sesame   Street   Learning   Fun   With   Educational   Activity   Books   Silly   Song   CDs   Shipped   Sale   6-in-1 Educational Do It Yourself Solar Powered Robot Kit $10 Shipped @ D/S http://www.dailysteals.com/ Tags: Educational   Yourself   Solar   Powered   Robot   Kit   Shipped   Educational Insights Eggspert 7883 $15.00 http://www.amazon.com/dp/B001SN8DE8/Free Shipping w/$25+ Order Tags: Educational   Insights   Eggspert   7883   1500   Finance education I am an engineer who has been promoted to a managerial role in which I have to deal with budgets, communicate with cost accountants etc. While my colleagues understand that i am relatively new to the role and are supportive by communicating in detail, I would like to educate myself about the concepts.I am good at reading material and understanding it. Are there some good books that are recommended for someone in my situation?Thanks in advance Tags: Finance   education   2-Day Sale! Save 50-85% On Educational Games @ SimplyFun (Dec 4-5 Only) SimplyFun&apos;s TWO DAY Sale
Dec. 4-5 Only!
Quantities are limited!Save 50-85% on over 40 toys and games for kids.
Ground Shipment (10% of order total, $8 minimum)
https://simplyfun.com/twoday/I ran across this company at a homeschooling convention that the company I work for was exhibiting at. I was incredibly impressed by their toys and games. How well they were constructed and packaged. How they were geared towards both learning AND having fun. I liked their stuff so much, I purchased a few things for my son before the convention ended. I just got this email about their 2-day sale. The prices are excellent, and everything listed in this deal is a good deal and a good buy. I&apos;ve seen their stuff. I&apos;ve touched it and played with it. I&apos;ve met their VP of sales. I like them a lot and wanted to pass along these savings to everyone here on FatWallet.Enjoy!Learning&amp;Connecting... Through Play!
At SimplyFun, we make learning fun and easy for children and keep families connected. How? Through the powerfully simple concept of PLAY.

Play teaches children important academic, social and developmental skills. It helps them make sense of their world. From ABC&apos;s to saying please, children are hard-wired to learn through play.

Play allows important human connections to take root, to grow, and to flourish. It allows us to share with each other to really know each other as human beings.

And ultimately, play lightens our load. It relieves stress and creates joyful memories that we can go back to mentally to help us through our rough patches.

Play keeps our families connected!PS... Because they have consultants in every State, you will be charged sales tax.PRODUCTS:$8.00 $1.50 81% OFF!
3D BUTTERFLYThis whimsical 3D puzzle is made of lightweight balsa wood.$10.00 $1.50 85% OFF!
3D DINOSAURSThis fierce 3D puzzle is made of lightweight balsa wood.$10.00 $1.50 85% OFF!
3D DOGThis exciting 3D puzzle is made of lightweight balsa wood.$15.00 $2.50 83% OFF!
3D DRAGONThis dramatic 3D puzzle is made of lightweight balsa wood.$10.00 $1.50 85% OFF!
3D FORMULA-1 RACERThis thrilling 3D puzzle is made of lightweight balsa wood.$15.00 $2.50 83% OFF!
3D SAILBOATThis adventuresome 3D puzzle is made of lightweight balsa wood.$12.00 $5.00 58% OFF!
40 WAYS TO CONNECTLet your kids know how much you love them - when they least expect it. Tuck a lunch note into a backpack, or make your kid&apos;s day with a &quot;fun&quot; coupon.$12.00 $5.00 58% OFF!
ADDITION WOOD PUZZLELearn addition with this clever and colorful puzzle. A great teaching tool!$32.00 $12.50 60% OFF!
ADVENTURES OF RILEY: PENGUIN RESCUEPacked with informative facts, twists and turns, get ready to travel across Antarctica and rescue five penguins. $18.00 $5.00 72% OFF!
BASEBALL ACROSS AMERICA 500PC PUZZLETake me out to the ballgame! Past and present baseball stadiums with interesting historical facts make this 500-piece jigsaw puzzle a &quot;home run&quot;!$25.00 $5.00 80% OFF!
BUILD AND PAINT: NATURE&apos;S WONDERSInterlocking pieces make assembling your 3-dimensional model without glue a snap! Finish it off with your own flair and then proudly display for all to see! $25.00 $5.00 80% OFF!
BUILD AND PAINT: THINGS THAT ROARInterlocking pieces make assembling your 3-dimensional model without glue a snap! Finish it off with your own flair and then proudly display for all to see! $12.50 $2.50 80% OFF!
COOL CARD KITThis is a fun project for expressing gratitude and care in a playful way. Each set makes eight one-of-a-kind cool cards. $23.00 $10.00 56% OFF!
CRAZY MIXED UP ZOO GAMEThis memory game will challenge even the sharpest elephant! Guess which pair of animals just traded places. $12.50 $2.50 80% OFF!
CUTE CARD KITThis is a fun project for expressing gratitude and care in a playful way. Each set makes eight one-of-a-kind cool cards. $14.00 $2.50 82% OFF!
DINOSAURS 104PC PUZZLETravel across North America to the places where dinosaurs once roamed. Our 104-piece puzzle features 20 different dinosaurs such as the mighty Stegosaurus and Tyrannosaurus. Features a wealth of interesting dinosaur facts.$39.00 $15.00 61% OFF!
DREAM PIGA SimplyFun favorite, the Dream Pig encourages you decorate the outside and then fill it up with spare change as you plan for your dream-come-true! $22.00 $7.50 65% OFF!
DRIVEDrive is a fun strategy game where the biggest car collector wins.$18.00 $5.00 72% OFF!
ENDANGERED SPECIES 500PC PUZZLEOur 500-piece standard jigsaw puzzle focuses on the preservation of some of the world&apos;s most unique and exotic species. Over 40 different endangered animals, reptiles, birds and insects.$18.00 $5.00 72% OFF!
FAMOUS GOLF COURSES 500PC PUZZLEFORE! Start down the path to the most popular golf courses in North America, Hawaii and the British Isles. Our colorful 500-piece jigsaw puzzle even lists phone numbers!$12.50 $5.00 60% OFF!
FUNGRAMSEach unique card is jammed packed with fun-filled activities, creative puzzles, and enjoyable games.$15.00 $5.00 66% OFF!
GRABBAGE&amp;MOREA wink. A nod. Or a well-placed tap on the table. Is that your partner&apos;s secret Grabbage signal?$18.00 $5.00 72% OFF!
HORSE BREEDS 500PC PUZZLEA horse lover&apos;s dream, showcasing 139 horse breeds from across the world. Detailed facts teach the unique traits of each individual breed including size, locale, and history.$12.00 $5.00 58% OFF!
HUEY ALPHABET WOOD PUZZLEYoung children learn the alphabet, colors and numbers while solving this brightly colored 33-piece wood puzzle. $34.00 $12.50 63% OFF!
IN10SITY A trivia game for everyone! All the answers are numbers from 1 to 10. $8.50 $2.50 70% OFF!
PAVEMENT PALS - CHALK&amp;ACTIVITY BOOKTransform a sidewalk or driveway into a playground! Package includes 14 fun games and activities and 6 pieces of jumbo chalk.$32.00 $12.50 60% OFF!
PLEXTPlext is &quot;the game of few words&quot;. Try to get through the letter sequence using the least number of words. $18.50 $5.00 72% OFF!
POWDER TROPICAL FISH PUPPETThere&apos;s Somethin&apos; Fishy about this puppet... Or is he a long lost Chum?$18.00 $7.50 58% OFF!
RIBBITHop on a lily-pad, or another frog&apos;s back and get across the river! $42.00 $10.00 76% OFF!
SIMPLY CATAN Based on the worldwide bestseller Settlers of Catan. $17.50 $7.50 57% OFF!
SNEAKS Players wildly pass cards around the table to collect four of a kind. Once you do, grab a sneaker, sit back and laugh while everyone else scrambles. $19.00 $5.00 73% OFF!
SOMETHIN&apos; FISHY How far will you press your luck? Reel in your catch now and save them? Or risk being eaten by a hungry shark... $8.00 $2.50 68% OFF!
SQUARED UP - DOMINOSThese fun puzzles will challenge even the most accomplished puzzlers. Put together the nine colorful squares so their edges match perfectly.$8.00 $2.50 68% OFF!
SQUARED UP - DRIVEThese fun puzzles will challenge even the most accomplished puzzlers. Put together the nine colorful squares so their edges match perfectly.$8.00 $2.50 68% OFF!
SQUARED UP - HORSESThese fun puzzles will challenge even the most accomplished puzzlers. Put together the nine colorful squares so their edges match perfectly.$8.00 $2.50 68% OFF!
SQUARED UP - PICNICThese fun puzzles will challenge even the most accomplished puzzlers. Put together the nine colorful squares so their edges match perfectly.$8.00 $2.50 68% OFF!
SQUARED UP - TRAVELThese fun puzzles will challenge even the most accomplished puzzlers. Put together the nine colorful squares so their edges match perfectly.$8.00 $2.50 68% OFF!
SQUARED UP - WALK THE DOGSThese fun puzzles will challenge even the most accomplished puzzlers. Put together the nine colorful squares so their edges match perfectly.$24.50 $10.00 59% OFF!
SUDOKU CHALLENGE / ZOODOKUBased on the worldwide Sudoku puzzle craze! $13.50 $5.00 62% OFF!
TAKE YOUR PICK : QRAZY QUANDARIESTake Your Pick between two tough choices! Would you prefer to wake up with floppy dog ears or a fuzzy bunny tail? $13.50 $5.00 62% OFF!
TAKE YOUR PICK: MOVIES, MUSIC&amp;MOREHow well do you really know your friends and family? $34.00 $10.00 70% OFF!
TEXAS ROLL&apos;EM Bring your best poker face to the table for Texas Roll&apos;em - the dice game of bidding and bluffing that&apos;ll have everyone hooting and hollering!$8.00 $2.50 68% OFF!
TIBBAR CLOCK WOOD PUZZLEOur good buddy Tibbar and his friends help children learn to tell time. Movable arms, and 12 puzzle pieces. $28.00 $15.00 46% OFF!
TIBBAR&apos;S EVERYDAY FELT ADVENTURESLet your child&apos;s creativity flourish as they exercise their imagination with hands-on fun! Featuring 88 full-color felt pieces and three story scenes. $24.50 $7.50 69% OFF!
TREASURE TROTEnter the world of Bella Sara. Have you met the lovely Bella, Thunder, Jewel and Fiona?$14.00 $2.50 82% OFF!
US STATE FLAGS 104PC PUZZLEHow well do you know your State Flags? Learn them all by putting together our 104-piece puzzle! Larger pieces make it great for both kids and adults.$12.00 $5.00 58% OFF!
US STATES WOOD PUZZLEMotor across the USA in a puzzling way. Matching the 50 states by shape and color is challenging and fun. Under each piece is also the state capital name.$34.00 $15.00 55% OFF!
WINDS OF FORTUNEFill the sails of your ship with wind as you navigate your way to the valuable jewels of a Lost Civilization! $39.00 $15.00 61% OFF!
WOODCHUCKBy tossing wood batons, the first team to knock over the opposing team&apos;s woodchucks and the King Woodchuck wins!$19.00 $7.50 60% OFF!
ZING!Zing is a trick-taking game like Hearts, with a crazy new twist. Tags: Day   Sale   Save   Educational   Games   SimplyFun   Dec   Only   Education Loan advice for international student I thought I would turn to the fw community for advice....My SIL who is an interntional student on a student visa is going to graduate school in texas. She has no income and no savings, she lives with us, rent free and bills free. She has no money to pay for her 3rd yr of law school. She is having a tough time finding an intership due to the economy and the saturated lawyers market. I am now looking for loans that graduate students can get, because I am afraid if I dont do something, my DH is going to end up footing a 27yr law students bill. my DH and I are already in school and working full time ourselves. I have tried to get her to find ways to make money using FW tactics, but she has no interest in it...so I have agreed with DH, that he can cosign the loan if need be....and my question now is, where are good places to start searching for graduate school education loans?
i have see the Citi and wellsfargo loan programs...any others you guys can recommend??? (they both require cosigners)Serious responses only and no pic requests!! I am reaching out for help... Tags: Education   Loan   advice   for   international   student   Barnes&amp;Noble/BN.COM 50% off 1 educational toy or game B&amp;M;and ONLINE 11/25 Black Friday Link Tags: Barnes   NobleBNCOM   off   educational   toy   game   and   ONLINE   1125   Black   Friday   BN 40% off one educational toy, game, puzzle, gift ISO http://www.barnesandnoble.com/email/print_nav.asp?r=1&amp;PID;=41325&amp;...
Expires 11/24 In store only Tags: off   one   educational   toy   game   puzzle   gift   ISO   Save $16.48 with this Months Box Tops For Education Coupons (Betty Crocker/General Mills/Pillsbury/Ziploc) Log in or register (Print limit is 2-Ex. 30 days from print)$.60 off one box of Honey Nut Cheerios cereal
$.60 off one box of Lucky Charms cereal
$1.10 off any one Frozen Pillsbury Egg Scrambles or Grands! Biscuit Sandwiches
$.60 off one box any flavor Lucky Charms Treats, Golden Grahams Treats, Chex Mix Treats, OR Milk&amp;Ceral Bars
$.80 off any flavor/variety Cascadian Farm product
$1.10 off two boxes of Chex cereals: Rice Chex, Corn Chex, Wheat Chex, or Honey Nut Chex
$.85 off two Various Yoplait Kids Yogurt multipacks
$1.10 off two Berry Crocker Cookie Mixes
$.60 off when you buy both Betty Crocker Supermoist Cake Mix and Betty Crocker Ready to Spread Frosting
$.60 off one 28 OZ. or larger Bisquick Baking Mix or Complete Pancake&amp;Waffle Mix
$.85 off one 16 OZ. or larger Bisquick Gluten Free Baking Mix
$.85 off two boxes any flavor Betty Crocker Supreme Brownie or Dessert Bar Mixes
$1.10 off two any flavor/variety Betty Crocker Box Muffin Mix or Fiber One Box Muffin Mix
$.40 off two cans any size/variety Pillsbury Refrigerated Grands! or Grands! Jr. Biscuits
$.50 off two Pillsbury Refrigerated Pizza Crust, Breadsticks, Loaves or Dinner Rolls
$.60 off two packages of packages of Pillsbury Rolled Refrigerated Pie Crusts
$.50 off two Pillsbury Sweet Rolls OR Grands! Sweet Rolls
$.60 off two Pillsbury Cresent Dinner Rolls
$1.10 off two packages any variety Pillsbury Refrigerated Cookie Dough
$1 off two Ziploc ContainersClick here top Print Box Tops for Education Couponshttp://www.boxtops4education.com/earn/clip/coupons.aspx Tags: Save   1648   with   this   Months   Box   Tops   For   Education   Coupons   Betty   CrockerGeneral   MillsPillsburyZiploc   Dept. Education Direct Loan Rebate? So I was finally able to login to the myedaccount website today, and saw something under the &quot;Benefits&quot; section of my loan summary.The Description section reads: &quot;DL REBATE NEGATIVE PR FOR LTP&quot; and indicates my status as &quot;Qualifying.&quot;Does anyone have any idea what this means? Tried calling, but was put on hold for an hour-long loop telling me my call would be answered in &quot;10 minutes&quot; and gave up. Tags: Dept   Education   Direct   Loan   Rebate   Dept. of Education Direct Loans So I&apos;ve been enrolled in Autopay for my Student Loans. Well today I noticed it didn&apos;t debit, and upon checking their website, they completely revamped it (Now it points to www.myedaccount.com). Which was expected. What I didn&apos;t expect was that my auto pay info was NOT carried over, and I missed a payment. Not to mention, the site is really messed up, its really lagging quite a bit. I suspect there are thousands of people out there trying to pay their late student loans.Questions..
- Has this happened to anyone else? Did you call and manage to get through to customer service?
- Will they report to the credit bureaus? It was due 10/7, and if I can get this damn thing to pay I&apos;ll pay it now, or call tomorrow and pay over the phone... Tags: Dept   Education   Direct   Loans   5 Free McGraw-Hill Math Educational Apps for on iTunes @ITune Everyday Mathematics Addition Top It
Everyday Mathematics Monster Squeeze
Everyday Mathematics Beat the Computer Multiplication
Everyday Mathematics Equivalent Fractions
Everyday Mathematics Divisibility DashTime limited Tags: Free   McGraw   Hill   Math   Educational   Apps   for   iTunes   ITune   McGraw-Hill Education 5 Math titles free on itunes -Septermber 24 to 26 only... If you have kids who are struggling with math, this freebie is for you!September 24 thru the 26th, McGraw-Hill Education is offering 5 of its 10 EM Game Apps for FREE!!! The Following Apps are Free via iTunes store for iphone and ipad:Addition Top-ItMonster SqueezeEquivalent FractionsBeat The ComputerDivisibility Dash Tags: McGraw   Hill   Education   Math   titles   free   itunes   Septermber   only   6-in-1 Solar-Powered Educational Robotic Kit With 6 Models! $10 Shipped @ 1 Sale http://1saleaday.com/ Tags: Solar   Powered   Educational   Robotic   Kit   With   Models   Shipped   Sale   Online homebuyer education workshop for certificate of completion HUD approved? Is there an online workshop/class for first-time homebuyer education that provides a certificate of completion and HUD-approved?
I live in Florida. I found many local workshops but all of them offer classes on Saturdays (I have work). None of the organizations I found on hud website has the online option. Thanks all. Tags: Online   homebuyer   education   workshop   for   certificate   completion   HUD   approved   New 6-in-1 Educational Do It Yourself Solar Powered Robot Kit $9.98 Shipped @ D/S http://toys.dailysteals.com/ Tags: New   Educational   Yourself   Solar   Powered   Robot   Kit   998   Shipped   6-in-1 Solar-Powered Educational Robotic Kit With 6 Models ($4.99) @ 1 Sale A Day 
 Tags: Solar   Powered   Educational   Robotic   Kit   With   Models   499   Sale   Day   TESSELL ROCKING HORSE / EDUCATIONAL PUZZLE PLAY MAT $50 Shipped @ Shnoop http://shnoop.com/ Tags: TESSELL   ROCKING   HORSE   EDUCATIONAL   PUZZLE   PLAY   MAT   Shipped   Shnoop   6-in-1 Solar-Powered Educational Robotic Kit With 6 Models! $10 Shipped @ 1 Sale http://1saleaday.com/ Tags: Solar   Powered   Educational   Robotic   Kit   With   Models   Shipped   Sale   Educational Toy - Snap Circuits FM Radio Kit $14 FSSS @ Amazon. Loads of fun! Ages 8&amp;up Snap Circuits FM Radio Kit Product DescriptionChallenge young scientific minds with this Snap Circuits kit that lets you build an FM Radio. Have fun building your radio; then tune it to your favorite FM station when you are finished. Easy to build and fun to use. Requires 3 &quot;AA&quot; batteries, not included. Tags: Educational   Toy   Snap   Circuits   Radio   Kit   FSSS   Amazon   Loads   fun   Ages   6 Free Online Educational Games at Kabongo Get 6 FREE Online Educational Games at Kabongo TWO online habitats (i.e. worlds of learning) that include 6 online games completely FREE (a $10 value)!Kabongo Builds the thinking skills kids need to read Games adapt to your childs level, inspiring confidence Interactive rewards keep kids playing&amp;learning Designed by cognitive psychologists&amp;learning experts.Play challenging learning games
Solve exciting mini quests
Explore fantastical habitats
Create your own character
Decorate your tree house
Make your own comic book
Build and ride in your own custom skate park
Parent Dashboard https://www.kabongo.com/impact-radius-landing/ Tags: Free   Online   Educational   Games   Kabongo   Roth 401(k) contributions -gt; Roth IRA rollover -gt; Education withdrawal penalty free? I currently have ~$15K of Roth 401(k) contributions in addition to the $5K worth of ~5% salary drop from my employer (not a match, not treated as Roth since from employer).I expect to have grad school expenses in fall of 2012. My current employment will end in Summer 2012. My thought was to roll over to Roth IRA at Vanguard upon termination of employment and then withdraw any money needed for school expense. Questions:1. Will I be subject to 10% withdrawal penalty on the Roth IRA, as a general penalty or in proportion to the contribution/earnings mix of my balance at the time of withdrawal? I would like to be able to withdraw all contributions (not earnings), penalty free as it will be a Roth IRA.2. How will the ~$5k of employer, non-Roth 401(k) contributions be treated if I do the rollover? Tags: Roth   401k   contributions   IRA   rollover   Education   withdrawal   penalty   free   How to profit when the higher education bubble bursts It&apos;s pretty obvious to me that higher education is in a bubble, just like tech in 2000 and the housing market three years ago. Skyrocketing tuition rates, increasing amounts of student debt, along with stagnant wages mean that people will soon be balking at paying $100k for a degree that will earn them $30k a year. I think this is going to mostly affect mid- to lower-ranked private schools (Boston University is a local example that comes to mind). I think schools like this will start to see fewer and fewer admissions over the next 5 years or so. Flagship state universities will see increasing numbers of applications from in-state students such that they&apos;ll have to cap the number admitted (many already do). Second-tier state universities will start to see more applications and will increase capacity in response. &quot;Hard&quot; majors like engineering (maybe finance?) will see increasing numbers of applicants across the board. Trade schools will prosper. I can&apos;t predict how for-profit schools (like University of Phoenix) will figure into this trend, but I believe that they will probably adapt and be successful.There will probably be more cascading effects, but the question is how can one profit from this? Education hasn&apos;t been packaged into a security that I know of other than publicly traded for-profits like U of P. How can you short George Washington University? Does it make sense to anyone else to invest in for-profit colleges? Tags: How   profit   when   the   higher   education   bubble   bursts   How to profit when the higher education bubble burtst It&apos;s pretty obvious to me that higher education is in a bubble, just like tech in 2000 and the housing market three years ago. Skyrocketing tuition rates, increasing amounts of student debt, along with stagnant wages mean that people will soon be balking at paying $100k for a degree that will earn them $30k a year. I think this is going to mostly affect mid- to lower-ranked private schools (Boston University is a local example that comes to mind). I think schools like this will start to see fewer and fewer admissions over the next 5 years or so. Flagship state universities will see increasing numbers of applications from in-state students such that they&apos;ll have to cap the number admitted (many already do). Second-tier state universities will start to see more applications and will increase capacity in response. &quot;Hard&quot; majors like engineering (maybe finance?) will see increasing numbers of applicants across the board. Trade schools will prosper. I can&apos;t predict how for-profit schools (like University of Phoenix) will figure into this trend, but I believe that they will probably adapt and be successful.There will probably be more cascading effects, but the question is how can one profit from this? Education hasn&apos;t been packaged into a security that I know of other than publicly traded for-profits like U of P. How can you short George Washington University? Does it make sense to anyone else to invest in for-profit colleges? Tags: How   profit   when   the   higher   education   bubble   burtst   Save $10 of $45 order of Educational Toys, Games and Kits at Escapade Direct www.EscapadeDirect.comGet your kids thinking in creative, &quot;outside the box&quot; ways! Help them Learn with educational brainy kits, books, games, and toys! Let them Think, Explore, and Experiment - all while having Fun! Shop our unique selection of products, and experience our one-of-a-kind services and creative ideas. Expect adventures! Save $10 when you spend $45 or more
Enter save1040 into the Source Code box during checkout, and click Apply.Only persons residing in United States who are at least 18 years of age can enter.Campaign Ends March 31, 2011 @ 11:59 pm (CDT) Tags: Save   order   Educational   Toys   Games   and   Kits   Escapade   Direct   Cat in the Hat&apos;s Learning Library - Educational Books for Kids - $5.00/ea Shipped (22 options) - WalMart.com http://www.walmart.com/search/search-ng.do?search_query=cat+in+the+hat+learning+library
Please copy/paste link (can&apos;t get the direct link to work properly)$5.00 each with Free Shipping to Home or Free Ship to Store.Compare at Amaz0n at $8.99/ea (Link to list for reference).
Hope some parents find this useful. Seems like a cool idea with LOTS of high reviews on Amaz0n. Although I gotta say, this is certainly a break from the Dr. Suess I grew up with!
Saw this on SD, so I thought I&apos;d bring it over. Thanks Nylene Tags: Cat   the   Hats   Learning   Library   Educational   Books   for   Kids   500ea   Shipped   options   WalMartcom   Kids educational Toy- VTech USA Learning Fun $12 free shipping Target TargetVTech USA Learning FunList: $17.94Save: $5.95 (33%) $11.99
Free Shippinghttp://www.target.com/gp/detail.html/?asin=B0038B2DTO&amp;ref;=sc_sk_...Includes 50 touchable objects that have 10 modes of play, a colorful map with fun graphics and a carry handle for transportability
Helps teach kids landmarks and more
Manufacturer&apos;s Suggested Age: 3 Years and Up5 out of 5 stars based on 2 reviews Tags: Kids   educational   Toy   VTech   USA   Learning   Fun   free   shipping   Target   Free $50,000 life insurance policy for low income parents to help cover educational expenses for their children Mods if you feel this post belongs in the free or finance forums please go ahead and move it.MassMutual is offering a free $50,000 life insurance policy for low income parents that will put $50,000 into a trust that will go for educational expenses.Some of the qualifications of this program are:Between the ages of 19 and 42;
The parent or legal guardian of one or more dependent
children under age 18;
A permanent, legal resident of the United States;
Currently employed full or part time with a total
family income not less than $10,000 or more than
$40,000 annually;
The only parent or legal guardian in your household
who has applied; and
In good health as determined by MassMutuals
underwriting guidelines.Under the LifeBridge Free Life Insurance Program,
Massachusetts Mutual Life Insurance Company
(MassMutual) will issue a $50,000 term life insurance
policy to a trust for a period of 10 years and at no cost
to you. MassMutual pays the premiums. If you die
within that time period, the $50,000 is used to cover the
educational expenses of your children.I don&apos;t qualify but I know several parents who would.link Tags: Free   50000   life   insurance   policy   for   low   income   parents   help   cover   educational   expenses   their   children   Free $50,000 life insurance policy for low income parents to help cover educational expenses for their children Mods if you feel this post belongs in the free or finance forums please go ahead and move it.MassMutual is offering a free $50,000 life insurance policy for low income parents that will put $50,000 into a trust that will go for educational expenses.Some of the qualifications of this program are:Between the ages of 19 and 42;
The parent or legal guardian of one or more dependent
children under age 18;
A permanent, legal resident of the United States;
Currently employed full or part time with a total
family income not less than $10,000 or more than
$40,000 annually;
The only parent or legal guardian in your household
who has applied; and
In good health as determined by MassMutuals
underwriting guidelines.Under the LifeBridge Free Life Insurance Program,
Massachusetts Mutual Life Insurance Company
(MassMutual) will issue a $50,000 term life insurance
policy to a trust for a period of 10 years and at no cost
to you. MassMutual pays the premiums. If you die
within that time period, the $50,000 is used to cover the
educational expenses of your children.I don&apos;t qualify but I know several parents who would.link Tags: Free   50000   life   insurance   policy   for   low   income   parents   help   cover   educational   expenses   their   children   Free Educational Kit from Panda express - Teacher or Homeschooler Free Educational Kit from Panda express
It says you can apply if you are a teacher or a homeschooler Kit includes
* Panda Express Year of the Rabbit DVD
* Year of the Rabbit Fact Sheet
* Jade Emperors Interactive Game&amp;Activity Sheet
* Chinese New Year Decoration Art Activity
* Lai See Activity Sheet
* Bookmarks (with a Free Kids Meal with purchase coupon attachedhttp://www.pandaexpress.com/px/2010/CNYSignUp.aspx Tags: Free   Educational   Kit   from   Panda   express   Teacher   Homeschooler   going on Educational Leave of Absence .. questions regarding insurance I have already cleared any paid time off and will be finishing off a doctoral degree in engineering during the 2 year time frame. I basically have research left, any classes I take are for my own enrichmwnt.My question falls on insurance for next year. I will be undetgoing eye surgery at the end of the year, which is the main reason insurance is important. Currently Iam in benefits correction period until Dec 31. I live in NH, work and go to school in MA. My school has a form to enroll in insurance... it claims that a change in job is a qualified event (i will have a graduate stipend, not sure if that counts) , but it also mentions declining COBRA or a health plan is an unqualified event. If unqualified, they claim that they will only provide 6 months of emergency care at policy start. School insurance is $1.5k til Aug 31st.
Work insurance per year (employee and employer cost together is 4.6k, employee cost is 1.5k)There is a possibility that school insurance is covered by my teaching assistanceship, but not totally sure yet, need to find out details.I haven&apos;t looked into buying insurance on my own, is that even an option given the scenario? Would appreciate anyone knowledgeable to respond with some advice as far as what option would make the most sense. Tags: going   Educational   Leave   Absence   questions   regarding   insurance   Educational Insights Eggspert &quot;Buzz-in system&quot; $14.99 reg $49.99 AMAZON http://www.amazon.com/Educational-Insights-7883-Eggspert/dp/B001...Great to use as a buzz-in game at home or school. No fights over who answered 1st.Regularly $49.99 Tags: Educational   Insights   Eggspert   Buzz   system   1499   reg   4999   AMAZON   Educational Insights Design and Drill Tool Kit was $29.99 now $9.99 @ Amazon Link w/FSSS * Action and sound of a real working power screwdriver
* Shifts from forward to reverse
* Carrying case folds out into a sturdy design board
* 60 bolts in 5 colors
* Activity guide with 10 patterns for kids to follow
* 5 New Colors
* Includes 60 regular bolts
* Includes carrying case Tags: Educational   Insights   Design   and   Drill   Tool   Kit   was   2999   now   999   Amazon   Educational Insights GeoSafari Talking Microscope Adventure Kit $24 Shipped @ Amazon Gold Box http://www.amazon.com/gp/goldbox Tags: Educational   Insights   GeoSafari   Talking   Microscope   Adventure   Kit   Shipped   Amazon   Gold   Box   Receive a FREE copy of Adobe Coldfusion 8 if you are a student, faculty, or staff at an eligible educational institution Receive a FREE copy of Adobe Coldfusion 8 if you are a student, faculty, or staff at an eligible educational institution.
LINKY Tags: Receive   FREE   copy   Adobe   Coldfusion   you   are   student   faculty   staff   eligible   educational   institution   Robotic 6 in 1 Educational Solar Kit $7 +4Ship orFS wFB code Robotic 6 in 1 Educational Solar Kit LINKY
FREE SHIPPING Code on Past Daily Deals on our Facebook page! Become a Fan today!The 6-In-1 Educational Solar Robotic Kit is an excellent beginner building kit designed to teach how solar power is used to drive a small motor. Children use the 21 snap together parts (no tools required) to build six different working models including a car, airboat, windmill, puppy, and two different airplanes. Solar building kits teach children the benefits of solar energy, while they create a toy that is both fun to play with and requires no batteries. Educators, science museums, and hobbyists will surely appreciate the durability, educational value, and endless hours of amusement for children and adults too! This is a beginner kit recommended for ages 10 and up.
.
For Children 10+
Build six different working models including an car, airboat, windmill, puppy and two different planes
Building these projects teach how solar power is used to drive a small motor
21 Piece kit (no tools required) ... only one project can be completed at a time21 Piece Solar DIY Model
Instruction Manual Tags: Robotic   Educational   Solar   Kit   4Ship   orFS   wFB   code   Free long distance learning Continuing Legal Education First Post For anyone who needs Continuing Legal Education classes, www.IPColloquium.com allows you to listen or download for free online to their hour seminars for which you can receive CLE credit in certain states. You can print off your certificate of attendance, which will be emailed to you, after listening to the seminar, and entering passwords. More information is available on the website. You may be charged a fee when you submit it to your state organization for CLE credit, but that charge is nominal, where I live, it&apos;s $2 for each hour, compared to paying $45 an hour for credit.Tina Tags: Free   long   distance   learning   Continuing   Legal   Education   How to set up a college education fund even though I don&apos;t have a kid? I am soon to come into some money under circumstances that I would rather not have happen and think a good thing to do with the money (and to have it serve a better purpose than myself just frivolously spending it) is to put it away for my future kid&apos;s college education. The thing is that I am unmarried, not currently dating, w/o kids and prob not getting married for a couple years. So what are some good ideas to put this money away? I&apos;m guessing the govt has 0 tax deferral options for people w/o kids thinking about future kids. I want my future kids someday to know that this money came from someone who cared for them even though they never met them. Maybe I could have their entire college education paid by the time they&apos;re ready -- and of course at that time, I would have to come up with stipulations for them to receive it.... Tags: How   set   college   education   fund   even   though   dont   have   kid   FREE iPhone/iPod Touch/iPad app: Happy Sex with Maryline: Sexuality Coaching and Education Guide for Adults, was $19.99 FREE iPhone/iPod Touch/iPad app: Happy Sex with Maryline: Sexuality Coaching and Education Guide for Adultshttp://itunes.apple.com/us/app/happy-sex-maryline-sexuality/id34...http://appshopper.com/lifestyle/happy-sex-with-maryline-sexualit... Tags: FREE   iPhoneiPod   TouchiPad   app   Happy   Sex   with   Maryline   Sexuality   Coaching   and   Education   Guide   for   Adults   was   1999   Company trying to clawback education reimbursement My sister recently left her old company. She&apos;d recieved some tuition reimbursement to get a Masters degree but left the company before the agreed-upon time she could leave without repaying the money back. She knew this in advance but the new offer was too good to resist.Anyways she owed them about 11k and has paid 6k back. They recently told her they need the 5k by Dec. 1 but also offered to adjust her final W2 so that the 5k would show up there in place of previously tax-deferred money. Maybe she didn&apos;t explain it to me properly but my gut instinct says just pay the 5k and avoid any tinkering with the W2. I guess my question is why the company would want to do things this way? And what possible benefit could my sis get from it? Tags: Company   trying   clawback   education   reimbursement   Midwestern Disaster Area increased Education Credit OK so a coworker of mine got this letter from HR block stating that since he lived in Indiana he may of been entitled to some deductions/credits that he did not get in 08/09 for his tax returns. He then met with a tax advisor at a local HR Block and they amended his return to state the changes in both years and he got about $2500 back because he was claiming the american tax credit before. I was a student in the same area and claimed the american tax credit so I called her to speak about it and she looked through my return because I filed in 09 at HR Block. I looked up the phone number and it looks legit, I looked up her name and e-mail which both show as hr block branded, email is first.last@tax.hrblock.com. She quoted me a number that was similar to his and I just wanted to get fatwallets take on this before I go through with amending. So what should I look at for? His amendment is on HR Block letterhead and he just is supposed to send it in. I want to make sure that the &quot;to good to be true&quot; bug doesn&apos;t bite me. Tags: Midwestern   Disaster   Area   increased   Education   Credit   Request your FREE copy of the Military.com Education Benefits Guide. http://edu.military.com/gibill/?ESRC=fd_edu_shrt80.op&amp;psrc;=1055_... Tags: Request   your   FREE   copy   the   Militarycom   Education   Benefits   Guide   6 in 1 Educational Solar Kit Robotikits $6.70 Howdy!A few days ago I found this solar kit but it was $8.90, so I thought it was a bit expensive. Fortunately, the price has decreased to $6.70!
I hope it works well and the pieces do not break too easily...Link to the FocalPrice ProductFocalPrice said:Description:
* This toy can be assembled into solar airboat, windmill, puppy, car, plane, revolving plane&amp;contains a total of 22 parts.
* It&apos;s not the kind of blankly building blocks, they will move.
* Sunlight shine solar panels, provide small toys with endless power.
* The toys can give full play and nurture children&apos;s imagination, creativity.
* It does not require screws to connect, just a simple assembly can be completed so that children can learn to enjoy yourself to bring sense of accomplishment.

Product Details (including package): weight:174 g size:21*18*4.5 cm
For those who love Solar gadgets and DIY things like me! Tags: Educational   Solar   Kit   Robotikits   670   Barnes and Noble: 40% off list price of @School item or Educational Toys&amp;Games Item @School
Toys&amp;GamesEnter code &quot;A7B9W7U&quot; at checkout to receive 40% off the list price of one @School item or an Educational Toys and Games item.The item must have a label next to it that says &quot;B&amp;N;@School&quot; or &quot;Toys and Games&quot; for it to work. (see icons)Code expires 8/7/10 at 2:59 am. Tags: Barnes   and   Noble   off   list   price   School   item   Educational   Toys   Games   Educational + Scholarship Freebies FREE 2010 Education Guide
Get your FREE 2010 Education Guide to obtaining Free Government Grants, Financial
Aid, and information on over 1,900 colleges and universities.FastWeb Free Scholarship Search
FastWeb has exclusive tools for students to search for college scholarships by their interests. Students
have the power to search, find, and apply for college scholarships all on one website!Try FREE Online Computer Classes
These courses are suited for both the savvy computer user and beginner alike. Our more popular
courses include Microsoft Office 2007 including Excel, Outlook, Word, and PowerPoint, Microsoft
Windows Vista, Introduction to Mac OS 10.5 Leopard, and Google Docs. Tags: Educational   Scholarship   Freebies   60% off tuition @ University of Texas [Nursing or Education] - possibly other schools and degrees available www.utadegree.comMy niece got her nursing degree in this little known online program (with resident training at her hospital). Same degree as on campus, same salary bump afterward ... but 60% less cost and online. Couple with your employer&apos;s tuition reimbursement to sweeten the deal. From their website:Enjoy these great program benefits: * Quality degree from UT Arlington
* Save 60% compared to other online master&apos;s degrees
* Complete online, at your convenience in as little as 13 months
* Start regardless of prerequisites and your prerequisites don&apos;t expire
* Earn the same degree as on campus
* Learn from the same professors who teach on campus
* Flexible payment options and financial aid availableChoose from the following degree programs: * RN to BSN (Bachelor of Science in Nursing)
* M.Ed. in Educational Leadership&amp;Policy Studies
* M.Ed. in Curriculum&amp;Instruction - Literacy Studies
* M.Ed. in Curriculum&amp;Instruction - Math Education
* M.Ed. in Curriculum&amp;Instruction - Science Educationwww.utadegree.com Tags: off   tuition   University   Texas   Nursing   Education   possibly   other   schools   and   degrees   available   Washington State Guaranteed Education Tuition (GET) Program I am thinking to open a Washington Guaranteed Education Tuition (GET) Program account for my 8-yr-old son. The GET Program is Washingtons 529 prepaid college tuition plan. You prepay for your childs future college tuition and the value of your account is guaranteed by the state to keep pace with rising college tuition. Please see the details from the link below: http://get.wa.gov/Does anybody have experience or comments about this program or simailar program? Thank you for the feedback Tags: Washington   State   Guaranteed   Education   Tuition   GET   Program   6 in 1 Educational Solar Kit,$6.99 free shipping from Popbuying http://www.popbuying.com/detail.pb/sku.29396Deal Expire on May 15th6 in 1 Educational Solar Kit Information
Mini Solar building kits teach children the benefits of solar energy while they create a toy that is both fun to play with and requires no batteries. Newest member of this popular line is the 6 in 1 Educational Solar Kit, an excellent beginner building kit designed to teach how solar power is used to drive a small motor. Children use the 21 snap together parts (no tools required) to build six different working models including an airboat, windmill, puppy, and two different planes.6 in 1 Educational Solar Kit Features
Building these projects teach the benefits of solar energy while having fun
Build six different working models including an airboat, windmill, puppy and two different planes
Only one project can be completed at a time
The projects are solar powered but the panel can be energized by a 50w household Halogen lamp6 in 1 Educational Solar Kit Specifications
Motor: 12000 rpm / DC 1.2V
Solar Panel Output: 75mA
Tool needed: Diagonal Cutter
Package size (L*W*T): 206.0*180.0*50.0mm
Weight (including the packing): 180.0g6 in 1 Educational Solar Kit Package Included
1 x 6 in 1 Educational Solar Kit Set
1 x Manual Tags: Educational   Solar   Kit699   free   shipping   from   Popbuying   60% off tuition @ University of Texas [Nursing or Education] www.utadegree.comMy niece got her nursing degree in this little known online program. Same degree as on campus, same salary bump afterward ... but 60% less cost and online. Couple with your employer&apos;s tuition reimbursement to sweeten the deal. From their website:Enjoy these great program benefits: * Quality degree from UT Arlington
* Save 60% compared to other online master&apos;s degrees
* Complete online, at your convenience in as little as 13 months
* Start regardless of prerequisites and your prerequisites don&apos;t expire
* Earn the same degree as on campus
* Learn from the same professors who teach on campus
* Flexible payment options and financial aid availableChoose from the following degree programs: * RN to BSN (Bachelor of Science in Nursing)
* M.Ed. in Educational Leadership&amp;Policy Studies
* M.Ed. in Curriculum&amp;Instruction - Literacy Studies
* M.Ed. in Curriculum&amp;Instruction - Math Education
* M.Ed. in Curriculum&amp;Instruction - Science Educationwww.utadegree.com Tags: off   tuition   University   Texas   Nursing   Education   Free Foundation for Individual Rights in Education Shirt or Mug - Must Add Widget TextYou have to add their widget to your blog or website Tags: Free   Foundation   for   Individual   Rights   Education   Shirt   Mug   Must   Add   Widget   Book Closeouts sale - Kids Educational books only $0.99 $0.99 Sale on selected kids&apos; educational books at http://bookcloseouts.comDon&apos;t forget about the CashBack! Tags: Book   Closeouts   sale   Kids   Educational   books   only   099   Free Reusable Tote Bag from Discovery Education - Teachers http://thinkgreen.discoveryeducation.com/bottom of page Tags: Free   Reusable   Tote   Bag   from   Discovery   Education   Teachers   
Popular Tags
 
 
Copyright©2010 FullOfDeals.com. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
