<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000609" url="http://www.scubish.com/overview/464/Asia/Taiwan" time="2012-07-12-15:53" support="2" score="0.0020569258938591723" bingtitle="scubish.com: Scuba diving Taiwan - Asia" webtitle="scubish.com: Scuba diving Taiwan - Asia">
			<query id="001084" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="001087" bing-rank="250"/>
	<description>... meal at a Western fast food restaurant ... to use a separate utensil ... agencies such as collection of parking fees, utility bills, traffic violation fines, and credit card ...</description>
	<body>
		Home 
 
 Africa Asia Europe North America Oceania South America 
 
 Destinations 
 
 News US Navy Scuba Manual Deepsix Scuba Manual Links Articles Fun: Quiz   
 
 Info Buddyfinder Gear Divelog Forum Search 
 
 Edit Profile Edit Dive Log My Trips My Buddylist My Comments   
 
 My Scubish 
 
 Contact Us FAQ   
 
 About Us   
 
 World ▫ Asia ▫ Taiwan 
 Overview Travel Guide Information Country Information Links Discussions 
 
 

 
 Taiwan 

In 1895, military defeat forced China to cede Taiwan to Japan. Taiwan reverted to Chinese control after World War II. Following the Communist victory on the mainland in 1949, 2 million Nationalists fled to Taiwan and established a government using the 1946 constitution drawn up for all of China. Over the next five decades, the ruling authorities gradually democratized and incorporated the local population within the governing structure. In 2000, Taiwan underwent its first peaceful transfer of power from the Nationalist to the Democratic Progressive Party. Throughout this period, the island prospered and became one of East Asia&apos;s economic &quot;Tigers.&quot; The dominant political issues continue to be the relationship between Taiwan and China - specifically the question of eventual unification - as well as domestic political and economic reform.
 

 Great dive locations in
 Taiwan : 
 Kaohsiung Keelung Ping-dong Xian Ping-tung Shi-chih City Shin Chu City Taichung Taipei Taitung County Taoyuan Hsien Taoyuon 
 
 

 
 Understand 
Taiwan has been populated for thousands of years by more than a dozen aboriginal tribes. Written history begins with the partial colonization of Taiwan by the Spaniards and then the Dutch in the early 17th century. (The old name of Taiwan, Formosa , comes from the Portuguese Ilse Formosa for &quot;beautiful island&quot;.) Han Chinese immigrants who had trickled in since the end of the Yuan dynasty (1300s) arrived in larger numbers during the domestic turmoil surrounding the decline of the Ming Dynasty. Although controlled by the Dutch, the Ming loyalist Koxinga defeated the Dutch garrisons and set up Taiwan as a rump Ming Empire with the hope of reconquering Qing China. His son surrendered to the Qing in the late 1600s. Although contact between China and Taiwan dates back thousands of years, it was not until larger numbers of Han residents arrived during the Ming and Qing dynasties that Taiwan was formally integrated into China as part of Fujian province. It became a separate province in 1885. Defeated by the Japanese, the Qing Empire ceded Taiwan to Japan under the terms of the treaty of Shimonoseki. Japan ruled the island until 1945, and exerted profound influences on its development. Much of the Japanese-built infrastructure can still be seen on the island today, and has been in fact continuously used up to the present day (e.g. rail-road crossing gates, administrative buildings, and the old port at Kaohsiung).

In the early 20th century, the Nationalists ( Kuomintang , KMT) and Communists fought a major civil war in China. Although the two sides were briefly united against Japan during World War II, they quickly began fighting again after the war was over. Eventually, the Communists were victorious. The Nationalist government, the remnant of their army, and hundreds of thousands of supporters fled to Taiwan. From Taipei, they continued to assert their right as the sole legitimate government of all China. Initially repressive, the government began to loosen control under the leadership of Chiang Kai-shek&apos;s son, Chiang Ching-kuo. Democratization began in earnest through the 1980s and 1990s, culminating with the first direct presidential elections in 1996, and the first peaceful transition of power between two political parties in 2000.

Taiwanese politics remain dominated by the issue of relations between Taiwan and the People&apos;s Republic of China, which still claims Taiwan as a &quot;renegade province&quot; and regularly threatens military action if Taiwan attempts to break away from the current awkward One China status quo, where both sides agree that there is only one Chinese nation, but disagree on whether that one nation is governed by the PRC or the ROC. To summarize a very complex situation, the Pan-Blue group spearheaded by the KMT supports eventual unification with the mainland, while the Pan-Green group led by the Democratic Progressive Party (DPP) supports eventual independence. The split extends down to trivial issues like Chinese romanization—the KMT prefers the mainland&apos;s hanyu pinyin , the DPP prefers a Taiwan-made variant called tongyong pinyin —and political demonstrations and rallies, always turbulent, on... 
 
 

 
 
 Taiwan (Traditional Chinese:台灣 or 臺灣, Simplified Chinese:台湾) is an island of about 36,000 square kilometers located off the coast of southeastern China, southwest of Okinawa and north of the Philippines. The island is administered by the Republic of China (中華民國 Zhōnghuá Mínguó ) or ROC . Shaped roughly like a sweet potato, the island is home to more than 22 million people and is one of the most densely populated places in the world. Besides its crowded cities and friendly people, Taiwan is also known for steep mountains and lush forests. In addition to the island of Taiwan, the Republic of China also governs the Pescadores (Penghu), Quemoy (Kinmen/Jinmen), and Matsu.

 Regions 
The Taiwan Area can be divided into five regions:

 Central Taiwan —This region includes the Central Mountains, central western coastal area, scenic Sun Moon Lake and Taichung city. Counties: Changhua County, Miaoli County, Nantou County, Taichung County. 
 Eastern Taiwan —This area, cut off from the rest of the island by mountains, contains Taiwan&apos;s most striking natural scenery, including the famous Taroko Gorge (Tailuge Gorge) and the cities of Hualien and Taitung. Counties: Hualien County, Taitung County, Yilan County. 
 Northern Taiwan —the capital, Taipei, and the high-tech hub, Hsinchu, are located in this region, as well as the Yangmingshan National Park. Counties: Hsinchu County, Taipei County, Taoyuan County. 
 Southern Taiwan —This area is more tropical than the rest of the island, with many beaches and coconut palms. Taiwan&apos;s second largest city, Kaohsiung, and oldest city, Tainan, are located in the south of the island. Counties: Chiayi County, Kaohsiung County, Pingtung County, Tainan County, Yunlin County. 
 The Outlying Islands —Green Island, Kinmen (Quemoy), Matsu, Orchid Island and Penghu. 

 Cities 

Taiwan has many large cities and towns. Below is a list of nine of the most notable. Other cities are listed under their specific regional section.
 Taipei (臺北 or 台北) is the seat of government of the Republic of China and its center of commerce and culture. Taipei is home to the world&apos;s currently tallest skyscraper, Taipei 101. Hsinchu (新竹) is a center of hi-tech industry, and one of the world&apos;s leading manufacturers of hi-tech components. Hsinchu Science Park is the home to many hi-tech companies. Hualien (花蓮) is located near Taroko Gorge, and is considered one of the most pleasant of Taiwan&apos;s cities. Jiufen (九份) - this former gold mining town located on the northeast coast is now a popular tourist destination. Kaohsiung (高雄) is the second-largest city on the island. It has one of the busiest sea ports (the Port of Kaohsiung) in the world and it has the island&apos;s second-largest airport, Kaohsiung International Airport (KHH) . Keelung (基隆) is the a center of transshipment in the north, and is located about a thirty minute drive from downtown Taipei. Puli (埔里) is located at the geographical center of the island, and it serves as a good base for exploring the central mountains and Sun Moon Lake. Taichung (臺中) is the third largest city in Taiwan, and has an abundance of interesting cultural amenities and activities. Tainan (臺南) is the oldest city in Taiwan and was the capital during imperial times. It is famous for its historic buildings and snack food. 

 Other destinations Kenting National Park - located at the extreme southern tip of the island in Pingtung County, this park is famous for its beaches and lush vegetation. Shei-pa National Park - a park spanning mountains and rivers located in Hsinchu County - great hiking trails Sun Moon Lake - nestled at 2,500 feet in lofty mountains in Nantou County, this lake is famous for its clear sparkling blue water and picturesque mountain backdrop. Taipingshan Forestry Recreation Area - a historic logging area and one of Taiwan&apos;s most scenic spots. Located in Yilan County. Taroko Gorge (太魯閣; tàilǔgé )- an impressive gorge located in Hualien County Yangmingshan National Park - spanning a mountain range overlooking Taipei 

 Understand 
Taiwan has been populated for thousands of years by more than a dozen aboriginal tribes. Written history begins with the partial colonization of Taiwan by the Spaniards and then the Dutch in the early 17th century. (The old name of Taiwan, Formosa , comes from the Portuguese Ilse Formosa for &quot;beautiful island&quot;.) Han Chinese immigrants who had trickled in since the end of the Yuan dynasty (1300s) arrived in larger numbers during the domestic turmoil surrounding the decline of the Ming Dynasty. Although controlled by the Dutch, the Ming loyalist Koxinga defeated the Dutch garrisons and set up Taiwan as a rump Ming Empire with the hope of reconquering Qing China. His son surrendered to the Qing in the late 1600s. Although contact between China and Taiwan dates back thousands of years, it was not until larger numbers of Han residents arrived during the Ming and Qing dynasties that Taiwan was formally integrated into China as part of Fujian province. It became a separate province in 1885. Defeated by the Japanese, the Qing Empire ceded Taiwan to Japan under the terms of the treaty of Shimonoseki. Japan ruled the island until 1945, and exerted profound influences on its development. Much of the Japanese-built infrastructure can still be seen on the island today, and has been in fact continuously used up to the present day (e.g. rail-road crossing gates, administrative buildings, and the old port at Kaohsiung).

In the early 20th century, the Nationalists ( Kuomintang , KMT) and Communists fought a major civil war in China. Although the two sides were briefly united against Japan during World War II, they quickly began fighting again after the war was over. Eventually, the Communists were victorious. The Nationalist government, the remnant of their army, and hundreds of thousands of supporters fled to Taiwan. From Taipei, they continued to assert their right as the sole legitimate government of all China. Initially repressive, the government began to loosen control under the leadership of Chiang Kai-shek&apos;s son, Chiang Ching-kuo. Democratization began in earnest through the 1980s and 1990s, culminating with the first direct presidential elections in 1996, and the first peaceful transition of power between two political parties in 2000.

Taiwanese politics remain dominated by the issue of relations between Taiwan and the People&apos;s Republic of China, which still claims Taiwan as a &quot;renegade province&quot; and regularly threatens military action if Taiwan attempts to break away from the current awkward One China status quo, where both sides agree that there is only one Chinese nation, but disagree on whether that one nation is governed by the PRC or the ROC. To summarize a very complex situation, the Pan-Blue group spearheaded by the KMT supports eventual unification with the mainland, while the Pan-Green group led by the Democratic Progressive Party (DPP) supports eventual independence. The split extends down to trivial issues like Chinese romanization—the KMT prefers the mainland&apos;s hanyu pinyin , the DPP prefers a Taiwan-made variant called tongyong pinyin —and political demonstrations and rallies, always turbulent, on occasion turn violent.

 Get in 
 Visa Information 

Citizens of many countries, including the United States, Canada, Australia and New Zealand, as well as the United Kingdom, Ireland and most other EU members, may enter Taiwan visa-free for thirty days or more provided that their passports do not expire within six months. For further information consult the Bureau of Consular Affairs .

 By plane 

There are international flights into Taiwan Taoyuan International Airport (formerly called Chiang Kai-Shek (CKS) International Airport) in Taoyuan, and to a lesser extent, to the Kaohsiung International Airport. Taichung and Hualien airports also serve small numbers of international passengers. The Songshan domestic airport is located in Taipei.
 Taiwan Taoyuan International Airport (formerly Chiang-Kai Shek Airport ) ( TPE ) is Taiwan&apos;s main international airport. Located 40km to the southwest of Taipei, it has good connections to many major cities except those in mainland China. The airport has direct buses to Taipei, Taichung and other nearby cities. Alternatively, the U-Bus company operates shuttles to HSR Taoyuan (Jhongli) station for high-speed train connections, and to Jhongli Transit Station, for mainline TRA train and southbound bus connections to Tainan, Hsinchu etc. 
 Songshan Airport ( TSA ) in downtown Taipei serves domestic flights only. 
 The Kaohsiung ( KHH ) domestic and international airports are located in the same complex. International flights are only to other Asian cities. 
 Taichung Airport ( RMQ ) serves domestic flights as well as international flights to Hong Kong and Vietnam. 
 Hualien Airport ( HUN ) serves domestic flights as well as some international charter flights to Japan, South Korea and Macau. 

Except for some charter flights at Spring Festival, there are no direct flights between mainland China and Taiwan . The usual practice is to fly via either Hong Kong or Macau, which have good connections both ways. Alternate routes via South Korea or Japan or other Asian countries are possible, but generally more expensive.

 Major airlines 
The main Taiwanese carriers are China Airlines and EVA Air . China Airlines has a dreadful safety record (12 major crashes in 30 years), and quite a few people opt to avoid it if possible. Cathay Pacific schedules many flights to Hong Kong as Taiwanese flights have to go to China via a third destination.
 Cathay Pacific - 2715 2333 China Airlines - 2715 1212 Eva Airways - 2501 1999 KLM Asia - 2711 4055 Northwest - 2772 2188 Singapore Airlines - 2551 6655 Thai Airways - 2509 6800 United Airlines 

For up-to-date information on cheap flights, check the advertisement pages of one of the three local daily English newspapers (see media below)

 By boat 
There are bi-weekly passenger ferry links between Okinawa Island, Ishigaki and Miyako in Okinawa, Japan and Keelung and Kaohsiung in Taiwan. Sometimes, the route goes via Ishigaki and Miyako in Okinawa Prefecture, while the Taiwan port alternates between Keelung and Kaohsiung. Departure from Okinawa is on Friday for the ferry to Kaohsiung (34 hours) and on Monday to Keelung (28 hours); departure from Taiwan is usually on Sunday and Tuesday .

 Get around 

 By plane 
There are four domestic airlines, all of which have business-sized planes and get across Taiwan quite quickly. Flights are frequent, and it is usually unnecessary to book flights in advance. Taipei and Kaohsiung have regular services and links to most other domestic airports; however, it may not be possible to fly from one domestic airport to another. The high-speed rail, which started in January 2007, is expected to give the plane companies a run for their money, with stops located in all the major cities.

If you want to visit places further apart from Taipei, especially some of the islands, you should seriously consider taking a plane. Fares are not too expensive, and local planes are very good. The domestic airport in Taipei is Song Shan Airport , which is located in the north of the Taipei and easily reached by Taxi. Domestic destinations include Kaohsiung, Tainan, Chiayi, Taichung, Pingtung, Taitung, Hualien, Makung (Penghu / Pescadores), Kinmen, Hengchun, Nangan and Beigan. Travelers heading to Kenting can avail themselves of the direct and frequent bus service from Kaohsiung airport that connect with flights arriving from Taipei.

 By train 
Taiwan&apos;s train system is excellent, with stops in all major cities. Train stations are often located in the centers of most cities and towns and serve as a convenient hub for most types of transportation. In addition, the train system allows you to bypass the highways, which can become extremely crowded on weekends and national holidays.

The new train backbone is Taiwan High Speed Rail (HSR, 高鐵) , a bullet train based on Japanese Shinkansen technology that covers the 345km route on the West Coast from Taipei to Zuoying (Kaohsiung) in 90 minutes. A one way economy class ticket from Taipei to Kaohsiung costs NT$1490. Other stops on the route are Banqiao, Taoyuan, Hsinchu, Taichung, Chiayi and Tainan, but note that many THSR stations have been built a fair distance from the cities they serve. Reservations can be made up to two weeks in advance at +886-2-6626-8000 (English spoken), with payment required only when you pick up the tickets.

Mainline trains are run by the separate Taiwan Railway Administration (TRA, 台鐵) , whose services are generally efficient and reliable. Reserving tickets well in advance is recommended when traveling with the train on weekends, especially for long distance travel. Slower (but more frequent) commuter trains without reserved seating are also available. Train timetables and online booking (up to 2 weeks in advance) are available on the TRA website; however, the online services only work between 8am and 9pm or thereabouts and there is a small charge, NT$7, for online bookings. Note that booking online only establishes a reservation as there is no Internet payment option. You must pay for the tickets you reserved at your local train station or post office to actually receive it. Children under a certain height go free, and taller kids get half-price tickets. If you get return tickets there is a small discount. There are also vending machines at the larger stations.

Round island tourist rail passes are also available which allow the holder to embark and disembark a set number of times for a fixed price are also available at most larger train stations. A foreign passport may be required for purchase.

 =Service= 
Aside from THSR, the fastest train is Tzu-Chiang, and the slowest is Pingkuai (Ordinary/Express). There is often little to choose between prices and destination times for adjacent train classes, but the gap can be quite large between the fastest and the slowest.
 Tzu-Chiang (Tsu-chiang /自強): The fastest (and most expensive). Assigned seating. Non-reserved (standing) tickets are also sold at full price. Chu-Kuang (Chu-kwang /莒光): Second fastest. Assigned seating. Fu-hsing (Fu-shing /復興): Third fastest. Assigned seating. Non-reserved tickets are sold at 80% of original price. EMU (Electric multiple unit /電車/Dian Che) and DRC (Diesel railcar /柴客): Short to medium distance commuter train, stops at all stations. No assigned seating. Express / Ordinary (普通): Stops at all stations, no air conditioning, most inexpensive. No assigned seating. Some Express trains (the light blue ones running on West Trunk Line) are air-conditioned while others (dark blue ones) are not equipped with air conditioners. Diesel Express : Only available on East Trunk Line and South Link Line. Mainly serve as commuter trains. No air conditioning. Tickets are the same price as Express and Ordinary. 

For travel to nearby cities, you can travel on electric dianche (電車) commuter trains . These arrive very frequently (about once every ten to fifteen minutes). In addition, &quot;standing tickets&quot; may be purchased on trains with assigned seating that have no available seats. Standing tickets are 80% the original ticket price and may be useful for last minute travelers. The downside is, of course, that you will be required to stand during your entire trip.

Also, do try to get your destination station written in Chinese and try to do some &quot;mix and match&quot; with the system map as well as looking out for the matching Chinese characters written on the station. Unfortunately for the foreigner, announcements are only made in Mandarin, Taiwanese and Hakka so English would not be of much help in the train. Therefore, be alert and always be on the lookout for your destination station, or you risk missing it.

 By bus 
Buses that run between cities and are called keyun , as opposed to gongch e which run within the county and city. Buses run by private companies are generally more luxurious (often boasting wide, soft seats, foot-rests and individual video screens) than those run by government-owned companies. Still, even the government-owned buses are comfortable, punctual, and maintain clean facilities on board.

In major cities, bus transportation is extensive. Route maps, however, are almost entirely in Chinese, though the destinations indicated on the front of buses are in English. If you&apos;re staying at a hotel, have the clerk suggest some routes for you, and circle your destination on the map. Show this to the bus driver, and he/she will hopefully remember to tell you when to get off. In smaller cities, there is often no local bus service, though the out-of-town buses will sometimes make stops in the suburbs. There are taxi ranks at all airports and bus terminals.

Occasionally a bus driver might stop a bus away from the curb at a bus stop. Sometimes it is due to a vehicle illegally parked at a bus stop. (Taiwanese traffic law and regulation prohibit vehicles from stopping or parking within 10 meters of a bus stop.) However, a bus driver might stop a bus away from the curb just because he or she does not want to wait for overtaking traffic while leaving a bus stop. Therefore, be much more careful when getting on or off a bus stopped away from a curb, as many motorcycles, motor scooters, and bicycles will definitely be tempted to overtake on the right side of the stopped bus where people get on and off! (As traffic drives on the right side of the road in Taiwan, buses have doors on the right side.)

 By metro 
Taipei has a useful and rapidly-expanding metro system. Kaoshiung&apos;s two-line metro system is still under construction, but is scheduled to open in 2007.

 By taxi 
Taxis are a dime a dozen in Taiwanese cities. You don&apos;t need to look for a taxi - they&apos;ll be looking for you. The standard yellow cabs scour roads looking for potential riders such as lost foreigners. It is possible but generally unnecessary to phone for a taxi. To hail one, simply place your hand in front of you parallel to the ground. But they&apos;ll often stop for you even if you&apos;re just waiting to cross the street or for a bus.

Drivers generally cannot converse in English or read Westernized addresses (except for special CKS airport taxis). Have the hotel desk or a Taiwanese friend write out your destination in Chinese, and also take a business card from the hotel. Show the driver the Chinese writing of where you are going.

Taxis are visibly metered, and cab drivers are strictly forbidden from taking tips. A maximum of four people can ride in one cab, and for the price of one. Relative to American taxicabs, Taiwanese cabs are inexpensive.

Although taxi drivers in Taiwan tend to be more honest than in many other countries, not all are trustworthy. An indirect trip might cost you half again as much. A cab driver using night-time rates during the daytime will cost you 30% more (make sure he presses the large button on the left on his meter before 11pm). Avoid the especially overzealous drivers who congregate at the exits of train stations. Also, stand your ground and insist on paying meter price only if any driving on mountain roads is involved - some drivers like to tack on surcharges or use night-time rates if driving to places like Maokong or Wulai. Such attempts to cheat are against the law.

From CKS Airport (TPE), buses are a much more economical option but if you want a direct route CKS airport drivers are the best choice. They&apos;re quite comfortable and get you to your destination as quick as possible. All the CKS taxi drivers are interlinked by radio so they could be forwarned if there are police. Sometimes, if there are traffic jams and no police around, the driver will drive in the emergency lane.

The badge and taxi driver identification are displayed inside and the license number marked on the outside. You must also be wary that the driver turns on his meter, otherwise he might rip you off - in such a case, you aren&apos;t obliged to pay; but make sure you can find a police officer to settle the matter. If there are stories of passengers boarding fake taxis and being attacked by the driver, it is best not to be paranoid about it. Drivers may be more worried about passengers attacking them!

If you do call a taxi dispatch center, you will be given a taxi number to identify the vehicle when it arrives. Generally, dispatch is extremely rapid and efficient, as the taxis are constantly monitoring dispatch calls from the headquarters using radio while they are on the move. This is also the safest way to take a taxi, especially for females.

Taxis are also a flexible although relatively expensive way to travel to nearby cities. They have the advantage over the electric trains in that they run very late at night. Drivers are required to provide a receipt if asked, though you might find them unwilling to do so.

Taxis, as elsewhere in Asia, are not keen on exchanging large bills. Try to keep some smaller denomination bills on hand to avoid the hassle of fighting with the driver for change.

Taxi drivers are known for their strong political opinions as many spend all day listening to Taiwanese talk radio. Be careful about your opinions on the cross-strait relations. In addition, if you see what looks like blood spewing from the driver&apos;s mouth, or him spitting blood onto the street - not to fret, it&apos;s merely him chewing betel nut (see box).

 By scooter or motorcycle 
Scooters with an engine size of 50cc require a license to drive, and should be insured and registered in the owner&apos;s name. Until recently - 2003 - it wasn&apos;t even possible to get a scooter above 150cc in Taiwan. Many of the scooters within cities are only 50cc and incapable of going faster than 80 km/h. The more powerful versions known as zhongxing (heavy format) scooters are now quite common and can be rented for short-term use, or found for sale used at English In Taiwan if you&apos;re going to need it for a while. They are not allowed on freeways even if they are capable of going faster than 100 km/h unless used for certain police purposes, but that just means you have to take the scenic route.

If you&apos;re just learning to drive a scooter on the streets of Taiwan, it would be a good idea to practice a bit on a back road or alley until you have a feel for the scooter - attempting to do so in the busier cities could easily be fatal. Certainly, things can get pretty hairy on Taiwanese roads and Taipei in particular has narrower more congested roads than many other cities. However if you know what you&apos;re doing, it&apos;s the perfect way to get around in a city.

It should be possible to rent a scooter by the day or week, depending on the city in which you&apos;re staying. In Taipei, as of 2006, the only place legally renting scooters and motorbikes to foreigners is the Bikefarm , which is run by a very friendly and helpful English guy called Jeremy. In Taichung, Foreigner Assistance Services In Taiwan F.A.S.T offers a rental service for foreign visitors. Otherwise, scooters are generally easy to rent in most major cities, with many such places being conveniently located near railway or bus stations. Most usually require some form of identification even if, in some cases, it consists of your expired Blockbuster video card!
The average price you may expect is 400NT$ for 24hours, this include one or two helmets.

Another option is to rent a motorcycle. Many foreigners swear by their 125cc Wild Wolf motorcycles, and a trip around the island on a motorcycle can be a great way to see the island up close.

 By car 
An international driving license is required for driving in Taiwan and may be used for up to 30 days, after which you&apos;ll need to apply for a local permit. Some municipalities may impose additional restrictions, so check ahead with the rental shop. VIP Rentals in Taipei is quite happy to rent cars to foreigners, and will even deliver the car to a given destination. A deposit is often required, and the last day of rental is not pro-rated, but calculated on a per-hour basis at a separate (higher) rate.

The numbered highway system is very good in Taiwan. Most traffic signs are in international symbols, but many signs show names of places and streets in Chinese only. The highways are in excellent shape with toll stations around every 30 km. Currently a car pays NT$40 when passing each toll station on a highway. Prepaid tickets may be purchased at most convenience stores, allowing faster passage and eliminating the need to count out exact change while driving.

 By thumb 
While Taiwanese themselves don&apos;t generally hitchhike, foreigners who have done so say that it was very easy. However, in rural areas people may not recognize the thumb in the air symbol, and you may have to try other ways - flagging down a car might work on a country lane with little or no public transportation, but doing so on a major road might lead to confusion, with the driver assuming that you are in trouble. A sign, especially one in Chinese, would therefore be of great help. The East coast around Hualien and Taidung enjoys a reputation for being especially good for getting rides. Taiwanese people are very friendly and helpful, so striking up a conversation with someone at a transport cafe or freeway service station may well see you on your way. However, to avoid possible confusion later, ensure that the driver realizes that you want a free ride.

 Talk 
A mix of Taiwanese (Minnan), Mandarin, Hakka and other Asian languages are spoken on the island, as well as several aboriginal Austronesian languages. Taiwanese is the mother tongue of 60% of the population. In the North where there is a large concentration of so-called &quot;mainlanders&quot; (those whose families came to Taiwan from China in the mid 20th century), most people speak Mandarin as their primary language (although Taiwanese is spoken in abundance), but in the South of the island, Taiwanese is far more common.

The Mandarin in Taiwan is a bit different from the official Beijing Dialect; most notably, Taiwan continues to use traditional Chinese characters, not the simplified versions used on the mainland. Taiwanese Mandarin also tends to not differentiate between the &quot;S&quot; and &quot;Sh&quot; sounds in Mandarin. All people schooled after 1945 are generally fluent in Mandarin, although it is sometimes not the first language of choice. Mandarin is fairly popular with young people. Some in the older generation are not fluent in Mandarin as they were schooled in Japanese or not at all. Universally the Taiwanese are very accepting of foreigners and react with curiosity and admiration for trying the local tongue. Generally, most people in Taiwan converse using a combination of Mandarin and Taiwanese by code-switching.

Especially in Taipei, people generally speak a little English. The children often understand more English than their parents, especially with the emphasis on English language education today. However, attempts to speak Mandarin or Taiwanese will be met with beaming smiles and encouragement, by and large.
 Do Spring Scream . A three day outdoor rock concert in Kenting held on 5, 6&amp;7 April 2007. Tickets NT$1,400 for all days, all venues. NT$650 for one day, one venue. Buddha&apos;s Birthday . Colorful but simple ceremonies are held at Buddhist monasteries that generally consist of washing a statue of the Buddha and a vegetarian feast. It is appropriate to make offerings to the monks and nuns at this time, though it is not mandatory. 24 May 2007. Dragon Boat Festival . A festival to commemorate the death of the Chinese patriotic poet Qu Yuan (born 340 BC), who drowned himself in a river out of despair that his beloved country, Chu, was being plundered by a neighboring country as a result of betrayal by his own people. The festival falls on the 5th day of the 5th lunar month (19 June 2007), and is marked by races of colorful dragon boats at various locations throughout the island. 
 Buy 

The currency of Taiwan is the New Taiwan Dollar (NTD, but also referred to as TWD), known locally as NT, 元 (yuan) or 塊 (kuai).

The exchange rate for US$1 is NT$33.105 (as of 1 Jun 2007). An easy rule of thumb is that NT$100 roughly equals US$3; NT$1000 roughly equals US$30. Taiwan&apos;s smallest denomination, the single dollar coin, is worth about 3 US cents.

One euro equals NT$44.536 (as of 1 Jun 2007). As a rule of thumb, NT$100 roughly equals€2.50; NT$1000 roughly equals€25.

Taiwanese currency is fully convertible and there are no restrictions on taking currency into or out of the island. Currency exchange is possible internationally, although you will get a much better rate if you wait until you arrive at the airport to exchange currency at the 24 hour window. Most banks in Taipei and Kaohsiung will also exchange money or offer cash advances on credit or debit cards. You should bring American currency, and additionally, please be sure to bring newer bills, as the banks and exchange-centers (such as in department stores) will only accept the newer bills. They will not at all accept the old-style small-bust bills, and the department stores will not exchange bills older than 1997. Don&apos;t forget to show your passport!

If you&apos;ve forgotten to bring any money at all, but have your credit or debit card handy, there&apos;s no need to fret. Taiwan&apos;s banking system is light-years ahead of most other countries, with the ability to use any of the abundant 24-hour ATM Machines to withdraw cash from anywhere in the world using the Plus or Cirrus systems. Certain banks&apos; ATMs will even tell you your available balance in your own currency or in NT$. There is a per transaction limit of NT$20,000 for ATM cash withdrawals (HSBC Global Access customers may withdraw NT$30,000 from HSBC ATMs).

Most hotels and department stores accept credit cards, generally Visa and Master Card as well as JCB. Diners Club or American Express cards are seldom accepted. Most restaurants and small stores do not accept cards, and cash is the main form of payment. Because street crime is rare, it is common for people in Taiwan to carry large amounts of cash with them.

Prices in Taiwan are expensive by Asian standards, though still significantly cheaper than Japan. A meal at a street stall may cost NT$50 or less; a meal at a Western fast food restaurant will run you about NT$100; a hotel room at a swanky hotel might cost NT$5000 or more.

 Shopping 
As in many Asian countries, night markets are a staple of Taiwanese entertainment, shopping and eating. Night markets are open-air markets, usually on a street or alleyway, with vendors selling all sorts of wares on every side. Many bargains can be had, and wherever prices are not displayed, haggling is expected. In the larger cities you will have a night market every night and in the same place. In smaller cities, they are only open certain nights of the week, and may move to different streets depending on the day of the week.

Every city has at least one night market; larger cities like Taipei may have a dozen or more. Night markets are crowded, so remember to watch out for your wallet! Shops selling the same items tend to congregate in the same part of the city. If you want to buy something, ask someone to take you to one shop and there will probably be shops selling similar things nearby.

Bargaining is OK and expected in night markets and small stores. Computer chain shops and department stores normally have fixed prices, but at least in department stores you may get a &quot;registered member discount&quot; if you&apos;re shopping a lot. Anyway it&apos;s always worth a try!

When bargaining at small stores, please note that the agreed prices are normally cash prices. If you like to use a credit card, the seller normally wants to add anything up to 5% to the price as a &quot;card fee&quot; etc. The fee consists actually of the credit company&apos;s commission and also the local sales tax/VAT. Even if you pay cash, you normally don&apos;t get an official receipt, as then the seller would have to report&amp;pay their taxes in full (tax evasion is rampant). If you ask for a receipt or &quot;fa piao&quot;, you will get it but you may need to pay 2-5% more.

 What to buy 
Popular things to buy include:
 Jade . Although it can be hard to know for sure if the item you&apos;re buying is real jade or not, some beautiful objects are sold. Most cities have a specific jade market dealing in jade and other precious stones. 
 Computers . Taiwan is a center of computer design and manufacture, so some places sell original equipment manufacturers&apos; (OEM) items at good rates. In particular Taiwanese companies produce laptop computers under license to international companies and then sell the same items under different brands locally, effectively giving the same quality for much lower prices. Desktop computers and components however tend to be the same price in Taiwan as in other areas of the world, though peripherals such as cables and adapters tend to be noticeably cheaper. If you&apos;re buying domestic it&apos;s best to go to tourist hangouts to buy your stuff as you might be saddled with Chinese documentation otherwise. Also, notebooks are typically only available with a Chinese or English keyboard. 

 Note : In order to protect the environment, a government policy rules that plastic bags cannot be given freely at stores in Taiwan, but have to be bought (at a flat rate of NT$1) - bakeries being an exception as the items need to be hygienically wrapped. Re-useable canvas and nylon bags are sold at most supermarkets.

 Eat 
Generally speaking, the foods of Taiwan are derived from mainland Chinese cuisines . It is possible to find Szechuan food, Hunan food, Beifang food, Cantonese food and almost every other Chinese cuisine on the island. Taiwanese renditions of these cuisines tend to be somewhat greasy, though, and completely authentic mainland cuisines are rare. This is especially true for the Cantonese cuisine, as demonstrated by the lack of Cantonese speakers on the island. The Taiwanese are also passionately in-love with eggs and seafood, as you will discover during your stay on the island.

Taiwan also has many of its own local specialties . Perhaps because of its long isolation from mainland China and distance from other parts of the world, most cities and towns in Taiwan are famous for special foods. For example, Ilan is famous for its mochi, a sticky rice snack often flavored with sesame, peanuts or other flavorings. Yonghe, a suburb of Taipei, is famous for its soy milk and breakfast foods. Taichung is famous for its sun cakes, a kind of sweet stuffed pastry. In Jiayi, it&apos;s square cookies, also called cubic pastry, crispy layered cookies cut into squares and sprinkled liberally with sesame seeds. Virtually every city has its famous specialties; many Taiwanese tourists will go visit other cities on the island only to try the local foods, then return home.

Taiwan also has remarkably good bakery items . Among the chain stores, the &apos;We Care&apos; bakeries offer some of the better options, such as whole wheat loaves, sour breads and ciabatta.

All Mahayana Buddhists, which account for the majority of adherents in Taiwan, aspire to be pure vegetarian in deference to the Buddha&apos;s teaching of non-violence and compassion. So, vegetarian restaurants (called su-shr 素食 tsan-ting in Mandarin, and often identified with the 卍 symbol) can be found in abundance all over the island, and they run from cheap buffet style to gourmet and organic. Buffet styled restaurants (called 自助餐, which means &quot;Serve Yourself Restaurant&quot;) are common in almost every neighborhood in large cities, and unlike the &apos;all-you-can-eat&apos; buffets (which charge a set price, usually ranging from NT$250 - NT$350 including dessert and coffee/tea), the cost is estimated by the weight of the food on your plate. Rice (there is usually a choice of brown or white) is charged separately, but soup or cold tea is free and you can refill as many times as you like. NT$90 - NT$120 will buy you a good sized, nutritious meal.

However, if you cannot find a veggie restaurant, don&apos;t fret. Taiwanese people are very flexible and most restaurants will be happy to cook you up something to suit your requirements. The following sentences in Mandarin might be helpful: Wo chr su - I&apos;m vegetarian, Wo bu chr rou - I don&apos;t eat meat. However, as Mandarin is a tonal language, you might need to say both, plus practice your acting skills to get yourself understood. Good luck! NB: If a restaurant refuses your order, don&apos;t push the issue. The reason will not be an unwillingness to accommodate your request, but because the basic ingredients of their dishes may include chicken broth or pork fat.

Although vegetarian restaurants in Taiwan do not aspire to vegan principles, due to the fact that Taiwanese do not have a tradition of eating dairy products, almost all dishes at Chinese style veggie restaurants will actually be vegan.

There are also the standard fast food places such as McDonalds (a standard Big Mac Meal costs NT$115), KFC and MOS Burger. In addition there are large numbers of convenience stores (such as 7-11) that sell things like tea eggs, sandwiches and drinks.

The cheapest food can be found in back-alley noodle shops and night market stalls, where you can get a filling bowl of noodles for around NT$35-70.

As with Chinese cuisine elsewhere, food in Taiwan is generally eaten with chopsticks and served on large plates placed at the center of the table. Unlike in the West, however, a serving spoon might not accompany the dishes, and instead guests will use their own chopsticks to transfer food to their plates. Some people unaccustomed to this way of eating may consider this unhygienic, though it is usually quite safe. However, those who prefer to use a separate utensil for serving have the option of requesting communal chopsticks (公筷 gongkuai ), and can gently encourage friends to use them if they do not automatically do so.

 Drink 

As Taiwan is a subtropical island with the south part in the tropics, it cannot hurt to drink a lot, especially during summertime. Drink vending machines can be found virtually everywhere and are filled with all kinds of juices, tea and coffee drinks, soy milk and mineral water.
 Water 
The general rule in Taiwan regarding drinking water has to be boiled (and preferably filtered). The locals do it, and so should you . If this is not possible, then you should buy bottled water.
 In Taipei , the water board officially declares the water they treat to be safe to drink. However, even if you rely on official guarantees, you can not rely on the piping in every building to be up to the same standard. Unless the building is very new, you should regard tap water as being safe to drink only once it has been boiled for at least 3 minutes. At most MRT stations (the Taipei Underground) you can usually find a drinking fountain to refill a water bottle. The water here is officially guaranteed as safe to drink and should have a recent chemical analysis posted above, for those with extreme interest in water quality. 
 In Kaohsiung , most people do not drink the tap water, even after filtering or boiling, since the water contains trace amounts of arsenic that is detrimental to ones health. The locals obtain potable water using pumps that look like gasoline pumps that are strewn throughout the residential areas. However, according to Taiwan Water, the arsenic concentration of the water in Kaohsiung is about 0.0007mg/L, which is much lower than the maximum limit promulgated by either U.S.or Taiwan EPA, and therefore they claim that quality of tap water in Kaohsiung is compliance with Drinking Water Quality Standards. If in doubt, follow the examples of the locals. However, irrespective of the arsenic problem, because water in Taiwan is generally stored in rooftop tanks, it definitely should be boiled before drinking. 
 In other parts of Taiwan, water is generally safe to drink after boiling. 

 Alcohol 
Traditional alcoholic drinks in Taiwan are very strong. Kaoliang is the most famous alcoholic drink. A distilled grain liquor, it is extremely strong, usually 140 proof or more, and often drunk straight.

Taiwan also produces many types of Shaoxing rice wine, which are considered by many as being some of the best in the world.

Taiwanese people enjoy beer on ice. A wide variety of imported beers are available, but the standard is Taiwan Beer , produced by a former government monopoly. It is brewed with fragrant penglai rice in addition to barley giving it a distinctive flavor.

 Tea and coffee 

Taiwan&apos;s specialty teas are High Mountain Oolong (高山烏龍, Gau-shan wulong ) - a fragrant, light tea, and Tie Guan-yin (鐵觀音) - a dark, rich brew. Enjoying this tea drank in the traditional way using a very small teapot and tiny cups is a experience you should not miss. This way of taking tea is called lao ren cha - &apos;old people&apos;s tea&apos;, and the name is derived from the fact that only the elderly traditionally had the luxury of time to relax and enjoy tea in this way.

 Pearl milk tea (珍珠奶茶 zhēnzhū nǎichá ), aka &quot;bubble tea&quot; or &quot;boba tea&quot;, is milky tea with chewy balls of tapioca added, drunk through an over sized straw. Invented in Taiwan in the early 1980s and a huge Asia-wide craze in the 1990s, it&apos;s not quite as popular as it once was but can still be found at nearly every coffee/tea shop. Look for a shop where it is freshly made.

The cafe culture has hit Taiwan in a big way, and in addition to an abundance of privately owned cafes, all the major chains, such as Starbucks, have a multitude of branches throughout major towns and cities.

 Soft drinks 
Taiwan is a great place for fruit drinks. Small fruit-juice bars make them fresh on the spot and are experts at creating fruit-juice cocktails (non-alcoholic, of course). zong-he - mixed - is usually a sweet and sour combination and mu-gwa niou-nai is iced papaya milk. If you don&apos;t want ice (though it is safe in Taiwan, even at road side vendors) say, chu bing and no sugar - wu tang .

 Soy milk , or doujiang, is a great treat. Try it hot or cold. Savoury soy milk is a traditional Taiwanese breakfast dish. It is somewhat of an acquired taste as vinegar is added to curdle the milk. Both sweet and savory soy milk are often ordered with you-tiao, or deep fried dough crullers.

There are a lot of pseudo health drinks in Taiwanese supermarkets and convenience stores. Look out for asparagus juice and lavender milk tea for example.

 Sleep 
Taiwan doesn&apos;t sleep - just look at the number of 24-hour stores out there. But since you have to....

For the budget-minded, there are hostels in Taipei and most other sizeable cities. Camping is also available in many areas.

 Motels (汽車旅館) can be easily found in suburbs of major cities. Many are intended for romantic trysts, and also offer &quot;rests&quot; (休息) of a few hours in addition to overnight stays (住宿). A single room with attached bathroom will cost you about US$40 to 50 each day.

Taiwanese hotels range in quality from seedy to very luxurious. Due to the complexities of doing business with both mainland China and Taiwan, most Western hotel chains do not operate on Taiwan, the most notable exceptions being Sheraton, Westin and Hyatt. There are still plenty of five-star hotels around, and in fact these are often the only ones that show up on hotel booking sites. Keep in mind, however, that many of the international hotels tend to be outrageously expensive, while comparable and much cheaper accommodation is usually available in the same vicinity. For example, the airport hotel at CKS International charges about three or four times as much as a hotel in Taoyuan which is a half hour cab ride away. Taxi drivers and tourist offices are invaluable resources for finding cheaper hotels

Many hotels in Taiwan have both Chinese and Western names, which can differ radically. Find out and bring along the Chinese name (in Chinese characters), as locals will usually not be able to identify the English ones.
Especially when you visit the regions less traveled by westerners (mostly because there is no business there), don&apos;t be shy to walk in on the more pricey hotels, especially off-season. The Ceasar, the Chateau and the Howard Beach Resort at Kenting, for example, located at one of the nicest beaches of tropical Taiwan, can be of exceptional value if you stay there during wintertime, as the rooms not yet let for the night are offered far below their normal price at last minute.

As in much of Asia, hotel beds in Taiwan are generally much harder than in the West. Only in the most upscale Western style hotels will you find beds any softer than a billiard table.

 Learn 
 Martial arts 
There are many styles of kung fu taught in Taiwan, largely by masters who came here with the Kuomintang in the late 1940&apos;s.

Styles include Ba Gua, Tai Chi, Wing Chun, Praying Mantis, Shway Shiao and various weapons systems. Many of the students are westerners in these classes, which has led to the rise of several NHB Allegra schools, as well as Ju Jitsu and Aikido from Japan.

Some of the more famous teachers will provide you with the paperwork needed to extend a student visa twice.

Taekwondo is also extremely popular and is often a mandatory part of school children&apos;s physical education.

 Work 

The majority of travellers who work in Taiwan pick up temporary jobs teaching English. Jobs teaching other languages (mainly European or Japanese) do exist but have a much smaller proportion of the market.

 Job requirements - in finding employment with a language school, experience, teaching qualifications and references are not required but obviously help. On paper, a big issue is also made about accents, with the North American English accent being heavily favored over British, Australian and South African accents in many language schools&apos; sales marketing. However, in practice, many schools that advertise &apos;American English&apos; and claim that their teachers are all from Canada or the USA, actually employ teachers from anywhere. Age is a factor, with applicants in their 20s seemingly being preferred. More than anything, appearance is probably the major factor in finding employment with most schools - Do you &apos;look Western&apos;? - and reliability and turning up on time for work is then the major factor for keeping your job. Therefore, if you look the part, it is very easy to find a school willing to take you on for at least a few days.

This &apos;look Western&apos; point has quite a bearing. Unfortunately, Taiwan is hardly a great promoter of equal opportunities . In many schools there is a prejudice towards teachers applying for jobs who are of white Caucasian appearance, seen as the typical Western appearance in Asian countries. This is independent of whether or not the teacher has relevant teaching ability and citizenship of one of the permitted ARC countries. Many parents who send their children to schools to be taught English expect the teacher to look like they are from the US, Canada, the UK, Australia, and so on, and so the decision on the part of the school managers is mainly about economics. For those affected by this, it&apos;s a sad fact of Taiwan that is unlikely to change in the near future. Good employers without such prejudiced requirements do exist, but greater perseverance is needed when looking for them.

It is illegal to work without a work permit and an ARC (or Alien Residency Permit), and legal work officially requires a university degree and usually a long (two month+) application process. However, illegal employment is easy to find with many school managers being willing to pay under the table for short durations. Be aware that if caught or reported, you risk criminal charges and could be deported. The government tends to waver from being very lax on this issue under one administration to suddenly taking action under the next; but remember that it only takes one disgruntled student to report you and have you fined and deported. Consider your options carefully!

The rules for getting an ARC do change often and each administrative part of Taiwan has its own ways of handling them, so it is best to check the pages of the website Formosa (see later) and find out what the experiences of others are in your area. Keep in mind, that you can only get an ARC for English teaching if you are a &apos;citizen of a native English speaking country&apos;. Taiwan&apos;s government defines these countries to be only the USA, Canada, the UK, Australia, New Zealand, Ireland and South Africa. Almost all teachers apply for an ARC through their employers only after starting work and it is tied to their ongoing employment with that school. Therefore, if the teacher wishes to leave their employment, they will have to quickly find an alternative employer or lose their ARC and hence be required to leave Taiwan. Also, very few schools will arrange an ARC without at least a year-long contract being signed. Frankly, with all this inflexibility, it&apos;s no wonder so many teachers opt for the non-legal route. That and tax evasion.

A lot of the illegal teaching work that the majority of English teachers partake in is simply through private student tuition with payment being cash-in-hand. You can find a lot of private students around universities that have a Chinese-teaching department - look for the areas where all the foreign students will be and check the noticeboards. Because the majority of adult private students want to practise English conversation, you won&apos;t need to have any Chinese ability. However, it is definitely a selling point and, if you do have Chinese-speaking ability, it&apos;s worthwhile mentioning that in any advertising of your services. Also, once you have some regular students, remember that in Taiwan, as in most Asian countries, &apos;connections&apos; or &apos;guanxi&apos; are very important - if your students like you, they will in all likelihood recommend you to their family and friends.

Teaching English in Taiwan can be lucrative, as the salaries are very high compared to the cost of living, typically ranging between 500 and 650NT per hour before deductions in most language schools, with anything between 500-1000NT per hour being negotiable for private students. In the past few years, the flow of would-be teachers into Taiwan has increased dramatically, resulting in stiffer competition for jobs as well as a general drop in wages and this trend may continue. On top of this, the Taiwanese dollar has been sliding in value over the past five years, meaning you get less and less for your dollar in foreign currency at the end of the month.

Aside from English-teaching, other common kinds of employment available for mainly native English-speaking travellers include such tid-bits as small acting parts for TV and film, voice talent (video games, dubbing tracks, etc), editing and even writing educational materials. Many of these will be advertised on billboards in Chinese language-teaching institutes and universities, where there are likely to be many foreign students.

If after travelling and living there, you find you are serious about working in Taiwan , the most lucrative employment to be had is if you are employed by a multinational company, perhaps in a high-paying country like the UK, US or Australia, and you are sent across to their office in Taiwan. Many foreigners end up doing the same job as their colleagues who were employed in the Taiwan office, but for perhaps 3 or 4 times their pay.

 Stay Safe 
 Crime 
Taiwan is very safe for tourists, even for women at night. This is not to say, however, that there is no crime, and you should always exercise caution. In crowded areas such as night markets or festivals, for example, pickpockets are a known problem. However, it is fair to say that the streets of Taiwan are generally very safe and that violent crime and muggings are very rare.

In addition, it is also very unusual to see drunks on the street, day or night.

Like anywhere else in the world, women should be cautious when taking taxis alone late at night. Although they are generally safe, it&apos;s a good idea to arrange to have a friend call you when you get home and to be seen making the arrangements for this by the cab driver. It also helps if a friend sees you being picked up as taxis have visible license numbers. As an additional safety precaution, tell taxi drivers just the street name and section instead of your exact address.

Police departments in most jurisdictions have a Foreign Affairs Police unit staffed by English speaking officers. When reporting a major crime, it is advisable to contact the Foreign Affairs unit in addition to officers at the local precinct. Police stations are marked with a red light above the door and display a sign with the word &quot;Police&quot; clearly printed in English. For more information see the National Police Agency website .

Foreign victims of a major crime in Taiwan are also advised to report the matter to their government&apos;s representative office in Taipei.

 Natural hazards 
Taiwan often experiences typhoons during the summer months and early fall. Heavy monsoon rainfall also occurs during the summer. Hikers and mountaineers should be sure to consult weather reports before heading into the mountains. A major hazard following heavy rainfall in the mountains is falling rocks caused by the softening of the earth and there are occasional reports of people being killed or injured by these.

Taiwan is also located on the Pacific Ring of Fire, which means that earthquakes are a common occurrence. Most earthquakes are barely noticeable, though the effect may be slightly amplified for those in higher buildings. While the local building codes are extremely strict, general precautions should still be observed during an earthquake, including opening the door for preventing it being jammed, taking cover and checking for gas leaks afterwards.

Taiwan&apos;s wild areas are home to a variety of poisonous snakes , including the bamboo viper, Russel&apos;s viper, banded krait, coral snake, Chinese cobra, Taiwan habu, and the so-called &quot;hundred pacer&quot;. Precautions against snake bites include making plenty of noise as you hike, wearing long trousers and avoiding overgrown trails. Most snakes are scared of humans, so if you make noise you will give them time to get away. The Russel&apos;s viper, one of the most dangerous snakes in Taiwan, is an exception...it generally prefers to take a stand against threats.

 Traffic 
Local drivers have a well-deserved reputation for being somewhat reckless. Many motorcycle riders also have a tendency of zipping through any space no matter how tiny. Be extra careful when crossing the road, even to the extent of looking both ways on a one-way street. When crossing at a pedestrian-crossing at a T-junction or crossroads, be aware that when the little green man lights up and you start crossing, motorists will still try to turn right, with or without a green feeder light.
If you happen to drive a car or a motorcycle, the obvious rule from the traffic is that if someone take a turn on your way in front of you, you should be the one to adapt. Do not expect drivers to yield way, or respect traffic lights in quiet areas, especially in southern Taiwan. Even on roads where traffic is infrequent and the green light is in your favor, bike-riders are still strongly advised to check the opposite lane.

 Emergency Phone Numbers Police : 110 Fire/Ambulance : 119 

 Stay Healthy 
 Westerners should be cautious of relatively undercooked food. Many Taiwanese restaurants offer plates of raw, sliced red meat and uncooked seafood that are brought to the table and either barbecued or simmered in a pot of stock. As this constitutes a staple of the Taiwanese diet, any bacteria that may remain doesn&apos;t affect the locals, but it can wreak havoc with foreigners. The best policy is to make sure you cook the food in a manner to which you are accustomed. Don&apos;t drink tap water without boiling it, though it&apos;s safe for brushing your teeth. Medicines are available for minor ailments at drug stores. You may also find common drugs requiring a prescription in the west (like asthma inhalers and birth control pills) cheaply available from drug stores without a prescription. The quality of the hospitals in Taiwan is excellent and on par with those found in the West. Legal residents with a National Health Card can avail themselves of the very convenient and efficient national health service, which covers treatment and medication using both Western and traditional Chinese medicine. However, this service is not available to short term visitors on tourist visas; nor does it cover major hospitalization expenses. Still, hospital visits and medicine in Taiwan tends to be far less expensive than in the west. For minor ailments and problems (flu, broken bones, stitches, etc) visiting a hospital for treatment should be in the USD $100-$200 range at most. 

 Respect 
 Culture 
Taiwan shares several cultural taboos with other East Asian nations. Do not stick your chopsticks straight up or even sticking into your bowl of rice. This is reminiscent of incense sticks at a temple, and has connotations of wishing death upon those around you. When putting down chopsticks, either place them on the provided porcelain chopstick rest (at fancier restaurants) or rest the chopsticks across the top of your bowl. Some Taiwanese are superstitious about anything connected with dying - unlucky things should never be mentioned. Do not write people&apos;s names in red. This again has connotations of death. When writing someone&apos;s English name, this is not a problem, but avoid writing Chinese names in red. Do not whistle at night. This is an &quot;invitation to ghosts&quot;. Do not point at cemeteries or graves. This is also an &quot;invitation to ghosts&quot;. There are numerous taboos dictating that certain objects shouldn&apos;t be given to others, often because the word for that object sounds like another unfortunate word: * Umbrellas, which in Mandarin sound the same as the word for &quot;break up&quot;. Friends should therefore never give friends umbrellas. Instead, friends will euphemistically &quot;rent&quot; each other umbrellas for a tiny amount (NT$1, for example). * Clocks. The phrase &quot;to give a clock&quot; (&quot;song zhong&quot;), in Mandarin, has the same sound as the word &quot;to perform last rites.&quot; If you do give someone a clock, the recipient may give you a coin in return to dispel the curse. * Shoes. Never ever offer shoes as a gift to old people, as it signifies sending them on their way to heaven. * Knives or sharp objects, as they are made for or could be used to hurt the person. The Taiwanese are certainly not puritanical and enjoy a drink, especially the locally brewed Taiwan Beer and Kaoliang. However, Taiwan does not have a culture of heavy drinking and is rare to see anyone drunk on the streets. While over indulging in alcohol is not a social taboo as such (and some people do so at weddings), it is considered a sign of lack of self-confidence and immaturity, and doing so certainly won&apos;t gain you any respect among Taiwanese friends. You are expected to remove your shoes before entering a house. You will find some slippers to be worn by visitors next to the entrance door. It is likely to be the same ritual for bathrooms and balconies where you will be expected to remove your slippers to wear a pair of plastic sandals (though it is less shocking not to use the sandals by then). In southern Taiwan, and especially in public places, physical contacts of any sorts should be avoided. As you will get along with Taiwanese people, you are very likely to receive small presents of any sorts. This will be drinks, food, little objects... These are a very convenient way to lubricate social relations for Taiwanese people, and are specially commons betweens friends in their 20s. You should reply to any such presents with something similar, but it does not need to be immediate, or specific to the person (i.e. keep it simple). You are not expected to offer anything in return as a teacher (i.e. in a classroom environment) as long as the relationships stays formal. Beware of the sometime overly generous parents who can go as far as offering presents running in the thousands of NT$ and who will then expect you to take special care of their child (understand that their expectations will be considered as fair in Taiwanese culture). You are not expected to tip in hotels and restaurants. 

 Politics 
Taiwanese society is rather polarized by allegiance between supporters of the two major political blocks informally known as &quot;Pan-Blue Coalition&quot; and &quot;Pan-Green Coalition&quot;, although there are large numbers of people who are either centrist or who don&apos;t care. To simplify a complex situation, pan-blue supporters tend to be more favorable toward the idea of (re)unification with China and pan-green supporters tend to be more favorable toward the idea of establishing a formally independent Republic of Taiwan, among other differences.

Although there are some correlations, it is highly unwise to assume anything about a particular persons political beliefs based on what you think you know about their background. Also, the very brief sketch of Taiwanese politics obscures a large amount of complexity.

Unless you know your listener well, it is unwise to say anything (either positive or negative) about the current government, about historical figures in Taiwanese history, about Taiwan&apos;s international relations, or about relations with mainland China. Some figures such as Sun Yat-sen are generally seen positively, but others (Chiang Kai-shek, Lee Teng-hui and Chen Shui-bian in particular) arouse very polarized feelings.

Some people will get very offended if you imply that Taiwan is part of China. Other people will get very offended if you imply that Taiwan is not part of China. Referring to the PRC as &quot;Communist China&quot; or &quot;mainland China&quot; rather than simply China will tend not to offend anyone. Referring to the Republic of China as a whole as &quot;Taiwan Province&quot; will draw a negative reaction from most Taiwanese. &quot;Greater China&quot; may be used in certain business contexts. Keep in mind however, that there are so many subtleties and complexities here that if you are talking about these things, you&apos;ve already wandered into a minefield.

However, simply referring to the island as &apos;Taiwan&apos; is fine, as that is the name used by the locals, regardless of their political persuasion. Titles such as &apos;Republic of China&apos; are reserved for official matters only.

 Contact 

 Getting Online 

Internet cafes are plentiful, although you may have to wander around before finding one. Rather, Internet cafes in Taiwan should be called gaming cafes. Although people do surf the Internet, most people primarly go there for a smooth experience of online gaming. Each hour of Internet access/game play is cheap, coming in at around NT$20. Some machines in the internet cafes are coin operated. For free internet access in big cities, try out the local libraries. In addition, a wireless internet accessing net covering all of Taipei City is available (it was free before May 2006 and is now payable at convenient stores in Taipei City) and Kaohsiung City is currently under construction; it already works in some huge MRT stations and on some special points. You will need some sort of login.

 Telephone 

Mobile phone coverage is relatively good in Taiwan. Among the major providers are Chunghwa Telecom, Taiwan Mobile and Far EasTone. Taiwan has both GSM 900/1800 and 3G networks and roaming might be possible for users of such mobile phones, subject to agreements between operators. Most payphones work with telephone cards (電話卡）which are available at all convenience stores.

 Media 

Taiwan has a very free and liberal press. There are three daily newspapers available in English:
 the China Post , the Taipei Times , Taiwan News 

Other news sources:
 TaipeiNews.net Taiwan Sun Taiwan Headlines Taiwan Journal the Taiwan Economic News Government Information Office&apos;s periodicals RTI (Radio Taiwan International) 

Free magazines:
 Lifestyle - info on Taiwan relating to what&apos;s on and current trends - bilingual. Taiphoon - a magazine dedicated to promoting peace and environmental awareness in Taiwan - bilingual. Journey East - a travel&amp;lifestyle magazine for northern Taiwan - bilingual. Highway 11 - A free english language magazine in Hualien County 

 Cope 
 Foreign Missions 

As the People&apos;s Republic of China (PRC) does not allow other nations to have official diplomatic relations with both itself and the ROC in Taiwan, many of the world&apos;s major nations do not have official embassies or consulates in Taiwan. However, as the PRC allows recognition of Taiwan as a separate economy, in the same way that Hong Kong and Macau are considered separate economies from mainland China, many nations maintain a &quot;Trade Office&quot; or something of similar nature in Taiwan and these usually perform limited consular activities such as issuing visas. For more information, visit the Ministry of Foreign Affairs web-site.

 Get Out 
As Taiwan is mainly surrounded by sea, there are not many places one can go to without flying from Taiwan. One might want to try an overnight ferry from Keelung to Okinawa in Japan. Limited trips might also be available between the island of Quemoy and Xiamen in mainland China.


 Taiwan (; Taiwanese: Tâi-oân) is an island in East Asia. &quot;Taiwan&quot; is also commonly used to refer to the territories administered by the Republic of China (ROC) , which governs the island of Taiwan, Lanyu (Orchid Island) and Green Island in the Pacific off the Taiwan coast, the Pescadores in the Taiwan Strait, and Kinmen and the Matsu Islands off the coast of mainland Fujian. The island groups of Taiwan and Penghu (except the municipalities of Taipei and Kaohsiung) are officially administered as Taiwan Province of the Republic of China.

The main island of Taiwan, also known as Formosa (from the Portuguese Ilha Formosa , meaning &quot;beautiful island&quot;), is located in East Asia off the coast of mainland China, southwest of the main islands of Japan but directly west of the end of Japan&apos;s Ryukyu Islands, and north-northwest of the Philippines. It is bound to the east by the Pacific Ocean, to the south by the South China Sea and the Luzon Strait, to the west by the Taiwan Strait and to the north by the East China Sea. The island is 394 kilometers (245 miles) long and 144 kilometers (89 miles) wide and consists of steep mountains covered by tropical and subtropical vegetation.

 History 

 Prehistory 

Evidence of human settlement in Taiwan dates back thirty thousand years, although the first inhabitants of Taiwan may have been genetically distinct from any groups currently on the island. About four thousand years ago, ancestors of current Taiwanese aborigines settled in Taiwan. These aborigines are genetically related to Malay and Polynesians, and linguists classify their language as Austronesian.

 Early settlement 
Han Chinese began settling in the Pescadores in the 1200s, but Taiwan&apos;s hostile tribes and its lack of the trade resources valued in that era rendered it unattractive to all but &quot;occasional adventurers or fishermen engaging in barter&quot; until the sixteenth century.

Records from ancient China indicate that Han Chinese might have known of the existence of the main island of Taiwan since the Three Kingdoms period (third century, 230 A.D.), having assigned offshore islands in the vicinity names like Greater Liuqiu and Lesser Liuqiu (etymologically, but perhaps not semantically, identical to Ryūkyū in Japanese), though none of these names have been definitively matched to the main island of Taiwan. It has been claimed but not verified that the Ming Dynasty admiral Cheng Ho (Zheng He) visited Taiwan between 1403 and 1424.

 European settlement 

In 1544, a Portuguese ship sighted the main island of Taiwan and dubbed it &quot;Ilha Formosa&quot;, which means &quot;Beautiful Island.&quot; The Portuguese made no attempt to colonize Taiwan.

In 1624, the Dutch established a commercial base on Taiwan and began to import workers from Fujian and Penghu as laborers, many of whom settled.The Dutch made Taiwan a colony with its colonial capital at Tayoan City (present day Anping, Tainan). The Dutch military presence was concentrated at a stronghold called Castle Zeelandia. The Dutch colonists also started to hunt the native Formosan Sika deer ( Cervus nippon taioanus ) that inhabited Taiwan, contributing to the eventual extinction of the subspecies on the island. The name Taiwan derives from Tayoan , meaning &quot;I&quot; in one of the Formosan languages.

 Koxinga and Imperial Chinese rule 
Naval and troop forces of Southern Fujian defeated the Dutch in 1662, subsequently expelling the Dutch government and military from the island. They were led by Koxinga (). Following the fall of the Ming Dynasty, Koxinga retreated to Taiwan as a self-styled Ming loyalist and established the Kingdom of Tungning (1662–83). Koxinga established his capital at Tainan and he and his heirs, Zheng Jing (), who ruled from 1662–82, and Zheng Keshuang (), who served less than a year, continued to launch raids on the south-east coast of mainland China well into the Qing Dynasty, attempting to recover the mainland.

In 1683, following the defeat of Koxinga&apos;s grandson by an armada led by Admiral Shi Lang of Southern Fujian, the Qing Dynasty formally annexed Taiwan, placing it under the jurisdiction of Fujian province. The Qing Dynasty government tried to reduce piracy and vagrancy in the area, issuing a series of edicts to manage immigration and respect aboriginal land rights. Immigrants mostly from Southern Fujian continued to enter Taiwan. The border between taxpaying lands and &quot;savage&quot; lands shifted eastward, with some aborigines &apos;Sinicizing&apos; while others retreated into the mountains. During this time, there were a number of conflicts between Chinese from different regions of Southern Fujian, and between Southern Fujian Chinese and aborigines.

In 1887, the Qing government upgraded Taiwan&apos;s status from prefecture of Fujian to full province, the twentieth in the country, with its capital at Taipei. This was accompanied by a modernization drive that included building Taiwan&apos;s first railroad and starting a postal service.

 Japanese rule 

Imperial Japan had sought to control Taiwan since 1592, when Toyotomi Hideyoshi began extending Japanese influence overseas. In 1609, the Tokugawa Shogunate sent Haruno Arima on an exploratory mission. In 1616, Murayama Toan led an unsuccessful invasion of the island.

In 1871, an Okinawan vessel shipwrecked on the southern tip of Taiwan and the crew of fifty-four were beheaded by the Paiwan aborigines. When Japan sought compensation from Qing China, the court rejected the demand on the grounds that the &quot;wild&quot;/&quot;unsubjugated&quot; aboriginals （) were outside its jurisdiction. This open renunciation of sovereignty led to a Japanese invasion of Taiwan. In 1874, an expeditionary force of three thousand troops was sent to the island. There were about thirty Taiwanese and 543 Japanese casualties (twelve in battle and 531 by endemic diseases).

Qing China was defeated in the First Sino-Japanese War (1894–95), and ceded Taiwan and the Pescadores to Japan in perpetuity in the Treaty of Shimonoseki. Inhabitants wishing to remain Chinese subjects were given a two-year grace period to sell their property and remove to mainland China. Very few Taiwanese saw this as plausible.

On May 25, 1895, a group of pro-Qing high officials proclaimed the Republic of Formosa to resist impending Japanese rule. Japanese forces entered the capital at Tainan and quelled this resistance on October 21, 1895.

The Japanese were instrumental in the industrialization of the island; they extended the railroads and other transportation networks, built an extensive sanitation system and revised the public school system. Still, the ethnic Chinese and Taiwanese aborigines were classified as second- and third-class citizens. Large-scale violence continued in the first decade of rule. Around 1935, the Japanese began an island-wide assimilation project to bind the island more firmly to the Japanese Empire. By 1945, just before Japan lost World War II, desperate plans were put in place to incorporate popular representation of Taiwan into the Japanese Diet to make Taiwan an integral part of Japan proper.

Japan&apos;s rule of Taiwan ended when it lost World War II and signed the Instrument of Surrender of Japan on August 15, 1945.

 Republic of China 

On October 25, 1945, Republic of China troops representing the Allied Command accepted the formal surrender of Japanese military forces in Taihoku. The ROC administration, led by Chiang Kai-shek, announced that date as &quot;Taiwan Restoration Day&quot; (). At first, they were greeted as liberators by the people of Taiwan. However, the ROC military administration on Taiwan under Chen Yi was generally unstable and corrupt; it seized property and set up government monopolies of many industries. These problems, compounded with hyperinflation, unrest due to the Chinese Civil War, and distrust due to political, cultural and linguistic differences between the Taiwanese and the Mainland Chinese, quickly led to the loss of popular support for the new administration. This culminated in a series of severe clashes between the ROC administration and Taiwanese, in turn leading to the bloody 228 incident and the reign of White Terror.

In 1949, on losing the Chinese Civil War to the Communist Party of China (CPC), the Kuomintang (KMT) , led by Chiang Kai-shek, retreated from Mainland China and moved the ROC government to Taipei, Taiwan&apos;s largest city, while continuing to claim sovereignty over all of China and Greater Mongolia. On the mainland, the victorious Communists established the People&apos;s Republic of China, claiming to be the sole representative of China including Taiwan and portraying the ROC government on Taiwan as an illegitimate entity. Some 1.3 million refugees from Mainland China, consisting mainly of soldiers, KMT party members, and most importantly the intellectual and business elites from the mainland, arrived in Taiwan around that time. In addition, as part of its retreat to Taiwan, the KMT brought with them literally the entire gold reserve and foreign currency reserve of mainland China. This unprecedented influx of human and monetary capital laid the foundation for Taiwan&apos;s later dramatic economic development. From this period through the 1980s, Taiwan was governed by a party-state dictatorship, with the KMT as the ruling party. Military rule continued and little to no distinction was made between the government and the party, with public property, government property, and party property being interchangeable. Government workers and party members were indistinguishable, with government workers, such as teachers, required to become KMT members, and party workers paid salaries and promised retirement benefits along the lines of government employees. In addition all other parties were outlawed, and political opponents were persecuted, incarcerated, and executed.

Taiwan remained under martial law and one-party rule, under the name of the &quot;Temporary Provisions Effective During the Period of Communist Rebellion&quot; (), from 1948 to 1987, when Presidents Chiang Ching-kuo and Lee Teng-hui gradually liberalized and democratized the system. With the advent of democratization, the issue of the political status of Taiwan has resurfaced as a controversial issue (previously, discussion of anything other than unification under the ROC was taboo).

During the 1960s and 1970s, the ROC began to develop into a prosperous, industrialized developed country with a strong and dynamic economy, becoming one of the Four Asian Tigers while maintaining the authoritarian, single-party government. Because of the Cold War, most Western nations and the United Nations regarded the ROC as the sole legitimate government of China (while being merely the de-facto government of Taiwan) until the 1970s, when most nations began switching recognition to the PRC.

Chiang Kai-shek&apos;s eventual successor, his son Chiang Ching-kuo, began to liberalize Taiwan&apos;s political system. In 1984, the younger Chiang selected Lee Teng-hui, a native Taiwanese technocrat, to be his vice president. In 1986, the Democratic Progressive Party (DPP) was formed illegally and inaugurated as the first opposition party in Taiwan to counter the KMT. A year later Chiang Ching-kuo lifted martial law.

After the 1988 death of Chiang Ching-Kuo, his successor as President Lee Teng-hui continued to hand more government authority over to the native Taiwanese and democratize the government. Under Lee, Taiwan underwent a process of localization in which local culture and history was promoted over a pan-China viewpoint. Lee&apos;s reforms included printing banknotes from the Central Bank rather than the Provincial Bank of Taiwan, and disbanding the Taiwan Provincial Government. Under Lee, the original members of the Legislative Yuan and National Assembly, elected in 1947 to represent mainland constituencies and having taken the seats without re-election for more than four decades, were forced to resign in 1991. Restrictions on the use of Taiwanese in the broadcast media and in schools were lifted as well.

In the 1990s, the Republic of China transformed into a true democratic state, as President Lee Teng-hui was elected by the first popular vote held in Taiwan during the 1996 Presidential elections. In 2000, Chen Shui-bian of the DPP, was elected as the first non-KMT President and was re-elected to serve his second and last term since 2004. Polarized politics has emerged in Taiwan with the formation of the Pan-Blue Coalition of parties led by the KMT, favoring eventual Chinese reunification, and the Pan-Green Coalition of parties led by the DPP, favoring an eventual and official declaration of Taiwan independence.

 Geography 
The island of Taiwan lies some 120 kilometers off the southeastern coast of mainland China, across the Taiwan Strait, and has an area of 35,801 square kilometers (13,823 square miles). The East China Sea lies to the north, the Philippine Sea to the east, the Luzon Strait directly to the south and the South China Sea to the southwest. The island is characterized by the contrast between the eastern two-thirds, consisting mostly of rugged mountains running in five ranges from the northern to the southern tip of the island, and the flat to gently rolling plains in the west that are also home to most of Taiwan&apos;s population. Taiwan&apos;s highest point is the Yu Shan at 3,952 meters, and there are five other peaks over 3,500 meters. This makes it the world&apos;s seventh-highest island.

The shape of the main island of Taiwan is similar to a sweet potato seen in a south-to-north direction, and therefore, Taiwanese people, especially the Min-nan division, often call themselves &quot;children of the Sweet Potato.&quot; There are also other interpretations of the island shape, one of which is a whale in the ocean (the Pacific Ocean) if viewed in a west-to-east direction, which is a common orientation in ancient maps, plotted either by Western explorers or the Ching Dynasty.

Taiwan&apos;s climate is marine tropical. The Northern part of the island has a rainy season that lasts from January to late March during the southwest monsoon, and also experiences meiyu in May. The entire island succumbs to hot humid weather from June until September, while October to December are arguably the most pleasant times of year. The middle and southern parts of the island do not have an extended monsoon season during the winter months, but can experience several weeks of rain, especially during and after Lunar New Year. Natural hazards such as typhoons and earthquakes are common in the region.

Taiwan is a center of bird endemism; see Endemic birds of Taiwan for further information.

 Environment and pollution 
With its high population density and many factories, some areas in Taiwan suffer from heavy pollution. Most notable are the southern suburbs of Taipei and the western stretch from Tainan to Lin Yuan, south of Kaohsiung. In the past, Taipei suffered from extensive vehicle and factory air pollution, but with mandatory use of unleaded gasoline and the establishment of the Environmental Protection Agency, the air quality of Taiwan has improved dramatically. The motor scooters which are ubiquitous in Taiwan, especially older or cheaper two-stroke versions, also contribute disproportionately to air pollution in Taiwan.

Land and soil pollution has decreased as Taiwanese industry moves out of heavy industry; however, several toxic sites continue to pose challenges. Solid waste disposal has become less of a problem as a nation-wide recycling movement has taken hold, especially with support from Buddhist charity organizations.

Water pollution remains a problematic issue. Nearly 90% of sewage waste in Taiwan is dumped into waterways untreated. Several rivers are so heavily polluted that it would take billions of dollars to clean them.

 Natural resources 
Because of the intensive exploitation throughout Taiwan&apos;s pre-modern and modern history, the island&apos;s mineral resources (eg. coal, gold, marble), as well as wild animal reserves (eg. deer), have been virtually exhausted. Moreover, much of its forestry resources was harvested during Japanese rule for the construction of shrines (using particularly firs) and has only recovered slightly since then. The remaining forests nowadays do not contribute to significant timber production mainly because of concerns about production costs and regulations of environmental protection.

Camphor oil extraction and cane sugar production played an important role in Taiwan&apos;s exportation from the late nineteenth century through the first half of the twentieth century. The importance of the above industries subsequently declined not because of the exhaustion of related natural resources but mainly of the decline of international market demands.

Nowadays, few natural resources with significant economic value are retained in Taiwan, which are essentially agriculture-associated. Domestic agriculture (rice being the dominant kind of crop) and fishery retain importance to a certain degree, but they have been greatly challenged by foreign imports since Taiwan&apos;s accession to the World Trade Organization in 2001. Consequently, upon the decline of subsistent importance, Taiwan&apos;s agriculture now relies heavily on the marketing and exportation of certain kinds of specialty, such as banana, guava, lychee, wax apple, and high-mountain tea.

 Energy resources 

Taiwan has significant coal deposits and some insignificant oil and gas deposits. Electrical power generation is nearly 50% oil-based, less than 10% natural gas, less than 10% nuclear power, and about 35% hydroelectric power, with the remainder from renewable energy sources. Nearly all oil and gas for transportation and power needs must be imported, making Taiwan particularly sensitive to fluctuations in energy prices. Because of this, Taiwan&apos;s Executive Yuan is pushing for 10% of energy generation to come from renewable energy by 2010, double from the current figure of approximately 5%. In fact, several wind-farms built by American and German companies have come online or will in the near future. Taiwan is rich in wind-energy resources, both on-shore and off-shore, though limited land area favors offshore wind resources. Solar energy is also a potential resource to some extent. By promoting renewable energy, Taiwan&apos;s government hopes to also aid the nascent renewable energy manufacturing industry, and develop it into an export market.

 Society 
 Ethnic groups 
The Republic of China&apos;s population was estimated in 2005 at 22.9 million, most of whom are on Taiwan. About 98% of the population is of Han Chinese ethnicity. Of these, 86% are descendants of early Han immigrants known as &quot; native Taiwanese &quot; (). This group contains two subgroups: the Southern Fujianese or &quot;Hokkien&quot; or &quot;Min-nan&quot; (70% of the total population), who migrated from the coastal Southern Fujian (Min-nan) region in the southeast of Mainland China; and the Hakka (15% of the total population), who originally migrated south to Guangdong, its surrounding areas and Taiwan, intermarrying extensively with Taiwanese aborigines. The remaining 12% of Han Chinese are known as Mainlanders () and are composed of and descend from immigrants who arrived after the Second World War. This group also includes those who fled mainland China in 1949 following the Nationalist defeat in the Chinese Civil War. Due to political reasons, more and more young people started to call the mainlanders hsin chu min (新住民), or &quot;new resident.&quot;
A survey in November 2006 conducted by the Taiwanese National Chengchi University, the Japanese University of the Ryukyus and the Chinese University of Hong Kong showed that more than 60% of Taiwan&apos;s population consider themselves Taiwanese, compared to only 18% in 1992.

 Dalu ren () refers to residents of mainland China. This group excludes almost all Taiwanese, including the Mainlanders, except recent immigrants from mainland China, such as those brides made ROC citizens through marriage. It also excludes foreign brides from Vietnam, Indonesia, Thailand and the Philippines or foreign grooms of which a greater number come from Western countries. One in seven marriages now involves a partner from another country. As Taiwan&apos;s birthrate is among the lowest in the world, this contingent is playing an increasingly important role in changing Taiwan&apos;s demographic makeup. Transnational marriages now account for one out of six births.

The other 2% of Taiwan&apos;s population, numbering about 458,000, are listed as the Taiwanese aborigines (), divided into 12 major groups: Ami, Atayal, Paiwan, Bunun, Puyuma, Rukai, Tsou, Saisiyat, Tao (Yami), Thao, Kavalan and Taroko.

 Languages 

About 80% of the people in Taiwan belong to the Hoklo (; Pe̍h-ōe-jī: Hok-ló) ethnic group and speak both Standard Mandarin (officially recognized by the ROC as the National Dialect) and Taiwanese (a variant of the Min Nan dialect spoken in Fujian province). Mandarin is the primary language of instruction in schools; however, most spoken media is split between Mandarin and Taiwanese. The Hakka (), about 15% of the population, have a distinct Hakka dialect. Aboriginal minority groups still speak their native languages, although most also speak Mandarin. English is a common second language, with many large private schools providing English instruction. English also features on several of Taiwan&apos;s education exams.

Although Mandarin is still the language of instruction in schools and dominates television and radio, non-Mandarin dialects have undergone a revival in public life in Taiwan. A large fraction of the populace speak the Taiwanese dialect, a variant of Min Nan spoken in Fujian, China, and a majority understand it. Many also speak Hakka. People educated during the Japanese period of 1900 to 1945 used Japanese as the medium of instruction. Some in the older generations only speak the Japanese they learned at school and the Taiwanese they spoke at home and are unable to communicate with many in the modern generations who only speak Mandarin.

Most aboriginal groups in Taiwan have their own languages which, unlike Taiwanese or Hakka, do not belong to the Chinese language family, but rather to the Austronesian language family.

 Religion 

Over 93% of Taiwanese are adherents of a combination of Buddhism, Confucianism, and Taoism; 4.5% are adherents of Christianity, which includes Protestants, Catholics, Mormons, and other non-denominational Christian groups; and 2.5% are adherents of other religions, such as Islam. Taiwanese aborigines comprise a notable subgroup among professing Christians: &quot;...over 64 percent identify as Christian... Church buildings are the most obvious markers of Aboriginal villages, distinguishing them from Taiwanese or Hakka villages.&quot;

Confucianism is a philosophy that deals with secular moral ethics, and serves as the foundation of both Chinese and Taiwanese culture. The majority of Taiwanese and Chinese usually combine the secular moral teachings of Confucianism with whatever religions they are affiliated with.

One especially important goddess for Taiwanese people is Matsu, who symbolizes the seafaring spirit of Taiwan&apos;s ancestors from Fujian and Guangdong.

 Culture 
The cultures of Taiwan are a hybrid blend of Confucianist Han Chinese cultures, Japanese, European, American, global, local and indigenous influences which are both interlocked and divided between perceptions of tradition and modernity (Harrell/Huang 1994:1-5).

After the retreat to Taiwan, the Nationalists promoted an official interpretation of traditional Chinese culture over the local Taiwanese cultures. The government launched a program promoting Chinese calligraphy, traditional Chinese painting, folk art, and Chinese opera.

Since the Taiwan localization movement of the 1990s, Taiwan&apos;s cultural identity has been allowed greater expression. Identity politics, along with the over one hundred years of political separation from mainland China has led to distinct traditions in many areas, including cuisine, opera, and music.

The status of Taiwanese culture is debated. It is disputed whether Taiwanese culture is part of Chinese culture or a distinct culture. Speaking Hoklo as a symbol of the localization movement has become an emblem of Taiwanese identity.

One of Taiwan&apos;s greatest attractions is the National Palace Museum, which houses more than 650,000 pieces of Chinese bronze, jade, calligraphy, painting and porcelain. The KMT moved this collection from the Forbidden City in Beijing in 1949 when it fled to Taiwan. The collection, estimated to be one-tenth of China&apos;s cultural treasures, is so extensive that only 1% is on display at any time.

Popular sports in Taiwan include basketball and baseball. Cheerleading performances and billiards are quite fashionable. Badminton is also common.

Karaoke, drawn from contemporary Japanese culture, is extremely popular in Taiwan, where it is known as KTV.

Taiwan has a high density of 24-hour convenience stores, which in addition to the usual services, provide services on behalf of financial institutions or government agencies such as collection of parking fees, utility bills, traffic violation fines, and credit card payments.

Taiwanese culture has also influenced other cultures. Bubble tea and milk tea are available in Australia, Europe and North America. Ang Lee has directed critically acclaimed films such as Crouching Tiger Hidden Dragon, Eat Drink Man Woman, Sense and Sensibility and Brokeback Mountain.

 Kaohsiung Taichung Tainan Taipei 

 Further reading Bush, R.&amp;O&apos;Hanlon, M. (2007). A War Like No Other: The Truth About China&apos;s Challenge to America . Wiley. ISBN 0471986771 Bush, R. (2006). Untying the Knot: Making Peace in the Taiwan Strait . Brookings Institution Press. ISBN 0815712901 Carpenter, T. (2006). America&apos;s Coming War with China: A Collision Course over Taiwan . Palgrave Macmillan. ISBN 1403968411 Cole, B. (2006). Taiwan&apos;s Security: History and Prospects . Routledge. ISBN 0415365813 Copper, J. (2006). Playing with Fire: The Looming War with China over Taiwan . Praeger Security International General Interest. ISBN 0275988880 Federation of American Scientists et al. (2006). Chinese Nuclear Forces and U.S. Nuclear War Planning Gill, B. (2007). Rising Star: China&apos;s New Security Diplomacy . Brookings Institution Press. ISBN 0815731469 Shirk, S. (2007). China: Fragile Superpower: How China&apos;s Internal Politics Could Derail Its Peaceful Rise . Oxford University Press. ISBN 0195306090 Tsang, S. (2006). If China Attacks Taiwan: Military Strategy, Politics and Economics . Routledge. ISBN 0415407850 Tucker, N.B. (2005). Dangerous Strait: the U.S.-Taiwan-China Crisis . Columbia University Press. ISBN 0231135645 

 External links 
 Central Weather Bureau - local weather and earthquake reports Satellite view of Taiwan at WikiMapia Statistics of Taiwan 






 
 

 

 

 Introduction: 
In 1895, military defeat forced China to cede Taiwan to Japan. Taiwan reverted to Chinese control after World War II. Following the Communist victory on the mainland in 1949, 2 million Nationalists fled to Taiwan and established a government using the 1946 constitution drawn up for all of China. Over the next five decades, the ruling authorities gradually democratized and incorporated the local population within the governing structure. In 2000, Taiwan underwent its first peaceful transfer of power from the Nationalist to the Democratic Progressive Party. Throughout this period, the island prospered and became one of East Asia&apos;s economic &quot;Tigers.&quot; The dominant political issues continue to be the relationship between Taiwan and China - specifically the question of eventual unification - as well as domestic political and economic reform.

 Location: Eastern Asia, islands bordering the East China Sea, Philippine Sea, South China Sea, and Taiwan Strait, north of the Philippines, off the southeastern coast of China

 Population: 23,036,087 (July 2006 est.)

 Languages: Mandarin Chinese (official), Taiwanese (Min), Hakka dialects

 Country name: conventional long form: none
 conventional short form: Taiwan
 local long form: none
 local short form: T&apos;ai-wan
 former: Formosa

 Capital: name: Taipei
 geographic coordinates: 25 03 N, 121 30 E
 time difference: UTC+8 (13 hours ahead of Washington, DC during Standard Time)

 Economy - overview: 
Taiwan has a dynamic capitalist economy with gradually decreasing guidance of investment and foreign trade by government authorities. In keeping with this trend, some large, government-owned banks and industrial firms are being privatized. Exports have provided the primary impetus for industrialization. The island runs a trade surplus, and foreign reserves are the world&apos;s third largest. Despite restrictions cross-strait links, China has overtaken the US to become Taiwan&apos;s largest export market and, in 2006, its second-largest source of imports after Japan. China is also the island&apos;s number one destination for foreign direct investment. Strong trade performance in 2006 pushed Taiwan&apos;s GDP growth rate above 4%, and unemployment is below 4%. Consumer spending recovered following a slowdown early in 2006, when banks tightened lending to address a sharp increase in delinquent consumer debt.


 
 
 
 

 
 Latest discussion about Asia ▫ Taiwan at forum.scubish.com : 
 
 New Mizuno MP-69 Irons Review Mizuno&apos;s MP series have always won a good reputation among golf lovers. [url=http://www.usgolfwholesale.com/Mizuno-MP-69-Irons-Golf_24.html]mizuno mp 69 irons[/url] are the latest perfect irons to del... 
 maomao12 0 
 

 Titleist 910 D2 Driver steal the show You are looking for distance, accuracy and control of the golf clubs?Just in time. I would like to recommend a latest creation of Titleist-Titleist 910 D2 Driver to you.The [url=http://www.ukgolfdepo... 
 maomao12 0 
 

 Inexpensive Great Ping G15 Irons is on sale As what I have got from Ping I know that with maximum forgiveness technology, Ping Irons provide a variety of design features to lower your scores and help improve your game.Of course , the [url=http... 
 maomao12 0 
 

 Dive report: Kenting, South end of Taiwan From our lodging in Kaohsiung, I popped in a cab at 5:30 am to the
Kaohsiung bus depot and caught a bus (local, big mistake) to Kenting to
try the diving. Prior, I had contacted a local dive guide who... 
 Nobody 0 
 

 Dive report: Kenting, South end of Taiwan From our lodging in Kaohsiung, I popped in a cab at 5:30 am to the
Kaohsiung bus depot and caught a bus (local, big mistake) to Kenting to
try the diving. Prior, I had contacted a local dive guide who... 
 Nobody 0 
 

 Diving in Taiwan Anyone know of any diving in Taiwan? I will be there for several days for
business, and will probably have a few days free. 
 bob 0 
 

 
 
 
 Join Scubish.com Now! 
 
 
 
 
 
 home | destinations | info | buddyfinder | divelog | forum | search | about us | submit a link | contact us 

 ©2010 Scubish.com | All Rights 
 Reserved | Terms and Conditions  | Copyright Notices
	</body>
</document>
