<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000430" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Marietta/El-Ranchero-Mexican-Restaurant_3" time="2012-07-12-15:41" support="2" score="0.0072366859203639835" bingtitle="El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant - Fast Food Restaurant Marietta, GA" webtitle="El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant - Fast Food Restaurant  Marietta, GA">
			<query id="000412" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000163" bing-rank="27"/>
	<description>El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant is a Fast Food restaurant ... They quickly took my order and i was back on the street. ... You will soon begin to receive the newsletters you ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
El Ranchero Mexican
Restaurant

 
Average User Rating
 
10
 
Perfect

 1 Reviews 
 
Sponsored Link


 
(770) 427-5352

 http://www.elrancheromexican.com/ 
 GA &gt; Marietta &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Review Social 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant
 El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant is a Fast Food restaurant located at 562 Cobb Pky Se in Marietta, GA . El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant has been described as an Perfect Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 10 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food, Mexican, Latin American Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant
 
 
 
All Reviews for El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant

 
 Anonymous 
 


March 27, 2009
 
Food
 
10
 
Decor
 
10
 
Service
 
10
 
This place was great! It was just like on the food network. Luckily i was able to go to NYC that summer after seeing the show. The hotdogs were cheap and had a wonderful taste and crispy skin. I got the papaya drink and it was amazing! the combo of the two were fantastic! My only regret was not getting 2+hotdogs and a super size drink!! They quickly took my order and i was back on the street. Highly recommended!
 
Overall Rating
 
10
 
&quot;Perfect&quot;
 
 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   1

 
Comments
 
 
El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant Tips
 The drinks!!!!!!
 
C W. Margaritas are off the chain, chilling with Tammy, Tammy and NuNu.
 
Chris H. Bomb ass drinks
 
Keyuna H. thebomb.com margarittas... and they are super strong.. so be careful when drinking... lol
 
Misha PinksugarAtlanta S. Best outdoor bar on Sundays in Atlanta.. see more hot spots on Pinksugaratlanta.com
 
Misha PinksugarAtlanta S. 
El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant News
 New Ownership Takes Reigns at El Chapin Located at 5010 York Boulevard ... to new ownership. New owner, Glassell Park native and Benjamin Franklin High School graduate Arnie Miller, says El Chapin fans should expect the same Guatemalan and Mexican fare when the restaurant reopens in February ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant - Vista - Vista, CA (760) 941-0749 · 1565 N Santa Fe Ave · &quot;Great Carne asada and seafood.&quot; ... &quot;The owner was very friendly and attentive .&quot; El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant - Winchester, VA (540) 535-1620 · 2197 S Pleasant Valley Rd · &quot;Always reliable. Good food and attentive service.&quot; El Azteca Mexican Restaurant - New York, NY, 10019 - Citysearch (212) 307-0616 · &quot;I don&apos;t even know where to begin. For starters, they gave my friend a dirty fork that ...&quot; · &quot;My fried and I find the food delicious ... El Paso Mexican Restaurant - New York, NY, 10029 - Citysearch (212) 831-3104 · A vast selection of traditional Mexican eats in Harlem. Mexican Restaurants - New York City, Menus, Ratings, Reviews, NYC ... Thanks for subscribing! You will soon begin to receive the newsletters you selected. To enjoy more benefits and personalization available on MenuPages.com, register now! 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 72° 
Fri
 
 70° - 86° 
Sat
 
 73° - 91° 
Sun
 
 72° - 95° 
 
Address
 
El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant

562 Cobb Pky Se

Marietta, GA 
 

 
Telephone
 (770) 427-5352 
El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant
 
 Rating :  10 out of 10 based on 1 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant Photos
 
 Fast Food Mexican Latin American 
 
 Local Places
 
 T K Fast Foods LLC 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food La Parrilla Mexican Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Wendy Templeton Voice Ima 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Huddle House 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Sonic Drive-In 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Subway 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Buffalo Wild Wings 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food China Doll Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Thomas Arvid Fine Arts Incorporated 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Black Sheep Crafts 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Durrett Studio Gallery 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Gwtw Museum Marietta City 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Marietta Aeronautical Museum 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries 
 

See all Marietta Art Museums Galleries 
See all Marietta ATMs 
See all Marietta Bars and Pubs 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant Coupons 

 El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant Marietta 

 El Ranchero Mexican Restaurant Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Marietta Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P Q | R | S | T | U | V | W | X Y | Z 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
