<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000877" url="http://www.insiderpages.com/b/3723311987/bakemans-restaurant-seattle" time="2012-07-12-16:14" support="26" score="0.06848344722007414" bingtitle="Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant - Seattle - Insider Pages - Restaurant ..." webtitle="Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant - Seattle">
			<query id="000733" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000267" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="001048" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="000312" bing-rank="202"/>
			<query id="000608" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="000891" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001165" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000265" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000261" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000977" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000281" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000985" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000108" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000288" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000923" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="001173" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="000276" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000545" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="001480" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000257" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000297" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="001519" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000045" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="001488" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000860" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000279" bing-rank="73"/>
	<description>Cons: Not a place to sit down and soak up the ambience, but who eats in on your lunch ... Let me preface this review by saying that I&apos;ve been to Bakeman&apos;s a number of times.</description>
	<body>
		join sign in 
 Find Near Browse Categories 
recommendations that matter most 
 Health&amp;Medical Home&amp;Garden Hair&amp;Beauty Auto
 Services Pets follow us Advertise With Us 
 Seattle, WA &gt; Food &gt; Restaurants &gt;Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 

 

 

 

 
Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant
 ★★★★☆ 22 Reviews Write a Review 
206-622-3375
 122 Cherry St Seattle , WA 98104 

 
 Add Photo Edit Business Claim Business 
 
About Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant
 Categories 
 Restaurants 
 
Food
 More choices in Seattle: 
 Mamma Melina Ristorante 
4759 Roosevelt Way NE Seattle, WA
 
 Pagliacci Pizza 
426 Broadway E Seattle, WA
 
 Reviews 
 
Insider Pages Reviews for Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant

Have experience with this business? Write a Review. 
 ★★★★★ The best turkey sanwiched 
 Billy S. | Insider Guru
| Rank: 1,444 5 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 
All of the locals know about Bakeman&apos;s...the best turkey sandwich. Get there early, quite the lunch rush. Nothing fancy, but great roasted turkey
 March 19, 2010 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★★★★★ Want Home Cooking? 
 Carmen C. | Insider
| Rank: 24,166 5 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 
Then try Bakeman&apos;s down by the courthouse. Hidden away in a basement, it&apos;s Seattle&apos;s most well known secret. Cafeteria style serving, it&apos;s all turkey all the time and just awesome. You can have a turkey and trimmings meal or just a sandwich. They only take cash, so be prepared and go early as they fill up fast!
 April 29, 2008 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 
Latest reviews from Citysearch .
 ★★★★☆ Go for the &quot;experience&quot;, stay for the freshly roasted turkey 
by Lisa Kennelly at Citysearch 4 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 April 08, 2010 
Get in the fast-moving line, quickly scan the dry-erase board for the menu and then place your order before the no-nonsense server chopping up freshly roasted turkey can snap her fingers at you. By your second visit to Bakeman&apos;s you&apos;ll be a pro.

The best sandwiches here are definitely the turkey: white or dark or both, cranberry and mayo and lettuce at your request. Other diner classics like meatloaf and egg salad don&apos;t disappoint. Neither do the 4 or 5 selections of soups and pies, or the daily specials like pot roast or beef stroganoff.

Yes, the lighting is fluorescent, the floor is nondescript tile, they only take cash and the owner will likely give you a hard time as he rings up your meal. But the &quot;Soup Nazi&quot; gimmick belies a friendly heart. Play along, tip him a dollar and he&apos;ll throw in a free chunk of cornbread with a wink.

Pros: Cheap and filling sandwiches, soups and pies

Cons: Snarky service (but part of the fun), low-rent setting


 ★☆☆☆☆ Better Places Than This 
by NeoPDX at Citysearch 1 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 December 15, 2009 
Cold and dry turkey on dried out bread... this was the worst! I would not eat here again.

Stop by Huber&apos;s or Downtown Freddy Brown&apos;s in Portland, Oregon for turkey done right - fresh, hot and juicy, served opened face with gravy and mashed potatoes. You&apos;ll come back for more!

Pros: ?

Cons: Many


 ★★★★★ Great food beats the sometimes mediocre service 
by Jupiter45 at Citysearch 5 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 June 20, 2008 
This place is the place to have lunch in downtown.
Salmon Friday is a day to look forward to on a weekly basis. The daily specials are good, the turkey sandwich are always good.
The owner can be a pain... but you either love him or not
However good food beats the attitude!

Pros: Great price, huge serving

Cons: Long lines, cash only


 ★★★★☆ Catering 
by ColleenBrowne at Citysearch 4 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 June 09, 2008 
Jason always comes through--even in a pinch--with good food, more than reasonably priced, more food than most &quot;per person&quot; caterers. I think he&apos;s a complete gem as is his staff. He may seem &quot;crabby&quot; to some, but it&apos;s just the soul of the place shining through.

Pros: Ready when you want, what you want

Cons: He&apos;s crabby--get over it


 ★★★★★ A Hidden Seattle Landmark 
by Mac206 at Citysearch 5 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 April 22, 2008 
My mom has been going to Bakeman&apos;s since the 70s. When she is back in town we always go to there and Jason at the register still recognizes her. Bakeman&apos;s is a classic Seattle restaurant. It seems like most people I know have never heard about it. Yet every time I go in it&apos;s packed. Its not the kind of place where you should expect to get royal treatment but that should be obvious when you walk in to the cafeteria-like setting. Bakeman&apos;s is fast efficient and they make the best damn turkey sandwich this side of Thanksgiving. Where else are you going to find a sandwich made on fresh homemade bread with real roasted turkey that was cooked that day for only 4 dollars? I know they have other sandwiches but I have yet to get past the turkey, its just too good. They are only open on weekdays for lunch and they only take cash. I think some people can be put off by the abrupt service. But keep in mind the place I always really busy and it&apos;s faster for everyone when you know what you want and keep the line moving. If you get yelled at just roll with it and be nice, half the time they a just messing with you. Go there get a turkey sandwich and tell your friends. Trust me you won&apos;t regret it.

Pros: Best Turkey Sandwich Ever! Cheap and Fast.

Cons: Don&apos;t take credit cards, cash only.


 ★☆☆☆☆ keep walking 
by hicktastic at Citysearch 1 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 September 13, 2007 
Mediocre food. The tomato basil soup tasted like a came out of a can and while I was impressed that they used real, whole-roasted turkey meat for their sandwiches, the wonder bread and cheap toppings made me pass and have a salad instead. The lettuce was brown on the edges by the way. The guy at the cash register was extremely rude to his customers which I didn&apos;t get -- it&apos;s possible to run an efficient line and be nice to your patrons at the same time. Tat&apos;s (Pioneer Square) proves it. Next time I feel like a cheap sandwich and quick turn-around I&apos;ll walk down to McDonald&apos;s. At least they&apos;re nicer.


 ★☆☆☆☆ a joke 
by soupcanharry at Citysearch 1 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 September 13, 2007 
Are you kidding me. anyone who would spend money at this place should have there head looked at. The food is half rate at best, looks like Carl Budding meat! If the owner thinks his attitude is cute then he should meet me in the alley after he gets off work, soup nazzzi wanna be ! This place is HORRIBLE and should be avoid solely to show this guy that if your going run a business you should at least be decent to people.


 ★★★★★ Y&apos;all keep eating at McDonald&apos;s if you don&apos;t like this place 
by shaniqua_w at Citysearch 5 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 August 30, 2007 
Getting fat and sick from eating McDonald&apos;s food aint no way to go through life. So what if Jason Wang (the cashier )is abrupt and efficient. Deal with it, y&apos;all.

Try the excellent turkey sandwich....try the soup.....have a brownie...enjoy life!

Pros: Good food, cashier keeps it real

Cons: Not open late enough and closed on weekends


 ★★★☆☆ &quot;C-MON, I DONT HAVE TIME!!!&quot; 
by mmmmmmgood at Citysearch 3 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 July 09, 2007 
Pretty good food. Good Price. But watch out!
....Know what you want ahead of time, and have your money ready to pay
......or else be prepared to get yealled at!!..... &quot;&quot;C-MON! C-MON! C-MON! I DONT HAVE TIME!!!!!!!&quot;&quot;

Pros: Good food. Cheap eats

Cons: Just Order, and Pay ....DONT do anything else, and you&apos;ll live


 ★★☆☆☆ Good cheap eats, with bad tasteless service. 
by btheg at Citysearch 2 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 May 20, 2007 
The food is average, BUT for the price you could say it&apos;s good. I have been there 4-5 times. I would go there more often but the owner is very rude, so I stay away. Every 5-6 months I go back, and try it again ...and Every Time, the owner has been rude. I don&apos;t think I will go back again. Neither the food nor the price, is good enough to deal with the owners poor attitude

Pros: Price is good

Cons: The Owner is openly rude to customers


 ★★☆☆☆ Good food Bad Aditude 
by btheg at Citysearch 2 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 May 20, 2007 
The food is average, BUT for the price you could say it&apos;s good.
I have been there 4-5 times. I would go there more often but the owner is very rude, so I stay away.
Every 5-6 months I go back, and try it again ...and Every Time, the owner has been rude. I don&apos;t think I will go back again. Neither the food nor the price, is good enough to deal with the owners poor attitude


 ★★★☆☆ HORRIBLE Service - not recommended 
by sandygal at Citysearch 3 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 April 24, 2007 
Yes, Bakeman has reasonably good sandwiches. HOWEVER, every single time I&apos;ve ordered lunches with Bakeman&apos;s the owner of the shop has been exceptionally rude, and today was the worst treatment I&apos;ve ever received by any restaurant. My boss happens to like their sandwiches, and likes them for his lunch meetings. I just emailed him today, requesting that we never use them again.

Typically I fax in the lunch order, and then call shortly afterwards to confirm it, and get chewed out by the owner that he doesn&apos;t have time to deal with calls like that and he&apos;s busy. Today I opted not to call in to confirm the order (and avoid getting yelled at) and when I arrived, they claimed not to have gotten the order, even though I brought in the confirmation and written order. The owner chewed me out for not calling and accused me multiple times of faxing it elsewhere or not sending it correctly. He started yelling in front of everyone that he didn&apos;t have time for this kind of stuff, and didn&apos;t want to fill the order. I insisted, and he fumed and complained and fortunately the food preparers started in. The food preparers started shoving sandwiches at me, and I asked for them to bag it up according to the order. The owner refused, and I had to insist again. I finally ended up at the cash register with half bagged food and lots of miscellaneous items that I insisted he bag for me. He chewed me out the whole time he was throwing things in the bags. He then refused to ring everything up and said he didn&apos;t have time, so he would just charge me $8 a bag (it should have been less than $7 a bag). I asked for a box and he dropped one on top of all the food bags and let me box everything up myself as he tried to start ringing up other customers around me.

It would be one thing if this was some weird occurence, but I get treated this way every time I go there. I&apos;ve even witnessed the owner &apos;train&apos; a new employee (aka yell at her and micromanage her in front of customers).

Cons: The customer service will leave a bad taste in your mouth, no matter how good the food is.


 ★★★★★ Amazing flavor and value 
by emily9802 at Citysearch 5 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 October 05, 2006 
This place is a gem! For $3.83 with tax, I got a half turkey sandwich (stuffed with an insane amount of turkey) and a ginormous hunk of still-warm sweet cornbread. Don&apos;t bother reaching for the chips at the beginning of the counter - wait until the cash register, where said cornbread resides in a basket. If we didn&apos;t have dessert waiting back at the office, I would have gladly jumped on the offer of carrot cake for a buck. The line moved fast - use the line time to study the simple menu and then you won&apos;t get flummoxed when it&apos;s time to tell them what you want. Fortunately, you mostly tell them if you want add-ons - you don&apos;t have to list the things you don&apos;t want. To the person who griped about them being rude, on what planet would soup come with a full sandwich that costs $3, esp. when the soup prices were clearly posted? The guy at the cash register was just teasing you - lighten up.

Pros: Great food, great prices, in and out quickly

Cons: Not a place to sit down and soak up the ambience, but who eats in on your lunch break?


 ★★★★★ Best REAL Turkey Sandwich 
by seattle_gourmand at Citysearch 5 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 September 20, 2006 
If you are looking for a great turkey sandwich, with real white or dark meat, not the paper thin sliced turkey, go to Bakeman&apos;s. Either eat there in a non-descript atmosphere, or if it is a nice day, take it to a nearby park bench. They will get you in and out quickly and your sandwhich tab will be under $4. Bakeman&apos;s has a great reputation because they provide a honest to good sandwich at a reasonable price. (Also, where can you get a slice of cake for $1?)

Pros: Quality Food; Fast in and out

Cons: Ambience but Ok for they type of restaurant it is


 ★★★★★ Great homemade food from Seattle&apos;s own Soup Nazi 
by jim98122x at Citysearch 5 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 May 31, 2006 
It&apos;s true, you&apos;d better know what you want when you get to the front of the line. They&apos;ll needle you if you don&apos;t, but it&apos;s all in fun. (timid Seattleites can be so easily injured...lighten up!) Most of the crowd here are regulars and with one taste you&apos;ll know why. The turkey sandwhiches are legendary and the soups are equally awesome. I don&apos;t work downtown anymore, and ate there recently after a gap of several years. It hasn&apos;t changed a bit-- even the prices are practically unchanged! I almost had to hold back a tear. Try it, you&apos;ll love it, no matter what you get. Don&apos;t expect to be coddled, but you&apos;ll leave stuffed and happy!

Pros: great homemade food, cheap prices, daily fresh turkey

Cons: long lines, blunt servers


 ★☆☆☆☆ Rude Service Leads to Walkout 
by raimundo at Citysearch 1 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 November 30, 2005 
Let me preface this review by saying that I&apos;ve been to Bakeman&apos;s a number of times. In this most recent occasion, I even dragged two co-workers with me. You don&apos;t expect red carpet treatment at a sandwich shop like this but the rude service I received this last time was totally inappropriate. When I asked if the soup comes with the sandwich before checkout, I was told by one of the servers that it was, but when they went to charge extra for the soup, I was confused. Then the checkout person told me &quot;Why would you ask that? That is such a stupid question.&quot; I was floored that a place of business would say something like that to its customer, so I just walked out. I never am going back here and recommend you save yourselves from this place&apos;s rude service.

Pros: dirt cheap sandwiches

Cons: rude service


 ★★★★☆ a really good lunch place 
by tootietuttle at Citysearch 4 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 February 10, 2005 
Just eat a turkey sandwich with cranberry with a piece of apple pie for dessert. You can thank me later.

Pros: price, food quality

Cons: crowded


 ★★★★★ Off the Beaten Path 
by markbalbrecht at Citysearch 5 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 June 28, 2004 
Hard to find under the former Seafirst Bank Building, but has the best fresh turkey sandwich and turkey soup in town. Have your order ready before your turn at the counter and skip eating at the restaurant --try UPS park a few blocks away.

Pros: great food, great value


 ★★★★★ My kind of Fast Food! 
by gorm at Citysearch 5 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 January 07, 2003 
Small, and almost invisible from street level, this place meets my definition of &quot;hidden treasure&quot;. But, you MIGHT think you have found the back entrance to somebody&apos;s company lunchroom when you enter this eating establishment. The difference is, this one serves outstanding food: rich, thick soups, terrific sandwiches, and what looked to be a wide variety of desserts,The emphasis here is on fresh ingredients. Try the turkey noodle soup (served daily) or any of a variety of other soups, which change daily. I had a meatloaf sandwich and a turkey sandwich, and a bowl of turkey noodle soup. The meatloaf sandwich was good, but I was REALLY impressed by the turkey sandwich was made with fresh, real turkey breast meat. Don&apos;t miss it unless you&apos;re allergic or something.

Pros: food, service

Cons: parking, non-ADA, lunchtime seating


 ★★★★★ The real thing 
by PG at Citysearch 5 Bakeman&apos;s Restaurant 
 August 27, 2002 
There&apos;s a reason that they&apos;re lined up 25 people deep and the ones by the front door will brave a December chill. Bakeman&apos;s serves em up FAST and fresh. Real roasted turkey on HOMEMADE bread with lettuce tomato and cranberry is $3.50 and you can have it in a bag with Jason&apos;s smiling service and ready-made change in less than 10 minutes - no matter how long the line. Same goes for the tuna, chicken pot pie special or meatloaf sands. Where do you find a meatloaf sandwich in Seattle? Ok it ain&apos;t tofu city and you better know what you want or you go to the back of the line. But if you&apos;re a working stiff in downtown you can&apos;t beat the food, price or speed. AND they were on NPR. Nuf said.

Pros: Cheap, good quality, Fast

Cons: It&apos;s not tofu city, You better not dawdle


 Write a Review Get Map&amp;Directions 
Modify or Try Another Search For:
 
Restaurants - Seattle, WA
 Find Near Home | About Us | FAQ | Blog | Help/Contact Us | Feedback | Store Finder | Doctor Finder | Sitemap | Privacy Policy (updated) | Terms &amp; Conditions ©2004–2012 Insider Pages. All rights reserved. Partner Sites: MyAutismTeam | Ask Answers | Ask Kids | Life123 | Citysearch | MerchantCircle | Urbanspoon
	</body>
</document>
