<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000862" url="http://www.hotfrog.com/Products/Hawaiian-Bbq" time="2012-07-12-16:13" support="1" score="0.001474107689608874" bingtitle="Hawaiian Bbq - Hotfrog - Your Business Directory" webtitle="Hawaiian Bbq">
			<query id="000729" bing-rank="214"/>
	<description>CK Hawaiian BBQ Barbeque Grill Fast Food Restaurant Boise ... retains the interest of an increasing number of ... Eat in, take away, party tray and catering are all welcomed</description>
	<body>
		Login 
 
 
 What are you looking for? Where are you looking? Search 

 You may have forgotten a search term 
 Add your business 
 
Hawaiian Bbq
 1 - 40 of 140 businesses results Hawaiian BBQ Festival 
Long Beach, CA
 (562) 426-3000 
 Hawaiian BBQ Festival Restaurant - Long Beach , Orange County, Los Angeles, CA - Order Hawaiian BBQ Online for Delivery Takeout Catering Pickup Take out using GimmeGrub
 
 Hawaiian Food 
 Da Kines Plate Lunches 
Santee, CA
 619 581 5613 
Our catering services deliver over 400 functions a year throughout San Diego, Orange, and Riverside counties
 
 Restaurants Hawaiian Hawaiian Food Ethnic Food Restarants Hawaiian Cuisine 
 Big Island Hawaiian Bbq 
Spring, TX
 562 961 7300 
Big Island Hawaiian BBQ - Long Beach Restaurant - Long Beach , Orange County, Los Angeles, CA - Order Hawaiian BBQ Online for Delivery Takeout Catering Pickup Take out using GimmeGrub
 
 
 C K Hawaiian Bbq 
Boise, ID
 (208) 376 4380 
CK Hawaiian BBQ Barbeque Grill Fast Food Restaurant Boise Idaho USA - Teriyaki BBQ, Seafoods, Chicken, Beef, Shortribs, Pork, Salads, Burgers - Asian Hawaiian Chinese Korean Japanese American Cuisines
 
 
 Cousin Cafe 
Pleasanton, CA
 (925)460 5268 
Offers HK-style cafe cuisine and delicious chinese cuisine. Eat in, take away, party tray and catering are all welcomed
 
 
 Ono Hawaiian Bbq 
Scottsdale, AZ
 101) (408)779 2688 
Ono Hawaiian BBQ is dedicated to bringing you the best Hawaiian dining experience by serving a delicious selection of &quot;plate lunch&quot; foods and American cuisine, with exceptional service in a beautiful and comfortabl…
 
 Plate Lunch 
 Aiea Grill 
Beaverton, OR
 503 617 1440 
Teriyaki and BBQ Grill. High quality, reasonably priced plates for dine-in or take-out. Catering for large groups also our speciality. Fresh deals on Teriyaki Bowls
 
 Hawaiian Food Macaroni Salad Plate Lunch 
 Big Island Barbecue 

 360 281 3014 
Big Island Barbecue has been providing the Greater Portland, OR and Vancouver, WA areas with our unique Hawaiian BBQ flavor since 1993. We provide catering services for small parties, picnics, weddings, and even large e…
 
 
 Kilohana Grill 

 925 830 1144 
Authentic Hawaiian BBQ . We serve Hawaiian style plate lunches in San Ramon, CA. Come try our BBQ Chicken, BBQ Beef or Loco Moco served with two scoops of rice and our house special potato salad. We also serve Saimin, SP…
 
 Hawaiian Food Saimin 
 Waikikie 
Atlanta, GA
 404 638 1115 
Waikikie is introducing Hawaiian Local Foods to the Atlanta area at reasonable prices, in the Ohana spirit, which means the importance of family and friends
 
 Hawaiian Food 
   Island Style Cafe 
San Diego, CA
 (858) 541 7002 
Island Style Cafe located in beautiful San Diego is a great Hawaii family owned and operated restaurant offering our best Hawaiian BBQ and breakfast recipes! Island Style Cafe is where to go for the best island comfort…
 
 
 Wasabi Oriental Buffet 
Williamsburg, virginia
 757 645 3988 
The WASABI Oriental Buffet retains the interest of an increasing number of loyal and satisfied customers We want to be Williamsburg&apos;s best Chinese cuisine Authenic Mongolian Grill and Hawaiian BBQ Come no…
 
 
 Grandfather&apos;s Salt 
HONOLULU, HI
 (808) 222 7350 
Grandfather&apos;s Hawaiian Salt - Pride of the Islands Above and beyond your average sea salt, this is the masterpiece of renowned Waikiki chef Joseph Lau, known to friends and family as Grandfather. A classic blend of the…
 
 Hawaiian Cuisine 
 Luau-party 

 800 871 0054 
We offer authentic luau entertainment and hawaiian props for hawaiian weddings, graduations and birthdays. Our hawiian menu and luau catering has the best hawaiian barbecue, poi and kalua pig in Southern California
 
 Hawaiian Food 
 Hula Mamas 

 (281) 710 7110 
Hawaiian and Southern food restaurant in Houston. Luau catering services and crawfish in season, plan your Houston luau party with Hula Mamas
 
 Hawaiian Food 
 Alisi&apos;s Hawaii 
Humble, TX
 281 710 7110 
Hawaiian and Southern food restaurant in Houston. Luau catering services and crawfish in season, plan your Houston luau party with Hula Mamas
 
 Hawaiian Food 
 Polynesian Weddings 

 800 871 0054 
Polynesian Weddings events annually from intimate sit down dinners to Wedding Hawaiian Wedding, Wedding Planning Services, Wedding Planners, Wedding Coordinators, Wedding Companies, Polynesian Weddings for thousand…
 
 
 Ono Ono Hawaiian Barbecue&amp;Veggies 
tustin, ca
 714 505 0650 
If you are ooking for great Hawaiian food in Orange County, check out Ono Ono Hawaiian Barbecue located in Tustin on Seventeenth Street, just east of the 55 freeway
 
 Hawaiian Food 
 Lucky Kitchen 
Ann Arbor, MI
 (734) 747 9968 
Lucky Kitchen Chinese Restaurant, Ann Arbor, MI - LKfit meals, takeout, delivery or dine-in of healthy, economical Asian food
 
 
 Cousin Cafe 
Newark, CA
 (510)713 9806 
Offers HK-style cafe cuisine and delicious chinese cuisine. Eat in, take away, party tray and catering are all welcomed
 
 
 Ck Hawaiian Bbq 

 208 376 4380 
CK Hawaiian BBQ Barbeque Grill Fast Food Restaurant Boise Idaho USA - Teriyaki BBQ, Seafoods, Chicken, Beef, Shortribs, Pork, Salads, Burgers - Asian Hawaiian Chinese Korean Japanese American Cuisines
 
 
 North Shore Hawaiian Bbq 
Rosemead, CA
 (626) 573 9255 
North Shore is a fresh take on Hawaiian BBQ located in Rosemead, California. Family-owned and -operated, we serve delicious dishes every day from 10:30am to 10pm
 
 Hawaiian Food 
 Hawaiian Bbq 
, CA
 (626) 579 2682 
Visit Hawaiian BBQ In El Monte California Serving Varieties Of Foods website - view company details, print free Hawaiian BBQ In El Monte California Serving Varieties Of Foods coupons online and find the best This Blog I…
 
 
 Ono Hawaiian Bbq-fontana 
Fontana, CA
 9098032988 
Ono Hawaiian BBQ is dedicated to bringing you the best Hawaiian dining experience by serving a delicious selection of “plate lunch” foods and Island cuisine, with exceptional service in a comfortable atmosphere. “Ono” m…
 
 Plate Lunch 
 Ono Hawaiian Bbq Sf 
San Francisco, CA
 4156816388 
Ono Hawaiian BBQ is dedicated to bringing you the best Hawaiian dining experience by serving a delicious selection of “plate lunch” foods and Island cuisine, with exceptional service in a comfortable atmosphere. “Ono” m…
 
 Plate Lunch 
 Manteca Airport Restaurants 
Manteca, CA
 2092399388 
Ono Hawaiian BBQ is dedicated to bringing you the best Hawaiian dining experience by serving a delicious selection of “plate lunch” foods and Island cuisine, with exceptional service in a comfortable atmosphere. “Ono” m…
 
 Plate Lunch 
 Ono Hawaiian Bbq-hayward 
Hayward, CA
 5103243688 
Ono Hawaiian BBQ is dedicated to bringing you the best Hawaiian dining experience by serving a delicious selection of “plate lunch” foods and Island cuisine, with exceptional service in a comfortable atmosphere. “Ono” m…
 
 Plate Lunch 
 Ono Hawaiian Bbq-stockton 
Stockton, CA
 2094749888 
Ono Hawaiian BBQ is dedicated to bringing you the best Hawaiian dining experience by serving a delicious selection of “plate lunch” foods and Island cuisine, with exceptional service in a comfortable atmosphere. “Ono” m…
 
 Plate Lunch 
 Ono Hawaii Bbq-upland 
Upland, CA
 9096087828 
Ono Hawaiian BBQ is dedicated to bringing you the best Hawaiian dining experience by serving a delicious selection of “plate lunch” foods and Island cuisine, with exceptional service in a comfortable atmosphere. “Ono” m…
 
 Plate Lunch 
 Ono Hawaii Bbq 
San Pedro, CA
 3105471888 
Ono Hawaiian BBQ is dedicated to bringing you the best Hawaiian dining experience by serving a delicious selection of “plate lunch” foods and Island cuisine, with exceptional service in a comfortable atmosphere. “Ono” m…
 
 Plate Lunch 
 Aloha Hawaiian BBQ 
Salinas, CA
 8317588028 
Welcome to Aloha Hawaiian BBQ in Salinas Aloha Hawaiian BBQ is committed to serving large and delicious plate lunches and the best Hawaiian BBQ dishes for a very low price We are proud to be Monterey Coun…
 
 
 Pearl Cafe 
Florissant, MO
 3148313701 
It&apos;s easy to customize your drink at Pearl Cafe Enjoy delicious choices such as Hawaiian BBQ Chicken, Hawaiian BBQ Beef Short Ribs as well as our Kalua Pork Lau Lau Combo and Loco Mocos
 
 
 L&amp;L Hawaiian Barbecue 
Vacaville, CA
 7074558881 
To understand the L&amp;L;Hawaiian Barbecue® concept, one must look back to the history of the food that L&amp;L;has branded as Hawaiian Barbecue– the Hawaiian plate lunch Anticipating the unfamiliarity of the plate l…
 
 Plate Lunch 
 Redwood Acres Recycling Center 
Eureka, CA
 7074448681 
TO ALL OF OUR SPONSORS **We are now accepting Vendor and Concessionaire Applications for the 2011 fair
 
 
 Pearls Kitchen 
Pasadena, CA
 (877) 749 0963 
Visit Pearls Kitchen Pasadena website - view company details, print free Pearls Kitchen coupons online and find the best Hawaiian BBQ and Chinese Food in Pasadena, CA in Pasadena in no time
 
 
 Eastcoastluaus 

 800 871 0054 
When it comes to east coast luaus, we are considered the best catering provider. We are the original and the definitely the best luau catering and events planning company in California. We can seriously pimp your luau b…
 
 Hawaiian Food 
 L&amp;L Hawaiian Bbq 
West Covina, CA
 626 732 2221 
L&amp;L;Hawaiian Barbecue Gift Certificate The OFFICIAL L&amp;L;Hawaiian Barbecue® logo polo shirt Celebrate Christmas with our limited edition &quot;Christmas Mele&quot; Hawaiian Christmas music CD
 
 Christmas Music Hawaiian Christmas Barbecue Gift Christmas Music Cd 
 Hawaiianhamburgers 

 800 871 0054 
Luau Catering / Luau Barbecue / Hawaiian BBQ / San Diego Hawaiian Food / Orange County Caterer / Los Angeles BBQ
 
 Hawaiian Food 
 Kalua-pig 

 800 871 0054 
If you are looking for something different, you have to tryu our hawaiian catering services. We are the original and the best when it comes to hawaiian fusion cuisine. We have been providing our clients with the best ha…
 
 Hawaiian Food 
 Kaluaporkcabbage 

 800 871 0054 
Looking for something different to serve to your guests? You can try our hawaiian fusion cuisine. Aside from our famous hawaiian barbecues, we also have several hawaiian inspired dishes. This included our best selling k…
 
 Hawaiian Food 
 First page Prev 10 pages   1 2 3 4 Last page Next 10 pages 
Businesses (140) 
 Related keywords 
 Restaurants Eating Places Plate Lunch Restaurant Full-Service Restaurants Restaurants Hawaiian Christmas Music Catering Logo Hawaiian Christmas 
 Hawaiian Bbq by state 
 CA TX OR HI MI NV GA UT WA 
 Hawaiian Bbq by city 
 Long Beach, CA San Diego, CA Thousand Oaks, CA Salinas, CA Tustin, CA Eureka, CA Atlanta, GA Honolulu, HI Ann Arbor, MI Las Vegas, NV 
 Businesses that regularly add new information and match your search 
Most active

 This week All time 
 
No results available
 
 Hawaiian BBQ Festival 

 Da Kines Plate Lunches 

 
 Business profiles just added to Hotfrog that match your search 
Just added
 
 Hawaiian BBQ Festival 08/22/2009 Da Kines Plate Lunches 03/14/2009 
 Most viewed businesses matching your search inquiry 
Most popular
 
 Hawaiian BBQ Festival 
 
 Small Business Hub 
 
Sharing tips, ideas and advice to help grow your small business
 View the Small Business Hub 
 Hotfrog AdVantage 
 
Hotfrog AdVantage ads appear above the rest in Hotfrog feature pages. By upgrading today your ad will appear in front of potential customers before they notice your competitors.
 Find out more 
 What are you looking for? Where are you looking? Search 

 You may have forgotten a search term 
 
Create your free Hotfrog business profile
 Add your business 
Join the Hotfrog community on:
 
Share on:
 
 About Hotfrog Advertise with us Contact us Terms of Use Privacy Policy Help 
 
 Hotfrog Small Business Hub 

 Grow your business Case studies Hotfrog how-tos 
 © Copyright Reed Business Information Pty Ltd 2005-2012 (v 11.5.7fs9.002 )
	</body>
</document>
