<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000840" url="http://www.mail.com/news/world/857656-egypt-cabinet-offers-to-resign-violence-grows.html" time="2012-07-12-16:12" support="1" score="0.000349504034377491" bingtitle="Egypt Cabinet offers to resign as violence grows - World news" webtitle="World - News: Breaking news and opinions - mail.com">
			<query id="001237" bing-rank="142"/>
	<description>... simply that he wants to hold on to his seat,&quot; said Sayyed, holding two rocks in his hand, ready to throw ... to a nearby sidewalk outside a Hardees fast food restaurant. A ...</description>
	<body>
		World - News: Breaking news
 edit 
 Get your free email account 
 Web Search 
 Home Free Email News Entertainment Sports Sci/Tech Business Jobs Dating Games 1&amp;1 MyWebsite Tools Log in 
 
 US World Politics 
 
World 

 
Vote on Xstrata, Glencore merger set for Sept. 7
 
Anglo-Swiss mining group Xstrata PLC says it has rescheduled a shareholder vote on its proposed merger with commodities trading giant Glencore ...  
 
Belfast cops gird for riot as Orange marches start
 
Tens of thousands of Protestants from the Orange Order brotherhood marched from their lodges Thursday across Northern Ireland in an annual ...  
 
Exiled Rwandan says Kagame hunted him, others
 
A prominent Rwandan exile who was shot in South Africa alleges his president was behind a plot to kill him, and that the leader has tried to kill ...  
 
Israel&apos;s Olmert says he won&apos;t re-enter politics
 
Former Israeli Prime Minister Ehud Olmert said on Thursday that he would not return to politics, two days after he was acquitted of the central ...  
 
Israeli vice premier pessimistic over draft change
 
Israel&apos;s vice premier is pessimistic about finding a formula to obligate ultra-Orthodox Jews to serve in the military before a court-determined Aug.  
 
Panel: UK spies wrong-footed by Arab Spring
 
Britain&apos;s spies were wrong-footed by the spread of unrest during the Arab Spring and failed to predict the dramatic uprisings that swept the region, ...  
 
AP Interview: Afghan civil war unlikely, US says
 
The outgoing U.S. ambassador to Afghanistan said Thursday that he thinks it&apos;s unlikely that the departure of most foreign troops by 2014 will plunge ...  
 
9 dead, 11 hurt, 4 missing in Mont Blanc avalanche
 
French authorities say a summer avalanche on the Mont Blanc range swept nine European climbers to their deaths and left 11 others injured and four ...  
 
Official: 95 killed in Nigeria fuel tanker fire
 
A Nigerian government agency says 95 people have died after a fuel tanker caught fire and exploded. A spokesman for the emergency management agency ...  
 
Militants take villagers hostage in Pakistan
 
Pakistani officials say dozens of militants coming from Afghanistan attacked a village in the country&apos;s northwest and took scores of villagers hostage  
 
Syria: ambassador who defected should be punished
 
Syria&apos;s Foreign Ministry said Thursday that the country&apos;s former ambassador to Iraq should be punished after his defection to the opposition seeking ...  
 
Mali arrests colonel behind attempted countercoup
 
Mali&apos;s government says the military has arrested an army colonel who directed a parachutist regime that attempted to stage a countercoup in April.  
 
Palestinian officials hesitant on Arafat autopsy
 
In an apparent flip-flop, Palestinian investigators looking into Yasser Arafat&apos;s death said Thursday they want to review reports from a Swiss lab ...  
 
End of era as BBC&apos;s Bush House goes silent
 
BBC World Service radio has broadcast its final news bulletin from its longstanding home at Bush House in central London. The global service is ...  
 
Military plane crash in Mauritania kills 7
 
An aviation official in Mauritania says seven people were killed in the crash of a military plane chartered by a Canadian mining company. The official ...  
 
US, China square off over South China Sea
 
The Obama administration pressed Beijing on Thursday to accept a code of conduct for resolving territorial disputes in the resource-rich South China ...  
 
Afghan president calls on Taliban to drop weapons
 
Afghanistan&apos;s president called on the Taliban Thursday to relinquish their weapons, saying that the group and its leader should join the political ...  
 
China probing bishop who quit government church
 
The government body that controls the Catholic church in China says it is investigating the selection of a bishop who cut his ties to the group as ...  
 
AP sources: Saudis to send 2 women to London Games
 
Saudi Arabia will send two female athletes to the London Olympics, ending the ultraconservative Muslim country&apos;s record of sending only all-male teams ...  
 
Ratko Mladic hospitalized after feeling unwell
 
Former Bosnian Serb military chief Ratko Mladic was hospitalized Thursday after complaining of feeling unwell at his genocide trial. Mladic was ...  
 
ECB overnight deposits plunge at zero interest
 
Banks have drastically cut the amount of money they hold overnight at the European Central Bank after it cut the interest rate on those deposits to ...  
 
Morgan Stanley executive investigated in Germany
 
A former governor from Chancellor Angela Merkel&apos;s party who is being investigated with the head of Morgan Stanley&apos;s German branch in connection with ...  
 
Day 6 of running of the bulls: 6 hurt, none gored
 
Six people were injured Thursday but none gored in the sixth day of the running of the bulls in Pamplona. Navarra Hospital said three people suffered ...  
 
Malaysia to repeal sedition law ahead of polls
 
Malaysia&apos;s leader has announced plans to repeal a colonial-era law curbing free speech in the latest political reform ahead of general elections, but ...  
 
In historic visit, Clinton reaches out to Laos
 
Decades after the U.S. gave Laos a horrific distinction as the world&apos;s most heavily bombed nation per person, Secretary of State Hillary Rodham ...  
 
 1 2 3 4 ... 50 ... 100 ... 150 ... 200    Popular Searches News 
 Olympia 2012 election 2012 Mitt Romney debt deal weather forecast 
 
mail.com recommends

 Easily create your professional website with 1&amp;1 MyWebsite 
 Most read articles 
 1 
Missing bank director sends confession, disappears  
 2 
$3.2 million yacht sinks in Lake Tahoe marina  
 3 
Vast wealth didn&apos;t shield the Rausings from drugs  
 4 
W.Va. sheriff says woman tortured; husband charged  
 5 
SOS call for historic ocean liner docked in Philly  
 
 Service 
 
 Headlines in pictures 
 
Click here to see the slideshow  
 
 
mail.com services

 Internet Explorer 9 Download Email Client Support Unlimited Email Storage Mail Collector Junkmail Filter Mail Notifier Multiple Account Management 
 Popular Searches Entertainment 
 cheap ebooks anger management xbox live Charlie Sheen concert tickets 
 Popular Searches Hot-Topics 
 DNSChanger mini iPad Ernest Borgnine nexus 7 tablet Microsoft surface 
 
 Home Free Email News 
 US World Politics 
 Entertainment 
 Celebrity Music Lifestyle Deadline by partner Hollywood Life by partner MovieLine by partner 
 Sports 
 Basketball Football Baseball Hockey More Sports 
 

 Sci/Tech 
 Sci/Tech News Health Boy Genius Report by partner 
 Business 
 Economy Markets Small Business Credit Cards Real Estate 
 Jobs Dating Games Video Tools 
 Android App iPhone App iPad App MailCheck Firefox Internet Explorer 
 

 Editions 
 US International India Россия Română Singapore South Africa México Indonesia Brasileira 
 Company 
 About mail.com General Terms and Conditions Press Room Privacy Policy Help us improve mail.com Contact us 
 
 Mobile site Follow mail.com 
 World - News: Breaking news channel for World. | Webmail | Email address | Mobile Clients 
Copyright 2012 Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.
Copyright©2012 1&amp;1 Mail&amp;Media Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
