<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000822" url="http://www.discoverhongkong.com/eng/dining/asian-halal-food.html" time="2012-07-12-16:11" support="2" score="0.008893238495321058" bingtitle="Halal Food, Halal Restaurants in Hong Kong - Hong Kong Tourism Board" webtitle="Halal Food, Halal Restaurants in Hong Kong - Hong Kong Tourism Board">
			<query id="000673" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="000657" bing-rank="119"/>
	<description>Halal food can be found in Hong Kong at Muslim restaurants along with other special Asian, middle eastern, and Arab cuisines. There is a wide range of halal food in ...</description>
	<body>
		| e-newsletter | Location / Language | Sitemap | Contact us | RSS | 
 Select A Site INTERNATIONAL - English Australia - English Canada - English China - 简体中文 France - Français Germany - Deutsch Italy - Italiano Japan -日本語 Korea - 한국어 Malaysia – Bahasa New Zealand - English Russia - русский Southeast Asia - English Spain – Español Taiwan - 繁體中文 Thailand - ไทย United Kingdom - English United States - English Remember selection 
 Home Plan Your Trip Attractions Shopping Dining Hong Kong Must Taste Cuisines Chinese Food Asian Food Western Food Halal Food Fast Food Food and Wine Pairing Where to Eat Dining Districts Best of the Best Culinary Awards Quality Tourism Services Dining Tips Hong Kong Dining Guidebooks Interactive Dining Planner Dining Search Touring Things to Do Events&amp;Festivals Interactive Corner Meetings, Incentives, Conventions&amp;Exhibitions About HKTB 
 
 Home  &gt;  Dining  &gt;  Cuisines  &gt;  Halal Food   
 Halal Food 
 Related Tags Hong Kong Dining Asian Cuisine Where To Eat Halal Food Muslim Restaurants 
 Hong Kong Dining Asian Cuisine Where To Eat Halal Food Muslim More+  
 
 
 Halal Food Hong Kong caters to every culinary desire, including a wide range of halal food. For all Muslims, for the meat of a land animal to be Halal, it must be slaughtered by a Muslim who pronounces the name of Allah before killing the animal by cutting its throat.

Muslim visitors will have no difficulty in finding halal food. However, some if not most of these outlets serve liquor. Muslim visitors are advised to enquire before patronising.

 

 Check out QTS restaurants for Halal Food 
 Printing Tools 
 Print this page Add to print basket Manage print basket 
 Social Bookmarks 
 Del.icio.us Digg Reddit 
 | e-newsletter | Sitemap | Contact us | RSS |
Last update:13 Jan 11. Best viewed with IE 6.0 / Firefox 1.5 or above in 1024x768 resolution
Copyright©2007 Hong Kong Tourism Board. All rights reserved. Privacy policy &amp; Terms of use
	</body>
</document>
