<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000260" url="http://www.ibeginfinance.com/2009/08/wwwopinionportcomyum-yum-brands.html" time="2012-07-12-15:27" support="35" score="0.05577285390912875" bingtitle="www.Opinionport.com/Yum - The Yum! Brands KFC Customers Survey" webtitle="www.Opinionport.com/Yum - The Yum! Brands KFC Customers  Survey">
			<query id="001385" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000915" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000897" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="000564" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="001117" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000583" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="000302" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="001220" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="000914" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="001494" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000364" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="001197" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000177" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000396" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="001196" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="000930" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000927" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="000866" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="001525" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="001386" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000582" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="001192" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000163" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000568" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="001381" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000739" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000929" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000426" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000051" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="001211" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000114" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000551" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000569" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="001400" bing-rank="73"/>
	<description>... the restaurant member on the front of the receipt ... one of the most clean well kept and friendy fast-food restaurant ... my food, i went to this store and first the cashier ...</description>
	<body>
		I Begin Finance 
 
 Talk about banking, credit card, home&amp;personal loan, insurance, investment, wealth management, and more... 
 
www.Opinionport.com/Yum - The Yum! Brands KFC Customers Survey
 www.Opinionport.com/Yum  is the official website of The Yum! Brands KFC Customers Satisfaction Survey, where you can leave your feedback about your recent experience in their store and win their weekly sweepstakes. Each winner will receive $1,000 in cash.
 
 To start the survey at Opinionport.com/Yum , enter the restaurant member on the front of the receipt you got from participating A&amp;W, KFC , Long John Silver&apos;s, or Taco Bell restaurants. The sweepstakes ends on December 31, 2009. Open only to legal residents of the 50 United States and the District of Columbia, and who are 18 years of age or older. Good Luck!! 
 Learn more from http://www.opinionport.com/yum Posted by Eric at Sunday, November 01, 2009 Labels: food , shopping , sweepstakes 
 
21 comments:
 Anonymous
said... 
your contest is about as valid as a lot of others i have seen that is why you only post winners initals
 November 28, 2009 8:27 AM Anonymous
said... 
When did the seniors discount on combos stop? I hve always been give this before. I also did not appreciate having a staff member sleep in one of the booths while I ate my lunch(at noon!!!)
 December 3, 2009 7:05 AM Anonymous
said... 
Stopped at store #022456 today for lunch.
Debra, who appeared to be the Manager, was very cordial and made helpful suggestions.
She seemed determined to make our visit a pleasant experience.
She succeeded.
We&apos;ll be back!
 December 11, 2009 1:16 PM W. E. Stokes
said... 
I went to KFC to get fried chicken when I was served the chicken was not fryed, It was boiled or baked, Very gooey. When I complained the manager said,&quot;Ido not make the rules or print the signs&quot;AND Walked away. On top of that I was supposed to get green beans, it even said so on my receipt, I got none.
 December 20, 2009 4:04 PM Mike McHugh
said... 
very unhappy with you closing A&amp;W&apos;s in San Diego has you only opened A&amp;W&apos;s by themselves they had a chance to succeed now we have no A&amp;W draft root beer in town because Yums has morons for marketing experts
 January 24, 2010 7:46 PM Anonymous
said... 
Don&apos;t know if you monitor your site
but even the rules say that the @#*
contest ended 12/31/09...Duh..waste
my time,LAZY good for nothings.Now
I must decide if I want to eat any
thing you would fix.Maybe you might forget to&quot;COOK&quot;it.Wake up,
folks, it&apos;s business.But then maybe you do not need your job..Tx
 February 2, 2010 3:20 PM L. Percle
said... 
Please try&amp;hire competient people to put your food together. Ordered 2 crunchy Taco Supremes. Neither came that way. One was everything but sour cream(suppose to have it) other one no tomatoes or sour cream&amp;very little beef(mostly lettece). Hardly any cheese. Paid for supreme at the Marrero location in LA. Store # 019848. Sadly enough this is not first time screwed up orders. Complained but of course nothing has changed. PLEASE get off yor behinds&amp;do something to serve your customers better or you may not have a store at all.
 February 10, 2010 5:41 PM Anonymous
said... 
Where do you enter the resturant number??? Why are we doing this if the contest ended 12/31/2009 ?????????
 February 10, 2010 9:09 PM Anonymous
said... 
I agree, where do we enter the number for the contest and if it ended why does the receipts still advertise.
anonymous
 February 17, 2010 9:06 AM Anonymous
said... 
STORE 0004261 TACO BELL, 2/26/10, 10:45PM, STATION 003,DT ORDER TAKER, CHECK 3542. On a break myself. No customers at the store, but myself. I sit in drive thru over a minute before the girl says be with you in a minute. She was three minutes before saying may I take your order. They make you wait on them constantly, if they are not making you return with the order made wrong. Is there not a manager on every shift. Will they get better or should I just go to MCDONALDS. THEY ARE NOT ALLOWED TO MAKE YOU WAIT AND MAKE FEWER MISTAKES.
 February 27, 2010 5:50 AM Anonymous
said... 
i had the buffet today and it was hot and tasty,but it does depend on who is working sometimes.
 March 6, 2010 4:26 PM Anonymous
said... 
very good service at Taco Bell 016041
 March 8, 2010 3:46 PM Anonymous
said... 
srore id # h220001, employee name jackie, date 5/30/10, satisfaction very very good!! enjoyable exeprience!! can&apos;t beat it!! was treated very well and pleased with the service !! can&apos;t say any better about it !! tessa roush
 May 30, 2010 4:06 PM Anonymous
said... 
Ive been in the most recent tacobell/kfc restaurant on baytown texas. and i must say it is one of the most clean well kept and friendy fast-food restaurant I&apos;ve been in quite some time... friendly customer service,since u walk in the restaurant they great u with a smille.... thanks to all the hard working personal... (( I DEFENETLY RECOMEND THIS PLACE))
 June 19, 2010 12:22 PM Anonymous
said... 
Ordered 2 hardshell tacos- got something else. I returned my order and got one taco only half filled. Counter help (teens )has a hard time concentrating on getting any order correct -several times . Seems to be new help too often . Problem is recent . store #tb19693
 August 7, 2010 4:39 PM Anonymous
said... 
Stopped at TACO BELL&apos;Store#24552.Fort Myers Florida&apos;&apos;employee name[ CLAUDIA ]Was Very cordial and made helpful suggestions. Sastisfaction very&apos;very good!! with the servise I LOVE....Idefenetly recomend this place...
 August 26, 2010 6:44 PM Anonymous
said... 
wooooo..recomiendo pasar por Taco Bell. the store#24552 de Fort Myers Florida.Fui atendido Xr&apos;&apos;CLAUDIA&apos;&apos;El cual me atendio super bien..El SERVICIO ES EXSELENTE..
 August 26, 2010 6:55 PM Anonymous
said... 
Mi esposa trabaja en un taco bell y a mi me consta q su prparacion en limpieza y atancion Al cliente y preparation d comida es la prioridad del restaurante. Y si quiere comprobarlo aga una parada x 48th ST.y broadway in phoenix AZ. PD.en lo personal a mi no me gusta mucho esa comida ya q 90% d la comida s la misma solo la cambian d emboltura. No estoy diciendo q s mala comida solo digo lo q veo.
 May 7, 2011 8:14 AM Anonymous
said... 
I went to KFC on 2011-05-08.Time 7:45 PM.Place 2532 Wesley Chapel Rd Decatur GA.Phone NO.770-593-2248. Store #W710132.Cashier: Tricey. It was the worst experience i ever had in this KFC outlet,let me first say something in my whole life and i mean i am 56 years and my experience was the worst i never eat any fast food other than KFC when i say never eaten any other foods in my fiftysix years i mean that really mean that,i usually cook my foods at home but when i am out KFC is my food, i went to this store and first the cashier was really nice, i order the 8PC meal, but i explain that i dont eat wings nor the leg,so if i can get 2brest and one leg for my gran baby and 5Thigh,the casher said that the 8piece comes with the wing and leg,this have a but in it, she said as i have to wait 15min for it she would oblige me and give me what i ask for, that waiting period took me one hour to get my chicken and to top it off i never got what i ask for, today the leg and wings are in the garbage money thrown in the bin,because it was only my Husband and Granbaby eating this fast food.
 May 9, 2011 12:31 PM 9c2b7e16-7a79-11e0-9f81-000bcdcb2996 said... 
i wwent to KFC on the 2011-05-02 Time 1:56 PM On 3555 Flat Shols Rd Decatur.GA. Ticket #3531 Store #w710293. Cashier:Roshanda,buy the same 8piece meal that i baught in the other store in the same Decature area and this Roshanda was excellant and i got what i wanted, i did not have to throw away any food that i dont eat this guy was polite kind and excellant, if there was a 10 i would have given him a 10, but for rating you all dont have a ten i would have to go for a 7 seven. Roshanda keep up the good work. louise
 May 9, 2011 1:19 PM Tony Kleiber,Kalkaska,Mi.
said... 
I have 2 complaints,both at store#003881,West Branch,Mi.The first was in the fall of 2010,you had a promotion of four extra pieces of chicken when buying a bucket.We were returning home from downstate and ordered a bucket in the drive-thru.The girl at the window asked if we would pull forward as our chicken wouldn&apos;t be ready for another 3 min. .25 min. later they finally brought out our meal. When we got home 45 min. later we discovered we didn&apos;t receive the extra chicken.Yesterday(5/17/2011)went there again on the eay home from downstate,ordered 12 piece meal,original,no wings,and was informed that they had no original breasts(would we take xtra-crispy?)..Mind you this is 5:00pm.(suppertime)After standing there 20 min. waiting for our baked beans we finally left for home....get there and find 3 wings in the bottom of our bucket ....is this any wayto run a business?Don&apos;t worry about it ,next time we&apos;ll go to Burger King next door.
 May 18, 2011 7:34 AM 
 Post a Comment 
 Newer Post Older Post Home Subscribe to: Post Comments (Atom) 
Search This Blog
 Loading... 
Followers
 
 
Recent Comments
 
My Favorite Sites
 
 CNN.com/Clarkhoward Couponsuzy.com MyEasyPayment.com MyCreditKeeper.com WellsfargoFinancial.com WalmartMoneyCard.com 
 
Blog Roll
 
 Disney Channel Bank of America Online Free Coupons Kontera Online Very Funny Ads Unemployment Benefits U.S. Department of Labor 
 
Blog Archive
 Blog Archive April 2012 (1) March 2012 (5) January 2012 (4) December 2011 (1) October 2011 (10) September 2011 (13) August 2011 (2) July 2011 (1) June 2011 (1) May 2011 (44) April 2011 (22) March 2011 (3) February 2011 (1) January 2011 (2) December 2010 (4) July 2010 (1) June 2010 (1) May 2010 (1) April 2010 (6) March 2010 (4) February 2010 (8) January 2010 (22) December 2009 (28) November 2009 (47) October 2009 (31) September 2009 (23) August 2009 (39) July 2009 (50) June 2009 (34) May 2009 (42) April 2009 (27) March 2009 (40) February 2009 (27) January 2009 (1) October 2008 (2) 
 Disclaimer : This blog does not host any media files. It is not responsible for the problems arising from external links. If you have any questions, please contact with erichill2010#aim.com (change # into @). 
  
 
 
 
 Simple template. Template images by mariusFM77 . Powered by Blogger .
	</body>
</document>
