<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000695" url="http://en-gb.facebook.com/note.php?note_id=10150163611577939" time="2012-07-12-15:59" support="1" score="0.0019072391466673593" bingtitle="Facebook 30 Day Challenge! | Facebook" webtitle="Facebook 30 Day Challenge! | Facebook">
			<query id="000253" bing-rank="175"/>
	<description>Day 15: Fave veganized meal at a fast food restaurant. ... in your community and reach out for support. Im ... bit difficult and I actually have to order most of my food ...</description>
	<body>
		Facebook logo 
 Email or Phone Password Keep me logged in Forgotten your password? 
 Sign Up Facebook helps you connect and share with the people in your life. 
 peta2.com&apos;s notes  ( 0 ) 
 
Tagged
 
 
 

 
 Get notes via RSS 
 
Facebook 30 Day Challenge!
 by peta2.com on Monday, 18 April 2011 at 13:34 · 
Okay—so there have been all kinds of these 30 day challenges on Facebook recently, and we thought a challenge relating to veganism would be pretty sweet. This challenge is a super easy way to enlighten your friends about the how completely awesome veganism is, while also showing how cruel the meat, dairy, and egg industries are.



Here&apos;s the scoop:



Start by creating a photo album on Facebook and labeling it&quot;30 Day Vegan Challenge.&quot;Find a pic that represents your answer to each day&apos;s statement, post the pic in your album, and put the statement for each day (and your answer) in the photo caption. That&apos;s it!



 Need an example? Here&apos;s a shot of my day 1: 



 



What are you waiting for? Get started already! 


 Day 1:   Why you went vegan.
Day 2:   Best thing about being vegan.

Day 3:   Fave vegan snack.

Day 4:   Fave vegan meat.

Day 5:   Fave vegan dairy product.

Day 6:   Fave vegan body product.

Day 7:   Fave animal rights quote.

Day 8:   Fave vegan shoes.

Day 9:   Fave flavor of vegan ice cream.

Day 10: Fave vegan recipe.

Day 11: Fave vegan candy.

Day 12: Vegan celebrity crush.

Day 13: Grossest factory farming fact.

Day 14: Something you wish everyone knew about dairy.

Day 15: Fave veganized meal at a fast food restaurant.

Day 16: Animal rights issue that inspires you the most.

Day 17: Most influential factory farm photo.

Day 18: Fave vegan meal.

Day 19: One reason why everyone should go vegan right now.

Day 20: One food your non-vegan friends don’t realize is already vegan.

Day 21: Best place to shop for vegan clothes.

Day 22: A fact that people don’t know about pigs.

Day 23: Most irritating myth about veganism (and why it&apos;s irritating!).

Day 24: Most delicious picture of vegan food you&apos;ve ever seen.

Day 25: Favorite vegan band member.

Day 26: Favorite song about animal rights.

Day 27: Fave vegan cookie.

Day 28: Fave animal rights slogan.

Day 29: Fave peta2 ad.

Day 30: Fave accidentally vegan item.
 


 Don&apos;t forget to add me on Facebook so you can keep track of my answers for the challenge! It&apos;s all about vegan solidarity, guys. 



Have fun!




 Knowledge is power!
- Christina 
 


P.S. Not vegan yet? Take our pledge here !

 Like · Comment · Share 
 Carolyn Luna , Veronica Ferrini , Rai Saab and 126 others like this. 
 Naty Marrocco Lee ♥ 18 April 2011 at 13:34 · 1 Callie Foley Awesome I am totally doing this :D 18 April 2011 at 13:36 · 2 Abigail Herman you should do one on vegetarianism because i am working my way up to vegan because it is difficult to go straight vegan 18 April 2011 at 13:37 · 9 Stephanie Kelley hella good idea ! ♥ 18 April 2011 at 13:38 · 1 Callie Foley ‎@Abigail, its not that difficult to go vegan, I found it to be a very easy and natural transition. find vegans in your community and reach out for support. Im sure they remember the challenges they first went though when they became vegan 18 April 2011 at 13:39 · 4 Lindsay Barrasse I took the pledge and started a blog - http:// lovetofu.tumblr.com/ ♥ What I will do is post the answer to my blog, which then I will post to facebook! I will say I never felt better in my whole life!!! ♥ 18 April 2011 at 13:41 · 2 Ellie Rummell what about a challenge about being vegetarian? It&apos;s very hard to go straight vegan! 18 April 2011 at 13:43 · 4 Sonja Stubbings awesome idea. I&apos;m going to start it today 18 April 2011 at 13:45 · 1 Tessa Benedetti this is SOOO GREAT IM DOING THIS TODAY!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!! 18 April 2011 at 13:46 · 1 Abigail Herman ‎@Callie I find it hard because of the money and it seems like there milk and eggs in everything. Plus there is no vegan that i know of in my community 18 April 2011 at 13:48 · 1 William Blizzard Being vegan is hard, vegan products arent cheap and alot of brands that put out so called&quot;vegan&quot;products use gluten or eggs n such and its not cheap gardein wings here for 8 is $5..... 18 April 2011 at 13:53 Courtney Skelley ‎@Abigail&amp;Ellie: I am trying to make the transition from vegetarian to vegan right now too&amp;something I&apos;ve found that I really enjoy is vegan mon-fri,&amp;vegetarian sat-sun.. its a really nice way to ease yourself into it without going cold turkey right away.. just a thought!! 18 April 2011 at 13:54 · 3 Abigail Herman ok thanks for the idea courtney! 18 April 2011 at 13:55 Christina Cordier ‎@Abigail: It&apos;s not alway easy going full vegan especially if you live in a smaller town. Finding vegan substitutes can be a bit difficult and I actually have to order most of my food/products online. I know a few people that are vegeta ... rian but no vegans. I get most of my support online and I can&apos;t tell you the number of books I&apos;ve read. The hardest part is everyone grilling you about your choices. More up north it&apos;s more excepted and there&apos;s much more choices for people but here in the deep south, it&apos;s all BBQ and buttermilk biscuits. It can be a bit of work and it&apos;s not for everyone but when you finally do make the switch- it is so worth it. See more 18 April 2011 at 13:57 · 4 Christina Cordier ‎**accepted

Attacked by autocorrect-lol 18 April 2011 at 14:00 · 1 Callie Foley Have you checked out the Accidently vegan food section on peta or peta 2? there is alot of food out there with no animal products. Just read labels and tweak your diet a bit. :) Here are some helpful links plus beyond processed food i alwa ... ys love eating a bowl of fruit, or a grilled earth balance peanutbutter and banana sandwhich or one of Amys kitchen non dairy burritos. http://www.peta2.com/ STUFF/ s-wte-groceryshopping.asp http://www.peta2.com/ STUFF/ s-wte-alternatives.asp http://www.peta2.com/ STUFF/s-wte-restaurants.asp http://www.peta.org/ living/vegetarian-living/ accidentally-vegan.aspx See more 18 April 2011 at 14:00 · 2 Kourtney Christine im doing it! 18 April 2011 at 14:03 · 1 &apos;Naomi Vazquez I wish I could do this. :l
But I can&apos;t. Because my mom wont let me be vegan. 18 April 2011 at 14:04 Callie Foley ps: Veganism is not expensive unless most of your diet is dependent on the pricier meat substitutes. I base most of my diet on simpler meals of fruits, soy and grains. 18 April 2011 at 14:07 Gintare Baublyte And I live in Lithuania.. wish I could be a vegan, but there&apos;s no such thing here as vegan food.. and if there is, it&apos;sjust too expencive.. and ordering it online from other countries is expencive, because the shipping adds a lot.. so it sucks here 18 April 2011 at 14:11 · 1 Monica Kain I did the 30 day vegan for my new years resolution but I decided to stick with it:) 18 April 2011 at 14:18 · 3 Muireann Nic An Bheatha make a vegetarian 30 day challenge:) 18 April 2011 at 14:50 · 3 Tessa Maurine Bailey There is a 28 day vegan challenge, i learnt about it here on fb. 18 April 2011 at 15:41 Katelyn Whittington I am going to tweak it to make it a vegetarian challenge 18 April 2011 at 16:23 · 4 Caroline TheGrimm Groomer ‎@Courtney great minds think alike. I&apos;m doing the vegan mon-fri and vegetarian sat-sun too. I tried going all out vegan and I was so tired so I thought I&apos;d give my body time to adjust.

Going to start the challenge and go vegan, 18 April 2011 at 17:09 Ashley Velazquez count me in! 19 April 2011 at 08:23 Kylie Kween Juggaluggalettee im doin this bt vegetarian styllee :D 19 April 2011 at 15:09 
 
 Facebook © 2012 · English (UK) Mobile · Find friends · Badges · People · Pages · About · Create an Ad · Create a Page · Developers · Careers · Privacy · Cookies · Terms · Help
	</body>
</document>
