<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000406" url="http://www.restaurantica.com/on/georgetown/shepherds-crook/23001023/" time="2012-07-12-15:39" support="10" score="0.018717852933421892" bingtitle="Shepherds Crook: Georgetown, ON | Restaurant Reviews &amp; Menus ..." webtitle="Shepherds Crook: Georgetown, ON | Restaurant ReviewsMenus | Restaurantica.com">
			<query id="001361" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="001283" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="001314" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="000107" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000984" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="001267" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="001000" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000311" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="001001" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="000999" bing-rank="215"/>
	<description>... took a bit of time, but this is definitely no fast food restaurant ... I should have figured it out when the table in front of us returned their food TWICE. Order: fisherman ...</description>
	<body>
		What? Where? Join Restaurantica  Sign Up 
 Your Page 
 
 Register Login Français Help 
 
 Home Ontario Restaurants Georgetown Restaurants Shepherds Crook 
 Be the first to add a photo! Upload 
 
Shepherds Crook
 4.0 stars ( 25 reviews, average rating: 3.1/5) Cuisines: Pub Food (905) 702-0456 86 Main Street South Georgetown , ON L7G 3E4 Neighbourhoods: Downtown Georgetown , Georgetown North 
 
 Write a Review Map it! 
 
 Yes No 
 Recommend Restaurant? 9 people have voted 44% of voters recommend Bloglink! If you&apos;ve reviewed this place on your blog, Add your review to this page! Restaurant Details Price range $$ ($11-$25) Are you the owner? 
 Claim this restaurant now! Incorrect business info? Let us know! 
 Restaurant Reviews 25 guava 
 
 1 2 3 next 
 1 Review 6 months ago 
 Lousy (no) service Reviewed by TorontoFoodie738 Overall 1.0 star 
 Food 1.0 star Services 1.0 star Atmosphere 1.0 star 
 
 Price Range (per person): $0-$10 Visit Again?: No Party Size: 1 
 
Party of five entered for lunch mid-December 2011 and sat at a table for five minutes without anyone approaching. No other customers around us either. The staff of three(male and 2 female), at the back of the place with other customers, kept looking at us but never came to our table. We walked out. I sent email to manager, no reply, I called him and he he didn&apos;t seem surprised, other than saying it shouldn&apos;t have happened.
 Order: Nothing - no service 
   Comment (0) 1 Review 10 months ago 
 We&apos;re addicted! Reviewed by megz Overall 5.0 stars 
 Food 5.0 stars Services 5.0 stars Atmosphere 5.0 stars 
 
 Price Range (per person): $11-$25 Visit Again?: Yes Party Size: 2 
 
I had driven by this downtown georgetown pub many times without even noticing it was there, so when a friend suggested we go in for a few beers, I was surprised that I hadn&apos;t heard of this place before!

The beer list was mostly new to my eyes. They offer a huge selection of local microbreweries, which are surprisingly delicious! We ordered the fish and chips as we sipped on beer that had been brewed no more than 40 km from where we were sitting. The food took a bit of time, but this is definitely no fast food restaurant.... The fish, which we were told was freshly beer battered in the kitchen, was the best we&apos;d ever tried. This would not be my last visit.

After coming in for the past year, I&apos;ve noticed that this pub is at times understaffed, service can be delayed due to volume, but this is also a place to come and take your time. Don&apos;t come in expecting to have a quick meal in time to make a movie...This pub was created for people to come in and forget about the hustle bustle of their day to day lives!
 Order: Highly recommend the lancashire hot pot! 
   Comment (0) Presented by Nearby Restaurants: 
 Chanan Little India 
 905-873-3300 78 Main St S, Georgetown, ON, L7G3G3 
 Yong&apos;s Restaurant 
 905-877-5106 109 Main St S, Georgetown, ON, L7G3E5 
 
 1 Review 10 months ago 
 Worst Service EVER! Reviewed by GeorgetownFoodie571 Overall 2.0 stars 
 Food 1.0 star Services 1.0 star Atmosphere 3.0 stars 
 
 Price Range (per person): $11-$25 Visit Again?: No Party Size: 4 
 
My husband and I went to the Sheperds Crook with our three children for dinner tonight. After ordering and waiting 40 minutes, I asked our waitress when our food would be ready. She said it would be a while because they were really busy (my estimation: 25% capacity). 15 minutes later, she said it would be another 15 minutes. 15 minutes after that, she said it would be another 5. 10 minutes after that, she came over and apologized that our order had been lost behind the counter, but not to worry, we wouldn&apos;t have to pay for our drinks. Um, gee, thanks. So, hungry kids, missed movie, terrible, terrible time. The only consolation, I suppose, by looking around at the other customers, we weren&apos;t the only ones unhappy. I should have figured it out when the table in front of us returned their food TWICE.
 Order: fisherman&apos;s plate, fisherman&apos;s plate, kids fish and chips, kids pogo, apple juice, cranberry juice, 1/2 pint beer 
   Comment (0) 2 Reviews 2011/06/10 
 I have been going to The Shepherds Crook in... Reviewed by NoraC Overall 4.0 stars 
 Food 5.0 stars Services 4.0 stars Atmosphere 4.0 stars 
 
 Price Range (per person): $26-$60 Visit Again?: Yes Party Size: 2 
 
I have been going to The Shepherds Crook in Georgetown since they opened. The food is consistently good, says my husband, I wouldn&apos;t know about that as I always, yes, always order the fish and chips. They are the best for miles, great batter, nice fish and good fries. A good portion for the price too. Service is always good, and they have Guinness on tap, what more can you ask for , Guinness on tap and great fish and chips and friendly service.
 Order: Fish&amp;Chips, Cuineess 
   Comment (0) 1 Review 2011/06/08 
 Friendly Servers, Great Pub Reviewed by DeannaE Overall 5.0 stars 
 Food 4.0 stars Services 5.0 stars Atmosphere 5.0 stars 
 
 Price Range (per person): $11-$25 Visit Again?: Yes Party Size: 2 
 
If your service was soo terrible on the Sunday- waitress stating the close time, then &apos;apparently&apos; leaving and making you wait 10 mins, then 5, 15 mins before even getting you a drink, asked you if you needed change twice (**HINT** if u respond the first time, she wont need to ask you twice. Neat little trick.. as she probably isn&apos;t psychic) then if she followed you outside throwing a penny at you that you left for her on the table (which let&apos;s face it, leaving a penny as a tip? pretty ignorant move) and shouting at you and making a scene... What on earth would possess someone to go back to that pub?? Seems more likely to me that when she refused you service after leaving her a penny, you got embarassed and angry and then made up a complete load of crap about her being unreaslitically rude and crazy in order to make a pretty outrageous point.

All the servers in the Shepherd&apos;s Crook are friendly girls. They all get along with eachother, are very knowledgeable, and treat their customers with loads of respect. Thing is, when they get rude, ignorant customers, or even customers that have been drinking too much for their own good, they have every right to refuse that customer service and maintain their own self respect. Did you expect your server to just smile and serve you on the Saturday after being extremely rude and leaving her a penny 3 weeks earlier? lol
Maybe next time treat your server with a little bit of respect.. Something to think about.

Enjoy the George in the meantime, however.
 Order: Best beer in town 
   Comment (2) 11 months ago 
 Recent Comment by : acheronbeach 
 
I&apos;d be shocked if the owner of the Crook knew about this ridiculous waitress. He&apos;s a decent guy (an Anglican priest) and an experienced businessman. I&apos;m going to try to let him know that his waitstaff have posted nonsense like this on the net.
 see all comments 4 Reviews 2011/06/08 
 Decent Food, Terrible Service Reviewed by Erin Overall 3.0 stars 
 Food 4.0 stars Services 1.0 star Atmosphere 3.0 stars 
 
 Price Range (per person): $11-$25 Visit Again?: No Party Size: 2 
 
My boyfriend and I used to come in here once every two weeks or so for lunch, and found the food to be decent and the atmosphere was nice enough. However, after receiving absolutely horrifying service from one of their waitresses, we will be sticking to the George from now on.

It was a Sunday night, and we came in around 9:00 with a couple friends, with the restaurant closing at 10:00. Right from the get go, our waitress was rude, stating the closing time in a tone that more or less suggested that we should leave. We stayed, and she didn&apos;t end up coming back to our table for about 10 minutes. I should note that there were only two or three other small tables at the time, and it was definitely not busy. When she came back, my boyfriend asked for a list of beers on tap, and after another 5 minutes, she came back stating she didn&apos;t have one, and wasn&apos;t able to list the beers herself. She dropped off our friend&apos;s drink, and my boyfriend ordered a bottle of beer. She didn&apos;t come back with it for another fifteen minutes (we counted); from our table we could clearly see her talking to another waiter the entire time.

We were definitely not impressed with the service, and our server was rude and showed no basic manners. We didn&apos;t end up ordering any food. When it came time to pay the bill, we paid with cash, with well over $10 in change we needed back (the bill only came to around $25 dollars). She asked us TWICE if we wanted change, after already saying we did, and gave us a dirty look, apparently because we weren&apos;t giving her the $10 as a tip. We decided not to tip her, and waited outside after the restaurant closed, to wait with our friend who was expecting a ride.

Five minutes later, the waitress came out the front door and started to shout at us. She took a penny that was left on the table (which happened to be the only change from a bill ending in a $.99 amount), and THREW it at my friend, told us to keep our change and called us&quot;retards.&quot;I have never seen a waitress act in such a childish way - perhaps someone should explain to the girl that tips are not mandatory, and are earned through good service.

My boyfriend and I were foolish enough to come back on a Saturday night three weeks later, hoping that we&apos;d have a different server, as we did not have any problems like this with any of the other waitresses. The restaurant was packed, but apparently that didn&apos;t stop the same waitress from leaving her other tables to come over and berate us some more (despite the fact that we were already being served by another waitress). She told us that she wasn&apos;t going to serve us, and that she would make sure none of the other waitresses would either. We stated we were regular customers and just wanted to relax after work, and she stated&quot;maybe you should have thought about that before your little&quot;penny trick&quot;.&quot;I can only imagine she did this without her manager&apos;s knowledge, but we were not in the mood to start a fight and decided just to leave.

We have never had any problems with any of the other waitresses here, but our experience with this one spoiled, unprofessional waitress has wrecked our entire image of the Crook, and we will not be coming back until we know she has left.
 Order: The Burger, Chicken Sandwich 
   Comment (1) 2011/06/08 
 Recent Comment by : DeannaE 
 
Check out the latest review, in response to your review.
 see all comments 4 Reviews 2011/04/02 
 it&apos;s no St. George Reviewed by Waltzie Overall 2.0 stars 
 Food 2.0 stars Services 2.0 stars Atmosphere 2.0 stars 
 
 Price Range (per person): $11-$25 Visit Again?: Maybe Party Size: 2 
 
Another example of a place in Georgetown with so much potential but no execution.

They have a good selection of beer on tap.

The food was really ho hum, nothing special and I&apos;d try to avoid eating there again.

Old grumpy servers, or half caring soccer moms are pretty much what you get. Again nothing special.

We really find this place just.... what&apos;s the word? oh yeah ho hum.
 Order: Steak and Mushroom Pie...quickly regretted it 
   Comment (0) 10 Reviews 2011/01/22 
 Great food. Great service. Reviewed by foodie119 Overall 4.0 stars 
 Food 4.0 stars Services 5.0 stars Atmosphere 4.0 stars 
 
 Price Range (per person): $11-$25 Visit Again?: Yes Party Size: 2 
 
A few months ago I was ready to ditch this place permanently. The food was always great but the slow, miserable service made me not want to bother. Tonight was completely different. As soon as we found a table we were greeted and given menus. Our server then came and was cheerful, very friendly, made recommendations where requested and checked on us a couple of times to make sure we had everything we needed. The bangers and mash was as good as ever but the fish and chips was some of the best I have tasted. Nice meaty piece of fish cooked in a light batter with great fries. Desserts were great too, the sticky toffee pudding is quite something. Maybe some new faces here, but whatever, it is a great place and back on our favourites list.
 Order: bangers and mash, fish and chips, lemon meringue pie, sticky toffee pudding 
   Comment (0) 33 Reviews 2010/10/14 
 OK pub Reviewed by SDD Overall 3.0 stars 
 Food 3.0 stars Services 4.0 stars Atmosphere 3.0 stars 
 
 Price Range (per person): $11-$25 Visit Again?: Maybe Party Size: 4 
 
4 of us ordered lunch specials which were all adequate, as pubs rarely provide a great surprise. The fries are beautifully dark and crispy&amp;the beer selection is great.
Our waitress was excellent, didn&apos;t bother us with&quot;Is everything all right?&quot;
One faux pas: She asked one of us&quot;Are you still working on that?&quot;Who works at dining?
 Order: chicken schnitzel sand., burger, braised lamb stew, philly steak sand. 2 Tetley&apos;s and a Creemore 
   Comment (2) 3 months ago 
 Recent Comment by : Char80 
 
In all reality, the server doesn&apos;t want to speak to you while you stuff your face, they couldn&apos;t care less, but hey, that&apos;s the job. And I bet you would be the first to complain if your server deserted you...
 see all comments 2 Reviews 2010/10/03 
 Disappointing Service Reviewed by Milly82 Overall 2.0 stars 
 Food 4.0 stars Services 1.0 star Atmosphere 2.0 stars 
 
 Price Range (per person): $11-$25 Visit Again?: No Party Size: 2 
 
We used to go into this establishment often and recently had a terrible experience with one of the servers. I don&apos;t know her name...blondish hair. Anyway, great food but service and treatment was so bad we won&apos;t go back at all. Our friends have also experienced the same thing with this woman.
 Order: drinks that we didn&apos;t get 
   Comment (0) 
 1 2 3 next 
 Nearby restaurants Capina Family Eatery 
 3.5 stars &lt;½ km The Cellar Restaurant 
 4.0 stars &lt;½ km Georgetown Thai... 
 3.5 stars &lt;½ km more nearby Georgetown Restaurants: A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z Quick Links to USA Cities 
 Arlington Charleston Charlotte Denver 

 Detroit Las Vegas Milwaukee Minneapolis 

 Nashville Orlando Pittsburgh Portland (OR) 

 Sacramento Salt Lake City Seattle Springfield (IL) 

 Toledo Tucson Tulsa All Cities 
 Quick Links to Canadian Cities 
 Burnaby Calgary Charlottetown Halifax 

 Hamilton Kelowna Kitchener Mississauga 

 Montréal Ottawa Québec City Regina 

 Saint John Saskatoon Surrey Toronto 

 Vancouver Victoria Winnipeg All Cities 
 
 Advertisers Advertise with us Add a Restaurant Restaurant Owners 

 About Us About Us Careers Privacy Policy Terms and Conditions Bookmark Us 

 Quick links Your page Invite a Friend Help and FAQ 

 Mobile and tools Mobile Apps Blog Link to Us 

 Partners Yellowpages.ca AutoTrader.ca Buysell.com Canada411.ca CanadaPlus.ca Autos.ca 

   Deal of the Day HomeTrader.ca PriceCanada.com RedFlagDeals.com Restaurantica.ca 
 

 
© Copyright Restaurantica 2008-2011. Neighbourhood data

© 2009 Urban Mapping Inc. Yellow Pages Group and the Walking Fingers&amp;Design are trademarks of Yellow Pages Group Co. in Canada.
 
 Best Results 
 No Results 
 Popular Cities 
 Las Vegas, Nevada New York, New York San Francisco, California
	</body>
</document>
