<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000746" url="http://www.gtaforums.com/index.php?showtopic=204937" time="2012-07-12-16:06" support="6" score="0.002928543871342083" bingtitle="GTAForums.com -&gt; GTA: San Andreas Girlfriends Guide" webtitle="GTAForums.com -&gt; GTA: San Andreas Girlfriends Guide">
			<query id="000249" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000550" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000400" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000230" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="001493" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="001469" bing-rank="223"/>
	<description>If it&apos;s a drinking/food/dancing ... She likes a fat man, so get CJ up to at least 50% fat (a few visits to a fast food restaurant ... her enough, in order to get a key card ...</description>
	<body>
		Network 
 GTA Network 
 GTA Forums 
 GTA 5 
 GTA CTW 
 GTA IV 
 GTA LCS 
 GTA San Andreas 
 GTA Vice City 
 GTA III 
 GTA Garage 
 GTA Modding 

 Forum Tools 
 Search 
 Members 
 Help 

 GTA Series 
 GTA V 
 GTA IV 
 - Ballad of Gay Tony 
 - Lost and Damned 
 - PC Performance 
 - Gameplay 
 - Mission Help 
 - Multiplayer 
 - Cheats&amp;Tricks 
 - Troubleshooting 
 - Multiplayer Events 
 - Modding 
 GTA Chinatown Wars 
 GTA Vice City Stories 
 GTA Liberty City Stories 
 GTA San Andreas 
  &gt; Gameplay 
 - Mission Help 
 - Cheats&amp;Tricks 
 - Troubleshooting 
 - Modding 
 GTA Vice City 
 - Gameplay 
 - Cheats&amp;Tricks 
 - Troubleshooting 
 - Modding 
 GTA III 
 - Gameplay 
 - Cheats&amp;Tricks 
 - Troubleshooting 
 - Modding 
 Top Down Games 
 - GTA Advance 
 - GTA 2 
 - GTA 
 GTA Series Chat 

 Multiplayer 
 Events 
 Gangs 

 GTA Modding 
 IV Era Modding 
 - IV Coding 
 - IV Vehicles 
 - IV Maps 
 - IV Modelling 
 - IV Other 
 III Era Modding 
 - III Coding 
 - III Vehicles 
 - III Maps 
 - III Modelling 
 - III Other 
 I/II Era Modding 
 Tutorials 
 Mod Showroom 
 - Coding 
 - Vehicles 
 - Maps 
 - Characters 
 - Tools 
 - Other 
 Hosted Mods 
 - GTA: State of Liberty 
 - Vice City Multiplayer 
 - Myriad Islands 
 - GTA: Liberty City 
 - NWO Wastelands 
 - DYOM: Support 
 - DYOM: Missions 

 Community 
 The Lounge 
 - General Chat (Off-Topic) 
 - Gaming Chat 
 - Tech&amp;PC Chat 
 - Web Design / Programming 
 - Movies&amp;TV 
 - Music Talk 
 - Sports Discussion 
 - Vehicle Talk 
 Expression 
 - Visual Arts 
 - GFX Requests&amp;Tutorials 
 - Writers&apos;Discussion 
 - Debates&amp;Discussion 

 The Network 
 Announcements 
 GTA Network Support 
 Site Suggestions 
 

 
   
 
 
 
 
   
 
   Welcome to GTAForums! Be sure to check out the Grand Theft Auto V Forum.

 You are not registered! (If you are, click here to login ) Registering is fast, free and easy and allows you to instantly reply to any topic on GTAForums.
Why wait? Click here to register your own unique username and become part of the ever-growing community! 

( Log In | Register | Revalidate Validation E-mail )
 Quick Log-In:           
 
 GTAForums.com  »  GTA Series  »  GTA San Andreas  »  Gameplay 
   GTA: San Andreas 


 
 GUIDES, WALKTHROUGHS, AND USEFUL LINKS: 
 Girlfriends · Supply Lines · Clothes · Gang Territory · Car Mods · Burglaries · Schools · Stunting · Vehicles · Weapons 
 Modding questions belong in the modding forums! 
 

 Pages: (3)  [1]   2   3   ( Go to first unread post ) 

 
 GTA: San Andreas Girlfriends Guide
 All you need to know to get 100% Track this topic | Email this topic | Print this topic 
   
 ***GTA***    Posted: Friday, Jul 22 2005, 22:03 

GTAuthority
 
 Group: BUSTED! 
Joined: Jun 29, 2005

 

 
 
 GTA: San Andreas Girlfriends Guide 

 --------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Girlfriend Overview
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

During the mission Burning Desire you will need to rescue a girl from a burning building. After you do this, she becomes your girlfriend whether you like it or not. This is CJ&apos;s first girlfriend, but not the last. You can date up to 6 girls in total all at the same time, if you want.

Each girl becomes available as you progress through the game but not all of them are aquired through missions. Some of them can be found around San Andreas and it is up to you to meet each girl&apos;s tastes. We&apos;ll go into that in more detail later in this guide.

 --------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Finding a Girlfriend
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

First off, you have to find them. Denise Robinson and Millie Perkins will pose no problem, because you meet these girls during missions. The others however take a bit more searching.

Below is the locations of each girlfriend, not found during missions. Each girl has a blue arrow above their heads and will be standing around doing various things, like talking to someone or shooting a gun.

 --------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Sex Appeal
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

Sex appeal is very important when getting a girlfriend and turning up to a date. Most of the sex appeal is achieved through the clothing, tattoos and haircut CJ has. But pulling up in a car with high sex appeal also contributes well. To boost your sex appeal I would sagest to get Comet, Cheetah, Turismo, Bullet or Infernus before going to the date. They are real sex appeal boosters, Comet is the most!

Collecting all Oysters also will boost your sex appeal so you don&apos;t have to worry about meeting girl&apos;s standards.

 --------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Dating Progress
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

Once you start dating a girl, your initial progress with her will be 15%. This will go up when you date her with a successful date. It will go down, if you dont date her, or a date goes badly.

Each girl has their own unique favourite type of date (which we will go into later in the guide), but each girl likes flowers. Flowers add a tiny amount of progress to the date and can be found all over san andreas, but later in this guide i will show you the nearest flowers to the girlfriends home. (to give flowers, select them from your weapons and go up to her and press L1. You may need to press it several times)

So why should you bother progressing with girlfriends? Well each girl offers rewards for higher dating progression, which will be detailed later.

 --------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Successful Dating
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

Successful dates depend on a number of factors. Firstly the condition in which CJ arrives on the date. Make sure CJ has high sex appeal and make sure your car isnt a wreck either.

There are several types of dates, depending on what girl you are dating. There are drinking dates, food dates, dancing dates and driving dates. When you meet your girl, she will tell you what she wants to do. If it&apos;s a drinking/food/dancing date, icons will appear on the map to show you where the locations of these places are. Driving dates depend on which girl you are dating, but can range from cruising about, driving fast as possible or driveby&apos;s.

Whatever date you take your girl on, DONT WASTE HER. You might expect her to appear again, but she doesnt. Once she&apos;s dead, she&apos;s dead. Excluding Denise, Barbara and Millie. It was discovered that you can&quot;re-meet&quot;those girls after killing any of them, but your progress will return to zero and you will have to start from the scratch. If you wasted Helena, Michelle or Katie and you want any of them back, then there is only one way to do it, collect 50 Oysters. All of the girlfriends you killed would come back to life and you could date them once again.

 --------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Abnormal ways to fail a date
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

 Abandoning Her: If you get too far away, you will fail.
 Abuse: If you attack your girlfriend, you fail. Keep it up after the date while she is running around and she will die.
 Dying: If you get wasted on a date, you lose progress
 Ending a date below her standards: The only way for this to occur is if you get fattened up just enough from a meal on an eating date. Yes, it does give you fat. This is very uncommon though, so don&apos;t worry about it.
 Girlfriend dies without abuse: This is hard to pull off, because if you try to trick someone into attacking your girlfriend, the person will probably hit you before he can hit her. And if you get attacked on a date, your girlfriend attacks the ones who are attacking you. The easiest way is to take Denise into Balla territory and let her shoot a Balla in a vehicle. The Balla will get out, run over to your car and pull Denise out. She will just stand there as the Balla empties a few rounds into her. Eventually, she will die and you will lose progress.

 --------------------------------------------------------------------------------
The Girls
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

 Denise Robinson 

 Occupation: Gang Girl
 Location: Do the mission Burning Desire and you will meet denise and she will become your girlfriend in that mission.
 First Appearance: In the mission Burning Desire.
 Tastes: She doesnt seem to be bothered about CJ&apos;s appearance as you meet this girl in a mission.
 At Home: Come by her house after 16:00 hours.
 Date she likes: If she asks to do a driveby, go into enemy gang territories and try to find some enemy gang members. She will lean out the window and shoot at them when you get close. Keep doing this until she wants to go home. If she asks for a food date, take her to the cluckin bell south of her house.
 Invites you in for&quot;coffee&quot;: After 40-50% progress
 Rewards: After 50% progress with denise, the green hustler parked outside her house becomes unlocked, but if you get a tractor or tow truck, you can drag the hustler to your garage and unlock it that way. After 100% progress you will get a pimp suit.

 

 Helena Wankstein 

 Occupation: NRA Nut
 Location: Go to the small town of blueberry and find ammunation. If she is there at that time, you will here her firing a gun at a target range beside ammunation up some steps.
 First Appearance: Because her pickup point is in the badlands, she doesnt come availabe for dating until you unlock San Fierro and the Badlands
 Tastes: Doesnt like much muscle or fat. Make sure CJ has less than 25% muscle and as little fat as possible, but make sure he has alot of sex appeal at the same time. Get a nice bike and ride it up to her on the balcony and get off it to ask her for a date. This will give you a little bit extra sex appeal.
 At Home: Come by her house after 14:00 hours.
 Date she likes: Helena likes to eat in restaurants and the closest place to take her is the reastaurant in Rodeo, Los Santos. If she wants a driving date, drive slowly because she doesnt like speed.
 Invites you in for&quot;coffee&quot;: After 70% progress
 Rewards: Right from the moment you start dating her, a Bandito appears at her farm. Alsoa flamethrower, chainsaw, molotov cocktails, and a pistol appear in a shed next to the farm building. At 50% progress with Helena, it is reported that you get the keys to the bandito, but actually, you can drive the bandito from the moment it spawns there. At 100% you get country style clothes (oooo how rewarding). Overall, there is not much point in dating her to 100%, but just going out with gives you a Bandito.

 

 Michelle Cannes 

 Occupation: Mechanic
 Location: Enter the driving school and she can be found inside talking to someone.
 First Appearance: As soon as you can get into the driving school
 Tastes: She likes a fat man, so get CJ up to at least 50% fat (a few visits to a fast food restaurant is all this may take. Eat 10 portions of food and no more to gain maximum fat per day. If you eat more than 10 portions, CJ will puke and lose all the fat gained.)
 At Home: Just after 00.00 hours. (it appears as though it&apos;s difficult to catch Michelle in. Lot&apos;s of people have reported her to be&apos;never in&apos;and I myself have had trouble catching her in. Keep trying though, she will eventually be at home).
 Date she likes: She really likes drinking dates so take her to one of those, if she wants that kind of date. Sometimes she&apos;ll want you to drive fast, so do that but try not to crash. There is also a special type of date that involves Michelle driving the car instead of CJ. When on this type of date, Michelle will drive and you can control the camera. Dont get out the car though otherwise it will fail the date.
 Invites you in for&quot;coffee&quot;: After 40% progress
 Rewards: As soon as you start dating her, you can use the garage next to her apartment, which acts as a pay n spray only it&apos;s free. After 50% progress, the monster truck that spawns next to her apartment becomes unlocked and at 100% you get the racing suit outfit. Overall, she&apos;s worth going out with for the monster truck and the free pay n spray, but as for the suit, it doesnt seem worth it.

 

 Katie Zhan 

 Occupation: Nurse
 Location: At the north east corner of the golf course in San Fierro, katie is practicing Marital arts near some bushes. You should be able to see her easily from the road.
 First Appearance: As soon as you have access to San Fierro
 Tastes: Lot&apos;s of muscle and lots of sex appeal. Try to aim for about 75% muscle or more.
 At Home: Just after 12.00 hours
 Date she likes: If she requests a food date, take her to the diner just north of her house. If she requests a drive, then you&apos;ll have to cruise around. Take her to china town to increase her fun meter quicker.
 Invites you in for&quot;coffee&quot;: about 50% progression in dating.
 Rewards: Dating Katie allows you to come out of hospital with your weapons, which is cool enough reason to date her. At 50% you will be able to unlock the hearse outside her house (dont ask me why there is hearse outside her house) and at 100% you will unlock the Medic uniform.

 

 Barbara Schternvart 

 Occupation: Cop
 Location: Find the sheriffs building in El Quebrados, The desert. She&apos;ll be outside talking to someone.
 First Appearance: As soon as you get access to Las Venturas and the desert.
 Tastes: She likes a fat man, so get CJ up to at least 50% fat (a few visits to a fast food restaurant is all this may take. Eat 10 portions of food and no more to gain maximum fat per day. If you eat more than 10 portions, CJ will puke and lose all the fat gained.)
 At Home: Just after 00.00 hours
 Date she likes: If she wants a food date, take her to the diner just south west of where you pick her up. Ocasionally she will ask to go dancing which is a real pain, because your pretty far from any dance clubs. On driving dates, she will want you to cruise and not speed.
 Invites you in for&quot;coffee&quot;: After 60% progress
 Rewards: A very cool reward when you first start dating her. She is a cop, so when you get busted, you get to keep your weapons and no money is taken from you. At 50% you will get to drive her ranger that spawns outside the sheriffs office. At 100% you will recieve the police uniform in your wardrobe. However, the police uniform does not let you get in the military areas such as the Naval base or restricted area in the desert without getting a wanted level.

 

 Millie Perkins 

 Occupation: Calgula&apos;s Croupier
 Location: You will meet Millie in the mission&apos;Key to her heart&apos;. You will automatically become her boyfriend during this mission.
 First Appearance: During the mission&apos;key to her heart&apos;
 Tastes: Because it&apos;s for a mission, there is no special taste that you need to satisfy in order to go out with her.
 At Home: Just after 12.00 hours
 Date she likes: Take her to a restaurant if she wants a food date. She also likes driving dates that are just cruising around. Wear the gimp suit to a date and she&apos;ll just want to go indoors for some&apos;fiki fiki&apos;(if you dont know what im talking about, dont ask!).
 Invites you in for&quot;coffee&quot;: Wear the gimp suit and you can do it anytime.
 Rewards: Dating Millie is part of the main story. You need to date her enough, in order to get a key card to Caligula&apos;s casino. You will get this key card around 35%. At 50% you can drive her pink Club, which is parked outside her house when she is home. No reward for 100%.

 

 --------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Tips
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

If the girl asks you to go to the club and impress her with your Dance Skills, but you hate to dance and/or club is too far away, just reload your save and next time she will change her mind and ask to go to eat or drive by.

It says that you need at least 50% fat to be able to start dating Barbera and/or Michelle... Now I&apos;m not sure about Michelle, but when I drove up to Barbera on my PCJ, she said I was too skinny... However, next thing I got me a nice car (Comet) which boosted my Sex Appeal to 100%, and she DID accept me!(asks for my number right away... wish it was that easy in real life, eh? )

Dildos and Vibrators are sex toys you can give to your gitlfriends as a present. They do the same effects as a flowers would, but there is no need going across town for dildo or vibrator, unless your gonna beat people with it instead of giving it. There are only one dildo and vibrator that can be picked up without cheats.

The purple double-ended dildo is inside the LSPD shower rooms, Los Santos.
 

The silver vibrator is behine the orange dumpster, Desert.
 

There are more dildos and vibrators, but they can only be accesable when you use the&quot;Slut Magnet&quot;cheat. Kill the hookers and they will drop a variety of sex toys.

&quot;Slut Magnet&quot;cheat:

 PS2: Square, Right, Square, Square, L2, X, Triangle, X, Triangle
 Xbox: X, Right, X, X, White, A, Y, A, Y
 PC: BEKKNQV

 --------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Sex Toys available in the game
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

 

 --------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Girlfriends License Plates
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

Denise = HOMEGIRL
Helena = No License Plate
Michelle = NOS
Katie = TRAUMA
Barbara = CUFFS
Millie = SPANK

 --------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Hot Coffee Mod
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------- 

With this mod you will be able to unlock the uncensored interactive sex-games with your girlfriends in San Andreas. Basically when any of your girlfriends in San Andreas invites you for a Hot Coffee or Something Hot and Wet, you will get a mini sex game instead of that bored camera man movement that you had before. Rockstar build all this stuff in the game, but decided to disable it in their final release for unknown reasons. And now this mod enables these sex-games again, so now you can enjoy the full experience. The mod is available for PC, PS2 and Xbox.

To download the mod simply go to Google or Yahoo and type Hot Coffee mod for PC, PS or Xbox (what ever is your game console). Please note that Hot Coffee Mod is no longer available on GTA Garage, as PatrickW explained: As a sign of support towards RockStar.

This mod is rated 18+



Big thanks to:

IKHAM
BaHaMuT
System Error
Abadede
srg
tommy vercetti guy

and others!

 This post has been edited by ***GTA*** on Thursday, Aug 4 2005, 08:15   
   


   
 simps    Posted: Friday, Jul 22 2005, 22:32 

I&apos;m a twat.
 
 Group: Members 
Joined: Apr 6, 2005

 

 

 
 
 This is a really nice guide. Maybe a mod could somehow merge it with the other Girlfriends Guide.   
   


   
 System Error    Posted: Friday, Jul 22 2005, 23:20 

Oh yeah.
 
 Group: Members 
Joined: Dec 21, 2004

 

 
 
 More additions...

Oysters - Collect all of these and you don&apos;t have to worry about meeting girl&apos;s standards.
Millie - Without the Gimp suit, she will invite you in for sex around 40%.
Abnormal ways to fail a date...

Abandoning her: If you get too far away, you will fail.
Abuse: If you attack your girlfriend, you fail. Keep it up after the date while she is running around and she will die.
Dying: If you get wasted on a date, you lose progress
Ending a date below her standards: The only way for this to occur is if you get fattened up just enough from a meal on an eating date. Yes, it does give you fat. This is very uncommon though, so don&apos;t worry about it.
Girlfriend dies without abuse: This is hard to pull off, because if you try to trick someone into attacking your girlfriend, the person will probably hit you before he can hit her. And if you get attacked on a date, your girlfriend attacks the ones who are attacking you. The easiest way is to take Denise into Balla territory and let her shoot a Balla in a vehicle. The Balla will get out, run over to your car and pull Denise out. She will just stand there as the Balla empties a few rounds into her. Eventually, she will die and you will lose progress.   
   


   
 thedude777    Posted: Saturday, Jul 23 2005, 02:32 

Did I say that out loud?
 
 Group: Members 
Joined: Mar 10, 2005

 

 

 
 
 
 QUOTE (simps@Jul 22 2005, 15:32) This is a really nice guide. Maybe a mod could somehow merge it with the other Girlfriends Guide. 

 No, I think it should REPLACE the other guide. The other one isn&apos;t really helpful.

But those are weird maps... 


 QUOTE Rewards: After 50% progress with denise, the green hustler parked outside her house becomes unlocked, but if you get a tractor or tow truck, you can drag the hustler to your garage and unlock it that way. After 100% progress you will get a pimp suit. Seeing as you get one later in the game much more easily, there doesnt seem much point in dating this girl. 


 No...you get a Gimp suit later in the game...not a pimp suit. The only way to get a pimp suit is to acheive 100% with Denise. 


 QUOTE Tastes: She likes a fat man, so get CJ up to at least 50% fat (a few visits to a fast food restaurant is all this may take. Eat 10 portions of food and no more to gain maximum fat per day. If you eat more than 10 portions, CJ will puke and lose all the fat gained.) 


 CJ can eat 11 meals a day. The 12th will make him puke, and lose all the fat he gained that day. 

 This post has been edited by thedude777 on Saturday, Jul 23 2005, 02:45   
   


   
 ***GTA***    Posted: Saturday, Jul 23 2005, 07:39 

GTAuthority
 
 Group: BUSTED! 
Joined: Jun 29, 2005

 

 
 
 Actually you can get pimp suite after compliting Pimpimg mission, which you need to do for 100% game complition. Whats wrong with the maps?   
   


   
 F-s-X    Posted: Saturday, Jul 23 2005, 08:31 

Kaikei, Chi Shingi Meiyo
 
 Group: Members 
Joined: Feb 19, 2005

 

 

 
 
 
 QUOTE (***GTA*** @ Jul 23 2005, 10:39) Actually you can get pimp suite after compliting Pimpimg mission, which you need to do for 100% game complition. Whats wrong with the maps? 

 No you don&apos;t, you get money when you are with a hooker.

But nice guide, i like the maps.   
   


   
 Superilldude    Posted: Saturday, Jul 23 2005, 09:43 

.
 
 Group: Members 
Joined: Jan 22, 2003

 

 

 
 
 Well done, I didn&apos;t know where Barbara was located before 

STICKY+ or MERGE STICKY +   
   


   
 ***GTA***    Posted: Saturday, Jul 23 2005, 13:33 

GTAuthority
 
 Group: BUSTED! 
Joined: Jun 29, 2005

 

 
 
 Glad to help   
   


   
 srg    Posted: Saturday, Jul 23 2005, 16:31 

Bored Ass
 
 Group: Members 
Joined: Mar 26, 2005

 

 

 
 
 Hey, I never realized ( it was my first time with her and haven&apos;t read it yet if ever ) that Michelle is a car thief too!After getting her 100%, she once asked me again to trust her with driving the Buffalo i jacked to date her. Then when CJ got off , she sped away with the car and there was a message that went something like&quot;she stole your car. You two have much in common&quot;or something like that. But when I pressed triangle (PS2), she stopped then I found the car there left by michelle. She was nowhere around and I got something like minus 10%. What&apos;s that for supposed to be? 

After that I always park my car facing the stairs or the garage whenever she asks CJ to drive his car 

Is there something wrong with the data\programming or whatever re these girlfriends? One seemingly glitch with at least some of them (Denise, helena&amp;michelle ) was that your proofed cars would turn normal if you ever used any for them girls. My BFEP elegy, Fireproof cheetah, BFP Tahoma were once victims of these bitches 
Michelle made my HPV 1000 bike disappear from my Paradiso garage after CJ and her passed bt there on a driving date.

 This post has been edited by srg on Saturday, Jul 23 2005, 17:17   
   


   
 ***GTA***    Posted: Saturday, Jul 23 2005, 19:21 

GTAuthority
 
 Group: BUSTED! 
Joined: Jun 29, 2005

 

 
 
 Your date was a falier so -10% as you made her unhappy Just reload the game and do it again. Use the guide to help you out   
   


   
 Fragger.    Posted: Saturday, Jul 23 2005, 21:38 

Vato Loco
 
 Group: Members 
Joined: Jun 18, 2005

 

 

 
 
 
 QUOTE (***GTA*** @ Jul 22 2005, 22:03) Michelle Cannes 

 Location: Enter the driving school and she can be found inside talking to someone.
 First Appearance: As soon as you can get into the driving school
 Tastes: She likes a fat man, so get CJ up to at least 50% fat (a few visits to a fast food restaurant is all this may take. Eat 10 portions of food and no more to gain maximum fat per day. If you eat more than 10 portions, CJ will puke and lose all the fat gained.)
 At Home: Just after 00.00 hours. (it appears as though it&apos;s difficult to catch Michelle in. Lot&apos;s of people have reported her to be&apos;never in&apos;and I myself have had trouble catching her in. Keep trying though, she will eventually be at home).
 Date she likes: She really likes drinking dates so take her to one of those, if she wants that kind of date. Sometimes she&apos;ll want you to drive fast, so do that but try not to crash. There is also a special type of date that involves helena driving the car instead of CJ. When on this type of date, helena will drive and you can control the camera. Dont get out the car though otherwise it will fail the date. 

Huh? Helena?
Great guide otherwise.   
   


   
 ***GTA***    Posted: Saturday, Jul 23 2005, 21:47 

GTAuthority
 
 Group: BUSTED! 
Joined: Jun 29, 2005

 

 
 
 Helena comes before Michelle What do you mean   
   


   
 Abadede    Posted: Saturday, Jul 23 2005, 21:57 

Snitch
 
 Group: Members 
Joined: Mar 4, 2003

 

 

 
 
 
 QUOTE (***GTA*** @ Jul 22 2005, 17:03) Whatever date you take your girl on, DONT WASTE HER. You might expect her to appear again, but she doesnt. Once she&apos;s dead, she&apos;s dead. 

Excluding Denise and Millie, I&apos;ve found that you can&quot;re-meet&quot;a girl after killing her.   
   


   
 tommy vercetti guy    Posted: Saturday, Jul 23 2005, 22:00 

A fellow canadian
 
 Group: BUSTED! 
Joined: Mar 3, 2005

 

 

 
 
 Other Girlfriend Guide = In The Fireplace
This Girlfriend Guide = On The Bookshelf


Some suggestions......

-talk about the girlfriend 2-player
-how to and what happens when you treat girlfriends badly
-what is the retarted hot coffe mod and how it works
-when other girlfriends catch you with another girlfriend
-what is the license plate on the girlfriends car
-giving dlidos   
   


   
 ***GTA***    Posted: Saturday, Jul 23 2005, 23:21 

GTAuthority
 
 Group: BUSTED! 
Joined: Jun 29, 2005

 

 
 
 I am taking your ideas on board   
   


   
 adamcs    Posted: Saturday, Jul 23 2005, 23:28 

Happy as larry that V has been announced.
 
 Group: Network Admins 
Joined: Jul 28, 2002

 

 

 
 
 Nice guide. And yea, this is far more in-depth than the other one, so I&apos;ll replace the link at the top of the page with this one.   
   


   
 srg    Posted: Sunday, Jul 24 2005, 06:23 

Bored Ass
 
 Group: Members 
Joined: Mar 26, 2005

 

 

 
 
 
 QUOTE (Abadede @ Jul 23 2005, 21:57) 
 QUOTE (***GTA***@Jul 22 2005, 17:03) Whatever date you take your girl on, DONT WASTE HER. You might expect her to appear again, but she doesnt. Once she&apos;s dead, she&apos;s dead. 

Excluding Denise and Millie, I&apos;ve found that you can&quot;re-meet&quot;a girl after killing her. 

Barbara too. Once, just for fun I torched her with a flamethrower, after she died I found her again later in the same spot, but I started back from zero.   
   


   
 chenjx1983    Posted: Sunday, Jul 24 2005, 08:15 

N.E.R.V
 
 Group: Members 
Joined: Aug 27, 2004

 

 

 
 
 beautiful guide man, but just one thing to point out:


 QUOTE Location: Do the mission Burning Desire and you will meet denise and become her girlfriend in that mission. 


C.J. become here g/f? LOL   
   


   
 ***GTA***    Posted: Sunday, Jul 24 2005, 09:18 

GTAuthority
 
 Group: BUSTED! 
Joined: Jun 29, 2005

 

 
 
 Thanks chenjx1983 for leting me know 

 This post has been edited by ***GTA*** on Sunday, Jul 24 2005, 12:30   
   


   
 tommy vercetti guy    Posted: Monday, Jul 25 2005, 01:14 

A fellow canadian
 
 Group: BUSTED! 
Joined: Mar 3, 2005

 

 

 
 
 HOLY sh*t!
THIS GUIDE REPLACED THE OTHER ONE!?!?
Bet the original girlfriend thread and thread starter is pissed! 

Anyways, here are the license plates....
Denise = HOMEGIRL
Helena = (didnt date yet)
Michelle = NOS
Katie = (cant remember, who takes that car for a drive anyways?)
Barbara = CUFFS
Millie = SPANK
Anyone knows what Helena&apos;s and Kaie&apos;s license plates are, tell us!

   
   


   
1 User(s) are reading this topic (1 Guests and 0 Anonymous Users)
 0 Members: « Next Oldest | Gameplay | Next Newest » 
 Pages: (3)  [1]   2   3  

 
 Search topic for posted by (exact match) 
   Close Topic Options Track this topic 
 Receive email notification when a reply has been made to this topic and you are not active on the board. 

 Subscribe to this forum 
 Receive email notification when a new topic is posted in this forum and you are not active on the board. 

 Download / Print this Topic 
 Download this topic in different formats or view a printer friendly version. 

   
 
       
 
 . Powered by Invision Power Board (U) v1.3 Final©2003  IPS, Inc. 
Content and Design©2001-2012  GTA Network.com
	</body>
</document>
