<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000039" url="http://www.daniweb.com/software-development/cpp/threads/238967/structures-best-use" time="2012-07-12-15:13" support="4" score="0.014360322480336812" bingtitle="Structures best use? | DaniWeb" webtitle="Structures best use? | DaniWeb">
			<query id="000275" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000252" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000267" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000279" bing-rank="59"/>
	<description>The data file is a menu of food items at a fast food restaurant. ... of all the menu items selected for the order. You ... Confirm Password:</description>
	<body>
		We&apos;re a community of 958K IT Pros here for help, advice, solutions, professional growth and fun. Join us! 
 Join DaniWeb Member Login Log In with Facebook 
 957,371 Members— Technology Publication meets Social Media &lt;DaniWeb&gt;®IT Discussion Community Technology Publication meets Social Media 
 Hardware&amp;Software Software Development Web Development Internet Marketing Business Exchange Community Center 
 Username: Password: Lost login information? Software Development &gt; C++ &gt; Structures best use? Have a different question to ask? Start New Discussion Reply to this Discussion 2 Years Ago 0 
Structures best use?
 
I have to write a program for class that will read a datafile into a structure. The data file is a menu of food items at a fast food restaurant. Basically simulate a cash register

I created a structure menu[26] which includes the following elements
key - a,b,c,d etc.
item - hotdog, hamburger etc.
price.

My question is this. What is the best way to create the customers order.

So far I have come up with this
 while ((keystroke=getch())!=&apos;=&apos;)
 {
 cin&gt;&gt;keystroke;
 for (int i=0;i&lt;26;i++)
 if (keystroke=menu[i].key)
 {
 menu[i].item=order[i].item;
 menu[i].price=order[i].price;
 }//end if
 }//end while 

However I know that if the customer orders more than soda for example the order will only contain one of that item.

Can anyone suggest a better approach?
 scott6480 Newbie Poster 12 posts since Nov 2009 Reputation Points: 10 Solved Threads: 0   2 Years Ago 0 
why don&apos;t you create a struct called menuitem that can store the description/price/etc of one item. Then make an array of all the menu items selected for the order. You could call up the menuitem with a unique key (1,2,3,4...} stored within the struct menuitem.
 jonsca Quantitative Phrenologist Team Colleague 5,621 posts since Sep 2009 Reputation Points: 1,165 Solved Threads: 581   
This article has been dead for over three months
 Post: Markdown Syntax: Formatting Help Bold Italic Code Inline Code Link Quote Heading Sub-Heading # List •List Undo Redo Insert Code Snippet (Alt+I) Join our community of 957,371 members to contribute Username: Password: Confirm Password:   Email: Confirm Email: You Software Development &gt; C++ Tweet   ©2012 DaniWeb®LLC Home | About Us | Contact Us | Terms of Service | Advertising Opportunities RSS Feed | Donate   
 Recently Updated Articles Join the DaniWeb Community
	</body>
</document>
