<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000390" url="http://www.dougshaw.com/essays/olive.html" time="2012-07-12-15:35" support="80" score="0.2296911558701586" bingtitle="Don&apos;t eat at the Olive Garden - Doug Shaw&apos;s Home Page" webtitle="Don&apos;t eat at the Olive Garden">
			<query id="000767" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="000772" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="000856" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000115" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="001339" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="001200" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000045" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000867" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000351" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="000545" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000108" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="001204" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="001111" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="001267" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="001518" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="001337" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000930" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000925" bing-rank="249"/>
			<query id="001173" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="001331" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000891" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="001180" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="001214" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="001120" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="000359" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="001399" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000860" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000853" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000248" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="001330" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000365" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000353" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000859" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="000733" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="001394" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="001205" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="001344" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="001126" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000363" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="001220" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000870" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="001457" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000234" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="001270" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000357" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="001207" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000373" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="001389" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="001023" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000765" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="001112" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000861" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="001408" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000367" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="001048" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="001110" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="001283" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="000923" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000246" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="001143" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000865" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000529" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="001016" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000358" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="001396" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="001275" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="001118" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="001219" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000374" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000608" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000514" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="000521" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000875" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="001403" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="001300" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="001127" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="001488" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="001268" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="001395" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="001519" bing-rank="30"/>
	<description>Many of the tackier restaurants nowadays give you a second menu, with special items that can&apos;t be put on the regular menu, because they weren&apos;t cleared with corporate ...</description>
	<body>
		Why
 you should NOT eat at                       The
 Olive Garden      
 
 When you&apos;re here, you&apos;re family. The kind of
family that we won&apos;t fucking leave alone until you buy some wine from us. 

I used to like eating at the Olive Garden . Why not? The food is okay, the
prices are okay, the commercials are cute, and the service is good. I used to go
there with my girlfriend periodically, get some pasta and sauce or some lasagna, and
mayhap a piece of cheesecake. So what&apos;s not to like? 

Have you been there lately? It&apos;s different now. 

It used to be that the purpose of the Olive Garden was to sell you some food and a nice
atmosphere, and keep things pleasant enough to get you to want to come back another time
and give them more money. No problem there. It was never a f a n c y restaurant, but it tried to be
nicer than a Perkins or a Chilis. And it succeeded. A very mellow place to go,
where you could overeat a little and relax.

As I said, it&apos;s different now. The present purpose of the Olive Garden is to sell
you their wine. That&apos;s it.

(I am basing the following on my recent experiences in Cedar Falls. I am
assuming, that since their owner, Darden Restaurants , is a 3.7
billion dollar corporation, they don&apos;t let store policies vary too much)

You walk in, and you are facing a bar, with bottles of wine prominently displayed,
drawing your attention to the blackboard with the wine specials written on it. No
big deal so far. I like bars, and wine specials are displayed at even the finest
restaurants. And then the hostess brings you to your table. The first thing
that strikes you about the Olive Garden is the decor. It is decorated in bottles of
wine. There may be frescos somewhere behind the bottles, but you don&apos;t see them. Wine bottles everywhere you look. Not interesting bottles, just the house
wine which, by the way, is for sale with your meal. I&apos;m not doing it justice - I&apos;m
not writer enough to do it justice.

You sit at your table. There are wine-glasses in front of you, and the hostess
asks you what you want to drink. Assume you don&apos;t say&quot;wine&quot;right
away. No longer your friend, she leaves you to your fate. Worry not, for soon
your waitperson appears, carrying the bottle of wine you sort of remember not ordering. &quot;Hello. I am Merlot, your waitperson. Can I pour you a glass of
wine?&quot; Assume that you say&quot;no.&quot; With a sigh, the wineglasses
are taken off your table. The message is clear. &quot;You blew it,
fuckpuppy, and now I take your wineglasses from you.&quot;

But then you get your two menus. TWO menus? Yes. Many of the tackier
restaurants nowadays give you a second menu, with special items that can&apos;t be put on the
regular menu, because they weren&apos;t cleared with corporate headquarters. But as you
look at the wonderfully photographed second menu, you notice something odd. Every
item on the second menu also appears on the regular menu. Every. Single. Item. Well, then, why have a second menu which is just a proper subset
of the first, albeit with more expensive photography? Easy: Because the second
menu has pictures of glasses of wine with all the dishes, and advice about which wine goes
best with each item. Yes, it is a nice big glossy ad for the wines, which you get
along with your menu, which itself has a wine list and lots of urgings. The last
time I was there, they went to the extent of smashing a bottle on the floor so the entire
section smelled like wine, but that could have been an accident.

I don&apos;t mind tacky places. I mind places that hadn&apos;t been tacky, that don&apos;t have
to be tacky, but choose to be.

The present purpose of the Olive Garden is to sell you their wine. That&apos;s
it. The food and the commercials exist to get you there to sell you wine. The
chairs are there so you have a place to sit while you buy their wine. The tables are
there so the wine has a place to be. The air-conditioner is there so the wine
doesn&apos;t go bad. (They don&apos;t want the wine to go bad, because they would sell less. If it still sold, they wouldn&apos;t care if it went bad. The point is to get you
to buy it.)  

I don&apos;t know why a fairly inviting restaurant chain chose to transform itself to a
hard-sell restricted-selection liquor store. Perhaps the&quot;kindly grandpa&quot;in the commercials owns a winery and is Connected. Or, more likely, this
conversation took place:
 
 CEO of DARDEN RESTAURANTS: Things are going well. Our&quot;Red Lobster&quot;restaurants are doing
 well. Our&quot;Bahama Breeze&quot;restaurants allow people to experience the
 delights of visiting the Caribbean without having to worry about interacting with
 Caribbean people. And our&quot;Olive Gardens&quot;are successfully
 matching a dinner-house concept against the independently-owned restaurants that used to
 be the mainstay of Italian dining . But if only we could make more money...
  GUY WITH MBA: Well, you have a huge mark up on your wine. Right now you have a bunch of
 customers who will never buy wine. You can&apos;t do much about them. You have a
 bunch of customers who will order wine no matter what, because they like it. We are
 fine on that front. But there are a few people who are so incredibly suggestible and
 stupid, that they wouldn&apos;t normally buy wine, but they will if you badger them about it. So I say that you change your restaurants from a&quot;pleasant dining
 experience&quot;to an&quot;annoying as bugfuck we will get you to buy our god damn wine
 sellfest.&quot; You may make some more money that way.
  CEO of DARDEN RESTAURANTS: Okay. 
 
I have an acquaintance who is a serious alcoholic. As soon as you walk in the
door, he is waving a bottle at you, trying to get you to have a drink with him so he has
an excuse to have several. Even at his worst he is not as obnoxious as the Olive
Garden is. As I said, I am not a good enough writer to properly convey the cheesy
hard-sell atmosphere of the new Olive Garden. But I am a good enough gambler to
issue to you the Doug Shaw Olive Garden Challenge: 

Next time one of their&quot;When you&apos;re here, you&apos;re family&quot;ads puts you and
your friends/family in the mood for their fast-food-car-dealership restaurant, move your
pasta-deprived ass to your phone book, and find the address for your local, independently
owned Italian restaurant. (Currently, one-third of all Italian
restaurants are Olive Gardens. This means two-thirds aren&apos;t. Luck will be with
you) Make a reservation if they take them. It couldn&apos;t hurt to tell them Doug
Shaw sent you. When you go, pay attention to the decor, the food quality, and save
the receipt. Dinner may wind up taking 15 minutes longer than it did at the Olive
Garden. Oh no! You&apos;ve spent an extra 15 minutes with a loved one instead of
watching TV! Make sure to note how much the final bill was.

If for some reason you then go to the Olive Garden again, take note of how it is
different. After all is settled, look at your bill. Notice that it wasn&apos;t that
different than the local place&apos;s. Recall how refreshing the Mom n&apos; Pop place was,
without the stink of Darden Marketing Consultants all over the designs of
everything. Recall how the food and wine at the local place was yummy plentiful
without being pushed at you. Recall how happy they were to see you there.

...and recall the Doug Shaw Olive Garden Challenge . If you had a better time at the local restaurant, email me and let
me know. And if I am in town, I will let you buy me a glass of wine there. If
you honestly thought that the Olive Garden offered you a better dining experience, I will
let you buy me dinner there, and I will buy you a glass of their wine. 

 Now, seriously: Let us not let the crass and tacky defeat
the classy and quality-y. The Olive Garden used to be a nice place. It isn&apos;t
any more. Let&apos;s all go somewhere else for dinner tonight. 

 Click here for Olive Garden&apos;s response!
 

 Update! Click here for some reader 
 feedback I&apos;ve received about this page, including some from Olive Garden management. 
 (Updated 10/2/2002)
 

 Olive Garden partnered with Coke for a&quot;H-2-NO&quot;campaign! The Coke corporate website details how managers were given bonuses 
 and trips if they could demonstratably decrease water consumption at their restaurants. Various techniques were taught to waitstaff to discourage customers from drinking 
 water. (Some time later, the campaign was amended to allow patrons to 
 drink&quot;Dasani&quot;water, which is Coke&apos;s bottled water) Coca Cola 
 took the pages about it down as soon as smart-alecks like me started drawing 
 attention to it. But, just for you, here 
 they are . Here are two links that give some 
 more information. 

 Respond via email 
 Respond via the bulletin 
 board 
Back to Doug&apos;s Essays 
Back to Doug&apos;s Home Page 
 
 Douglas J. Shaw, 2001 
 
 

 Doug Code 6/2001: eifg:   xqu ji qkcrl-himpoifp hcmmowcrp rohk bi kcb gcu hcbcbimohp? wdcpqi:   wkhcfpk lku sfrsorr lkon tomotft nkhxonktkmbp is snfobp cme ykgkbcwrkp. 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

I didn&apos;t make this part up. Darden restaurants are glad that they are putting
your happy local family-owned restaurant out of business. Check out their website if you don&apos;t
believe me.

 

 

 

 

 

 

I didn&apos;t make this part up, either. Darden restaurants brag about this fact on their website .
	</body>
</document>
