<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000053" url="http://blackberry-applications.toptenreviews.com/health-and-fitness/fast-food-calorie-counter-review.html" time="2012-07-12-15:14" support="1" score="0.0029276935287134553" bingtitle="Fast Food Calorie Counter 2012 - TopTenREVIEWS" webtitle="Fast Food Calorie Counter 2012 - TopTenREVIEWS">
			<query id="001032" bing-rank="50"/>
	<description>Application Aims: Make Better Fast Food Decisions Reviewer’s Comments As if watching what we eat isn’t challenging enough, there seems to be a fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		Application Aims: Make Better Fast Food Decisions

 Reviewer’s Comments 
As if watching what we eat isn’t challenging enough, there seems to be a fast food restaurant everywhere we turn. Sure they’re handy and the fare can be tempting, but their menus are also notorious for featuring high-calorie, high-fat foods. The Fast Food Calorie Counter application is a tool that helps you to make wise selections even when you find yourself in the fast food line.

Fast Food Calorie Counter is organized around the menus of forty-one fast food chains. Its list includes ubiquitous burger outlets like McDonald’s and Burger King, chicken chains including KFC, Church’s and Popeye’s, and pizza giants Pizza Hut, Papa John’s, Sbarro and others. It also features large but more regional outlets like Jack-In-The-Box and Hardee’s. In all, there are more than 4,700 menu items rated.

When you choose a restaurant, you’ll be presented with a listing of most of its menu selections. You can sort the menus by category, name, or calorie content as well as by fat, carbohydrate, fiber or protein level. For any selected menu item, you can select the View More Info/Chart option and you’ll be given a graphic breakdown of the item’s total calories and grams of fat, carbohydrates, fiber, and protein.

The Fast Food Calorie Counter application won’t rid the world of high calorie, low nutrition foods but it does give you a tool that will help in making choices that won’t sabotage your best efforts to eat properly. Whether you have the opportunity to plan your destination in advance or find yourself in line making a last minute decision, this handy guide is as close as your BlackBerry. It’s well worth its $9.95 price if it saves you from putting on unwanted pounds or jeopardizing your health.

Check out our complete lineup of BlackBerry health and fitness apps as well as our other application reviews to help you get the most out of your BlackBerry smartphone.

 
 Fast Food Calorie Counter Screenshots See All (5) images    in image gallery or click the thumbnail to view at 100%   Share Newsletters Share this [X] del.icio.us Digg StumbleUpon Yahoo! My Web Facebook Google Bookmarks ma.gnolia Newsvine reddit Windows Live Home Software Electronics Web Services Mobile Appliances Auto Tech Science Tech Small Business Careers Entertainment Video Health and Fitness Blackberry Apps Review Main Categories All Apps Finance Blackberry Apps Health and Fitness Blackberry Apps Productivity Blackberry Apps   Learning Center Recent Topics: Screaming Fun Halloween iPhone Apps Samsung Announces New App Store Green Up Your Life with iPhone Apps See All Topics Newsletters We&apos;ll deliver fresh reviews, articles, tips and deals right to your inbox. New Review Sites DIY Tech Tech of the Month See more... See All (5) images 
Fast Food Calorie Counter 1.20
 Sponsored Ad 
Publisher: Mobigloo LLC

Version: 1.20
 Overall Rating Features Interface Graphics Stability Support Value 
PUBLISHER

$9.95
 Ranked #6 of 10 in Health and Fitness Blackberry Apps. See the side-by-side comparisons . Learn More: Editor Review Specifications Images Feature Checklist Health and Fitness Blackberry Apps Learning Center 
Fast Food Calorie Counter Review
 Next Steps Research the product (Still need more information? See our side-by-side comparisons .) Find the lowest price for Fast Food Calorie Counter. Make the purchase. Ready to buy now?   $9.95   Company Pages Company Info 
 About The Site 
 Contact Us 
 Advertise with Us 
 Using our Content 
 Licensing and Reprints 
 Privacy Policy 
 Sitemap TechMediaNetwork Brands TechMediaNetwork TopTenREVIEWS LAPTOP 
 SPACE.com 
 LiveScience TechNewsDaily 
 Newsarama 
 Life&apos;s Little Mysteries OurAmazingPlanet iPadNewsDaily BusinessNewsDaily MyHealthNewsDaily SecurityNewsDaily InnovationNewsDaily IT TechNewsDaily Herman Street NorthOrion Join our Mailing List Join our community 
 

 FOLLOW US ON... Copyright©2012 TechMediaNetwork.com 
All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
