<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000296" url="http://www.topix.net/wire/county/brown-ks" time="2012-07-12-15:29" support="1" score="0.0017417676841732265" bingtitle="Brown County Newswire - Topix" webtitle="Brown County Newswire - Topix">
			<query id="001436" bing-rank="165"/>
	<description>Comprehensive Real-Time News Feed for Brown County, KS. ... were bow hunting along the Nemaha-Pottawatomie County line. ... 3 arrested after search warrant near ... 5 Roger Hollister ...</description>
	<body>
		Local News: Germany   

 | 

 Sign Up 

 | 

 Sign In 
 1 2 3 
China
US, China Square Off Over South China Sea 
Mitt Romney
Romney campaign accuses Obama of making false outsourcing clai... 
Health Care
Oct. trial set in Miss. suit over health care law 
 Home Forums Top Stories Popular Local Election Poll US Politics World Sports Entertainment Offbeat Other 
 
Brown County

 News Forums&amp;Polls Real-Time News 
 
Brown County Newswire

Comprehensive Real-Time News Feed for Brown County, KS.
 
Results 1 - 20 of 27 in Brown County, KS

 
 Teens in Amber Alert Case Face Drug, Obstruction Charges w/Photo 

Yesterday | WDAF

... of official duty, possession of marijuana and possession of drug paraphernalia. The charges were filed in Brown County , Kansas. Police in Leavenworth County issued an Amber Alert for Hord on July 5th after Burris allegedly forced her into a car ... Comment? 
 Related Topix: Drugs , Leavenworth County, KS , Leavenworth, KS 
 
 
 House explosion victim identified 

Monday | KSNT-TV Topeka

... s natural gas system. The teenager accused of kidnapping his girlfriend last week will face multiple charges in Brown County and at least one in Leavenworth County. Comment? 
 
Real-Time Twitter Feed
 Click For More &gt;&gt; 
 Teens involved in Amber Alert may face charges 

Monday | The Capital-Journal

Two teens involved in an Amber Alert last week could face several charges in Brown County , where they were found Thursday. Comment? 
 Related Topix: Atchison, KS , Leavenworth, KS , Hiawatha, KS , Drugs 
 
 
 Teens Involved In Amber Alert Both Charged In Brown Co. w/Photo 

Monday Jul 9 | WIBW-TV Topeka

 Brown County Attorney Kevin Hill&apos;s office said Monday that it will file counts Tuesday against Logan Burris for driving on an invalid license, obstruction and possession of marijuana and drug paraphernalia. Comment? 
 Related Topix: Drugs , Leavenworth, KS , Hiawatha, KS 
 
 
 One dead after house explodes in Horton 

Friday Jul 6 | The Capital-Journal

... ermine the cause of the explosion. Attempts to obtain further information from the Horton Police Department and Brown County Sheriff&apos;s Office weren&apos;t successful. Check CJOnline.com for more information as it becomes available. Comment? 
 Related Topix: Horton, KS 
 
 
 Amber Alert cancelled for missing Kansas teen 

Friday Jul 6 | KSNT-TV Topeka

... afternoon is cancelled after the missing girl and man she was believed to be with were spotted in Hiawatha. The Brown County Sheriff&apos;s Office says a woman recognized 16-year-old Jenna Hord and 17-year-old Logan Burris and called officers. The alert ... Comment? 
 Related Topix: Hiawatha, KS 
 
 
 Amber Alert for 16-year-old girl canceled w/Photo 

Thursday Jul 5 | The Capital-Journal

A Kansas Amber Alert issued for a 16-year-old girl last seen Wednesday in Leavenworth was canceled after she and a suspect in her disappearance were located safe Thursday evening in Hiawatha, an official with the Brown County Sheriff&apos;s Office said. 1 comment 
 Related Topix: Leavenworth, KS , Hiawatha, KS , Atchison, KS 
 
 
 Reinhart makes first court appea... 

Jun 6, 2012 | Journal

A 59-year-old New Ulm man facing 16 felony theft counts allegedly involving more than $90,000 in checks written on accounts of the Brown County Agricultural Society and New Ulm Baseball Association accounts since January 2009, made his first appearance Tuesday in Brown County District Court. Comment? 
 Related Topix: New Ulm, MN , Brown County, MN 
 
 
 Slain woman&apos;s ex-husband has probation revoked 

Jun 5, 2012 | The Capital-Journal

... after having his probation revoked a second time on a third-offense driving under the influence conviction. Brown County District Judge John Weingart ruled Monday that Kimmi, of rural Everest, had violated a condition of his probation by testing ... Comment? 
 Related Topix: Horton, KS , Everest, KS , Prison , Atchison County, KS 
 
 
 Slain woman&apos;s ex-husband has probation revoked 

Jun 5, 2012 | The Capital-Journal

... after having his probation revoked a second time on a third-offense driving under the influence conviction. Brown County District Judge John Weingart ruled Monday that Kimmi, of rural Everest, had violated a condition of his probation by testing ... Comment? 
 Related Topix: Horton, KS , Everest, KS , Prison , Atchison County, KS 
 
 
 Murdered Woman&apos;s Ex-Husband Back In Jail w/Photo 

Jun 5, 2012 | WIBW-TV Topeka

 BROWN COUNTY , Kan. -- The ex-husband of murdered Horton woman, Patricia Kimmi, has had his probation revoked for the second time. Comment? 
 Related Topix: Horton, KS 
 
 
 Reinhart faces 16 felony theft c... 

May 25, 2012 | Journal

A 59-year-old New Ulm man faces 16 felony theft counts in a Brown County District Court case involving $91,727.79 in checks payable to himself or his business on the Brown County Agricultural Society account and $7,907.26 in checks issued by himself payable to his business on the New Ulm Baseball Association account. Comment? 
 Related Topix: New Ulm, MN , Brown County, MN 
 
 
 Sleepy Eye woman ordered to pay $10,000 restitution 

May 12, 2012 | Journal

A 49-year-old Sleepy Eye woman originally charged with eight felony counts of financial exploitation of a vulnerable adult and theft received a stay of execution for five years probation Friday in Brown County District Court. Comment? 
 Related Topix: Sleepy Eye, MN , Brown County, MN , Willmar, MN 
 
 
 Picking judges 

May 8, 2012 | Journal

... We have felt that the process works pretty well, and the announcement of three finalists for the vacancy on the Brown County District Court bench is evidence of that. Those interested in the position apply to the Commission on Judicial Selection. ... Comment? 
 
 Atchison Co. Man Likely Facing Attempted Murder Charges w/Photo 

May 3, 2012 | WIBW-TV Topeka

... for an attack that injured a woman and a three month old child. KNZA Radio reports Horton Police and the Brown County Sheriff&apos;s Office were called Wednesday night to a home in Horton. Authorities say the woman was apparently attacked when she ... Comment? 
 Related Topix: Horton, KS , Atchison County, KS 
 
 
 Local Election Wrap-Up 

Apr 3, 2012 | WIBW-TV Topeka

... attendence center and athletic activity sights. The measure passed with 371 voters for and 177 against. And in Brown County , the city of Hiawatha elected Crosby Gernon as mayor with 231 votes. His challenger, Eric Clary, recieved 93. Comment? 
 Related Topix: Jefferson County, KS 
 
 
 Local Election Wrap-Up 

Apr 3, 2012 | WIBW-TV Topeka

... attendence center and athletic activity sights. The measure passed with 371 voters for and 177 against. And in Brown County , the city of Hiawatha elected Crosby Gernon as mayor with 231 votes. His challenger, Eric Clary, recieved 93. Comment? 
 Related Topix: Jefferson County, KS 
 
 
 Kan. custodian called a hero for saving man&apos;s life 

Mar 18, 2012 | The Capital-Journal

... started blowing out from the intense heat. &quot;Denny saved a man&apos;s life and risked his own life in the process,&quot; Brown County Sheriff John Merchant said. &quot;He is definitely a hero.&quot; Merchant identified the man inside the car as Gerry Alkire, 94, of ... Comment? 
 Related Topix: Hiawatha, KS , Fire , Natural Disasters , Wildfire 
 
 
 Kan. Custodian Called A Hero For Saving Man&apos;s Life w/Photo 

Mar 18, 2012 | WIBW-TV Topeka

... inside. He pulled Alkire, who suffered only minor burns, to safety as tires started blowing out from the heat. Brown County Sheriff John Merchant said Gray was a hero for risking his life to save another&apos;s. Comment? 
 Related Topix: Hiawatha, KS , Natural Disasters , Wildfire , Fire 
 
 
 Alvin Emery Dickinson, 91, of rural Hiawatha, KS w/Photo 

Feb 28, 2012 | KQTV

... employed at Ford Motor Co. in Hiawatha. He later farmed and raised livestock and was employed 24 years at the Brown County Co-op Assn. Mr. Dickinson was a longtime member of Bethany United Church of Christ in Hiawatha where he was very active ... Comment? 
 Related Topix: Hiawatha, KS , Leavenworth, KS , Powhattan, KS , Fairview, KS 
 
 
 
 «Previous 1 2 Next» 
 
 Brown County Forum 

 Topic Comments 3 arrested after search warrant near ... 5 Roger Hollister&apos;s Wife Holds Auction 2 US man, Gabe Watson, who has been cha... 1 Brown County collision injures two 1 

 Read all comments | Start a discussion » 
 
 Most Popular 

 Mob of Black Teens Attack Whites in Columbus After Fireworks  -  327 comments Google Launches Gay Rights Campaign  -  101 comments Sex education worries  -  144 comments Palin: Romney needs to set &apos;hair on fire&apos;  -  122 comments US and Mexican relations strain over death involving border patrol  -  82 comments Romney Absorbs Boos, Tells NAACP That Democrats Have Failed Blacks  -  81 comments Without IDs from home, Mexicans struggle in US  -  43 comments Romney to make pitch to black voters at NAACP  -  47 comments Residents angry as Obama plans to close 9 Border Patrol stations across 4 states  -  42 comments W.Va. trooper now involved in 2nd fatal shooting  -  59 comments 
   
 
Germany

 News Forums&amp;Polls Real-Time News 
 
Explore More Topix

 Home Page Forums Top Stories Most Popular Issue Maps US News US Cities list World News World Countries list Politics Celebrities Business Finance Autos Sports 

 Sci-Tech Electronics Entertainment Movies Music Television Video Games Health Life Arts Food Home Travel Offbeat Site Map / All Topics 
 
About Topix

 About Us Media Kit Topix Blog Press Room RSS Newsfeeds Law Enforcement School Officials Cyber-bullying Resources Jobs FAQ Privacy Policy Terms of Service Feedback? Report Abuse? 
 
Local Classifieds&amp;Listings

Reach Local customers. Post a classified listing for your business. Promote job, auto, rental, and local event listings.

 Learn more» 
 
Join the Topix Community

 Create your own profile, complete with quick links to your favorite topics. Personalize your forum posts with your photo and hometown. Exchange Personal Messages with other registered users. 

 Sign up today!» 
 
 Topix Politix» 
 
 Feedback? 
Comments made yesterday: 113,039 •Total comments across all topics: 178,877,163 
 
Copyright©2012 Topix LLC
 
• Flag inappropriate post Post has been flagged for review 

• Send feedback 

• Cancel 
 
 Sci-Tech Video Business Life Health Site Map Recently Visited Brown County, KS 

 NFL MLB NBA NHL NASCAR NCAA Basketball NCAA Football Golf World Soccer More Sports... 

 Books Celebrities Games Movies Music TV Video Games 

 News Forums Dating Crime Obituaries Politics Yellow Pages Local Business Local Sports Shopping Real Estate Jobs 
 
Change location
 
Current location: Germany 
 
New location

 City, ST or ZIP 

 
 
International users, click here .
	</body>
</document>
