<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000136" url="http://forums.musculardevelopment.com/showthread.php/56818-Q-and-A-with-the-PRO-CREATOR-Hany-Rambod/page16" time="2012-07-12-15:20" support="2" score="0.000987958481421313" bingtitle="Q and A with the PRO CREATOR: Hany Rambod" webtitle="Q and A with the PRO CREATOR: Hany Rambod - Page 16">
			<query id="000023" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="001277" bing-rank="234"/>
	<description>... eating stuff I made at home instead of fast food/restaurant stuff. ... plain chicken breast, plain veggies, no condiments ... post workout: 8 oz of top sirloin with 1 cup of ...</description>
	<body>
		Register Help Remember Me? 
 
 Home Supplement Store Forum 
 FAQ Calendar Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 
 View Site Leaders 
 
 News Articles 
 Nutrition Column Archives Chemical Enhancement Supplement Reviews Training Supplements Sex Essay Contests Fat Loss 
 Radio Show MD Videos Contest Coverage 
 Contest Articles&amp;Videos Men Bodybuilding Contest Gallery Men Physique gallery Figure, Fitness and Bikini Gallery Women Bodybuilding Contest Gallery 
 Connect 
 
 Advanced Search 
 
 Forum MD Bodybuilding Forums MD Q&amp;A Q and A with the PRO CREATOR: Hany Rambod 
 
 If this is your first visit, be sure to
 check out the FAQ by clicking the
 link above. You may have to register before you can post: click the register link above to proceed. To start viewing messages,
 select the forum that you want to visit from the selection below. 
 Page 16 of 19 First ... 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 Last 
 Jump to page: 
 Results 256 to 272 of 323 
Thread: Q and A with the PRO CREATOR: Hany Rambod 
 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Display 

 Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 
 September 9th, 2010,  05:38 PM #256 Trapozoid 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Dedicated Noob Join Date Nov 2009 Location Jack Town, NC Posts 16 
 
 Hey Hany,

I&apos;m trying to bring up my back on width and thickness, what type of excercises shoud I be doing? Reply With Quote September 27th, 2010,  01:39 AM #257 Zenith 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Amateur Threat Join Date Sep 2009 Posts 1,548 
 
 Hany
Congrats on the condition you helped Jay and Phil achive at the Olyimpa! They were easily the best conditioned athletes in the show in my opinion.
I was curious as to what methods you use to track your clients progress as they approch a show. Do you like them to get skinfold caliper measurements and body part measurements such as waist, hips, ect? Or do you go just on how they look?
Thanks Reply With Quote November 1st, 2010,  12:23 PM #258 Jake B 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Dedicated Noob Join Date Feb 2010 Posts 28 
 
 hey hany, i have a couple questions. i am a couple weeks into my contest prep and i am thinkning about using a fat burner. so therefore i wouldnt use my preworkout anymore because of the caffiene. so i was thinking about using your EVP for preworkout and Cell KEM for post workout. would that be a good thing to do? my nutrition seems okay for now, and the only supplements i would be using would be the fat burner, EVP, Cell KEM, and a protein powder. so do you think that would be okay to use? i would use it like this: morning cardio- fat burner, 6 hours later- fat burner, pre workout- EVP, post workout Protein shake(at gym), and Cell KEM(drive home). any help is appreciated. thanks Reply With Quote November 2nd, 2010,  09:29 PM #259 Bundy33 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Nobody Join Date Jul 2010 Posts 3 
 
 Hey Hany, just to clarify. When bodybuilders say they eat clean all year, what exactly is that.. to me it was basically eating stuff I made at home instead of fast food/restaurant stuff. Sandwiches, pastas, etc ok? Or is it just very basic stuff like a plain chicken breast, plain veggies, no condiments (ketchup, ranch, etc)? Thanks Reply With Quote November 9th, 2010,  02:21 PM #260 Fleming_08 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Nobody Join Date Nov 2010 Location Kentucky Posts 2 Gender Male 
 
 Hey Hany, I know you get a lot of questions but I really need help.
I&apos;m 160lb and only 5&apos;8 I am having a lot of trouble gaining weight.
I&apos;m a collage student and Im playing for it all myself.
So I don&apos;t have alot of money.
Do you have any tips for me in nutrition and supplementation? Reply With Quote November 19th, 2010,  01:25 PM #261 Gabri 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Beach Body Join Date Dec 2006 Location Italy Posts 762 
 
 New 12 week transformation set to begin jan 2011 



 Your 12-week plan will include: 
- Workouts written by Hany Rambod and tailored to achieve the your best conditioning 
- Cardiovascular training program written by Hany Rambod 
 - Individualized diets designed and written by Hany Rambod to bring you in at your optimum condition 
- Bi-monthly updates and check-ins 

 E-mail Updates/Check ins must be received according to the following schedule: 
1.Saturday January 15, 2011 by 1 pm PST. First Check-in
2.Saturday January 29, 2011 by 1 pm PST
3.Saturday February 12, 2011 by 1 pm PST
4.Saturday February 26, 2011 by 1 pm PST
5.Saturday March 12, 2011 by 1 pm PST
6.Saturday March 26, 2011 by 12 am (midnight) PST Final Check-in

Each e-mail update/check-in submitted must include current pictures (front, side, back full body shots with shorts and no shirt for men and sports bra and shorts for women) and current body stats. Your program will then be updated and sent back by the following Monday morning before 9 am PST (California time).
The winner of FST-7 12-Week Transformation Challenge will be chosen based on the largest percentage of change in his/her physique from the start of the competition to the end. The winner will be announced by April 11, 2011 and will be featured on www.fst-7.com . 
Here is your chance to get in the best shape of your life and to maximize your FST-7 workouts with a customized program from the creator of FST-7, Hany Rambod!
If you have any further questions please e-mail them to fst7training@gmail.com This e-mail address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it .
 Entry Costs for the FST-7 12-Week Transformation Challenge: 
 EARLY BIRDS: $600 for payments received on or before December 11, 2010.
 REGULAR PRICE: $750 for payments received after December 11, 2010.

 ***THE DEADLINE FOR ENTRIES IS DECEMBER 30, 2010.*** 
 ENTRY FORM 


 Please include the following information in your e-mail: 
Full Name
Age
Height
Weight
Body Fat %
Where you are from
Occupation
Daily schedule: what time you sleep, wake-up, meal times, training time, cardio time, work time
Your typical two-day diet
Your current workout regimen including what exercise you do for each body-part, weights used and sets and reps performed
Food Allergies
Injuries or disabilities or exercises you cannot perform
Short-term goals
Long-term goals
Current pictures including front, back, sides
How you heard about the transformation
 Thanks and we look forward to your transformation! 
 -Hany Rambod 
 Reply With Quote November 20th, 2010,  07:52 AM #262 Flavio 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Nobody Join Date Nov 2010 Location Brazil Posts 4 Gender Male 
 
 Mr.Hany Rambod, id&apos;like to know your opinion.. i want to lose the most fat as i can with losing the less muscle(everybody wants that right..).. so i want to know how much cardio should be done daily or weekly in a drug free cutting phase.. what is your recomendation? Reply With Quote November 28th, 2010,  05:23 AM #263 Ahmad_Sawad 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Nobody Join Date Nov 2010 Posts 2 Gender Male 
 
 Hi Hany,

I have 2 questions for you:

1) Are you a fan of HMB?

2) Which speed of lifting do you recommend for maximum growth?
a) Slow lowering and lifting
b) Slow lowering and Fast lifting
c) Fast lowering and lifting Reply With Quote November 30th, 2010,  08:10 PM #264 marlonb2011 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Nobody Join Date Jul 2010 Posts 4 
 
 I have been training for 8 months, I so far have took 3 1 week breaks. I read that you should take a break every 8-16 weeks if your training heavy all the time. Should I
BE TRAINING HEAVY ALL THE TIME or do that light/heavy phase stuff? Thanks Reply With Quote December 23rd, 2010,  09:08 PM #265 Mini ForkliftⓋ 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message Visit Homepage 
 Forum Leader: Powerlifitng&amp;Strongman Join Date Jan 2010 Location S 330 / B 236.5 / D 429 @ 143 bw Posts 14,712 Gender Male 
 
 Hi Hany,

Just fininshed watching your FST-7 DVD now. I&apos;m a PT/PL&apos;ing/Multisport coach so was quite looking forward to hearing what all the hype was about in regards to your new training system.

First impressions after the first watch...

 Hany knows his stuff, some good ideas in there and interesting thoughts on the smaller points of training, such as angling the feet during leg presses&amp;hamstring curls
 Some of the sets are the most intense I have seen Jay train for a while now. The back session looked an absolute killer, and was funny seeing Jay sitting down (because he felt like puking) after training biceps of all bodyparts
 Phil looks an all round nice guy, good fun to be around and no doubt in great shape at a little under 270lb (despite what looked some strangely shaped tri&apos;s)? He seemed initially quite flat and fed up during most of his chest workout and his incline bench had hardly any ROM Do you think that by increasing Phil&apos;s ROM through some of his pressing movements it&apos;s something that could make a further improvement to his physique Hany? Having said all that if he can bring Jay&apos;s kind of intensity to the gym he could well be Jays&apos; main competition over the next couple of years
 All in all I though the system was well explained and was technical enough without being overly complicated. I think it has more of a place for people with a Personal Training background, or the advanced BB&apos;err looking to take it to the next level. I&apos;ll definately be implementing it into my training from the start of 2011 and see how I respond to it.

I&apos;ll have another watch tomorrow but first impressions are...

 PRO: It&apos;s a good, motivating, and educational DVD
 CON: No bonus sections and not an overly long DVD (think it was just over an hour)

Definately worth adding to your collection IMHO, especially if you&apos;re a fan of Jay. Cheers 1st Chch PL&apos;ing Champs 2011
 1st Chch Raw Champs (+3 raw records)
 http://www.youtube.com/user/kiwilifter?feature=mhee 
 
 Reply With Quote December 30th, 2010,  04:38 PM #266 jsanatar 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Spotter Join Date Jan 2010 Posts 130 
 
 hani a quick question about cardio...my schedule has me only able to lift in the am,,,hit the gym at 5 and pound it out...really getting great work and then use the day to work and feed the body...diet is the best its ever been with a shake after training and 3 to 5 solid meals...im having a major problem fitting in cardio and its not that i dony have the time at night its that i cant seem to have the energy at the end of the day...im toast!!! im 52 but i have always been in the gym and i would say im in good shape...what do you think is wrong Reply With Quote January 8th, 2011,  10:43 PM #267 batista 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Spotter Join Date Mar 2010 Posts 107 
 
 hey hany, i am trying to put on some size but are trying to keep bodyfat where is it , so i am not eating carbs at dinner which is my last meal of the day but also my 1st meal after my workout.. what do you think i should do as my progress has stopped. Reply With Quote January 19th, 2011,  02:50 PM #268 chachi1984 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Dedicated Noob Join Date Mar 2010 Posts 31 
 
 hey hany hows it going, I know your busy but could you try to answer my question the best you can. I usually eat a pretty welll balanced diet. eating around 6 meals a day meat usually chicken, turkey and some beaf. my carb source is usually 1.5 cups of rice per meal. if I were to startiong doing 30min cardo 3-4 times a week but keep my diet the same could I lose body fat. Reply With Quote January 20th, 2011,  02:01 PM #269 UncleSpam81st 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Dedicated Noob Join Date Jan 2011 Location Fort Campbell, KY Posts 26 Gender Male 
 
 prices and rates please? Reply With Quote January 22nd, 2011,  02:03 PM #270 bigswo 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Dedicated Noob Join Date Jan 2011 Posts 10 Gender Male 
 my metabolism
 Hey,Hany Rambod I have question for you I really need to something about my metabolism. It seems like everytime I increase my calorie intake I loose weight just by eating more junk food carlories. Dose this mean I need to increase my crabs to get ripped? this is what my diet looks like.
this is for rest days
meal:1 6 scrambled eggs, 3 cups of harsh browns, 1 cup of oatmeal and 3?4 cup of blueberries.

meal:2 protien shake with skim milk with cup of brown rice

meal:3 8 oz of top sirloin steak , 1 cup of brown rice

meal:4 protien shake

meal 5 8 oz of top sirloin total calories:2338

the following is for workout days

meal:1 6 scrambled eggs, 3 cups of hash browns, 1 cup of oatmeal and 3?4 cup of blueberries.

meal:2 protien shake with 2 cups of rice


meal 3 8 oz of top sirloin steak , 1 cup of brown rice

meal 4 protien shake

post workout: 8 oz of top sirloin with 1 cup of white rice calories 2786 bodyweight is 240, bodyfat percentage is 19.3, protien:241 grams, carbs;325 grams, fat:58 grams and on rest day my intake is protien:241 grams, carbs:213 grams, fat:58 grams. Reply With Quote January 23rd, 2011,  12:58 AM #271 Mini ForkliftⓋ 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message Visit Homepage 
 Forum Leader: Powerlifitng&amp;Strongman Join Date Jan 2010 Location S 330 / B 236.5 / D 429 @ 143 bw Posts 14,712 Gender Male 
 
 Does Hany ever get on here? Just the top of this page goes back to September 2010 and he hasn&apos;t answered anything since then. Surely he&apos;s not that busy that he can&apos;t get on for 5 or 10mins a day to check in? 1st Chch PL&apos;ing Champs 2011
 1st Chch Raw Champs (+3 raw records)
 http://www.youtube.com/user/kiwilifter?feature=mhee 
 
 Reply With Quote February 10th, 2011,  04:54 PM #272 themakcompany 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Private Message 
 Spotter Join Date Mar 2010 Posts 264 
 
 Question: How do the bodybuilders of today make such gains on working a bodypart once per week or four times per month. Do you recommend that or are you old school a bodypart gets worked twice a week? Recently Haney said the same thing. Makes no sense to him. Once per week? Reply With Quote 
 Page 16 of 19 First ... 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 Last 
 Jump to page: 
 Quick Navigation MD Q&amp;A Top 
 Site Areas Settings Private Messages Subscriptions Who&apos;s Online Search Forums Forums Home Forums MD Bodybuilding Forums 
 No Bull MD Q&amp;A The&quot;Z&quot;Zone 
 MD Staff&amp;Pros 
 The Jay Cutler Zone The DY Zone Victor&apos;s Journal 
 2008 Team MD Transformation Challenge, Sponsored by MHP. 
 Kick Ass Inc. Flex Wheeler Full Access RODNEY RAW POWER ROLLER Extreme Truth with Carlon M. Colker, M.D. The Anabolic Doc-Thomas O&apos;Connor, MD 
 MD&apos;s Bodybuilding Contest Coverage 
 Past IFBB&amp;NPC Contests 
 The International Board Past 2011 IFBB and NPC Contests 
 2011 British Grand Prix 2011 Flex Pro Bodybuilding Championships 2011 FitExpo 2011 Arnold Classic Weekend 2011 Arnold Amateur Weekend 2011 Mr Europe Grand Prix 2011 Australian Pro Grand Prix 2011 FIBO Power Germany 2011 IFBB Europa Show of Champions Orlando 2011 IFBB Pro and NPC Pittsburgh Championships 2011 Body Power Expo 2011 New York Pro Championships 2011 Jay Cutler Classic 2011 IFBB Pro Europa Super Show - Dallas 2011 NPC Bev Francis Atlantic States 2011 NPC Jr Nationals 2011 NPC Garden State Championships 2011 NPC Southern States Championships 2011 PBW Tampa Pro 2011 Arnold Classic Europe Pro 2011 Branch Warren Classic 2011 Team Universe and NPC National Fitness 2011 IFBB Dexter Jackson Classic/Jacksonville Pro IFBB Pro World Masters Championships December 10, 2011 in Miami Beach, Florida 2011 NPC New Jersey State 2011 IFBB North American Championships 2011 NPC National Championships 2011 IFBB Mr Olympia Weekend 2011 Sheru Classic - India IFBB Pro 2011 Teen, Collegiate&amp;Masters Nationals 2012 Flex Pro 2011 Europa Battle of Champions - Hartford 2011 NPC Jr USA Bodybuilding Championships 2011 Toronto Pro SuperShow 2011 NPC USA Championships 2011 Phoenix Men&apos;s Pro 
 2012 Arnold Sports Festival 2012 Fitness Expo Past 2010 IFBB and NPC Contests 
 2010 Australian Pro Grand Prix 10 2010 NPC USA Bodybuilding, Figure&amp;Bikini Championships 2010 Jacksonville Pro Championships 2010 Olympia Weekend: Bodybuilding, Figure, Bikini&amp;Fitness 2010 Europa Supershow - Dallas, TX 2010 NPC National Bodybuilding, Figure&amp;Bikini Championships 2010 NPC Sacramento Bodybuilding, Figure, Bikini&amp;Fitness Championships 2010 IFBB Phoenix Pro - Bodybuilding and Fitness Show 2010 Branch Warren Classic 2010 NPC Jr. National Bodybuilding Championships 2010 Europa Battle of Champions - Hartford, CT 2010 Detroit Pro Championships 2010 Bev Francis Atlantic States 2010 Team Universe, NPC National Fitness&amp;New York Pro Figure Championships 2010 NPC Teen, Collegiatte and Masters National Championships 2010 IFBB North American Championships 2010 Pro Bodybuilding Weekly Championships 2010 NPC Pittsburgh Championship - Bodybuilding, Fitness, Figure, Bikini 2010 IFBB New York: Pro Men&apos;s and Women&apos;s Bodybuilding and Pro Bikini Championships 2010 Europa Show of Champions - Orlando 2010 IFBB New York Pro Fitness Classic&amp;NPC Metropolitan 2010 Arnold Classic&amp;Ms International 
 Past 2009 IFBB and NPC Contests 
 2009 Nationals Weekend 2009 Olympia Weekend 2009 Teen, Collegiate&amp;Masters Nationals 2009 Dexter Jackson Classic 202 and Figure 2009 Pro Bodybuilding Weekly Tampa Bay Pro Championships 2009 Jr. Nationals 2009 GNC IFBB North American Championships 2009 Branch Warren Classic 2009 Europa SuperShow 2009 Atlantic City ProAm 2009 USA Bodybuilding Championships 
 2012 IFBB Australian Pro Mens, Figure&amp;Amateur GP Past 2008 IFBB and NPC Contests 
 2008 NPC Nationals 2008 Teen, Collegiate and Masters Nationals 
 
 
 MD Bodybuilding Training Forums 
 Contest Prep 
 Evaluation Stage Plastic Surgery 
 Breast Augmentation Gynecomastia 
 
 Training 
 Bodybuilding Myth Busters Sports Specific Training Military Muscle 
 Masters Bodybuilding 
 Masters Archive 
 Beginner&apos;s Board Teen Bodybuilding 
 Teen Training Journals Teen OT 
 Powerlifting and Strongman 
 Info for Beginners 
 Bodybuilding Training and Workout Videos - Trenches - Pro Training Injuries and Treatment Member Training Journals 
 MD Sponsored Forums 
 IronMagLabs ANIMAL 
 MD Spotlight 
 MD TV Videos 
 In The Trenches Hardcore Series 
 The MD Radio Show MD Audio Online Show MD TV Community Channel 
 MD Women&apos;s HQ 
 MD 1 on 1 with... IFBB Female Athlete Corner Women&apos;s Bodybuilding Women&apos;s Fitness, Figure&amp;Bikini Women&apos;s Training Journals Ladies Locker Room 
 MD Nutrition and Supplementation Forums 
 Supplement Reviews, Discussions&amp;Research 
 Guest Q&amp;A 
 The Kitchen 
 The Cupboard Recipes 
 Fat Loss Fanatics Chemical Enhancement 
 Enhanced Cycle Journals Designer steroids/Prohormones Chemical FAQ Female Pharmacology 
 Bodybuilding Science Nattie Talk 
 MD Community Activity Central 
 Forum Member Galleries Take it to the&quot;Stage&quot; 
 MD Sports Boards 
 No Bull Sports UFC / MMA WWE / TNA 
 Muscular Development&apos;s Off Topic Forums 
 OT Stuff 
 MD Pets! The Game Room 
 Politics&amp;Religion Love&amp;Relationships The Music Room Movies/Films/Celebs&amp;Hollywood Computer Help Desk 
 Video Games 
 Careers and Opportunities The Flea Market 18 and Over The Pit 
 FAQ&apos;n Help 
 MD Connect! MD Digital Magazine Advertising Inquiries and Information 
 
 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
Bookmarks
 
Bookmarks

 Digg del.icio.us StumbleUpon Google 
 
 Posting Permissions
 
 You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts   
 
 BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On [VIDEO] code is On HTML code is Off 
 
 Forum Rules 
 
 
 The Top Brands in Sports Nutrition
	</body>
</document>
