<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000375" url="http://www.foodsoftware.com/Product_0005_01.asp" time="2012-07-12-15:34" support="1" score="0.00039592747093746537" bingtitle="Restaurant Business Plan Software / Restaurant Starting / Opening ..." webtitle="Restaurant Business Plan Software / Restaurant Starting / Opening /Buying: QuickPlan Restaurant">
			<query id="000298" bing-rank="33"/>
	<description>QuickPlan Restaurant is based on a 166-seat full-service restaurant ... fine-dining, full-service or fast-food restaurant ... Enter your food and beverage revenue ...</description>
	<body>
		FoodSoftware.com 
    Restaurant Business Plan Software / Restaurant Starting / Opening /Buying: QuickPlan Restaurant 

 Home  |  Catalog  |  Shopping Checkout  |  Contact Us  |  About Us  |  Dealer Sales  |  Educational Sales  |  Site Map  |  Previous  |  Next  |  
 

 
 
  
 QuickPlan Restaurant Business Plan Software 

 QuickPlan rapidly develops restaurant business plans you can take to the bank! Whether you are starting a fine-dining, full-service or fast-food restaurant, are looking for expansion capital to open your next restaurant or want to sell your multi-restaurant chain, with QuickPlan, all you have to do edit and fill in the details of an already written and organized sample restaurant business plan. Downloadable for rapid delivery. 

 QuickPlan Restaurant 
 Overview Outline Comparisons Testimonials 
 QuickPlan Family 
 All Restaurants Bars&amp;Night Clubs Bed&amp;Breakfast Coffee Shop Delicatessen Diner Coffee Drive-Thru Fast Food Restaurant Hotel Ice Cream Parlor Pizzerias Resort Sandwich Shop Wine Bar 
 Related Products 
 Business Plan Software New Restaurant Start Up 
 
QuickPlan Restaurant
Business Plan Software
 New Business Plans Financial Forecasts Business Appraisel Financing&amp;Refinancing

 
Product Group Guides

 Restaurant Software Restaurant Business Plans 
 

 
Info, Quotes&amp;Orders:
 805-375-7000 
8am - 11pm Pacific

 Email: 
sales@FoodSoftware.com

 Advanced Analytical, Inc.
Newbury Park, CA 91320 We Accept 
All Major Credit Cards Revised: 10/27/2011 
 
 
 &gt;  Home  &gt;
 QuickPlan Restaurant Business Plan Software 
 
    
 Our Price 
 $169.95     
 QuickPlan Restaurant Business Plan Software Product ID: DC-QPR-005 Class: Business Plan Software&amp;Books More Classes: Business Plan Software&amp;Books ; Downloadable Software ; Food Software ; Foodservice Education ; Foodservice Software ; How to Start a Restaurant ; Restaurant Accounting ; Restaurant Business Plans ; Restaurant Software ; Restaurant Starting ; Spreadsheets ; Starting a New Restaurant Business 
 
 
 &lt; Back    Next &gt;    
 
 QuickPlan Restaurant Business Plan Writing Software helps you create a restaurant business plan if you are:
 Starting a new restaurant Looking for money to expand your restaurant Appraising your restaurant to sell it

QuickPlan Restaurant is the fast and easy way to save yourself hundreds of hours 
 writing, organizing and researching your restaurant business plan. 
 This is the only complete, industry-specific business plan 
 software available for full service, limited service, fast food, bakeries, caterers,
 night clubs, themed expansions and franchises.
QuickPlan Restaurant is based on a 166-seat full-service restaurant and is appropriate for most restaurant types. Other members of the QuickPlan family are tailored to specific types such as pizzerias and coffee shops. Please see the links in the left margin under QuickPlan Family for additional QuickPlan titles.
Whether you are starting a new restaurant, raising additional capital to
 expand your existing restaurant or setting a sellingprice for your
 restaurant, you will do much better with a business plan than without.

 Business plans make it easy for your banker to take action and gain insight
 into the details of your restaurant and your goals. Potential investors can review your plan and decide whether or not to make
 an investment based upon the risk. You will benefit as you study and gain detailed insight into your own operations. Updating and constantly reviewing your plan gives you more insight as both
 a manager and decision maker.

 Survive Competition: Most new restaurants fail because of poor planning
 in a highly competitive market. Your management decisions will decide
 whether your restaurant survives or thrives in the face of ever-increasing
 competition. The most important benefit of a business plan is that
 it sets the stage for the future of your restaurant plan itsposition
 in the marketplace.
 Save Time and Money: Without QuickPlan, we estimate that it
 takes an average of 100 hours to research and write a comprehensive business
 plan. Creating and compiling the five-year financial plan and forecasts,
 including 5 years of budgets, income statements, balance sheets, cash flow
 and key financial ratio analyses, can take more than 20 hours of work by
 you or your accountant.
 Research Already Included: QuickPlan includes the Foodservice Industry Analysis which was written from numerous current sources including the National Restaurant Associations&apos; Food Industry Analysis , which covers both full-service and fast food restaurants.
 How QuickPlan Works: With QuickPlan, all you have to do instead
 is sit down in front of your computer and edit and fill in the details of
 an already written and organized sample restaurant business plan and outline.
Whether you are starting a fine-dining, full-service or fast-food restaurant,
 are looking for expansion capital to open your next restaurant or want to
 sell your multi-restaurant chain, you will be able to modify this plan into
 your own .
You can use your word processor and spreadsheet to edit the plan. Enter your food and beverage revenue assumptions, operating expense assumptions and cash flow assumptions into the QuickPlan five-year forecasting template using your spreadsheet 
program. You will immediately have five years projected month-to-month operating 
budgets, income statements, balance sheets, cash flow analysis and key financial 
ratios.
Download QuickPlan

Want to start right away? QuickPlan products are delivered by email within an hour of purchase during Eastern US business hours and less regularly during non-business hours.
Download the QuickPlan Demo Spreadsheet

 Click here to download the QuickPlan Restaurant Demo Spreadsheet. Pop-ups must be enabled as this link will open a new browser window to display the spreadsheet.
 Click the Next link below for more information about this product. 
 &lt; Back    Next &gt;    
 QuickPlan is a trademark of Demand Creation, Inc. 
 
 

 Home  |  Catalog  |  Shopping Checkout  |  Contact Us  |  About Us  |  Dealer Sales  |  Educational Sales  |  Site Map  |  Previous  |  Next  |
	</body>
</document>
