<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000788" url="http://blog.doha-delivery.com/using-doha-delivery/how-to-find-a-restaurant-menu/" time="2012-07-12-16:07" support="1" score="0.0006498110977833968" bingtitle="How to Find a Restaurant Menu on Doha Delivery | doha-delivery.com" webtitle="How to Find a Restaurant Menu on Doha Delivery | doha-delivery.com">
			<query id="001484" bing-rank="212"/>
	<description>Fast Food; Restaurant Locations; Media. Doha Delivery on BBC World ... Order Food Now. Order American Grill Online; Order ... bar is includes our search function and a number of ...</description>
	<body>
		Doha&apos;s Delivery Menus Online 
 Home About Us 
 About Doha Delivery Announcements Cuisines Our Restaurants Fast Food Restaurant Locations Media 
 Doha Delivery on BBC World Doha Tweetup–Doha 101 
 Statistics 
 July 2011 Stats August 2011 Stats September 2011 Stats 
 Legal Notices 
 Privacy Policy Terms&amp;Conditions 
 
 Restaurant Managers 
 Get your Menu Online Add your Menu the EASY way Manage Your Menus Set-Up Online Ordering 
 Manage Your Orders Manage Your Emails Customer Orders–What Happens 
 
 How to Order Food 
 How to Find a Restaurant Menu How to Create an Account Ordering Food Online 
 Order Food Now 
 Order American Grill Online Order Bread&amp;Bagels Online Order Kabab-ji Grill Online 
 Contact Us 
 
 How to Find a Restaurant Menu 
 Tweet 
A quick guide to finding menus on Doha Delivery

 

At Doha Delivery we have over a hundred delivery menus in our database, so finding the restaurant you’re looking for can be a bit daunting. This easy to use guide is designed to help you navigate our menu options and find the menu that’s right for you.

When you land on the Doha Delivery Homepage you’ll see a maroon bar across the top of the screen. This bar is includes our search function and a number of buttons that take you to different pages. When looking for a restaurant menu, you need to use either the search function or the“ Restaurants ”button.

The Search Function lets you search by restaurant name, cuisine type or location.

The Restaurants button gives you a list of ALL the restaurants in our database.

 

The Search Function can be used in many different ways. You can search by restaurant name by typing the name into the search bar. You can search by cuisine by choosing from our drop-down list. You can choose to search by location by choosing a Zone in Doha or Al Rayyan from the drop-down menu. Or, you can search for any combination of the three!

For example, if you wanted to search for a McDonald’s Restaurant in Markhiya, you can type in McDonald’s in the search bar and select Markhiya from the drop down list. Here are your search results:
 
Doha Delivery Search Example - McDonald&apos;s in Markhiya
 
You can do the same with cuisines and locations, creating combinations to see what restaurants are where.

The Restaurants button takes you to a list of ALL the restaurant menus in our database. It takes you to a“Results Page”that lists all the restaurants.
 
Doha Delivery Restaurants Button
 
The initial page only displays three restaurants (we like to keep things simple), you can scroll through all the restaurants by hitting the Next button on the bottom, right-hand side of the page or by clicking on a page number. The numbers next to the Next button show the number of pages and let you jump from page to page.
 
Use this bar to navigate through the Restaurant List
 
You can also change the display and show 5 or 10 restaurants per page by clicking on the 5 or 10 in the bottom left hand corner of the page.
 
Change the number of results per page
 
Now, when you find the restaurant you were looking for you can also see their menu by clicking the Restaurant Name or the Restaurant Menu Button .

 

So what are you waiting for? Let’s find a Delivery Menu!
 Go to Doha Delivery! Created by Salsabil Ventures, LLC | Copyright Maendeleo Ventures Qatar, LLC 2011
	</body>
</document>
