<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000087" url="http://www.yelp.com/biz/tenders-fresh-food-cornelius" time="2012-07-12-15:16" support="3" score="0.009881130229317777" bingtitle="Tenders Fresh Food - Cornelius, NC" webtitle="Tenders Fresh Food - Cornelius, NC">
			<query id="000034" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="001100" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000880" bing-rank="221"/>
	<description>The condiments are on the way to the restroom and that whole area reminded me of a ... Tenders ain&apos;t your momma&apos;s fast food restaurant. Brought to you by the owners of ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Search Form Skip to Navigation Skip to Page Content 

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 Log In Sign Up for Yelp Friends&apos; Activity 0 Loading... 
 Yelp is using Facebook to personalize your experience. What is this? Not you?
 Log out of Facebook Don&apos;t want to be connected?
 How to turn this off 
 
 Yelp 
 Real people. Real reviews. ® 
 
 Search for (e.g. taco, cheap dinner, Max&apos;s) 

 Near (Address, City, State or Zip) 
 Search 
 Welcome About Me Write a Review Find Reviews Find Friends Messaging Talk 

 Member Search 
   
Tenders Fresh Food
 29 reviews Rating Details 
 Categories: Restaurants Fast Food Restaurants Sandwiches Fast Food , Sandwiches   [Edit] 
 18341 Statesville Rd 
 Cornelius , NC 28031 
 (704) 895-6017 http://www.tendersfreshfood.com/ Menu 
 
 Add Photos Hours: 
Mon-Thu, Sun 11 am - 9 pm

Fri-Sat 11 am - 10 pm
 Good for Kids: Yes
 Accepts Credit Cards: Yes
 Parking: Private Lot
 Attire: Casual
 Good for Groups: Yes
 Price Range: $ 
 Takes Reservations: No
 Delivery: No
 Take-out: Yes
 Waiter Service: No
 Outdoor Seating: Yes
 Wi-Fi: Free
 Good For: Lunch, Dinner
 Alcohol: No
 Drive-Thru: Yes
 Noise Level: Average
 Ambience: Casual
 Has TV: No
 Caters: Yes
 Wheelchair Accessible: Yes
 Dogs Allowed: Yes
 First to Review Jon E. 
 Edit Business Info 
 Send to Friend Bookmark Send to Phone Write a Review 
 Reviews (29) About This Business 

 
 
29 reviews for Tenders Fresh Food
 Reviews Matching: Search Reviews 
Review Highlights  
 
 &quot;My fav was the sweet heat and chipoltle.&quot; In 3 reviews &quot;Make sure to try Tenders&apos; homemade dipping sauces .&quot; In 4 reviews &quot;My favorite is the crispy turkey sandwich combo with fries...&quot; In 2 reviews 
   Loading... Sort by: Yelp Sort | Date | Rating | Elites&apos; | Facebook Friends&apos; 
Facebook Friends


 
From Reviewers You&apos;re Following 


 
Reviews from Your Friends


 
29 reviews in English

 
Review from Liza W. 
 
 16 friends 1 review 

 Liza W. 
 
Washington, DC
 5/16/2012 
Since I moved away from North Caroline 1 year ago, Tenders has been one of the things I miss most about NC. I dream in Tenders. Honestly, it doesn&apos;t get any better than 3 tenders, fries, a soda, and a TON of Texas Pete.

Def eat in, you don&apos;t want those fries getting soggy.

Tenders, I love you with all my heart and soul.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (2) Cool   
 
 Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 Comment from Brooks B. of
 Tenders Fresh Food 5/16/2012    «Hide Wow! Thank you so much for the glowing review, Liza. I moved… More» Wow! Thank you so much for the glowing review, Liza. I moved to Cornelius from Silver Spring, MD, so I can definitely tell you that I miss the food when I get the opportunity to go home as well. Let us know when you&apos;re in town as we would love to see ya again :-) Flag this comment 
Review from Michael B. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 9 friends 64 reviews 

 Michael B. 
 
Atlanta, GA
 4/24/2012 1 Check-in Here 
Really enjoyed the chicken tenders they were very, very, very good.

Like the coke machine that has a ton of different coca cola products you can choose from (very nice touch).

The shakes look great, would love to have some didn&apos;t on this trip.

The place is very clean and well maintained.

What I didn&apos;t like - the fries.  For a place that has such a limited menu if you want 4/5 stars you better do those items right.  In this case, the fries were very disappointing.  Yes they are fresh cut, but they are sooo thin, not well seasoned and mine came out cold.  If the fries were better, would definitely get a 4th star for the quality of the chicken strips alone.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 Comment from Brooks B. of
 Tenders Fresh Food 4/24/2012    «Hide Awesome! Thank you so much for the overwhelmingly positive… More» Awesome! Thank you so much for the overwhelmingly positive feedback, Michael. Give me a shout on here, on Twitter (@tendersfresh) or on Facebook (/tendersfreshfood) as I would like to have you back to show you how great our fries are. Looking forward to hearing back from you and thank you again for the feedback, sir. Flag this comment 
Review from Josh H. 
 
 0 friends 6 reviews 

 Josh H. 
 
Charlotte, NC
 7/5/2012 
Love this place! It&apos;s a very simple restaurant with a simple fresh menu. The prices are the same as fast food, but higher quality food
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 Comment from Brooks B. of
 Tenders Fresh Food 7/7/2012    «Hide Thank you for your kind words, Josh. We&apos;re glad you noticed… More» Thank you for your kind words, Josh. We&apos;re glad you noticed that we boast a full service kitchen and make almost everything in our building from scratch. Please make sure to introduce yourself the next time that you come in as we would love to meet you! Thank you again for your kind words and we look forward to seeing you soon, brotha! Flag this comment 
Review from A. L. 
 
 2 friends 2 reviews 

 A. L. 
 
Cornelius, NC
 7/1/2012 
Love the food, but their workers need to do a better job at getting orders correct. Just about every other time I go here, I can expect some part of my order to be incorrect.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 Comment from Brooks B. of
 Tenders Fresh Food 7/2/2012    «Hide Thank you for your feedback and I I must say that I couldn&apos;t… More» Thank you for your feedback and I I must say that I couldn&apos;t agree with you more; accuracy of orders is extremely important. I accept full responsibility for our shortcoming and wanted to apologize to you for not getting what you expected.

Our FOH staff are thoroughly trained to repeat the order back to you along every step of the way, upon completing your order and upon receiving your food.

Give me [Brooks] a shout the next time that you&apos;re coming by and I&apos;ll ensure that you are properly taken care of. My direct number is 301.512.7391 and my email is bbriz@eatpdq.com . Looking forward to hearing from you and thank you again for your feedback. Flag this comment 
Review from Michael F. 
 
 0 friends 5 reviews 

 Michael F. 
 
Cornelius, NC
 6/3/2012 2 Check-ins Here 
Fast and friendly service! Good food. Priced well. If you&apos;re in the area and have never been, you need to stop in....try EVERY sauce!!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 Comment from Brooks B. of
 Tenders Fresh Food 6/4/2012    «Hide Thanks so much for dropping in, Michael! Glad you always… More» Thanks so much for dropping in, Michael! Glad you always have a great experience and please introduce yourself the next time that you stop in (I&apos;ll be in the guy in the white chef coat handing you your food haha). Flag this comment 
Review from Jonathan B. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 38 friends 130 reviews 

 Jonathan B. 
 
Cornelius, NC
 11/19/2011 5 Check-ins Here ROTD 2/19/2012 
I took that fateful step and dipped my first bite of that delicious looking chicken into a sauce I thought was cocktail or marinara. Lo and behold it truly was barbecue sauce - likely the most amazing I have ever had!

This was the effect Tenders had on me. One previous reviewer classified this as &quot;fast food&quot; but I wouldn&apos;t even put it in that category despite the fact that it is in many ways. The fried chicken is juicy and spices cover it with a flavorful embrace. The dipping sauces are honestly to die for. Like I said before, the barbeque looks a lot like cocktail or marinara sauce but its surprisingly a delicious barbeque. And the sweet yet spicy chipotle is a great combination for even those of us who typically don&apos;t do spicy so well. The fresh, crispy fries appear to be covered with sea salt - better than the table alternative.

Seal the deal with a desert of granny smith apples soaked in pineapple juice and dipped in a caramel-like Heath bar medley. The staff is awesomely friendly and helpful and even the other patrons of the restaurant are willing to converse with a stranger. Tenders is a delightfully simple eating experience for which I could pass on any fast food alternative any day!
 
 Listed in: Fast Food Faves 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (9) Funny (3) Cool (7) 
 
 Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 Comment from Brooks B. of
 Tenders Fresh Food 2/22/2012    «Hide Thank you for the love, Jonathan! We appreciate the positive… More» Thank you for the love, Jonathan! We appreciate the positive review and wanted to congratulate you for being featured as the ROTD on Yelp! You deserve it with the hard work that you&apos;ve put in for the Yelp community :-) Flag this comment 
Review from Josh J. 
 
 15 friends 25 reviews 

 Josh J. 
 
Huntersville, NC
 11/5/2011 
Had my first trip to Tenders today -- delicious chicken fingers, fries, dipping sauces and apple slices. But seriously -- the children in this place made me want to pull my hair out. They were everywhere, screaming, being tickled by adults who should be shot. It was a cacophony and made us want to run screaming.

How did I live up this way for 3 years and not try this joint? Part of it is that it looks a little redneck-ish from the road. I had no idea until recently that it is owned by the same group that runs 131 Main, one of our favorite restaurants. So, that made it something we were a little more adventurous with. But the children... dear God... the children...

I agree with others that the one drink machine, the sort of sterile environment, and the large numbers of people (and children!) hanging all over the place at 2:00pm on Saturday make it a place I will probably only visit on off hours, or to eat in my car. Thus the 3 stars, even though the food deserves 4. Great tender chicken!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (2) Cool (1) 
 
 Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 Comment from Brooks B. of
 Tenders Fresh Food 2/5/2012    «Hide Hey Josh, thank you for all of the positive feedback; we… More» Hey Josh, thank you for all of the positive feedback; we really appreciate it. I just wanted to let you know that we added another Coke Freestyle machine to alleviate the lines that were developing. Additionally, I always recommend visiting us during slower hours (2-4 PM or 7:30-9 PM) to try and avoid the crowds. Thank you again for your kind words and we look forward to seeing you again soon! Flag this comment 
Review from Sam P. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 87 friends 228 reviews 

 Sam P. 
 
Charlotte, NC
 11/3/2011 2 Check-ins Here 
So we just stopped in here for a shake, but saw the fries, so ended up with fries and a shake. It just so happened to be happy hour, so we got the shake for half price!  Good timing (between 2-4). The chocolate shake was awesome, they give you a huge straw because it&apos;s pretty thick stuff. Taste like they use some hot fudge to make it. Fries are fresh cut and tasty. I didn&apos;t check the condiment station, but the fries would love some seasoning salt next time. Regardless, every last fry morsel was consumed.

Service is worth-mentioning friendly. The condiments are on the way to the restroom and that whole area reminded me of a church basement gathering space, not sure exactly why.

Next time we are up there, i&apos;ll be sure to stop and this time might even try the tenders.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Alex N. 
 
 6 friends 8 reviews 

 Alex N. 
 
Bloomington, IN
 7/25/2011 
Tenders ain&apos;t your momma&apos;s fast food restaurant.

Brought to you by the owners of another Cornelius favorite, 131 Main, Tenders is a simple but delectable fast-casual restaurant specializing in fried chicken. While the menu selection doesn&apos;t get past fried or grilled chicken tenders, sandwiches, salads, fries, and a selection of milkshakes, it more than makes up for it with it&apos;s finger lickin&apos; good food. I usually go for the traditional chicken tenders combo, but have tried the crispy turkey breast sandwich as well. While fried food isn&apos;t the healthiest, Tenders offers all of their meals with grilled chicken if that floats your boat. Likewise, their chicken is never frozen, and their french fries are cut from potatoes daily. This should at least make you feel a little bit better as you indulge in some of the most succulent fried chicken you will ever taste.

Make sure to try Tenders&apos; homemade dipping sauces. My friends and I swear by the creamy garlic, a more flavorful and zesty version of traditional ranch dressing. They also offer a honey mustard, BBQ, and sweet heat, a spicier version of their creamy garlic sauce. While not a big shake fan, I&apos;ve had a few bites of my friends, and I can assure you they&apos;re quality.

Hidden on their menu is the option to trade your french fries for sliced apples. Don&apos;t be fooled...these sliced apples are served with an absolutely scrumptious homemade toffee caramel dip that is out of this world. Not sure if it&apos;s healthy, but you will literally be scraping out the remains of this dip with your finger until every last drop of it is gone.

Perfect for a quick lunch while boating on Lake Norman or heading out with co-workers, Tenders is a welcome addition to the Cornelius area that is highly recommended!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (4) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Eric D. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 61 friends 270 reviews 

 Eric D. 
 
Cornelius, NC
 8/14/2011 1 photo 5 Check-ins Here 
I know, I know 5-stars for fast-food, but this is good fast-food.  Definitely not good for you...but good.

Atmosphere - White, large/ spacious, clean, basic. The only thing that may take this place down a notch to 4-stars is atmosphere.  It&apos;s kind of...no...it is sterile.  Bright white sterile.  At least you know it is clean.

Food - Awesome!  I have eaten here twice in three or so weeks (which is good for me as I rarely eat fast-food anymore).  On my first visit I had the Chicken tenders, which were very fresh tasting.  No precooked and frozen then fried chicken here!  It came w/ a side of fresh cut fries and a tea.  All tasty.  On my second visit I had the Cajan Fried Turkey sandwich.  It had the right amount of kick and was not dry as turkey can sometimes be.  It was a filet cut too, no ground turkey.  Again, I got the meal w/ fresh cut fries and a tea...all delicious.  ( I believe they have grilled options...but who wants that?)

Price - On my second visit it was $7.21 out the door.

Overall - For fast-food this is a 5-star place.  I recommend checking it out.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from David C. 
 
 6 friends 17 reviews 

 David C. 
 
Huntersville, NC
 2/25/2012 2 Check-ins Here 
Great fast , cheap chicken fingers  and good fries
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 Comment from Brooks B. of
 Tenders Fresh Food 3/7/2012    «Hide That&apos;s what we do! Thank you for the positive feedback,… More» That&apos;s what we do! Thank you for the positive feedback, David, and we look forward to seeing you soon, sir! Flag this comment 
Review from Meredith S. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 17 friends 56 reviews 

 Meredith S. 
 
Charlotte, NC
 7/11/2011 
Tenders is Yummy! Yes, it&apos;s true they do have a very limited menu, but what they do have is delicious. I have been to tenders several times and have always been pleased with the service and the freshness of the meal. My favorite is the crispy turkey sandwich combo with fries and Cheerwine. Recently I visited and tried the apple pie milkshake, which is now the best milkshake in town.
Tenders is always clean and the prices are good as well.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Alisa N. 
 
 16 friends 43 reviews 

 Alisa N. 
 
Charlotte, NC
 2/2/2012 5 Check-ins Here 
Their tenders are so much better than Chick Fil A and their fries are real good too. I always order to go since I&apos;m not a fan of the dog rescue they had on the patio this past summer. I love finding good, cheap eats!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 Comment from Brooks B. of
 Tenders Fresh Food 2/22/2012    «Hide Thank you, Alisa! We appreciate the positive feedback. As… More» Thank you, Alisa! We appreciate the positive feedback. As for the dogs, we welcome them in every few months on Saturday afternoons for the Great Dane Rescue of the Carolinas. Looking forward to seeing you again soon :-) Flag this comment 
Review from Rob S. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 52 friends 51 reviews 

 Rob S. 
 
Huntersville, NC
 4/26/2011 3 photos 6 Check-ins Here 
Tenders has become my favorite quick bite restaurant. We moved into the area over 2 years ago and avoided this place because of it&apos;s simple appearance.  Eventually we discovered the team was the same behind 131 Main so we gave it a shot and were not disappointed. I think I went twice a week the first few months.

This place is a great stop for summer months in-between lake or pool days, and the portion size does not disappoint. The deal on their party platters is amazing for tailgating or get togethers.

Be sure to like them on Facebook, they do contests from time to time, and my wife won a $50 gift card carving a Tenders pumpkin.

The menu is small, so don&apos;t expect a lot of options, but expect to love all the choices there.  Shakes are delicious, and bonus points for being the only restaurant I have ever been to that gives you a super wide straw so your not fighting the milkshake the whole time.

I won&apos;t knock them a star for it, but they use to have a pork chop sandwich that was AMAZING, and then it was replaced by the not as good for me, but still tasty, Thanksgiving Day sandwich.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Tom C. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 33 friends 230 reviews 

 Tom C. 
 
Huntersville, NC
 5/11/2011 1 Check-in Here 
Tenders is great for what it is. A limited menu of poultry based (chicken and turkey grilled or fried) sandwiches and fresh chicken tenders with good dipping sauces. No frills but they know what they are doing in this space.

The service is fast and friendly and I love the drive up, at your car, service if you want it to go. Only requests would be to go back to the original fries and add both a spicy chicken and a chicken salad sandwich to the menu.
 
 Listed in: Lake Norman Eats 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jen G. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 37 friends 233 reviews 

 Jen G. 
 
Troutman, NC
 1/25/2011 
This place is to chicken tenders what In-N-Out is to burgers. Hands down, the best tenders around. Juicy. Big. Great flavor and only the smallest amount of well seasoned breading. Great fries - though they are sized for Polly Pocket and not human hands. That said, they are fresh, perfectly prepared and awesome w/malt vinegar. My husband really enjoys the pork sandwich though he does wish it were a tad bigger (well, he&apos;d never say tad...or smidgeon...but you get the point).

Kids&apos; meals are great and fresh fruit is offered as a side. These meals are great for kids or adults w/a smaller appetite.

Like In-N-Out, the place is surgically clean and the staff is very friendly. My only complaint is that we drive 17 miles to get there!
 
 Listed in: Good Food That&apos;s Bad for You… 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from SilviaElena E. 
 
 2 friends 11 reviews 

 SilviaElena E. 
 
Charlotte, NC
 1/6/2012 3 Check-ins Here 
A real chef, delish chicken fingers, killer honey mustard and the coolest soda machine around. All that real food foe less than a greasy burger meal.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 Comment from Brooks B. of
 Tenders Fresh Food 2/5/2012    «Hide Hey Silvia, thank you for your kind words! Just to give you… More» Hey Silvia, thank you for your kind words! Just to give you a heads up, we actually added a second Coke Freestyle machine so now we have twice the soda machine coolness in our building! Looking forward to seeing you again soon. :-) Flag this comment 
Review from Michelle B. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 45 friends 289 reviews 

 Michelle B. 
 
Charlotte, NC
 11/17/2011 4 photos 2 Check-ins Here 
Finally, I made a trip to Tenders for dinner.  This is a nice little spot for a quick bite to eat.  I had the crispy tucker breast sandwich with cajun spice, served on an egg bun with lettuce, tomato, pickles, and sweet heat sauce.  It was served with fries and the absolutely delectable apple slices with toffee dip! Loved the sandwich and applies with dip!  The fries were a bit salty but I didn&apos;t want them anyway.  On my next visit, I will ask for a double serving of applies instead.  Beware, the kids chicken finger meal comes with just one chicken finger, so order wisely if you have a hungry lad.  It is most likely true that they have 100 drinks.  I didn&apos;t take the time to explore them all, but they are PLENTIFUL (see photo) and you can drink to your heart&apos;s content.  I had lemonade (delicious) and tea mixed and was completely satisfied.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Karen t. 
 
 0 friends 5 reviews 

 Karen t. 
 
Davidson, NC
 1/18/2012 
Great,  inexpensive place to eat.  I get food here for my staff meetings,  as most everyone can find something they like.  Nothing fancy,  just quality food,  fast.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 Comment from Brooks B. of
 Tenders Fresh Food 4/25/2012    «Hide You definitely understand what we strive for, Karen! Thank… More» You definitely understand what we strive for, Karen! Thank you so much for the positive feedback and we look forward to seeing you again soon :-) PS- Please introduce yourself the next time that you stop in! Flag this comment 
Review from Jon E. 
 
 0 friends 8 reviews 

 Jon E. 
 
Huntersville, NC
 1/25/2009 
This is a brand new place from the owners of 131 Main. It&apos;s a fast food concept meant to compete with Chick-fil-a. It&apos;s at the corner of Westmoreland and Statesville Rd.

Food: Good chicken sandwiches and hand cut fries. I think the fries are the same type served at 131 Main. They also have chicken tenders and pork tenderloin sandwiches. The chicken sandwich had a nice, crisp batter on it. The sandwich comes with lettuce, tomato, mayo, onions, and pickles. They emphasize freshness (nothing frozen).

Price: Plan on spending around $7 for a sandwich, fries, and a drink.

Atmosphere: Very casual. This is a fast food place at heart. Right now it&apos;s in an old building, but plans are to build modern fast-food outlets as the chain grows. Right now, this one is it and it&apos;s unique.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (4) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from chad h. 
 
 24 friends 37 reviews 

 chad h. 
 
Cornelius, NC
 7/17/2011 
Excellent food.  It feels like a fast food place, but the food tastes better, fresher, and healthier.  The menu can seem a bit exotic for a casual dining place, but I would urge you to not alter anything when ordering.  Everything is put together that way for a reason, and its delicious.  Love this place on a saturday or sunday for lunch.  Bump chick fil a and their no sunday gimmick.  This place is the real deal Holifield.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Michael B. 
 
 5 friends 4 reviews 

 Michael B. 
 
Huntersville, NC
 7/20/2009 3 photos 
You can definitely tell that the chicken is fresh. It is nicely moist and the breading is well seasoned. You can also order your sandwich grilled rather than fried which is a nice option.

I do think that their chicken isn&apos;t showcased well by their choice of toppings. They should keep it simple. Maybe just mayo, pickles, and tomato. The lettuce and onion flavors detract from the excellent chicken.

The pork chop is also very tender and succulent but my wife felt it was a bit on the salty side.

The chicken tenders that we got in the kid&apos;s meal for my daughter were probably the best thing we got because all you taste is the moist chicken and superbly seasoned breading. Oh, and the creamy garlic sauce we got was great with the tenders. I&apos;m glad they decided to carry it over from 131 Main.

The fries are good and cut in house -- you can see bags of potatoes stored under the condiment stand. But, while the fine cut fits in very well at 131 Main, I wish they would go with a more coarse cut at Tenders.

The restaurant was very clean and the staff was patient (you wouldn&apos;t believe how long it took my family, my mother included, to choose from such a short menu) and friendly.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Brandon U. 
 
 11 friends 3 reviews 

 Brandon U. 
 
Charlotte, NC
 11/6/2009 
You can tell a place is good when the parking lot is always full. In a short time, Tenders has become a very popular place to eat in Huntersville.

Besides Chik-fil-A, these are the best chicken nuggets you&apos;ll find. The price seems a little steep but don&apos;t be fooled by the portions--the 3-piece meal will fill you up.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Alex S. 
 
 5 friends 2 reviews 

 Alex S. 
 
Tampa, FL
 8/11/2011 
This is the best chicken sandwich that I have ever had.  I was tempted to go up and get a second sandwich I was so impressed but I decided to try a milkshake instead....amazing!  I talked to the manager and he told me a little about the restaurant.  Everything is fresh...this makes a lot of sense because you can really taste the difference.  I wish I lived in North Carolina so I could visit more often.  Tenders will be a must do every time I am up in Charlotte.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Joe G. 
 
 0 friends 20 reviews 

 Joe G. 
 
Huntersville, NC
 3/1/2011 
The kids love it.  Great food.  Limited menu (that&apos;s the point).  Friendly, very courteous and attentive staff.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Derek C. 
 
 20 friends 23 reviews 

 Derek C. 
 
San Francisco, CA
 3/7/2011 
So, born and raised in the south, Chic-fil-a has been a staple for my chicken nugget/strip/sandwich craving for as long as I remember. I have driven by Tenders countless times and decided to finally give it a try, and man do they do a good job at what they do. Simple menu...chicken tenders, a couple of sandwiches and fries...thats it. I got a 3 piece strip with fries must say that they were the best chicken strips I have ever had. Perfect seasoning of salt, pepper and thyme(pretty sure) with a light and crispy batter without being greasy. The chicken was still moist and perfectly cooked. The homemade sauces are awesome as well....sweet heat BBQ, chipoltle, creamy garlic and honey mustard. My fav was the sweet heat and chipoltle. Only reason I am not giving 5 starts is because the fries were a little over done for my tastes, but still hand cut and fresh. I&apos;m sure they will be adding more locations, but in the mean time if you are ever in the huntersville/cornelius area and have a chic-fil-a craving, skip it and give this place a try.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny (2) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Joseph R. 
 
 0 friends 5 reviews 

 Joseph R. 
 
Cornelius, NC
 12/16/2010 
We just love this place... Been going there since their free shakedown trials, and we keep going back. If &quot;anything&quot; is not to your liking, they comp you. Just great!

Fresh cooking, handmade french fries and absolutely great shakes - so thick they use a super-size straw! Gotta love a place like this.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Paul S. 
 
 0 friends 21 reviews 

 Paul S. 
 
North Andover, MA
 12/19/2009 
Great place for a quick lunch. Super clean inside (almost on the sterile side), but can&apos;t go wrong for fresh chicken sandwiches
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Kim J. 
 
 0 friends 13 reviews 

 Kim J. 
 
Huntersville, NC
 12/13/2010 
LOOVE Tenders!  This place is always immaculately clean, the wait staff is SO nice, and their Chicken is GREAT.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
 ( 4 Filtered )  
 
 Write a Review What&apos;s This? 
About This Business
 Provided by business 
Specialties
 
Tenders Fresh Food located in Cornelius, NC, specializes in never frozen chicken tenders, chicken sandwiches and turkey sandwiches. Tenders also features fresh cut fries, hand-spun shakes, made-to-order salads and much more!
 
History
 
 Established in 2009 

Tenders was born on a rainy Sunday afternoon by Joe Douglass of 131 Main restaurants and his children. A simple idea of offering of fresh, never frozen products in an atmosphere that makes people feel home is what still stands true today. We welcome you to experience Tenders and find out what we are all about.
 
Meet the Manager: Brooks B.
 
Head Computer Nerd/Community Liaison.
 Flag as inappropriate View Larger Map/Directions 
Browse Nearby:
 
 Restaurants | Nightlife | Shopping | Movies | All 
 
People Who Viewed This Also Viewed...
 
 131 Main  44 reviews &quot;Also, the Roast Beef Sandwich was amazing.&quot; Restaurant X  18 reviews &quot;The trio was delicious - crab cake, salmon&amp;tuna atop...&quot; Sangam Indian Cuisine  33 reviews &quot;My fiancé loves the chicken tikka masala.&quot; Zapata&apos;s Cantina Mexican Restaurant  10 reviews &quot;...son loves the food here and -BONUS- kids eat free on Sunday.&quot; Galway Hooker  31 reviews &quot;Best of all, the Comedy Zone is upstairs.&quot; 
 
Related Lists
 More» 
 Lake Norman Eats 
Decent choices for everything from fine dining to casual noshing in the LKN area.
 Good Food That&apos;s Bad for You :) 
Because sometimes you just want something so bad it&apos;s good. Like that smoldering bad boy you dated in…
 Fast Food Faves 
Where I go for a quick grab when I&apos;m running short on time.
 
 
People Viewed This After Searching For...
 
 Restaurant Cornelius 
 
About

 About Yelp Yelp Blog Press Investor Relations Terms of Service Privacy Policy 
 
Help

 FAQ Advertise Content Guidelines Contact Yelp Business Support Developers 
 
More

 Careers Yelp Mobile The Weekly Yelp Yelp Apparel RSS Top Searches 
 
Countries

 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany 

 Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom 
 
Language

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 
 
 Cornelius Business Listings # A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z | Newly Added | Talk Archive 

 Site Map | Atlanta | Austin | Boston | Chicago | Dallas | Denver | Detroit | Honolulu | Houston | Los Angeles | Miami | Minneapolis | New York | Philadelphia | Portland | Sacramento | San Diego | San Francisco | San Jose | Seattle | Washington, DC | More Cities 

Copyright©2004-2012 Yelp Inc. Yelp logo and related marks are registered trademarks of Yelp. All rights reserved.
 
 Email Address Step 1 of 2 Zip Code 
 
Hey , you can use Facebook to make signing up for Yelp even faster . Yes, use Facebook to sign up 
 Already have an account? Log In Now 
 Email Address Password Zip Code Birthdate (Optional) --- Jan Feb Mar Apr May Jun Jul Aug Sep Oct Nov Dec --- 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 --- 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 2000 1999 1998 1997 1996 1995 1994 1993 1992 1991 1990 1989 1988 1987 1986 1985 1984 1983 1982 1981 1980 1979 1978 1977 1976 1975 1974 1973 1972 1971 1970 1969 1968 1967 1966 1965 1964 1963 1962 1961 1960 1959 1958 1957 1956 1955 1954 1953 1952 1951 1950 1949 1948 1947 1946 1945 1944 1943 1942 1941 1940 1939 1938 1937 1936 1935 1934 1933 1932 1931 1930 1929 1928 1927 1926 1925 1924 1923 1922 1921 1920 1919 1918 1917 1916 1915 1914 1913 1912 1911 1910 1909 1908 1907 1906 1905 1904 1903 1902 1901 Country 
 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom United States 
 
 United States Change 
 
By clicking the button below, you agree to the Yelp Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .
 
 
 Cancel Sign Up 
 
 Use Facebook to sign up faster! 
 Already have an account? Log In Now 
 First Name Last Name Email Address Password City / Town: Zip Code Birthdate (Optional) --- Jan Feb Mar Apr May Jun Jul Aug Sep Oct Nov Dec --- 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 --- 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 2000 1999 1998 1997 1996 1995 1994 1993 1992 1991 1990 1989 1988 1987 1986 1985 1984 1983 1982 1981 1980 1979 1978 1977 1976 1975 1974 1973 1972 1971 1970 1969 1968 1967 1966 1965 1964 1963 1962 1961 1960 1959 1958 1957 1956 1955 1954 1953 1952 1951 1950 1949 1948 1947 1946 1945 1944 1943 1942 1941 1940 1939 1938 1937 1936 1935 1934 1933 1932 1931 1930 1929 1928 1927 1926 1925 1924 1923 1922 1921 1920 1919 1918 1917 1916 1915 1914 1913 1912 1911 1910 1909 1908 1907 1906 1905 1904 1903 1902 1901 Gender (Optional) Male Female Country 
 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom United States 
 
 United States Change 
 
By clicking the button below, you agree to the Yelp Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .
 
 
 Cancel Sign Up 
 No account yet? Create an Account 
 Email Password 
 
 Cancel Log In 
 
Add a Profile Picture

More people will read your reviews and you will be one step closer to the Yelp Elite Squad if you have a profile picture.
 Import Facebook Photo You don&apos;t have Flash installed, Facebook Connect requires the latest version of Flash
	</body>
</document>
