<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000906" url="http://www.medicinenet.com/script/main/art.asp?articlekey=56598&amp;page=2" time="2012-07-12-16:16" support="3" score="0.011978590935246043" bingtitle="More chains offering healthy fast-food alternatives" webtitle="More chains offering healthy fast-food alternatives">
			<query id="000886" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="000446" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="001317" bing-rank="242"/>
	<description>... speaking, is in the &quot;quick casual&quot; rather than fast-food ... &quot;But once it&apos;s on your tray, it will probably make it ... might tip the scale when you go to place your order.</description>
	<body>
		About Us | Newsletter July 12, 2012 
 Follow us on: 
 
 Home Slideshow
Pictures Image
Collection Quizzes Diseases
 &amp; Conditions Symptom
Checker Health
 &amp; Living Medications MedTerms
Dictionary Pet
Health 
 
 Slideshow Pictures 

 All Slideshows Newest Slideshows Pet Health Slideshows 
 
Featured Slideshow
 
Sexual Health

Surprising Health Benefits of Sex

View Slideshow  » 
 
 Image Collection (categories) 

 Allergic Skin Disorders Bacterial Skin Diseases Bites and Infestations Diseases of Pigment Fungal Skin Disease Medical Anatomy and Illustrations Noncancerous, Precancerous&amp;Cancerous Tumors Oral Health Conditions Papules, Scales, Plaques and Eruptions Scalp, Hair and Nails Sexually Transmitted Diseases (STDs) Vascular, Lymphatic and Systemic Conditions Viral Skin Disease Additional Skin Conditions 
 
Featured Image
 
Picture of Psoriasis

A reddish, scaly rash often located over the surfaces of the elbows, knees, scalp, and around or in the ears, navel, genitals or buttocks...

View Image Gallery  » 
 
 See All Quizzes (99) 

 Happiness - Test your emotional IQ Superfoods - Are you eating enough? Fat and Fats - What do you know about fat? Skin Pictures - Can you identify these conditions? Chronic Fatigue Syndrome –What do you know about CFS? 
 
Featured Quiz
 
Take the Sex&amp;Love Quiz!

The brain. The body. The bedroom. What do you know?

View Quiz  » 
 
 Topic Centers 

 Conditions A-Z Procedures A-Z Allergies Alzheimer&apos;s Arthritis Asthma Blood Pressure Cancer Cholesterol Chronic Pain Cold&amp;Flu Depression 
 
 

 Diabetes Digestion Eyesight Health&amp;Living Healthy Kids Hearing&amp;Ear Heart HIV/AIDS Infectious Disease Lung Conditions Menopause Men&apos;s Health 
 
 

 Mental Health Migraine Neurology Oral Health Pregnancy Senior Health Sexual Health Skin Sleep Thyroid Travel Health Women&apos;s Health 
 
 Health&amp;Living 

 Diet&amp;Weight Management Exercise&amp;Fitness Nutrition, Food&amp;Recipes Prevention&amp;Wellness 
 
Featured Topic
 
Weight Loss

The No-Diet Approach

Learn More » 
 
 Medications 

 Supplements and Vitamins 
 
 home &gt; health&amp;living center &gt; nutrition, food&amp;recipes a-z list &gt; fast food: can you indulge without guilt? article
 
 
 smaller medium larger 
 
 Previous 1 2 
 
 
Fast Food: Can You Indulge Without Guilt? (cont.)
 


Hurley also gives high marks to Subway, which, strictly speaking, is in the &quot;quick casual&quot; rather than fast-food restaurant category. She praises Subway for pioneering and promoting healthy, delicious sandwiches with fewer than 6 grams of fat.

Eating out used to be an occasional thing, but today Americans consume about one-third of their total calories in restaurants, says Margo Wootan, DSc, CSPI&apos;s nutrition policy director.

&quot;Both adults and children eat about twice as many calories out compared to eating at home,&quot; she says. &quot;And they eat more saturated fat, and less calcium, fiber, fruits and vegetables.&quot;

She says that healthy fast-food choices often are not obvious, and that consumers need information in order to make good decisions. &quot;One of the policies we&apos;re working on is to get the chains -- both (sit-down) restaurants and fast food -- to list calories on their menus or menu boards,&quot; she tells WebMD.

Kathleen Zelman, MPH, RD, WebMD Weight Loss Clinic Dietitian and American Dietetic Association spokesperson, advises limiting visits to fast-food restaurants to a few times a week. &quot;All foods fit, including an occasional burger and fries,&quot; she says. &quot;You just can&apos;t be living there. Most of the time, try to fill up on salads or grilled chicken.&quot; Given the epidemic of obesity among children, Zelman advises parents to request healthy substitutions for kids&apos; meals, like a small salad instead of fries. &quot;You might have to pay a little more, but you don&apos;t have to get the standard kid meal,&quot; she says.

And by all means, the nutrition experts say, stay away from the chains&apos; &quot;value pricing&quot; promotions, which offer huge portions for a few cents more than regular portions.

&quot;Who doesn&apos;t like a bargain?&quot; Hurley asks. &quot;But once it&apos;s on your tray, it will probably make it to your mouth.&quot;

Future Fare

Of course, this latest healthy fast-food trend could end up going the way of the McLean burger, but industry observers say there are some promising signs.

&quot;Garden Sensations probably accounted for 10 percent of Wendy&apos;s sales when it first rolled out early in 2002,&quot; Butkus says. &quot;That could have been a honeymoon period, but everybody would like to have an extra 10 percent of sales. If this trend is successful, the chains will roll out more products, promote more chicken products and look for ways to make kids&apos; meals healthier.&quot;

And there have been other developments, including:

 In England, McDonald&apos;s offers a bag of apples and grapes to customers. The fruit can be purchased separately or substituted for French fries in Happy Meals. McDonald&apos;s is testing all-white meat Chicken McNuggets. Kentucky Fried Chicken will introduce more non-fried products. Jack in the Box plans to open an &quot;Innovation Center&quot; in 2004 to develop lighter products to attract more female customers. Fast-food chains are paying attention to the appeal of &quot;quick casual&quot; restaurants like Panera Bread, Cosi, and Au Bon Pain, that serve fresh, non-fried foods. Butkus says the fast-food chains might borrow menu ideas. CSPI, noting the dangerous increase in obesity among children, is pushing the chains to stop targeting children with ads for unhealthy foods. &quot;We&apos;d like for them to be good corporate citizens,&quot; Wootan says, &quot;but if not, we&apos;d like the government to step in and limit the advertising to children of foods that are low in nutrition and high in calories, saturated fat and sugar.&quot; 

One sure way to know what you&apos;re getting at the fast-food counter, nutrition experts say, is to consult the restaurant&apos;s nutrition guide. A little knowledge can help you plan your menu selections before you succumb to those yummy-smelling French fries.

These guides, provided by several fast-food chains, contain so much information that they can be daunting. But remember that you don&apos;t have to weigh every single value. Zelman advises making choices based on the number of calories and amount of fat. Simply seeing the difference between a Big Mac and a regular hamburger -- 590 vs. 280 calories, and 34 vs. 10 grams of fat -- might tip the scale when you go to place your order. And don&apos;t forget, you can ask for nutrition guides at the restaurants you visit, or find them online.

Published May 14, 2003.
 
©2003 WebMD Inc. All rights reserved. 
 Last Editorial Review: 5/14/2003 
 
 
 Previous 1 2 
 
 Privacy Policy 
Weight Loss Wisdom

Get tips, recipes and inspiration.
 Health&amp;Living Center 
 Diet&amp;Weight Management Exercise&amp;Fitness Nutrition, Food&amp;Recipes 
 Eating Out&amp;Entertaining Food&amp;Cooking Tips Food&amp;Grocery Shopping Food Safety Nutrition Tips Recipes Special Diets&amp;Recipes Nutrition, Food&amp;Recipes RSS Calorie Counter from WebMD 
 Prevention&amp;Wellness 
 
WebMD Food&amp;
Fitness Planner

Diet and exercise just
got a lot easier.
Introducing the new
way to meet your healthy living goals.
 
Latest Nutrition, Food&amp;Recipes News
 
 U.S. Schools Throwing the Book at Unhealthy Drink Health Tip: Flavor Food Without the Fat Health Tip: Clean Your Fruits and Veggies Gene Boosts Tomato Color, But Make It Less Tasty Pictures of Fatty, Sugary Foods May Spur Cravings Want More News? Sign Up for MedicineNet Newsletters! Health News Feed 
 Use Pill Finder Find it Now 
Pill Identifier on RxList

 quick,
easy,
pill identification 

Find a Local Pharmacy

 including
24 hour
pharmacies 
 Adult Skin Problems Recognize These Skin Conditions? View Slideshow 
From WebMD
 
Nutrition and Healthy Eating Resources

 Spouse Sabotaging Your Diet? Healthy Eating Habits for Teens Healthy Recipe Finder: Heartburn Edition 

Featured Centers

 Dupuytren&apos;s Contracture: What You Need to Know Eating Out? Cut Calories, Heartburn What&apos;s Lurking in Your Mouth? 

Health Solutions From Our Sponsors 

 Treating Depression Joint Pain Help Center Understand Fibro 
 
Health Categories:

 Slideshow Pictures Diseases&amp;Conditions Symptoms&amp;Signs Procedures&amp;Tests Medications Image Collection Quizzes MedTerms Dictionary Pet Health 
 
Popular Health Centers:

 Allergies Arthritis Blood Pressure Cancer Chronic Pain Cold&amp;Flu Diabetes Digestion Health&amp;Living Healthy Kids 

 Hearing&amp;Ear Heart Infectious Disease Men&apos;s Health Mental Health Pregnancy Sexual Health Skin Women&apos;s Health More... 
 
MedicineNet.com:

 Privacy Policy Newsletters Contact Us Site Map WebMD Corporate WebMD Medscape Medscape Reference eMedicineHealth RxList BootsWebMD 
 
Follow Us On:

 Facebook Twitter Google+ RSS 
 Ad Choices ©1996-2012 MedicineNet, Inc. All rights reserved. Terms of Use. 
MedicineNet does not provide medical advice, diagnosis or treatment. See additional information .
	</body>
</document>
