<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000946" url="http://www.hungrygowhere.com/singapore/hong_kong_kim_gary_restaurant_vivocity/" time="2012-07-12-16:18" support="5" score="0.005324774303489143" bingtitle="Hong Kong Kim Gary Restaurant (VivoCity) - Singapore Food Reviews ..." webtitle="Hong Kong Kim Gary Restaurant (VivoCity) - Singapore Food Reviews, Promotions and Information">
			<query id="000305" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="000303" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000298" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000284" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="001381" bing-rank="153"/>
	<description>... The ambience reminds many of a fast-food restaurant in Hong Kong ... remember the exact name) &amp; add $1.50 for a cup of ... &quot;Enter&quot; to submit photo captions.</description>
	<body>
		Best Deals Events Movies News Shopping Travel English 
 English Tiếng Việt Khmer 
 
 Hotmail Messenger Download IE8 SkyDrive 

 Astrology Business Coupon Promotion Dating&amp;Personals Entertainment 

 Football Channel Formula 1 Games Golf Lifestyle 

 Mobile Movies News Property Restaurant Reviews 

 Sports Sudoku Travel Video Weather Forecasts 
 

 Logout HungryGoWhere 
 Singapore Editorial Forum 
 
 Member Login Join 
 Email Password Remember Me 
 Write Review/Vote Suggest A Place New Establishments Latest Reviews 
 Other Cities 
 Ha Noi Ho Chi Minh City Hong Kong Kuala Lumpur Melbourne Phnom Penh Siem Reap Singapore Sydney 
 
 Hong Kong Kim Gary Restaurant (VivoCity) 
 Tweet 
 Restaurant Reviews Photos Quips! 
 
 Address: 1 Harbourfront Walk , #02-128 VivoCity , Singapore 
 
 Tel: +65 6376 8183 
 
 
 Type of Place Bakery/Dessert Restaurant 
 
 Type of Cuisine Asian Chinese 
 
 This place is recommended for Lunch (30) Dinner (29) Large Group (27) Vibrant/Noisy (25) Children/Family (23) After Work (14) Cheap Eat/Budget (14) Girls Night Out (12) Hi Tea (10) Brunch (10) View/Scenery (10) Boys Night Out (8) Waterfront (6) Supper/Night Dining (4) People Watching (3) Chillout (2) Quiet/Peaceful (1) Healthy Eating (1) Private Dining (1) Take Away (1) Breakfast (1) More... Less 
 
 
 Opening Hours Daily: 11am–9.30pm
 Price/Pax: S$5–23 Price Range: $ Based on 35 reviews 63 % Recommended 65 votes Would you recommend this place? Recommend Not Sure Not Recommended 
 Write Review/Vote 
 Change your vote Add Must Try Dishes 
 Add Review View Map Add to List Share Report Close 
 
Reviews
 
 
 Hong Kong Kim Gary Restaurant (VivoCity) 
 2 10 
5

Overall
 
 Irene Soh Not Recommended. 
 
 Food/Beverage: 4 Ambience: 5 Value: 5 Service: 5 
 Disappointing! 18 May, 2012 Dropped by Kim Gary again after a few mths for dinner with family members, only to be disappointed terribly.

We ordered 3 sets meals but only one was served to us, with my dad and I waiting for quite some time. A quick peek at the receipt issue revealed that they had only take note for one set meal. The waiter apologise for the error and promised to serve the remaining 2 sets soon. But that is not the end. They made another error by serving me with the wrong soup. I request for Borsch soup but was given another type instead.

01. S Fish FLT Curry BK Rice

The curry was okie, but the fish had a very heavy frozen taste. Not sure if they had ample time to defrost it properly.

02. Herb Lamb CHP Hot Plate Set

The lamb chop was severely overcook. I had a hard time cutting it, even with the knife provided.

03. GRL CHKN Chop Hot Plate Set

The chicken chop was okie, but the black pepper sauce taste kinda weird to me.

Spent abt $58 in total. Given the amount spent, I was expecting something better than the above. Don&apos;t think I&apos;m going to be back again after this.

 
 Comment Share Management Response 
 
 Please login to leave your comments 
 
 Hong Kong Kim Gary Restaurant (VivoCity) 
 299 13 
7

Overall
 
 The Hungry Bunny Recommend. I spent about S$12 Per Person 
 
 Food/Beverage: 6 Ambience: 7 Value: 7 Service: 7 
 Good if you like such food 05 September, 2011 Read the full review at http://thehungrybunnie.blogspot.com/2011/07/hong-kong-kim-gary-restaurant-vivocity.html 

The food is in the style of Hongkong&apos;s &quot;cha chan tengs&quot;, serving east-west &quot;fast-food&quot;, with a bustling atmosphere and quick efficient service. While I personally don&apos;t fancy such &quot;fast-food&quot;, to have it once a while is fine by me. 

We had:

1)  Mix Curry BK Rice ($11.90) grilled chicken, pork cutlets, ham, hotdogs slathered with cheese and baked till a golden brown. A few fried potatoes, one lonely broccoli floret and hard boiled egg completed the artery-clogging dish

2) A-Mix Set Meal ($10.90) grilled chicken steak, pork chop, sunny-side egg, ham, hotdog, accompanying pepper spaghetti and boiled veggies. Good value for money.

3) Dai Pai Dong Curry Fishballs ($4.90), which is basically fried fish balls with sweetish spicy sambal. Nice.

 
 Comment Share Management Response 
 
 Please login to leave your comments 
 
 Hong Kong Kim Gary Restaurant (VivoCity) 
 120 12 
7

Overall
 
 DanielFoodDiary Recommend. 
 
 Food/Beverage: 8 Ambience: 6 Value: 8 Service: 7 
 One of The Best HK Cafes in SG 14 July, 2011 More reviews at http://DanielFoodDiary.com 

The ambience reminds many of a fast-food restaurant in Hong Kong – uniform green and white hard plastic cards with reflective silver decorations around. If you are lucky, you will be seated near the windows where you will be promised a view of the offshore Sentosa. The ventilation is still rather open, so it does not get too noisy even though it is constantly crowded.

The menu offers a wide variety: From Hong Kong Specialty items like Minced Beef and Fried Egg Spaghetti ($6.90), Shanghai Style Vegetable Rice ($6.90 to $7.90), Hong Kong Chinese Mushroom Rice ($6.90 to $7.90), Hong Kong Spicy Noodles ($7.90 to $8.50), to Korean Spicy Mushroom Noodles ($6.50).

For the budget conscious, order the Hong Kong Style Baked Rice with Cheese Combo (which range from $10.90 to $11.50) which includes a Borsch or Cream Soup, Baked Rice and Drink.

The Chicken Chop version I ordered came in a timsum basket, with a choice of cream or red sauce. The cheese was lightly burnt, rice moist enough, and chicken soft and tender. The lotus leaf at the bottom added fragrance to the warm rice. It was definitely a better version that other dry and cold rice elsewhere.

 
 Comment Share Management Response 
 
 Please login to leave your comments 
 
 Hong Kong Kim Gary Restaurant (VivoCity) 
 63 6 
3

Overall
 
 alan yeo 545 Not Recommended. 
 
 Food/Beverage: 3 Ambience: 3 Value: 3 Service: 3 
 The last of the many HK Cafe in Singapore 15 June, 2011 The menu here has a huge variety of dishes. Most are your typical HK dishes like the cheese baked rice and the noodles and stuff. The food are not really fantastic, i would say they are slightly below average standard. I would spend my $$$ elsewhere. I also recommend this place for:

 Type of Meal : Lunch , Dinner Occasion : Large Group , Children/Family Atmosphere : Vibrant/Noisy 
 
 Comment Share Management Response 
 
 Please login to leave your comments 
 
 Hong Kong Kim Gary Restaurant (VivoCity) 
 249 12 
7

Overall
 
 Princess J Recommend. I spent about S$18 Per Person 
 
 Food/Beverage: 7 Ambience: 6 Value: 7 Service: 7 
 Another yumz in Vivo 04 December, 2010 Met my sis for dinner at Vivo and she wanted to eat at HK Gary. As I have never tried despite the numerous visits to Vivo, I decided to go along with her suggestion.

With the rest of our family of 8, we waited in line for a table enough for us! But good thing was it didn&apos;t take too long, so that was nice.

Sis recommended their grill sets and reviews also said their baked rice is nice so we ordered mainly their grill sets and baked rice.

Their sets come with a soup and I was very taken with their Borsh Soup!! Such a pity it was such a small serving! I also found they are generous with their meat! I guess I shouldn&apos;t be complaining but I&apos;m not that bad a meat fan so I found the serving large.

All in all, I found HK Gary slightly better than Xin Wang tho Xin Wang also have their winning dishes. Am just glad that I have another joint to makan at Vivo now. :)

 Must tries: Grill Sets, Baked Rice Sets I also recommend this place for:

 Type of Meal : Supper/Night Dining , Dinner , Hi Tea Occasion : Large Group , Children/Family , Boys Night Out , Girls Night Out , After Work , Chillout Atmosphere : Vibrant/Noisy 
 
 Comment Share Management Response 
 
 Please login to leave your comments 
 
 Hong Kong Kim Gary Restaurant (VivoCity) 
 188 35 
8

Overall
 
 Caleb Lim Recommend. I spent about S$13 Per Person 
 
 Food/Beverage: 8 Ambience: 8 Value: 8 Service: 8 
 late lunch with family 08 July, 2010 After 1.5 years (based on my last review) I am back at Kim Gary with my family for a late lunch (2pm) after a visit to Sentosa. The place is only 30% full when we entered. The view consist mainly of tall cranes and construction in progress, hope it will be better when RWS is complete.The food is still consistently good (it&apos;s hard to go wrong with lotsa cheese on top). The set meals here ranges from $8 - $12 (++) and include a soup, drink and main course.Borsch soup&apos;s really good. The pork chop and beef steak are tenderized with bicarbonate of soda but not as much as some Chinese restaurants. We loved the almond drink and almond drink with egg but I am surprised that they served the drink before the main course.The ordering system is weird and inefficient. There is a black folder containing about 7 different types of form for different types of dishes and the drinks list appear on several of the forms. Then the waitress have to flip through the 3 forms I used to search for my ticks. Yes, there is a paper trail but why waste the paper and time filling and reading the form? I also recommend this place for:

 Type of Meal : Lunch 
 
 Comment Share Management Response 
 
 Please login to leave your comments 
 
 Previous Review(1) Best HK Cafe so far 26 February, 2009 I concur with most of the reviews that the food standard is quite good given the not too expensive prices. I arrived at 11.45am on a weekday so I get to enjoy the restaurant with 3 other friends when ... Read Full Review 
 
 Hong Kong Kim Gary Restaurant (VivoCity) 
 4 0 
8

Overall
 
 grace ang Recommend. 
 
 Food/Beverage: 10 Ambience: 10 Value: 8 Service: 7 
 Milk teasss 13 May, 2010 I love love love Milk teas!

And I like the milk tea that they served too!

This week my friends and I decided to go for something simple and fast, we also decided to try a shop that we&apos;ve never eaten at in vivo, although we all visit vivo very often.

I enjoyed the simple dinner there, with the nice view of the waters through the glass wall!

The serving was very generous and filling too.

I also realised that so many Singaporeans have their dinner so late! It was around nine plus ten!

Anyway, what I really didnt like was the plate and bowls that they used. I wished that they&apos;d buy nicer looking ones? haha.

Oh, the ordering process was a little too confusing for my friends and I. We need an idoit proof way of ordering food!

 I also recommend this place for:

 Type of Meal : Lunch , Dinner Occasion : Large Group , Children/Family , After Work Atmosphere : Waterfront 
 
 Comment Share Management Response 
 
 Please login to leave your comments 
 
 Hong Kong Kim Gary Restaurant (VivoCity) 
 33 5 
6

Overall
 
 Greedy D. Recommend. I spent about S$18 Per Person 
 
 Food/Beverage: 6 Ambience: 4 Value: 5 Service: 3 
 Poh Kim By Any Other Name 20 April, 2010 Let me admit first off that I’ve walked past this restaurant many times thinking that it’s a DVD store. It’s probably got something to do with the green plastic pillars and navy blue fonts that spell out “Kim”.  I only recently discovered that it was a restaurant as a colleague of mine swore that its instant noodles blew Xin Wang’s out of the water.

I’m not an instant noodle fan, but the seafood cheese baked rice (prawn&amp;abalone) was pretty darn satisfying. At $12.50 a pop though, don’t go in expecting 3 star Michelin -grade food. It’s not fine dining by anyone’s standards, more like Asian junk food .That said, the rice came with a generous serving of prawns, some abalone that tasted fairly authentic, a big mussel and a couple of pieces of marinated squid…all studded in a thick salty baked cheese topping. I finished the meal off with a ginger boiled coke  which was done quite well. It tasted like a sweet ginger tea with a pleasant lemony undertone.

The curry fries were rather yummy too - think Madonald&apos;s fries with a lovely ajinomoto-type curry powder.  Tasty enough to put a smile on your face, but not so potent that you feel your hair falling out as you eat. All in all a pretty comforting meal, and really not too expensive.

My only gripe? The interim receipts (the ones you get while waiting for your food) are printed in Mandarin! So much for  racial harmony eh?

 Must tries: seafood baked rice, curry fries I also recommend this place for:

 Type of Meal : Lunch Occasion : Large Group , Children/Family 
 
 Comment Share Management Response 
 
 Laksa King haha to your DVD comment. I thought the same thing 09 March 2012 11:05 Please login to leave your comments 
 
 Hong Kong Kim Gary Restaurant (VivoCity) 
 27 0 
6

Overall
 
 I Lurve My Food! Not Sure. 
 
 Food/Beverage: 6 Ambience: 6 Value: 6 Service: 6 
 Slightly better than other HK Cafes in SG 18 March, 2010 My experience...

Noisy and crowded... Reminded me of HK cafe just that it is located in a mall, and the design is somewhat nicer.

Sat besides a couple with tables only about 7 inches apart.

Menu was filled mainly cheese dishes. We finally decided on the Pork Chop Burger Macau Style, Supreme Beef Curry Baked Rice, Assorted Mushrooms (double cheese), Yin Yong drink HK style and Fresh Orange and Carrot Juice (I actually wanted Orange and Celery... and just as I am writing, I saw on the receipt that it was wrong all this while, but I hadn&apos;t realised when I was drinking. No wonder there was no celery taste at all!).

Wait staff were quite nice but not exactly friendly. I felt like I was eating in HK where the wait staff don&apos;t serve with smiles much. After seeing the mistake, it is apparent that the service wasn&apos;t worth commending.

Food came.

Pork was marinated nicely. Burger buns were toasted such that it was a bit warm and crispy on the outside. It was kinda&apos; nice.

Beef curry was all right. Beef was a bit chewy.

Mushrooms was good. The double cheese used went very well with the mushrooms, especially inoki mushrooms.

My juice was genuinely very nice. I was quite amazed that there was no celery taste until now that I realised there was a mistake. Nevertheless, it tasted really good. Better than the carrot and orange juice I&apos;ve drank outside.

I didn&apos;t try Yin Yong.

Overall, it was a place good for a hunger fix. Don&apos;t expect any quick fix though.

 I also recommend this place for:

 Type of Meal : Lunch , Dinner Occasion : Large Group , Children/Family 
 
 Comment Share Management Response 
 
 Please login to leave your comments 
 
 Hong Kong Kim Gary Restaurant (VivoCity) 
 23 0 
?

Overall
 
 Ms Junkie Recommend. I spent about S$20 Per Person 
 
 Food/Beverage: na Ambience: na Value: na Service: na 
 at least a close to HK cafe in SG! 09 January, 2010 Had been to too many named HK Cafe, but always to find the food localised (SG style).

Never tried Kim Gary despite my bro&apos;s repeated recommendation.

Decided to try again since he asked again in this new year =)

80% close to what i&apos;ve gotten in HK -- not bad!

but if they include also the Swiss Chicken Wings

they serve the baked rice/ noodle in twin very much like that those in HK

Milk Tea -- evaporated milk and sugar aside (thumbs up for that)

Lemon Ribena Ice Blended ($3.90) -- is well blended like a sobert

Mango Coconut drink -- better than Hui Liu San in HK now

Husband didn&apos;t like the cream soup that comes with the set menu, but this is exactly what i say is HK style

Grill sets with standard drink, soup&amp;garlic bread for $15.50 - $17.50 is indeed a bargain

We had also fries with minced meat sauce and a pork bun to share.

Porkchop is good, unfortunately the bun is no where close (milk taste is too strong).

Just as we end the meal, mummy&amp;me were already thinking what else to eat for the next visit. Portions are huge like in HK too, too stuffed to try the thick toast -- will be back soon! Yup for the moment, this is the closest HK cafe food that i can find in SG and i&apos;m happy Must tries: Milk Tea, Almond Tea, Yin Yang, Ribena Ice Blend, Desserts, Grills, Instant Noodles I also recommend this place for:

 Type of Meal : Brunch , Cheap Eat/Budget , Lunch , Dinner , Hi Tea Occasion : Large Group , Children/Family , Boys Night Out , After Work Atmosphere : Vibrant/Noisy , View/Scenery , Waterfront 
 
 Comment Share Management Response 
 
 Please login to leave your comments 
 
 Displaying 1 - 10 of 45 1    2    3   ...    RESTAURANT MEMBER SEARCH: Name, Dish SEARCH: Member Nickname SEARCH: Name, Dish   Find me Location (Optional) Category search 
 --- all food places --- Bakery/Dessert Beer Bistro/Brasserie Cafe Catering Cha Chaan Teng Coffee Shop Dance Clubs Deli Delivery Fast Food Karaoke Kiosk/Stall Lounge Pub/Bar Restaurant Tea Wine/Spirits --- recommended for --- After Work Alfresco/Outdoor Dining Beer Lists Boys Night Out Breakfast Brunch Buffet Business Breakfast Business Dining Cheap Eat/Budget Children/Family Chillout Corporate Functions Dancing Dinner Fine Dining Girls Night Out Healthy Eating Hi Tea Hidden Find Large Group Live Music Lunch People Watching Pet Friendly Private Dining Quiet/Peaceful Romance/First Dates Supper/Night Dining Take Away Vegetarians Vibrant/Noisy View/Scenery Waterfront Weddings Wheelchair Friendly Wine Lists --- all cuisines --- African Asian   * Chinese      - Beijing      - Cantonese      - Dongbei      - Foochow      - Fujian      - Hainanese      - Hakka      - Hangzhou      - Henan      - Hunan      - Jilin      - Mongolian      - Shaanxi      - Shandong      - Shanghainese      - Sichuan      - Taiwanese      - Teochew      - Xinjiang      - Yunnan      - Zi Char   * Indian      - North Indian      - Pakistani      - South Indian   * Indochinese      - Burmese      - Cambodian      - Thai      - Vietnamese   * Japanese   * Korean   * Malay / Indonesian   * Nepalese   * Nonya / Peranakan   * Philippine   * Singaporean Fusion Halal International Latin American   * Argentinean   * Brazilian   * Caribbean   * Mexican Middle Eastern   * Lebanese   * Persian   * Turkish Pizza Seafood Steak and Grills Steamboat Vegetarian Western   * American      - Cajun/Creole   * Australian   * Canadian   * European      - Belgian      - Czech      - Danish      - Dutch      - English      - French      - German      - Greek      - Irish      - Italian      - Portuguese      - Russian      - Spanish      - Swedish      - Swiss   * Mediterranean      - Moroccan   * New Zealand --- all prices --- S$1 - S$15 S$16 - S$30 S$31 - S$45 S$46 - S$60 above S$60 
 Areas, Locations, Promotions 
 -- All Areas -- City / Central West Jurong / Bukit Batok Orchard / Holland Newton / Bukit Timah Balestier / Geylang East Coast Changi / Pasir Ris Serangoon / AMK North East North Alphabetical Postal   Promotions DBS Standard Chartered Bank UOB In-House Promotion 
 Clear Search Instant Reservations for Lawry&apos;s Singapore, The Cliff, Da Paolo and more at TableDB Hong Kong Kim Gary Restaurant (VivoCity) http://s3-ap-southeast-1.amazonaws.com/hgwcache2/review_photo/21338.jpg/300_225_1291982932.jpg 63 % Recommended 65 votes Based on 45 filtered reviews Is this your business?
 Contact us to post your photos for Free
 Upload Photos &quot;Enter&quot; to submit photo captions. Your photo caption has been updated. 
Location (Mouse over pin for details) 
 If you like Hong Kong Kim Gary Restaurant (VivoCity) , you may also like... Woody Family Cafe (Sembawang) 53% recommend this restaurant. 12F Andrews Avenue 
Sponsored
 Kumo (ICON Village) 71% recommend this restaurant. 12 Gopeng Street #01-58 ICON Village In-house promotion 
KUMO welcomes Spring season with our specially crafted seasonal menus utilizing the best ingredients available.
Japanese Spring vegetables and seafood are carefully paired and harmonized in each exquisite dish by Kaiseki Maestro Chef Nobuaki.
Spring Kaiseki menus start from $78+ per pax. Enjoy our highly popular omakase dining for only $168+ per person!
 
Sponsored
 Swee Choon Dim Sum Cafe 86% recommend this restaurant. Lao Ban Soya Beancurd (Old Airport Road) 79% recommend this restaurant. Marutama Ra-Men (The Central @ Clarke Quay) 62% recommend this restaurant. Recommended by myhgw Community 
Must Tries

drinks
borsch soup
baked rice
ice red bean drink
beef noodles
set meals
french toast
thick toast
pork chop bun
baked items
yin yang drink
borsh soup
pork chop baked rice in two sauces
mini drumlets
baked rice with steak
cheese baked rice
set lunches
double sauce pasta
hotplate drumlets
beef baked rice
supreme curry
drinksnonstiff
mushroom rice
n/a
as above
curry rice/spagetti
hot milk
yuan yang
milk tea
almond tea
yin yang
ribena ice blend
desserts
grills
instant noodles
seafood baked rice
curry fries
grill sets
baked rice sets
 
 Terms of Use Privacy Policy Advertising Policy Review Policy Reliability of Reviews 

 About Us Contact Us Feedback Advertise with Us Press 

 Singapore Barbeque Wholesale BBQ Catering Singapore Food Delivery 

 
 
 
©2012 GTW Holdings Pte Ltd. All rights reserved
	</body>
</document>
