<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000867" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/how-fresh-food-fast-food-restaurant-546609.html" time="2012-07-12-16:13" support="9" score="0.016870405101725404" bingtitle="How to Get Fresh Food from a Fast Food Restaurant - Yahoo! Voices ..." webtitle="How to Get Fresh Food from a Fast Food Restaurant - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="001533" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000995" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000996" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="001468" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="001462" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000959" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000999" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000990" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000965" bing-rank="34"/>
	<description>Fresh food from a fast food restaurant is not an impossibility.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
How to Get Fresh Food from a Fast Food Restaurant
 Bridget Ilene Delaney , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
Sep 18, 2007 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: Fresh Foods Fast Food Restaurants 
 Flag Close All people like fresh food. Most people can agree that fast food restaurants are conveniet. Yet, at times, it seems impossible to get fresh food from a fast food restaurant. This is not true. Fresh food from a fast food restaurant is not a myth. It can be obtained.
In order to get fresh food from a fast food restaurant, diners must arrive there at a certain time. Diners may think that arriving around the mealtime hour is a good solution to getting fresh food. It seems to make perfect sense.

Arrive at lunch time and lunch should be fresh. Arrive at dinner time and dinner should be fresh.

This is not the case.

When it comes to the fast food business, restaurants start preparing food for the meal time rush about an hour ahead of time. For lunch, that&apos;s around 11am and for dinner, that&apos;s around 4pm. Sometimes workers will start preparing the food a bit later or a bit earlier.

If diners are simply driving through to pick up food, arrive with enough time to place an order. Do not expect to definitely get fresh food, though. Even if diners arrive at 11am or 4pm, there&apos;s the factor of what the workers had to do for the day. Other tasks may have prevented them from cooking the food at a certain time.

It is definitely more likely for diners who are driving through to pick up fast food to get fresh food if they arrive an hour before the meal time rush.

Dine-in diners are more likely to be able to get fresh food. Of course, this will depend on the amount of customers that are in line at the restaurant and in line at the drive-through.

Dine-in diners can stand back at the menu acting as if they are deciding what to order if they know what they want or actually discussing orders. While doing this, they can watch what is happening in the back. Diners can then see when new food is starting to be cooked and time when they want to join the line in order to buy fresh food.

The elusive quest to get fresh food from a fast food restaurant can be put to an end.
 
Published by Bridget Ilene Delaney 

Bridget Ilene Delaney is the author of &quot;This is My Bucket.&quot; She has a Bachelor of Science degree in Journalism. She writes many articles on a variety of other subjects. She is interested in diabetes compli...  View profile 
 
 &quot;Healthy&quot; Fast Food: America&apos;s Biggest Oxymoron Seldom today can one go anywhere without being bombarded by food advertisements. Whether it&apos;s a high-rise billboard or a ten second radio commercial, food has worked its way into the everyday lives of Americans. The Old North St. Louis Grocery Store Co-Op Delivers Fresh Food to Area Residents In an old brick building on 13th street local Missouri farmers deliver fresh fruit and vegetables to north side residents. The Spice Rush: How Fast Food is Turning Hot Catch the spice rush in action at a variety of fast food chains that are offering zesty spins on traditional sandwiches and menu items. Learn which bold flavors are best suited for your tastes, and how the trend is mo... Could Living Near a Fast Food Restaurant Be as Bad as Second Hand Smoke? A study at the University of michigan showed that the risk of a stroke in a neighborhood increased by 1 percent for every fast food restaurant that was located there. Ways to Make Fresh Coleslaw That&apos;s Healthier Coleslaw is surprisingly healthy if made right. Here&apos;s how to make fresh coleslaw you can eat without guilt. 
 
 McDonald&apos;s - From Obese Fast Food Grease Joint to Healthy Sophisticated Food Bar How to Eat Healthy at Arby&apos;s Fast Food Restaurant The Alli Diet&apos;s Fast Food Restaurant Choices Fast Food Fix: 75 + Amazing Recipe Makeovers of Your Fast Food Restaurant Favorites Fast Food Myths: How Safe is Your Favorite Food? How to Get Free Food when You Have No Money It is Possible to Order Healthy Items at a Fast Food Restaurant 
 
 
 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Health and Lifestyles Network. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
