<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000628" url="http://www.kcby.com/news/business/March-foreclosure-activity-down-to-near-5-year-low-147155445.html" time="2012-07-12-15:55" support="2" score="0.0007261784561099099" bingtitle="March foreclosure activity down to near 5-year low | Business ..." webtitle="March foreclosure activity down to near 5-year low | Business | KCBY CBS 11 - News, Weather and Sports - Coos Bay - North Bend, OR">
			<query id="000793" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="000400" bing-rank="160"/>
	<description>March foreclosure activity down to near 5-year low ... the pipeline, the faster the market can be in a place to ... Homes can exit the process if the overdue payments are ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to primary navigation Skip to main content 
 KCBY 11 Thurs Partly Cloudy H: 65° L: 53° Fri Partly Cloudy H: 65° L: 54° Sat Partly Cloudy H: 65° L: 54° 
 News 
 Local&amp;Regional National&amp;World Business People at Noon Entertainment Health Technology Consumer Offbeat 
 Weather 
 Weather Cams Regional Conditions Radar Satellite Closures Glossary Tides Ski report Flight Status 
 Sports 
 Inside the PAC Ducks Beavers Preps Professional NCAA Video 
 Politics 
 Local National Video 
 Outdoors What&apos;s Happening KCBY TV 
 TV Schedule CBS Player CBS News Live Feed Newslinks News Staff Contests&amp;Events Birthdays 5 Minute Gourmet Careers Contact Us 
 YouNews Health Connections 
 
March foreclosure activity down to near 5-year low
 By ALEX VEIGA, AP Real Estate Writer Published: Apr 12, 2012 at 7:16 AM PDT Last Updated: Apr 12, 2012 at 1:26 PM PDT 
Share this story

 

 print email 
 LOS ANGELES (AP) - More U.S. homes are entering the foreclosure process, setting the stage for a surge in properties repossessed by lenders this year.

The number of homes that received first-time foreclosure notices rose 7 percent in March from the previous month, foreclosure listing firm RealtyTrac Inc. said Thursday.

That marks the third consecutive monthly increase this year and reflects stepped-up efforts by banks to take action against homeowners who fail to keep up with mortgage payments.

&quot;We&apos;re not out of the woods yet with foreclosures,&quot; said Daren Blomquist, a vice president at RealtyTrac. &quot;There are more batches of foreclosures coming through the pipeline.&quot;

Foreclosure activity, as measured by the number of homes receiving foreclosure-related notices, slowed sharply in the fall of 2010 when claims surfaced that some banks and mortgage servicers were processing foreclosures without verifying documents.

A $25 billion settlement reached in February between the nation&apos;s biggest mortgage lenders and state officials has paved the way for banks to take action on unpaid mortgages, many of which have been in a procedural limbo for months or years. And it&apos;s those homes that could ultimately be foreclosed-upon and end up back on the market.

Foreclosures typically sell at a discount to other homes and can drag down the value of neighboring properties, so the prospect of more foreclosures means it could take longer for home prices in some areas to bounce back.

The U.S. housing market remains weak, even after the best winter for home sales in five years and steady improvement in the job market. Home prices are now back to 2002 levels, according to the Standard&amp;Poor&apos;s/Case-Shiller U.S. home price index.

Rather than a large wave of bank-owned homes crashing onto the market at once, it&apos;s likely the new crop of foreclosures will arrive in smaller waves throughout the year, Blomquist said.

Still, many of the homes entering the foreclosure process now are properties with loans that have gone unpaid for a long time, not instances of borrowers just starting to fall behind. That suggests the possibility that the number of homes at risk of foreclosure could begin to taper off once banks tackle the crop of homes with long-overdue mortgage payments.

&quot;The faster we can move some of these old foreclosures through the pipeline, the faster the market can be in a place to recover,&quot; Blomquist said.

At the end of last year, some 1.5 million U.S. homes had mortgages that had gone unpaid at least 90 days, according to Mortgage Bankers Association data.

First-time foreclosure notices, such as warnings of initial default, are the first step in the process that can potentially result in a home being foreclosed upon. Homes can exit the process if the overdue payments are paid. Sometimes, a bank will allow that the home be sold for less than what the borrower owes on their mortgage, a so-called short sale.

All told, 101,939 U.S. homes received a first-time notice in March, the biggest monthly increase since October, RealtyTrac said.

Thirty-one states posted a monthly increase in homes with a first-time foreclosure notice. Nevada led the pack with an increase of 153 percent.

Even so, foreclosure activity overall - as measured by the number of properties receiving a notice of default, scheduled for auction or repossessed by lenders - sank in March to the lowest level since July 2007, the firm said.

In all, 198,853 homes received a foreclosure-related notice last month, down 4 percent from February, and down 17 percent from March last year.

Banks took back 55,075 homes in March, down 14 percent from the previous month, and down 25 percent from March 2011.

RealtyTrac expects banks will repossess close to 1 million homes this year. Last year, lenders took back 804,000 homes.

For the first three months of this year, foreclosure activity fell 2 percent compared to the last quarter of 2011 and was down 16 percent from the first quarter of last year, the firm said.

Foreclosure activity in the first quarter fell primarily in states where the courts do not play a role in foreclosures. Among them: Arkansas (79 percent), Nevada (62 percent) and Arizona (21 percent).

In contrast, many states where courts must sign off on foreclosures saw outsized increases foreclosure activity, including Indiana (45 percent), Connecticut (38 percent) and Florida (26 percent).
 
Share this story

 

 print email 
 Learn about changes coming to commenting 
POLL: Sun
 
Do you soak up the sun?

 I try to avoid it I wear sunscreen regularly I let it tan my hide I&apos;ve already had a sunburn this spring 
 
 Most Popular 
 
 National&amp;World The week&apos;s best photos (Photo Gallery) 
 By KOMO Staff Published: Jul 6, 2012 at 8:46 AM PDT Last Updated: Jul 6, 2012 at 5:43 PM PDT Read More... 
 Local&amp;Regional Quake shakes beneath ocean off Coos Bay 
 By KCBY News Published: Jul 6, 2012 at 9:46 PM PDT Last Updated: Jul 6, 2012 at 9:46 PM PDT 
A 4.4 magnitude earthquake shook under the Pacific Ocean about 162 miles off Coos Bay on the Oregon Coast, according to the US Geological Survey.
 Read More... 
 Health A Few Unique Ways to Burn Extra Calories -- NEAT (Non-Exercise Activity Thermogenesis) 
 By Charles Stuart Platkin Published: Jan 9, 2008 at 12:27 PM PDT Last Updated: Jan 18, 2008 at 4:02 PM PDT It might be the simplest way to lose weight that ever existed – simply laugh more, stand and pace when you’re on the phone, gesture with your hands when you talk, and lower the heat. Read More... 
 Health You Are What You Poo – What Your Body&apos;s Solid Waste Can Tell You about Your Diet 
 By Charles Stuart Platkin Published: Apr 30, 2008 at 1:04 PM PDT Last Updated: Nov 20, 2008 at 7:10 PM PDT 
I’m going to warn you right now: If you have an aversion to your body’s waste, don’t read any further. However, if you’re like most people, you’re probably very interested in what your stool can tell you about your diet and your health.
 Read More... 
 Entertainment New Vuitton-Kusama collection is a frenzy of dots (Photo Gallery) 
 By SAMANTHA CRITCHELL AP Fashion Writer Published: Jul 11, 2012 at 9:45 AM PDT Last Updated: Jul 11, 2012 at 9:45 AM PDT French fashion house Louis Vuitton is again putting a bit of Japanese culture on the arms of its customers. Read More... 
 Home Large boat runs ashore in Charleston 
 By Ricky Maranon, KCBY News Published: Jul 11, 2012 at 6:12 PM PDT Last Updated: Jul 11, 2012 at 6:12 PM PDT A large boat ran ashore near the Charleston Marina Wednesday morning. Read More... 
 Politics Obama will be in Portland for July 24 fundraiser 
 By Steve Benham KATU.com Politics Editor Published: Jul 10, 2012 at 8:16 PM PDT Last Updated: Jul 10, 2012 at 8:20 PM PDT 
Obama&apos;s campaign began officially asking for supporters to attend the event on its website Tuesday.
 Read More... Copyright©2012 Fisher Interactive Network 
KCBY-TV, 3451 Broadway Fisher Interactive Network 
KCBY-TV, 3451 Broadway, North Bend, OR 97459 Contact Us | Advertise with Us | Media Kit | Careers | Privacy Policy | Terms of Use | Public Filing Report | Closed Captioning Copyright © 2012 Fisher Communications, Inc. CBS Powered by Broadcast Interactive Media .
	</body>
</document>
