<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000170" url="http://www.ocala.com/article/20100608/articles/100609710" time="2012-07-12-15:21" support="8" score="0.005492076937399088" bingtitle="4 from Broward arrested, charged in vehicle burglaries | Ocala.com" webtitle="4 from Broward arrested, charged in vehicle burglaries | Ocala.com">
			<query id="000709" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000241" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000588" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000579" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="000714" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="000573" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="000583" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000578" bing-rank="53"/>
	<description>Real Estate; Jobs; Cars ... were at Jervey Gantt dog park ... at a gas station and at a fast food restaurant. Inside the stopped vehicle, officials found a receipt ...</description>
	<body>
		Ocala.com Ocala Mom Bargain Shouter Veterans Health Pets Mugshots 
 Register | Log in   
 News Web Search by YAHOO! 
 Web Search
by YAHOO! | Home Delivery | eBANNER | Print Ads | Mobile | Place Ad 
 Home News 
 Local State Nation World Business Crime Elections Data Center Photo Galleries Video Weather Mugshots In Education Archive 
 
 Special Section Columnists Storm Guide Data Center Mobile SMS Mobile Alerts Mobile Real Estate Ocala.com Mobile Subscriptions Daily Headlines Breaking News Alerts Star Banner Print Edition 
 Sports 
 Prep Sports Gatorsports.com Colleges NFL MLB NBA NHL Golf Horse Racing Auto Racing 
 
 Scores Football Scoreboard Mobile Stats Blogs Bowling Blog User Photos Opix 
 Entertainment 
 TV Listings Movies Photo Galleries Video Games Events Tickets 
 
 Special Section Johnny on the Spot Multimedia Opix Community Events Calendar Featured Events Deal of the Week 
 Living 
 Health Crossword Sudoku Coupons 
 
 Home Decor In Education TV Listings Multimedia Photo Galleries Video Opix Data Center Restaurant Inspections Mobile Mobile Real Estate 
 Opinion 
 Send us a Letter Editorial Cartoons Blogs 
 
 Blogs The Legal Dish What is That? Snapshots from the Past 
 Blogs Obituaries Classifieds 
 Merchandise Boats Motorcycles Yard Sales Roommates Pets Services Announcements Personals Print Ads Place an Ad Enhance Your Ad Legal 
 

 Real Estate Jobs Cars 
 Home Article Repository 
 Comments Share 
 Digg Reddit LinkedIn Mixx Technorati Myspace 

 FARK FURL 
 Email Print 
 WITH PHOTO NO PHOTO 
 Reprints Enlarge Text 
 Tweet 
 4 from Broward arrested, charged in vehicle burglaries 
 By Austin L. Miller 
Staff writer
 
Published: Tuesday, June 8, 2010 at 9:06 p.m.

Last Modified: Wednesday, June 9, 2010 at 7:27 a.m.
 
OCALA - A rash of vehicle burglaries throughout the city of Ocala on Tuesday resulted in the arrest of four people from Broward County who officials think may be connected to a string of similar cases statewide, authorities say.
 
Arrested by Ocala police officers for several counts of burglary to a conveyance and fraudulent use of credit cards were Gary Burgess, 26, Christopher Whitehead, 30, Alfred Bridgett, 30, and Tammy Bloodsaw, 32. More charges may be pending, officials say.

Police said that inside a black, four-door Dodge occupied by the foursome were a significant number of credit cards and identification cards, and a receipt that authorities say was used from a credit card stolen from a purse in an earlier vehicle burglary.

As of late Tuesday evening, detectives were sifting through the cards. They saw a few that were from Gainesville and Lake City.

Law enforcement officials from surrounding areas such as Gainesville, Leesburg and Lake City have been contacted by Ocala police because police in these areas have reported similar cases of vehicles being burglarized and items removed.

“That&apos;s fast. It&apos;s unbelievable they got them so fast,”said Lisa Stevens, who along with her husband, Jason, were victims of Tuesday&apos;s incidents.

Seated in the lobby of the Ocala Police Department waiting for a purse that contained credit cards and other identifications taken from their Honda CRV, the couple said they were at Jervey Gantt dog park located off Southeast 28th Street with their dogs, Jack, an 8-month-old Great Dane, Bailey, a nearly 2-year-old black and tan German Shepherd, and 1 -year-old Jenna, a white German Shepherd at around 1:30 p.m., when Jason went to get a drink from the vehicle.

After getting the drink, he returned to the area where his wife was and continued playing with the dogs. The couple said they later went to the vehicle when they noticed the front passenger window had been smashed.

Lisa said the doors were locked, and her purse, which was in between the two front seats, was covered with a plastic bag.

“We immediately called the OPD,”said the couple, adding that they quickly canceled their credit cards.

When police arrived, they went to the nearby Aquatic Center, where two vehicles had been reported burglarized.

The Stevens said that when officers finished with their vehicle, went to the Aquatic Center and returned, police told them that the people allegedly responsible for the burglary had been apprehended.

Officials say the crime spree began around 12:30 p.m. when they began receiving calls about vehicle burglaries citywide.

Calls came from College of Central Florida, where windows of at least two vehicles were busted and purses stolen. Then, car burglaries were reported from the 1400 block of Southeast 17th Street by the Duck Pond and from Jervey Gantt.

Witnesses told police of seeing several people in a black vehicle acting suspiciously. A bulletin was put out, and a vehicle stopped by police.

Officers had been told by a victim from the Duck Pond that someone had used her credit card at a gas station and at a fast food restaurant. Inside the stopped vehicle, officials found a receipt from the restaurant on which there was credit card information.

The three men and one woman in the vehicle were taken into custody and transported to the OPD for questioning. While the suspects were being questioned, officials said they recovered purses from trash cans.

Based on evidence collected, officials think the four may be involved in other cases in which vehicles have been burglarized and valuables removed.
 4 from Broward arrested, charged in vehicle burglaries By Austin L. Miller Ocala.com June 9, 2010 7:27 AM &lt;p&gt;OCALA - A rash of vehicle burglaries throughout the city of Ocala on Tuesday resulted in the arrest of four people from Broward County who officials think may be connected to a string of similar cases statewide, authorities say.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Arrested by Ocala police officers for several counts of burglary to a conveyance and fraudulent use of credit cards were Gary Burgess, 26, Christopher Whitehead, 30, Alfred Bridgett, 30, and Tammy Bloodsaw, 32. More charges may be pending, officials say.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police said that inside a black, four-door Dodge occupied by the foursome were a significant number of credit cards and identification cards, and a receipt that authorities say was used from a credit card stolen from a purse in an earlier vehicle burglary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As of late Tuesday evening, detectives were sifting through the cards. They saw a few that were from Gainesville and Lake City.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Law enforcement officials from surrounding areas such as Gainesville, Leesburg and Lake City have been contacted by Ocala police because police in these areas have reported similar cases of vehicles being burglarized and items removed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“That&apos;s fast. It&apos;s unbelievable they got them so fast,”said Lisa Stevens, who along with her husband, Jason, were victims of Tuesday&apos;s incidents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seated in the lobby of the Ocala Police Department waiting for a purse that contained credit cards and other identifications taken from their Honda CRV, the couple said they were at Jervey Gantt dog park located off Southeast 28th Street with their dogs, Jack, an 8-month-old Great Dane, Bailey, a nearly 2-year-old black and tan German Shepherd, and 1 -year-old Jenna, a white German Shepherd at around 1:30 p.m., when Jason went to get a drink from the vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After getting the drink, he returned to the area where his wife was and continued playing with the dogs. The couple said they later went to the vehicle when they noticed the front passenger window had been smashed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lisa said the doors were locked, and her purse, which was in between the two front seats, was covered with a plastic bag.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We immediately called the OPD,”said the couple, adding that they quickly canceled their credit cards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When police arrived, they went to the nearby Aquatic Center, where two vehicles had been reported burglarized.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Stevens said that when officers finished with their vehicle, went to the Aquatic Center and returned, police told them that the people allegedly responsible for the burglary had been apprehended.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Officials say the crime spree began around 12:30 p.m. when they began receiving calls about vehicle burglaries citywide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Calls came from College of Central Florida, where windows of at least two vehicles were busted and purses stolen. Then, car burglaries were reported from the 1400 block of Southeast 17th Street by the Duck Pond and from Jervey Gantt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Witnesses told police of seeing several people in a black vehicle acting suspiciously. A bulletin was put out, and a vehicle stopped by police.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Officers had been told by a victim from the Duck Pond that someone had used her credit card at a gas station and at a fast food restaurant. Inside the stopped vehicle, officials found a receipt from the restaurant on which there was credit card information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The three men and one woman in the vehicle were taken into custody and transported to the OPD for questioning. While the suspects were being questioned, officials said they recovered purses from trash cans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on evidence collected, officials think the four may be involved in other cases in which vehicles have been burglarized and valuables removed.&lt;/p&gt; Copyright 2012 Ocala.com - All rights reserved. Restricted use only. 
All rights reserved. This copyrighted material may not be re-published 
 without permission. Links are encouraged.
 ▲Return to Top 
 Most Read Most Emailed Most Recent 
 
 Former Gator coach Zook enjoying life on Lake Weir Police, community and calendar briefs for July 12, 2012 Doctor: Fla. teen in beating case deeply troubled Ocala city manager proposes cutting $700K from OPD Source: Ex Carroll aide alleges misconduct 
 
 Former Gator coach Zook enjoying life on Lake Weir Last drugs standing: Key Alzheimer results coming Foley gets funny 
 
 Editorial: Finding our voice on water crises Can’t get those O’Brady Burgers off my mind Letters to the editor for July 12, 2012 July 12-18: Live music in Marion County Frankly, my dear, this story sickens 
 
 Photos 

 
 Pictures of the day 07.11.12 
 
 Ballerinas downtown 
 
 Live Oak Flood Residents Revisited 
 
 Pictures of the day 07.10.12 
 
 De Soto series: Day 4 
 
 Ocala All-Stars Challenge Basektball League 
 
 
Events Calendar More Events Submit Event 

 12 Thu 13 Fri 14 Sat 15 Sun 16 Mon 
 
 Find Local Businesses 
 
 Keyword(s): Location: Popular Searches Apartments in Ocala 
 Attorneys in Ocala 
 Auto Dealers in Ocala 
 Auto Parts in Ocala 
 Auto Repair in Ocala 
 Beauty Salons in Ocala 
 Car Rental in Ocala 
 Dentists in Ocala 
 Doctors in Ocala 
 Flowers in Ocala 
 Hotels in Ocala 
 Insurance in Ocala 
 Loans in Ocala 
 Mortgages in Ocala 
 Movers in Ocala 
 Pizza in Ocala 
 Realtors in Ocala 
 Restaurants in Ocala 
 Storage in Ocala 
 Tax Preparation in Ocala 
 Travel in Ocala 
 Featured 
 More... 
Powered by Local.com 
 
 News 

 Local Politics State Nation/World Weather News Archive 
 
 Multimedia 

 Photos Video Blogs Forums 
 
 Sports 

 Local Colleges Professional Youth Horse Racing Golf Tickets 
 
 Entertainment 

 Movies TV Listings Promotions Tickets 
 
 Living 

 In Education Coupons 
 
 Real Estate 

 For sale Rentals Find an Agent 
 
 Classifieds 

 For Sale/Wanted Special Sections Services Legal Rentals Autos Print Ads Place an Ad Enhance Your Ad Local Businesses 
 
 Contact Us About Us Advertising Subscribe Work for Us Help Privacy Policy About Our Ads Corrections RSS Terms of Service Photo Reprints Site Map 
 Copyright©2012 Ocala.com—All rights reserved. Restricted use only.
	</body>
</document>
