<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000008" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/12/1497772/restaurant/Design-District/Sakaya-Kitchen-Miami" time="2012-07-12-15:12" support="2" score="0.0037166647906841602" bingtitle="Sakaya Kitchen - Design District - Miami | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Sakaya Kitchen - Design District - Miami | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000564" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000568" bing-rank="80"/>
	<description>I paid with a credit card, before getting my food, as this is a fast-food place. ... disregarded my request for a to go box because I did not put a ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Miami » Miami-Dade County » Design District » Sakaya Kitchen 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Atlanta Charleston Jacksonville Los Angeles New York Orlando Tampa Bay More... 
 
Sakaya Kitchen
 
(305) 576-8096
 Design District 3401 N Miami Ave 
 Miami , FL 33127 
 sakayakitchen.com 

Added by Harold Deloatch 
 See all 28 reviews Cuisine Asian , Korean , Chinese Feature Outdoor Dining Menu $ Under $10 per entree Tatsuta Age, Age Tofu, Harumaki, Yakitori, Shumai, Gyoza, Yasai Gyoza... View menu 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch               Dinner               Late 
   187 people have voted 92 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 Andiamo! Brick Oven Pizza 92% $$ Little Haiti - Pizza, Italian 5600 Biscayne Blvd 
 
 Puerto Sagua 85% $$ South Beach - Cuban, Coffee, Latin American 700 Collins Ave 
 
Critic reviews

 January 4, 2012 Eater 38 Eater A restaurant serving freshly made, gourmet Asian street fare in the middle of Miami sounds too good to be true, but... More from Eater November 16, 2010 Zagat Check the chalkboard for daily specials at this new Korean Midtown fast... More from Zagat April 8, 2010 Miami New Times Serious Asian food with no frills in Wynwood More from Miami New Times 
 13/20 Gayot In a shopping complex, a locals&apos; &apos;best kept secret&apos; serves creative Korean/Chinese/Thai/Vietnamese fusion fare that&apos;s... More from Gayot 
 Critics&apos; top pick Miami New Times Sakaya serves a concise menu of casual Asian/Southeast Asian fare such as Filipino egg rolls, Japanese miso soup... More from Miami New Times 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews

 June 19, 2012 Really likes it The Primlani Kitchen Even though we had a set itinerary planned for our short visit to Miami, impromptu, I managed to squeeze in Sakaya Kitchen for a quick-lunch stop.  And I must admit, that I am so glad we... More from The Primlani Kitchen June 14, 2012 Miami Culinary Tours This week is a whole new stage in my life and even though I leave things behind, what always stays with me is the passion for food. I am happy I have food as a companion, I admire food, I... More from Miami Culinary Tours August 28, 2011 Likes it Fatgirl Hedonist Sakaya Kitchen helps me not kill people on the drive home. More from Fatgirl Hedonist July 22, 2011 Be a Wok Star One of my fav at Sakaya Kitchen is Spicy Dae Ji pork tenderloin with coconut rice&amp;buttered broccoli. It encompasses all the flavors that make me think of Asia! More from Be a Wok Star March 1, 2010 The Chowfather akaya is a very casual spot specializing in Korean type fare. Richard Hales is chef/owner who spent time as chef over at The Mandarin Oriental in Miami.. The menu is written on the wall... More from The Chowfather 
 Show 1 more 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 July 11, 2012 Likes it Good Stuff by C.D.S. ( 29 reviews ) This place is awesome, just go. June 14, 2012 Vietnamese bun by Miami Culinary Tours ( 80 reviews ) Then I got temped with these pork Vietnamese version of a petite sandwich which is a classic I know at every Vietnamese place. It was good, sweet and salty, enough to feed anyone for lunch or for a flu snack in the middle of the day. I give this little sandwich a 7 because something was missing, not exactly sure what was missing but something certainly was. August 16, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by Miami4me2c ( 18 reviews ) THIS IS WHAT FOOD TRUCKS GOURMET IS ABOUT! Dim Ssäm à GoGo is king! Was at The Margate Festival @ JM Lexus and this is #1 Items that are a MUST: *Kurobuta pork belly bao buns with chili sauce (Heavenly light bun and a multitude of flavors that makes you savor every bite) *Gingered Brussels sprouts (golden caramelized and crunchy) Do not despair if the lines are longer than those at any other truck but are well worth the wait. (learn to gauge the crowd and understand that customers come in waves when you at these events) Cheers! 1 out of 1 found this review helpful February 13, 2012 Likes it I would go back by hawkke6 ( 12 reviews ) Drove from central Broward on a coworkers suggestion to try this place out, worth the trip if you ask me. I had the bulgogi burger, tator tots and shrimp / pork egg rolls. Everything was very good. The burger was the best of the three but the tator tots were very good. I would make the drive again. February 22, 2010 Doesn&apos;t like it Disapointment by rjc ( 16 reviews ) Service: I paid with a credit card, before getting my food, as this is a fast-food place. I was instructed to leave a tip in advance, for fast food service. Need I say more. Menu: Choices are very limited. There was no seafood of any type available. I wanted to have sake, however, there was only a choice of mini bottles available, at $28 each. Get real, this is a FAST-FOOD place. Poor choice of beer as well. Ambiance: 1970&apos;s rock music blasting from the speakers. The bathroom was filthy. Food: The kimchi was pretty good and that&apos;s about it. The rice, both the brown and white, was sweet, dry, overcooked and tasteless. The ribs were so over roasted that the consistency was that of pate. I like tender ribs, but these had no texture at all. The wings were nothing special. Overall, everything lacked even simple flavors, much less complex layers of flavor I expect in Asian cuisine. I would not return. 2 out of 2 found this review helpful January 12, 2012 Likes it Spicy Tater Tots... by Mabel ( 12 reviews ) This place is what I can describe as very unique. Had the Pork bun and the spicy tater tots. Didn&apos;t really like the texture of the bun but the tater tots were amazing! I still recommend though, a lot of interesting items on the menu..The actual restaurant is much better/fresher than their food truck.. December 4, 2010 Likes it Mobile review by Defamed ( 47 reviews ) Awkward ordering process, mediocre execution do not compromise an overall unique experience, particularly for Miami. Nice food, lively ambiance. Gringo Korean for beginners. March 6, 2010 Likes it Mobile review by CL ( 27 reviews ) Of course all u have to do is tell them and they change the music. Walked in hungry and left very satisfied....go try it for a change of pace. +1 more review from CL March 6, 2010 Mobile review Pork roast swank with salad and grilded chicken with rice and salad were both excellent. Music too loud but food is good. January 8, 2012 Likes it Good .......but c&apos;mon 26$ per head! by Danny Reyes ( 1 review ) Its good but but I spent 26 dollars very quick there. For 2 ppl your spending 45$ easy. The food is good don&apos;t get me wrong but at the end of the day it&apos;s still fast food . January 18, 2010 Mobile review by Harold Deloatch ( 7 reviews ) Great new restaurant in the Design District. November 17, 2010 Likes it Good option for fast food... by Diner n Miami ( 14 reviews ) ...nice asian / healthy concept. a good option for a quick cheap out-of-the-box fast food meal. July 2, 2010 Likes it Really enjoyed it by sobeiam ( 4 reviews ) So nice to find good Asian food aside from sushi in the Miami area. I love that they use spice and different flavors combined with locally sourced or organic ingredients. I loved the soft shell crab bun. I thought the ribs were too sweet but that is usually how I feel about ribs. Having said that though I loved the Korean fried chicken with scallion waffle that has a sweet/spicy maple sauce on it. Next time I will ask for that on the side. I can&apos;t wait to go back and try other things. March 4, 2011 Likes it WOW! by aleja ( 6 reviews ) this is the kind of food I crave. i am married to the ribs in orange sauce with brussels sprouts and rice, fortunately as I dont go alone, i have been able to try other dishes as well, all of them very good. unpretencious good food at reasonable prices. March 22, 2010 Likes it Loved it again by Lisa ( 1 review ) Stopped by today for lunch (3rd time i&apos;ve been) and loved it again. We t ried some the new stuff on the menu we did not see before, Korean chicken and waffles, roku beef slider w spicy blue cheese, soft shell steamed bun. all were fantastic and a good balance of spiciness. Also, had the ribs again and sooooo good. I am not sure who is creating these dishes but they are nailing it. cool funky place for asian and so glad they opened in my hood. March 18, 2011 Food great... service sketchy by Mel P ( 1 review ) I&apos;m always craving their burgers and usually eat from the DSAGG truck. Went to Sakaya two days ago and thought all was well .. nice ambiance etc. You pay before you get your meal so I did with my card intending to leave a tip in cash at the end of my meal. Well needless to say no tip was left after the much to be desired waiter completely disregarded my request for a to go box because I did not put a tip on my card. Way to work for your tip buddy. .. and no he did not forget because when i went to get it myself the box was practically thrown at the cashier after she requested it from him for me. .. Anyway the food is awesome and thus you all should try it and hope if said waiter is there he is not on his monthly cycle. March 20, 2010 Likes it Great place by Toni ( 1 review ) Went after I read all the reviews online and left very happy. Tried the pork buns, ribs and beef lettuce wraps - loved the flavors. The pork buns were my favorite and friend loved the ribs. Def a different type of Asian restaurant w/ the punk to classic rock music playing. 
 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by Miami Culinary Tours Sakaya Kitchen by Billie Nomnom Edamame, potato... 
 All 12 photos View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Five Guys Burgers and Fries 86% $ Design District - Burgers, Hot Dogs/Sausages, Fast Food Yogurbella $ Design District - Desserts/Ice Cream, Smoothies, Coffee Gigi 83% $$ Design District - Barbecue, Noodle Shop, Tapas Pieducks $ Design District - Pizza, Salads, Organic Vega Baja Cafeteria Design District 
 More nearby restaurants 
Nearby Places

 Hialeah Race Track Park -
NE 32nd St&amp;NE 4th Ave Midtown Inn Miami -
3400 Biscayne Blvd 
 People reached this page by searching for: 
 sakaya sakaya kitchen sakaya kitchen menu sakaya kitchen miami menu korean bbq miami 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
