<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000435" url="http://www.wowjobs.ca/job/Cashier+(Retail+Hardware+Store+Cashier)-timberjack+building+supplies-edson+ab-9339647" time="2012-07-12-15:41" support="1" score="0.0018512689315265919" bingtitle="Cashier (Retail Hardware Store Cashier) Job - EDSON - Timberjack ..." webtitle="Cashier (Retail Hardware Store Cashier) Job  - EDSON - Timberjack Building Supplies Job Id: 9339647 -WowJobs Canada">
			<query id="000288" bing-rank="98"/>
	<description>... and clean counter area, Greet customers, Enter ... - Restaurant Cashier (Part-time) Jobs Clerk Cashier C ... Fast food restaurant manager (Assistant Food Service Manager ...</description>
	<body>
		Employers My.WowJobs Sign In 
 
 
 Keywords (Job Title or Skill) Location (City, Province or Postal)   Advanced Search 
 


 
Cashier (Retail Hardware Store Cashier) job - EDSON - Timberjack Building Supplies
 



 
 Cashier (Retail Hardware Store Cashier) (Expired) Timberjack Building Supplies EDSON Cashier (Retail Hardware Store Cashier) ( NOC: 6611 ) Terms of Employment: Permanent, Full Time, Weekend, Day Salary: $11.11 Hourly for 40 hours per week Anticipated Start Date: As soon as possible Location: Edson, Alberta (1 vacancy) Skill Requirements: Education: Completion of high school Credentials (certificates, licences, memberships, courses, etc.): Not required Experience: Experience an asset Languages: Speak English, Read English, Write English Work Setting: Retail establishment Business Equipment: Price scanner, Cash register, Interac machine, Calculator, Computer terminal Specific Skills: Customer service oriented, Operate cash register, Process money, cheques and credit/debit card payments, Scan items, Stock shelves and clean counter area, Greet customers, Enter prices of items on cash register, Wrap or place merchandise in bags Essential Skills: Working with others, Computer use Employer: Timberjack Building Supplies Ltd. How to Apply: Please apply for this job only in the manner specified by the employer. Failure to do so may result in your application not being properly considered for the position. By Mail: 4840 2nd ave. Edson, Alberta T7E 1T6 In Person between 9:00 .... Found at Jobbank on 2010-12-10 13:07:04 



 
 Recent
	</body>
</document>
