<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000033" url="http://deals.woot.com/deals/details/114fa625-3cfd-4f9e-ae37-959d63363b36/the-most-interesting-box-mystery-box" time="2012-07-12-15:13" support="1" score="0.0008431619418203327" bingtitle="&quot;The Most Interesting Box&quot; - Mystery Box for $24.99 - mystery, box ..." webtitle="&quot;The Most Interesting Box&quot; - Mystery Box for $24.99 - mystery, box">
			<query id="001432" bing-rank="182"/>
	<description>Will report in upon receipt. Hope its worth it GearXS. ... Mine&apos;s nowhere near 5 lbs... 1.4 lbs. The suspense builds! ... Purchases through Deals.Woot don&apos;t count, because in ...</description>
	<body>
		Woot 
 The original deal pioneer keeps on pinching pennies and cracking wise. No, that price isn&apos;t a typo.
 Go to Woot. 
 Today&apos;s Woot Dyson DC35 Multi Floor Vacuum $199.99 Refurbished Woot Plus 
 Altec Lansing Camping Essentials SOLD OUT Gunnar Optiks Advanced Computer/Gaming Glasses 
 Home.Woot 
 High living at low prices with name-brand deals for your pad, crib, nest, or castle - inside and out.
 Go to Home.Woot. 
 Today&apos;s Woot Water Tech Robotic Pool Cleaner $499.99 $1,299.99 62% off List Price Woot Plus 
 Momeni Harmony Rugs Wolfgang Puck Kitchen SOLD OUT WoodWick Candles 
 Sport.Woot 
 Sports, fitness, and outdoors deals, because saving money is only one of your passions.
 Go to Sport.Woot. 
 Today&apos;s Woot Callaway RAZR X Black Driver (460cc) $169.99 $249.00 32% off List Price Woot Plus 
 Daiwa Fishing Shape Up Teva Footwear 
 Kids.Woot 
 Deals for moms and dads and anybody else who needs kids&apos; stuff, from toys to baby gear to furniture to clothing.
 Go to Kids.Woot. 
 Today&apos;s Woot Boppy Nursing Pillow and Slipcover $22.99 $49.99 54% off List Price Woot Plus 
 Melissa and Doug Kids Activities Guidecraft Wooden Furniture Ohio Art Nanoblocks 
 Shirt.Woot 
 Our exclusive graphic tees will make you laugh, will make you cry, will make you look totally hot.
 Go to Shirt.Woot. 
 Today&apos;s Woot FURBALL! $12.00 Woot Plus 
 Caffiends 
 Wine.Woot 
 Direct from the winery to your thirsty lips: wine deals worth doing a spit-take over.
 Go to Wine.Woot. 
 Today&apos;s Woot Triacipedis the White III (5) $59.99 Woot Plus 
 Lucas&amp;Lewellen Vineyards J. Dusi Wines 
 Sellout.Woot 
 Last chance deals for hardcore cheapskates. Catch &apos;em before they - you guessed it - sell out.
 Go to Sellout.Woot. 
 Today&apos;s Woot Turtle Beach Gaming Headset $39.99 Refurbished Woot Plus 
 Deals under $50 Gaming Accessories 
 Community Sourced Deals.Woot 
 289,130 deals (and counting) from around the web, shared and ranked by a community of deal fiends like you.
 Go to Deals.Woot. 
 Top Community Deals 
 27 Home - Krispy Kreme Doughnuts and Coffee for $0.75 @ krispykreme.com 6 Comments 37 Word Shaker: Appstore for Android for $0.00 + free shipping @ amazon.com 2 Comments 32 Cowboy Bebop: The Movie [Blu-ray] for $8.99 @ amazon.com 5 Comments 
 
 New to Woot? Start here or Sign in Stuff You Bought | Your Account beta feedback 
 Deals.Woot 

 community deals ask the community leaderboard what is deals.woot? 
 
 deals → &quot;the most interesting box&quot;- mystery box for $24… 
 18
	</body>
</document>
