<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000799" url="http://www.bukisa.com/articles/192555_the-five-most-unhealthy-fast-food-burgers" time="2012-07-12-16:10" support="3" score="0.010216786969390672" bingtitle="The Five Most Unhealthy Fast Food Burgers" webtitle="The Five Most Unhealthy Fast Food Burgers">
			<query id="000594" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="001107" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="000887" bing-rank="145"/>
	<description>You&apos;re hungry for the taste of a freshly cooked hamburger and you don&apos;t have time for a sit down meal so you pull into your local fast food restaurant and order one ...</description>
	<body>
		Share your Knowledge Hi, please Log In or Log in via or Join now Publish Content Featured Content Get Help Other categories 
 Health&amp;Nutrition › Diet&amp;Nutrition 
 You are in: Home » Health&amp;Nutrition » Diet&amp;Nutrition »The Five Most Unhealthy Fast Food Burgers 
The Five Most Unhealthy Fast Food Burgers
 Nov 17th, 2009 by Kristie.Leong.M.D 1 comment 
 Most fast food burgers couldn&apos;t be classified as health food, but here are five that really stand out. Discover America&apos;s most unhealthy hamburgers. 
 
You&apos;re hungry for the taste of a freshly cooked hamburger and you don&apos;t have time for a sit down meal so you pull into your local fast food restaurant and order one of their featured burgers. How much harm are you really doing to yourself with that extra thick burger from the fast food restaurant? Unfortunately, more than you might think. Here are some of the burgers who might win the prize for most unhealthy burger:
 
Most unhealthy burger: Carl&apos;s Jr. Double Six Dollar Burger

This one is a doozy both for size and the number of calories and fat grams. Would you believe this hamburger weighs in at 1520 calories and 111 grams of fat? You may satisfy your hunger by devouring this monstrosity, but you&apos;ve pretty much blown your calorie quota for the day. If you&apos;re courageous enough to eat the six dollar burger, don&apos;t add insult to injury by ordering the French fries.

Most unhealthy burger: Hardee&apos;s Monster Thickburger

While some fast food restaurants have moved towards adding healthier selections to their menu, Hardee&apos;s has made a name for itself by bucking the trend. After adding the Monster Thickburger to their menu, they experienced a turnaround in sales. The question is how many heart attacks did they create in the process? At 1420 calories and 107 grams of fat, this burger is not for the faint hearted or the squirrelly eater. What&apos;s on the Monster Thickburger? Try two third pound slices of Angus beef, three slices of cheese, four strips of bacon, and mayonnaise all on a buttered bun. Let&apos;s hope your gall bladder can hold up to the fat challenge you&apos;re going to give it when you eat one of these doozies.

Most unhealthy burger: Hardee&apos;s Double Bacon Cheese Thickburger

Hardee&apos;s gets top honors again for an unhealthy burger creation. It&apos;ll set you back 1300 calories and 96 grams of fat. The only thing it may be a better choice than is the Monster Thickburger. At least you&apos;re saving 120 calories. If you&apos;re concerned about healthy eating, it might be best to ignore that red and yellow Hardee&apos;s sign that beckons to you from the road.

Most unhealthy burger: Hardee&apos;s Double Thickburger

It&apos;s beginning to look like a trend with Hardee&apos;s winning three most unhealthy designations in a row. Although slightly healthier than the previous two Hardee&apos;s creations, your cardiologist still wouldn&apos;t approve. At 1250 calories and 90 grams of fat, don&apos;t be surprised if you feel like a grease ball after you devour the last bite. Some people actually find this burger to be tasty in a decidedly unhealthy sort of way. If you&apos;re using this as a splurge, come with a big appetite!

Most unhealthy burger: Burger King Triple Whopper Sandwich with Cheese

It looks like a single or double Whopper wasn&apos;t enough for the voracious appetites of Americans. Burger King had to challenge them with the triple version of the time tested Whooper. At 1230 calories and 82 grams of fat, it offers only a slight improvement over the Hardee&apos;s burgers. If you&apos;re going to order this culinary cardiac nightmare, at least ask them to add some extra lettuce to assuage your guilt.

Yes, the fast food burger market is a minefield when it comes to your health. Do your research and tread lightly. Did I mention that Burger King has a 340 calorie veggie burger?


 
Written by Kristie.Leong.M.D 

 Rate this Article: 
 digg it reddit this
	</body>
</document>
