<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000938" url="http://www.freesamplesite.com/ydf/showthread.php/252175-List-of-fast-food-receipts-that-give-free-food-with-survey" time="2012-07-12-16:18" support="15" score="0.02575310148721207" bingtitle="List of fast food receipts that give free food with survey" webtitle="List of fast food receipts that give free food with survey">
			<query id="000678" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000677" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000241" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="001380" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="001526" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000240" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000052" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="001463" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="001404" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="000051" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="001464" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="001400" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="001396" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="001525" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="001403" bing-rank="18"/>
	<description>To start viewing messages, select the forum that ... filling out the survey on the bottom of your receipt. ... Fast Food &amp; Restaurant Coupons; Drug Store &amp; Pharmacy Coupons</description>
	<body>
		Register Help Remember Me? 
 
 Home Forum 
 FAQ Calendar Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 

 
 Blogs What&apos;s New? 
 
 Advanced Search 
 
 Forum YDF Freebies - Discounts - Deals Freebies - Discounts - Deals List of fast food receipts that give free food with survey 
 
 If this is your first visit, be sure to
 check out the FAQ by clicking the
 link above. You may have to register before you can post: click the register link above to proceed. To start viewing messages,
 select the forum that you want to visit from the selection below. 
 + Reply to Thread Page 1 of 8 1 2 3 4 5 6 ... Last 
 Jump to page: 
 Results 1 to 10 of 71 
Thread: List of fast food receipts that give free food with survey 
 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Search Thread 
 
   Advanced Search 
 
 
 02-19-2009,  10:28 AM #1 jkshel 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Mar 2001 Posts 191 
List of fast food receipts that give free food with survey
 I wanted to start a new list of fast food restaurants that will give you a free food item for filling out the survey on the bottom of your receipt. The surveys can be done over the phone or online. Usually it is an automated phone survey that takes a few minutes, and you are given a code to write in on your recipe to present as a coupon. Ill start with the two I have:

Taco Bueno
Free taco or bean burrito (limit one per day)

Arbys
Free Roast Beef or Beef n cheddar sandwich (must complete within 2 days)

If you know of any please post and lets help each other save some money!

JTF Reply With Quote 02-19-2009,  11:01 AM #2 JoyNPeace7 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Dec 2006 Posts 1,043 I went to Burger King last week. On the back of my receipt was an opportunity to take a survey. At the end you get a code good for 1 free hamburger. Reply With Quote 02-19-2009,  12:21 PM #3 KrissyG89 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Sep 2007 Posts 414 I think Wendy&apos;s will give you a free frosty if you fill out their survey on the back of the receipt. But I&apos;m not sure... Maybe someone can check on that? Reply With Quote 02-19-2009,  12:24 PM #4 classic pooh 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Jun 2001 Location The Heartland Posts 1,305 Buffalo Wild Wings will give you six traditional wings if you fill out their survey. Reply With Quote 02-19-2009,  12:29 PM #5 bunny420 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Apr 2006 Posts 685 Papa Murphys will give you free choclate chip cookie dough survey takes 3 mins Reply With Quote 02-19-2009,  12:33 PM #6 Kolbycheese 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Aug 2007 Posts 250 Sonic gives you a free Route 44 drink if you do the survey at the bottom of their receipt. It can be a Premium drink too, like cherry limade or slushes! Reply With Quote 02-19-2009,  12:39 PM #7 AmberGA 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries Visit Homepage View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Dec 2003 Posts 573 thanks! Reply With Quote 02-19-2009,  12:42 PM #8 audrey2580 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Oct 2007 Posts 319 Panda Express does a buy 1 entree get 1 free after their survey Reply With Quote 02-19-2009,  01:07 PM #9 kittygirl3 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Nov 2008 Posts 66 
Free Food For Survey
 On my receipt from Wendy&apos;s last night - they changed it from a free frosty to a free single hamburger (cheese or bacon extra). Reply With Quote 02-19-2009,  03:10 PM #10 sweetjenn 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Sep 2008 Posts 102 Thank you soooo much for sharing,I had no idea they did this . Reply With Quote
	</body>
</document>
