<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000630" url="http://www.nytimes.com/keyword/food-waste" time="2012-07-12-15:55" support="4" score="0.004235011497260181" bingtitle="Articles about Food Waste - New York Times" webtitle="Articles about Food Waste - New York Times">
			<query id="000463" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="001028" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000450" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="001060" bing-rank="13"/>
	<description>Food Waste News. Find breaking news, commentary, and ... In the past, farmers sometimes amde deals to pick u food ... family can easily spend $20 for one meal at a fast-food ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Page Today&apos;s Paper Video Most Popular Times Topics Most Recent 
 Help Register Now Login Search All NYTimes.com Article Collections COLLECTIONS &gt; FOOD WASTE 
Food Waste
 FIND MORE STORIES ABOUT : 
 Rikers Island Pollution Charities Garbage Recycling 
 
 
 New York Takes Out the Trash 
 To the Editor: Composting, which you advocate, is not a method likely to be used extensively in an urban setting like New York City (editorial, July 13). A far better answer exists in expanding the use of food waste disposers. Instead of expensive and environmentally damaging truck-based collection, transfer and export to distant landfills, food waste collected through existing underground infrastructure ends up as fertilizer on agricultural land -- the same goal, but more efficiently accomplished. July 16, 2002 
 Waste, Down the Drain 
 To the Editor: In addition to outdoor composting at Rikers Island and basement worm &quot;factories&quot; (letters, Jan. 25), New Yorkers have another option for the efficient and beneficial disposal of food waste: in-sink food waste disposers. The common use of so-called garbage grinders was legalized in New York City in 1997. The use of &quot;garbage grinders&quot; would greatly reduce the percentage of food waste in the city&apos;s residential waste stream. Moreover, since pulverized food from in-sink food disposers ends up in sewage and is reused for agricultural purposes, the disposers offer an environmentally preferable... February 1, 1999 
 
 
 Less Food for Rats 
 To the Editor: &quot;Rat Fears&quot; (editorial, July 16) cites &quot;every slight change in the way humans handle garbage,&quot; including expanded street collection and penetrable plastic bags instead of building-based incineration and metal cans, as contributing to New York City&apos;s expanding rat problem. New York residents now have another option, widely practiced across the country: use of food waste disposers that use a building&apos;s plumbing system to immediately rid kitchens of food waste. July 23, 2000 
 &apos;Grinding Garbage In the Sink&apos; 
 To The Editor: Your otherwise interesting article discussing food waste disposers [&quot;Grinding Garbage in the Sink,&quot; Dec. 7] neglected any real discussion of their benefits. From my work with residential building management, I know that food waste disposers can eliminate the damage that leaking garbage bags cause to floors, hallway carpets, elevators, stairwells and trash chutes. If this wet, dripping garbage is no longer awaiting pickups from waste haulers, then other things could be eliminated as well, such as feasts for roaches, rodents and other vermin, time spent by building maintenance... December 14, 1997 

 
 Cheap Food Is Costly 
 To the Editor: The cost of wasting food should not be reported in merely economic terms (Week in Review, Sept. 21). One of the major reasons not to use more food than we need is ecological. Agriculture and meat production are very hard on the environment. So are processing, packaging and shipping. The billions of pounds of food wasted annually represents vast amounts of other waste, including water, fertilizers, agricultural run-off and fossil fuels, to produce the energy used in production. September 24, 1997 
 Food for the Hungry 
 To the Editor: &quot;Cutting Waste Can Be a Waste&quot; (Week in Review, Sept. 21) focused on a handful of critics who believe that recovering excess food is a waste of time because it doesn&apos;t pay off economically. But that food adds up to 96 billion pounds a year -- nearly a third of the United States food supply. I agree that food waste is a sign of our prosperity and agricultural abundance. But amid all this plenty, nearly 12 million Americans may face food insecurity this year. Food recovery is a highly organized effort to rescue mass quantities of excess, edible food throughout the commercial food chain. September 28, 1997 
 
 
 Pigs Dig In to Help Recycle Trash 
 A bag of orange peels and melon rinds may be nothing more than yesterday&apos;s garbage to most people. But thousands of Philadelphians know that a human&apos;s food scraps can make a feast fit for a pig, and they are doing something about it. People throughout the city have been leaving their eggshells and steak bones on the curb for New Jersey pig farmers to pick up and feed to their swine. The farmers make predawn rounds through the city, collect the feed from waste cans and haul it back to their farms. February 20, 1994 
 Energy From Your Sink 
 To the Editor: An Aug. 21 letter discusses the needless loss of a potential source of energy through the export of New York&apos;s garbage to out-of-state landfills. But much of this energy would be available if the food-waste portion of the trash -- about 15 percent of the city&apos;s solid waste -- were ground by residents with in-sink food-waste disposers, which have recently been made legal in the city. The infrastructure is already in place in the city&apos;s water-pollution control network, which not only conveys ground garbage efficiently and noiselessly to 14 waste-water treatment plants but also converts most of... August 24, 2000 

 
 BY THE WAY; From Your Table to the Pig Sty 
 Anybody who cooks and eats has to dispose of table scraps. The same is true, on a much bigger scale, for restaurants, super-markets, hospitals and other institutions. In the past, farmers sometimes amde deals to pick u food scraps and feed them to their pigs. A year-old company called Enviro-Feed does much the same; it collects food waste (at a lower price than the garbage man) and takes it to its facility in Perty Amboy, where it turns it into dry feed that is sold for farm animals. January 30, 2000 
 Cruise Industry Accepts Ban On Dumping in Inside Passage 
 A cruise ship industry group has assured government regulators that ships will not dump untreated sewage or ground-up garbage in loosely regulated parts of Alaska&apos;s Inside Passage. At a meeting between industry officials and environmental regulators on Friday, a main topic of concern was those areas where raw sewage and ground-up garbage may legally be dumped. Most of the Inside Passage is a maze of narrow channels, straits, canals and fjords, but a few areas of open water are three miles or more from land, which technically makes them international waters. December 5, 1999 

 
 This Week: Look Ahead 
 BY ANNE RAVER The midsummer lull is a good time to start thinking about next year&apos;s game plan. Do you need better-raised beds, more manure and compost, a new, sunnier space for cut flowers and vegetables, fall cover crops to add nitrogen to the soil and make it tillable. Even city dwellers can cut down on their garbage and make compost by using redworms. In New York, agents at the Cornell Cooperative Extension, 15 East 26th Street, will teach you how to compost newspaper and food waste with worms in a box, right in your kitchen. July 21, 1991 
 Will America Make World Safe for Global Warming?; Let&apos;s Generate Less 
 To the Editor: &quot;How Do You Fix a Broken Planet?&quot; (Living Section, April 25) highlighted well the frustration of citizens who want to help the environmental cause but are overwhelmed by conflicting advice. While the article noted confusion over garbage management options, it failed to mention the most crucial of all - source reduction. Source reduction leads the Environmental Protection Agency&apos;s hier-archy of waste management options, followed by recycling, incineration and landfilling. May 14, 1990 
 
 
 The Way We Live Now: 9-16-01: Salient Facts: Alternative Energy; The Dregs 
 BY ROBB MANDELBAUM The crisis in California&apos;s grid seems to have abated for now, but in its wake, it has left renewed interest in alternative energy technologies. By 2006, the state hopes that 17 percent of its power will come from renewable energy, and it is now allocating $135 million a year to meet that goal. But California has its work cut out: last year, only 12 percent of its energy came from alternative sources. Here&apos;s what is in the pipeline. FOOD IS FUEL Recently, Los Angeles World Airports, which manages LAX, began hauling small amounts of... September 16, 2001 
 Recycling and Incineration Dispose of Different Kinds of Waste 
 To the Editor: In &quot;Why Dump Recycling?&quot; (Op-Ed, May 29), Barry Commoner makes a good point: we could recycle more than we do. However, he is mistaken in his belief that waste-to-energy plants -- which burn garbage as fuel -- are in economic competition with recycling facilities. As a major supplier of both, we firmly believe that an integrated solution of recycling, composting of leaves and yard waste and, finally, burning the rest in modern waste-to-energy plants, makes the most sense. June 13, 1991 

 
 What&apos;s Wrong With Irradiating Food? Plenty; Feasible and Safe 
 To the Editor: Your Jan. 21 front-page article on food irradiation is reminiscent of stories aired during the early years of milk pasteurization. Foes of any new technology, then as now, eventually fade from the scene as consumers recognize the benefits and embrace it en masse. There are indeed a few romantic souls who even today cling to the imagined (metaphysical?) benefits of raw, untreated milk; and they will go so far as to deny others this newfangled pasteurization technology. February 6, 1992 
 Degradable Plastics and Recycling Don&apos;t Mix; Misguided Campaign 
 To the Editor: I applaud the tenacity of Tanja Vogt, the West Milford, N.J., high school sophomore who led a campaign to ban polystyrene trays from her school cafeteria (news story, April 28). Unfortunately, her actions will exacerbate the problem. There is a growing feeling in this country that it would be environmentally responsible to ban plastics. But we need simply to look at the title of Tanja&apos;s inspiration, Thomas Paine&apos;s &quot;Common Sense,&quot; to see what is missing in this debate. May 12, 1989 
 More Popular Articles about Food Waste : 
 1 2 3 4 NEXT PAGE &gt; 
 Home Times topics Member Center Copyright 2012 The New York Times Company Privacy Policy Help Contact Us Work for Us Site Map Index by Keyword
	</body>
</document>
