<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000049" url="http://www.theage.com.au/national/one-dead-in-twocar-smash-20090126-7pl9.html" time="2012-07-12-15:14" support="2" score="0.001032999213135768" bingtitle="One dead in two-car smash at Frankston - The Age - Business, World ..." webtitle="One dead in two-car smash at Frankston">
			<query id="000704" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000802" bing-rank="177"/>
	<description>... they were in was in a collision with another car ... said Karen Gill, manager of a nearby fast-food restaurant. ... investigating the death of a woman at Noble Park ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to navigation Skip to content Help using this website - Accessibility statement 
 JavaScript disabled. Please enable JavaScript to use My News, My Clippings, My Comments and user settings.

 New feature Personalise your news, save articles to read later and customise settings View Demo 
 Hi there! 
 Sign-up Log in 
 Beta version 
If you have trouble accessing our login form below, you can go to our login page .
 
If you have trouble accessing our login form below, you can go to our login page .
 
 11:14PM Thursday Jul 12, 2012 958
 online now See today&apos;s paper 
 Fairfax Digital 
 The Age Real Estate Cars Jobs Dating Newsletters More 
 Essential Baby Stayz InvestSMART Trading Room Weatherzone More sites» 
 
 
 The Age 

 National 

 Investigations Environment Multimedia Photos Blog Central 

 You are here: Home National Article 
 
Search age:
 
Search in:

 theage.com.au 
 theage.com.au Web 
 
 
One dead in two-car smash
 Date January 26, 2009 
 Read later 
 
Britt Smith
 
 Tweet Pin It Email article Print 
 
The scene of this morning&apos;s crash at Frankston in which one man was killed. Photo: Angela Wylie 
 
A man died and four young males were injured - two seriously - when an early morning fishing trip turned to tragedy in Frankston this morning.

Police say four mates were driving to Frankston to go fishing when the sedan they were in was in a collision with another car at traffic lights at the intersection of Ferndale Drive and Cranbourne Road about 6.40am.


Both drivers were trapped for 45 minutes. The 23-year-old driver of the sedan died at the scene. His passengers, 16, 17 and 18, all from Cranbourne, were injured.
 
 View Larger Map 
The driver of the second vehicle, a 24-year-old from South Morang, suffered upper-body injuries and was flown to The Alfred hospital where he was in a stable condition.

 Advertisement 
Police closed the intersection and diverted traffic.

Ambulance Victoria spokesman Ray Rowe said two
of the injured - the 16-year-old and the 24-year-old - were taken to The Alfred hospital and others to Royal Melbourne Hospital.


A witness described the aftermath of the crash as &quot;chaotic&apos;&apos;.

&quot;There were two cars and both were badly damaged, totally crumpled,&apos;&apos; said Karen Gill, manager of a nearby fast-food restaurant.

&quot;It looked pretty serious, there were police everywhere and they are still out there now.&apos;&apos;

Frankston police Sergeant Bruce Buchan said the men in the sedan were driving to Frankston to go fishing.

 
 Tweet Pin It Email article Print Reprints&amp;permissions 
 
Related Coverage
 
 Woman found dead in home 

 26 Jan Homicide squad detectives are investigating the death of a woman at Noble Park North about 10.15pm yesterday.
 Advertisement 
 
 Latest Video 
 
National News Video More video 
 
We will get him: Police

Police say they are confident they will get the man who fatally attacked Tom Kelly in Kings Cross at the weekend.
 
 Click to play video 
 &apos;I don&apos;t have anger&apos; 
 Click to play video 
 House fire contained in Carrum 
 Click to play video 
 Pilot dies in Broome plane crash 
 
 
 Featured advertisers Sponsored links 
Special offers Powered by Mozo 
 View these special offers by Mozo. Advertisement Advertisement 
 Real Estate 
 
 Renovating bit by bit 
 
 Domain.com.au Buy real estate Need an inspection report? Download a Domain mobile app 
 
 Jobs 
 
 Personalise your job search with MyCareer 
 
 Mycareer.com.au Sign up to the new MyCareer Don&apos;t miss the latest jobs. Job search 
 
 Find A Babysitter 
 
 Juggling between family&amp;work? Get help now! 
 
 Findababysitter.com.au Melbourne Child Care Geelong Child Care Shepparton Child Care 
 
 Holiday Rentals 
 
 Find the best deals in executive accommodation 
 
 Rent-a-home.com.au Sydney city accommodation Melbourne accommodation Short-term rentals 
 
 Managed Funds 
 
 Top Performing Investments In 2012 
 
 Investsmart.com.au Want to become a millionaire? 6.01% Term Deposit! One-off Share Sales 
 
Compare and Save
 
Skip to:

 Best Deals Mobile Broadband Home Loans Credit Cards Low Rate Cards Rewards Cards Savings Accts Term Deposits Loans 
 
Check out today&apos;s best deals
 
 USaver Rate Increase 
 
 NEW 5.71% bonus rate for popular USaver account 
 
 Compare rates 
 
 ANZ Online Saver 
 
 5.25% bonus rate. Until 30/11/2012 
 
 Check it out&gt;&gt;&gt; 
 
 UHomeLoan 
 
 Low 5.62% comparison rate + $500 EFTPOS gift card 
 
 Save now&gt;&gt;&gt; 
 
 Bonus Beats Headphones 
 
 On HTC One S and HTC One. RRP of $279 
 
 Free Headphones 
 
 Samsung Galaxy S3 
 
 Save 10% online, compare double data offers and more.... 
 
 Compare Online Deals 
 
Readers&apos; most viewed
 Most viewed articles on Brisbane Times 
Top 5 National articles

 A weight off your mind - and your knees Nation of workers sitting on sidelines The great desert hope Australian drug carrier faces 15 years Slow and steady no longer wins the race 
 Most viewed articles on WA Today 
Top 5 National articles

 Duck producer in trouble over &apos;false claim&apos; ads This cosmetic surgeon wants others to advertise in a responsible manner G20, we don&apos;t want it: Doyle What really happened when asylum seekers&apos; boat exploded Australian drug carrier faces 15 years 
 Most viewed articles on The Sydney Morning Herald 
Top 5 National articles

 Bid to play down child abuse shows denial persists Coles gains reprieve in NSW Duck producer in trouble over &apos;false claim&apos; ads Singer who made the Cross swoon From Croatian poverty to property empire 
 Most viewed articles on Canberra Times 
Top 5 National articles

 Breastfeeding could contribute to nut allergies: new study HMAS Canberra, captured in construction Coles goes to umpire to avoid more strikes &apos;No misconceptions whatsoever&apos; about Muslims No turning back on Abbott navy stance 
 Most viewed articles on The Age 
Top 5 National articles

 This cosmetic surgeon wants others to advertise in a responsible manner Breastfed babies develop nut allergy: study Women&apos;s perfection push must stop: Therese Rein Duck producer in trouble over &apos;false claim&apos; ads Allowed to get away with it 
 
 The Age Home Victoria National World Environment Opinion Business Technology Digital Life Entertainment Life&amp;Style Travel Cars Exec Style Sport Weather 
 
 
The Age
 Sitemap About Us Contact Us Advertise With Us AM Today Last 8 days Text Version Site Accessibility Guide 

 
Products&amp;Services
 Subscribe to the Newspaper Manage My Subscription Subscriber Benefits Good Food Guide The Age Shop Newsletters 

 
Connect
 Mobile Site The AGE for iPad Digital Edition iPhone App RSS Facebook Twitter LinkedIn 

 
Classifieds
 Place an Ad Classifieds&amp;Notices Accommodation Cars Dating Jobs Property Price Data Real Estate Trading Post Tributes&amp;Celebrations 

 
Fairfax Media
 Member Centre Conditions of Use Privacy Policy News Store Archive Photo Sales Purchase Front Pages Fairfax Syndication Fairfax Events Fairfax Careers Press Council 
 Fairfax Media 
Our Sites

 The Sydney Morning Herald The Age MyCareer Domain Drive RSVP Essential Baby InvestSMART APM Stayz Weatherzone The Vine 

Our Partners

 Business Hair Salons Electricians Fitness Homebuilders Lawyers Mechanics Wine Wedding Wine 
 Copyright©2012 Fairfax Media
	</body>
</document>
