<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000620" url="http://businesstips.ph/how-to-franchise-jollibee-in-the-philippines/" time="2012-07-12-15:55" support="4" score="0.0037634340728823364" bingtitle="How to Franchise Jollibee in the Philippines | Business Tips ..." webtitle="How to Franchise Jollibee in the Philippines | Business Tips Philippines">
			<query id="000427" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="000178" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="000930" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001390" bing-rank="211"/>
	<description>... you on how to get a franchise of this famous fast-food ... Upon receipt of application, this will take 2-3 months ... must activate the subscription in your email to receive ...</description>
	<body>
		Home About Popular Partners Contact Forum Directory Business Management Marketing Money&amp;Finance Internet&amp;Technology 
 Home » Business » How to Franchise Jollibee in the Philippines 
How to Franchise Jollibee in the Philippines

Mar 16, 2011 by Victorino Abrugar at Business , Franchise 
 
How to franchise Jollibee in the Philippines? It’s very inspiring to see businesses booming in our own land, and Jollibee is one of those popular original Philippine brands that have successfully provided the Filipino people with excellent products and services. If you are planning to start a business, you may want to start an already successful business through franchising. Though it requires higher investment and capitalization, you will have a higher chance to get your money back than starting on your own business. If you want to have a slice of Jollibee’s proven success, the following will guide you on how to get a franchise of this famous fast-food restaurant in your area. 

 
 What is Jollibee? 

Jollibee is a leading fast-food restaurant chain based in the Philippines. It began as a two-branch ice cream parlor in 1975 offering hot meals and sandwiches and became incorporated in 1978 with seven outlets to explore the possibilities of a hamburger concept. In 1984, Jollibee hit the P500 million sales mark, landing in the Top 500 Philippine Corporations. In 1987, barely 10 years in the business, Jollibee landed into the country’s Top 100 Corporations. It became the first Philippine fast food chain to break the P1 billion sales mark in 1989. In 1993, Jollibee became the first food service company to be listed in the Philippine Stock Exchange; thus broadening its capitalization and laying the groundwork for sustained expansion locally and beyond the Philippines.

The Jollibee mascot was inspired by local and foreign children’s books. Lumba created the product names“Yumburger”and“ChickenJoy”. He had the company incorporated and leased a house on Main St. in Cubao, Quezon City as the first headquarters. Every Filipino, especially kids, know Jollibee. At present, there are more than 600 Jollibee stores in the Philippines. More than half of these are operated by franchisees. However, demand does not wane and opportunities still abound in various regional operations in and around Mega Manila, North Luzon, South Luzon and the Visayas-Mindanao areas. Market opportunities extend to territories abroad. Currently, Jollibee operates 26 stores in the USA. It is also present in Brunei, Hong Kong, Saudi Arabia and Vietnam.

 
 Qualifications of a Jollibee franchisee 

The following are qualifications Jollibee looks for in a franchisee:

•  An entrepreneur who is self-driven;
•  Knows how to motivate his people;
•  Willing to devote time to oversee the day to day operation of his restaurant;
•  Willing to undergo a full time training on restaurant operations;
•  Ability to fund the investment requirement.

 
 How much is the investment required for a Jollibee restaurant? 

The financial requirement depending on the final store size and facilities ranges from P15 to P30 Million. This investment includes the construction of the store, kitchen equipment and facilities, furniture and fixtures, air-con system, signage, and pre-operating expenses.

 
 Steps on applying Jollibee franchising 

The following are the steps on the initial application of a Jollibee franchise.

1. Download and print a copy of the Franchise application form . Please make sure to fill-out the form completely.

2. Prepare a proposal containing the following documents:

•  Letter of Intent–containing the exact address of your proposed site, your exact mailing address, contact numbers, etc.
•  Vicinity Map of Proposed Site–that will more or less guide our field personnel who will go there and conduct an on-site evaluation.
•  Legal document certifying applicant’s ownership of the site.
•  Detailed resume or bio-data.

3. Mail these documents to:

 JOLLIBEE FOODS CORPORATION 
Franchising&amp;Events Department
9th Floor Jollibee Plaza
#10 F. Ortigas Jr. Road
Ortigas Center, Pasig City 1605

Upon receipt of application, this will take 2-3 months of processing. However, submission of an application form does not obligate you or Jollibee in any way. It is just the first step in the application process, which is an evaluation of your proposed location.

Jollibee franchise ranges from 15M to 30M (USD266,445.00 to USD532,890.00). Details of investment cost, return of investments and other franchising details will be discussed with you once your application has been approved.

To learn more about franchising Jollibee, please visit the Franchise page of Jollibee Food Corporation .
 
About Victorino Abrugar 

 Victorino Abrugar is the founder and chief writer of BusinessTips.Ph. Vic is a social media enthusiast who loves to share his knowledge and insights through blogging. He provides business coaching to aspiring small business owners and entrepreneurs to help them reach their business and life&apos;s goals. Follow him on Twitter @viclogic 
 
Related Posts
 
 Richest People in the Philippines (June 2012) 
Posted on Jun 21, 2012
 Business Philippines 
Posted on Jun 19, 2012
 What is SALN (Statement of Assets, Liabilities, and Net Worth)? 
Posted on May 29, 2012
 May 2012 CPA Board Exam Results and List of Passers 
Posted on May 20, 2012
 
 
Tags
 
 fast-food restaurant franchising franchising company Jollibee Philippines startup 
 
Receive Free Business Tips in Your Inbox!
 You must activate the subscription in your email to receive free business tips daily. You can unsubscribe anytime. We respect your privacy. 

 

 
Leave a Comment
 Click here to cancel reply. 
 Name (required and must be your real human name) 

 Mail (required and will not be published) 

 Website (put your website here and not on the comment field) 

 Spam protection: Sum of 3 + 6 ? 

 
Important: Repetitive questions will not be approved. Hence, before asking any question, please make an effort to read the article, previous comments and answers first. Further, please post your comment or question on the relevant articles. Kindly spare some time to browse our list of articles in the “Archives Page” ”. Please help us save more time we can use to continue writing, researching and providing 100% free and useful information for everyone. We reserve the right to reject any comment that will not follow these guidelines. Thank you.
 
 
Connect and Subscribe
 Follow me on Twitter 
We Recommend
 
Recent Tips
 
 7 Small Business Tips from Babies 
Posted on Jul 10, 2012
 18 Personal Development Tips for Entrepreneurs 
Posted on Jul 5, 2012
 5 Business Tips for Success 
Posted on Jul 5, 2012
 How to Earn Passive Income Online Through Blogging 
Posted on Jul 4, 2012
 5 Success Tips for Business Owners and Entrepreneurs 
Posted on Jul 3, 2012
 
 
Advertisement
 
Popular Tips
 
 How to Compute Withholding Tax on Compensation (BIR Philippines) 10 Small Business Ideas in the Philippines How to Compute Income Tax in the Philippines (Single Proprietorship) List of Famous Filipino Entrepreneurs and their Brands November 2011 Philippine Bar Exam Results (2012 Release) 
 
Recent Discussions
 
 Victorino Abrugar on 6 Factors to Consider when Investing in the Philippines Alvin on How to get a TIN ID from the BIR Philippines tata on 15 Tips to Make Your Small Business Successful Ann on How to get a TIN ID from the BIR Philippines Alvin on Penalties for Late Filing of Tax Returns 
 
Tags
 BIR blog blogging brand business businessman business tips company corporation customers employees employment entrepreneurs entrepreneurship Facebook finance Financial Statements human resource management income-tax Internet internet marketing leader leadership List management marketing money motivation Online Business organization people personal development Philippines sales self-help self-improvement SEO small business social media success tax taxation tips website work 
Categories
 Select Category Accounting Amazing Business Banking Blogging Branding Business Business Advice Business Development Business Ethics Business Guide Business Ideas Business List Business News Business Quotes Business Regulation Business Startup Business Tips Economics Entrepreneurship Entrepreneurship Quotes Financial Analysis Franchise General Marketing HR Management Incorporation Insurance Internet&amp;Technology Investing Jobs and Career Labor Laws Law&amp;Government Leadership Leadership Quotes Make Money Online Management Management Quotes Management Tips Marketing Marketing Quotes Marketing Tips Money&amp;Finance Online Marketing Personal Development Personal Finance Philippine Laws Politics Real Estate Registration Religion Sales Tips Search Engine Small Business Social Media Social Responsibility Society Sports&amp;Events Tax Tips Taxation Technology The Richest Top Business 
Archives
 Select Month July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 
Copyright © 2011-2012 • BusinessTips.ph • All Rights Reserved | Archives | Advertise | Links | Terms, Disclaimer&amp;Privacy Policy 
 &lt; &amp;lt;a href=&quot;http://s49.sitemeter.com/stats.asp?site=s49biztipzph&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;img src=&quot;http://s49.sitemeter.com/meter.asp?site=s49biztipzph&quot; alt=&quot;Site Meter&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;/&gt;&amp;lt;/a&gt;
	</body>
</document>
