<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000769" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/45885619/A-new-Type-of-Third-Place" time="2012-07-12-16:07" support="1" score="0.008032976184488541" bingtitle="A_new Type of Third Place - Scribd" webtitle="A_new Type of Third Place">
			<query id="000108" bing-rank="45"/>
	<description>... by democracy and sociability, a place to sit and where ... test the clarity of the questions and the order ... Older adults’ frequent visits to a fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 Comment Go Back 
 Download   A new type of “Third Place”? Alix Slater Alix Slater Consultancy&amp;Training Ltd, London, UK, and Hee Jung Koo London College of Communication, University of the Arts London, London, UK Abstract Purpose – The purpose of this paper is to explore the notion of “Third Place” in an arts context by exploring the consumption of two arts venues, Tate Modern and the Southbank Centre (SBC) on the regenerated South Bank in London, UK. Design/methodology/approach – A n int erp ret ati ve phe nom eno log ic al app roa ch wa s tak en drawing on 45 qualitative interviews that were conducted in and around Tate Modern and the SBC during Autumn 2009. Findings – Four audience groups were identiﬁed segmented by their motivations, experiences and feelings about the two buildings. The ﬁrst group “Place to see” visit Tate Modern and the SBC to attend exhibitions and performances. The second meet friends and spend time in the cafes and bars using them as a “Place to hang-out and meet”. The third group use the buildings as a “Place to drop-in” on their way to somewhere else. The fourth group use the SBC as a “Third Place”, to study, for meetings, to read, escape and rejuvenate. Research limitations/implications – This was an exploratory paper. Further research is required to test the ﬁndings in other art museums, arts venues, libraries, parks and other public and private spaces within communities. Originality/value – The paper ﬁlls a gap by drawing on the “Third Place” literature to explore the consump tion of art museums and venues . It provide s us with a bette r understandin g of the meanings these public buildings have to individuals, the way they are used by the public and how arts managers might attract new audiences from their communiti es. It also provides insights for planners and town centre managers as to the types of places individuals are seeking during their daily lives. Keywords Arts, Museums, United Kingdom Paper type Research paper Introduction In his book, The Great Good Place (1999) Oldenburg argues that gathering places such as bars, coffee shops and barbers, places that are not home or work, are “Third Places”. The idea of a third place is not a new notion. For years people have gathered in coffee houses, social and sports clubs, pubs and taverns for informal association, to have a drink and talk (Olden burg and Brisset t, 1982). Oldenb urg and Brissett ’s (1982) original interest was in the decline of American comm unity life and the loss of such places with the result that many people spend most of their time at work or home. Oldenburg (1999) argues that these places are essential to community and public life and provide health beneﬁt s as they offer social interaction, combating loneliness and giving people a se ns e of re ali ty th rou gh co nv ers at ion . Pu tn um (20 00) has bro ug ht the iss ue of community life back to the fore with his bestselling title, Bowling Alone, the Collapse and Rev iva l of Amer ica n Com mun ity th at di sc us ses in so me de tai l th e ong oin g insularity of the American population. The current issue and full text archive of this journal is available at www.emeraldinsight.com/1753-8335.htm A new type of “Third Place”? 99 Journ al of Place Manageme nt and Development Vol. 3 No. 2, 2010 pp. 99-112 q Emerald Group Publishing Limited 1753-8335 DOI 10.1108/17538331011062658   Although art museums and venues have been recognised as places to spend leisure ti me th ey ha ve no t be en co ns id er ed as “T hi rd Pl ac es ”. Th e pu rp os e of th is st ud y is to ﬁl l th is gapin th e lit era tu re . Ta te Mod ern , an artmuse um andthe So ut hb ank Ce nt re (S BC) , a mi xed art s ve nu e we re ch ose n as st ud y sit es . Bot h are si tu ate d on th e re ge ne rat ed Sou th Ba nk on th e ban ks of th e Riv er Th am es in Ce nt ral Lo nd on , UK alo ng sid e oth er attractions such as the London Eye and Shakespeare’s Globe, restaurants, retail spaces, private and public housing and community facilities. We sought to ﬁnd out why and when individual s come to Tate and SBC, with whom, what they do there, how they feel about the buildings and the meanings people attach to these places. The paper is org ani sed in to fo ur par ts . Fi rst , we rev ie w th e ex ta nt lit era tu re on “T hi rd Pl ac es ” an d th e co ns ump ti on of art mu se um s and ve nu es . In th e me th odo log y, we de scr ibe th e qualitative approach to data collection and analysis. We then report the ﬁndings and conclude the paper with theoretical and practical implications of this research. Theoretical context A “Third Place” describes publi c places that are not home or work where people gather voluntarily, informally and frequently. One of the characteristics of a “Third Place” is that it is homelike, where people feel psychologically comfortable and can unwind, re ge ner at e, fe el at eas e and ﬁn d com pa nio nsh ip. Th ey are ne ut ral pla ce s, eas ily accessible and often in non-descript buildings that have a low proﬁle in the community. Th ey are ch ara ct eri se d by de mo cr acy and soc iab ili ty , a pl ace to si t and whe re conversation is important, the mood is playful and everybody is treated as an equal. Their users consider them as “their own” and they see them as part of themselves, unique places where they can have experiences and relationships that they cannot access elsewhere (Oldenburg and Brissett, 1982; Oldenburg, 1999). “Third Places” have been described as places to escape to (Glover and Parry, 2009), however, Oldenburg (1999, p. 282) argues that “Third Places” are not just a place to escape, but enabling places, that provide a “temporary world within their ordinary world”. Ironically, Oldenburg and Brissett (1982) would not have been able to predict that home and work would merge with the creation of the world wide web and other technological advances (Khermouch and Veronsky, 1995). In the UK, it is estimated that 3.5 million people, 12 per cent of the working populat ion, now work from home, an increase of 600,000 people since 1997 (IT Forum Foundation, 2009). This has resulte d in a new trend, individuals working from home looking for public places for social interaction during the week but not in the same way as in the past. Individuals want people around them but do not necessarily want to interact in the same way. Their engage ment is more likely to be virtual as they communicate with others through their laptop and mobile telephone. Bookstore and cafe ´ owners have met this demand by cr eat in g pl ace s in th e com mu ni ty wh ere in div id ual s ca n acc es s fr ee Wi- Fi, bu y refreshments and read a book or do some work in a comfortable space where they feel they belong. We suggest these spaces are still providing “Third Places”, not home or work, but not quite as Oldenburg imagined. In the extant literature restaurants (Cheang, 2002; Rosenbaum, 2006), curling clubs in rural Canadian communities (Mair, 2009), sports stadiums (Suny, 1993), libraries (La wson , 2004 ), a farm er’s mar ket (Ti ema nn, 2008 ) and “vir tual ” env iron ment s (Sou kup , 2006) have all been explored as “Third Places”. Some of these studies have been site speciﬁc, others comparative. Lawson (2004) argues that libraries are the best JPMD 3,2 100   type of “Third Place”, welcoming everybody regardless of creed, age and economic sta tus, prov idin g soc ial inte ract ion, inf orma tion and ind epen den t lear ning for a ple thor a of tastes. The physical stimuli, social experiences and interactions that occur in these pl ace s mak e th em me ani ng ful to in div id ual s tra nsf orm in g th em fro m pla ce s of consumption to places of signiﬁcance, i.e. a “Third Place” (see Rosenbaum, 2006 for a review). For example, Glover and Parry (2009) found cancer patients and their family and friends use Gilda’s Club as a therapeu tic landscape to seek refuge and escape from ho me and ho sp ita l (fo r ma ny wor k wa s no lon ge r an opt ion ). Th is is si mi lar to St oko ws ki (2 00 2) an d So ja ’s (1 99 6) id ea s of a “T hi rd sp ac e” , wh er e sp ac e is se en as a co mb in at io n of the phys ical space and it ’s social s igniﬁcan ce, as “rea l and imagined p laces” (So ja, 1996, p. 6) and Lynch’s (1960, in Silva, 2009) “imageability” in a city context. As Stokowski (2002, p. 372) summarises, the socio-cultural meanings attached to places are “created and reproduced through interpersonal interaction, formalized in social behaviour and ultimate ly persist in collect ive memory”. A “Third Place” is not, however, a permane nt state, places can lose their character if a particular group dominate with a single purpose (Oldenburg and Brissett, 1982) or a place changes, for example becomes touristic (Tieman n, 2008). This is important in the context of this study as some arts venues are ﬁndings members’ rooms in particular are being taken over by freelancers using them as free meeting rooms and work spaces. Furthermore, iconic buildings such as Tate Modern attract large numbers of tourists that for some visitors impairs their own experience. At this point it is imp ortant to high light what we kno w about the cons umption of art mus eum s and ven ues draw ing on the soci ology , mark etin g and vis itor stud ies lite ratu re. There is an establis hed body of work documentin g who consume s the arts, with whom (AC E, 2008 ; DiM aggi o, 1996; Kra ckma n, 1996 ; McC arth y and Jin nett , 2001 ; Slat er, 2007b ; Tr ien ke ns, 200 2; Ve rda asd on k, 199 6; van Eij ck , 199 7; Wal ke r et al . , 20 02 , 20 08 ) an d wh y (s ee Sl ate r, 200 7a for a su mm ary ) and th eir be ha vio ur in th e mu se um (F alk and Di er kin g, 199 2; He in, 199 8; RO M, 197 6). In th e sam e way , th e “T hir d Pl ace ” lit er atu re has loo ke d at the building and social interactions that take place in it. Falk and Dierking (1992) de ve lop ed a mo de l su mm ari sin g th e mu se um ex pe rie nc e as th e ou tc om e of an individu al’s int eractions with t he phy sical, s ocial and personal contex ts. These insights have led to the modern art museum that includes dedicated space for resting, eating, drinking and shopping during the museum visit and has led some critics to comment that museums have been “disneyﬁed” and become “experiencescapes” (Hall, 2008). It is becoming evide nt that some visitors only use these retail and catering spaces and may never look at a painting or attend a performance or event (Rentschler and Hede, 2007; Slater, 2007a) although there is limited literature exploring this type of consumption. In contrast, retailers put considerable effort into understanding how their customers consume the “servicescape” and how they can use atmospherics and design to create an image and inﬂuence behaviour, for example, extending the shopping experience (Bitner, 1992). Rosenbaum’s (2006) study of a casual dining restaurant in the USA draw on place research in a marketing context (Sherry, 2000). He identiﬁes three types of customers: place-as-practical, place-as-gathering and place-as-home. The ﬁrst group may or may not revisit, the second group’s loyalty might be temporal as it is dependent on others wanting to meet there and the ﬁnal group saw the restaurant as a home, sometimes eating there six nights a week. They felt safe, as though they belonged, A new type of “Third Place”? 101 of 00 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
A_new Type of Third Place
 The purpose of this paper is to explore the notion of “Third Place” in an arts context by
exploring the consumption of two arts venues, Tate Modern and the Southbank Centre (SBC... ( More ) The purpose of this paper is to explore the notion of “Third Place” in an arts context by
exploring the consumption of two arts venues, Tate Modern and the Southbank Centre (SBC) on the regenerated South Bank in London, UK. ( Less ) Download or Print 161 Reads Info and Rating 
 Category: Research &gt; Business&amp;Economics Rating: Upload Date: 12/25/2010 Copyright: Attribution Non-commercial Tags: This document has no tags. 
 Flag document for inapproriate content This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
