<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000525" url="http://foodmummy.com/food-combo-working-with-a-fast-food-cash-register/" time="2012-07-12-15:48" support="3" score="0.024911727305788684" bingtitle="Food combo | Working with a Fast Food Cash Register" webtitle="Food combo | Working with a Fast Food Cash Register">
			<query id="000882" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000349" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="001102" bing-rank="5"/>
	<description>If your job is a cashier at a fast food restaurant, stress. You have a great responsibility. ... as well as a box, you are responsible for getting items such as the order of ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to World famous restaurants and food 

Welcome to the famous Worldwide restaurants|Chinese food||American food|Italian restaurants|top lists dishes
 
 Home Food Restaurants 
 
 Food combo | Working with a Fast Food Cash Register 
 July 2, 2011–9:42 am 
If your job is a cashier at a fast food restaurant, stress. You have a great responsibility. Orders must be completed correctly and on time. That&apos;s why one? Good cooperation between colleagues is a necessity. Thus, customers are satisfied with the food you ordered. In particular, be satisfied with the overall experience they received at the restaurant.


To operate a cash register fast food, you must first learn their duties. In general, as well as a box, you are responsible for getting items such as the order of the people.


So learn the combos and special. Even suggest to you the number of food combining and remember current promotions. So when customers want to eat the food that indicates the identification number, you can get. Asked to detail is not necessary, so that customers are satisfied with their service.


That&apos;s why we recommend for you to be aware of promotions that feed prices. As a result, can be of service to the customer quickly and accurately.


You should also make sure you know how the buttons on the register. We know that sometimes the buttons on the register are not so clear, the explanation most in need of a partner.


Nice and friendly is a must for a box. You should be good on the counter and over the intercom. As a result, customers are satisfied with their service and could return to his restaurant.


 
 
 
More Stories

 
 
 Pizza | October 28, 2011 8:28 PM Seafood Restaurants | McCormick&amp;Schmick’s Seafood Restaurants Recognize U.S. Military Veterans On Sunday, November 13 Family Restaurants | Your Favorite Food Icons: Fact Or Fiction? World Wide Food | Kashmir Education: My Way Discount Food | 7-25-2009 Altamont Cruisers Cruise-In French Restaurants | Winnipeg Restaurant-Provence Bistro Fresh food | sights Buy local fresh food programs American Restaurants | George’s Gaslight Inn–Oshkosh, WI 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
Tags: business , cash register , sales 
 
Post a Comment

 Name (required) 

 E-mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 

 

 
 
 
 
Sponsored Links

 
 
 
 
 
 
Popular

 Korean Restaurants | Hermit Kitchen Combo Food | Natural Cures for Yeast Infection Infants Dining | Reservation exceed Cloud Australia Restaurants Italiano | California Dreaming? Then north cheap hotels in central London - London Rooms | Restaurants 
 
 
 
Pictures
	</body>
</document>
