<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000120" url="http://www.menuism.com/restaurants/mesa-fresh-mexican-grill-wayne-192215" time="2012-07-12-15:18" support="3" score="0.004632694746680271" bingtitle="Mesa Fresh Mexican Grill - Reviews &amp; Menu - Wayne 19087" webtitle="Mesa Fresh Mexican Grill - Reviews&amp;Menu - Wayne 19087">
			<query id="000603" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="001341" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="001483" bing-rank="164"/>
	<description>... Mesa Fresh Mexican Grill is a Mexican and Fast Food restaurant where ... A few of the items are a bit basic/bland, I highly ... and you’ll have a scrumptious party on a tray ...</description>
	<body>
		Menuism - Restaurant and dish reviews 
 Explore Restaurant Reviews&amp;Menus 
 Restaurants Near Me Make Online Reservations Order Delivery&amp;Takeout Restaurant Week Directory Popular Cities Popular Chains What&apos;s Menu ism ? Monthly Review Contest 
 Remember Personal Dining Journal 
 My Favorites My Try List My Photos Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 
 Learn Foodie Education Blog 
 Food Primers Exclusive Interviews 
 
 FIND AROUND GO 
 Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 

 Not a member? To save, rate, and share reviews, sign up! Already a member? Log in (OpenID) Connect with Facebook 
 
 larger map / directions 

 Mesa Fresh Mexican Grill Menu 

 Mesa Fresh Mexican Grill Locations 
 
 - Pages - The Restaurant Map/Directions Dishes/Menu Images 
 Wayne Restaurants » Mexican » Mesa Fresh Mexican Grill Share | 
Mesa Fresh Mexican Grill
 
 4.5 star rating           
  4.5 rating over 4 reviews 
 (610) 975-0908 

 239 E Swedesford Rd ( ) 

 Wayne , PA 19087-1462 

 View Nearby Businesses» 
 Send to Phone Email Listing Print Listing   
 View Dishes Read Reviews (4) View Map/Directions 
 
 Information From the Restaurant Offers 
 
 Description:  Mesa Fresh Mexican Grill is a Mexican and Fast Food restaurant where most Menuism users came for a meal on the go , paid less than $10 , and tipped less than 15% . Tags: Mexican, Fast Food, Kid Friendly, Takeout, and Good For Kids Stats: 
 35 dishes entered by diners at Mesa Fresh Mexican Grill 
 
 
Nothing yet.
 
 Do you own Mesa Fresh Mexican Grill? Contact us to connect with your diners. 
 
 Suggest Corrections/Menu 
 
Reviews for Mesa Fresh Mexican Grill
 Write a review 
 4 reviews First reviewed by RJones 
 
&quot;Powered by Tofu!&quot;

 202 helpful votes over 106 reviews 
 RJones 
 106 Restaurant Reviews +198 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 Mesa Fresh Mexican Grill RJones 
 December 11, 2007 
 5.0 
 5.0 star rating           
 0 0 0 0 Votes   
Tasty Mexican Food
 
Made-to-order fresh fast food–similar to a Rubio’s or Baja Fresh. This would be my favorite among the three. The guacamole is excellent, although served in tiny portions. A few of the items are a bit basic/bland, I highly recommend choosing something with lots of toppings. The salsa is great, the beans are great, the guacamole is great. Order a steak quesadilla and you’ll get a tortilla with cheese and steak strips. It’s good, but not great. Order the nachos and you’ll have a scrumptious party on a tray, sized big enough for two or more.
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply kerryw 
 from Citysearch 
 
September 22, 2009
 
 1 star rating           
 
crappy food
 
The food here is just terrible. It is so bad i had to write a review. It&apos;s like a rock on my stomach. I can&apos;t believe anyone would say it&apos;s good. It is just bland, heavy and full of sodium. It&apos;s been three hours since i had this food and i…

 read full review» 
 hungry5 
 from Citysearch 
 
July 15, 2009
 
 5 star rating           
 
our favorite lunch
 
The food is amazing. My girlfriends and I go to Mesa at least once a week!! the food is all made while you watch from real stuff(fresh veggies, fruits, high grade sirloin and lean chicken).We love it because it is so much healthier than…

 read full review» 
 test 
 from Citysearch 
 
October 3, 2006
 
 4 star rating           
 
Not bad but not authentic
 
The food here is pretty good, but this is flat out the smallest, most expensive burrito I have ever seen, anywhere. In the (San Francisco) Mission, or even South Philadelphia, this place would be out of business in about 2 days. And…

 read full review» 
 Read 4 reviews on Citysearch» 
Best Dishes at Mesa Fresh Mexican Grill

These dishes from the Mesa Fresh Mexican Grill menu are contributed by Menuism users directly, 
 as part of a restaurant review, or as part of an image upload.
 
BEAN&amp;CHEESE BURRITO
 
 0.0 star rating           
 
Burrito N’ Bowl
 
 0.0 star rating           
 
BOTTLED WATER
 
 0.0 star rating           
 View all dishes 
 Massage Envy Spa Wayne PA Tj Maxx Staples House Doctors Orchard Properties, LLC dba House Doctors of The Main Line Barnes&amp;Noble Booksellers Gilbert, Jodi L, LCSW Bike Line Courtyard Philadelphia Valley Forge/King of Prussia Couples Counseling Ctr 
 Mesa Fresh Mexican Grill is located near the cities of Saint Davids, St Davids, Radnor Township, Radnor Twp, and Radnor. People found this by searching for: Mesa Fresh Gateway, Mesa Grill Gateway Pa, Reviews Wayne Berwyn Mesa, Restaurant Havertown Mesa Grill, Mesa Grill Gateway, Mesa Mexican Grill, Mexican 19087, and Mesa Grill Wayne Pa. Write a Review Add to Try List Add to Favorites Suggest Corrections Upload Pics 
Featured in Wayne
 
 4.4 star rating           
 Italian Delight 
 3.8 star rating           
 East Star Chinese Restaurant 
 3.5 star rating           
 Jacquette&apos;s Bakery 
 3.875 star rating           
 Phil&apos;s Famous Pizza&amp;Steaks 
 3.5 star rating           
 Rocco&apos;s Pizzeria 
 4.5 star rating           
 Red Lobster 
 5.0 star rating           
 VIP Pizza&amp;Pasta 
 5.0 star rating           
 Szechuan Hill Chinese Restaurant 
 4.0 star rating           
 Marrone&apos;s Pizzeria 
 4.0 star rating           
 The Pub of Penn Valley 
 Upload Pics Photos
 
 See All 11 
 
Nearby Restaurants
 Maggie Moo&apos;s The Gateway Cafe Little Tokyo Japanese Steak HS Panera Bread Five Guys 
Link to Mesa Fresh Mexican Grill
 
Copy the link below and paste onto your website or blog to display badge.

 Copy 
 
Related Links
 Philadelphia Inquirer Review 
 Follow Menuism around the web Find us on Facebook Follow us on Twitter Find us on Google+ 
 
 Learn More
 Advertise About
Advertise
FAQ
Privacy
Terms of Use 
 Take Action
 Link to Menuism / Badges and Widgets 
 Browse
 Restaurant Week Restaurant Locations Popular Cities Sitemap 
 
 ©2006 - 2012 Delta Beans, LLC
 Contact Menuism 

Some Images and Data provided by Citysearch .
	</body>
</document>
