<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000762" url="http://www.dailyglow.com/six-salads-that-are-worse-than-the-average-fast-food-restaurant-menu-0718.html" time="2012-07-12-16:06" support="2" score="0.0035042528814320183" bingtitle="Six Salads That Are Worse Than the Average Fast Food Restaurant Menu" webtitle="Six Salads That Are Worse Than the Average Fast Food Restaurant Menu">
			<query id="001184" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="000964" bing-rank="229"/>
	<description>Six Salads That Are Worse Than the Average Fast Food Restaurant Menu ... hair to grow fast and want them straight too tell ... your visits to this Site and other websites in order ...</description>
	<body>
		Newsletters : Daily Beauty Tips | Dr. Wu Hollywood Dermatologist Apps Register Sign in Close Welcome, My Account | Log Out 
Log-in to DailyGlow with one click!
 
 OR 
 Log-in with your Daily Glow Account: 
E-Mail Address:
 
Password:
 Forgot Your Password? 
That&apos;s ok, we can send you a new one. Just fill out your email address below and we&apos;ll mail it to you right away!
 Groups | Blogs | Ask a Question | Quizzes 
 Skin&amp;Beauty Hair Care Personal Care Makeover Beauty Buzz Experts Product Picks 
 Home » Beauty Buzz » Beauty News » Six Salads That Are Worse Than the Average Fast Food Restaurant Menu 
Six Salads That Are Worse Than the Average Fast Food Restaurant Menu
 
By Carol Roach
 
Related Articles

 Low-Cal Restaurant Foods May Have More Calories Than You Think Healthy Skin on the Menu Celeb Trainer Jillian Michaels Shares Her Sexy Abs Secrets 
 
Beware of salads that are worse than eating burgers at fast food restaurants. Many women get fooled by the fast food restaurants that sell salads as part of their healthy choice menus. One would think that salads would be healthier. However, it depends largely on the ingredients.

Though vegetables and fruits, as we know, are very healthy, not all salads are good for our waistlines. The biggest culprits or those containing a lot of oils, sauces, and rich salad dressings. Another hidden ingredient is the salt. According to The Telegraph in the UK, 1 out of 10 salads sold there are worst than eating a Big Mac, and it all has to do with the sodium content. Are American restaurants any better at controlling the sodium content in their salads? Though the trend now is lowering sodium content, not all restaurants have complied. It would be wise to read the web site nutritional value for fast food restaurants before visiting the restaurant. Though fast food restaurants are cheaper than other restaurants and very conveniently located in shopping malls, around industrial parks, office buildings, and main city arteries, they are not necessarily good for our health. America&apos;s obesity rate is reaching epidemic proportions.

To keep your waistline trim and your heart in good shape, consider avoiding these six salads that are worse than eating a Whopper.

Though delicious with all the croutons, creamy Caesar dressing has large portions of cheese, which can raise the caloric intake to 750 calories with about 50 grams of fat. Burger King&apos;s Chicken Caesar salad has a 27 grams of fat, 7 grams of saturated fat, 70 mg of cholesterol, and a whopping 1850 mg of sodium. This creamy delight ranks among the six salads that are worst than eating a BK burger

 MedicineNet warns that MacDonald&apos;s crispy bacon ranch salads that are worse than eating a Big Mac. The salad has 51 grams of fat , 11 grams of saturated fat, 85 mg of cholesterol and 1570 mg of sodium.

Wendy&apos;s Chicken BLT Salad with homestyle garlic croutons and honey mustard dressing has 47.5 grams of fat, 12.5 grams of saturated fat, 85 mg of cholesterol, and 1630 mg of sodium.

Taco Bell&apos;s Taco Salad with Salsa has 51 grams of fat, 14 grams of saturated fat, 60 (mg )of cholesterol and 1630 mg of sodium. If you skip the salsa the sodium is reduced to 1500 mg of sodium.

One would think that a chef salad should be healthy enough, but not so for the Au Bon Pain&apos;s chef salad. It is loaded with bacon, ham, turkey, and cheese. It has 15 grams of fat, 7 grams of saturated fat, 65 mg of cholesterol, and 1370 mg of sodium

When we look at the small list of six salads that are unhealthy, we cannot just target fast food restaurants. Applebee&apos;s Grilled Shrimp &apos;N Spinach salad is a sneaky one. Because of the spinach, one would think this salad is a healthy choice; however, the salad contains 1,050 calories, 72 g fat (11 g saturated), and 2,530 mg sodium.
 Last Updated:
 
 Monday, July 18, 2011 Comments 
More Beauty News
 
 Related Topics Beauty News Beauty Buzz Blog The Skin Doctor Bing&apos;s Beauty Bag Beauty Product Giveaways Daily Glow Beauty Awards Best and Worst Cities for Skin 
 
 Related News Low-Cal Restaurant Foods May Have More Calories Than You Think Healthy Skin on the Menu Celeb Trainer Jillian Michaels Shares Her Sexy Abs Secrets Six Foods for Great Hair Spinach 
 
Ask A Question. Get Expert Answers.
 
Featured Questions in Six Salads That Are Worse Than the Average Fast Food Restaurant Menu

 Peanut butter pimples: Can peanut butter make pimples worse? Treat Hair Thinning, Improve Hair Growth: I am 23 years old; my hair is too thin and grows slowly. Please solve my problem of oily skin and hair. Grow straight hair fast: I am 19 year old male and I want my hair to grow fast and want them straight too tell me what to do! 
 Ask Your Question 
 See More Questions »
 
 Most Popular Most Recent 
 
 How to Pack for a Vacation Is Your Moisturizer Working? How to Find the Best Body Wash for You Ingredient Decoder: NutriumMoisture Best Ways to Beat Dry Skin The Best Stealth Moisturizers 7 Surprising Causes of Dry Skin 8 Keys to Skin Health 
 
Follow Daily Glow
 Follow Us on Twitter Facebook 
Learn More About...
 
 that are worse 
 
 
 Copyright©2012 Everyday Health, Inc. 
 About Us | Need Help? | Popular Searches | Privacy | Terms of Use | Disclaimer | Ad Policy | Advertise With Us | Feedback | Hair Care&amp;Skin Care Tips Blog 
 Advertising Notice 
This Site and third parties who place advertisements on this Site may collect and use information about your visits to this Site and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like to obtain more information about these advertising practices and to make choices about online behavioral advertising, please click here 
 
The material on this web site is provided for educational purposes only, and is not to be used for medical advice, diagnosis or treatment.
See additional information . Use of this site is subject to our terms of service and privacy policy .
	</body>
</document>
