<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000843" url="http://blogs.e-rockford.com/comingsandgoings/2010/08/04/274/" time="2012-07-12-16:12" support="1" score="0.00029164678801389313" bingtitle="Parthenios closing at end of week – Comings and Goings ..." webtitle="Parthenios closing at end of weekComings and Goings - Rockford, IL - Rockford Register Star">
			<query id="001458" bing-rank="156"/>
	<description>... institution since 1969, will close at the end of ... Whether it&apos;s a new boutique popping up, a fast-food restaurant ... her bus was hit, she fell from the driver’s seat ...</description>
	<body>
		Site Print archives Web Web Search powered by YAHOO! SEARCH 
 Jobs 
 Cars 
 Homes 
 Classifieds 
 Apartments 
 Coupons 
 Subscriber Services 
 Home News Obituaries Business Sports Entertainment HealthyRockford Insight Rockford Woman Special Sections 
 
 Facebook Twitter Mobile E-mail headlines Local Loop Calendar Newspaper Ads Newspaper Archives Contests Contact Us 

 Your Town Public Safety Schools Real Estate Transactions Nation/World Celebrations Calendar 

 Real Estate Transactions Face of Business On the Move Say Cheese Star 60 Markets Stocks 

 Hoops Preps College Sports Bears IceHogs Twitter 

 Movies Music&amp;Arts Food&amp;Dining My Last Bite Life&amp;Style; Georgette Braun Will Pfeifer Twitter Calendar Contests 

 Health care jobs Health Directory 

 Problem Tracker Submit letter or guest column Opinions What You&apos;re Saying Blogs Bruce Quast Cartoons Videos 

 Facebook Twitter 

 Local Loop Reader Content Daily Deals People Living Spaces Branded Content 
 Comings and Goings Keep track of the latest business openings and closings. Whether it&apos;s a new boutique popping up, a fast-food restaurant closing down or a progress report on a major development, you&apos;ll find all the latest bits of information here. See something while you&apos;re out and about? Leave a comment or send an e-mail to business@rrstar.com and we&apos;ll check it out. Read more Follow @mlwestphal Skip to content 
Parthenios closing at end of week
 Posted on August 4, 2010 at 3:20 pm by Alex Gary Tweet 
 Editor’s Note: This blog post contained incorrect information when it first published about the 1995 bus accident that killed a Parthenios patron. That information has been corrected. 

Parthenios Luncheonette, a downtown Rockford institution since 1969, will close at the end of business Saturday.

The restaurant has been run for years by John and Jim Parthenios, but Jim has been in and out of the hospital much of the year and 73-year-old John Parthenios said of the 70-hour work weeks,“I’ve had enough. I can’t do it anymore.”

Parthenios said there are no other family members willing to take the business on and he plans to place a“For Sale”sign in the window by the end of the week.

Parthenios Luncheonette is one of four restaurants the brothers have run over the years, beginning with a Beloit, Wis. eatery in 1962.

It took Father Time to finally close the 132 N. Church St. restaurant. The brothers have overcome several obstacles to keep the business going. Those obstacles range from business cycles—the deep recession of the 1980s and the near total retail desertion of downtown—to tragedy.

In 1995, a Rockford Mass Transit bus crashed into the restaurant after a man high on cocaine crashed his car into the bus. The accident killed a 79-year-old restaurant customer.

In 1999, Jim Parthenios was opening the restaurant on Thanksgiving when a 33-year-old homeless man from Alabama stabbed him five times. Jim recovered and the brothers continued to open on Thanksgiving and other major holidays.

“I hope someone comes along and buys it,”John said.“We’ve got good loyal customers. They are the reason we’ve kept it going this long.”
 
 Assistant Business Editor Alex Gary filled in for Melissa Westphal, who is out of the office this week. 
 
 Related posts: 

 Dog‘n Suds opening delayed one week Tumbleweed closing Wednesday Caffe Greco closing its doors Blockbuster near State Street and Trainer Road closing My Secret Garden closing 
 This entry was posted in Uncategorized and tagged closings . Bookmark the permalink . ← Northwoods Grill and Bar closing Saturday Noodles&amp;Company opening Thursday → 
10 Comments

 jimmy crackcorn says: August 4, 2010 at 5:09 pm 
i believe the bus driver, a woman, was not wearing a seat-belt. when her bus was hit, she fell from the driver’s seat causing her to lose control of the bus. the driver who caused the accident was a black man, and he, not the bus driver, was loaded w/ cocaine.

that is the way i remember the happenings. if i am wrong, someone will tell us.
 Anna Derocher says: August 4, 2010 at 5:21 pm 
jimmy crackcorn: You are correct. We had the information wrong when we first published this post. It has since been corrected. Thank you for pointing out the error.

Anna Derocher, assistant managing editor, rrstar.com
 jimmy crackcorn says: August 4, 2010 at 5:25 pm 
anna, you are welcome………..and your pretty cute too,
 BS says: August 4, 2010 at 8:06 pm 
My father was the gentleman killed in that horrific bus accident. Our family has been forced to spend the rest of our lives without him because of the bus driver’s negligence. The accident did not result from the driver of the car; the bus driver was completely negligent, not paying attention to the road and traffic signals, ran a red light, and hit the car the resulting in a chain of events. However, no one found it necessary to test the bus driver for drugs or alcohol. Because of the accident, my father died inside that restaurant. My family&amp;I sat through the entire trial listening to testimony from witnesses that were on the bus that day. Anna Derocher, your accounts of this accident are inaccurate. The accident is public record and can be obtained from the city.
 Anna Derocher says: August 5, 2010 at 2:47 pm 
BS,

I am sorry you lost your father in such a tragic way.

However, I want to clarify a couple things.

In July 1998, a circuit judge threw out allegations that Rockford Mass Transit District or the bus driver contributed to the accident because the bus driver wasn’t wearing her seat belt.

In January 2001, a jury awarded $1.7 million to your family during a civil lawsuit. Jurors found the car driver 70 percent liable for your father’s death and the public bus system 30 percent responsible.

Anna Derocher, assistant managing editor, rrstar.com
 BS says: August 5, 2010 at 5:08 pm 
Anna,
your clarification is what you’ve read, my facts are what I heard and observed the day of the accident and throughout the legal precedings but I don’t intend to debate this issue w/you. Thanks for your comments.
 Laurie says: August 7, 2010 at 7:13 pm 
To the Parthenios family, I send best wishes to you all and prayers to Jim during this difficult time. I am really sad to hear that the doors of the restaurant are closing permanently, but I am glad that you are finally taking some time for yourselves. You have all worked very hard over the years and you definitely deserve a break now. I wish I could have made one last stop in before the closing just so I could see Nano’s (John) in the kitchen. I miss you guys and I am very grateful that I had a chance to work with you and grow up around your family. The memories will never fade! Hope to see you around town sometime. Take care one and all.
 Kathe ryn Schlesner says: August 9, 2010 at 9:23 am 
My husband\’s mother used to work for Parthenios and whenever my husband took us there, the owners rememebered him and his mother. The one thing we ordered was the shakes and I took in the way the restaurant looked with the way that not many restaurants have the old fashioned scenery to them anymore. Parthenios, you and your malts will be missed. Thanks for the memories.
 Karyn Schlesner says: August 9, 2010 at 9:25 am 
My name was spelled wrong for some reason, oops.
 Barbie says: September 25, 2010 at 11:00 am 
I’m sorry for the loss of any tragic accident, but our destiny is in God’s hands. We are not promised tomorrow. No matter whos fault, it is beyond our hands.
 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 Notify me of followup comments via email. You can also subscribe without commenting. 
 
   
Search This Blog
 Search for: 
Recent Posts

 Red Mango yogurt shop opening in Machesney Park BP gas station on Charles Street in Rockford converting to Mobil Kochi Japan restaurant opening next week in Rockford Salon open at Stewart Square Pacemaker grocery store adds fuel pumps in Poplar Grove 
 
Recent Comments

 Norma on Closure of Ello Furniture is end of an era Jeff on BP gas station on Charles Street in Rockford converting to Mobil Patti V. on Molly’s Attic hosting grand opening Saturday in Roscoe Martink on Gray’s Foods grocery store on Auburn Street closing Anna Carlson on Olive oil store opening in Loves Park 
 

 
Recently Shared
 
 
 Melissa Westphal’s Stories 

 Closure of Auburn Street driving facility angers local officials Rockford driver&apos;s license facility moving over needed upgrades Illinois cemetery industry hit with new licensing rules Americans boost charitable giving in 2011 OSF on Cloud 9 over better pictures from new MRI machine 
 
 
Archives
 Select Month December 2011 (4) November 2011 (5) October 2011 (8) September 2011 (8) August 2011 (9) July 2011 (12) June 2011 (13) May 2011 (9) April 2011 (6) March 2011 (16) February 2011 (17) January 2011 (10) December 2010 (10) November 2010 (9) October 2010 (12) September 2010 (8) August 2010 (14) July 2010 (12) June 2010 (4) May 2010 (5) April 2010 (8) March 2010 (6) February 2010 (4) January 2010 (10) December 2009 (7) November 2009 (8) October 2009 (5) September 2009 (6) August 2009 (1) July 2009 (5) June 2009 (6) May 2009 (1) April 2009 (2) March 2009 (7) January 2009 (8) December 2008 (3) November 2008 (10) October 2008 (8) September 2008 (11) August 2008 (1) July 2008 (1) April 2008 (7) March 2008 (5) February 2008 (6) January 2008 (5) December 2007 (9) November 2007 (11) October 2007 (3) 
Categories
 Select Category Business move  (2) Cherry Valley  (1) Coming  (26) Going  (5) Health  (1) Machesney Park  (1) Restaurants  (12) Retail  (22) Retail expansion  (5) Retail move  (4) Rockford  (3) Uncategorized  (160) 
Tags
 Select Tag Business move (3) closings (51) Expansion (3) openings (99) Restaurants (12) Retail (12) Subscribe to Posts    Subscribe to Comments Marketplace • Classifieds • Find Rockford jobs • Cars • Homes • Coupons Site services • Subscribe • Place an Ad • Buy a photo reprint • Newspaper Archives • Weddings/Engagements • Anniversaries Your Town • Belvidere • Boone County • Cherry Valley • Loves Park • Machesney Park Your Town • Rockford • Rockton • Roscoe • South Beloit • Winnebago County Submit content • Calendar listing • Letter to the Editor • Press release • News tip Our sites • BusinessRockford.com • Go.rrstar.com • HealthyRockford.com • RockfordWoman.com • RockfordHomeOnline.com • RockfordWheels.com • m.rrstar.com 
 Contact us | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service | About our Ads 

Rockford Register Star |
 99 E. State St. Rockford, IL 61104

Copyright©2006-2012 GateHouse Media, Inc. Some Rights Reserved.

Original content available for non-commercial use under a Creative Commons license, except where noted.
 SEO by eLocalListing | Advertiser profiles | RadarFrog Merchant Directory
	</body>
</document>
