<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0000471" url="http://www.buzzflash.com/mailbag/05/02/mai05023.html" time="2012-07-12-15:43" support="1" score="0.0013657970610264421" bingtitle="BuzzFlash &gt; Mailbag &gt; 2/1/05" webtitle="BuzzFlashMailbag2/1/05">
			<query id="001228" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>... for them, so they ate after the event at some fast-food restaurant. ... 1) The first numbers they throw out are these: U.S ... at the transparent ballot boxes ...</description>
	<body>
		February 1, 2005
 MAILBAG
 ARCHIVES   
 The BuzzFlash 
 Mailbag 

The opinions expressed in the Mailbag are not 
 necessarily those of BuzzFlash. Read the BuzzFlash 
 FAQ for info on submitting to the Mailbag.
 
Subject: TORONTO: &apos;Fiscal irresponsibility 
 in Washington&apos;....

U.S. President George W. Bush continues to 
 demonstrate a shocking lack of fiscal responsibility, 
 even as he insists that there is nothing to 
 worry about when it comes to the U.S. government&apos;s 
 finances. In the space of four years, supposedly 
 the most conservative American president in 
 a generation has destroyed years of hard work 
 by the Clinton administration to balance the 
 books and has left them awash in red ink. 
 The huge surplus left behind by the previous 
 administration is only a distant memory thanks 
 to Bush&apos;s tax-slashing and profligate spending. 
 A time of vastly increased government spending 
 - and potentially billions more if the United 
 States finds itself embroiled in another foreign 
 conflict or costly peacekeeping mission - 
 is not the time to be making permanent tax 
 cuts, as every other U.S. president in wartime 
 has understood.

Frank
 
Subject: IRAQ ELECTION

I heard that voters will still get to cast 
 their ballots in Iraq even though polls have 
 closed. Why couldn&apos;t that happen in Ohio?

Brian
 
Subject:&quot;insurgents&quot;

Dear Buzz:

I wish you stopped [sic] calling Iraqi fighters insurgents. Try 
 to look at it from a different angle. Perhaps a scenario like this 
 one will make you try to find a different name for those fighters:

Imagine, just imagine an army of strangers invading United States. 
 Foreign soldiers bomb your cities. Foreign soldiers capture and 
 torture your neighbors and family. Foreign soldiers rape your women. 
 Foreign soldiers inflict harm and pain onto your country. The American 
 army has been destroyed, and what is left, organizes itself into 
 small but violently courageous units, that attack the invaders whenever 
 and wherever they can. They only do what is right: they defend their 
 country and their way of life.

What do you call them? Insurgents?

I call them patriots.

Sorry, Buzz. Your description of Iraqi patriots is insulting and 
 inaccurate. What is good for the corporate media, is not necessarily 
 good for BuzzFlash. Please correct yourself, and call those fighters 
 what they really are.

Regards,

Malgoska
 
Subject: Voting

Are those Diebold machines they&apos;re using in Iraq?

Michael Barry
Reston, VA
 
Subject: oxymoron

Isn&apos;t the term&quot;Fighting for Peace&quot;sort of like&quot;Screwing 
 for Virginity&quot;?

So, how many Republicans does it take to overturn the U.S. Constitution? 
 Answer: Evidently 1

How many Republican lies does it take to kill 1300 Americans? Answer: 
 It varies. It depends on how stupid the rest of the country is.

How many Right-Wingers live in FantasyLand? Answer: Well, There&apos;s 
 Jeb and George and Karl and Donny and....

Bruce F.
 
Subject: Could We Have Achieved Free Elections In Iraq Without 
 Ever Firing A Shot? - Remember This Story?

While Bush is busy patting himself on the back, and the&quot;liberal 
 media&quot;is fawning all over the great accomplishment we&apos;ve achieved 
 (it only cost us $200 billion, tens of thousands of dead Iraqis, 
 and over 1400 American lives), I&apos;d like to remind everyone that 
 we possibly could have achieved this exact same result (free elections) 
 without one ounce of blood being spilled.

Remember the story that came out over a year ago, that Saddam had 
 attempted to strike a last minute deal to avert war? He&apos;d used a 
 Lebanese businessman as an intermediary. ONE OF THE CONCESSIONS 
 OFFERED WAS FREE ELECTIONS!!!!

And to address those who will say,&quot;come on - negotiate with 
 a man like Saddam?&quot;, I&apos;d remind them that we negotiated with 
 Mohammar Qaddafi. In fact, the neocons have praised that deal for 
 a year now.

Here&apos;s the link: Iraq 
 offered U.S. deal to avert war (AP/Pittsburgh-Tribune Review) 

Lance Collins
Sugar Land, TX

[BuzzFlash Note: We found many stories on or around 11/7/03 covering 
 this, but where is the mention of free elections as a negotiating 
 chip?]
 
Subject: Iraqi Election = Democracy and Freedom

Today is a remarkable event in world history - what the US administration 
 has called the&quot;first free election&quot;in Iraq.

So what does our government consider a&quot;legitimate&quot;(according 
 to Richard Perle and other pro-administration figures) election? 
 It has been made clear that the Bush administration considers this 
 election an important event, and an example of democracy and freedom 
 taking hold in Iraq. News commentators refer to it as a&quot;free 
 election.&quot;Pundits call it&quot;inspiring,&quot;and&quot;history 
 in the making.&quot;

So, what would an Iraqi voter be offered today? What would be the 
 circumstances?

We should only consider facts, and not opinions about this. So, 
 imagining that you are an Iraqi voter, desiring democracy and the 
 right to participate in choosing your government - these are some 
 known facts, reported in various news media:

1. You do not know the names of many of over 200 candidates, or 
 if you do, you only were told a couple days ago.

2. You will be electing an assembly, which will write a constitution, 
 and appoint a council to elect the President. By law, some percentage 
 must be women, which apparently overrules the vote.

3. You are told that you may be killed or attacked by anti-election 
 terrorists if you go to vote.

4. The location of your polling place was not revealed until yesterday.

5. The military force which removed your nation&apos;s dictator about 
 a year and half ago, and enforces curfews, and has set up road blocks 
 and shut down phone systems, is conducting increased raids and attacks 
 on suspected insurgents.

6. There has been no public debate or discussion of issues, or of 
 candidates&apos; platforms or promises.

7. The leader appointed by the occupying nation&apos;s coalition has 
 spent $4 million on television ads, and has campaigned in helicopters 
 provided by the occupying force. The state television network was 
 established by the occupying forces.

8. You are not able to drive your car to the polling places because 
 of road blocks. If you drive, you may be randomly inspected by armed 
 military from the occupying forces.

9. Soldiers from the occupying forces have told reporters that it 
 is hard to tell an&quot;insurgent,&quot;their enemy, from a civilian.

10. There are no UN or other outside election monitors in country, 
 because of security problems.

11. The majority of election monitors are agents of political parties, 
 and others are affiliated with the occupying force.

12. The occupying force has killed a large number of your country&apos;s 
 civilians and has tortured prisoners detained without charges or 
 evidence, and has not made any visible change in such practices.

I wonder if Americans would want such a&quot;legitimate&quot;and&quot;free&quot;election here.

Scott
 
Subject: Democracy in Action

Dear BuzzFlash Readers,

I fully support the writer from Wichita, 
 Kansas who embraces unity among Democrats as opposed to the 
 divisiveness among our party that has been so ingenuously manipulated 
 by the GOP. Unfortunately, too many Democrats have bought into this 
 divisiveness and have become that which they hate among their Republican 
 counterparts. In our effort to combat the twisted ideals of the 
 extreme right, we have assumed the persona of the extreme left, 
 leaving behind many of the grassroots or mainstream Democrats in 
 the wake of the chasm that separates us.

In so doing, we have also inadvertently provided the Republican 
 Party with the opportunity to penetrate the Democratic electorate. 
 There are many older, mainstream, life-long Democrats, like myself, 
 whose voices are silenced by both the extreme right and the extreme 
 left platforms, and who seek the nuances of an otherwise black or 
 white agenda. For example, I support Roe vs. Wade and the right 
 of women to choose; however, I also support reasonable methods of 
 intervention that serve to dissuade women who face this dilemma 
 from choosing abortion as an only option. This, I believe, is also 
 the position expressed by Mrs. Clinton, a position she has held 
 since her debut into the political spotlight. To advocate debate 
 and discussion on the issue of abortion should not be perceived 
 as giving in to the GOP, but simply as an attempt to address this 
 concern in a responsible way and to create a platform on abortion 
 that is tenable not only to Democrats, but to all of those who appreciate 
 the complexities of this argument.

The Democratic Party, as a fanatical, intractable, extreme left-wing 
 organization, is doomed to failure. Our purpose must be not only 
 to defeat Republicans, but to unify and build upon the ideals that 
 are true to our tradition and to the traditions of America. Perhaps 
 we can be reminded of this by the words of Dr. Martin Luther King 
 Jr.
 
When evil men plot, good men must plan. When evil men burn and 
 bomb, good men must build and bind. When evil men shout ugly words 
 of hatred, good men must commit themselves to the glories of love. 
 Where evil men would seek to perpetuate an unjust status quo, 
 good men must seek to bring into being a real order of justice.
 The good men and women of the Democratic Party are destined to 
 bring meaningful change to our nation, but we must begin by bringing 
 meaningful change to our Party. 
A BuzzFlash Reader
Hazel Crest, Illinois
 
Subject: How can 1 vote for someone whose name they find out at 
 poll&amp;have no other inf

I can&apos;t believe that everyone is so excited about this election, 
 where the voters didn&apos;t even know the names of the candidates before 
 going to the polls, and certainly what they stand for, except perhaps 
 that some are Shiites and some are Kurds...or maybe, like the US, 
 what candidates stand for means diddly, and who they are doesn&apos;t 
 matter either....

The Bushies feed the world this success crap (it was not so different 
 in Afghanistan) and everyone buys it, then goes on to the next story...scary...only 
 Iraq will not be like Afghanistan (that&apos;s just a heroin supermarket), 
 but maybe the story is over the world press and Bush will come out 
 a big hero, Allawi the CIA puppet will run Iraq, and the next story 
 will be Iran.

I suppose nobody remembers that this is a repeat of a cycle: The 
 Brits put in Saddam, and the US put in the Shah of Iran, who was 
 overthrown by the Mullahs, now we&apos;re beginning the cycle all over 
 again.

A BuzzFlash Reader
 
Subject: please reporters, ask.....

Would someone please ask Mr. Bush about some specifics on his social 
 security plan? What does he mean by near when he says at or near? 
 What will his changes mean to us fifty year old women whose husband 
 left us for a 27 year old skinny blond?

Liza M.
 
Subject: mailbag

Greetings to Buzz and Buzzers,

Hey Gary Sartori - what exactly do you mean that Joe Lieberman didn&apos;t 
 speak at the Convention so in that case he can&apos;t be compared to 
 Zell Miller. I don&apos;t think anyone is suggesting that Senator Lieberman 
 has the same personality or manner of speaking (if you want to call 
 it speaking) as Zell Miller. I think the point is that he votes 
 like Zell Miller. Like a republican. Why shouldn&apos;t Democrats be 
 able to criticize a Democratic Senator that votes with Republicans? 
 Jeez, lighten up people! I can&apos;t believe you are all over BuzzFlash&apos;s 
 case when they are one of the few web sites telling the truth - 
 the Whole Truth! As usual, I agree with Shirley.

A BuzzFlash Reader who can&apos;t stand Joe Lieberman either! - for very 
 valid reasons
 
Subject: Risking lives for the sadist

Only Bush the Sadist could get people to risk their lives for a 
 fraudulent election. I didn&apos;t believe the results of the election 
 in America, and I have no reason to believe (and neither does anyone 
 not on life support) the results of the Iraqi farce. Now Bush will 
 scream victory and will succeed, once again with the help of the 
 media, in creating reality for America&apos;s bumbling class.

A BuzzFlash Reader
 
Subject: doesn&apos;t pass the smell test! :):)

72%? sorry, that number is not gonna pass the smell test.

A BuzzFlash Reader
 
Subject: Northern Exposure

Dear Buzz,

There&apos;s a letter to the editor in the February 7 issue of&quot;The 
 Nation&quot;from Lee Zaslofsky, who works at the War Resisters 
 Support Campaign in Toronto. In it, he asks Americans and Canadians 
 to contact the Canadian government of Prime Minister Paul Martin 
 and encourage them to provide sanctuary to Americans who choose 
 to resist the war in Iraq, much as they did in Vietnam. Currently, 
 war-resisting Americans wishing to go to Canada have to apply for 
 refugee status, rather than being treated like ordinary immigrants. 
 Obtaining refugee status is a much more bureaucratically complex 
 matter, and makes it much more difficult for American war resisters 
 to obtain sanctuary.

More information on this matter can be obtained at: http://www.resisters.ca 

A Buzzflash Reader
 
Subject: anne coulter

Wow! Anne Coulter thinks Canada sent troops to Vietnam? Did she 
 really go to college or did she make that one up as well? Did she 
 even finish high school? Grade school? What is truly embarrassing 
 about the entire Canadian interview in which she insists Canada 
 sent troops to Vietnam (they didn&apos;t) was the fact that an extraordinary 
 number of Americans listen to this idiot and believe every word 
 she says. It doesn&apos;t say much for the collective IQ of the US.

 Ann 
 Coulter gets schooled by Canada (jossip.com) 

A BuzzFlash Reader
 
Subject: State of the Union Speech

How about this for fighting back? I intend to call the House Democratic 
 Whip (my congressman Steny Hoyer) and suggest that for Dubyas SOTU 
 speech, they distribute police whistles to all the Democratic Members 
 of the House. When Dubya commences to tell a lie, the Democratic 
 members will sound the whistles full volume and and each holds up 
 a sign with a simple message...&quot;LIAR&quot;

Time to stop pulling our punches and fight back. The reaction 
 of the TV pundits would be priceless, and just maybe America would 
 wake up from our fear of them bad brown folks and see that evil 
 can have a bland white face and a bachelors degree from Yale?

A BuzzFlash Reader
Bowie, Maryland
 
Subject: Plenty for Democrats to Chew On . . .

BuzzFlash,

Below is that quote from your site regarding the soldier who was 
 ordered to Bush&apos;s Celebration of Himself . . . and again, and again, 
 we see the reality over and over and I want to hear our Democrats 
 react about this constant neglect of our troops. Constant! I remember 
 the&quot;good ole days&quot;when a Democrat would be outraged 
 and really giving Bush hell over the way Bush and his administration 
 treat our troops . . . it would not change the way that Bush thinks 
 of us&quot;common folk,&quot;but it would help to let people know 
 what is really going on instead of the constant flow of propaganda 
 put out by this regime. Aside from the fact that most people get 
 their news from TV, a great number of Americans still do not have 
 computers.
 
My son is an army reservist and he returned from Iraq last March. 
 He was ordered to attend one of the inauguration parties.

I am prior service myself, so I felt very proud that he was chosen 
 from all the people in his group. This particular gathering was 
 to honor many of the soldiers and their families who have been 
 to Iraq. Agroup of five drove down from Long Island to Washington 
 last Monday morning, and they were to return Tuesday evening.

Around midnight on Tuesday, my son returned home, looking tired 
 from the drive. The next morning, he told me he didn&apos;t have a 
 good time because they basically stood around and watched the 
 president say a few words. He said there was no food provided 
 for them, so they ate after the event at some fast-food restaurant. 
 They spent all this money for this celebration and can&apos;t feed 
 my son? He stayed at a local military base with the rest of the 
 group, but they made him pay for the room.
Apparently, there was a mix-up, or they were short a room.

I don&apos;t care what the problem was, he was told to go, this was 
 not an option, orders were cut for this excursion! I am disgusted 
 and horrified that he had to even show his wallet for this event.

In addition to serving as a medic in the 310 MP Battalion, my 
 son is a full-time student and works part-time to fill in the 
 gaps the military doesn&apos;t. He takes his responsibility as a soldier 
 very seriously.

I am angered at the way he has been treated. People need to know 
 how some heroes are being treated by their own government.

Rebecca Lawson, West Babylon, N.Y.

 MSNBC - Citizen 
 Journalists on the Iraqi elections 
 
Then there are those who advocate more killing of our young people 
 by enlarging our military and those who also don&apos;t give seem to 
 give much thought about US youths and the loss of their lives due 
 to Bush&apos;s lies, and complete disrespect for our military and their 
 families . . . I won&apos;t leave out Bush&apos;s hoydenish disposition towards 
 the rest of America&apos;s citizens, either.

I will never understand anyone not standing up against this self-serving 
 fascist regime. Never. Congress Democrat or Ordinary Citizen . . 
 . I&apos;ll never understand. Whatever their beliefs are . . . it is 
 a moral obligation of all Americans to stop this Republican killing 
 machine . . . whether it&apos;s a fight for Democracy or for the humane 
 treatment of all human beings . . .

Thanks BuzzFlash,

Shirley
 
Subject: The Iraqi Election - The Catch

Hi Gang! The new Cheerleader of State, Condiliesalot Rice had 
 this to say in regards to a Shiite majority-led government in Iraq:
 
I&apos;m sure that they will have a healthy debate about the role 
 of Islam, about the role of religion in that society. -- Condi 
 Rice on CNN&apos;s Late Edition with Wolf Blitzer (scoop.co) 
 
Right...just like we are engaged in a healthy debate about the 
 role of Christianity, about the role of religion in our society.

Jerry Peurala
Westfield, IN
 
Subject: On the Ground in Mosul

Hi Gang!

Just after Christmas, the brother of my brother-in-law&apos;s wife was 
 sent to Mosul, Iraq.
He is a member of the Indiana National Guard, of course. My brother-in-law 
 told my wife tonight that there are not enough MRE&apos;s to go around, 
 so he and his buddies are rationed down to one meal a day.

Second, the email that they are all supposed to be able to use 
 freely? They have to pay for it. Utter and complete bullshit, courtesy 
 of the Neo-Cons and the lemmings that keep supporting them.
  
Jerry Peurala
Westfield, IN
 
Subject: Dick &quot;Snow Parka&quot; Cheney and Lynne

Does anybody know how much Dick and Lynne gave to the Tsunami rescue 
 effort, by the way? Did you all see how Lynne was all wrapped up 
 in her warm parka, too? Did she even wonder about those Jews and 
 homosexuals, like her very own daughter, who were forced to stand 
 there in the exact weather with only a slave uniform and maybe even 
 no shoes? Wonder what Mary Cheney and her partner would have looked 
 like to Dick and Lynne standing there as another ultra right wing 
 in the past had contempt for the liberals and homosexuals in that 
 country, and made laws against them? The irony of it all is shocking.

Betsy from Texas
 
Subject: Better&quot;snarky&quot;than sold out!
 Give me snarky any day . . . 
 Subject: Snarky editorializing headlines 

Hillary, sounding freakishly DLC-ish, says opposing sides in 
 abortion debate should find &quot;common ground.&quot; What Exactly is 
 That, Anti-Choice Extremists Should Only Blow Up Half a Planned 
 Parenthood Clinic? 1/27

This kind of snarky editorializing demeans BuzzFlash and is 
 offensive to readers...
 
I missed the original (protest) letter. But please...offended 
 readers? Have you taken a poll? I, for one, wasn&apos;t 
 offended. I agree with Shirley: Hillary is tacking to the right (as in DLC positioning) -- and her opening 
 volley may not be the end of her willingness to make concessions 
 to the Christian fundamentalist/evangelical right. 

(An aside: Why doesn&apos;t anyone realize that many DLC positions 
 and people stayed afloat only because they wore the life jacket 
 of Bill Clinton&apos;s personality? Which, of course, explains 
 why Rethuglicans fought so hard to bring him down: the sex scandals 
 were simply pretext; the encroachment on Rethug territory was 
 the underlying issue.) 

Back to Hillary. Although I&apos;d love to see a progressive 
 woman as President in my lifetime, I see her as Bill 
 minus the charm, warmth, and people skills. Give me Barbara Boxer 
 instead, PLEASE!! She doesn&apos;t hedge her bets or talk out 
 of both sides of her mouth. (Pardon the cliches; sometimes 
 they fit.) The moronic conclusion that Democrats must move 
 to the mythical center -- i.e., turn themselves into quasi-Republicans 
 -- is exactly what the Rethugs want to hear. 

I just read a prediction that the dollar is in for a much more 
 rapid and extreme fall, worldwide, than anyone is telling us. Do you think the Bushites are REALLY worried? (Nah, they&apos;ve 
 got their own futures covered quite nicely, thank you.) But that would be the perfect excuse for eliminating ALL safety 
 net programs. Never mind &quot;fixing&quot; Social Security or Medicare/Medicaid; 
 &quot;Oops, sorry, folks, there just isn&apos;t any money to pay for them. Have a nice life under the bridge.&quot;  

An expanded &quot;pre-emptive/spread democracy&quot; foreign policy would 
 ensure the same results, though more gradually, even if the dollar 
 stays afloat. And kiss our public (secular humanist) education 
 system goodbye. But I digress. 

I agree with Shirley: Hillary is trying to ride to victory 
 down the middle of the track, dumping all that &quot;liberal/progressive 
 baggage&quot; along the way. (If Howard Dean isn&apos;t chosen to 
 head the DNC, I&apos;ll know that the party is thinking the same as 
 Hillary. And I, for one, will bolt. I&apos;d rather lose 
 with a candidate I respect and can honestly support -- no, that 
 doesn&apos;t include Ralph Nader; he&apos;s had far more than his allotted 
 15 minutes of fame, and has proved himself an egomaniac in the 
 process) -- than go down with another Titanic. 

Just one more note: I&apos;m not implying that Hillary is wrong 
 for encouraging Democrats to find common ground with anti-Roe 
 v. Wade advocates in terms of alternatives to &quot;abstinence until 
 marriage&quot; -- but (1) many if not most of these people would also 
 ban contraception and reality-based sex education if given the 
 chance, and (2) I strongly suspect her motives. OF COURSE 
 we need sex education, including the use of contraceptives, beyond 
 &quot;abstinence only&quot; -- and the &quot;Plan B&quot; emergency solution seems 
 to have passed many more critical health tests than Vioxx, et 
 al., ever did. Hillary&apos;s ignoring the fact that the people 
 she&apos;s seeking to find &quot;common ground&quot; with are just as adamant 
 in opposing alternatives to abstinence as they are to abortion 
 rights is enough evidence, at least to me, that she&apos;s a female 
 version of Joe Lieberman. One Joe Lieberman is more than 
 enough, thanks.

Barb in Athens, GA
(Blue soul in Red state)

[BuzzFlash Note: We find our readers&apos; debate in Mailbag, sparked 
 by the&quot;snarky headline,&quot;gratifying. We don&apos;t support 
 reader v. reader attacks, or personal attacks on public figures...and 
 our feelings aren&apos;t too hurt that we were criticized, 
 but you&apos;ve been giving us a lively debate of issues...Are leading 
 democrats shifting on the issues? Where is the party going? Who 
 can we trust? Although we can&apos;t publish every letter, let&apos;s keep 
 up the debate!]
 
Subject: Deceptive media on voter turnout

Hello BuzzFlash,

I love your site. Thank you for a sane oasis in a lying deceptive 
 media ocean. I&apos;m contacting you about the horrible blanket coverage 
 I&apos;m seeing in the media about what a &quot;great&quot; turnout there was 
 in the Iraqi &quot;elections.&quot; Please help get the word out about how 
 manipulative these stories are!!! You are one of the few web sites 
 that can actually see through the complete lies of the media whores 
 4 Bush.

First of all, they parrot Bush calling the elections a &quot;resounding 
 success.&quot; What about any neutral observers - if there are any? 
 Bush is the LAST person who should be quoted for this story.

Then, they use all kinds of manipulative techniques to make 
 the turnout sound much higher than it actually is. Examples:

1) The first numbers they throw out are these: U.S. State Department 
 spokesman Noel Clay said 5,171 polling centers -- 98.8 percent 
 of the 5,232 that were expected to open -- actually did so. What 
 bullshit!! They&apos;re trying to make it sound like there&apos;s 98.8 percent 
 turnout, when they&apos;re really talking about polling places &quot;that 
 were expected to open,&quot; This is a complete smokescreen. That could 
 exclude any arbitrary number of polling places that AREN&apos;T expected 
 to open! How many people don&apos;t have access to a polling place? 
 We have no way of knowing.

2) &quot;The IECI clarified an earlier estimate of a 72 percent turnout, 
 saying that the &quot;figures are only very rough, word-of-mouth estimates 
 gathered informally from the field.&quot; &quot;What is certainly the case 
 is that turnout has exceeded expectations throughout the country,&quot; 
 the statement said.&quot; This is crap! 72 percent is totally made 
 up!! (as they admit) All they say is &quot;exceeded expectations.&quot; 
 Totally meaningless. Could be ANYTHING!

3) &quot;About 66 percent of Iraqi expatriates who were registered 
 to vote -- 186,619 -- cast ballots in the first two days of their 
 three-day voting period, the United Nations&apos; Iraq out-of-country 
 voting program said Sunday. More than 280,000 expatriates registered 
 for the election.&quot; First of all - now they switch to expats - 
 totally different from within the country. I had heard somewhere 
 that only 1 in 4 eligible expats actually registered. Whether 
 that&apos;s true or not - it strikes me as LOW that only 66 percent 
 of REGISTERED voters actually did. After all - they must have 
 registered specifically to vote in this election! Why did only 
 2 in 3 actually vote?

4) &quot;In former president Saddam Hussein&apos;s hometown of Tikrit, 
 polling stations were virtually empty. But in other parts of the 
 country booths were packed. In the northeastern town of Baquba, 
 CNN&apos;s Jane Arraf found a polling station where a long line of 
 Iraqi voters chanted and clapped their hands in front of the camera. 
 (On the Scene) Unofficial figures indicated that 30 percent of 
 eligible voters there came to the polls.&quot; Hmmm. SO in Tikrit polling 
 stations were empty. In Baquba there was 30 percent turnout. But 
 the elections were a &quot;resounding success?!&quot;-- what crap! 
 And on and on and on.

I&apos;m sure you agree. I just wanted to vent to someone sane, and 
 hope that you and others will help expose these horrible manipulations 
 of facts and reality with &quot;heartwarming vignettes of old women 
 being wheeled to the polls in wheelbarrows.&quot; Give me a fucking 
 break! Anyway. Thanks for the outlet. And thanks for all you do!! 
 Sooner or later - these media whores will be flushed down the 
 toilet.

 Sporadic 
 violence doesn&apos;t deter Iraqi voters: Bush calls election a &apos;resounding 
 success&apos; (CNN) 

Dave Portland
Portland, Oregon

[BuzzFlash Note: The last 6 paragraphs (of 55) of CNN&apos;s story 
 are perhaps more telling. But who reads that far, past 7 cheery 
 headlines and subheads?]
 
Subject: The Borderline Between a War and a Crime . . . Sanity 
 - Insanity

BuzzFlash,

If possible, statistics might provide the evidence that for some, 
 the borderline between war and crime is easily crossed. There 
 was a kidnapping and murder of a young woman from a Wal-Mart parking 
 lot. Crime happens everywhere . . . but, I found this crime disturbing 
 because the young man who was caught because of a surveillance 
 camera and a botched robbery days later . . . happened to be a 
 four year Marine who served in Iraq. Since being released, he 
 had been arrested for possession of cocaine and out on bail just 
 a month before being arrested for the murder and another foiled 
 robbery. Is there a correlation because of serving in Iraq . . 
 . I don&apos;t know, but it wouldn&apos;t be the first.

Aside from the facts that the war in Iraq is a crime . . . that 
 makes all of the killing crimes, shouldn&apos;t it . . . and then we 
 have had reports of many Iraqi children, parents, friends, neighbors, 
 being killed for no reason. What happens to people who are told 
 to kill innocent people . . . families? What happens to people 
 when they find out they are invading a country . . . that the 
 Iraqis hate them and want them to leave? What happens to our people 
 when they learn that Iraqis do not consider them heroes . . . 
 but, murderers . . . the enemy?

How many people in the US will become victims due to the violence 
 in Iraq and bring that violence back to the US and keep on killing? 
 It&apos;s one thing for a person to fight for a belief in his country 
 . . . it is quite another thing for a person to fight and kill 
 unarmed men, women and children . . . we cannot expect military 
 to come home as if nothing happened to them while in Iraq.

This careless, illegal war has victims everywhere one looks. Iraqi, 
 US military, families of dead military, psychologically damaged 
 military and the victims of those who will be affected in some 
 way because of the violence they have perpetrated or experienced 
 in Iraq. George Bush bears responsibility for this war and all 
 of the results from this war. He took an oath of office and he 
 lied this country into a war. There are victims that Bush could 
 never understand or care about. When will our members in Congress 
 stop this genocide? Military will be dead, wounded, or mentally 
 disturbed because of a lie and a country destroyed.

So far, we have seen our military used for an illegal war, denied 
 proper equipment and food, denied proper pay, billed while wounded 
 for food and care or for plane rides home etc., benefits cut to 
 military families, denied proper psychiatric care . . . this is 
 Bush&apos;s job to see that it is done . . . but when a person lies 
 to start a war, pilfers Iraq and the US treasury without being 
 held accountable . . . yet, our military is being held accountable 
 . . . US citizens are being held accountable for all of these 
 losses . . . and Bush is still in office, along with promotions 
 for his loyal accomplices in these atrocities.

American citizens, not only have to bear the financial debt -- 
 largest in US history -- that may destroy our economy, but are 
 Americans willing to watch while the heart and soul of our Democracy 
 and everything we believe in . . . destroyed for the selfish purposes 
 of the Bush administration?

So far . . . the answer is yes. Another question is, what happens 
 to our members of Congress after they have been in DC for a number 
 of years? Have they, too, stopped believing in Democracy or justice? 
 What borderline are they standing on? Why do they help Bush and 
 his administration with their votes and still refuse to try and 
 make this administration held accountable for so much death and 
 destruction during the last four years?

Just wonderin . . .

Thanks BuzzFlash,

Shirley Smith
 
Subject: Fareed 
 Zakaria story ....my my, what a difference!

Dear Buzz,

Is it just me or are we seeing the war whoopers, and Zakaria 
 was firmly in that camp, now changing their tunes and talking 
 about liberal democracy? Buzz, I enjoy coffee in the morning, 
 but reading the line about &quot;liberal democracy&quot; from Mr. Zakaria 
 was almost cause me to cough the coffee out onto the monitor!

It is just dawning on the higher minds that maybe Bush&apos;s little 
 bungle in the desert is not going to turn out well? I can&apos;t imagine 
 why! Buzz, we have learned from Robert Fisk that only 5 polling 
 places in Iraq were permitted to be filmed and covered. 4 were 
 in Shia districts expecting a heavy turnout, and 1 was in an upscale 
 Sunni area. Like it or not, we have been played by image management 
 again.

Ask yourselves the following: do Iraqis have control of their 
 own oil; do Iraqis have secure streets and countryside; do the 
 Iraqis have a loyal army and police force; and do Iraqis have 
 proper support infrastructure to sustain a viable sense of community? 
 So, while Mr. Zakaria&apos;s article dances around all of these points, 
 and then drops the old, better angels line, as if this makes everything 
 OK. Look at how the chickens have come home to roost when it comes 
 to &quot;Plan Dubya From Outer Texas,&quot; as I have long called Bush&apos;s 
 Iraq mania, so I am not coming from a position of 20/20 hindsight, 
 but from a position that was in opposition to the entire Iraq 
 hysteria since day #1.

But the kicker is how Mr. Zakaria, from the comforts of his upscale 
 office, and in such a quick and blaséfashion, wants Iraq 
 to have some other economic engine besides oil. The inference 
 being that oil leads to &quot;distant and detached&quot; rulers. Buzz, this 
 is too much to ask us to endure. Read this part after his paragraph 
 starter, &quot;Second, create a non-oil-based economy...&quot;

Do you see the problem here? Iraq has huge oil tracts, that are 
 not developed, and the potential wealth is enormous...but Mr. 
 Zakaria would have the Iraqis go do something else like say, basket 
 weaving perhaps, because oil leads to distant and detached rulers! 
 Well guess what, not since Rush Limbaugh said that troops were 
 just blowing off steam at Abu Ghraib, and that it was like a frat 
 hazing prank, have I heard or read anything more completely dishonest, 
 or utterly contemptible! Who gets the oil, Mr. Zakaria? If not 
 the Iraqis, because they obviously won&apos;t want detached and distant 
 rulers, then maybe the American occupiers, perhaps? Those distant, 
 detached and rather murderous &quot;rulers&quot; of the moment, is that 
 who gets the oil Mr. Zakaria?

Buzz, Iraq is a fiasco, and was from day number one little more 
 than a Klondike, a veritable Klondike, for every shady security 
 operation, every second rate services contractor, and every single 
 defense ordinance and weaponry supplier in the US and Britain. 
 But Mr. Zakaria wants us to have hope that this fumbled and jumbled 
 disaster in the desert is going to be all better if the Iraqis 
 just get his three points.

I have hope that one day Iraq will heal and become better. But 
 we expect too much, too soon, considering that the Iraq war is 
 and was unnecessary. But my most fervent hope is that one day 
 the Iraqis at large will forgive us for our brutality and perversity 
 towards them. Perhaps saying, &quot;We forgive you, for your nation 
 was in the grips of greedy and clever madmen.&quot;

 We&apos;ll 
 go on cheering &apos;democracy&apos; - and the Iraqis will go on dying (Robert Fisk/The Independent/information clearinghouse) 

Steve from Syracuse
 
Am wondering about a comment by Judith Miller (NYT) on Sunday 
 (Jan 30) Hardball, in which she said her sources told her that 
 the US had offered Chalabi the post of Interior Minister BEFORE 
 the Iraqi elections. Matthews went ballistic, and asked how this 
 was possible...said something to the effect, &quot;How does the US 
 determine cabinet positions of a country which just had a free/democratic 
 election to begin determining its own government?&quot; The actual 
 transcript should be posted somewhere, I just can&apos;t find it. Matthews 
 also said something to the effect, &quot;Do you mean the man who started 
 this war will end up winning it?&quot; (controlling it) Please look 
 into this. AAR is now talking about this (9:00 a.m. CST, Jan 31).

 Together, Again: Judith 
 Miller and Ahmad Chalabi (Jack Shafer/slate.com) 

 &apos;Hardball with 
 Chris Matthews&apos; for Jan. 30 (MSNBC) 

Ann
 
Subject: Iraq election

Just a week ago, there were reports about the disappointing rate 
 of registration to vote, both in Iraq (25%) and among Iraqis living 
 abroad (10%). So what is this 60% participation rate that is being 
 used to tout success? Is it 60% of 25%? That&apos;s pretty dismal, 
 in fact.

Doreen Broneer
St Quentin les Troos, France (US citizen)
 
Subject: Voting vs Democracy

Yes...they had an election in Iraq, and you could consider that 
 to be step one in the establishment of Democracy in that country. 
 But it will require a lot more to say with any certainty, that 
 Iraq has become a Democratic nation. When they have a functioning 
 economy, an equitable judicial system and social integration that 
 encompasses all belief systems as well as equal rights for all 
 citizens...you could make a real case for the triumph of Democracy 
 in the nation and the march of Freedom in the Middle East.

Until then...don&apos;t count out the killers and con men and political 
 terrorists, all armed with sadistic focus on the destruction of 
 each achievement earned under the Bush occupation. The next couple 
 years will play out in complete unpredictability, so The Bush 
 Cartel oughta keep a tight lip on their victorious pronouncements. 
 Hey George...it&apos;s time to get real and do something good for the 
 United States of America...your sworn duty.

Richard Wagner
Saginaw, Michigan 
 
Subject: &quot;Every Cock is proud on his own dunghill!&quot;

&quot;I HAVE ACHIEVED EVERYTHING!&quot;&quot;I Have Achieved 
 Everything,&quot;the beginning of that quote sounds very impressive. 
 The whole quote is:&quot;I have achieved everything I set out 
 to do, and have thus become perhaps the greatest German in history!&quot;The speaker who declared that with certainty was Adolph Hitler.

This morning George W. Bush and the Pollyanna press were gushing 
 with enthusiasm about the turnout in the Iraqi Election. Are we 
 jumping the gun a bit? At this point the voting data is still 
 guess work, with some of the first predictions being down graded. 
 Before we beat the drums of success, let&apos;s look a little further 
 down the road. Before George Bush once again credits himself for 
 turning another corner, he should remember most of his turns ended 
 up in a dead end or became a&quot;u&quot;turn, and that nothing 
 is certain or unchangeable.

The trouble in Iraq is far from over. Who will the leaders be, 
 and will they ensure the peace or cause a civil war? Will this 
 be seen as a dual Presidency by the world if Ayad Allawi wins? 
 At best getting a Constitution written up with all parties agreeing 
 is quite a feat, especially with all the differing viewpoints. 
 Will the situation in Iraq end up being in chaos for years? How 
 long will Americans pay with their lives? How long will our taxpayers&apos; 
 money be used in Iraq, money that could be used for our own nation?

A more cautious leader might have waited a few weeks or even 
 a few months before patting themselves on the back! George Bush 
 declares success without remorse, while not admitting mistakes, 
 and blaming others for his failures!&quot;People wrapped up in 
 themselves make very small packages!&quot;

We congratulate the Iraqi people on their vote and their bravery. 
 Most of the world agrees that the Iraqi people should be able 
 to control their own future! It is a shame they also had to run 
 through so many cemeteries and suffer the deaths of so many on 
 the way to the voting booths! Yes, freedom comes at a price, but 
 there could have been different coin used to get there with less 
 cost of human life! The Iraqis&apos;&quot;free elections&quot;were 
 tainted with curfews and emergency rule. There were too many candidates 
 that the people knew too little about. The Military was seen everywhere, 
 though necessary, still a very strange scene to be envisioned 
 in a&quot;free&quot;election. There was also the loss a minority 
 vote of Sunnis which questions the effectiveness of the election. 
 Many facts in the Iraqi Election must be assimilated before it 
 is declared a&quot;success!&quot;

We have seen too much subterfuge in the past from the Bush Administration. 
 We must have more than just a dearth of information before a conclusion 
 is reached and specious claims of victory are announced!

We should not be able to invade Sovereign Nations at will. All 
 means do not justify the ends! We can not bomb or shoot people 
 into submission in order to install any form of government because 
 we think it&apos;s right for them! We cannot install puppet governments 
 or enter a war under false pretenses because we wish to change 
 the face of many nations in our image! In the face of what seems 
 to be a first step we cannot dismiss how we got there for reasons 
 of profit or to leave a legacy!

We must change places for a moment to envision another nation 
 invading our country!&quot;The victor will not be asked afterwards 
 whether he told the truth or not. In starting and waging war, 
 it is not right that matters, but victory!&quot;This was another 
 viewpoint expressed by Adolph Hitler!
  
Susan Carr
Tucson
 
Subject: election farce

In poll after poll Iraqis have voiced their conviction that America 
 is an occupying power more concerned with Iraqi oil than Iraqi 
 people. By a vast majority they want America to leave Iraq as 
 soon as possible, and those who express reservations about America 
 leaving do so almost universally out of fear of what will follow 
 if the US walks away from the nightmare it has created. It is 
 against this background that we should view the election and its 
 results.

&quot;In great numbers, and under great risk, Iraqis have shown 
 their commitment to democracy.&quot;

What the Iraqis have shown is that the people of an occupied country, 
 unable to expel their occupier by force, will participate in the&quot;elections&quot;orchestrated and controlled by the invaders 
 if it is their only means of regaining some control over their 
 own destiny. With widespread ignorance of who was running and 
 what they stood for (for&quot;security reasons&quot;the names 
 of many candidates where not even known until election day) and 
 with the field of candidates wholly controlled by the interim 
 puppet government, the only thing&quot;historic&quot;about these 
 elections is the breathtaking scope of the charade that they were&quot;democratic.&quot;

Albert Clark
NY
 
Subject: Bush Social Security and Public Opinion Polls

For years now Bush has claimed he does not use public opinion polls 
 to help him make policy. The Bush Republicans repeat this mantra 
 as if it was the secret to eternal life. Yet recent events appear 
 to show just the opposite. Bush relies heavily on public opinion, 
 he just doesn&apos;t use the conventional polls to get his data.

Bush has decided he would take on the third rail of Politics in 
 a Herculean effort to &apos;save&apos; Americans from themselves and Democrats. 
 He was going to make Social Security work and keep it from bankruptcy. 
 He started this crusade the same way he has started all his crusades, 
 with misinformation, erroneous facts and FEAR.

I will not go into the details of Social Security other than it 
 is not Social Security that is broken, it is the Government&apos;s inability 
 to cover the Treasury Bonds Social Security will be redeeming to 
 pay our retiring Baby Boomers, I will not mention the Medicare crisis 
 which dwarfs the Social Security issue.

Bush has stated he has a grand plan to fix what does not need to 
 be fixed, and ignore the fire that is burning down the house. He 
 however has not told us what that fix is, because he still hasn&apos;t 
 finished gathering his data from America. To find out what form 
 of smoke and mirrors will the US citizens accept, so he can hide 
 the fiscal chaos his ill advised tax cuts have created.

Bush surrogates are currently polling America. They are doing this 
 by floating the bright ideas that are coming out of Bush&apos;s crack 
 economic team. As each new idea comes to life, the Surrogates trot 
 out the idea to the various talking heads shows, then listen for 
 the reaction to each idea. Through this process they fine tune the 
 Social Security &apos;fix&apos; Bush has in mind.

Once an idea is floated, the &apos;paid&apos; news reporters talk it up, the 
 &apos;unaffiliated&apos; RNC think tanks poll public opinion, and ideas are 
 tweaked, modified or eliminated accordingly.

This is not truly &apos;polling&apos; in the strict sense, but what else would 
 you call it, but governing by public fiat.

The world is slowly making it known that the National Debt, The 
 Deficit, The Trade Deficit and the growing irresponsible monetary 
 actions of the Republican-controlled US Government are the reasons 
 the US dollar is in decline, and the fiscal stability of the US 
 is potentially in jeopardy.

As I said before, the Emperor has no Clothes.

Sean Lewis
Founder of the Open Debate Forum 
Subject: oh yea

 Your Jan 20th 
 editorial was right on. You continue to provide perceptive 
 analysis on the criminal regime that occupies our Federal Government 
 and therefore provide an invaluable service to the country. Please 
 continue on and yes ...I have purchased several BuzzFlash premiums 
 and will purchase more in the future.

Richard Wagner
 
Subject: Those Iraqis that were cheering in the pix were all 
 to similar to the fake crowd toppling Saddam&apos;s statue!

Take a quick look at all the Reuters&apos; pictures and any others 
 you can see. It is another case of this administration&apos;s manipulation 
 of truth. Next, go back and look at pictures from any anti-war 
 march or the March for Women&apos;s lives just last year. Funny, how 
 those marches only had a hundred thousand or so, but this election, 
 with all of about 100 or so people standing in each line had 15,000,000 
 participants. 15 million votes! Right! Did you take a look at 
 the transparent ballot boxes, Tupperware things? There must be 
 all of about a hundred votes in each one, if that. And the pictures 
 ended up being filled with&quot;absentee&quot;ballots.

Let&apos;s just examine the rhetoric surrounding this&quot;election.&quot;&quot;More voters than anyone expected.&quot;Really? Don&apos;t you 
 think this headline was in the can long before the election even 
 happened? There was going to be a happy face story if half the 
 country was blown to smithereens.

This story is all too similar to the toppling of Saddam statue 
 that is shown forever and a day. And having seen it live on TV, 
 the reality and the hype were 180 degrees different.
Will any mainstream media question the premises of this election 
 story? And I do mean&quot;story.&quot;

Will anyone do the math? Count polling places. Count soldiers 
 guarding the polling places and divide into the the actual numbers 
 of polling places. Look at pictures dumping these huge ballots 
 on heavy paper onto piles to be counted. There must be all of 
 30 ballots in a box. How many of the jubilant Iraqis were from 
 outside Iraq? How many were paid jubilants with those nice new 
 Iraqi flags?

I am of Irish descent. Shouldn&apos;t I be able to vote in the Irish 
 elections? The Iraqi people they show pictures of here, haven&apos;t 
 been there in 40 years. Have they signed up to go to war? Have 
 they signed up to even go back? They are just there for the pictures...and 
 the quotes...since no quote is worth hearing unless it is in English. 
 You know they only use the ballots of these ex-Iraqis to make 
 the election look like it has more support than it does.
Do they think we are all fools...DON&quot;T ANSWER THAT!

BuzzFlash Addict

[BuzzFlash Note: Remember this one?&quot;The fake troops in 
 Bush&apos;s new ad&quot;at http://www.dailykos.com/story/2004/10/27/22442/878 .]
 
Subject: social security and brickbats

Dear BuzzFlash,

Any Democrat who goes along with the GOP on making Social Security 
 out to be in crisis is nuts. It is imperative that the other side, 
 the true story, is made well known to the public. So many people 
 are writing about it, but will it really get out and be the talking 
 point &apos;around the water coolers&apos;? The administration is setting 
 up the same company, used during the late campaign, to handle 
 the publicity for this so-called crisis. Since the Swift Boat 
 Liars was such a success, it is frightening to think that the 
 same &apos;success&apos; could happen again.

On another note, do you suppose that &apos;Reds&apos; are behind the brickbats 
 you have been getting? Your squibs for the various links can be 
 irreverent, but that is what makes you interesting...and charming. 
 I guess I am saying...don&apos;t change, just keep doing your good 
 work.
  
Stephanie
Dearborn, Michigan
 
Subject: Iraq elections -- in the long run

BuzzFlash,

The media and chickenhawks are gushing over the Iraq election, 
 but what will the long-term effects be?

 The 
 Iraqi election: In the long run... (realitybasednation.com) 

I simply can&apos;t believe our media is falling for it again. Have 
 they and the American public learned nothing from this war?

Bob Cesca,
Editor, Reality Based Nation 
 
Subject: Dean as DNC Chair

 Interesting 
 article by Bob &quot;the Traitor&quot; Novak as it was only last night 
 that I sent an email to Nancy Pelosi saying if they did to Dean 
 now what they did to him in the primary I would immediately change 
 my registration to the Green Party and stop contributing to any 
 Democrat (other than someone like Barbara &quot;Rule of Law&quot; Boxer) 
 until I see some actions rather than words. As I said, principles 
 matter more than winning at all costs but I believe principles 
 are the road to winning.

Steven Brown
Palm Springs, CA

[BuzzFlash Note: The DNC is here: http://www.democrats.org/contact/ .]
 
Subject: A MILLION ROSES FOR BARBARA BOXER

Hello to everyone at BuzzFlash,

In my humble opinion Barbara Boxer is the bravest and most honest 
 Senator in the United States. She&apos;s also got bigger cajones than 
 any of the men who profess to serve we the people in the Congress 
 and Senate. She may be little but she&apos;s one tough cookie and I 
 think we should all let her know how much we appreciate her.

I thought about sending her a lace jockstrap but then I heard 
 about a program provided by Coast to Coast Florists on the Mike 
 Malloy Show on Air America Radio. For $10.00 they&apos;ll send Senator 
 Boxer 3 roses for Valentines Day, along with a very nice message 
 of appreciation for her honesty and courage. I just called and 
 placed my order and I was happy to learn that the response to 
 the program has been extremely enthusiastic. It&apos;s easy to let 
 her know we think she&apos;s a real American heroine. Just call 1-888-501-ROSE. 
 Orders must be placed by February 12th.

Senator Boxer has been savagely criticized in the press for refusing 
 to recognize the Ohio electoral delegation as well as her grilling 
 of Condoleezza Rice during her Senate hearings. Are they attacking 
 Senator Boxer fairly or is it their knee-jerk reaction to an honest 
 progressive? I think they&apos;re scared to death of the petite senator 
 who speaks the truth.

Let&apos;s show the media that we progressives appreciate courage 
 and honesty. A MILLION ROSES FOR BARBARA BOXER just might get 
 their attention. And it might persuade a few more senators that 
 we expect them to be strong and stand up for progressive values; 
 and when they do, we will support them. I hope everyone will consider 
 taking part in this endeavor.

As usual, thank you BuzzFlash for being there.

Judy Maclean
Colorado
 
Subject: Let&apos;s have some REAL democracy!!!!

If we REALLY wanted to demonstrate whether Iraq is a democracy 
 or not we should let them vote on if they desire the American 
 troops to stay or leave Iraq.

Sw
 
Subject: Today&apos;s deaths in Iraq

It must be tough on today&apos;s reporters when a reliable bit of 
 boilerplate White House spin suddenly becomes obsolete. For example, 
 in today&apos;s reports of Marine deaths in Iraq, there&apos;s nothing said 
 about why insurgents killed them. That may seem like a small change, 
 but think about it--for months now, virtually every killing by 
 insurgents has been &quot;intended to disrupt the upcoming historic 
 elections,&quot; or, &quot;an attempt to dissuade Iraqis from voting in 
 the upcoming national elections.&quot; That was why our kids were dying 
 a week ago.

But now, the election behind us, they&apos;re apparently just dying. 
 The stories seem a little naked, somehow--a little bald and purposeless. 
 So maybe, with that trusty old saw lost to us forever, we should 
 seek a new rationale for the insurgents&apos; doings--perhaps describing 
 the bloodshed as &quot;intended to disrupt forcible occupation and 
 corporate looting,&quot; or, &quot;an attempt to persuade us to leave their 
 country.&quot;

A BuzzFlash Reader
Halfway, OR
 
Subject: Minor League Baseball Player Is A Pro In The Marines

Hi BuzzFlash,

This was a Sports Article by Jeff Jacobs in The Hartford Courant. 
 Too bad Bush, Cheney, Rumsfeld and Wolfowitz won&apos;t take a tour 
 of Iraq with Stevens in his Humvee. From the sounds of it, they 
 might &quot;see a little action,&quot; and find out what war is &quot;like.&quot;

 He&apos;ll 
 Never Be Called Safe: Tony Stevens, Ex-Rock Cats Shortstop, Has 
 Survived Nine Bombings In Iraq (Hartford Courant) 

Tom Wieliczka
 
Subject: Social Security Savings Accounts

If most Americans are not saving money now, what makes the Bush 
 Administration think they will suddenly start with private social 
 security accounts?

A BuzzFlash Reader
 
Subject: Blog Request

Would love it if BuzzFlash would take a look at my blog. Thanks 
 in advance for your attention to this message!
 
Brendan Smith 
http://brandoland.blogspot.com/ 
Los Angeles, CA
 
Subject: How to end the preemptive war...January 31, 2005, A 
 Peace Plan:

In the days of yore, leaders led from the front, not sitting 
 in front of computer monitors thousands of miles away in the bomb 
 proof bunker called the Pentagon or the &quot;situation room&quot; of the 
 White House. To get things back on track, I propose that every 
 politician who votes to send our children off to slaughter and 
 be slaughtered, should by law, be required to be trained, then 
 sent to spend six-months inside the theater of action, be it Iraq 
 or whatever war-du-jour. Provisions could be made for these legislators 
 to continue to vote and legislate via secure channels on the internet. 
 When done, the younger politicians would be issued weapons and 
 combat gear (including body armor--but only after all the young 
 soldiers their policies placed in harms way, have all been issued 
 theirs). They then would routinely be ordered out on combat patrols 
 in the same armorless Humvees our young troops are dying in.

Pols too old to go on patrol will be given a tent inside the 
 green-zone where they can learn to live with the fear and uncertainty 
 of rubbing shoulders with Iraqis, any of whom might just be the 
 next vest-bomber. Their sleep won&apos;t be so solid since every random 
 incoming rocket or mortar round has a chance to wound, maim or 
 kill them. After doing their legislative work via e-mail, the 
 older pols would be assigned to work as orderlies with the grave 
 registration units where they can help prepare the mutilated bodies 
 of our young for shipment back to their grieving parents. Also, 
 health permitting, these older politicians who voted to send our 
 youth off to &quot;their war,&quot; must put on their blue, pin-striped 
 suits and serve as escorts on the body-planes shuttling back and 
 forth to the Dover body-processing-center, and then on to the 
 homes of the dead soldiers where they will personally present 
 the American flag to their grieving parents in lieu of their children.

(Note: The Secretary of Defense will be required to actually 
 sign the death letters and not use his signature machine.)

If travel is deemed too hard on the aging bodies of these politician/warriors, 
 they would be assigned to work as orderlies in MASH tents where 
 they can clean up the body-fluids and bloody gauze created by 
 amputation operations. Perhaps when these spine-challenged politicians 
 are required to see and hear and smell the reality of the armless, 
 legless, eyeless young men and women their policies have created, 
 they will think twice about sending them off to a war that truly, 
 short of oil, had no cause.

It&apos;s easy to strut around saying, &quot;Bring &apos;em on&quot; when you&apos;re 
 thousands of miles away from the awfulness of war. If we passed 
 a resolution that stuck all those NeoCon, chicken-hawk, war-lovers 
 in the middle of that carnage of their making, we would quickly 
 see some real foreign-relation policy changes--especially if you 
 told them after six months that their tour of duty was being extended.

Miguel Lanigan
Clearlake Oaks, CA
 
Subject: Bush&apos;s Medicare proposals

On C-Span over the weekend, there was a hearing before a number 
 of Democratic Senators. Appearing before the Senators were several 
 administrators or career federal employees who had spent their 
 entire extensive careers in administrating Medicare policies. 
 They have gotten memos etc. through there official channels to 
 sell the Bush Plan on Medicare reform. These whistle blowers requested 
 the hearing. They feel that it is unprofessional, illegal and 
 personally disgusting to take a political platform as a part of 
 their job.

This is just another way that Karl Rove, President Cheney, King 
 Bush use our tax dollars to spread their bs, and the administrators 
 are to send out information that would on appearance look as an 
 official statement from Medicare.

Also on the panel was a person who represented Government Oversight. 
 I believe that one of the Senators is taking it to the Justice 
 Department.

I suppose the next use of our tax dollars is to spread Fundamental 
 Christianity, and who will spread that message-Our Welfare Department 
 or perhaps the Defense Department?

I hope BuzzFlash can get the entire script for us BuzzFlash fans.

Larry Swick
Wounded Knee, S.D.
 
Subject: Bush&apos;s $6 billion helicopters

Buzz,

This is worse, but similar to Bhagwan Rajnesh with his dozens 
 of Rolls Royces. $6,100,000,000 for 23 presidential helicopters 
 is $273,913,043.00 per helicopter, and why does Bush need 23 of 
 them?

 Lockheed wins Marine 
 One contract (AP/MSNBC) 

 Lockheed 
 Martin wins presidential helicopter contract (AP/USAToday) 

etc...., but not much about the obscene amount of money to transport 
 the Smirking Chimp to various photo ops.

Bob
 
Subject: put alternative radio.org on the links list please

I think BuzzFlash is GREAT and I would like to see alternative 
 radio put on the links list, ie front page. I believe AR 
 has been doing a great job and has a lot to offer the BuzzFlash 
 folks. Thanks for your time.
  
jp thomas
bend oregon
 
Subject: Bobby Kennedy Jr

We need a man of integrity to lead us into the future the same 
 way JFK led us to the moon. I am tired of the less than 100 IQ 
 inbred skull and bones men like Bush. It&apos;s time we had an intelligent 
 President again, let&apos;s elect someone with better than a &quot;C&quot; average...how 
 about a 130 IQ minimum for our President? Let us elect Bobby Kennedy 
 Jr. for our next president. I can not think of anyone who has 
 lived as true to integrity in government. 2008 Kennedy! Vindication!
  
Maurice Chatigny
San Diego, Ca
 
Subject: Taking a Step Backward . . .

BuzzFlash,

This from Truthout -
 
 Soros 
 Says Kerry&apos;s Failings Undermined Campaign against Bush (Bloomberg.net) 

Kerry, a Massachusetts senator, said in a Newsweek interview 
 that he lost because he failed to connect with voters, the magazine 
 reported in its Jan. 10 issue. He also attributed his loss to 
 Bush&apos;s head start in organizing and fundraising, and Bush&apos;s 
 advantage of incumbency, particularly at a time of war, the 
 article said.
 
Also from Truthout below the above article -
 
 Kerry 
 Says bin Laden Tape Gave Bush a Lift (NY Times) 

Senator John Kerry said on Sunday that the attacks of Sept. 
 11 were the&quot;central deciding thing&quot;in his contest 
 with President Bush and that the release of an Osama bin Laden 
 videotape the weekend before Election Day had effectively erased 
 any hope he had of victory.
 
The DLC always wanted to get closer to Republicans . . . well 
 judging from all of the excuses, they are . . . Kerry says that 
 Sept 11 was the central deciding thing . . . Did he ever say that 
 Iraqis had nothing to do with 911? Did he ever say that Bush lied 
 to Congress about WMD? There is much yet to tell about 911 to Americans 
 . . . Kerry went after Bush with a velvet gloved handshake, a hug 
 and a kiss.

So, Kerry says he failed to connect with voters . . . which ones, 
 those who had their votes stolen, those who stood in line for hours 
 because of no machines, those who worked their asses off for months 
 . . . those who constantly donated to him? The DLC have learned 
 how to dismiss the real reasons for continued loss in elections. 
 DLC . . . Democratic Losing Candidates - join here . . . if an organization 
 or persons involved can&apos;t examine itself close enough . . . aside 
 from the votes that were scrapped and downright fraudulent . . . 
 Kerry might have won with the proper attitude about how important 
 votes are to Americans or a Democratic platform that explained the 
 difference between Democrats and what the Bush administration has 
 been doing for the last four years against our Country . . . those 
 ideas could have helped . . . just for starters.

Everyone fighting for recounts and explanations in Ohio . . . looked 
 more like candidates than Kerry, who hightailed it as soon as he 
 could. He dismissed the average intelligence of Democratic voters 
 when he took off to Iraq instead of challenging the Ohio vote, so 
 that he couldn&apos;t be called a&quot;sore loser.&quot;I hope he didn&apos;t 
 compare us Democrats to Republican voters thinking that we also 
 would believe everything that is told to us.

He should take another vacation, rest and contemplate . . . is he 
 trying to convince Democrats why he lost or just himself?

Democrats still have fraud to contend with while the DLC sit back 
 and lick their imaginary wounds . . . because in my mind, backing 
 the DLC against Republicans is a double loss for the Democratic 
 Party and never again will I vote or support any DLC candidate. 
 I&apos;m a Democrat not a Republican Lite. Be true to thine own self, 
 Democrats.

Just a thought,

Thanks BuzzFlash,

Shirley Smith
 back to 
 top
	</body>
</document>
