<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001654" url="http://ezinearticles.com/?Live-Well-By-Counting-Your-Daily-Calories-Intake&amp;id=1010992" time="2012-07-12-17:25" support="2" score="0.016492123274143202" bingtitle="Live Well By Counting Your Daily Calories Intake" webtitle="Live Well By Counting Your Daily Calories Intake">
			<query id="001435" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="001418" bing-rank="37"/>
	<description>Whenever a new fast food restaurant opens within our city, we ... Therefore, it is advisable to count your daily intake ... your daily intake of calories in food and change your ...</description>
	<body>
		Search Home » Health and Fitness » Weight Loss Tom Chuong 
 Platinum Author |   101 Articles 
 Joined: October 19, 2006 Was this article helpful? 0 0 
Live Well By Counting Your Daily Calories Intake

 By Tom Chuong 
 
We all want to try out different things to eat. Whenever a new fast food restaurant opens within our city, we do not resist the temptation of hanging out there. However, the problem is that such food harms your health, as they contain much higher level of calories. Therefore, it is advisable to count your daily intake of calories in your diet in order to avoid any adverse effects on your health.

There are various means through which you can count your daily intake of calories. There are numerous software tools that help you in counting calories, as they contain diet planner also. They provide professional advice on food combining detox suggested daily calorie intake both for men and women, calorie intake from beverages consumed and various other guidelines for speeding up your metabolism.

In fact, you can easily watch your diet by simply eating half of everything you buy from a fast food restaurant. Order one meal, and split that burger or fries with a friend or significant other. You both saved money and you&apos;ll lose more weight using this method.

If you are gaining weight and are feeling tired all the time, you should start counting your daily intake of calories in food and change your daily diet. For individuals to get sufficient nutrients and stay healthy, they need around 1200 calories a day.

There are numerous cases where the doctor also advises to take sufficient intake of daily calories for improving your health. Henceforth, it is important to have standard calories in your daily diet. Fewer intakes lower your health power and more makes you chubby by increasing your weight.

Again, there are various programs out there for you, so that they can easily count your daily intake of calories in order to avoid any ill effects on your health. Do this now and start living a healthy lifestyle.
 
Tom Chuong works as an Health Consultant for Clay Media Group, LLC. Currently, he&apos;s writing health articles on topics related to Hoodia Diet Pills , Hoodia , and Herbal Remedies . If you need an experienced SEO expert to work on your commercial website, please contact him.
 
Article Source: http://EzineArticles.com/?expert=Tom_Chuong 
 Did you find this article helpful? 0 0 Get Involved 0 comments Suggest a topic Article Tools Print this article Download a PDF E-mail to a friend EzinePublisher Report this article Cite this article Stay Informed Get notified by email when new articles are added to this category or written by this author. 
Subscribe to New Article Alerts:
 
 Health and Fitness: Weight-Loss 
 Tom Chuong 
 Email Address: Subscribe Weight Loss Article Feed Find More Articles Search 
Similar Articles

 The Negative Calorie Diet Plan Weight Loss Solution Easy Weight Loss Diets - Create a Diet Plan in 4 Steps The Calorie Shifting Diet Plan - How to Know the Best Weight Loss Diet Plan Healthy Weight Loss Diet Plan - Calorie Shifting Learn Foods For Diet and Weight Loss Dieting Review of Weight Loss Diets Finding Quick Weight Loss Diets That Work - Why They Work and Where to Find Them Effective Fast Weight Loss Diet Strategies Proven Weight Loss Diet - Is Calorie Shifting a Proven Weight Loss Diet? Weight Loss Diet Plan - Fail to Plan and Plan to Fail 
 
Recent Articles

 Natural Weight Loss Strategies That Can Quickly Be Applied to Your Everyday Lifestyle Burn Belly Fat Fast Exercising May Actually Hurt Your Weight Loss Efforts Using Facebook As a Weight Loss Tool Simple And Effective Weight Loss Solutions You Can Use Choosing a Lose Weight Quickly Diet - The 3 Essential Criteria 3 Amazing (And Little Known) Things That Will Happen To You If You Naturally Lose Weight! Junk Food Addicts Have Telling Signs How To Lose Weight Without Pills, Diet or Exercise Colon Cleansing - Benefits of Colon Hydrotherapy Treatment for Healthy Living 
 
Submitted On February 26, 2008. Viewed 211 times. Word count: 312.
 
 Important Disclaimer: Articles provided are for general information purposes only and are not intended to substitute for informed professional medical, psychological, tax, accounting, legal, investment, or any other professional advice. EzineArticles.com expressly disclaims liability for any product, manufacturer, distributor, service or service provider mentioned or any opinion expressed by any of our members or anywhere else within the site. Lastly, EzineArticles.com does not endorse any article. Use at your own risk.
 MLA Style Citation: 
Chuong, Tom &quot;Live Well By Counting Your Daily Calories Intake.&quot; Live Well By Counting Your Daily Calories Intake .
 26 Feb. 2008 EzineArticles.com. 12 Jul. 2012&lt; http://ezinearticles.com/?Live-­Well-­By-­Counting-­Your-­Daily-­Calories-­Intake&amp;id=1010992 &gt;. APA Style Citation: 
Chuong, T. (2008, February 26). Live Well By Counting Your Daily Calories Intake .
 Retrieved July 12, 2012, from http://ezinearticles.com/?Live-­Well-­By-­Counting-­Your-­Daily-­Calories-­Intake&amp;id=1010992 Chicago Style Citation: 
Chuong, Tom &quot;Live Well By Counting Your Daily Calories Intake.&quot; Live Well By Counting Your Daily Calories Intake EzineArticles.com . http://ezinearticles.com/?Live-­Well-­By-­Counting-­Your-­Daily-­Calories-­Intake&amp;id=1010992 
 EzineArticles.com 

©2012 EzineArticles.com
All Rights Reserved Worldwide
 
 About Us FAQ Contact Us Member Benefits Privacy Policy Shop Site Map 

 Blog Training Video Library Advertising Affiliates Cartoons 
 
Authors
 
 Submit Articles Members Login Premium Membership Expert Authors Endorsements Editorial Guidelines Terms of Service 
 
Publishers

Follow Us
 
 Terms Of Service Ezines / Email Alerts Manage Subscriptions EzineArticles RSS
	</body>
</document>
