<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001647" url="http://www.askbizdex.com/" time="2012-07-12-17:25" support="1" score="0.00012549391114359396" bingtitle="ABD Marketing - Your Marketing Powerhouse" webtitle="ABD Marketing - Your Marketing Powerhouse">
			<query id="000743" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>&quot;AskBizDex is an affordable and superior way to reach a mass number of consumers with your ... &quot;With Amazing return of 831 coupons, the ABD fast food restaurant flyer program ...</description>
	<body>
		PRINT SERVICES { PRINT SERVICES }     DESIGN SERVICES { DESIGN SERVICES }     MAILING SERVICES { MAILING SERVICES }     DOOR-TO-DOOR DISTRIBUTION DOOR-TO-DOOR
{ DISTRIBUTION }     ADVERTISING&amp;MORE! { ADVERTISING&amp;MORE! }     REQUEST A QUOTE { REQUEST A QUOTE }   
 
 
 
 
   ABD PRINT {ABD PRINT} SERVICES {SERVICES} ABD NEWS {ABD NEWS} ABOUT ABD {ABOUT ABD} DESIGN GALLERY {COMING SOON} BLOG {SOON} CONTACT ABD {CONTACT ABD}   
 
 
 


 ABD Marketing is dedicated to providing quality marketing programs that work for
your business. We work directly with our clients to bring superior marketing and print
solutions that meet specific needs while remaining within budget. The core principles
of your business need to be effectively communicated. Our comprehensive advertising services allow your business to reach your targeted audience and connect with
your customers. By utilizing ABD Marketing, your business has a trusted
printing&amp;advertising partner.

We pride ourselves in our creative processes, design capabilities,
and customer satisfaction. Whether you own a small business,
a franchise or can be counted among the Fortune 500- we have
the resources to help you. Our services listed below highlight
our capabilities. If you need further customized services,
ABD will go the extra mile for you!

 ABD is Your Marketing Powerhouse! 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
       
• OFFSET&amp;DIGITAL PRINTING 
• DESIGN SERVICES 
     - GRAPHIC DESIGN
     - IDENTITY / COMPANY BRANDING
     - WEB DESIGN&amp;MORE!
• MAILING SERVICES 
• DOOR TO DOOR DISTRIBUTION 
• ADVERTISING SERVICES&amp;MORE!     
 
 
             ABD IS NOW OFFERING TICKETS! 

 ABD Marketing has just recently embarked into the world of ticket services, and are pleased to offer a new site called ABDTicketShop.com ! 

 Whether it’s a sporting event, concert, special event, or tickets to shows in Vegas, ABD Ticket Shop offers you easy access at the most competitive pricing for all your ticket needs.


 { LEARN MORE } 
   GET GREAT DEALS AND BRAND EXPOSURE! 

 ABD Marketing invites you to visit ValleyCoups.com , a place where both businesses and consumers can benefit by promoting or searching for amazing deals. 

 Clean and easy to navigate, coupons are quickly found along with instant branding recognition. Utilizing the latest social media technology, people can easily follow their favorite companies and keep informed. 

 { LEARN MORE} 
             
 
 
       We appreciate the opportunity to work with you and your business!

 Dave DelVecchio and the Staff at
ABD Marketing&amp;Printing Services 
 
         
Over 6 years ago Dave DelVecchio was in the pursuit of developing a company that would provide clients with great customer service, financial savings and most importantly, quality products and services for their business.

We have gained experience&amp;knowledge through trial&amp;error making ABD Marketing a powerhouse in the industry. We know what it takes to succeed and enjoy providing services that keep businesses thriving in the US. We take pride in our award winning designers to complete any project, quality full service printing, direct mailing campaigns, perceptible signage, cutting edge advertising programs and much more!

Dave will be the first to tell you that ABD Marketing&apos;s success is due to the great companies we get to work with and the dedicated employees working hard to provide you with exceptional end products and customer service each and every day.
       
 
   

 
  { CLICK HERE TO SEE A LIST OF ALL CLIENTS } 

 
   
 
&quot;AskBizDex is an affordable and superior way to reach a mass number of consumers with your message alongside reputable brands. I highly recommend AskBizDex as an effective print method for communicating your brand message to the general market.&quot; 

Jillian K. - Cricket Communications, Inc.

&quot;With Amazing return of 831 coupons, the ABD fast food restaurant flyer program far exceeded our expectations!&quot;

Diane D. - San Diego Zoo

&quot;Over the past few years, Dave has consistently provided top notch service, with amazing customer service, and competitive pricing. The attention to detail from his team ensures the finished product meets expectations and delivers the message to consumers I am after.&quot;

Peter T. - Pepsi Beverages Company

   
 
 
 
   ABD HOME  |  SERVICES  |  ABD NEWS  |  ABOUT ABD  |  DESIGN GALLERY  |  BLOG  |  CONTACT ABD  |  PRINT SERVICES  |  DESIGN SERVICES 
 MAILING SERVICES  |  DOOR-TO-DOOR DISTRIBUTION  |  ADVERTISING&amp;MORE!
	</body>
</document>
