<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001135" url="http://ezinearticles.com/?Top-10-Distractions-That-Lead-to-Car-Accidents&amp;id=4683123" time="2012-07-12-16:34" support="3" score="0.0018588457580135025" bingtitle="Top 10 Distractions That Lead to Car Accidents" webtitle="Top 10 Distractions That Lead to Car Accidents">
			<query id="000955" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000239" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000959" bing-rank="99"/>
	<description>... in their driving history has gone through a fast food restaurant ... concentrating too much on tuning the radio, picking ... may need to consult a car accident lawyer in order ...</description>
	<body>
		Search Home » Automotive Bryan Snyder 
 Platinum Author |   67 Articles 
 Joined: May 6, 2008 Was this article helpful? 0 0 
Top 10 Distractions That Lead to Car Accidents

 By Bryan Snyder 
 
Even though most people do it every day and take it completely for granted, driving a car is a complicated task that requires hand-eye coordination and undivided attention. Unfortunately, far too many people on the road do take driving for granted, and allow themselves to be distracted by one or more factors that can result in serious car accidents, debilitating injury or pain and suffering.

Some of the most common distractions that lead to car accidents include:

• Eating and driving. Everyone at some point in their driving history has gone through a fast food restaurant and nibbled behind the wheel. Though seemingly benign, concentrating on eating rather than driving, as well as having hands full of hamburgers, burritos or a soft drink significantly increases the risk of having a car accident. If a car is a manual transmission, this risk increases exponentially, as it makes shifting gears that much harder.

• Putting on makeup. Perhaps one of the most dangerous risks behind the wheel is applying makeup. Not only are your hands occupied with various applicators, brushes and sponges, they are often near delicate parts of your face that require precision and concentration.

• Talking on a cell phone. More and more studies are coming out that put talking on a cell phone as an even more dangerous than driving drunk. Although many states have outlawed the practice or mandated using hands-free devices, many people disregard the safety of others and chat chat chat away.

• Texting and driving. Even more dangerous than talking on a cell phone is texting on a cell phone. Not only are your eyes off the road, they are focused on a tiny screen that requires precision typing in order to be successful.

• Road rage. Not everyone is the best driver in the world, nor is everyone as considerate as they could be, especially if they are in a hurry. Sometimes long drives, or drives that just seem long because of traffic, tax the reserves of someone that in other situations is the most peaceful and serene personality. Road rage clouds your judgment, increases risk-taking behavior and distracts you from serious conditions present even in the best driving situations.

• Control Freak. Modern cars are awash in pushbutton convenience that puts climate, speed, seat position and other factors at your fingertips. Unfortunately, all this means is that you have more things to divert your attention from the road and into your own little world inside your car.

• Loud music. Although most people instantly equate vision as the only sense necessary to drive, hearing plays a critical if understated role in safety on the road. Other cars and motorcycles make noise so that even if you can&apos;t see them, you can hear and react to them, and loud music that distracts you or flat out prevents you from hearing them presents a danger for any and all on the road.

• Your car is not a DJ booth. Related to loud music is concentrating too much on tuning the radio, picking out the right CD or searching for that perfect mp3. Each one of these actions requires a driver to take their eyes, hands and mind off the road and into an internal situation within the car. And yes, picking the wrong driving track could be disastrous, but getting into a car accident or causing injury would be infinitely worse.

• Reading a map/GPS. Some people think that finding their way to their destination is more important than safely getting there. We have all done that at some point, and we take it for granted that we can simply multitask. Unfortunately, that is rarely the case, and trying to read (or fold!) a map or GPS unit while driving is a very serious distraction indeed.

• Talking to your passengers. Yes, even talking to your passengers can be a serious distraction, especially if the conversation drifts into arguments or heated discussions. Teenagers are particularly susceptible to this type distraction, as they lack the experience and wisdom to make the best decisions.

Understanding that no one is perfect, and we all make mistakes and are vulnerable to dangerous distractions while driving can help make the road a safer place for everyone. Keep these factors in mind next time you are behind the wheel, and hopefully you can avoid an accident.

If someone else made these mistakes, and you suffered injury or pain and suffering as a result, you may need to consult a car accident lawyer in order to protect your rights and get the financial compensation you deserve.
 
For more than 25 years, personal injury attorney Bryan Snyder has worked with people who have suffered injuries because of distracted drivers. As an auto accident lawyer , Bryan Snyder has successfully represented Southern California accident victims and their families.
 
Article Source: http://EzineArticles.com/?expert=Bryan_Snyder 
 Did you find this article helpful? 0 0 Get Involved 0 comments Suggest a topic Article Tools Print this article E-mail to a friend EzinePublisher Report this article Cite this article Stay Informed Get notified by email when new articles are added to this category or written by this author. 
Subscribe to New Article Alerts:
 
 Automotive 
 Bryan Snyder 
 Email Address: Subscribe Automotive Article Feed Find More Articles Search 
Recent Articles

 7 Gas Saving Tips You Can Start Using Today The Factors Looked At During Your Vehicle&apos;s MOT Test How to Prevent Your Vehicle From the Heat This Summer What You Need To Know When Changing Fuel Filter In Cars Tips For Changing Air Filter In A Car Changing Differential Fluid Of A Vehicle Top 5 Summer Car Tips For Drivers Dry Ice Blasting Is An Innovative Method For A Thorough Clean In The Automobile Industry Find Out What Is The Purpose Of A Car&apos;s Radiator How To Prepare For Your Driving Lessons and Driving Tests 
 
Submitted On July 16, 2010. Viewed 333 times. Word count: 756.
 MLA Style Citation: 
Snyder, Bryan &quot;Top 10 Distractions That Lead to Car Accidents.&quot; Top 10 Distractions That Lead to Car Accidents .
 16 Jul. 2010 EzineArticles.com. 12 Jul. 2012&lt; http://ezinearticles.com/?Top-­10-­Distractions-­That-­Lead-­to-­Car-­Accidents&amp;id=4683123 &gt;. APA Style Citation: 
Snyder, B. (2010, July 16). Top 10 Distractions That Lead to Car Accidents .
 Retrieved July 12, 2012, from http://ezinearticles.com/?Top-­10-­Distractions-­That-­Lead-­to-­Car-­Accidents&amp;id=4683123 Chicago Style Citation: 
Snyder, Bryan &quot;Top 10 Distractions That Lead to Car Accidents.&quot; Top 10 Distractions That Lead to Car Accidents EzineArticles.com . http://ezinearticles.com/?Top-­10-­Distractions-­That-­Lead-­to-­Car-­Accidents&amp;id=4683123 
 EzineArticles.com 

©2012 EzineArticles.com
All Rights Reserved Worldwide
 
 About Us FAQ Contact Us Member Benefits Privacy Policy Shop Site Map 

 Blog Training Video Library Advertising Affiliates Cartoons 
 
Authors
 
 Submit Articles Members Login Premium Membership Expert Authors Endorsements Editorial Guidelines Terms of Service 
 
Publishers

Follow Us
 
 Terms Of Service Ezines / Email Alerts Manage Subscriptions EzineArticles RSS
	</body>
</document>
