<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001792" url="http://notalwaysright.com/page/102" time="2012-07-12-17:34" support="3" score="0.0014092728911650222" bingtitle="Funny &amp; Stupid Customer Stories – Not Always Right" webtitle="FunnyStupid Customer StoriesNot Always Right">
			<query id="001245" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="001237" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000274" bing-rank="247"/>
	<description>A customer walks up and throws down a packet of pigs ... Fast Food, Restaurant | Kansas, USA | Food &amp; Drink ... for something to satisfy her, I find a cup sleeve ...</description>
	<body>
		Add Your Quote!  |  About/FAQ   Contact  |  Top   Random   Hall of Fame  |  Extras  |  Store Featured Story: 
 Never Say No To La Novia (1,848 thumbs up) FOR SALE: 
 The YAM Network (Auction ends Thursday, July 12, 2012!) 
 Gravity, The Universal Mood Killer 
 Liquor Store | Brisbane, Australia | Rude&amp;Risque 
 (A middle-aged man approaches my register with a carton of beer, which he struggles to lift onto the counter.) 

 Customer: “I must be getting old. I can’t even get it up anymore!”

 (There’s a long awkward silence as he realizes what he said.) 

 Customer: “Oh…I’m so sorry!”
 ( 1,055 Thumbs Up!) 
 She’s A No Nonsense Kinda Girl 
 Retail | Columbus, IN, USA | 
 (I work in a big box retailer in the toy department. A customer approaches me when I’m stocking in the Barbie aisle to ask a question.) 

 Customer: “Excuse me?”

 Me: “How can I help you?”

 Customer: “I’m looking for a specific Barbie and I was wondering if you had it in.”

 Me: “Okay, which one?”

 Customer: “Do you have Fascist Barbie?”

 Me: “ Fascist Barbie?”

 Customer: “Yeah, it’s Fascist Barbie.”

 Me: *confused* “Uh, no, we don’t have a Fascist Barbie doll.”

 Customer: “Really? I can’t find that anywhere! I don’t really know the name of it. It’s like fascist. Fashion-something Barbie.”

 Me: “Oh, Fashionista Barbie?”

 Customer: *suddenly happy* “Yes! That’s it!”

 Me: “Yeah, we have those. They’re right over here.”
 ( 1,062 Thumbs Up!) 
 Holding A Smoking Gun 
 Gun Store | South West, FL, USA | Criminal/Illegal 
 (A customer is filling out a handgun license application.) 

 Customer: “It asks here if I have a misdemeanor for domestic violence.”

 Me: “Yes, that is what it is asking you.”

 Customer: “You can’t buy a gun if you have a domestic violence charge?”

 Me: “Of course not. You can’t even legally be in this store.”

 Customer: “What do you mean,‘Of course not’? You f****** b****!”

 Me: “Have a good one.”

 Customer: *grabs paperwork, tears it up, and tosses it at me* 
 ( 1,532 Thumbs Up!) 
 Preparing For The Not-So-Inevitable 
 Customer Service | Ontario, Canada | 
 Customer: “Don’t get upset, okay?”

 Me: *confused* “…okay?”

 Customer: “Just, please don’t be mad at me.”

 Me: “Um, all right.”

 Customer: “I like your hair.”

 Me: “Thanks.”

 Customer: “It’s a compliment.”

 Me: “I know. Thanks.”

 Customer: “So, don’t get mad.”

 Me: “Okay…”
 ( 941 Thumbs Up!) 
 Password Reset In Just $ Steps 
 Tech Support | Michigan, USA | Technology 
 (A customer calls and needs a password reset. I reset it and the password has upper and lower case letters and a number in it.) 

 Me: “Okay, I have a new password for you.”

 (I spell out the password for the customer to write down.) 

 Customer: “Thanks. Is the 4 capital, too?”

 Related:
 As Easy As !-@-# 
 ( 564 Thumbs Up!) 
 The Gift That Keeps On Grouping 
 Bookstore | Michigan, USA | 
 Customer: “Hi, I’d like to return this item, I can’t give it as a gift .”

 (He hands me a copy of Pygmalion.) 

 Me: “That shouldn’t be a problem. Is there anything wrong with it?”

 Customer: “Turns out it’s a play. They wont be able to read it.”

 Me: “Oh, they don’t like plays?”

 Customer: “No, they can’t read it because there aren’t enough people to read the parts!”

 Me: “Might I suggest that they just read it like a regular book?”

 Customer: *looks at me like I’m crazy* 
 ( 986 Thumbs Up!) 
 When One Door Closes, Another One…Never Mind 
 Retail | Carmel, CA, USA | Extra Stupid 
 (I work in a small gift shop that has two doors, one in front and one in back. The front door latches to the outside wall to keep it from swinging shut. One day, a little old lady comes to the back door.) 

 Customer: “Excuse me, but your front door is locked.”

 Me: “Are you sure? I’m looking at it now. It’s open.”

 Customer: “Well, I just tried it and I couldn’t get it open.”

 Me: “I’m sorry, but it’s open already.”

 Customer: “But I couldn’t open it!”

 (At this point, it dawns on me that she has been trying to open the door while it was latched to the wall, while ignoring the obviously open doorway to her immediate left.) 

 Me: “I’m sorry. I’ll look into it…”
 ( 748 Thumbs Up!) 
 All Of The Calories, None Of The Taste 
 Restaurant | Nova Scotia, Canada | Crazy Requests , Food&amp;Drink 
 (I work at a cashier at a local fast food place. A young woman approaches me.) 

 Me: “Hello and welcome to [restaurant]. Can I take your order?”

 Customer: “I’d like a medium Diet Coke.”

 (I get the Diet Coke and give it to her. She pays and leaves. Five minutes later, she returns looking rather angry.) 

 Me: “Hello, did you enjoy your Diet Coke?”

 Customer: “NO! This isn’t Diet Coke! I can taste the Coke in it!”

 Me: “Uh…let me get you a new one, then…”
 ( 573 Thumbs Up!) Page 102/819 First « ... 100 101 102 103 104 ... » Last 
 
19,759
Fans 
5,025
Followers 
10,881
Subscribers 
 
Navigate
 Announcements At The Checkout Awesome Customers Bigotry Bizarre Body Problems Bookstore Canada Children Coffee Shop Comics Comics Single Crazy Requests Criminal/Illegal Extra Stupid Extras Food&amp;Drink Funny Names Geeks Rule Geography Health&amp;Sickness History Holidays Home Improvement Hotels&amp;Lodging Language&amp;Words Liars&amp;Scammers Love/Romance Married Customers Math&amp;Science Money Issues Movie Theater Musical Mayhem Old Comics One-Liners Parents Pets&amp;Animals Physical Politics Religion Roundups RSS-Announce Rude&amp;Risque Students Technology Theme Time Top Tourists/Travel Uncategorized Underaged Xcluded View by Job 911 Airline Airport Animal Shelter Announcements Apartment Complex Aquarium Arcade Art Gallery Artist Auto Mechanic Auto Parts Baby Store Bail Bonds Bakery Bank Bar Beach Beauty Salon Blood Bank Boat Rental Bookstore Bowling Alley Bridal Store Buffet Bus Cable Company Cafe Call Center Camera Shop Camera Store Camp Candy Shop Car Dealership Card Shop Car Rental Car Wash Cash Advance Casino Catering Cellphone Store Charity Check Cashing Chemist Child Care Chocolate Shop Church Clinic Clothing Store Coffee Shop College Comic Book Store comic store Computer Lab Computer Repair Computer Store Concert Hall Concession Stand Construction Contractor Convenience Store Copy Shop Costume Shop Country Club Craft Store Cruise Ship Customer Service Dance Studio Daycare Day Spa Deli Dentist Department Store DMV Doctor Dog Daycare Dog Kennel Dollar Store Donut Shop Drug Store Drugstore Dry Cleaner Electronics Repair electronics store EMT Fabric Store Farm Farmer&apos;s Market Fast Food Fencing Club Ferry Fish Store Flea Market flooring company Florist Flower Shop Frozen Yogurt Shop Furniture Store Garden Store Gas Station Gift Shop Golf Course Government Graphic Design Grocery Grocery Store Gun Store Gym Hair Salon Hardware Store Help Desk Highway Patrol home home furnishings home furnishings store home improvement Home Security Hospital Hotel Ice Cream Shop Ice Cream Store Insurance Internet Cafe Investment Firm ISP Jewelry Store Key Shop Landscaper Laundromat Law Firm Lawn Care Lemonade Stand library lifeguard Lingerie Store Liquor Store Locksmith Mall Marina Marine Biologist Massage Medical Office Military Miscellaneous Morgue Mortgage Company Movie Theater Museum Music Festival Music Store newspaper Non-Profit Nursing Home Office Office Supply Store Online Store Optometrist Outdoor Supply Store Paintball Field Paramedic Park Parking Lot Party Planner Party Store Party Supply Store Pawn Shop Pest control Pet Groomer Pet Hotel Pet Store Pharmacy Phone Company Photo Lab Pizza Pizza Delivery Pizza Place Plant Nursery Plumber Police Polling Station Pool Pool Maintenance Pool Supply Porn Billing Portrait Studio Post Office Power Company Print Shop Private School Property Management Publishing Radio Station Real Estate Recording Studio Record Store repair shop Resort Restaurant Retail Retirement Home Roadside assistance Sales Sandwich Shop School Security Self Storage Shipping Company Shoe Store Sign Installer Ski Resort Smoke Shop Smoothie Shop Snack Bar Software Company Souvenir Store Sporting Goods Store Summer Camp Supermarket Tanning Salon Tattoo Parlor Taxi Tax Preparer Tea Shop Tech Support Telemarketing theater Theatre Theme Park Thrift Store Ticket Sales Tire Center Tour Tour Guide Tourist Attraction Toy Store Train Station Travel Agency Travel Store Tree Nursery Tutor TV Studio University Vet Video Editor Video Game Store Video Rental Video Rental Store Video Store Vitamin Store Water Park Web Design Well Driller Wine Store Zombies Zoo View by Month July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 
Not Always Sites

 Not Always Romantic Not Always Related Not Always Working 
Friends

 The Awesomer Passive Aggressive Notes Retail Hell 

Archives
 
 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 
 
Most Viewed Stories

 Why Barkeeps Should Rule The World 19763 views Scamming In Plain Sight 16197 views Coming To A Theater Near You: Gangsta Ushers 15571 views Choose Your Battles 14526 views Don’t Mess With The Candyland Gang 14119 views Fighting Fire With Fire 9335 views The Road To Yell(ing) Is Paved With Good Intentions 7018 views Human Watching 5070 views For My Next Trick… 4173 views Who Needs Enemies When You’ve Got Bricks 3015 views 
 

 
Not Always Right Poll
Sorry, there are no polls available at the moment. 

 
 
 
About Not Always Right

Not Always Right features funny&amp;stupid customer stories that show the customer is NOT always right! More... 

 About/FAQ 
 Press 
 Contact 
 Term of Use 
 Privacy Policy 
 Send Us An Extras/FB/Twitter Tip 
 Link To Us 
 Apps 

Copyright 2007-2012 NotAlwaysRight.com 
Subscribe&amp;Follow

 Facebook 
 Twitter 
 RSS 
 Email Subscription 


Network Sites

 Not Always Romantic 
 Not Always Related 
 Not Always Working 

 IYAMLOL 
 IYAMCHEAP 
 IYAMYOURS 
 IYAMBAD 
 IYAMHEALTHY 
June 2012 Top Referrers


 Passive Aggressive Notes Etiquette Hell Retail Hell Underground Consumerist STFU Parents Customers Suck! You Are Not A Photographer Funny Junk The Mary Sue Tech Comedy 

 Join Our Top Referrer Program!
	</body>
</document>
