<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001714" url="http://www.acitydiscount.com/Tabletop.1.25385.2.1.htm" time="2012-07-12-17:29" support="11" score="0.023016727242003158" bingtitle="Table Top &amp; Front-of-House Restaurant Supplies | ACityDiscount ..." webtitle="Table Top&amp;Front-of-House Restaurant Supplies | ACityDiscount Restaurant Equipment">
			<query id="001329" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="001257" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="001263" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000504" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000530" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000513" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="001320" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000526" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000516" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000670" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="001332" bing-rank="64"/>
	<description>Table Top &amp; Front-of-House Restaurant Supplies Categories ... and a stainless steel four slot flatware cutlery tray ... invites you to highlight your establishment’s place ...</description>
	<body>
		Used Equipment Specials&amp;Liquidations Showroom Make An Offer Coupons Sell Equipment 
 
 Commercial
Kitchen Equipment 
 Cooking Equipment Food Preparation Equipment Cookware&amp;Kitchen Tools Commercial Sinks, Faucets&amp;Dishwashers Storage&amp;Handling Equipment Heating&amp;Warming Food Display Cases Work Tables, Equipment Stands Hood Systems, Fire Suppression Baking, Dough Equipment »All Commercial Kitchen Equipment 
 Refrigeration
&amp;Ice Machines 
 Commercial Refrigerators&amp;Commercial Coolers Commercial Ice Machines Walk-In Coolers&amp;Freezers Commercial Freezers Ice Cream Machines Reach-In Cooler Freezer Combo 
 Bar&amp;Beverage
Equipment 
 Coffee, Tea&amp;Espresso Machines Beverage Dispensing Blenders, Mixers&amp;Juicers Bar Mats Beer Keg Coolers&amp;Dispensers Bar Sinks Bar Supplies Ice Bins Bar Furniture Other Bar Equipment »All Bar Equipment 
 Catering&amp;Dining
Equipment 
 Catering&amp;Buffet Equipment Tabletop Food&amp;Beverage Serving Wine Buckets&amp;Stands 
 Concession
Equipment 
 Hot Dog Machines Popcorn Machines Condiment Systems Nacho Chip&amp;Cheese Warmers Beverage Dispensers Snow Cone&amp;Shaved Ice Machines Pizza Display Case Concession Carts&amp;Stands Concession Funnel Cake, Donut, Doughnut Fryers Pretzel Machines »All Concession Equipment 
 Restaurant
Furniture 
 Chairs&amp;Seating Dining&amp;Bar Tables Patio&amp;Outdoor Furniture Restaurant Signage Decorations, Decor Other Furniture, Decor 
 Customized
Equipment 
 Custom Kitchen Equipment Custom Refrigeration Custom Restaurant&amp;Bar Furniture Custom Food&amp;Beverage Merchandisers Custom Hood Systems Custom Catering&amp;FOH Equipment 
 Kitchen Tools
&amp;Smallwares 
 Tabletop Utensils Knives Commercial Cookware, Pans Commercial Bakeware Commercial Cookware, Pots Food Storage Containers&amp;Lids Bar Supplies Stick Blenders&amp;Hand Mixers Commercial Cutting Boards »All Smallwares&amp;Kitchen Tools 
 Home Kitchen
Appliances 
 Kitchen Tools&amp;Cookware Home Bar Outdoor Living Small Kitchen Appliances Gift Guide Home Dining Major Appliances Plumbing&amp;Fixtures 
 
 

 
 Home » Catering&amp;Dining » Tabletop 
 Jul 12, 2012 
 
 
 
By Category ( ↑up ) 
 Tabletop Bar Glassware Commercial Dinnerware Commercial Flatware Menu Covers&amp;Holders Pitchers&amp;Carafes Salt&amp;Pepper Grinders Tabletop Accessories 
By Brand
 Anchor Hocking Arcoroc Cal-Mil Carlisle Crestware Dexter Russell Edward Don&amp;Co. F. Dick Food Machinery of America G.E.T. Georgia Pacific Libbey Precision Pours Tomlinson Industries Town Food Service Equipment Tuxton China Inc Update International Ventura Vic Firth Gourmet 
By Condition
 Used New 
By Promotions Available
 Free Shipping Make an Offer Energy Star 
 
 
Tabletop

Tabletop accoutrements contribute a visual, yet practical element to your restaurant decor. At ACityDiscount select from a various types of dinnerware, plain and pattern flatware, water tumblers and glassware, linen tablecloths and napkins for your front-of-house. For casual restaurants we also offer a variety of accessories, including napkin dispensers, condiment holders, and menu covers and stands.
 Tips from the Experts: &quot;It&apos;s important to know exactly what is going to be included as a part of every individual place setting. It may be tedious at first, but when ordering, it will help with item counts, and down the road, it will help with inventory.&quot; - Hap 
 
 
 
 Crestware WIN305 36Dz Windsor Serrated Dinner Knives Heavy Weight Stainless Sale Price: $269.06 Original Retail Price $447.84 Save $178.78 
 
 
 
 
 
 Crestware WBP3 12ea Stainless Steel 3-1/4 Quart Bell Pitchers Sale Price: $261.63 Original Retail Price $434.64 Save $173.01 
 
 
 
 
 
 Crestware SKPR2 50 Dz Round Steak Knife w 4-7/8&quot; Blade&amp;Tipped Plastic Hdle Sale Price: $257.84 Original Retail Price $428.00 Save $170.16 
 
 
 
 
 
 Crestware WBP2 12ea Stainless Steel 2-1/4 Quart Bell Water Pitchers Sale Price: $229.89 Original Retail Price $378.72 Save $148.83 
 
 
 
 
 
 Crestware BER602 36 Dozen Berkshire Dinner Forks Heavy Weight Stainless Sale Price: $201.26 Original Retail Price $327.96 Save $126.70 
 
 
 
 
 $269.06 $261.63 $257.84 $229.89 $201.26 
 

 
 Buy Used Table Top&amp;Front-of-House Restaurant Supplies
	</body>
</document>
