<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001236" url="http://www.packaging-gateway.com/features/" time="2012-07-12-16:41" support="1" score="0.0014483365761541736" bingtitle="Packaging Industry Feature Articles - Packaging Gateway" webtitle="Packaging Industry Feature Articles - Packaging Gateway">
			<query id="001138" bing-rank="219"/>
	<description>Take care of the planet: recycled ... has acquired the cup production arm... Subway introduces green packaging for salad bowls, lids Fast food restaurant chain Subway ...</description>
	<body>
		Jump to page content Accessibility News, views and contacts from the global Packaging industry Log in or Register 
 Home Products&amp;Services Company A - Z Projects Features Videos White Papers News Events Advertise With Us 
 Latest Features | Features A - Z | PCI Features | Contributors   
Features
Our editorial board comprises a specialist group of leading industry figures who, in conjunction with the packaging gateway editorial team, identify the main drivers of the industry helping to produce regular, thought provoking opinion pieces on the latest issues, challenges and developments. 
Latest Packaging Feature
 Inside Packaging Magazine: Issue 5 
 27 June, 2012
 From digital presses to high-performance, eco-friendly inks and printed electronics: How the latest printing trends are transforming...
 &gt;read more The future of flexible packaging 14 June, 2012
 by Chris Lo Modern developments in flexible packaging are bringing pouches, films and foils to the market on an unprecedented scale. We profile some of the flexible packaging market&apos;s most... 
 Printed electronics: high tech on a small scale 06 June, 2012
 by Chris Lo Could printing with electronic displays or RFID usher in the next generation of packaging? There are still obstacles standing in the way of its progress in the packaging world, but as Chris... 
 
By Category
 
 Beverage (43) Brand Security (23) Flexible (20) Food (42) Labelling (21) Other (end market) (9) Other (material) (6) Other (type) (5) Packaging Machinery (6) Packaging Materials (44) Packaging Printing and Pre-Press (21) Paper and Cartons (11) Personal Care / Cosmetics (16) PET (6) Pharmaceutical (29) Retail (17) RFID and Supply Chain (17) 
 
 Top trends in printing and ink for 2012 23 May, 2012 Advanced printing technologies are making packaged products more striking and vivid than ever before. And on today&apos;s cut-throat store shelves, they need to be. We profile the printers and inks...

 Supporting eco-friendly packaging: green inks 26 April, 2012
 by Chris Lo The ever-improving performance of eco-friendly alternative ink is making waves in the printing and packaging world. Covering water-based and biodegradable inks and UV curing methods, Chris Lo...

 Inside Packaging Magazine: Issue 4 25 April, 2012 We explore the latest trends in food and drinks packaging and find how new technologies help to improve shelf life and consumer...

 Packaging space food: Interview with Michelle Perchonok of NASA 05 April, 2012 Packaging is heading to a new frontier as scientists attempt to preserve foods for longer space expeditions. Sarah Blackman speaks to Nasa&apos;s Michele Perchonok about the current materials...

 Material world: innovative packaging components 29 March, 2012 Today&apos;s packaging material is expected to play a greater role in product integrity and sustainability than ever. Chris Lo explores the world of polymers, plants and plastics to reveal some of...

 Home from home: cross-border packaging design 23 March, 2012 By dint of its homely all-American feel, family-owned organic food producer Amy’s Kitchen has a loyal US customer base. As the brand’s transition into the UK and European markets progresses,...

 Take care of the planet: recycled packaging 23 March, 2012 Personal care brands are responding to consumers’ environmental concerns by using post-consumer recycled content in their packaging. But do they really know what’s involved in the recycling...

 A source of pride: responsible paper production 23 March, 2012 By implementing responsible sourcing guidelines, Nestlé has moved beyond the simple ticking of boxes to prove the provenance of its fibre, as Nic Paton...

 Flex appeal: the pros of flexographic printing 23 March, 2012 Brand owners and retailers are on the hunt for packaging that is consistent, rapidly delivered and cost-efficient. Debbie Waldron-Hoines of the European Flexographic Industry Association...

 Over-packaging: It’s in the balance 23 March, 2012 The environmental impact of over-packaging is widely debated, and rightly condemned. But less discussed is the fact that food and beverage packaging performs an indispensable role....

 View all features a-z 
 
 
 Latest Suppliers Products&amp;Services 
 
 LasX Industries - Laser Converting Equipment and Service Solutions 
LasX Industries manufactures high-quality laser converting equipment...

 CCL Label - Pressure-Sensitive Labels, Stretch Sleeves and Shrink Sleeves 
CCL is a global specialty packaging company, headquartered in...

 Rapak and Worldwide Dispensers - World Leader in Liquid Packaging and Dispensing 
Rapak and Worldwide Dispensers are major divisions of DS Smith...

 Amcor - The World&apos;s Largest Supplier of Flexible Packaging 
Amcor is the world&apos;s largest packaging company and the world&apos;s...

 Metsä Board - Paperboard for the Packaging Industry 
Metsä Board, formerly M-real, is one of the world&apos;s leading producers...
 See all suppliers 
 Brand Protection and Anti-Counterfeiting Can Forming, Filling and Sealing Cartoning and Form, Fill and Seal Machines Case/Tray, Palletising and Packaging Machines Chemicals, Adhesives and Coatings Closures and Dispensing Systems Converters, Equipment and Components Conveyor Systems for Packaging Applications Inspection and Detection Machines Package Design and Holographics Packaging Containers and Components Packaging Graphics and Printing Packaging Machinery and Components Packaging Materials Packaging Solutions, Logistics and Services Printing and Labelling Equipment and Solutions Product Management and Protection Shrink and Wrap Machines Used Packaging Equipment 
 
 Latest Videos HyGuard: A New Oxygen Barrier System for PET Containers 
HyGuard: a new, game-changing oxygen barrier system for PET... 
 See all videos 
 Latest White Papers 
 Identifying Counterfeit Medicines with Industry-Suitable Technologies 
AlpVision
 Global Packaging Industry CEO Business Outlook Survey 2012-2013 
Canadean
 Annual Deal Report - Packaging 
Canadean
 Liner-Qualities from MM Karton for Flexo Printing 
Mayr-Melnhof Karton
 Global Packaging Survey 2012-2013: Market Trends, Marketing Spend and Sales Strategies 
Canadean
 See all white papers 
 
 
 Latest News Latest Press Releases 
 
 Multivac introduces new pack inspection system 
Multivac Marking&amp;Inspection has unveiled a new inspection system...

 Ecover launches eco-friendly PlantPlastic bottles 
Green cleaning products manufacturer Ecover has introduced its...

 Bemis and Thin Film to develop flexible packaging platform 
Flexible packaging and pressure-sensitive materials provider Bemis...

 Sato introduces new label printer for food traceability 
Barcode printing, labelling and EPC/RFID technology provider Sato...

 Indian institute to design new method for meals packaging 
The Indian Institute of Packaging (IIP) is set to design a new model...
 See all news 
 New Internet Homepage for BERICAP 
 Wednesday, July 11, 2012
 by BERICAP At the start of July 2012, BERICAP presented its new company website. With...

 Vacuum Headspace Analyser for Lyophilised Vials Released by Bonfiglioli 
 Tuesday, July 10, 2012
 by Bonfiglioli Engineering Bonfiglioli Engineering has developed a revolutionary vacuum checking...

 Compostable Film Chosen to Package Organic Tea 
 Friday, July 06, 2012
 by Innovia Films Innovia Films’ compostable cellulose-based material, NatureFlex™ NVR,...

 Mondi will Enter the Guinness World Records with Longest Ever Drawing 
 Friday, July 06, 2012
 by Mondi Mondi has successfully set a new world record with the longest drawing on...

 Brand New High Speed Linear Leak Tester 
 Friday, July 06, 2012
 by ALPS ALPS is proud to introduce the new Speed-Glider container leak tester at...
 See all press releases 
 
 Follow Us: Twitter    Contact us 
 Advertise with us Terms and conditions 
 Privacy Links Newsletter sign up 
 Online magazine sign up 
packaging-gateway.com is a product of Net Resources International. Copyright 2011 Net Resources International, a trading division of SPG Media Limited.
	</body>
</document>
