<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001926" url="http://shermanrestaurantguide.com/" time="2012-07-12-17:49" support="2" score="0.0007535518000974349" bingtitle="SHERMAN Restaurants | SHERMAN Restaurant Guide | SHERMAN, Texas" webtitle="SHERMAN Restaurants | SHERMAN Restaurant Guide | SHERMAN, Texas">
			<query id="000293" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="000306" bing-rank="237"/>
	<description>You can enter the partial or full name of the restaurant, or the cuisine type for the search keyword. You may also type an address such as &quot;&quot;, or intersection as &quot;Texoma ...</description>
	<body>
		[ login ] or
 [ add a Restaurant ] 
SHERMAN restaurant guide
 
 
 
 


 
 ,  Near: What restaurant (eg. Canadian)           Where (eg. 
10 Main St
) 
 Metro city of the Month. Dallas, Tx ( 32.802955,-96.769923 ) of Dallas Restaurant . 
Welcome to the restaurant guide and directory for SHERMAN, Texas and area. 
In addition to our extensive list of restaurants in SHERMAN, you will also find restaurant descriptions, hours, coupons submitted by local restaurant&apos;s management and unique ratings and reviews written by restaurant patrons.
You can enter the partial or full name of the restaurant, or the cuisine type for the search keyword. 
You may also type an address such as &quot;&quot;, or intersection as &quot;Texoma Pky and Nall St E&quot;, or postal code as &quot;75090&quot; to restrict your search within a certain area.
 
 Recently Added restaurants: 
 The Metropolitan Cafe in Downtown Historic Sherman 107 N Travis St 903-361-0835 
 

 Top 50    Cuisine Types    Downtown Restaurants    Alphabetical Alphabetical Listing | A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H | I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P | Q | R | S | T | U | V | W | X | Y | Z 
 Most popular restaurants 
 The Metropolitan Cafe in Downtown Historic Sherman 107 N Travis St
 MG&apos;s Restaurant 1721 N Woods St
 Digger&apos;s Bar and Grill 5637 Texoma Parkway
 LaMesa Mexican Restaurant 2124 Texoma Pkwy
 OO Smokehouse 200 S Montgomery St
 Cheddar&apos;s Casual Cafe 3300 N Us Highway 75
 City Limits 4521 Texoma Parkway
 Tracks 109 N Woods St
 Tokyo 2916 N Us Highway 75 Fwy # 300
 Oo Smokehouse 200 South Montgomery Street
 Kathleen&apos;s Kitchen 1913 N Travis St
 Cici&apos;s Pizza 1900 North Grand Avenue
 Baris Pasta and Pizza 2100 Texoma Pkwy
 Arby&apos;s Roast Beef Restaurant 2131 North Sam Rayburn Freeway
 Popeye&apos;s Fried Chicken 3109 N US Highway 75
 The Library Bar and Grill 5147 N Travis St
 Wingstop-Sherman 734 East Us Highway 82
 Logans Road Restaurant 3700 North USHighway 75
 El Chico Mexican Restaurant 2815 N Sam Rayburn Fwy
 Eddie Mac&apos;s 2600 North Travis Street
 Cellarman&apos;s American Pub 2130 Texoma Pkwy
 Braums Ice Cream and Dairy Stores 600 N Travis St
 Cackle&amp;Oink Bar-B-Que 3210 Texoma Pkwy
 LA Mesa Mexican Restaurant 2124 Texoma Parkway
 Eddie Mac&apos;s 2600 N Travis St
 Catfish King 3301 S Sam Rayburn Fwy
 
 Browse restaurants by Cuisine Type: 
 AMERICAN 14 BAKERY 2 BAR 1 BAR / PUB / BREWERY 1 BAR AND GRILL, BAR 1 BARBECUE 2 BARS&amp;PUBS 1 BURGERS 1 CAFE 1 CHINESE 4 COFFEE&amp;TEA 1 COFFEE HOUSE 1 DELI / SANDWICHES 3 DESSERT / ICE CREAM 1 ECLECTIC 1 FAST FOOD 8 HOT DOGS 1 ITALIAN 1 JAPANESE 2 LOUNGE 1 LUNCH&amp;FINE DINING 1 MEXICAN 3 PIZZA 6 RESTAURANT 2 SEAFOOD 1 SOUTHERN 6 STEAKS 1 SUBWAY, SUB 1 TEX-MEX 3 Unknown Category 34 WINGS 1 
 Restaurants in the downtown area: 
 Applebee&apos;s Neighborhood Grill and Bar 4817 Texoma Pkwy Arby&apos;s 2131 N Sam Rayburn Fwy Arby&apos;s Roast Beef Restaurant 2131 North Sam Rayburn Freeway Barbi Jo&apos;s Snack Shack 600 E Taylor St Baris Pasta and Pizza 2100 Texoma Pkwy Blue Door Cafe 219 N Travis St Braums Ice Cream and Dairy Stores 600 N Travis St Burger King 1213 N Travis St Cackle&amp;Oink Bar-B-Que 3210 Texoma Pkwy Cafe On The Hill 500 N Highland Ave Catfish King 3301 S Sam Rayburn Fwy Cellarman&apos;s American Pub 2130 Texoma Pkwy Cheddar&apos;s Casual Cafe 3300 N Us Highway 75 Chicken Express 1824 Texoma Pkwy Chili&apos;s Grill and Bar 2809 N Sam Rayburn Fwy China Star 2324 Texoma Pkwy Chuck E Cheese 201 North Walnut Street Church&apos;s Chicken 0 1417 and Lamberth Cici&apos;s Pizza 1900 North Grand Avenue City Limits 4521 Texoma Parkway Coffee USA Inc 105 N Montgomery St Conrads Pies&amp;More 221 Sunset Blvd Conrads Pies and More 124 S Woods St Corn Dog 7 4800 Texoma Pkwy Dairy Queen 2002 E Lamar St Denny&apos;s 1835 Texoma Pkwy Derek Damon Rn 2204 N Crockett St Dickey&apos;s BBQ 529 West Lamar Street Digger&apos;s Bar and Grill 5637 Texoma Parkway Eddie Mac&apos;s 2600 N Travis St El Chico Mexican Restaurant 2815 N Sam Rayburn Fwy El Pueblo Restaurant 401 South Sam Rayburn Fwy Fine B B Q 1743 Texoma Pkwy Firehouse Subs 853 Northcreek Dr Golden Corral 900 W US Hwy 82 Gourmet China 4909 N Sam Rayburn Fwy Grandy&apos;s 3201 Texoma Pkwy In-N-Out Burgers 429 N Sam Rayburn Fwy International House Of Pancakes 2617 N Sam Rayburn Fwy Jack In The Box 100 W FM 1417 Johnny Carino&apos;s Italian 306 E Us Highway 82 Kathleen&apos;s Kitchen 1913 N Travis St Kelly&apos;s Restaurant and Catering 115 S Travis St Kentucky Fried Chicken 818 N Travis St Knollwood Country Store 223 Knollwood Rd LA Mesa Mexican Restaurant 2124 Texoma Parkway La Independentia Land Sherman 512 N LaMesa Mexican Restaurant 2124 Texoma Pkwy Little Italy Ristorante 110 E Houston St Logans Road Restaurant 3700 North USHighway 75 Luby&apos;s 3113 Hwy 75 N Lupe&apos;s Tamales 129 E Wall St MG&apos;s Restaurant 1721 N Woods St McDonald&apos;s 401 E US Highway 82 Mr Jims Pizza 705 E Taylor St OO Smokehouse 200 S Montgomery St One Stop Mini Mart 1015 W Houston St Oo Smokehouse 200 South Montgomery Street Pancho&apos;s Mexican Buffet Inc 1909 Texoma Pkwy # 103 Papa John&apos;s Pizza 1909 Texoma Pkwy Pizza Hut 2020 Texoma Pkwy Pizza Inn 1916 Texoma Pkwy Popeye&apos;s Fried Chicken 3109 N US Highway 75 Red Lobster 4900 Texoma Pkwy Rendezvous Club 2111 Texoma Pkwy SONIC Drive-In 1200 W Taylor St Sonic Drive In 1820 Texoma Pkwy Subway 1417 West Lamberth Road Taco Bell 1800 Texoma Pkwy Taco Bueno 2204 Texoma Pkwy Taqueria Angeles 900 N Broughton St Taste Of China 4801 Texoma Pkwy The Library Bar and Grill 5147 N Travis St The Metropolitan Cafe in Downtown Historic Sherman 107 N Travis St Tokyo 2916 N Us Highway 75 Fwy # 300 Tracks 109 N Woods St Vitina&apos;s Deli Delights 1001 N Travis St Watsonburger Of Sherman 706 W Houston St Wendy&apos;s 3301 Texoma Pkwy Whataburger 2801 N Sam Rayburn Fwy Wingstop-Sherman 734 East Us Highway 82 
 
 NEW! , Promote your local service and website to the visitors from SHERMAN, Texas.

Nearby Cities:
 North: Oklahoma City 
 South: Dallas 
 East: Tyler 
 West: Wichita Falls 
 
 Other Major US Cities 
 


 
 
 Contact Link to us About us Local Resources Disclaimer 
 
 SHERMAN Restaurants Guide 2007 - 2011 SHERMAN Restaurants | Restaurant Guide | SHERMAN Dining | Fine Dining SHERMAN 
Other areas: Other Cities  
Business Information© Dine Here .
	</body>
</document>
