<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001242" url="http://www.slowfoodupstate.com/" time="2012-07-12-16:41" support="10" score="0.057073869370114216" bingtitle="Home - Slow Food Upstate" webtitle="Home - Slow Food Upstate">
			<query id="000164" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="000422" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000419" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000431" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="001110" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="000413" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000170" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000182" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000181" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="001160" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>Everyone is welcome to receive our local newsletter, and ... began with a protest against the opening of a fast food ... Red Fern Farms has whole lamb available for order.</description>
	<body>
		Slow Food Upstate 

Supporting Good, Clean and Fair Food
 
 Home About Us Earth Market Ark of Taste Membership Calendar About Slow Food Upstate Donate Current Newsletter Photos Slow Food Upstate Grants Slow Food Publications Links Slow Food for Children 
 
 
 
 Slow Food is an idea, a way of living and a way of eating. It is a global, grassroots movement with thousands of members around the world that links the pleasure of food with a commitment to community and the environment.

 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
 Welcome 
 Sign In or Register 
 Upcoming Events 
 Itty Bitty Bites, Kids Eat Free night at Earth Fare Thursday, Jul 12 at 4:00 PM -
 8:00 PM Join Slow Food Upstate at the Blueberry Festival Saturday, Jul 14 at 9:00 AM -
 1:00 PM Slow Food Foothills-French-Inspired Potluck Dinner Meeting Sunday, Jul 15 at 4:30 PM -
 6:30 PM Palmetto Tasty Tomato Festival Sunday, Jul 15 at 5:00 PM -
 9:00 PM 
Meet Our Board Members
 
Janette Wesley, Chapter Leader

Marnie Record, Co-Chair

Debbie Cooke, Founding Chair

Clark Mizell, Treasurer

Lil Glenn, Secretary

Ann Marshall

Renato Vicario

Nello Gioia

Adam Gautsch

Anna Kate Hipp

Beth Kunkle

Byron Jones

Donna Johnston

James Wilkins

Joe Augello

Jordon Lea

Linda Lee

 
News
 
 Upcoming Slow Food Upstate Events: 




 Earth Market July 19 

 Felting with Cassie Larsen, $70.00 

Reserve in Advance

 &quot;Sensational Kids&quot; programming thanks to our grant from LBDG and the  euphoria!  event 

 Cooking Class July 7 

 &quot;Risotto&quot; by Renato Vicario at Willams Sonoma 

 The Gift of Bees and Honey Tasting 

at  Whole Foods Market Cafe&apos;  

Sunday July 8 from 11:00-12:00

 The Blueberry Festival at Roper Mountain Science Center 

July 14, from 9 am-1 pm

Join Slow Food Upstate in the Living History Farm for a cooking demonstration over an open fire with old Native American Recipes.

 Reclaiming our Food in Community Gardens 

a Collaboration between Slow Food Upstate,

Gardening for Good 

and the Swamp Rabbit Cafe&apos; and Grocery




 Want to know more about G.M. O&apos;s? 

What are they? How do they effect the earth and my health?

Come to the Earth Market, August 16 and meet Ms. Samm Simpson, GMO educator.

 
 

 Other News&amp;Information:   

 Carolina Farm Stewardship Association announces the

 Sustainable Agriculture Conference: Oct. 26-28, 2012 in Greenville, SC 

EARLY BIRD REGISTRATION STARTS JULY 16th!

 

 Local Foods Feast - Purchasing Individual $50 Tickets 

 The American Chestnut Foundation is seeking volunteers  June, July and Septmeber, to help save a very rare and endnagered species, and one that is listed on the Ark of Taste. 

 One Cause:  Slow Food Upstate is featured on One Cause, a web site that allows you to shop on line and your selected merchants will contribute a percentage of the sale to Slow Food Upstate. Go to www.onecause.com and become a member, then select Slow Food Upstate as your Cause to support.  

 Earth Market Producer, Red Fern Farms, has whole lamb available for order. 

 
 

 Tell the FDA to label genetically engineered (GE) foods . http://justlabelit.org/ 

 Like us on Facebook:  Find our events, news and more: http/www.facebook.com/SlowFoodUpstate 

 Get Involved: Volunteer with Slow Food Upstate! 

 See the Earth Market on WSPA TV  

 See our calendar for more information. 

 Get a Digital copy of Edible Upcountry Here 

 Get a Digital copy of TOWN Magazine Here 

   

 
 
Copyright 2009
	</body>
</document>
