<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001960" url="http://nurol.com/restaurant-point-of-sale/fine-dining-restuarant-pos.php" time="2012-07-12-17:52" support="2" score="0.003929642481096012" bingtitle="Fine Dining Restaurant Point of Sale | Fine Dining Restaurant POS" webtitle="Fine Dining Restaurant Point of Sale | Fine Dining Restaurant POS">
			<query id="001396" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="001008" bing-rank="53"/>
	<description>NuRol provides restaurant point of sale packages to ... items Point of Sale Restaurant Equipment like Aldelo Restaurant Software, touch screen monitors, receipt ...</description>
	<body>
		Advanced Search 
 

 Industry Solutions&amp;Categories 
 Restaurant POS Systems Full Service Restaurant Systems Quick Service Restaurant Systems Take Out&amp;Delivery Restaurant Systems Pizza Restaurant POS Systems Mexican Restaurant POS Systems Asian Restaurant POS Systems Fine Dining Restaurant Systems Bar Point of Sale Systems Cafeteria POS Systems Retail POS Systems 

 
 
 
 
 
 
   
 


Fine Dining Restaurant Systems

NuRol&apos;s Fine Dining Restaurant Point of Sale systems are built around the leading edge Aldelo Pro Restaurant Software.
Each solution includes NuRol tested and approved fine dining POS software and hardware with features designed to give restaurant owners the tools they need to run their restaurant efficiently.


 Full Service Features: 
 Reservations Table Layout Bar Service Inventory Control&amp;Recipe Management Employee Time Clock Integrated Credit card and Gift Card Processing 
 
Our Complete Restaurant Point of Sale systems ship with the Aldelo Restaurant Software pre-installed and hardware configured, tested, and labeled 
for easy installation. This enables you to focus on running your fine dining restaurant not 
managing your computers. Just add your restaurant information, and menu items and go! 

 Build your own using one our pre-configured systems 
below or contact us to design a Mexican Restaurant POS System specifically for your needs.
 Full Service Restaurant POS Systems Select Your System Below 
 PRO 1 Station Restaurant POS System - Cashier Station 
 
 $1843.00 
 PRO 2 Station Restaurant POS System - Cashier&amp;Wait Stations 
 
 $3748.00 
 Pro 3 Station Restuarant POS System - Cashier/Wait/Bar Stations 
 
 $5580.00 
 Pro 3 Station Restaurant POS System - Cashier/Wait/Hostess Stations 
 
 $5755.00 

NuRol provides innovative and affordable Fine Dining Restaurant POS 
Systems to restaurant owners worldwide. Our 
wide selection of Restaurant Point of Sale products and 
packages are designed to fit your specific business needs. Each package contains 
popular items Point of Sale Restaurant Equipment like Aldelo Restaurant Software , touch screen monitors , receipt printers, cash drawers and more. So whether you run an upscale Fine Dining Restaurant or a quick service deli or 
anything in between, NuRol is your Restaurant POS source for Restaurant POS Systems &amp;Equipment. 


   
 Policies&amp;Info | Privacy | Resources | Site Map | Contact Us 
©2005 NuRol. All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
