<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001370" url="http://www.bakersfieldbusinessguide.com/business_listing/maui-pho-fusion-bbq-grill?quicktabs_2=0" time="2012-07-12-16:51" support="2" score="0.002477750635155353" bingtitle="Maui Pho Fusion BBQ Grill | Bakersfield Business Guide" webtitle="Maui Pho Fusion BBQ Grill | Bakersfield Business Guide">
			<query id="001237" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="001228" bing-rank="64"/>
	<description>Don&apos;t let the drive-thru window throw you off. This ... restaurant; you order at the counter, take a seat ... You order your food at the register like a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Jump to Navigation Bakersfield Business Guide 
Main menu

 Register / Log in home find businesses new reviews all categories advertise your business about us BreakingPromos 
 Home › Food&amp;Dining › Cuisine › Vietnamese › Maui Pho Fusion BBQ Grill 
Maui Pho Fusion BBQ Grill
 Claim this business 
 Food&amp;Dining Cuisine Chinese Vietnamese Casual Drive-thru 
 4011 Ming Ave Bakersfield , CA 93309 (661) 834-3235 
 Report Problem 
 
Comments
 
Comment viewing options
 Flat list - collapsed Flat list - expanded Threaded list - collapsed Threaded list - expanded Date - newest first Date - oldest first 10 comments per page 30 comments per page 50 comments per page 70 comments per page 90 comments per page 150 comments per page 200 comments per page 250 comments per page 300 comments per page Select your preferred way to display the comments and click &quot;Save settings&quot; to activate your changes. 
 can we say, been there done that. it looks like a great place... 
 Submitted by dave31 on Sun, 2010-03-28 15:57. 1 
can we say, been there done that. it looks like a great place to eat, the food was eh, boba was unacceptable, yes cheaper than other places but you can taste it.
 
 Report Problem 
 
 I wanted to try this place for a while, especially after... 
 Submitted by kimberwyn on Thu, 2010-03-25 22:37. 2 
I wanted to try this place for a while, especially after reading good reviews online. I ordered fried shrimp and sweet and sour chicken with chow mein, and a milk tea boba on the side. I wasn&apos;t impressed with any of the food. The fried food was so rich and way too breaded for my taste. The sweet and sour chicken was just pieces of fried chicken with some red sauce poured over a couple of pieces, and some pinapples thrown on top. The chow mein wasn&apos;t bad. The fried shrimp was good, but too breaded for my tastes.
I was particularly unimpressed with the boba. The milk tea tasted watered down and didn&apos;t have much flavor. The boba itself was sweet tasting but not firm enough; too mushy. I might go back and try something there that wasn&apos;t fried, but probably not anytime soon.
Oh, and expect to pay $10 if you want a plate, or if you want a 2 item combo with a drink. If you want a 3 item combo + drink, expect to pay more. The boba is less expensive than other places in town, though, but I prefer the boba at Surf City Squeeze.
 
 Report Problem 
 
 DAMMM good ,,,,,i love pho ,,,pronounced,,,FU,,an spring... 
 Submitted by dynamikkdave on Mon, 2009-11-23 01:22. 5 
DAMMM good ,,,,,i love pho ,,,pronounced,,,FU,,an spring rolls,,las time i had food like this i was in the army in hawaii
 
 Report Problem 
 
 Never got to actually eat the food because when I tried to... 
 Submitted by hapa99 on Tue, 2009-05-26 21:55. 1 
Never got to actually eat the food because when I tried to call in a pick up order they put me on hold for so long I hung up. Tried to call back, but the line was busy . . . they forgot they had a customer waiting and never hung up the phone. Ridiculous customer service.
 
 Report Problem 
 
 This restaurant has a very friendly atmosphere and the food... 
 Submitted by hanstaekwondo on Wed, 2009-01-14 00:48. 5 
This restaurant has a very friendly atmosphere and the food is delicious. I recommend everyone to try. You will get your money&apos;s worth.
 
 Report Problem 
 
 I&apos;ll admit that I have been a China Bistro fanatic for nearly... 
 Submitted by ferretnaura on Sat, 2008-11-22 01:16. 5 
I&apos;ll admit that I have been a China Bistro fanatic for nearly a decade. I&apos;m into the&quot;cheap eats&quot;. Give me a lot of good taste for little money. Where else could I feed my family of five for $20.00 and close to home?
Well, I found a new favorite for my orange chicken fixation. Maui Pho (pronounced&quot;fuh&quot;), I like to call it M.P. This new location is a match to China Bistro on price, but wins the war on portion size, and taste. After you look over the menu and its many items and place your order with the smiling young lady behind the counter, you can sit down at a table or a cushioned couch and watch some television on their large flat screen TV. Hit the soda bar (pepsi products) for refills until the tasty food arrives at your table. The food does take a little longer than the China Bistro express line, but its worth the wait, as they are cooking it to order.
I&apos;ve ordered the triple combo for all three of my visits, changing up the entree each time. My last visit, I ordered the teriyaki chicken (my 3rd favorite of the choices, great sauce and good pieces of meat), orange chicken (my favorite with the homemade orange sause recipe), and sweet&amp;sour chicken (comes with green peppers, my 2nd favorite). My fourth favorite, but not ordered on my last visti, is the sweet&amp;sour pork that comes with real pieces of pineapple in the sauce. I received a mound of each plus great tasting rice (with large pieces of egg, which I like, inside) and choimein. All of this arrived on a large, real plate (not styrofoam). My wife has tried the egg soup (HUGE bowl) which comes with some wonton sticks, potstickers, egg roles, and a few other dishes and has enjoyed them all. We were even treated to their salt/pepper shrimp. DELICIOUSLY flavored and large portions. Unlike other cheap Chinese places, every piece of chicken was edible and delicious. None of those&quot;chew-forever&quot;and spit into your napkin pieces at The M.P.
On each visit, we noticed the owners working in the back and coming out to say hello to some of the customers. Some of which seemed to be regulars due to the young lady behind the counter greeting them by name. Others who have been to The M.P. have recommended the Boba drinks. Guess I&apos;ll have to try those on my next visit.
M.P. has the taste of PF Changs, but the pricing of China Bistro and in between on the atosphere and decor. 2 triple combo meals and I can feed my family of five for $20.00 and be full at the end of the meal. You can&apos;t beat that in today&apos;s economy.
Give Maui Pho (M.P.) a shot when you&apos;re on Ming avenue doing some shopping. The place is located in the new Home Depot/Zody&apos;s shopping center) If you&apos;re a China Bistro fan, you may find yourself switching over to The M.P. I did!
 
 Report Problem 
 
 First impressions of Maui Pho Fusion...Since I work in the... 
 Submitted by Collquest on Sun, 2008-08-24 05:02. 5 
First impressions of Maui Pho Fusion...Since I work in the glass industry I noticed walking in to the restaurant the detail on their entry door that kind of impressed me. It made me think that the owners really paid attention to detail which is apparent by the interior of the building. The atmosphere is hip and inviting.
My brother in law ordered the seafood chowmein. I ordered the Hawaiian Spareribs and my sister ordered green bean Chicken which was not on the menu but the chef made it to her specifications. I was very impressed with that. Ya know when you order something and the person sitting across the table from you orders something that you are jealous of and you wish you would of ordered the same thing? Well...I was feeling like that when my brother in law got his order. His seafood chowmein came with a FUN sizzling plate of food. I tasted some of the noodles which looked slightly grilled from the hot plate...wow! The sound was very impressive and the taste was even better. I know it sounds like I don&apos;t get out much but if your food makes noise well, that&apos;s an added bonus! The spareribs were excellent...very tender and the sauce was light and not too salty which is normally my complaint with some restaurants.
I also have to mention the employees at Maui. What a lively group they are! Very very helpful and super courteous as this was our first experience at the restaurant. We mentioned to the person that was busing the table next to us how wonderful the food was and service and he went in the kitchen and told the chef what a nice complement we gave her. Lynn Chan owner/chef personally came to our table to thank us. Lynn is absolutely adorable. Omg...my sister and I got all chatty with her and she literally gave up the&quot;secret&quot;ingredient in her meat marinade. NO joke...she is amazingly warm and lovely and meeting her was definitely the cherry on top of our dining experience at Maui Pho Fusion BBQ Grill.
Please visit this restaurant. It&apos;s a great dining experience. Don&apos;t let the drive-thru window throw you off. This is not fast food. It&apos;s super fresh, super delightful and I highly recommend it.
 
 Report Problem 
 
 I was very impressed with the decor as I walked in. It also... 
 Submitted by PinkLily on Wed, 2008-05-07 16:19. 5 
I was very impressed with the decor as I walked in. It also looked very inviting on the exterior with a patio for outdoor seating. When I looked at the menu, I was impressed with the variety of selection available. The server at the counter greeted me with a friendly &quot;Welcome to Maui Pho, how can I help you?&quot; and also offered to help me out with my choice since I was a first timer. The set up is like a fast casual restaurant; you order at the counter, take a seat, and the food is brought out to you.
While we waited for our food, there was a plasma tv showing movies to keep us entertained. That was a good investment on the owner&apos;s end in order to keep the customers busy while their food was being prepared.
The food was absolutely delicious. I ordered the Hawaiian Rib combo dinner which came with fried shrimp and teriyaki chicken. My friend ordered a combination with rice, noodles, Orange Chicken, and Kung Pao Chicken. She also really enjoyed her food. Each item had such distinct flavors- orange chicken was tangy with a hint of spice to give it a kick. The hawaiian ribs were juicy and had a savory teriyaki taste to it. Everything was hot and fresh, and tasted homemade.
I definitely plan to go back again soon. I may try the pho or some of their specialty dishes such as the beer braised fish. MMM...sounds delicious. Also, I will have to check out their drive thru in case im in a rush or just want a quick fix of a boba drink. :)
Why I plan on going back- the price is very reasonable (&gt;$10 per person) and they give a good size portion of food. Plus everything was DELICOUS!! We need more places like Maui Pho in Bakersfield.
 
 Report Problem 
 
 I had the chicken katsu. It was OK but not anything to brag... 
 Submitted by charlie1 on Wed, 2008-04-23 19:51. 3 
I had the chicken katsu. It was OK but not anything to brag about. Since this was my first time dining there, I will have to reserve further opinion until after I try some other item on the menu. It may take some time to do this because I doubt I will return soon.
 
 Report Problem 
 
 In a word, DELICIOUS. I had the chance to try the chicken... 
 Submitted by chargersfan on Sun, 2008-02-24 04:09. 5 
In a word, DELICIOUS. I had the chance to try the chicken pho, teriyaki chicken and the orange chicken. Everything was wonderful. I have never had pho before. I wish I had discovered this soup a long time ago. The orange chicken was crisp as it should be (in my opinion). I went through the drive thru, so I can&apos;t speak too much for the service that you might get inside. The food was fresh cooked, but I was there for just about 5 min. The young lady that was working the window answered all my questions with a smile and was helpful in my selections. I will be back often.
 
 Report Problem 
 
 I think this is a charming little spot to go to for... 
 Submitted by aim284 on Fri, 2008-01-25 02:37. 4 
I think this is a charming little spot to go to for asian/hawaiian fusion food. There&apos;s a good selection of pho. I&apos;ve tried the beef&amp;seafood combo pho(I think that&apos;s the name?). I enjoyed both of them. The&quot;small&quot;pho bowl is more than enough for one person. The short ribs are pretty tasty, it was cooked somewhere between medium rare and medium well, which is good for my fiance. The teriyaki chicken was also tasty.
You order your food at the register like a fast food restaurant, but they will give you a number to put on your table where they will serve your food.
I don&apos;t really have no complaints so far. Next time, I will try their bobas.
 
 Report Problem 
 
 I saw Maui Pho while driving down Ming Avenue and decided to... 
 Submitted by mlfulton on Wed, 2008-01-23 15:51. 4 
I saw Maui Pho while driving down Ming Avenue and decided to take a chance on it because I felt like some soup. (Pho is Vietnamese noodle soup).  I went to the drive-through and asked some questions about the menu.  Several of the things I asked about were not available, and strangely, only the large size of pho was available in the drive-through although the small size was also listed on the menu.  But it was late and I didn&apos;t feel like looking for another place to eat, so I ordered the chicken pho.  I had to wait at least 10 minutes in my car for my order, but the pho turned out to be excellent.  The broth with chicken was in one container, and the thin rice noodles, scallions and bean sprouts were in the another container, along with some small containers of sauce.  I mixed it all up when I got home and it was yummy!  And the price was right at $7 for a large container of soup.   The rest of the menu is a bit of a mishmash -- some Chinese, some Hawaiian, some Vietnamese -- but now I&apos;m looking forward to going back and trying something else.
 
 Report Problem 
 
 I really enjoyed Maui Pho. It was not greasy like many of the... 
 Submitted by duracel on Sun, 2008-01-20 05:23. 5 
I really enjoyed Maui Pho. It was not greasy like many of the Chinese restaurants in Bakersfield. The fried wontons were delicious (I usually do not like fried wontons at all!) The boba drinks were also very good. I tried the Thai tea and it was excellent. Coming from the east coast where boba drinks are very popular it was a pleasant suprise to find them here!!
 
 Report Problem 
 
 Still new, this former fast food location has a staff that is... 
 Submitted by cfryguy on Tue, 2007-11-27 04:10. 4 
Still new, this former fast food location has a staff that is working hard to get it right. The approach is basically Asian fast food, cooked to order. With a large menu blending Hawaiian BBQ, Chinese, Vietnamese, and Japanese entrees, there are plenty of options. On two visits we tried the beef pho, which was quite good; the orange chicken combo meal, which also was very good, the Maui special chow mein, and a spicy seafood dish. The chow mein included shrimp, chicken and pork, and was distinctive in that it wasn&apos;t greasy like that served in many of the local Chinese fast food places, had more vegetables and meat than most competitive cafeteria style eateries, and did not have cornstarch in the sauce. The flavor was good. On our second visit the restaurant was out of lids for the to-go soft drink cups. The server made a real effort, searching high and low, to produce lids that would fit the cups, but to no avail. The effort nevertheless made a good impression.
 
 Report Problem 
 
 Reviews Map Location 
 Reviews of Maui Pho Fusion BBQ Grill can we say, been there done that. it looks like a great place... 1 Report Problem Reviewed by: dave31 
can we say, been there done that. it looks like a great place to eat, the food was eh, boba was unacceptable, yes cheaper than other places but you can taste it.
 Read full review... I wanted to try this place for a while, especially after... 2 Report Problem Reviewed by: kimberwyn 
I wanted to try this place for a while, especially after reading good reviews online. I ordered fried shrimp and sweet and sour chicken with chow mein, and a milk tea boba on the side. I wasn&apos;t impressed with any of the food. The fried food was so Read full review... DAMMM good ,,,,,i love pho ,,,pronounced,,,FU,,an spring... 5 Report Problem Reviewed by: dynamikkdave 
DAMMM good ,,,,,i love pho ,,,pronounced,,,FU,,an spring rolls,,las time i had food like this i was in the army in hawaii
 Read full review... Never got to actually eat the food because when I tried to... 1 Report Problem Reviewed by: hapa99 
Never got to actually eat the food because when I tried to call in a pick up order they put me on hold for so long I hung up. Tried to call back, but the line was busy . . . they forgot they had a customer waiting and never hung up the phone. Read full review... This restaurant has a very friendly atmosphere and the food... 5 Report Problem Reviewed by: hanstaekwondo 
This restaurant has a very friendly atmosphere and the food is delicious. I recommend everyone to try. You will get your money&apos;s worth.
 Read full review... I&apos;ll admit that I have been a China Bistro fanatic for nearly... 5 Report Problem Reviewed by: ferretnaura 
I&apos;ll admit that I have been a China Bistro fanatic for nearly a decade. I&apos;m into the&quot;cheap eats&quot;. Give me a lot of good taste for little money. Where else could I feed my family of five for $20.00 and close to home?
Well, I found a Read full review... First impressions of Maui Pho Fusion...Since I work in the... 5 Report Problem Reviewed by: Collquest 
First impressions of Maui Pho Fusion...Since I work in the glass industry I noticed walking in to the restaurant the detail on their entry door that kind of impressed me. It made me think that the owners really paid attention to detail which is Read full review... I was very impressed with the decor as I walked in. It also... 5 Report Problem Reviewed by: PinkLily 
I was very impressed with the decor as I walked in. It also looked very inviting on the exterior with a patio for outdoor seating. When I looked at the menu, I was impressed with the variety of selection available. The server at the counter greeted me Read full review... I had the chicken katsu. It was OK but not anything to brag... 3 Report Problem Reviewed by: charlie1 
I had the chicken katsu. It was OK but not anything to brag about. Since this was my first time dining there, I will have to reserve further opinion until after I try some other item on the menu. It may take some time to do this because I doubt I will Read full review... In a word, DELICIOUS. I had the chance to try the chicken... 5 Report Problem Reviewed by: chargersfan 
In a word, DELICIOUS. I had the chance to try the chicken pho, teriyaki chicken and the orange chicken. Everything was wonderful. I have never had pho before. I wish I had discovered this soup a long time ago. The orange chicken was crisp as it should Read full review... Write a review of Maui Pho Fusion BBQ Grill See all reviews of Maui Pho Fusion BBQ Grill Javascript is required to view this map. 
NOTE: This map cannot be displayed in IE7.
 
Find a business by category
 A-list Featured Businesses A-list Deals Arts&amp;Entertainment Food&amp;Dining Personal Care&amp;Services Home&amp;Garden Real Estate Shopping Automotive Health&amp;Medicine Pets Special Occasions Sports&amp;Recreation Travel&amp;Transportation Business&amp;Commercial Financial Services Legal Services Churches Education Services Government&amp;Community Specialty Services Regional Markets Out of Business xzy 
Find a Business by Name
 Search this site: 
   
 
   
 What do you think? 
Hot Deals
 
 

 
 Bakersfield.com Network Site Map 
News
 Breaking News 
 Local News 
 Obituaries 
 Sports 
 Business 
 Health 
 Entertainment 
 Staff Blogs 
 Politics 
 Opinion 
 Columnists 
 Weather 
 E-mail Newsletters 
 RSS Feeds 
 
Community
 Kern Events 
 Bakersfield Pictures 
 Worship Guide 
 Bakersfield Life 
 Bakersfield Voice 
 Tehachapi News 

Business Guide
 Find Businesses 
 List Your Business 
 All Categories 
 New Reviews 
 
Classifieds
 Find Jobs in Bakersfield 
 Homes 
 Drive 
 Rentals 
 Stuff 
 Place An Ad 

Mobile
 661411.com 
 SMS Alerts 
 Android App 
 Blackberry App 
 iPhone App 
 
Advertise With Us
 Media Kit 
 Rate Cards 
 Contact Advertising 

Other Resources
 Contact Us 
 
 Californian Subscriber Services
 Phone: (661) 392-5777 
 Toll Free: 1-800-953-5353 
 Email: circulation@bakersfield.com 
 Office Hours: 
 Mon-Fri 5:30 a.m. to 4:30 p.m. 
 Sat 5:30 to 10:30 a.m. 
 Sun 5:30 a.m. to Noon 
 Holidays 5:30 to 10:30 a.m. 

FAQs

 How do I report a missing paper or delivery problem? How do I place or resume a vacation hold? How do I change my delivery address/phone number? Click for more FAQs 
 
Bakersfield.com Network

 661411.com Bakersfield.com Bakersfield.net Bakersfield.org BakersfieldBuyandSell.com BakersfieldCalifornianFoundation.org BakersfieldDrive.com BakersfieldEZads.com BakersfieldHomeHunter.com BakersfieldBusinessGuide.com BakersfieldLife.com BakersfieldMom.com BakersfieldNetwork.com BakersfieldPicks.com Bakersfield Pictures BakersfieldTalks.com BakersfieldVoice.com Bakosphere.com Bakotopia.com CaptureKernCounty.com Daily Deal HealthyBakersfield.com KernEvents.com MasBakersfield.com MyBakersfieldSports.com SeniorHealthCareDirectory.com TailsofBakersfield.org TehachapiBuyandSell.com TehachapiNews.com 
 
Copyright 2011 The Bakersfield Californian
 Privacy Policy | Terms of Use | About Our Ads | Advertise With Us
	</body>
</document>
