<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001109" url="http://www.airportbirchesmotel.co.nz/facilities.html" time="2012-07-12-16:32" support="1" score="0.0009250613592863065" bingtitle="Christchurch Airport Accommodation New Zealand - Airport Birches Motel" webtitle="Christchurch Airport Accommodation New Zealand - Airport Birches Motel">
			<query id="001273" bing-rank="62"/>
	<description>Large selection of meals for delivery to your unit. Local fast food restaurant within walking distance. ... we offer you the service of leaving your car in ...</description>
	<body>
		390 Yaldhurst Rd, Christchurch, NZ
 4km Airport | 8km City 
 + Home + Accommodation + Facilities + Online Booking + Contact Us + F A Q + Christchurch 
 
Facilities

 
Motel Facilities

 All non smoking rooms All ground floor rooms Zenbu wireless broadband Continental breakfast SKY Television Rooms fully serviced daily Fax facilities at office Guest Laundry - Free laundry powder Free Cot and highchairs on request 
 
We offer fast broadband on demand, we can provide a free 50mb voucher per room, simply ask us upon arrival. For additional information you can visit Zenbu .
 
Continental breakfast

Our continental breakfast is made on site, and is delivered fresh to your unit the night before for your convenience. Breakfast is charged at $10 per person.

Our continental breakfast consists of:

 Glass of Orange Fruit Juice Choice of fruit Apricots Peaches Choice of cereals Cornflakes Museli Weetbix Fresh Toast and Butter Choice of toast spreads Honey Jam Marmalade Vegemite Marmite Jug of Fresh Milk 

Toaster and tea/coffee making facilities are all available in your room.

 
Room Facilities

 Electric blankets Direct dial phone Radio/alarm clocks Complimentary tea/coffee/milk Coffee Plungers En suite Bathrooms Kitchenettes - fridge, microwave, hot pan Cooking and eating cutlery Iron and Ironing boards 
 
Restaurant and food options

 Avonhead Tavern restaurant, free transfers. Large selection of meals for delivery to your unit. Local fast food restaurant within walking distance. Local small dairy within walking distance. Caltex Starmart open 24/7 with ATM within walking distance. 
 
Courtesy Shuttle

Our free Courtesy Shuttle operates between the hours of 9:00am - 1:00am everyday, except, Xmas Eve, Day, Boxing Day and New Years Eve, Day.

We operate this service from these locations only.

 Christchurch International and Domestic Terminals. Addington Railway station From Hornby Hub - By prior arrangement only. To Riccarton Racecourse only. 

Specific details on how to gain access to our shuttle is provide with your reservation details. If your flight is delayed after our 01:00am deadline, you will have to catch a taxi to our motel, if this occurs we will leave a late note at reception.

Please note that we do not provide a &apos;meet and greet&apos; service.
 
Car Minding

Long term parking, even short term parking at the Christchurch Airport can be extremely expensive. Five days parking at the Christchurch Airport can cost upwards of $50 dollars. Since we are close to the Christchurch Airport, we offer you the service of leaving your car in our capable hands.

 Car storage is charged at $2 per day, per car. 

Please note transfers upon return are only applicable for those staying the night with us. Otherwise a taxi will be necessary.
 
Rental Cars

Looking for a good, reliable rental car agency, why not check out U Save Rentals? They have a wide selection of vehicles at very competitive rates. They will even come pick you up from the motel and take you to the depot during business hours. You can get a quote online using the form below.
 
Check Availability

No booking fees
 
Call us toll free (NZ only)
 0508 342 333 

Airport Birches Motel
390 Yaldhurst Rd
Christchurch
New Zealand


Phone: +64 3 342 3338
Fax: +64 3 342 3328
 Home | Accommodation | Facilities | Online Booking | Contact Us | F A Q | Christchurch | Motel Policies | Latest News 
 Christchurch Motel Accommodation | Christchurch Airport Accommodation 

Airport Birches Motel - 390 Yaldhurst Rd, Christchurch, New Zealand | Freephone 0508 342 333 | Ph +64 3 342 3338 | Fax +64 3 342 3328
Copyright © 2011 Airport Birches Motel
	</body>
</document>
