<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001913" url="http://articles.orlandosentinel.com/keyword/indigent-care" time="2012-07-12-17:49" support="1" score="0.0001970301924504777" bingtitle="Articles about Indigent Care - Orlando Sentinel" webtitle="Articles about Indigent Care - Orlando Sentinel">
			<query id="001301" bing-rank="245"/>
	<description>This money is placed in a trust fund to help pay ... State lawmakers have passed a bill that&apos;ll give ... Mary used to work in a fast-food restaurant until her pregnancy ...</description>
	<body>
		Advertisement 
 

 Home Delivery Digital Memberships Place an Ad Jobs Cars Real Estate Rentals Classifieds Public Notices 
   
 

83°F
 Thursday, July 12 , 2012 11:48 AM EDT 
 Home 
 Digital Memberships MOBILE Obituaries Traffic Blogs Columnists Subscribe Send a News Tip El Sentinel Contact Us 
 Local 
 Breaking Obituaries Politics Crime Trayvon Martin FAMU Winter Park Forum Clermont Forum Orange Seminole Lake Osceola 
 Weather 
 Radar Get Email Alerts Hurricane HQ Hurricane Guide Hurricane Blog Orange Seminole Lake Osceola Volusia Marine 
 Sports 
 Orlando Magic Olympics Soccer Varsity Gators Knights Seminoles Recruiting Baseball NASCAR Golf Tickets Fan Shop 
 Business 
 Deals Personal Finance Your Career TECHNOLOGY Real Estate Disney Frugal Force Blog-o-nomics Social Tech 
 Entertainment 
 Events Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Music ARTS&amp;THEATER Movies Movie Times TV Celebrity Horoscope Comics Shopping 
 Life/Family 
 Schools Moms at Work Food/Recipes Home/Garden Summer Camps Religion Growing Bolder Weddings Pets Celebrations 
 Health 
 Breast Cancer Awareness Vital Signs Cancer Awareness Dental Health DIABETES Fitness Medicare Guide Nutrition 
 Travel 
 Explore Florida Vacation Deals Cruises Attractions Daily Disney Beach Golf Springs News 
 Opinion 
 Editorials Letters to the Editor Other Views Ticked Off! Columnists Our Blogs Your Blogs Cartoons 
 Videos 
 Surveillance Videos Viral Videos News Videos Orlando Magic Videos Sports Videos Entertainment Videos Political Videos 
 Home Delivery Digital Memberships Place an Ad Jobs 
 Find a Job Post Your Resume Post a Job Top 100 Companies Sentinel Careers Higher Education 
 Cars 
 Buy a Car Autos A-Z Research Cars Find a Dealer Other Vehicles&amp;Boats 
 Real Estate 
 New Construction Search: Foreclosures database Rentals Commercial Property What&apos;s selling Sell A Home 
 Rentals Classifieds 
 Jobs Cars Real Estate Rentals 
 Public Notices 
 
 TRENDING: ESPYs Robert Blake Daniel Tosh Kate Upton All Star Game 2012 DirecTV Frank Ocean George Zimmerman 
 
 
 
 
 Advanced Search 
Advanced Search
 X 
 include all of these words: include any of these words: include this exact phrase: exclude: Select a date range this week past 30 days past 3 months past year Create a custom date range From: To: 
 
Watch live at 1pm
 
 Interviews with Orange County Commission candidates 
 Home → Collections → Indigent Care IN THE NEWS 
Indigent Care
 FIND MORE STORIES ABOUT: 
 Lake County Florida Leesburg Deland Volusia County |   More 
 FEATURED ARTICLES LOCAL 
 Don&apos;t Pass The Buck 
 April 30, 1987 HURRAH for Winter Park Hospital&apos;s withdrawing from the indigent- care arrangement. Medical costs for indigent care are a community responsibility. It is illogical and fiscally unsound for private patients, who have no say in the matter, to end up paying for indigent care.Everyone wants a healthy United States, but let&apos;s see this tough political-economic dilemma for what it is: a responsibility of the government at all levels -- federal, state and local.Government created massive indigent-care programs. ARTICLES BY DATE LOCAL 
 EDITORIAL: The state&apos;s future health 
 Chattanooga Times Free Press, Tenn , June 30, 2012 Now that the Supreme Court has affirmed the constitutionality of the Affordable Care Act , Tennessee Gov. Bill Haslam and state lawmakers have a clear duty to begin planning for the state&apos;s nonprofit, flat-rate insurance exchanges that are required under the law. They also must decide whether to accept or reject the enormous benefit of federal funds to expand Medicaid to low-income Tennesseans, or possibly 200,000 to 300,000, who are now... Advertisement BUSINESS 
 Call For Health-insurance Reform Legislator Says Employers Should Offer Coverage 
 By John F. Persinos of The Sentinel Staff , November 22, 1986 Rep. Sam Bell, D-Daytona Beach, called Thursday for legislation that would require private employers in Florida to provide at least some health insurance for employees.In a seminar on indigent care during the Florida Hospital Association&apos;s annual meeting in Orlando, he said that the state&apos;s safety net for poor people needs mending.But Bell, chairman of the House Appropriations Committee and a longtime supporter of efforts to improve health-insurance benefits, is not optimistic about passage of such a bill next year. LIFE/FAMILY 
 Health care ruling divides Manatee County businesses 
 Josh Salman and The Bradenton Herald, Fla , June 29, 2012 Manatee County businesses and health care providers are at odds about the impact of Thursday&apos;s 5-4 Supreme Court ruling to uphold President Barack Obama &apos;s health care reform law. Local businesses are worried that the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act , first approved by Congress two years ago, will negatively affect their bottom lines. &quot;There&apos;s some provisions we think will be hurtful to the business community,&quot; said Neil Spirtas, vice president of Public Policy and Small Business for The Manatee Chamber of Commerce. LOCAL 
 Board Votes To Pay For Specific Indigent Care Patients At Fish Hospital 
 By Purvette A. Bryant of The Sentinel Staff , April 9, 1994 The West Volusia Hospital Authority said this week it will pay up to $1.5 million to fund indigent care at the new Fish Hospital in Orange City.In a 4-1 vote, board members signed an agreement Tuesday to pay for indigent care patients with &apos;&apos;specific&apos;&apos; DeBary, Deltona and Orange City zip codes. The decision does not increase the indigent care costs, said Hospital Administrator Mark Van Fleet.The payments will be made at 80 percent of charges up to a maximum of $1.5 million through Sept. 30, 1994, Van Fleet said. LOCAL 
 West Ocoee 
 February 11, 1990 TAX DISTRICT. City commissioners want their legislators to know they support the West Orange Hospital Tax District. Commissioners voted Tuesday to draw up a resolution saying the city endorses the tax district, which supports the hospital&apos;s ambulatory service and indigent care. Members of the Southwest Orange County Homeowners Association have said they want the district dissolved after the hospital&apos;s new complex is built in Ocoee in 1992. LOCAL 
 Thrown Off By Example 
 July 30, 1986 YOUR editorial headlined &apos;&apos;Indigent care on critical list&apos;&apos; was very informative -- but I was completely thrown off course by your example of an Orange County couple.&apos;&apos;Joe and Mary both work. When the time arrives for her baby to be delivered, Joe drives her to the hospital, where she delivers a healthy baby. The bill comes to $3,000.&apos;&apos;For what?Juliet H. CulbertMERRITT ISLAND LOCAL 
 Aids Clinic 
 By Compiled from staff reports , July 7, 1987 INDIGENT CARE. Volusia County will move closer today to establishing the area&apos;s first clinic for indigent people afflicted with the AIDS virus. The county health department will receive a $12,000 donation from the Bert Fish Testimentary Trust Fund, which helps pay for medical care for poor people in Volusia. The health department plans to solicit more donations and state grants to operate an AIDS clinic. The $12,000 is the first donation. Health department officials have not set a fund-raising goal. LOCAL 
 County May Replace Hospital Board Members 
 By Ramsey Campbell of The Sentinel Staff , June 4, 1987 Frustrated by their unsuccessful attempt to verify indigent patients in the Northwest Hospital Tax District, Lake County officials are toying with replacing the five-member district board.Terms for all five members have expired and the Leesburg Hospital Association Inc. has asked that each be reappointed immediately. However, county health and general services director Lonnie Strickland said he wants the county commission to advertise the vacancies in order to consider possible new appointees. LOCAL 
 Hospital Deal Leaves Some Uneasy 
 By Purvette A. Bryant of The Sentinel Staff , November 1, 1996 A $9 million loss on a lease agreement between the West Volusia Hospital Authority and an Ormond Beach health corporation was reported in an audit released Thursday.When West Volusia Memorial Hospital was leased to Memorial Health Systems Inc. in 1994, Memorial Systems assumed about $9.7 million in debt, said Bill Kelly, the hospital board&apos;s accountant.&apos;&apos;However, the book value on the building and equipment was $9 million higher than the debt assumed by Memorial,&apos;&apos; Kelly said Thursday.That extra $9 million was counted as a loss to the hospital board in its 1995 annual audit conducted by Lovelace, Roby and Co. of Orlando. LOCAL 
 Hospital board trying to establish new policies 
 June 19, 2012 TAVARES — The North Lake County Hospital District board will have to hold another special meeting in a few weeks to try to hash out policies and procedures to meet requirements outlined in a new state law. Board members spent several hours last week tackling new rules to comply with the law, approved in March to improve the district&apos;s accountability and transparency. Chairman Ken Carpenter brought forth at the meeting a proposal to set aside about 90 percent of the tax dollars collected to cover indigent care for Leesburg Regional Medical Center and Florida Hospital Waterman in Tavares. LOCAL 
 Hospital district works to make changes required by new law 
 
By Eloísa Ruano González, Orlando Sentinel
 , May 20, 2012 TAVARES —North Lake County Hospital District board members are scrambling to comply with legislation recently signed by Gov. Rick Scott intended to give voters more control of the district and increase its accountability and transparency. Board members held a special meeting last week to start rolling out new procedures and rules required by the legislation, which state Rep. Larry Metz, R-Yalaha, sponsored. It could take several months to meet the &quot;complex&quot; requirements set out in the bill, said Ken Carpenter, board chairman. LOCAL 
 Lawmakers pass bill calling for vote on North Lake hospital district tax 
 
By Stephen Hudak , Orlando Sentinel
 , March 14, 2012 State lawmakers have passed a bill that&apos;ll give Lake County voters a chance to decide whether to continue a controversial tax that provides millions of dollars annually to two privately owned and operated hospitals. The bill, which was sent to Gov. Rick Scott for approval, calls for an election in 2016 by voters in the North Lake County Hospital District. It also includes several reforms proposed by Rep. Larry Metz, R-Yalaha, and endorsed by all of Lake&apos;s legislative delegation except Sen. Alan Hays , R-Umatilla. LOCAL 
 North Lake hospital taxing district faces appellate challenge 
 By Stephen Hudak, Orlando Sentinel , November 29, 2011 TAVARES - An appellate court will be asked to review the decision of a circuit judge who ruled in favor of a controversial property tax benefitting privately owned hospitals in Lake County. The appeal was filed by Joseph Little, a University of Florida law professor who represents Marilyn Bainter, a member of the North Lake Hospital District&apos;s elected board, who opposes the tax as unconstitutional. The tax also may face a challenge from lawmakers, depending on what the county&apos;s legislative delegation decides Wednesday at a public hearing at the Mount Dora Community Building, 520 N. Baker St. The meeting begins at 7 p.m. State Rep. Larry Metz, R-Yalaha, has proposed a bill that would reorganize the North Lake Hospital District and let voters decide if they want to pay a tax to defray the cost of providing medical care for the poor. LOCAL 
 Dozens weigh in on plan to revamp Lake hospital tax 
 By Christine Show, Orlando Sentinel , November 12, 2011 TAVARES — Dozens of residents and hospital officials crowded a Lake County legislative delegation meeting this week as state Rep. Larry Metz, R-Yalaha, presented his plan to restructure a controversial tax to local lawmakers. Metz urged the five other state legislators who represent Lake at the nearly five-hour meeting to support his proposal to repeal the North Lake County Hospital District and allow voters to decide whether to set up a new district that would use taxpayer money exclusively for indigent care. LOCAL 
 Hospital district issue gives voters a chance to control tax 
 Lauren Ritchie and COMMENTARY , November 6, 2011 So, you&apos;re sick of paying taxes. You grouse about them to your neighbors. You wish you could do something, short of staging a coup. You can. This is the easiest and most direct chance ever to have a profound effect on guiding your own tax destiny. If you fail to take it, you have forever lost whining privileges. From 5:30 to 10 p.m. Wednesday, Lake County&apos;s legislative delegation will meet at the round courthouse in Tavares. The topic: whether to OK the filing of a legislative bill allowing voters to decide on abolishing the North Lake County Hospital District. BUSINESS 
 Hospitals Hope To Avoid Tax Bite 
 By Gene Yasuda of The Sentinel Staff , June 8, 1992 Central Florida hospital administrators are hoping that as Gov. Lawton Chiles scrambles to find ways to raise $2.5 billion in additional taxes, he won&apos;t look in their direction.Chiles has done little to indicate he would strip hospitals of some of the tax exemptions they enjoy. But it&apos;s not an unrealistic scenario. A year ago, lawmakers tried to make non-profit hospitals pay sales tax.Non-profit hospitals are exempt from sales tax if they provide a certain level of indigent care.A hospital can obtain an exemption if 2.5 percent or more of its total patient days is attributable to indigent care. LOCAL 
 Hospital Trustees On The Ballot 
 November 4, 1990 North Lake County residents for the first time will elect members of the new North Lake Hospital District Board of Trustees.The six-member board deals with indigent care for Waterman Medical Center and Leesburg Regional Medical Center.The board will meet three or four times a year to levy a hospital tax of $1 per $1,000 of property value, establish a budget and to make sure the estimated $2.5 million in tax revenue is spent for indigent care, said Zeb Osborne, president of Waterman Medical Center Foundation. 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 | Next LOCAL 
 Time to rethink need for hospital taxes 
 October 27, 2011 Gov. Rick Scott seems never to have met a tax he likes. He&apos;s still pushing for tax cuts, even with lawmakers facing a $2 billion budget shortfall next year and the prospect of slashing more spending from education, health care and other basic services. But Scott&apos;s skepticism of at least one tax - paid by some property owners to operate or subsidize local hospitals in Florida - is well founded. There are 16 hospital taxing districts in the state. Three are in Volusia County, two are in Lake County. LOCAL 
 Hospital district tax for north Lake would be abolished under legislator&apos;s proposal 
 Lauren Ritchie and COMMENTARY , October 2, 2011 Finally - a chance that Lake County residents could be relieved of a tax burden they&apos;ve been carrying unnecessarily for years is dangling before them, thanks to state Rep. Larry Metz. The Yalaha Republican campaigned on a promise to reform hospital district taxes, and now he is following through. But Metz could use a little help from you. First, let&apos;s take a quick look at the structure of the district that Metz seeks to change. It&apos;s the North Lake County district, which in 2010 collected nearly $10 million and handed it to the two hospitals in its area, Florida Hospital Waterman and Leesburg Regional Medical Center. 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 | Next Index by Keyword | Index by Date | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service Please note the green-lined linked article text has been applied commercially without any involvement from our newsroom editors, reporters or any other editorial staff.
	</body>
</document>
