<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001730" url="http://restaurantscammers.blogspot.com/" time="2012-07-12-17:30" support="6" score="0.015473798187397077" bingtitle="Restaurant Scammers" webtitle="Restaurant Scammers">
			<query id="001035" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="001004" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000227" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="001476" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="000377" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000221" bing-rank="134"/>
	<description>WHERE IS MY FOOD!!! I never understood why people ... truly tight for time you can always go to a fast food restaurant ... tall and was so pleased about not having to pay ...</description>
	<body>
		Restaurant Scammers
 
 A bloggers rant about people who dine at restaurants to scam to get free food and drinks. A retired servers point of view about hard to please customers who are never satisfied and who whine, complain and make a scene just to get something for free. Not only customers have opinions, rate and give reviews of restaurants but servers and retired servers have opinions of pain in the butt customers who practice scamming to get free food and drink. If you can&apos;t afford to eat out DON&apos;T. 
 

 
 Sunday, April 1, 2012 
 Restaurant Scammers 

 There are many people who scam restaurants daily. Restaurant Scammers do it to get a free drink, meal or dessert. Restaurant Scammers don&apos;t care if they make a scene and it&apos;s because they want what they ate and drank for free. I consider Restaurant Scammers to be dirt-bag people with no class or shame. They are rats who do a great job at complaining and whining just to get something for free. They usually aggravate the restaurant workers and obviously have no respect for them or themselves. In this blog I share some of the Restaurant Scammers I&apos;ve had the pleasure of serving over the years. Instead of reading restaurant reviews from customers only, I felt a retired server like myself had a few interesting stories to share about serving the public. Not all customers are a huge pain in the butt but there are many customers who should stay home and never dine out. 

 I will start this blog with the complaint that pisses me off the most. If you find this blog offensive then you probably are the kind of customer I could live without ever serving again.  

 WHERE IS MY FOOD!!! 

 I never understood why people would go out to eat if they are so tight for time. CUSTOMERS WHO COMPLAIN ABOUT WAITING FOR THEIR FOOD TO BE COOKED CAN GO KISS MY BUTT. Why would someone go out to dine if they have to complain that there food is taking too long and then make a scene about waiting 30-minutes for good quality food to be cooked properly? Why would people go out to eat lunch if they don&apos;t have the time? There are different kinds of restaurants for different occasions. If you are going out to dine with your gang to socialize and have fun, why would you go out of your way to be an ass? Why complain that the $30.95 entree needs time to be cooked properly by an experienced chef for you to enjoy? Why make a scene and make the server uncomfortable when you should be enjoying that $50.00 bottle of wine, appetizers, salads and the company you chose to dine and have fun with? If a server is cruising along and all is going well with serving you why complain at all? I feel the people who complain constantly for no good reason complain to get something for free and in my experience as a server find that the people who do whine, complain and make a scene get something for free such as an appetizer taken off their check, a round of free drinks or free dessert. Scamming over time probably keeps a lot of money in your pockets or bank account.  IF YOU CAN&apos;T AFFORD IT STAY HOME!!! 

 If you are truly tight for time you can always go to a fast food restaurant such as a diner, Denny&apos;s, Toco-Bell, McDonalds, Burger King, Friday&apos;s, Applebee&apos;s and so on. These are the kind of places where you order fast and get food fast. Fast food restaurants have plenty of processed foods ready to be cook and prepared fast. OK, a lot of diners have good quality food but diners are set up and equipped to cook and serve food fast. 

 I did learn that money and class don&apos;t always go together. There is good and no so good in every group of people.  

 JULY 2010 

 I started a new serving job in June 2010. The restaurant was a more of an upscale establishment and most of the clientele were financially well off. Dinner entrees ranged between $18.95 to $31.95. Good quality delicious food. Anyway, within the first couple of months of working there I had to deal with customers who always complained, whined and wanted something for free. Annoying to say the least. The majority of the regular customers knew I was new and made my job a lot harder than it needed to be. At this job I learned that many of the wealthy who are well off financially because they know how to scam to get something for free and have no shame doing whatever it takes to save a dollar. Most of the clientele at this place were very good at complaining, whining and making a scene to get anything deducted off their check. What&apos;s the point of dinning out if you don&apos;t go out to simply enjoy a delicious meal and appreciate it? 

 In the first week of working there I had the pleasure of serving a grown man who made a huge scene by having a hissy fit. I greeted the table, they ordered cocktails, I served the cocktails and started to recite the specials and before I could get through reciting the first special one man at the table asked about a dish he saw on the restaurant website. I kindly explained the website was outdated and that the restaurant no longer had the entree he wanted. He immediately SLAMMED (yes, slammed) his FIST on the table. The slam ECHOED throughout the dinning-room AND he started to speak very loudly to the point of other customers kindly asking for him to take it down a notch. He whined for an additional 60 seconds then demanded to speak with a manager. The manager did apologize about the website being outdated and that the chef would be more than happy to cook a dish he wish to have if they had the ingredients in house. Of course the man got a special dish cooked for him and the man continued to stay annoyed and dissatisfied but he ate his entire plate of food and stayed for coffee and dessert. The man made me feel uncomfortable every single time I went to his table and the man did not care. When it came time to bring over the check the manager had deducted his entree, coffee and dessert. I watched that man walk out of the restaurant with his friends and he stood tall and was so pleased about not having to pay for his meal. He had no shame whatsoever but the couple he dinned with was surely embarrassed. In my opinion the man was a professional scammer. A DIRT-BAG WITH A PLAN TO SCAM. 

 I WANT IT FOR FREE!!! 

 Another trick scammers use to save a few bucks while dinning out is to complain about the soda. I&apos;ve lost count how many times a manager has had to deduct soda off a check. Sodas are usually served in a big glass (16 oz.) so if someone drinks a whole glass of soda it usually equals the amount of a can of soda. Because most restaurants add ice to the glass before pouring the soda into the glass the soda probably equals the amount of a 12 oz. can of soda. Customers have done this to me so many times and they are so pleased that the soda they drank gets deducted from the check. Try to picture the scenario. Customers sit down, get greeted, order drinks such as the soda, orders their food, receives the food and half way through eating their meal they will call me over to tell me that the soda is flat AFTER THEY DRANK MOST OF IT. I apologize, remove the soda glasses off the table, ask if they would like another kind of drink (of course they don&apos;t) inform the manager that the customers feels the soda is flat (when in reality the soda is not flat) the manager will ask me if they would like anything else to drink, I tell the manager no and the manager then goes to the computer to deduct the $2.00-$2.75 glass of soda off the check and in many cases more than one soda is deducted off the check. When it comes time to bring over the check and I bring the check to the table of course I am asked if the soda or soda have been deducted off the check. When I inform the customers that the soda has been taken off the check the customers are pleased and happy becuase they saved a few bucks. Because this is a regular occurrence when certain customers come in to dine I and the managers already know what will soon happen. Each restaurant usually have their regular customers and after a while restaurant managers, servers and owners know exactly who scams just to save a few dollars. I believe restaurants probably have a reserve of funds just to please customers who waste food, drink and money. I would think it&apos;s just a part of having a business. 

 EARLY 90&apos;s 

 The first time I dealt with a Restaurant Scammer, I was about 20-years-old working at a local pub. The pub served a huge side salad with every entree. Nothing fancy but always had fresh mixed lettuce leaves with vegetables and they were fresh because the salads were made before each dinner shift. The restaurant never served day old salads to customers the next day. 

 On a Thursday night shift I signed in, did prep work and started serving customers and everything was moving along just fine until a party of four walked in the door. I went over to greet them, they were talking and laughing with each other and ignored me so I figured being ignored for at least sixty seconds gave me a reason to move along to continue serving other customers then go back to them to start all over again. I figured a fresh start with another warm welcome would catch their attention. I went back to the table and the people were being rude and trying to be funny so I went along with it the best I could. I finally get their drink order, bring it over, take their order and then moved along to get the process of serving them into action. I bring out the salads with the dressing they requested and two of the four customers ate their salads but the other two wanted to save their salads for when the entree come out. No problem, I do what they ask and all four entrees were now in front of them and they started to eat. I went back to the table to check on them after they took a bit or two they all seemed content and happy with their entrees. About ten minutes later one of the woman who had saved her salad to eat with her meal shows me that there is a full cigarette in her salad. The lady got very loud complaining and freaked out over the fact that there was a full previously lit cigarette in her salad. The cigarette looked like it had been lit, put out and placed in the salad. She was right but that cigarette butt did not get in that salad from the kitchen staff preparing it. OH NO, it was placed there by the customer. How do I know it was placed there by the customer? Keep reading to find out.  The four top drank a couple of cocktails, two out of four ate their salads and all four ate at least half of a large entree THEN THEY STARTED TO COMPLAIN AND MADE A SCENE. 

 I did my best to apologize and the manager went over to the table to apologize too and informed the table of four that they were only being charge for two entrees. The four top only had to pay for two entrees and the drinks were on the house too. The customers calmed down, continued to finish their entrees, paid and started walking out the side door. Because of all the excitement and getting very nervous by what had happened, I went outside to smoke a cigarette and while I was on the side of the building I could see the four top hear them talking loud and clear. As they were walking to their van they were all laughing and saying to each other how it gets easier every time to get free drinks and food. They were happy and laughing and so pleased with the fact that they made a scene and lied just to get some free food that they probably could afford. WOW! My first experience serving Restaurant Scammers. The four people were sure a bunch of dirt-bag trash. I&apos;m sure karma came back to them sometime throughout their life. 

 As time goes on I will add to this blog. Experiences do pop up in my mind occasionally and will be more than happy to share my stories. 


 Posted by Retired Server at 10:51 AM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: food service , restaurant runners , restaurant scammers , restaurant scamming , restaurant servers , restaurant stories Home Subscribe to: Posts (Atom) 
Google Search Engine
 Loading... 
About Me
 Retired Server Blogging about the jerk-offs I&apos;ve had the pleasure to serve during my 35 years of being in the restaurant business. Not all but many customers are truly jerk-offs. View my complete profile 
More Conversation
 
 LotOfCoupons.com Pain In The Ass Customer Stories 
 
Follow by Email
 
 
 
 

 

 

 

 

 
Infolinks In Text Ads
 
 
 Simple template. Template images by linearcurves . Powered by Blogger .
	</body>
</document>
