<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001387" url="http://www.southsideworks.com/directions.htm" time="2012-07-12-17:09" support="6" score="0.006694999212984245" bingtitle="SouthSide Works" webtitle="SouthSide Works">
			<query id="000808" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000744" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000807" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="000798" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000802" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000793" bing-rank="36"/>
	<description>Merge onto I-579 S via exit number 8A towards VETERANS BRIDGE. Take the 7th Avenue/6th Avenue exit. Take the ramp ...</description>
	<body>
		The SouthSide Works is located 
 between 26th Street and Hot Metal Street. Plenty of convenient parking is available in any of the four structured parking garages offering some of the lowest parking rates available in the city. Due to construction, the temporary surface lot is now closed. Check out the map for 
 exact garage locations.

 From North I-79 
Follow I-79 S and merge onto I-279 S toward Pittsburgh. 
 Merge onto I-579 S via exit number 8A towards VETERANS 
 BRIDGE. Take the 7th Avenue/6th Avenue exit. Take the 
 ramp toward MELLON ARENA. Turn left onto BIGELOW BLVD. 
 Turn right onto WASHINGTON PL. and WASHINGTON PL. becomes 
 CHATHAM SQ. Turn left onto FORBES AVENUE. Merge onto 
 the BIRMINGHAM BRIDGE toward South Side. Turn left onto 
 E. Carson Street. Access the property by making a left 
 onto 23rd St. through 28th St.

 From East I-376 
Follow I-376 W toward Pittsburgh. Take EXIT 3A toward 
 GLENWOOD. Turn slight right onto Bates St/PA 885. Turn 
 Left onto PA-885/2nd AVENUE. Turn right onto HOT METAL 
 ST. Turn right onto SIDNEY ST. and discover the SouthSide 
 Works.

 From South I-79 
Follow I-79 N and follow signs to I-279 N toward Pittsburgh. 
 Continue through the tunnels and follow signs to Monroeville 
 and take the 1C GRANT ST. exit on the left. Continue 
 straight through the light and make a right onto FORBES 
 AVENUE. Follow for 1.2 miles and merge right onto BIRMINGHAM 
 BRIDGE toward SOUTH SIDE. Turn left onto CARSON STREET. 
 Access property by making a left onto 23rd STREET through 
 28TH STREET.

Alternate Route–Continue through the tunnels 
 and follow signs to Monroeville and take the 1C GRANT 
 ST. exit on the left. Continue straight through the 
 light. Make a right onto FOURTH AVENUE. Make a left 
 onto ROSS STREET. Make a right onto 2ND AVENUE. Follow 
 2ND AVENUE along the river until you come to the HOT 
 METAL BRIDGE. Make a right onto the HOT METAL BRIDGE. 
 Turn right onto SIDNEY ST and discover the SouthSide 
 Works.

 From Homestead/East Carson 
 Street 
Follow Eighth Avenue to Carson St. exit. Follow East 
 Carson Street. Access property by either making a right 
 onto HOT METAL STREET and a left onto SYDNEY STREET 
 or making a right onto 28th through 26th STREET.

 Click 
 here for a detailed map and driving directions. 
 
 

PARKING RATES

Daily Rates

Monday through Friday

                             Hours                 Rate

                              0 to 1                 $3.00

                              1 to 2                 $4.00

                              2 to 3                 $5.00

                    3 to 4            $6.00

                              4 to 5                 $7.00

                              5 to 8                 $8.00

                              8 to 9                 $9.00

                              9 to 10              $10.00

                            10 to 11              $11.00

                            11 to 12              $13.00

                            12 to 24              $15.00

Monday through Friday AFTER 5 PM

and ALL DAY Saturday&amp;Sunday

First hour FREE, $3.00 maximum

Monthly Lease Rate: $140.00

 

 

BUS SCHEDULES

SouthSide Works

is located directly on the bus line!

 75 

 

Be sure to check out the Pittsburgh Port Authority Website for Rates and Bus schedules!
	</body>
</document>
