<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001239" url="http://www.fastfoodindustry.net/news.php" time="2012-07-12-16:41" support="58" score="0.1482588633351007" bingtitle="Fast Food Industry" webtitle="Fast Food Industry">
			<query id="000209" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000461" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="001106" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000060" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="001222" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="000178" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000898" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000427" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000046" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000900" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="001534" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000353" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="000416" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000521" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000447" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="001200" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="000173" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000458" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000465" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000886" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000189" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="000415" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="001126" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="000176" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="001535" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="001118" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="000186" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000166" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000772" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="001389" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000422" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="000182" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="000050" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="000892" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="000906" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="001127" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="001317" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="000444" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="001112" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000941" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="000907" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000751" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="000453" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000040" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000359" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000446" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000041" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000061" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000689" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="001526" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000374" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="000421" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000204" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="000425" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="001243" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="001520" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="001528" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="000373" bing-rank="241"/>
	<description>Fast food venders will receive a blanket ban ... Arby’s Group Inc., the third-largest U.S. fast-food restaurant ... tested at the center, including warming trays that ...</description>
	<body>
		About Us Contact Us FAQ&apos;s 
 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 UK FOOD FRANCHISEE&apos;S POLL 

 A unique view into the minds of the
food franchisee&apos;s community in the UK 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 The Fast Food Jobs UK Car! 
 
 Car supplied by Acorn finance, graphics supplied by Blue Lizard , contact number supplied by the 0845 Team. 

If you have any breaking or intersting news you think may interest the industry please send it to steve@fastfoodjobsuk.co.uk 
 
 
 
 McDonalds goes to great lengths to promote the British food it buys, but it fails to mention its chicken which is imported from abroad 
 
7th June 2010
 

Our customers care about where their food comes from,”insisted Nick 
Hindle, the company’s vice-president for communications from London.“People want to eat British food. They think it is supporting the 
British economy and they trust the quality.”But there’s one staple on the menu at McDonald’s that is not mentioned 
in any of the blurbs, that fails to feature in any of the media spin, 
and that undermines the whole PR exercise: chicken. The reason? Because 
99% of it comes from abroad. Some 60% of the chicken breast meat used in
the fast food chain’s sandwiches, wraps, burgers, salads and the 
copyrighted Chicken McNuggets are imported from Brazil. About 30% is 
sourced from elsewhere in Europe, including Holland and France, and 9% 
is from Thailand.

So in all of Friday’s“countryside to counter”tour, not a single 
chicken was on display, dead or alive. That was odd, given that up to 
half the meat eaten in branches of McDonald’s these days is chicken–said to be equivalent to 30 million birds a year.

 
 Click here for the full story 
 
 Ronald McDonald Retiring???? 
 
22nd May 2010
 
 RONALD McDonald is not retiring, 
McDonald&apos;s Chief Executive Jim Skinner said at the fast food giant&apos;s 
annual meeting in Chicago after recent calls for the mascot to be canned
because he markets unhealthy food to children, The Chicago Tribune 
reported. 
&quot;Ronald McDonald is not retiring,&quot; Mr Skinner said, adding, &quot;He is a
force for good...he does not hawk food.&quot;

His comments were met 
with applause from shareholders.

Corporate Accountability 
International, which describes itself as a corporate abuse watchdog has 
called for McDonald&apos;s to retire Ronald.

 
 Click here for the full story 
 
 Chipotle Opens First London Restaurant 
 
11th May 2010
 
Chipotle Mexican Grill /quotes/comstock/13*!cmg /quotes/nls/cmg ( CMG 136.92 , +8.09 , +6.28% ) today opened its first European 
restaurant in London located at 114-116 Charing Cross Road. The 
company, 
which operates nearly 1,000 restaurants in the United States, is 
also 
looking for additional sites in London and exploring other 
European 
markets including Paris and select cities in Germany.
&quot;We think the prospects are very good for Chipotle in London and around 
Europe,&quot; said Steve Ells, founder, chairman and co-chief executive
officer of Chipotle. &quot;The food culture in Europe is based on 
local, 
sustainable and artisanal foods, which are all core values of 
Chipotle 
and we have been instrumental in bringing this kind of thinking to
fast 
food in the U.S. We call it&apos;Food with Integrity&apos;and it is one of
the 
ways we are changing the way people think about and eat fast 
food.&quot;

 
 Click here for the full story 
 
 Dominos launch SUBS nationwide 
 
5th May 2010
 

Domino&apos;s launch subs NATIONWIDE

LAUNCH: 7th June and include the following fillings -
Cheese Steak Melt, Meatball Sub, Vegetarian Supreme, New Yorker,
Breakfast Sub and Nuclear Sub.

More to follow

 
 Jamie Oliver praises McDonald&apos;s 
 
26th April 2010
 

The celebrity television chef criticised gastropubs and said they could 
learn 
a lot from the world’s largest chain of hamburger restaurants.

“McDonald’s in the UK is very different compared to the US model–the 
quality 
of beef, they only sell free-range eggs, they only sell organic milk, 
their 
ethics and recycling is being improved and improved,”Oliver said.

 
 Click here for the full story 
 
 Tightrope Pizza Delivery to Create History at Wembley 
 
16th April 2010
 
Jade Kindar-Martin will create history at Wembley Stadium on Saturday when he becomes the first person to walk across the width of the world famous venue - but he will be doing it at a height of more than 150 feet on a wire no wider than that width of your finger!

As part of the pre-match show at the Saracens v Harlequins Guinness Premiership clash, the daredevil performer will walk the 500 feet across the roof of the world famous venue on a wire just 16mm thick–while also delivering a pizza in full Domino’s uniform!

The sky walk, sponsored by Domino’s Pizza, is yet another first for Saracens at the iconic venue which has already hosted matches against Northampton Saints, South Africa and Worcester Warriors this season in front of club record crowds.

Kindar-Martin is no stranger to creating history having sky walked at some of the most unique spots around the world. He set a Guinness World Record when he walked 1,500 feet across the River Thames and he topped that with a 1km walk across the Han River in Seoul to set another world record.

The Sky Walk is just a small part of the pre-match show at Wembley on Saturday which includes performances from 90s pop sensations Right Said Fred, the hit West End play WarHorse, circus acts and there will also be 10,000 knights at the stadium.

Tickets are on sale now priced 10 for adults and 5 for U16s and are available from www.ticketmaster.co.uk or by calling 0844 847 2482.

-Ends-
 
 UK-KFC Faces Boycott Threat From Muslims Over Halal Trial 
 
12th April 2010
 
Fings were not lickin&apos;good for KFC in their bid to sell fried 
chicken to Islamic customers in Britain, the News of the World reported 
Sunday.
The fast food chain was being threatened with a boycott 
by both Muslims and non-Muslims.
It hoped to woo the Islamic market 
by opening 86 trial outlets selling halal-only meat, slaughtered under 
strict religious guidelines.

 
 Click here for the full story 
 
 First Iceland&apos;s Economy Collapsed, Now They&apos;ve Lost Their Fast Food 
 
11th April 2010
 
 
The final ignominy has befallen the plucky/wildly over-leveraged island nation. Pizza Hut have announced that they&apos;re closing two of their three Reykjavik restaurants. McDonald&apos;s closed theirs earlier this year. Both companies blamed the collapse of the Icelandic economy.In 2008 the nation&apos;s currency and three of its largest banks collapsed. Since then unemployment has risen, and so have foreclosures. Which means that people have no money, and that importing things—even the crappy ingredients for fast food—as the Icelandic Krona is worth less, has become very expensive.
 
 
 Click here for the full story 
 
 Fast-food restaurants wage a breakfast food war 
 
11th April 2010
 
 Subway hopes some people will eat breakfast and order lunch at the same time, since the regular menu also will be available in the morning. Based on test market results, a few may even start their days with meatball marinara subs and other lunchtime items, company officials said.
&quot;It&apos;s an extension of what we&apos;ve been doing all along, which is providing sandwiches,&quot; said Les Winograd, a spokesman for the Connecticut-based company. &quot;The breakfast day part is one of the areas where we felt we could do a better job.&quot; 
 
 Click here for the full story 
 
 Doner kebab becomes Germany&apos;s favorite fast food 
 
9th April 2010
 
 
BERLIN—Forget about bratwurst, currywurst and other kinds of sausages—doner kebab, or shawarma, has overtaken traditional German fast food as the country&apos;s favorite snack on the go.

First brought to Berlin by Turkish immigrants in the 1970s, the grilled meat snack that comes wrapped in a pita bread with shredded lettuce, tomatoes, onions and different dressings, is now being sold everywhere in Germany from the Baltic Sea to the Bavarian Alps.
 
 
 Click here for the full story 
 
 &quot;This is a war zone -- not an amusement park,&quot; 
 
7th April 2010
 
 The U.S. military has long had the Taliban in its cross hairs, but it&apos;s recently set its sights on another target in Afghanistan - the Whopper.




Fast food joints like Burger King, Pizza Hut and T.G.I. Friday&apos;s have given soldiers at military bases throughout the country a taste of home during their combat tours. But those days are numbered, according to a Reuters report .



&quot;This is a war zone -- not an amusement park,&quot; Command Sgt. Maj. Michael Hall blogged earlier this year.


 CBSNews.com Special Report: Afghanistan 


&quot;Supplying nonessential luxuries to big bases like Bagram and Kandahar makes it harder to get essential items to combat outposts and forward operating bases, where troops who are in the fight each day need.&quot;
 
 
 Click here for the full story 
 
 Dominos Challenge at Wembley 
 
2nd April 2010
 
 250,000 up for the grabs in the Saracens Domino’s Challenge
 One lucky 
fan at the Saracens vs. Harlequins match at Wembley Stadium on Saturday 17th 
April will have a chance to win 250,000 during half-time.
Stuart Tinner 
famously won 250,000 during the interval when Saracens played at Wembley last 
November.
In the Domino’s Challenge, one spectator - selected at random from 
the crowd - will have as many place-kicks as possible in 30 seconds to kick the 
ball through a circular target within a giant Domino’s pizza box suspended 
between the posts.
Tickets from 5 are available at www.ticketmaster.co.uk&lt; https://mail-svr01.saracens.net/exchweb/bin/redir.asp?URL=http://www.ticketmaster.co.uk &gt; 
or by calling 0844 847 2482.

 
 Register * Market Data Loading Chart o Dow Jones 10,624.70&amp;#9650;12.85 (0.12%) o NASDAQ 2,367.66&amp;#9660;0.80 (-0.03%) o S&amp;P 500 1,149.99&amp;#9660;0.25 (-0.02%) o Google 579.54&amp;#9660;1.60 (-0.28%) NASDAQ:.DJI Dow Jones Company ID 
 
13th March 2010
 
Fast food joints are scrambling to find alternate sources for one of
America&apos;s favorite sandwich toppings after a winter freeze took a huge
bite out of Florida&apos;s tomato harvest. Due to unusually cold winter
weather, 60% to 70% of Florida&apos;s tomato crop was destroyed, said
Terence McElroy, a spokesman at the Florida Department of Agriculture.
And because the sunshine state produces about 75% of U.S. tomatoes,
prices across the country have spiked.
 
 Click here for the full story 
 
 Britain&apos;s biggest fast food chains are importing cheap chicken from South America and Asia without ever having to tell customers where the meat comes from. 
 
7th March 2010
 

 The Sunday Telegraph has established that chicken sold in chains 
including McDonald&apos;s, Subway and Kentucky Fried Chicken is often reared and 
slaughtered thousands of miles away and then shipped frozen to the UK in 
container ships.

There is no obligation on the fast food chains to admit to the country of 
origin on menus and boards, despite growing pressure to come clean.

Subway, which has 1,300 outlets in the UK–100 more than McDonald&apos;s - has 
admitted sourcing its chicken from five different countries: Thailand, 
Brazil, Uruguay, Argentina and Chile.

McDonald&apos;s states on its website that all the beef in its burgers is sourced 
from the UK or Ireland, but neglects to mention that the chicken in Chicken 
McNuggets and other meals comes from not only the UK and Europe but also 
Brazil and Thailand. In all, McDonald&apos;s uses 14 million chickens a year in 
its UK outlets.

Last month, following an investigation by this newspaper, the sandwich chain 
Pret a Manger was forced to change its packaging, replacing the word&apos;fresh&apos;on labels with&apos;good&apos;in its description of ingredients.

Pret has admitted that all its chicken is sourced from Brazil although it is 
now looking to switch to a British supplier of free-range chicken.

Nina Arnott, a KFC spokesperson, said: &quot;The majority (59%) of our 
chicken, including all of our signature Original Recipe chicken on the bone, 
comes from major suppliers in the UK, and all of our Original Recipe chicken 
is delivered fresh, not frozen, to our stores.



 
 Click here for the full story 
 
 Scotland to introduce fast food limitations to curb obesity levels 
 
24th February 2010
 

With the media really going to town with regards to soaring obesity
rates in both adults and children, Scotland is set to introduce a
number of measures, to try and tackle the problem at one of the major
sources, junk food culture.

The fact of the matter is, the number of obese people in Scotland
alone, is set to double by as soon as 2030. There will be 12m obese
adults by 2010 and 1 in 4 children are already obese before school age.
These are the facts and with obesity costing us a nation, 3 billion
pounds yearly, it is definitely time that something was done.

 The measures 

Fast food venders will receive a blanket ban, preventing them from
trading anywhere near schools. They will also need to curb portion
sizes, as will restaurants.

The Public Health Minister, Shona Robison believes that fast food
retailers should also limit the amount of sugar and salt that they put
into food and to display the amount of calories present in every meal.

 Criticism 

The plan has been met with a great deal of criticism from people who believe that the move is‘unenforceable nonsense’.

David Mcguire, the CEO of the Glasgow Resteraunters’Association
said it would simply place too many limitations on our decisions to
dine out. We at WeightWorld believe that there is some substance the
move. It would be good for raising awareness about the importance of a
balanced diet although simply putting the number of calories alongside
meals is not enough. People need to be educated about the dangers of
excessive calorie levels.

We can help to prevent obesity through basic lifestyle choices. Our diet and exercise levels are key to staying healthy.



 
 Click here for the full story 
 
 Delivery driver robbed of car at knife-point in Glasgow 
 
21st February 2010
 
 A fast food delivery man has been held at knife-point and robbed of his car in the Barmulloch area of Glasgow. 
 
 Click here for the full story 
 
 Food Standard Agency 
 
19th February 2010
 
It is very important that all food businesses obey the law and supply food that 
is safe to eat. Consumers in certain areas can already see how well a food 
business complies with food hygiene regulations through Scores on the Doors 
schemes run by their local authority.

The primary purpose of these 
Scores on the Doors schemes is to allow consumers to make informed choices about 
the places in which they eat out and from which they purchase food, and, through 
this, to encourage businesses to improve hygiene standards.

Local 
authority enforcement officers are responsible for inspecting food businesses to 
ensure that they meet the legal requirements on food hygiene. Under Scores on 
the Doors schemes, each food outlet is given a hygiene rating or hygiene score 
that reflects the inspection findings and may display this in their premises 
where consumers can see it. Scores are also available via websites where 
consumers can see the scores for all the businesses in the local area.

At the moment, more than 200 local authorities across the UK have Scores 
on the Doors schemes in place. These schemes vary in their design and the way 
that they are operated so the Agency is working towards a national approach to 
avoid further proliferation of different arrangements in different areas, and so 
ensure consistency for consumers and clarity for businesses.

Following a 
public consultation in the summer of 2008, the FSA Board agreed that a six-tier 
national scores on the doors scheme should be established in England, Wales and 
Northern Ireland as the majority of schemes already operating in these countries 
are based on this design. A two-tier scheme will continue in Scotland in line 
with the prevailing views of stakeholders there.

A UK-wide Steering 
Group, with local authority, industry and consumer representation, has been 
established to oversee development of the six-tier national scheme and to ensure 
commonality of approach with the two-tier scheme continuing in Scotland.
 
 Click here for the full story 
 
 DOMINOS LAUNCHES ITS HOTTEST PIZZA YET 
 
18th February 2010
 

 After one of the 
coldest British winters in living memory, Domino’s is this month putting a bit 
of spice back into our lives with the launch of its hottest pizza yet–Meltdown-The Revenge. 

 Set to tingle the 
taste buds of those who are brave enough to take on this fiery pizza, the new 
addition to the Domino’s menu is covered in an array of mouth and eye watering 
toppings. With five different types of heat in the form of chilli cheese slices, 
sweet chilli peppers, jalapeos, bird’s-eye chilli peppers and American style 
mustard, as well as ground beef, meatballs and mozzarella, Meltdown-The Revenge 
has the power to drive even the toughest pizza-eater to tears. 

 

 
 Click here for the full story 
 
 Dominos Pizza UK&amp;IRL plc has announced another exceptional set of results 
 
17th February 2010
 
 Domino’s Pizza UK&amp;IRL plc has announced another exceptional set of results with like-for-like sales growth of 8.4% across 501 mature stores, an increase in system sales of 16.0% to 406.9m and a record 55 new store openings. 

 



 Chris Moore, CEO, said:“We continue to succeed, even in the current harsh economic conditions, because of our unrelenting focus on the quality of our pizzas, intense devotion to service and by marketing to our customers when and where they want to order. 

 It is this passion that has delivered profit growth of 27.8% to 29.9m (2008: 23.4m) and that will continue to drive our business in years to come. 

 

 




 
 Click here for the full story 
 
 Papa John&apos;s UK gets new MD 
 
10th February 2010
	</body>
</document>
