<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001833" url="http://www.bettylabrancherealtor.com/property-listing/mls.php?cid=1023&amp;action=resultslist&amp;searchid=978&amp;testing=true" time="2012-07-12-17:37" support="1" score="0.0008829337315288389" bingtitle="Betty LaBranche Real Estate Inc." webtitle="Betty LaBranche Real Estate Inc.">
			<query id="000804" bing-rank="167"/>
	<description>... on the MA/NH border, minutes away from I-93 Exit 47 ... new Prime Retail/Office Building at Crown Place. ... Non Disclosure Required Fast Food Restaurant Rockingham County NH.</description>
	<body>
		Portsmouth 
100 Market St., Suite 103
Portsmouth, NH 03801
T: 603.766.1500
F: 603.766.1504 Exeter 
115 Water St.
Exeter, NH 03833
T: 603.772.3301
F: 603.772-3501
 Hampton Beach 
931 Ocean Blvd.
Hampton Beach, NH 03842
T: 603.926.4013
F: 603.926.4046
 
 
$3,500,000
Exeter NH
 View this listing 
 These flexible Class B spaces consist of 4,428 rsf on the first floor (Suite B) and 8,470 rsf on the second floor (Suite C). Bullpen areas, private offices, conference rooms, kitchenettes, private bathrooms for each unit and many other support areas highlight these oak trimmed office suites. Lots of windows and/or skylights for natural light. Rent is plus utilities only.
 
$3,000,000
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour Portsmouth - Business location, very high visibility off Portsmouth Traffic Circle, Route 1 Bypass South. Potential at this location for lease space and build site. This property offers medical practice, office use or business expansion opportunity. Don&apos;t miss out on rare corner location off Route 1 Bypass and Borthwick Avenue. 1,400 sq&apos; +/- to 5,616 sq&apos; +/- plus additional 1,600 sq&apos; +/- in detached garage office building. Take this opportunity to lease space in one of Portsmouth&apos;s premier locations!
 
$2,990,000
Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 62 Room Year Round Hotel With Large Full Service Convience Store. Covered Pool, Large Lobby and Office Suite, Breakfast Room, 7 Room Apartment. Laundry Room, Property Includes Additional Double Lot for Parking. Rare Opportunity to Own a Major Hotel in the Heart of Hampton Beach.
 
$2,500,000
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 This premium, first class office property is located in the dynamic southern New Hampshire community of Londonderry. It is surrounded by professional, business and medical office users actively participating in the vibrant economic environment the state is currently experiencing. The convenient country setting is only a street away from shopping centers, restaurants, town services and minutes to the states major highway systems. The structure is designed in the appealing Colonial Williamsburg style and set on a ridge overlooking a small natural pond and acres of grass. Currently, the building is operated as a corporate headquarters but can easily be configured as a multi-tenant facility to accommodate the most discerning occupants. The site plan allows for expanded parking and room for added amenities to satisfy a variety of corporate requirements.
 
$2,250,000
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 Rare opportunity to acquire a c.1950, 14,700SF brick, two story building on 40,000SF intown lot with onsite parking and views of the South Mill Pond, City Hall Hill&amp;City Recreation area. Sited adjacent to the District Court house, Junior High School, Portsmouth Fire Department and Citizens Bank this large, level lot in the Mixed Residential Office zone offers a development opportunity difficult to acquire within walking distance to Market Square. Mechanical systems, roofing and elevator have been well maintained.
 
$2,200,000
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 Classic downtown Portsmouth brick building located on Bow Street. Property has deep water frontage and a thirty foot dock on the Piscataqua River. Presently building is a mix of two floors of retail and two apartments. Wonderful outdoor space over looking the boat float and the river.
One of a kind opportunity.
 
$2,100,000
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Hard to find retail strip center for sale with 466 +/- feet of frontage on Route 28. Anchored by 7-11 and Derry Kitchen and bath. Economically sized units make it easy to fill vacancies. $316,000 in potential rents and $239,000 potential NOI for the facility. The 18 units allow for spreading of vacancy risk. The current mix includes many long standing tenants. Newly resurfaced parking lot offering plenty of parking. Excellent signage on Route 28.
 
$2,000,000
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 -Development Opportunity- Portsmouth Waterviews! 

 Three buildings on three lots among the finest residential condominiums in Portsmouth, with views of the Piscataqua River, Badgers Island, in close proximaty to Strawbery Banke, Prescott Park, and all that Portsmouth has to offer. This is the Premier end for residential development, commanding the highest prices per square foot. Bring me your developers for a tour. Fantastic area for mixed use development, retail, office, and whatever your imagination dictates. Portsmouth Awaits!
 
$1,999,900
Kingston NH
 View this listing 
 16.98 acres with over 1531&apos; frontage on Route 125 with curb cuts. Zoned C-2 with additional uses: supermarkets and grocery stores, financial institutions, multi-store retail complexes, office and office complexes, manufacturing and storage facilities, recreational facilities, materials distribution plants and lots more.
 
$1,800,000
Exeter NH
 View this listing 
 Investment opportunity, 100% Leased! Perfect 1031 Tax Deferred Exchange situation. Brand new Prime Retail/Office Building at Crown Place. Maintenance free construction, excellent exposure and curb appeal, great signage,and ample parking. The Epping Road/Rt 27 corridor is where Exeter&apos;s growth and expansion is vibrant.
 
$1,700,000
Salem NH
 View this listing 
 Locate your business here, great visibility with high traffic count. This property was originally designed as an high end automobile dealership. The property includes both sales and service facilities. Features include four service bays with glass observation area from above. Wall to wall tile upstairs, separate kitchen facility and hardwood in executive areas. The property has the potential for conversion such as medical office or specialty retail/high end office. This property also for lease.
 
$1,695,000
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Owner Financing available.The building is located next to a shopping center and other franchises Mc Donalds, ect. Along with 6.24 ac of land Build 40,000 with 200 parking. This property already has the drive thru.The building is located on the Hwy 93 corridor near the Mass border in Derry NH. on Crystal ave downtown. Has an 40 month existing lease. Building can also be purchased separate from land.
 
$1,695,000
Windham NH
 View this listing 
 Premier Windham Location for many busniess/residential uses! 2 Blds 60x150 Current Busines use as a HALL wiht heat/water/AC and 60x200 Horse/Storage Steele Barn- with no utilities- Rolling 40 Acre parcel abutts Windham Rail Trail! Road Frontage 600+ ft. Plus Rear 50&apos; access from Taylor Farm Rd. 
No Current Use! Great Opportunity for Development!
 
$1,695,000
Stratham NH
 View this listing 
 &quot;The Collectors Eye&quot; an historic destination in the Town Center is being offered for sale. Built in the 18th century, this unique property consists of the Main House, The Tannery,The Cobble House and the famous Collectors Eye Barn, a 24 stall, 2 story barn, operating as a retail antique shop. The Main House is currently owner occupied, The Tannery&amp;The Cobble house are fully rented and the Collectors Eye Barn is chock full of antique dealers and inventory. The Town Center zoning allows for many uses. Property is located on almost 4 acres of land to include a 2 acre Mill Pond. Property also includes a heated workshop overlooking the Pond. Great development potential opportunities! All interested parties to provide proof of financing prior to appointment.
 
$1,650,000
Windham NH
 View this listing 
 For Sale or Lease. Call for pricing. Great location on a busy road off of Exit 3 on I-93 and Route 111. Multiple units available with flexible floor plans. Perfect for office, lab, medical, education, fitness, health, beauty or light industrial use.
 
$1,625,000
Kingston NH
 View this listing 
 -Premier commercial development site located just off Route 125 near the Carriage Towne Plaza, Rockingham County Courthouse and abutting the Sears Logistics site and another parcel of 16.98 acres on Route 125. Currently a horse farm and retail space with 5107+/- sf colonial home with apartment, attached barns&amp;5+ stall horse barn with paddocks.
 
$1,600,000
Rye NH
 View this listing 
 Great opportunity to own a commercial/mixed use property on busy Route 1 in Rye, NH. The property currently consists of 3 retail units, 1 warehouse, and 4 residential apartments. Potential for condo conversion. Also, potential to subdivide off one buildable lot from existing lot. 100% occupied.
 
$1,600,000
Epping NH
 View this listing 
 This property is two lots combined to give you a tremendous amounts of parking and turn around area for trucks in your business. A total of 5 -16 foot doors, with 7314 sf of commercial space. Combination of store front 30X60&apos; and large heated metal building measuring 90x60&apos;.High ceilings giving you versatility for use.Rear building has floor drains, garage doors and is heated but not cooled. Front section is cooled and heated.
Possibilities of lease, rate would be $7000/mo.
 
$1,549,000
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 18 unit Garden style multi-family. Fully occupied with lease. Cash Cow!! Great Londonderry location!
 
$1,500,000
Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 Landmark hotel in prime location at Hampton Beach. Ocean view. 21 units (some with kitchenettes), 2-bedroom owner unit, staff room plus room for expansion. .31 acre parcel with 110&apos; of frontage on Ocean Blvd. Hampton Beach has won national recognition for its water cleanliness. State funded $14.5M redevelopment project is complete! Be part of the new Hampton Beach! Exceptional opportunity!
 
$1,495,000
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 REDUCED!! Highly Visible 7790 s/f retail free std. bldg. on 1.05 acres. Located at major highway exit. 38 parking spaces and easily accessible. This bldg. is equipped with display racks, 4 register stations and shopping carts. Located 1/4 mile from Exit 4. This bldg. is fully air conditioned and includes 650 s/f of warehouse. This location has great signage and is ready for retail. Property also available for lease at $16.24psf NNN.
 
$1,395,000
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Allows for many uses with 2400 sf of office in place and 8000 sf of high ceiling warehouse space. Bulding built in 2002 with updated sustems and ample parking all on 2.79 acres. Property is currently split 9into 8 units or can be combined for one user. SBA assumable loan to qualified users makes for easy financing.
 
$1,350,000
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 Tremendous opportunity for the right buyer/ operator includes business, land and buildings. Established used auto dealer in prime location in the seacoast region. Details released to qualified buyers upon execution of Confidentiality Agreement.
 
$1,300,000
Exeter NH
 View this listing 
 Custome Auto Body and Car Repair Shop since 1982, PLUS a 5 unit rental building. This 11,000+ sq.ft. commercial building sits directly on Main Street, and is the only auto repair facility on this side of town. Six over sized garage doors and 25 interior parking bays. Equipment not included with sale, separaetly negotiable. 5-unit multifamily included in Sale.
 
$1,300,000
Brentwood NH
 View this listing 
 Looking to locate in Southern New Hampshire? Here is your chance! 23 level acres near major intersection and in an area of expanding retail/service businesses. Walmart, Lowes are some of your neighbors. Long road frontage on busy Route 125, mostly cleared along highway, great visibility. Older bldg. at rear of property, not seen from road. Remarkable opportunity to implement your development plans.
 
$1,249,000
Exeter NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour The Green Gate campground and Banquet Hall was established in 1964 on 53.76 A. The property includes 109 campsites w/ water&amp;sewer&amp;electric meters, 2 bath houses, inground pool. Campsite office, store&amp;game room. The Banquet Hall has a capacity of 200, fully equipped bar, prep kitchen&amp;commercial kitchen. 
Apartment w 1 bed. Additional buildings, 2 septic systems&amp;well. Kayak&amp;canoe on the Exeter River.
 
$1,200,000
Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 10,000sq.ft.Ocean front lot with three retail units.Plenty of room to expand or build new.
 
$1,200,000
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 LAND-BUILDING-BUSY REPAIR BUSINESS WITH DEALER PLATE FOR SALE. 2.06 acre zoned commercial II of which .922 acres in Londonderry and 1.140 acres in Hudson. A 2500 s/f 2 bay garage, 16&apos; clg ht and 2-12x14 OH doors. Zoning permits retail office, light industrial and automotive. Plus 3 room office. Great exposure, ample parking and more. Currently business is equipment sales, service and repairs.
 
$1,200,000
Hampstead NH
 View this listing 
 Existing business and real estate......gives a whole new meaning to the expression, &quot;Turn-Key&quot;...full service restaurant, lounge and function room...Plenty of room for growth with catering and functions. FF&amp;E;in good to excellant condition....plenty of parking....
 
$1,110,000
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 Just off Exit 5, I-93 in North Londonderry! Up to 17,000 SF of warehouse/manufacturing. 1 dock, 3 doors. Near Airport and all major routes! Can be subdivided to a 6,500 square foot unit with one 14 ft door and a 10,500 square foot unit(doors and dock). Property available for Sale or Lease.
 
$1,060,000
Salem NH
 View this listing 
 53 Unit Multi Family; Condos / Apartment Approval. Two Buildings on 4 Acres of level land on the New Hampshire/Massachusetts Border. Water&amp;Sewer to come from Methuen, MA. No Wetlands
 
$999,000
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 A rare opportunity to own a building with over 25,0000 sq ft including a garage which houses 11-20 parking spots! With a prime location just three blocks to downtown, this stately brick building has many potential uses including condo conversion, office spaces or a spectacular show-room. Extra-tall ceilings and a gracious center-staircase create a grand feeling upon entering. There is a sprawling deck on the second level perfect for entertaining. Details abound throughout this unique building include hardwood floors with authentic trenail design, beautiful stained glass windows and extraordinary built-ins. The potential here is endless.....bring your creative ideas to this unique building located in the most desirable town on the Seacoast!
 
$995,000
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Excellent condition, warehouse/distribution facility with 1200 s/f office. Close to major N/S highway. Has minor tenant at will.
 
$995,000
North Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 Development Possibilities on this prime 3.4 acre site on busy Route 1 Seacoast corridor minutes to Portsmouth with 451 of frontage. Former RV dealership (land is currently vacant) and perfect for many uses including any type of vehicle sales or business needing wide open land area for display, storage or sales. High traffic counts. Back buildings totaling approx. 4,000 s.f. include 2-bay garage w/1 drive-through bay and freshly painted office area in great condition. Additional upstairs space could be used for office or apartment. Attached storage building. Front units are currently leased (approx. 3,315 s.f.) Site could be purchased and developed. Perfect for industrial condos or other uses. For sale or lease!
 
$995,000
Plaistow NH
 View this listing 
 Fantastic Opportunity for a growing business to own Commercial property and have great visibility on busy Route 125! This unique building consists of foyer area, coat room, full bar, huge function room with dance floor, full kitchen, bridal/reception room, two full bathrooms, newer furnace, ect. The exterior boasts newer roof, side garden area and plenty of on site parking. Currently utilized as a function facility however,the possibilities are endless! Additional food service equipment and storage container negotiable.
 
$990,000
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour -***EXCEPTIONAL***Custom Built 10,600 sf Industrial building in Londonderry, NH located adjacent to Manchester-Boston Regional Airport. Features include steel frame construction, a split-faced block exterior, 2 docks and 2 drive-in doors. With 6,400 sf of hi-bay warehouse area and 4,200 sf of office space with beautiful conference room, kitchen area, 4 baths, this property is desirable to manufacturing and distribution companies. Building is able to be split into 2 separate units. GREAT BUILDING, GREAT LOCATION! Seller is related to listing agent.
 
$975,000
Newton NH
 View this listing 
 Commute to work no longer, this listing not only offers a 10,000 square foot building, but also a well appointed four bedroom home. Just what have you been searching for. Endless possibilities with 3-phase electric and compressor. Shop area offers cement slab, 7 overhead garage doors 4 independent heating systems oil and gas. 2,000 square feet class-A office space located on the second floor with separate entrance. Situated on 8.9 Acres. To view more information on the home included in this sale please view MLS#4089805.
 
$975,000
Newmarket NH
 View this listing 
 Profitable Gas Station and convenience store with a full kitchen that provides Middle Eastern style food called Turkish Delights. This is a private brand operation and has no franchise fees or price restrictions. It is the lowest priced gas in the entire area and has a loyal following. Sales of gas are headed towards the 1 Million gallon level and at a 20 cent/gallon profit. Inside takes in $596,000 at a 40% profit level makes this a winner. It also features a 3 bedroom apartment that rents for $1500/month. confidentiality Agreement is required for all additional information.
 
$950,000
Salem NH
 View this listing 
 Salem - &quot;VFW Post 8546&quot; circa 1930 to present. Consists of 7,325+SF with 50+ Parking Spaces - includes bar/lounge&amp;function hall - all on 1.25 acres. Zoned Commercial[CIB] w/public Water&amp;Sewer. Located North of Rockingham Park on Rte 28 just beyond the junction of Rte 97&amp;Rte 28. 
Excellent exposure, high traffic count, prime for development!
 
$899,900
Exeter NH
 View this listing 
 The Gardner House, Circa 1826 -A rare opportunity to own an extraordinary 17 room building, virtually in the center of downtown Exeter next door to the town office and across the street from the town hall. A distinguished facade, with approximately 6100 SF, lends itself to many commercial uses. Sited in the heart of all the activity in downtown Exeter. Deep lot w/plentiful parking. Walking distance to Phillips Exeter Academy campus.
 
$895,000
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 -Owner Financing..The building is located next to a shopping center and other franchises Mc Donalds, ect. This property already has the drive thru. The building is located on the Hwy 93 corridor near the Mass border in Derry NH. on Crystal ave downtown. There is an existing lease for 40 months.
 
$879,900
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 Signage has Extreme High Visability due to location and 25,000 car count. Building right off Rte 102 and ample parking for small Retail business or office. Trustee is a licensed Real Estate Broker.
 
$879,000
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 OFFICE BUILDING 2 Acres Water&amp;Sewer Build 13000+ ft and Earn 7% on investment 
Office building for sale with 7% cap rate on 2 acres. Build 13,000+ feet, water, sewer at lot.
 
$838,500
Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 Announcing a wonderful opportunity to own a local landmark. The Victoria Inn is available for sale. Located on over 5 acres this property includes; (1) a 14 room inn with 7 bedrooms and 6.5 bathrooms, (2) a rear pavillion for functions (including outside bathrooms), (3) a cottage that has a year round upstairs apartment and first floor prep kitchen with garage, (4) 5 acres of land. Situated a short walk to North Beach and next to an attractive new neighborhood and other well cared for homes. Broker interest, contact for a private showing.
 
$829,000
Chester NH
 View this listing 
 This is ideal property for development. It&apos;s a corner lot with 1,200 feet of frontage on Route 102 and 1,700 feet of frontage on a secondary road. There are 9.8 acres zoned Residential and 24.65 acres zoned Limited Light Industrial, Commercial. There is approximately a 7 acre 40 foot hill of sand, gravel and crushable rock materials on the property. These materials can be used to reduce development costs on site.
These Materials can also be sold if local permits are obtained.
 
$815,000
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 -Mixed-use income/owner occupied building located on Rt 28. Main level currently leases for $2,275/mo. Parking in front&amp;around building w/ramp. 3 phase electric. Huge 2nd floor apt. leases for $1,250/mo. Crystal Avenue signage. Owner financing available.
 
$799,900
Salem NH
 View this listing 
 Vacant 9.29 acre lot zoned commercial on inbound side of Rte 38 (Lowell Road) from Pelham towards Route 93. Conceptual plan for a gas station/mini mart is available. Could be used for retail or light industrial condominums. Hight traffic count with over 900 feet of frontage. Owner/Broker
 
$779,900
Rye NH
 View this listing 
 A Wonderful Mixed-Use two level building on Route 1 between Hampton and Portsmouth, NH Owner occupied with additional tenant.

Owner&apos;s very profitable business is available for $100,000 plus inventory.
 
$750,000
Salem NH
 View this listing 
 Great opportunity! Ideal location for retail, bank, restaurant, strip mall, etc. Great frontage on Rt 28. High traffice, high visability. Easy access to I-93 Exit2. Town water/sewer.
 
$750,000
Exeter NH
 View this listing 
 The 2.19 acre cleared level lot in C2 commercial zone with 332 feet of frontage. 8,200 vehicles per day (2008). Principal permitted uses include retail services, business and medical offices, auto repair&amp;Sales. See attachment for complete list. Survey and Wetland Function and Values Assessment available. Public water and sewer.
 
$750,000
Kingston NH
 View this listing 
 This restaurant has been a landmark location of fine dining in Kingston, NH for generations. The owners are considering retirement and are quietly offering the establishment for sale. They are committed to operating the restaurant everyday just as they always have until consummating a sale. Included in the sale price and to be sold only in combination with the business and real estate is an extensive wine collection of approximately 5,000 +/- bottles of wine. (Inventory List Available with Broker) The structure itself totals over 16,285 +/- square feet of restaurant, retail and residential apartment space. There are two residential units on the second floor adding to the income potential of this property. The restaurant sits on .9 +/- acres. Please respect the ongoing business by not inquiring within. There will be no sign on the property.
 
$750,000
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 Attractive free standing 6,200 SF office building with recently renovated exterior and professional Landscaping. Great location for travelling to Manchester or Boston on I-93 and there is a bus stop across the street. Perfect location for a variety of businesses including retail and restaurant.
 
$750,000
Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 
 
$725,000
Exeter NH
 View this listing 
 Circa 1809, The Sullivan-Sleeper House is located in the heart of downtown Exeter. With 6,252+- sq. ft, the property has original woodwork/moldings throughout and is very well maintained. This Federal style building has three floors, 10 working fireplaces, 10 baths and a partially finished full basement area. There is also a 900 sq. ft. commercial space attached to the main building, currently leased as Cornucopia Wine and Cheese Market. The building could be converted to office space, or the 1st floor could be commercial/retail/or office space with the upper floors as rental units, or move your entire business/offices to the property and live onsite! Outdoor garden space in the rear with five designated parking spaces adjacent to the property. DO NOT INQUIRE WITHIN.
 
$709,000
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour Industrial Condo for sale in a recently constructed (2006) building with a close to the Airport Location. Attractive professional offices, Mezzanine areas for staging or storage. Two overhead doors. Sale listing consists of two condo units in the building. Perfect for an owner/investor to use have and lease the rest.
 
$695,000
Exeter NH
 View this listing 
 Ideal location for a Garden Center, Landscaping Business, or Business Offices with long road frontage and great visibility from Route 101. Zoned Neighborhood Professional, this 6 room, 3 bedroom home has a heated garage with an office attached and a one bedroom apartment above. An adjacent 2+ acre lot is available for an additional $85,000. With a possible subdivision, up to an estimated 3,000 sf building may be allowed to be built.
 
$695,000
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 BURSAW&apos;S PANTRY, a RTE 1 C-STORE AT PRIME CORNER W/LIGHT. GREAT RESTAURANT AND OR RETAIL POTENTIAL. HIGH TRAFFIC COUNT AND LARGE 3 BEDROOM APARTMENT and 1 bathroom apartment in Portsmouth. Over 2,100 s.f. with room for a restaurant or other retail use. Property is across the street from the new Service Credit Union, which will employ over 400+. The only way to&amp;from the SCU building will be through that light, as they will be blocking off the other street. Full dry basement for office use or storage. TOWN WATER&amp;SEWER!
 
$695,000
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 Prime downtown location in the heart of Portsmouths revitalization district and diagonally across from the new Port Walk development. Historic downtown Portsmouth is one of Americas top tourist destinations as well as one of the countrys most desirable place to live.

This two unit mixed-use property (residential and commercial) currently operates as a 64-seat restaurant (approved for 75-seats) with adjacent 2 bedroom apartment. High visibility on corner lot. CBB zoning permits a range of service, retail and office uses. Excellent parking opportunity with on site and abutting town parking lot. Town water&amp;sewer! Why lease when you can own!!

Please do not inquire within

REAL ESTATE ONLY BUSINESS NOT FOR SALE
 
$675,000
Salem NH
 View this listing 
 NEW PRICE&amp;LEASE OPTIONS!! Wonderful and unique opportunity to own this elegant Victorian style office building in Central Business District, Commercial/Residential, on .45acre corner lot. Approx 4500sqft with 3 separate rentable suites. Main office is currently owner occupied, used as professional office space. 2.5 stories and roughly 2184sqft, 8 rooms, 1.5 baths, loaded with charm. It has been completely renovated, original stain glass windows, woodwork and molding. Kitchen with granite counters, custom built-in cabinets, bookcases, 2 fireplaces, new carpeting, windows, central air and heat. 2 additional suites, one with approx. 1800sqft with 5 office spaces, waiting room, baths and kitchens. 2nd suite is approx 483sqft with 2 offices, bath and kitchen. Both recently renovated with fresh paint, carpeting, high speed internet cable. Deeded parking for 21+, town water/sewer. Prime location, minutes from Route 93 and Rockingham Mall. Also available for rent.
 
$674,900
Kingston NH
 View this listing 
 Prime location, high traffic count, former successful restaurant.Restaurant sale also offers single family home and additional land. Home needs rehab. Call listing agent for additional pamphlet.
 
$650,000
Northwood NH
 View this listing 
 Resort, Inn, Restuarant, lounge, function hall
Family run ince 1926. Features original antique house w/full restaurant&amp;dining; Function hall approx 4500 sq ft; Inn w/32 guest rooms most w/porch overlooking lake; Lounge w/bar, stone frplc,gameroom,baths; Owner&amp;staff quarters; private lakeside cottage; garages, service areas,etc- Set upon 6 beautiful acres w/1200&apos; +/- frontage on Jenness Pond (a sparkling clean 267 acre lake), private beach, boat launch, docks, rolling lawns, state ski mobile trails. All located 30 miles to Portsmouth,17 miles to Concord, 1.3 miles to rte 107, 3 miles to rte 4, 20 miles to NH Motor Speedway, 7 lakes nearby, 32 miles to Gunstock, NH ski mobile trails on site. This property may be well suited for other uses such as assisted living, rental/condo conversion, church, group or company retreat, lakefront land development...but has had many generations of families returning year after year with year round draw
 
$649,000
Newton NH
 View this listing 
 Fully permitted 22-25 unit age restricted, condominium development. Infrastructure - roads, septic, well, underground utilities is complete. Ten units are completed, five of the ten are sold and occupied. Fully permitted for an additional 12 units. The Town of Newton has approved another three units but the three need plans to be submitted. Completed units are 1496 sf, hardwood 1st floor, 2 to 2 3/4 baths, gas fireplace, one car garage, full basement, first floors are constructed to universal design.
 
$649,000
Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour FOR SALE OR LEASE! Terrific space available for professional office, school, day care and more! Extensive renovations and remodeling have been completed in the past few years. Main building (circa 1920) houses offices, classroom,&amp;dining hall with commercial kitchen. 1985 addition has been converted to classrooms, offices, nurses office, central control office, large conference room, science lab&amp;art room. State of-the-art camera/security system&amp;fire protection/sprinkler system. Great location within minutes to commuting routes and walking distance to schools&amp;town services. Lease options for the whole building or can be split up - call for details! Seller is a NH licensed Real Estate Agent.
 
$639,900
Raymond NH
 View this listing 
 Owner Occupy or Invest in 6 Warehouse/Industrial Units on Route 107. Building is currently totally leased with two units becoming available in April 2012. Each unit consists of 1350+/- sq feet with a 14&apos; door and 16&apos; ceiling height. Units are made complete with office space and bathroom. Units are separately metered for propane and dedicated 200 AMP service. Close to major routes. Plenty of parking.
 
$625,000
Exeter NH
 View this listing 
 Attractive colonial built as a residence in 1890, has been office building since 1987. Single story addition in 1990, opportunity to add 2nd floor or possibly create a roof top deck for al fresco dining. Flexible C-1 zoning permits most uses. Easy walk to downtown or the Academy. Seller will consider owner financing. Also available for lease, $4500/mo. modified gross.
 
$614,400
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 Great Visibility 16,000 cars a day excellent location for this 5.44 ac building offering both an excellent showroom&amp;storage space for materials. For the new business owner or all in one business&amp;apartment upstairs also available.
 
$599,900
Windham NH
 View this listing 
 REDEVELOPMENT OPPORTUNITY! Newly re-zoned to CDA, this property is located on Route 28 on the Windham/Derry town line. With 7.4+/- acres of land and approximately 288ft of frontage, this property is suited for retail, outside sales areas, business or professional offices, restaurants, service stations, etc. Currently a farm, there is plenty of pristine land to develop.
 
$599,900
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 Located in the heart of Londonderrys medical and business corridor, this free standing building is close to the high traffic intersection of Route 102 and Mammoth Road, just minutes from Exit 4 on I-93 and the Manchester-Boston Regional Airport. There is visibility from busy Route 102 and great signage. It is currently the home of Training Effects Fitness, but other possible uses include retail, medical, office or a dance studio. The interior offers lots of open space and can be subdivided.
 
$599,000
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Prime retail property. Recently closed Kentucky Fried Chicken restaurant with drive-thru. 50 seats, 30 parking spaces. 26,000 cars per day. Equipment is available. Franchise business is not for sale--Real estate only. Bring your own franchise or tenant. Dunkin donuts across the street. CVS, Walgreens a 7 iron shot away! Very motivated Seller!
 
$595,000
Raymond NH
 View this listing 
 Drastic Price Reduction!! 6,700 SF first class office/showroom building with separate 5000SF Metal building with drive in door and loading dock. Property is near Jackson lumber, Trucking Company and WalMart distribution center. This location is central to all the major population centers in NH and New England. This property is ideal for any corporate office distribution center. The office building has recently been updated with new Heating and Air conditioning system, windows and roof. The Medal building is clear span with 24 foot ceilings in the middle. Property has 3- Phase power. Just off exit 4 Route 101 for a great location. 8.3 acres for expansion.
 
$578,000
Kingston NH
 View this listing 
 Over 17 acres with over 484 feet of frontage on busy Route 125 in Kingston, near the Plaistow town line. C-3 zone allows for most commercial uses. State approved driveway, plus a curb cut in the future median strip. One multi-use building currently on the property.
 
$575,000
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Owners retiring after 40 years of operating this wholesale/retail antique business. Property consists of three buildings,a unique 1840&apos;s barn that has been converted into a sprawling retail showroom, a storage building with a full loft, and a small woodworking shop, totaling over 15,000 sf of floor space.

Located approx 1.5 miles east of the Derry Traffic Circle on Route 102.
 
$575,000
Stratham NH
 View this listing 
 Superb location - corner lot w/ 1.87 acres on Rte. 33/108. This wonderful lot has great visibility with a high traffic count. 283&apos; frontage on 33&amp;455&apos; on Bunker Hill Ave. Abuts town offices and police station. Antique colonial on site in need of restoration or removal. Zoned professional office/residential. Come build your office complex here.
 
$569,000
Seabrook NH
 View this listing 
 Net leased investment property, currently under favorable long term lease to high quality national tenant, with extensions and escalations.. Showroom and two story office/ retail. Recent tenant&amp;owner improvements include new furnace, roof, flashings, central air, landscaping and internal&amp;exterior painting. Excellent signage on high traffic Route 1 just north of MA line in tax free NH! Plenty of paved parking. Retail neighbors include Walmart, Home Depot, Lowes, Kohls, Starbucks, Applebees, Chilis and more. Full investment package available.
 
$550,000
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 Grandfathered residential use allowing for 15 foot set back using existing structure.
 
$549,900
South Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 Impressive, Renovated Prime Office With Renovated Residential Rental Unit Above. 5 Large Offices With Expansive Meeting Room, Large Kitchen, Bath, Outdoor Patio, Separate Entrances and Full, Dry Basement. Great Access Along Nh/ma Border. T1&amp;Cat 5 Throughout.
 
$549,500
Chester NH
 View this listing 
 Mixed use building.. fully equipped with sprinklers, 40 + parking spots, Used to be a restaurant and at one point school. Highly visible and accessable to route 93 and route 101..Needs some tlc. 28+ acres of land w/ possibility of subdivision 3-6 house lots!!! A must See! **Expenses listed depend on usage**
 
$529,900
Newmarket NH
 View this listing 
 Investment Opportunity!! 7 unit mixed use building Four (4) retail units and three (3) residential units on the corner of Main St.&amp;Route 108. Reconditioned, remodeled&amp;upgraded included new fire alarm system, rubber roof, thermo pane windows&amp;vinyl siding! 100% leased with great rental history. Privately owned parking lot plus town/street parking. Abuts Durham/UNH and is considered a college town. Town water&amp;sewer. Financials available.
 
$525,000
Windham NH
 View this listing 
 Just off Rte 93 Exit #3 and Rte 111 in Windham, NH you will find an excellent signage exposure for your company. This building offers a nice view, elevator to second floor, large open area, close to major shopping center, restaurants and much more. It is avilable for lease and/or sale.
 
$525,000
Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 Fantastic investment opportunity in the heart of Hampton Beach! Restaurant + 4 units. Restaurant is equipped and seats 90. Rental units: one 3 bedroom, two 1 bedroom and 1 studio. High traffic location near site of $14.5 State complex. Ocean views! Hampton Beach has received a 5 star rating for water quality.
 
$500,000
Raymond NH
 View this listing 
 All offers will be considered for this great site with 3 existing building and space available for more buildings. 600&apos; road frontage on Rt 27 ( aka Rt 101 loop). Storage buildings : 115&apos;x 45 &apos; barn, 180&apos; x 25&apos; garage with sliding doors, 130 &apos;x 15 &apos; open shed shelter. Opportunity to expand your business as needed with out moving. Owner will consider some owner financing , sale of business and sale of inventory( additional) See paper clip for allowed uses.
 
$499,900
Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 INVESTMENT OPPORTUNITY!! 10% CAP!! Own real estate with positive cash flow. Seven (7) unit mixed use property. 100% occupancy with great rental history. Hurry, this one wont last in this crazy financial market! Town water&amp;sewer. No sign on property, please do not inquire within.
 
$499,900
Epping NH
 View this listing 
 VERY NICE level area for pad site. Great exposure, Possible owner financing available. This location is ideal for a retail spaces&amp;or strip mall. Many uses permitted. Heavily traveled,near intersection&amp;gas station. Additional lot of 20 acres in rear can be purchased seperately. Public water has been brought up near the site. Subject to a lot line adjustment.
 
$499,900
Epping NH
 View this listing 
 This location is ideal for a smaller retail users, great for drive thru, storage units, car wash or car sales. Small office is currently on the property and can removed. Many uses permitted. Heavily traveled, near intersection&amp;gas station. Additional lot of 20 acres in rear can be purchased seperately. Public water has been brought up near the property for possible furture hook up. Subject to a lot line adjustment.
 
$499,900
Plaistow NH
 View this listing 
 Previosly South East Plumbing. This Beautiful Victorian home PLUS 2 story barn, holds 9+ cars and plenty of storage above. Home has 3 large bedrooms, 2 gas fireplaces, enormous kitchen, formal dining room and living room, great room with bar and loft, 3rd bedroom has a separate staircase. Hardwood floors, tile baths, too many features to mention.
 
$499,000
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 Fantastic retail location for sale in heart of downtown Portsmouth. Currently the home of City&amp;Country Home Furnishings. Real Estate and Business for sale. Store has excellent reputation for quality and service with numerous repeat customers. This opportunity wont last!!!!
 
$499,000
Hampton Falls NH
 View this listing 
 High Traffic, High Visibility :: 4.48 acre development parcel on Route 1 in Hampton Falls, just north of the Seabrook town line in tax free NH. Business district B zoning allows for a myriad of uses. Corner lot with 417&apos; frontage. Don&apos;t miss this opportunity. 21,000 vehicles per day, 2009 NHDOT
 
$499,000
Epping NH
 View this listing 
 2 bay/4 car garage/shop with an additional 24 X 21 ft. tented slabbed storage space upon entering the driveway just off of 125 in Epping NH. The shop is a business that has many licenses with the town. The current primary use of the business is for: Motorcycle Sales, Auto Sales, RV Sales (No class A), 4 Wheel, All Terrain Sales, Repairs,&amp;Inspections. The home is on the same land and is situated in the back, just about 500 feet from the shop. It is secluded and very private. There is a 3/4 wrap around porch attached to the house. The home is a ranch, which has 3 bedrooms, 2 full baths, living room, dining room and a large fully applianced kitchen with lots of cabinet space.
 
$499,000
Atkinson NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour Stand alone office building in Office/Industrial Park on 1.85 Acres. Total of 4331 sqft. on main level and additional 1000 sq.ft. in LL that is heated and good for storage or assembly work area. Loading Dock. Could easily be converted to two units one with 2000 sqft and the other 2331 sqft. Seperate utilities already in place. 3 baths with additional 3 baths possible. Central Air.
 
$475,000
Northwood NH
 View this listing 
 Huge development potential; 23.68 acres, surveyed and tested. Two buildings over from the new North East Credit Union and Dollar Store currently under construction. Currently a single family home and barn on the property. Was subdivided into 4 lots in 2003, no lots were conveyed. Sale subject to Planning Board approval.
 
$469,000
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 7 Unit Mixed Multi- 3 Retail Units and 4 Residential Units
 
$468,000
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 Inside is open with Post and Beam against brick walls.
Parking is right in front. In busy commercial area.
 
$450,000
Raymond NH
 View this listing 
 Unique Property - 1000ft of frontage on Route 156&amp;Ham Road, two curve cuts, a 7680 SF Office/Showroom/Warehouse
plus approx. 3200 SF Home (see MLS#4058882)on 3.40A, C-1 zoned. Building offers heated and cool storage areas, three offices, showroom, small apt., 3 Overhead Doors w/one having access to full basement. 
Got an internet business that you have out grown the home or needing that property that will work for both commercial and residential purposes?
 
$450,000
Plaistow NH
 View this listing 
 Perfect Location for Contractor...

...Great property for contractors or tradesmen (Plumbers, Electricians, Printers, etc.). This half acre plus property has approximately 3000 SF of renovated workshop with additional renovated spaces above for use as office/warehouse. This property is located a short distance from Route 125, on the way to Plaistow Center .
 
$450,000
Seabrook NH
 View this listing 
 Honey Dew Donuts Franchise :: Profitable Honey Dew franchise with primary and satellite locations. Located in prime location, in excess of 20,000 vehicles per day, on a major retail artery, and across from major proposed shopping center. Satellite location on Route 1 in Portsmouth, NH with similar location attributes. Business has wholesale accounts as well as retail. Sale includes all furniture, fixtures and equipment, and business rights as allowed in franchise agreement.
 
$450,000
Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 First New Water Front Commercial Space on Hampton Beach in over 25 Years. 6+ Units Below 36 Unit Condomindium Project Being Built for May 2013 Occupancy by Green and Company. Directly Across from Ocean, Covered Walkway Outside Beautiful Glass Doors. This Is a Year Round Building Being Offered.
 
$450,000
Northwood NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour Very high traffic count area. Yards from a busy intersection making this property a great potential commericial endeavor for someone. Land is a lovely combination of fields, woodlands, brook -have a farmstand, doggy day care/grooming or in-home business. Existing house is in need of some updating and barn would be easily converted to a variety of needs. 42 acres on Route 4 -hard to come by!
 
$450,000
Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 Convenience Store with Owner Apartment and attached One Bedroom Apartment with separate access.Convenience Store has large walk in cooler, new HVAC unit, and upgraded electrical. Sales Price includes Business without inventory. Financial information available with acceptable non-disclosure agreement.
 
$449,900
Kensington NH
 View this listing 
 Residential property in commercial district! Property consists of a 3 bedroom home, a workshop/garage which could be rented, a two story barn which also could be rented. Many options for the owner of this property. Present owner has conceptual plan for 12 commercial condo&apos;s. 2009 traffic reports 3900 vehicles per day on Rte 150 and another 3800 vehicles per day on Rte 107.
 
$449,900
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 Brand New Retail Space in Downtown Portsmouth. Nice big windows, street level,with close proximity to the Square. This space is clean, crisp, wide open, with all new systems. Ready to occupy......move your business here,
put on the finishing touches, and open your doors!
Broker interest.
 
$429,000
Kingston NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour -Fabulous investment opportunity located on the Plaines of Kingston consisting of three commercial/business units and three apartments. This well maintained property comes with many recent upgrades including septic 2007, roof 2004, well 2009, new concrete front stairs, parking area pavement. Deleaded under State of NH guidence. All six units have been recently renovated.
 
$425,978
Newmarket NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour Price Drop! Unique Waterfront Land Opportunity in wonderful location. The last piece in the puzzle of Newmarket&apos;s downtown and waterfront development. One of the best locations on the Lamprey River. Approvals in place for 7 two bedroom condos, 3-1/2 stories on 11,000+/- SF. Private double ramp access to the 90ft tidal dock. Wonderful views from all levels up and down the Lamprey River, and across to the protected conservation land on the other side of the river. All tides access to Great Bay and the Atlantic Ocean. Only a few steps and you will be wandering through beautiful downtown Newmarket, with its wonderful mix of retail shops and eateries. Boating, Kayaking, and nature trails conveniently on the doorstep. If you have the vision, this can be your crown jewel. Annual community activities are focused on the waterfront area, including the Heritage Festival, Olde Home Weekend and Oyster Festival. Zoning allows for many commercial opportunities.
 
$425,000
Exeter NH
 View this listing 
 Great space for an in-home business. Potential use of this well maintained New Englander includes small business or medical/law practice and residential. New windows, new furnace, kit&amp;more. Turn around driveway&amp;large parking area for business use. Beautifully landscaped yd w/patio. Lots of privacy yet great visibility for your busniness. Truly a must see. Lots of possibilities here. Variances from town may be needed depending on the business.
 
$425,000
Rye NH
 View this listing 
 Commercial/retail Condominium Unit With High Visibility on Ocean Blvd and Directly Accross from Jenness Beach. Has Been Operated As Convenience Store With Breakfast/lunch Counter for over 50 Years. Most Equipment and Furnishings Included in Sale. Leased Thru April 2015.
 
$425,000
Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 Development opportunity for this 2.64 acre parcel tucked back from Route 1 (Lafayette Road) in a B zone. Total Upland 2.15 Acres. Access to parcel is a right of way over a Route 1 frontage parcel.Could be ideal site for an office park,condominium project,residential apartment building, office building,retail use,construction company,storage facility - all with Zoning Board permission.
 
$424,900
Newmarket NH
 View this listing 
 LIVE WHERE YOU WORK,LOVE WHERE YOU LIVE!Wonderful opportunity to own this extensively updated and upgraded New Englander in a high visibility location,zoned in-home business. Boasting almost 3000 sf,the house includes an 850 sf office space-easy commute. Parking is plentiful, including a newer 2-car garage with a second story for storage. Inside, house has a grand gourmet kitchen, featuring a gas cooktop plus double-wall oven. Gleaming granite counters/island provide plenty of work space while custom maple cabinets store all your staples. Did I mention the fantastic first floor laundry area in the great family mudroom entrance w/an extra fridge&amp;more storage? Or how about the ability to have 2 units at the property,in-law or income? 3 charming bedrooms grace the 2nd floor along with 2 baths including an exquisite full Master Bath. A comfortable family room provides escape on the 2nd floor. Finished third floor for guest bedroom/playroom.Outdoor oasis,well landscaped and private!
 
$419,000
Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 Four unit property consisting of year round restaurant, three bedroom 1 1/2 bath apartment, one bedroom apartment w/ loft, and two bedroom year round cottage. 3BR has laundry hook-up and gas fireplace. 1BR has laundry hook-up. Decks on cottage and house.
 
$400,000
Newmarket NH
 View this listing 
 These spacious second floor office suites (Suite 201- 1,421+/- s.f. and Suite 202 - 4,348 +/- s.f.) in The Commons at Kent Place boast an elegant finish and convey a professional image. Kent Place is located right off of Main Street and offers easy access to Route 108 and all major highways. It is located in the heart of downtown Newmarket within walking distance of shops, dining and amenities. Suites have multiple private offices, conference rooms, open work areas, a kitchen/break room. three restrooms and a reception area. Building features an elevator and ample parking. High speed internet is available. Suites can also be sold separately (call for individual pricing of each suite). NOTE THAT SUITE 201 IS LEASED THROUGH 4/30/13.
 
$399,900
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 Great opportunity to own over 2700 SF of office space in the hub of downtown Portsmouth. Two units combined into one on the second floor at 10 Vaughan Mall on Congress Street. Central Air. Heat and electric included in condo fee.
 
$399,900
Epping NH
 View this listing 
 This location is ideal for a smaller retail users, great for drive thru, car wash or car sales. Many uses permitted. Heavily traveled, near intersection&amp;gas station. Additional lot of 20 acres in rear can be purchased seperately. Public water has been brought up near the property for possible furture hook up.
 
$399,900
Exeter NH
 View this listing 
 Prime visibility from Route 101 and Route 27! Zoned C-3, endless possibilities, possible build to suit. Oversized garage/workshop, freestanding 2 bedroom residence on site.
 
$399,000
Stratham NH
 View this listing 
 Beautiful Victorian home with many period features. This property was renovated in the late 1990&apos;s. Lovely red birch floors in formal areas. The large updated kitchen has cherry cabinets, tile floors, chef&apos;s gourmet stove and a free standing island. 5 bedrooms upstairs and separate garage with heated office. Nicely landscaped. This property was granted in 3/11 to become part of town center district which provides more opportunties for multi use purposes.
 
$399,000
Deerfield NH
 View this listing 
 -Gateway to Deerfield on corner of busy Rt. 43 in southern Deerfield with lots of drive by traffic. Large 3,858 sq. ft. 10 room colonial with 7 fireplaces and 4 level barn. Property was site for several businesses, apartment. Great location for new commercial business, home business and/or small farm. The property is only 18 miles to the Manchester-Boston Regional Airport in Manchester, NH, and less than 14 miles to Manchester itself. Route 43 is a state road, with easy access to Route 101 and exit 3 in Candia, less than 5 miles away.
The property features a historical 1810 colonial 11 room built for gentry, in the old style, on a 3.6-acre lot.
4 level barn includes just under 4,100 sq. feet of space that used to include an electronics shop with its own driveway cut, an apartment that included an artists studio. The barn has lots of wiring for power (used for the electronics business), and its own heating system. This would be an ideal, centrally-located site for a business.
 
$395,000
Salem NH
 View this listing 
 5,700 SF open light industrial space (1,500 sf office, 2,700 sf manufacturing, 1,500 sf mezanine). (1) 14&apos; overhead door and (1) 8ft dock. Municipal water/sewer and 208V 3-phase power. Space can accommodate a variety of uses.
 
$395,000
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Free standing 6000s/f stand alone industrial building with 1500s/f office, loading dock, town facilities and more. Located on 1 acre in industrial park setting. Zoned for manufacturing, industrial and retail. &quot;A Rare Find&quot; Excess power 400 amps and more.
 
$389,900
Hampton Falls NH
 View this listing 
 Luxurious Route 1 office building completely renovated in 1995 w/two levels of office space plus a separate garage and basement in a high traffic location w/excellent signage and visibility. Generous parking. 3 separate condo units in building being sold as a package consisting of 3,108 total sf(Unit 15-1716sf, Unit 14-720sf and Unit 13- 672sf). Main unit features executive office suite with custom cabinetry, Subzero refrigerator, wet bar, walk in closet and separate task/network desk/built in. Suite has adjoining conference room and both rooms are accessed by a reception room with marble, wood burning fireplace. Crown moldings, wainscotting and recessed lighting throughout. 2nd floor is open w/private offices, vaulted ceilings and separate bullpen area. Easy access to I95/Route 101. Rear units feature sep entrances, vaulted ceilings, private baths, motorized skylights and HW floors. All units can open up as one unit or be rented separately. Trustees are licensed RE estate brokers
 
$389,900
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 Great exposure on Route 102 for this newer, freestanding, professional office building. Stylish finishing touches with Marble foyer, open stair case, lots of hardwood and brick front. 4 finished levels of space with almost 5000 SF of total space. Also available for rent.
 
$385,000
Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 Very well located commercial building on Route 1 (Lafayette Road) in downtown Hampton, NH. Formerly leased as a convenience store, this versatile block building would be suitable for many retail uses. Over 20,000 vehicles per day in traffic with many retail neighbors including Dunkin Donuts, Rite-Aid, CVS, Citizens Bank, Provident Bank, the 401 Tavern, Las Olas and more. Property has an existing pylon sign, building signage, parking lot, and designated loading area.
 
$379,900
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 Brand New Retail Space in Downtown Portsmouth. Nice big windows, street level,with close proximity to the Square. This space is clean, crisp, wide open, with all new systems. Ready to occupy......move your business here,
put on the finishing touches, and open your doors!
Broker interest.
 
$375,000
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Multi use consisting of 912 s/f 2-3 bedroom home and 466 s/f finished L.L. 1000 s/f Wood frame warehouse, 3.46 acres. Neighborhood land uses residential, sheet metal fabricator, self-storage, etc. Permitted uses include light industrial, self-storage, warehouse and more. Previously designed for a 13000 s/f warehouse bldg., 5 units, 2400 s/f each unit size. Over 430&apos; rd. frtg., well and septic. Seller will lease house and wood frame warehouse for $1600/MO+UT for up to 2 years.
 
$375,000
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour Terrific corner lot makes for a great location in downtown Derry. Signalized, 18,000 cars/day, .5 miles to I-93. Perfect for high exposure offices such as accountants, attorneys, family counseling, broker&apos;s etc. 5050sq/ft., Approx. 2,500 S.F. of office space with potential 2 residential income units, 1,200 S.F./unit, 24 parking spaces, good access and egress. Completely renovated exterior, extensively renovated heating, electrical and plumbing. 3 mile radius: 30,010 population, 11,685 rooftops. Grocery/merch $&apos;s 165,000.000.+
 
$370,000
Epping NH
 View this listing 
 A great place to live and work. Custom home with an over sized &quot;garage&quot; currently used as a wood workshop. Need to bring your trucks and equipment home? Zoning is general commercial industrial with easy access to 101 for customers and shipping. See listing 4142567
 
$369,000
Exeter NH
 View this listing 
 Owner says SELL! Price drastically reduced on this completely renovated and upgraded 1790 Antique Colonial. Low maintenance and beautiful! All new systems, windows, vinyl siding, new carpet, central air and loads of storage. Wide pine floors. Great location on medical mile. Up to 7 private offices, conference room, bullpen&amp;partial kitchen. Double garage. For sale/lease/lease option. Town water&amp;sewer. Easy highway access just off of I-95 and Route 101.
 
$369,000
Newmarket NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour Large Parcel with Two Building Lots in great location with easy access to downtown Newmarket. Conceptual site plan for 5,000+/- SF on Lot 1, and 7,000+/- SF building on Lot2 (conceptual site plans attached). Great Rte 108 location surrounded by Irving Gas, MacDonald&apos;s, Car wash, and other businesses on busy Route 108 in Newmarket. Zoning allows for Retail, Office, Daycare, Hotel, Recreation facility, Health club, Restaurant, Wholesale, Light Manufacturing, and more. Conceptual site plan allows for 7,000+/- SF building on this lot, with shared access access from Rte 108 and ample parking. Lots can be sold separately subject to Subdivision. See MLS #&apos;s 4022651 and 4075730.
 
$369,000
Danville NH
 View this listing 
 Back on the market at a reduced price, this property has many possibilities. Currently used as a successful lessons and boarding barn, it could be modified to accomodate a manufacturing business, storage or cottage industry. It has a small home attached to the barn and two extra house lots right on Rte 111. A commercial size septic was recently installed and it is very close to the major highways and the seacoast.
 
$359,900
Seabrook NH
 View this listing 
 Renovated circa 1776 office/retail building on corner lot on highly visible Route 1 in Seabrook opposite Demoulous&apos; Market Basket and less than one mile from Interstate 95. Ideal office or retail (currently both). Past uses included successful antique furniture retail store. Updated substantially with all new mechanical systems while retaining the original period antique moldings, fireplaces and original features. Property can be leased as well at $10/sf NNN.
 
$359,900
Salem NH
 View this listing 
 Industrial condominium unit for sale or lease at 26 Keewaydin Drive in Salem, NH, conveniently located right off Exit 2, I-93. This flexible unit is suitable for manufacturing, warehousing or distribution and can be combined. The surrounding neighbors consist of high profile corporations, hotels/conference centers, health clubs, financial services, as well as two regional colleges.
 
$350,000
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 2400 s/f, 2 story office bldg. on OWN lot, svcd. by town water&amp;private septic. Second level divided into 7 offices&amp;includes wtg/recep, bath, 3 offices, conference, lge. 12x18 work room, break room&amp;storage area. Down are 2 open spaces, tastefully decorated, one 17x26 area w/tile floor, one 29x26 fully carpeted, track lighting, bath, kitchen, counter area w/sink. Lge dble. door in addition to front door entry. 40 s/f signage, marquee. Many permitted uses includes office/retail. Close to Exit 4, I-93. For Sale: $350,000. and owner will negotiate. Occupying second level.
 
$350,000
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 A rare opportunity presents itself to acquire the highly acclaimed, successful restaurant in the heart of the Portsmouth entertainment district. This restaurant boasts a casual, lively atmosphere for early or late dining and drinks. 

All furniture, fixtures, equipment, trade names and other business assets included in this sale. Attractive lease terms available in this prime location just outside Market Square, taking advantage of the location without the onerous Market&amp;Congress Street occupancy cost. 

Very strong financials, very strong net income. This is an unusually exceptional opportunity for the right restaurateur!

Confidential listing, details provided after signing and acceptance of a Confidential Non Disclosure Agreement.
 
$350,000
Salem NH
 View this listing 
 A potential for a Retail, professional office use &quot; if approved by the Town of Salem, NH.&quot; Corner lot, next to a large parcel connected to Homestead and Rte-97. This property may be a perfect location for a Professional office, Medical, Convenience Store and much more. It is located at the New Hampshire and Massachusetts State lines.
 
$350,000
Brentwood NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour -Large Commercial/Industrial property with existing buildings located in Brentwood on Route 125. Numerous possibilities to bring your business to this great central Southern , NH location. Heated office, enclosed garage space with high ceiling are some of the amenities.
 
$349,900
Exeter NH
 View this listing 
 Wonderful opportunity to own a property that can be continued as a Convenience store ( same owner since 1957) or be used for any professional who would want exposure at a full traffic light. Property has two apartments on the second floor to pay your mortgage. Separate utilities. Plenty of parking around the building. Phillips Exeter Academy abuts the property in the rear. Great Location with full traffic light and only a short walk to the Exeter Hospital. Any Doctors out there? Could be reconfigured for more apartments by converting the Store and attic area into more apartments. The property is sound but needs updating on the first floor. The apartments have new windows and doors in last few years. New Roof recently. High demand area for what ever you need!!!!
 
$349,000
Rye NH
 View this listing 
 1.01 Acres of land with 150&apos; of frontage on busy Route 1 location zoned commercial. 1/2 mile from the Portsmouth town line. Mixed use zone allows for commercial or residential. Existing 2 bedroom with separate attached office or workshop. Excellent visibility on busy Route in shopping district with high traffic counts. Perfect for development or home/office business. Town water at street.
 
$349,000
Epping NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour 2007 Commercial Office. 9.2 Acres. Fenced In Parking Lot To Accommodate 20+ Vehicles. 3 Rooms, 2 Half Bathrooms On The First Floor. Full Basement, Commercial Septic And Well. Framed In 2nd Floor With Potential 3-4 Rooms, 2 Full Bathrooms Already Wired And Plumbed In. 18 x 36 Garage To Easily Fit 2 Cars.
 
$329,900
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 1.11+/- acre parcel located in flex. ind/comm zone&amp;can be utilized in many ways. The structure is currently a three unit facility. 1 unit is res. 3 bed home w/ deceptively modern interior. A 2nd unit, an efficiency, is perfect for added income. 3rd commercial unit was recently used as R.E. office. Also has storage on 2 levels of garage&amp;barn.
 
$325,000
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour Ground floor commercial office/retail condominium in the historic Federal Row Condominium, FHA- Gas with Central A/C, fireplace and brick wall, water view of harbor and draw bridge, large basement storage, shared courtyard in rear, potential to lease 1 or 2 parking spaces from Rosa Restaurant. Broker is Trustee.
 
$325,000
Kingston NH
 View this listing 
 Over 3.01 acres with over 259 feet of frontage with 26X32sf buliding with new septic system on busy Route 125 in Kingston, near the Plaistow town line. C-3 zone allows for most commercial uses. State approved driveway, plus a curb cut in the future median strip. Building is currently used as a retail store with an apartment on the second floor. Store can be converted back to a garage.
 
$319,900
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 Commercial space condominium. New construction for sale or lease. Prime street level space for Retail, Restaurant or Office. Huge windows, high ceilings great visibilty&amp;high traffic. Steps to Market Square. Flexible floor plan. Space can be enlarged or contracted. Property available for owner/tenant buildout.
 
$317,900
Plaistow NH
 View this listing 
 C2 ZONING, 12,000 DAILY TRAFFIC COUNT, IDEAL LOCATION AND LAYOUT FOR PROFESSIONAL OFFICES! Tastefully appointed historic renovation with many vintage features. Refinished wide board flooring, coiffured ceilings, ornamental tin, original hardware, tongue-and-groove woodwork and custom handmade cabinetry blend seamlessly with a fresh decor and modern amenities including updated baths, tile, and granite for a &quot;best of both worlds&quot; environment. Updated maintenance/systems include new electrical, plumbing&amp;heating, newer windows, new insulation and new perimeter drainage. Large workshop (or garage) with electrical&amp;wood stove plus separate shed provide tons of storage. Multiple entrance layout, ample parking (8+ spaces) and high visibility at this &quot;Gateway to NH&quot; location known as &quot;Bradley&apos;s Corner.&quot;
 
$315,000
Newton NH
 View this listing 
 19 acres with possibilty of subdividing. Property includes a 3 bedroom home, commercial warehouse. Great opportunity to work at home.
 
$304,995
Raymond NH
 View this listing 
 Business allowed with permit. Previous plumbing business.
39x50 barn,heated +septic connection,barn extension 13x42, 200 amp service. Stairs to Loft area.Door height 13&apos;+/-.
Ranch house w/2c attached garage, full basement, 3br,2ba,propane fireplace,hot air heat + c a/c.fully applianced +washer/dryer+farmers porch&amp;deck;,irrigation sys.fully landscaped.See Res.MLS#4147946
RV FRIENDLY.
 
$299,000
Exeter NH
 View this listing 
 The 1,438 SF 1 1/2 story building is on a well traveled street (8,200 VPD - 2008 NH DOT Traffic Count) offering high visibility and 10 parking spaces. Potential uses include retail services, business and medical office, daycare and by special exception, residential conversion. On the main floor is a reception and retail area, a bathroom and large work area. The second floor includes three rooms and a bathroom. A storage shed is included in the sale.
 
$299,000
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 Well maintained two level building presently being used as a place of worship with 4212 total square feet with 65 parking spaces.First Level- Large auditorium (2094 square feet) accomodating 215. Tiled entree&amp;Coat Room off entree&amp;two public restrooms. Library. Lower Level has two large Conference Rooms and Utility Rooms.First Level is Handicap Accessible.Only 2.5 miles from 93. Short distance to Manchester.Less than one hour to Boston. Renovation in 1996 - New roof,chairs,boiler,hot water heater,Central AC. Well priced. Shows well.
 
$299,000
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 Great office / warehouse located close to town. Paved parking out front. Office and garage entrance accessible from the street. Large space at a great price!
 
$295,000
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 2.89 residential acre lot with 3 bedroom state approved septic design and existing 40x70 metal building. Currently being used for truck repairs, and rented at $1000/mo
 
$290,000
Exeter NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour BRING YOUR BUSINESS BUY OR RENT. CAN&apos;T GO WRONG! Over 4000 sq. ft. of fabulous space. 3 levels of large open rms, reception area, another 4 good size rms, 2 half baths, central air, new roof, new siding, lots of parking, docking,&amp;great visibility. Lots of uses; retail, offices or school (more info available). The building is in great condition inside&amp;out. Easy to show. ALSO, CAN BE RENTED FOR $3000 PLUS UTILIES.
 
$289,900
Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 NEED OFFICE SPACE? Look no further than Hampton&apos;s desirable Towle Office Park -- just off Rt 27, minutes to Rts 1, 101,&amp;I-95. Available FOR SALE or FOR LEASE: 2nd flr layout includes over 3700 sf of office and conference space, an abundance of natural light, Cable T1/T3, 2 private bathrooms (one w/a shower for all those runners out there). Plenty of on-site parking. Sprinkled building. Public water/sewer. BONUS: 3rd flr storage space. Convenient day-care option within same complex! Note: fabulos rate for a min of 3 year lease: yr 1 just $1500/mo&amp;utilities; yr 2 $2000 + utilities; yr 3 and beyond just 4% annual increase. AMAZING OPPORTUNITY FOR THE RIGHT BUYER/TENANT!!!!
 
$279,900
Epping NH
 View this listing 
 Great Opportunity for restaurant, bakery,Coffee Shop, Retail in downtown Epping, NH.
 
$279,000
Greenland NH
 View this listing 
 Industrial Flex Condominium Units available at Autumn Pond Park in Greenland. Currently fit up with 5 offices, conference room, mezzanine storage and 16&apos; clear height shop floor/ warehouse serviced by a 10&apos;x10&apos; overhead door. ADA compliant rest room, mezzanine office/ conference room, wet sprinkler system, air conditioned. Floorplan divides into roughly 1900sf office, 800sf shop/ warehouse&amp;1550sf mezzanine storage. Adequate parking in a well maintained, landscaped park.
 
$279,000
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Terrific corner lot makes for a great location in downtown Derry, one lot down from the Town&apos;s recently renovated major intersection. Perfect for high exposure offices, such as accountants, attorneys, brokers, etc. Approximately 3,000 sf of office space along with an income producing apartment. All windows recently replaced, full cellar and all town utilities.
 
$275,000
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 Established Turn Key Deli/Pizza Restaurant, in southern NH! Sale Includes Business and equipment only. 12 years left on lease!
 
$275,000
Candia NH
 View this listing 
 This property currently operates as a COUNTRY STORE. The sale also includes an attached 3+ BR home and would be ideal for a family looking to operate their own business. Almost 5 acres on well traveled High St (Rte 27). Flexible retail space, could be easily adapted to accommodate a wide variety of uses. Residential/commercial zoning affords multiple opportunities to expand and grow this or any business. Plenty of visibility on well traveled route 27 (aka High Street). With the right use and owners this property will provide great opportunity for growth and business potential. Sale includes land and buildings only, business itself is not for sale. Also see MLS 4148106.
 
$274,900
Exeter NH
 View this listing 
 Great Price! APPROVED SUBDIVISION! This property has been approved for 7 detached single family condominum homes 24x32. All town utilities available at this location. All conditions have been met.
 
$269,900
Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 Location, Location, Location. Are you renting your office space now? In the market to buy your own an office building to house your own business? Looking for a strong investment? Look no further - well maintained office building just steps to Hampton Center available for immediate occupancy. Currently a law office, this space is ideal and features two conference rooms, kitchen, private office with private bath, book case lined reception room, administrative offices, photo copying room and two additional private offices. Building is priced $94,600 below current assessment! A great investment!
 
$269,000
Northwood NH
 View this listing 
 Opportunity for the Entrepreneur. Condex With a Multitude of Uses, Individual Offices, or Live in One Unit, Use the 2nd One for Business. Great Location, Great Visibility on Route 4 Which Is the Main Route from the Seacoast to the Capitol. Cape Style Bright Condex Office Complex in Excellent Condition. Unit 1 Features 5 Rooms, Unit 2 Has 6 Rooms Each With Vaulted Ceilings. Large Front Paved Parking, 673&apos;route 4 Ftg, Unit 2 Is Wheelchair Accessible to 3 Large Office Spaces or As Bedrooms if Converted Into a Home. the Possibilities Are Endless. 
Priced Below Assessment.
 
$262,900
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 ***DRASTIC PRICE REDUCTION***Restaurant, NiteClub Banquet Hall, Private Club, Bar, Kitchen, 3 floors with offices, in town location, possible rent to own. Downtown lots of on street parking and muni lots available.
 
$259,999
Windham NH
 View this listing 
 Improved .902 acre lot with newly renovated home. Flexible house with convenient location near Exit 3, I-93&amp;convenient to Hudson/Nashua. Home is currently being rented, thus rental could continue or ended for you to move in. It makes a nice residential property, but is officially in commercial zone. Property was completely renovated in 2002. The property is one lot off of lighted intersection of Route 111 and Route 128. Use property as home and capitalize the future value as the commercial area grows.
 
$249,900
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Great for living and working. Offers Location, quality and value, hardwood floors, pocket doors, farmers wrap-around porch, recent burner unit&amp;upgraded electric. Full basement&amp;walk-up attic for storage or finish. Oversized 2 Car drive-thru garage. Zoned OBD - Office or Retail is OK.
 
$249,900
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 This well maintained free standing office building offers 2,551 square feet on 1.2 acres. Located at the south end of the Manchester-Boston Regional Airport, near Stonyfield Farms corporate office and minutes away from the new airport access road. Building has a brick exterior with architectural shingles and 25 on-site parking spaces. Zone allows typical industrial uses as well as professional office and motor vehicle maintenance and repair; group child care is allowed by special exception. Potential redevelopment opportunity exists.
 
$239,900
Epping NH
 View this listing 
 Great Opportunity to own property in downtown Epping. Day Care, Yoga Studio, Cafe, Coffee Shop, Office,Hair Salon, Floral, etc. endless possibilities. Live on one side, business on other side. Agent related to Seller. 24 hour notice. 24 hour notice.
 
$239,000
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Sale includes 6 room single family home, with detached garage that has special permission as auromotive repair.
NOT for the use to sell cars, but is legal and up to code for auto repair: garage has place for lift. Home has many up-grades and is in move-in condition...even has a finished TV room in the basement. GREAT set-up for the mechanic to have a business&amp;residence.
 
$235,000
Raymond NH
 View this listing 
 Site was approved for a 14,000SF Strip Center. Seller will consider 4,000SF lease back!! Was approved with 6,000 Gal per day sepic design. Town water at site. This site has excellent soils and can be used for many uses. All engeneering has been done and available for reapproval or new site plan as needed. Good location for business headquarters near exit4 RT101
 
$230,000
Newmarket NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour ATTN Small Business owners - Great Opportunity to own where you work and benefit from the exciting buzz that abounds in the newly renovated Downtown. Large open window for visibility. This stand alone building is in turnkey and ready to go condition. Beautiful hardwood floors, 2 half baths, kitchenette, conference room, and private office overlooking Main Street. 
Located right in the heart of the renovated Newmarket Downtown, where new businesses and industry are popping up even stronger since the start of the Downtown Mill renovations. Don&apos;t miss it. Owner is Licensed NH Real Estate Broker.
 
$229,900
Northwood NH
 View this listing 
 This property is currently priced at $43,500 beneath its assessed valuation. It is the former award winning Moonlight Maple Farms. There is an existing 3 room building containing approximately 1,334 sq ft of space with additional storage space in the attic. The property sits on 3+ acres of land over looking Harvey Lake with 105&apos; lake frontage. It also approximately 400&apos; of frontage on Rt.4 with plenty of room for parking. This property will provide an excellent opportunity for a commercial venture aided by a very high traffic count on busy Rt.4.
 
$225,000
Brentwood NH
 View this listing 
 Industrial land ready to build road and building area to sub grade all site permits in place. Pull a building permit and get underway. 
Approved for 50,000 square feet could build up to 100,000.00 square feet of commercial/industrial. Flexible sellers lease and build to suit options available.
 
$224,500
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 High Traffic Location! Busy rt 102 at the heart of Londonderry&apos;s Retail/Medical area. Across from Crossroads Mall, and 3 Drug Stores, Dunkin Donuts. Just down the Street from Elliot&apos;s new medical facility.Excellent location for Medical Office or Commercial Service Location. Property has recently received Planning Board approval for commercial usage. 3 approved parking spaces. Many upgrades have been made already.
 
$224,000
Brentwood NH
 View this listing 
 Centrally located antique 9 room Colonial in great condtion. 2,888 sq.ft. office/residential plus detached garage and two storage sheds/shop space. Town Center location close to municipal buildings and schools. Legal 2-family home.
 
$223,000
Auburn NH
 View this listing 
 3,250 sf industrial condo. 750 sf office area and 1,750 sf high bay warehouse along with a cement floor steel framed (unfinished) mezzanine. Located in a newer industrial park, with easy access to the major highways. Great building for service contractors or light industrial users.
 
$221,900
Newmarket NH
 View this listing 
 B3 zoned - 3 bedroom 2 bath log home with detached 2 car garage with walk up storage above on 1.6 sloping acres.
Basement is walk out with office and family room and utility area.
 
$215,000
Newmarket NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour Retail pad site directly on Rte 108. Conceptual site plan 5,000+/- SF on Lot (conceptual attached). Great Rte 108 location surrounded by Irving Gas, MacDonald&apos;s, Car wash, and other businesses on busy Route 108 in Newmarket. Zoning allows for Retail, Office, Daycare, Hotel, Recreation facility, Health club, Restaurant, Wholesale, Light Manufacturing, and more. Conceptual site plan allows for 5,000+/- SF building at front on Rte 108. Shared access and ample parking. Subject to subdivision approval.
 
$209,900
Northwood NH
 View this listing 
 How can you pass this deal up? Work&amp;Play all in one spot! 6 + ac of land on RT 4 w/a ton of frontage, High traffic count, lot can be subdivided! Ideas should be spinning in your head right now. Being used as a quilting shop now, but could be anything. Charming Cape home with many update within the past 3 years, Walking dist to Coe-Brown Academy, 15min to Concord, 40 min to Manchester and Seacoast, on major trucking route. How about an inn? enjoy all the local lakes all within 5 miles for fishing and summer time fun.
 
$199,900
Raymond NH
 View this listing 
 Locate within thirty Miles of All NH major population centers,four Registry of deeds, the State House,Me, Ma and sixty-Five miles to Boston TD Garden. All engineering for a 21,000 SF office building included with permits.Town water at site, excellent soils to work with. Just off Exit 5 Route 101. Will do a build out to qualified buyer/Lease with purchase option. Will help with plans if you want changes. Half way between Route 95 and 93. Great location for Business headquarters, Sales force, Title Company, Lawyers, If you need to have access to any southern NH City or Town,Seacoast of NH, Me and northern Ma this is the location for you come check this out and see for yourself what a great site this is for any business.
 
$199,900
Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 BROKER INTEREST (Owner) The 2,800 square foot office condo is in an association that has a mix of offices and retail services (dentist, hair stylist) so most any user is welcome. The unit has one office down and two offices on the second floor, or it can be used as one continguous office as it is currently a law office using both floors. Owner/occupant could use part and lease part to offset ownership costs.
 
$199,900
Sandown NH
 View this listing 
 MCC Northwoods Business Center, an established 18 lot Commercial/Industrial park located in both Sandown and Hampstead. 3 Sandown lots available: 2.5, 2.9 or 3.1 acres. $69,900 per lot or all three for $199,900. Reference MLS 4092270, 4092272 and 4092277 for individual lot listings.
 
$199,900
Candia NH
 View this listing 
 -Location, Location, Location ! Have your Business and Residence on the same Property! 33 Acres on Rt.27/Raymond Rd.in Candia,near Post Office.Mixed use with the front portion Commercial Zoned and the middle/back Residential Zoned.Check out Meridian Plot Plan for details. Can be purchased with the 5.0 acres adjacent to it. MLS # 4111212 (409-192)
 
$199,000
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 Popular local Tavern with well below market rate lease in place. Great high visibility location just a few steps to Market Square. Year round local customer base as well as a popular tourist spot, The Daniel Street Tavern is a real income producer.
 
$199,000
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Non Disclosure Required Fast Food Restaurant Rockingham County NH. Business for Sale. Fully equipped seats 90, drive thru Restaurant Air Conditioned 18,000 cars a day. Possible 50% Partnership offered!!!.Fit up is all New!
Ask for C 129 ID #.
 
$194,900
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Hard to find industrial condos, 2326.5 s/f.can combine for larger space.Office, Mezzanine, Warehouse. Near two I-93 exits.
 
$194,900
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Hard to find industrial condos, 2696.6 s/f.can combine for larger space.Office, Mezzanine, Warehouse. Near two I-93 exits
 
$189,900
Salem NH
 View this listing 
 Italian Restaurant, business only in super location on Route 28! Free standing building, parking for 35 cars. Great income, high visibility, heavy traffic. 23 year lease. Ideal for corporate franchise.
 
$184,995
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 Professional office for sale or lease. completely remodeled&amp;architecturally designed for medical/non-medical office. Medical office set up consisting of 4 exam rooms/lab with sinks, open concept front/waiting areas. Good access to downtown, highways&amp;Portsmouth Regional Hospital. Seller is a licensed realtor.
 
$184,900
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Hard to find industrial condos, 2115 s/f.can combine for larger space.Office, Mezzanine, Warehouse. Near two I-93 exits.
 
$184,900
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Hard to find Industrial condos 2115 Sq ft. can combine for more space. office, warehouse, mezzanine.Plenty of parking Close to I-93
 
$184,900
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Hard to find industrial condos, 2115 s/f.can combine for larger space.Office, Mezzanine, Warehouse. Near two I-93 exits.
 
$184,900
Derry NH
 View this listing 
 Hard to find industrial condos, 2115 s/f.can combine for larger space.Office, Mezzanine, Warehouse. Near two I-93 exits
 
$180,000
Newmarket NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour Building Lot in great location with easy access to downtown Newmarket. Conceptual site plan for 7,000+/- SF building on Lot2 (conceptual attached). Great Rte 108 location surrounded by Irving Gas, MacDonald&apos;s, Car wash, and other businesses on busy Route 108 in Newmarket. Zoning allows for Retail, Office, Daycare, Hotel, Recreation facility, Health club, Restaurant, Wholesale, Light Manufacturing, and more. Conceptual site plan allows for 7,000+/- SF building on this lot, with shared access from Rte 108 and ample parking. Front lot at Rte 108 also available, see MLS # 4022651. lots can be combined and sold together. Subject to subdivision approval.
 
$180,000
Kingston NH
 View this listing 
 New Construction - Business commercial condominiums reduced in price. Buyer can customize unit for need - mezzanine possibilities available. Great curb appeal. Established commercial park - uses vary - professional office, light manufacturing, retail stores, contractors, etc. Convenient location off Rte 125.This unit contains 3000 square feet to accomadate Buyer&apos;s needs.
 
$179,900
Plaistow NH
 View this listing 
 Fantastic Opportunity to Buy or Lease space in the RED OAK BUSINESS CONDOMINIUMS! Unbelievable build-out with 3 large private offices, (sub-dividable), administrative areas, 2 bahts, (1 w/shower) recessed lights, tile garage/storage area, burglar&amp;fire alarms.Sale or lease for $1200. Month NNN
 
$179,000
Newmarket NH
 View this listing 
 Approved Building lot, ideal for contractor use. Approvals in place for two buildings, parking for 6 trucks and 4 other spaces. Road frontage of 258ft directly on Rte 152 with easy access to Route 108, Route 125, and Route 101. Proposed buildings are both 32&apos;x36&apos; footprint for office and garage use. Site work improvements have been completed, already paid for be Seller, and site is ready for construction. Site plans available.
 
$179,000
Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 $45,000 PRICE REDUCTION! Incredible Price in an incredible location! Desirable 2,600square foot commercial industrial condo with 18 foot plus ceiling height for Sale in Hampton, NH. Two loading dock doors make it perfect for the business owner with light industrial use, warehouse space, or just for storage needs. This is a rare find in the Seacoast at this price and ideally situated close to routes 95, 1 and 101. Space already has a security system in place and water to unit. Two parking spaces in frotn of unit and plenty of surface parking spaces for your clients.
 
$175,000
Northwood NH
 View this listing 
 Virtual Tour EXCELLENT BUSINESS EXPOSURE, with plenty of parking. Great location for your owner-occupied business or investment property. Beautiful 2+ bdrm apt.in lower level with garage&amp;lots of privacy. Plenty of parking in back at entrance to additional garage space and large basement area. Excellent potential on commuter-friendly Rte. 4. Easy to show! Seller will look at all offers!!!
 
$175,000
Northwood NH
 View this listing 
 -Great business opportunity! High traffic counts and great major road frontage, this property is right on Antique Alley in Northwood, NH. Property is a home and separate shop with excellent visibility, outstanding parking, and a shop that will display your antiques or other business in a setting to enhance their beauty. Several 1875 Apothocary cabinets in shop - beautiful craftsmanship. The home built by James Hannaford in 1777 is a reminscence of yesteryear with comforts of 21st century. This is a must to be seen! What a perfect in-home business opportunity. Don&apos;t let this chance pass you by.
 
$174,900
Portsmouth NH
 View this listing 
 Twenty year history of a successful and extremely busy gas station/convenience store that has a 100% location on the busiest road in Portsmouth, NH. Average volume is 2,000,000+ gal gas and $500,000 in convenience store. This is a Business Only sale.
 
$169,000
Epping NH
 View this listing 
 Zoned Residential/Commercial. 275&apos; Frontage on Route 125, Private Septic and Water and Town water and sewer available too. Ranch style home.
 
$169,000
North Hampton NH
 View this listing 
 -This &quot;end&quot; unit is on the second level at the south end of the main building above a retail store with access from a door adjacent to the main parking lot. External visiblity of the unit is above average due to its location at the south end of the building and near one of the entryways to the plaza and Dunkin Donuts. That it has dormered windows viewing south is an appealing feature of the unit not enjoyed by others in Fern Crossing.
 
$169,000
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 This nationally recognized company manufactures and produces health food bars that sells to MD&apos;s-Physicians-Nutritionists-Health Food stores-Internet Stores-Medical Spas-Plastic Surgeons.This business can be run from your home or small inexpensive space. Owner finance with substantial down payment.
 
$165,000
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 -1329 s/f 8 room office condo. Lots of window walls, 6 private offices, recep., office, waiting area, kitchenette. Ample parking, minutes to I-93. End unit. Available for lease $1908/MO + Util. Excellent condition.
 
$165,000
Londonderry NH
 View this listing 
 -1536s/f Former Dental office with equipment, furniture, fixtures etc... Layout includes 1/2 bath plus 1/2 HC bath. Lab with cabinetry, sterilization room with cabinetry, dark room, consult office, waiting area, reception/business office and 4 operatories. Private entry end unit. Close to exit 4 I-93, additional space available.
 
$159,900
Greenland NH
 View this listing 
 Now Available: Industrial / Office Condo - &quot;Corner&quot; Unit For Sale at $159,900 or For Lease @ $1,995 per month - located at Autumn Pond Park. Consists of 5 offices, 3 bathrooms&amp;kitchen/ laundry area, 2nd story storage loft[mezzanine]plus shop area with garage door access. Sprinkler System and ADA compliant restroom. Tenant to pay utilities and taxes. Broker/Owner Interest.
 
$159,900
Hampstead NH
 View this listing 
 Large lot in Industrial/Commercial Hampstead Subdivison!
Build your Dwelling Here!
  Home | News&amp;Tools | Our Commitment To You | Property Listing | Sell My House | Contact Us | Site Map 
2011 Betty LaBranche Real Estate , Inc. | Subject to errors, omissions, or change without notice.
	</body>
</document>
