<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001705" url="http://www.ocregister.com/articles/don-14518-restaurant-puck.html" time="2012-07-12-17:29" support="2" score="0.004187434425003907" bingtitle="Wolfgang Puck heads to O.C. | don, restaurant, puck - Life - The ..." webtitle="Wolfgang Puck heads to O.C. | don, restaurant, puck - Life - The Orange County Register">
			<query id="001441" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="001424" bing-rank="176"/>
	<description>... 59, talked to me about Orange County diners (are we any different than Los Angeles foodies?) and what fast-food restaurant he&apos;s ... this new restaurant is that it is counter ...</description>
	<body>
		REAL ESTATE JOBS CARS DEALS CLASSIFIEDS PLACE AN AD 
 
 SIGN-IN/SIGN-UP SUBSCRIBE E-REGISTER CUSTOMER SERVICE TODAY&apos;S PAPER 
 Orange County Register 
LIFE
 
 SURF REPORT/CAMS |  WEATHER  | LIVE TRAFFIC 
 
 HOME NEWS SPORTS BUSINESS ENTERTAINMENT LIFE TRAVEL OPINION 
 
 Newsletter RSS Mobile Facebook Twitter 
 Beaches | Best of OC | Blogs | Columns | Comics | Contests | Food | Gift of Giving | Health and Fitness | Home and Garden | Horoscopes | OC Moms | OC People | Outdoors | Pets | Photos | Puzzles and Games | Shopping and Deals | Video Published: April 29, 2009 3:00 a.m. Text: Next Article» 
Wolfgang Puck heads to O.C.
 On Saturday, the food icon will do a cooking demonstration and book signing at the grand reopening of his South Coast Plaza bistro. Tweet    
 Posh Party Box $40 for $100 towards Your Party Box at PoshPartyBox.com ADVERTISEMENT 
More from Food
 
 Home cooking expert Marion Cunningham dies at 90 Mediterranean flavors delight in laid-back setting New restaurant on way to Dana Point 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 By NANCY LUNA / The Orange County Register 
 
Food icon Wolfgang Puck heads to South Coast Plaza on Saturday for the grand re-opening of his only sit-down Orange County eatery.

At the christening of Wolfgang Puck Bistro in Costa Mesa, the affable celebrity chef is slated to lead a kids cooking demonstration, as well as sign the latest edition of his book, &quot;Wolfgang Puck Makes it Easy.&quot; The event starts at noon.
 Wolfgang Puck, shown earlier this year at the Academy Awards ceremony, will appear at South Coast Plaza on Saturday. The food icon and celebrity chef will be christening his newly remodeled mall eatery: Wolfgang Puck Bistro.File photo by Mark Rightmire ADVERTISEMENT 
Wolfgang Puck Bistro

 What: The restaurant, formerly Wolfgang Puck Cafe, is celebrating its grand reopening Saturday with chef-owner, Wolfgang Puck. The food icon will share samples of bistro foods, sign his latest book and lead a children&apos;s cooking demonstration.

 When: Noon

 Cost: $10 reservation fee benefits Festival of Children Foundation

 Phone: 714-708-3333 ext. 4706

 Where: South Coast Plaza, 3333 Bear St., Costa Mesa
 
More South Coast Plaza events
 South Coast Plaza blog has the latest updates on mall events . 
In between trips this week to his restaurants in Los Angeles and Las Vegas, the carb-counting Puck, 59, talked to me about Orange County diners (are we any different than Los Angeles foodies?) and what fast-food restaurant he&apos;s willing to eat at—if forced by his kids. (Hint: It&apos;s not McDonald&apos;s.)

Here&apos;s what he had to say:

 Q. Why did you scrap the Wolfgang Puck Cafe concept at South Coast Plaza, and other locations, in favor of this new Wolfgang Puck Bistro? 

 A. The restaurants were already 15 years old. Our restaurants are in constant evolution. We never sit still. We are not like McDonald&apos;s, where they do the same thing for 50 years. We have to change because people really expect it or they get bored.

 Q. One of the main differences at this new restaurant is that it is counter service by day and table service by night. What&apos;s the advantage of this? 

 A. We have one restaurant in downtown Los Angeles and Westlake that are like this. I still don&apos;t know if it will work out. When you have the rich women coming in for lunch from shopping (at South Coast Plaza), they might want to be waited on. It is still a work in progress.

 Q. What is the biggest challenge for you when it comes to running fast-casual units? 

 A. It&apos;s always more difficult to have a restaurant like that. I have to work harder. I&apos;m so used to using luxury foods. It&apos;s very difficult to say, you can&apos;t use this or that because you have to consider price and speed.

 Q. So it forces you to be creative? 

 A. Yes. At Spago, to make a great sandwich it&apos;s easy. I make a great grilled lobster sandwich for $26. But I can&apos;t do that here (at Wolfgang Puck Bistro). It&apos;s not that style of restaurant. Instead, I do something with roasted chicken. Still, we don&apos;t want to be a deli. I&apos;m testing braised short ribs and lamb shanks in some of the Los Angeles restaurants.

 Q. Including the new O.C. bistro? 

 A. Yes, we&apos;ll try it there.

 Q. Speaking of sandwiches, one of the best I&apos;ve ever eaten was at your old Wolfgang Puck restaurant at the Block in Orange. You used to have a larger presence here, including Disneyland&apos;s California Adventure. Why did you leave? 

 A. We couldn&apos;t make any money.

 Q. Yet, you have very successful fine dining restaurants in Los Angeles. Is the OC diner different than LA? 

 A. No. At the end of the day, everyone&apos;s the same. There are people from Los Angeles to Newport Beach who know about food, and there are people who don&apos;t care what they eat. Except for San Diego. When you go down to San Diego, they are not willing to spend money like in Orange County.



 Q. How has dining changed since you first started? 

 A. When you look back when Spago opened, you could say &apos;arugula&apos; or &apos;goat cheese&apos; and those (terms) were new. Now, people travel a lot, and watch shows on TV. That helps educate people. Most importantly, you have so many young Americans that are in the (culinary) profession. When I was a kid in the 1970s, if I told anyone I was a chef, they&apos;d laugh. It was not a glamorous job as it is now.

 Q. Because diners are more informed, does that challenge you as chef? 

 A. No. The more you know, the better it is for me.

 Q. What do you think of consumer-driven food review sites such as Yelp and Chowhound? 

 A. I don&apos;t do the computer so I have no idea. I never look. It&apos;s not that we don&apos;t care what they say. But it&apos;s done by people critiquing what they don&apos;t know. It&apos;s like me critiquing opera.

 Q. So you don&apos;t have an email? 

 A. I don&apos;t do email (because) then, I can&apos;t think. When I&apos;m at the restaurant, I concentrate at the restaurant. When, I&apos;m at the market, I concentrate on that. I don&apos;t want to be on the phone all day, or email all day.

 Q. The tanking economy has impacted casual and fine dining the most. Is that true for your company? 

 A. In certain places, we feel it more than other places. Like at the airport, we don&apos;t decide how many flights go in and out. We can feel it when they (the airlines) cut down 15 percent of flights. We are also affected in catering, especially in movie making. We did a lot of that, but now not as much.

 Q. How do you cope? 

 A. At the end of the day, we just have to manage better. Like at Spago, we have them work less hours or there&apos;s no overtime.

 Q. I write a fast food column for the paper. So I must ask: do you eat fast food? 

 A. I rarely eat out. And I rarely eat fast food. My wife and my older kids love In-N-Out. But for me, I like to sit down at a table and eat.

 Q. You can sit down at In-N-Out. 

 A. Yes, but we usually go through the drive-through.

 Q. You must order something while you are in the car. What is it? 

 A. If I do order something, I order that one with no bread.

 Q. Ah. The protein burger. Do you limit your carbs? 

 A. Yes. I like bread a lot.

 Q. If you could choose your last meal, what would it be? 

 A. I&apos;m too young to even think that. Call me in 50 years.

 Q. Will do. 

 Contact the writer: nluna@ocregister.com or 714-796-6756. Checkout my fast food blog at ocregister.com/fastfood

 
 More from Food» 
 
 COMMENTS | PRINT | EMAIL |   Reader Comments Comments are encouraged, but you must follow our User Agreement .
1. Keep it civil and stay on topic.
2. No profanity, vulgarity, racial slurs or personal attacks.
3. People who harass others or joke about tragedies will be blocked.
 View Article | Article Videos Return to Top 
 home news sports business entertainment life travel opinion Real estate Jobs Cars Deals Classifieds Place an Ad 
 
 
ADVERTISE OPTIONS

 Self Service Place an Online Ad Place a Print Ad Place a Classified Ad Media Kit Advertising Contact Info 
 
CONTACT OCREGISTER

 About Us Careers Contact Us Corrections Customer Service Subscribe Today Subscriber Services Site Help Site Feedback 
 
OCR SERVICES

 Archives Buy Our Photos California Lottery Deals OCRegister Fanshop Orange County Businesses Register Insider Register in Education Obituaries Facebook Comments FAQs 
 
NEWS YOUR WAY

 Blogs E-Mail Newsletters E-Register Mobile RSS Article Map Site Map Video 
 
ADVERTISING

 Classifieds Cars Deals Jobs Real Estate Place a Classified Ad View our Media Kit Interactive 
 
PARTNERS

 KDOC-TV MSNBC OC Excelsior Coast Magazine Preferred Destination OrangeCounty.com FreedomPolitics.com Freedom Printing 
 
 
 Privacy Policy | Site Help | User Agreement | Site Map
	</body>
</document>
