<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001919" url="http://www.lagrange-restaurants.com/restaurant/Countryside-IL/Al&apos;s-Beef" time="2012-07-12-17:49" support="4" score="0.008655658885627242" bingtitle="Al&apos;s Beef in Countryside, IL - photos, visitor reviews, phone and more" webtitle="Al&apos;s Beef in Countryside, IL - photos, phone, description and more">
			<query id="001009" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="001135" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000037" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="000726" bing-rank="40"/>
	<description>THE TABLE WAS NOT CLEAN.MY ORDER WAS TO STAY-BUT IT WAS BAGGED. NO SOAP IN RESTROOM.HAD ... Santiago’s Mexican Restaurant · Stella’s Fast Food Restaurant · Golden ...</description>
	<body>
		Home » Countryside, IL restaurants 
 
Al’s Beef
 
 Features: American (Traditional), Hamburgers, Hot Dogs, Italian Beef
 9 ratings for Al’s Beef Average rating of 2 stars (out of 5 possible) Al’s Beef - reviewed by Ron F. from Chicago IL. on May 14 . THE TABLE WAS NOT CLEAN.MY ORDER WAS TO STAY-BUT IT WAS BAGGED. NO SOAP IN RESTROOM THE TABLE WAS NOT CLEAN.MY ORDER WAS TO STAY-BUT IT WAS BAGGED. NO SOAP IN RESTROOM.HAD TO GO BACK FOR CUPS-CLERK FORGOT.AND THE DARN MUSIC WAS WAY TOO LOUD! BUT THE BEEF WAS VERY GOOD! Al’s Beef - reviewed by jesanangel from La Grange, IL on Apr 13 . TERRIBLE - Tasteless and bland. Way too much gravy on the bread - the sandwich fel TERRIBLE - Tasteless and bland. Way too much gravy on the bread - the sandwich fell apart. This is probably the worst beef sandwich EVER. I asked for peppers - UGH! Never again. Rating: 1.5 Al’s Beef - reviewed by Mitnov from Brookfield, IL on August 26, 2010 . A BIG DESSAPOINTMENT ! After hearing about Al&apos;s Beef on Channel 11&apos;s Check Please, A BIG DESSAPOINTMENT ! After hearing about Al&apos;s Beef on Channel 11&apos;s Check Please, we tried it and were dissapointed. It had no flavor, the beef was only small shredded pieces of meat, and the green peppers were too“mushy”.

We won&apos;t go back there, since there are many much beter it… Read more Rating: 3 id: als5321sla 
See similar restaurants in Countryside, Illinois: American (Traditional) | Hamburgers | Hot Dogs | Italian Beef 
 
 Search by keyword:  
 Close 
View Larger Image
 
 More photos» 
 Al’s Beef is located at 5321 S La Grange Rd 
 Countryside , IL 708-354-2333 
Do you own or manage this restaurant?
 and update or enhance this page with photos, menus and more information! 
 
See other types of restaurants&amp;cuisines in Countryside, including area Bars and Bagels . 
In nearby La Grange, take a look at a number of other restaurants, including Prasino and Moy Goy Inn .
 
Check out our sister restaurant guide in Paso Robles, CA , including our comprehensive list of Cafes and Mexican dining.
 
Popular restaurants on www.lagrange-restaurants.com

 Morton’s - The Steakhouse   ·   Off Broadway Pub   ·   Priscilla’s Ultimate Soulfood   ·   DiNico’s Pizza&amp;Gelato Uno   ·   Broadway Pancake House   ·   Rascal’s Restaurant   ·   Alex&amp;Aldo’s   ·   CaféCalbay   ·   Nancy’s Pizza   ·   CaféSalsa   ·   Panchero’s Mexican Grill   ·   Sushi House   ·   Q BBQ   ·   Knead Marketplace   ·   Pop’s Italian Beef&amp;Sausage   ·   Nickson’s Eatery   ·   Santiago’s Mexican Restaurant   ·   Stella’s Fast Food Restaurant   ·   Golden Wok Restaurant   ·   Chequers (English Pub)   ·   Original Pancake House   ·   Tony’s Breakfast Café   ·   Baskin-Robbins   ·   Magic Wok Restaurant   ·   Lucca Pizzeria 
 
 Home  ·   Brookfield  ·   Countryside  ·   Hillside  ·   La Grange  ·   La Grange Park  ·   Westchester   |   Photos 

 About Us   |    |   Privacy Policy   |  

Thursday 05th of July 2012 01:49:31 PM
	</body>
</document>
