<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001297" url="http://www.kltv.com/category/7857/news" time="2012-07-12-16:44" support="1" score="0.0012275496835002302" bingtitle="Local News - KLTV.com-Tyler, Longview, Jacksonville, Texas | ETX News" webtitle="Local News - KLTV.com-Tyler, Longview, Jacksonville, Texas | ETX News">
			<query id="001429" bing-rank="183"/>
	<description>... Police have made four arrests in a major credit card ... are investigating a late Wednesday night fast food restaurant ... students aren&apos;t just seeking justice, but a change ...</description>
	<body>
		KLTV.com-Tyler, Longview, Jacksonville, Texas | ETX NewsLocal News
 SITE SEARCH WEB SEARCH BY 
 
 KLTV Faces Slideshows Big Red Box See It, Snap It, Send It KLTV.com Mobile Text&amp;Email Alerts News Tips Who&apos;s on 7 RSS Feeds America Now 
 
 Texas Headlines Weekly News Archives Education News Politics Business Tech RSS Feeds 
 
 Interactive Radar Hurricane Tracker Text&amp;Email Alerts Mobile StormTracker National Radar Current Radar Image Personal Forecast Pollen Center KLTV.com Mobile ThunderCall 
 
 The Red Zone Victory Lane 7 Sports Smackdown Die Hard Sports Pro Pigskin Pick&apos;em Texas Sports Headlines 
 
 ETMC Medical Resource Guide Senior Resource Women&apos;s Health Men&apos;s Health 
 
 Birthday Club 
 
 Main Summer Back to School Entertainment Money Home/Family Health Food Pets Tech Travel Beauty&amp;Style Tax Guide VideoBytes Press Releases 
 
 America Now ABC Shows Online At the Movies Horoscopes 
 
 Healthy Women Community Calendar Baby Boomer Daily A Better East Texas Everyday Heroes Community Spotlight ASK Seek Knock 
 
 Who&apos;s on 7 Employment Online Media Kit 388 Filed with the FCC EEO Summary 
 
 
 
 Local News More&gt;&gt; 
 
 Child care matters luncheon 

 Child care matters luncheon 
 Updated: Thursday, July 12 2012 9:28 AM EDT 2012-07-12 13:28:39 GMT Carol Burnett is the executive director of the Mississippi Low-Income Child Care Initiative. Burnett said the organization wants state leaders to focus more on providing money to expand affordable daycare More &gt;&gt; The Mississippi Low-Income Child Care Initiative will host a media luncheon called &quot;Child Care Matters,&quot; on Thursday to discuss issues related to affordable daycare in Mississippi. More &gt;&gt; 
 Early Heavy Drizzle Makes Impact On Traffic 

 Early Heavy Drizzle Makes Impact On Traffic 
 Updated: Thursday, July 12 2012 9:07 AM EDT 2012-07-12 13:07:11 GMT Steady early morning rain and heavy drizzle continues to make the street wet and very slick to start off the day. Expect a high of 84 degrees with a 90% chance of spot showers and isolated T-storms. Winds More &gt;&gt; Steady early morning rain and heavy drizzle continues to make the street wet and very slick to start off the day. Expect a high of 84 degrees with a 90% chance of spot showers and isolated T-storms. More &gt;&gt; 
 Grandmother blames botched manicure for teen&apos;s surgeries 

 Grandmother blames botched manicure for teen&apos;s surgeries 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 11:44 PM EDT 2012-07-12 03:44:46 GMT A Jackson teenager blames a bad manicure for a lost nail and several hospital stays. Now her family says the shop owner won&apos;t take responsibility for the infection that developed. Virgie Peterson was More &gt;&gt; A Jackson teenager blames a bad manicure for a lost nail and several hospital stays. Now, her family says the shop owner won&apos;t take responsibility for the infection that developed. More &gt;&gt; 
 Natchez man takes 2 year old to drug deal 

 Natchez man takes 2 year old to drug deal 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 11:13 PM EDT 2012-07-12 03:13:44 GMT Authorities in Adams County say a Natchez man took a toddler to an undercover drug transaction. Lucas Lorenzo Rogers, 28, was arrested for selling marijuana, Xanax, and Lorcet to an undercover buyer. More &gt;&gt; Authorities in Adams County say a Natchez man took a toddler to an undercover drug transaction. Lucas Lorenzo Rogers, 28, was arrested for selling marijuana, Xanax, and Lorcet to an undercover buyer.  More &gt;&gt; 
 Rainy weather possible factor in accidents 

 Rainy weather possible factor in accidents 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 10:45 PM EDT 2012-07-12 02:45:28 GMT Showers that moved through much of central Mississippi Wednesday may be to blame for a few accidents in Jackson. A truck somehow managed to get stuck under a viaduct at Gallatin Street. The driver More &gt;&gt; Showers that moved through much of central Mississippi Wednesday may be to blame for a few accidents in Jackson. A truck somehow managed to get stuck under a viaduct at Gallatin Street.  More &gt;&gt; 
 Slow Barge Traffic at Grand Gulf 

 Slow Barge Traffic at Grand Gulf 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 10:37 PM EDT 2012-07-12 02:37:10 GMT What you are seeing is partly another result of the winter we didn&apos;t have last winter. Lack of the normal huge snow levels up north are one reasons causing this, the unusually low Mississippi River we More &gt;&gt; What you are seeing is partly another result of the winter we didn&apos;t have last winter. Lack of the normal huge snow levels up north are one reasons causing this, the unusually low Mississippi River we are experiencing now. And what makes it more odd, this is just a year after the record flood of 2011.  More &gt;&gt; 
 Police identify 3 shooting victims 

 Police identify 3 shooting victims 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 9:44 PM EDT 2012-07-12 01:44:43 GMT Jackson police have identified three people shot while sitting in an SUV at 947 Robinson Street Tuesday night. More &gt;&gt; Jackson police have identified three people shot while sitting in an SUV at 947 Robinson Street Tuesday night. More &gt;&gt; 
 Judge continues to block Mississippi abortion law 

 Judge continues to block Mississippi abortion law 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 8:09 PM EDT 2012-07-12 00:09:04 GMT A hearing Wednesday will help a federal judge decide whether to keep blocking a Mississippi abortion law. More &gt;&gt; A federal judge is continuing to block a new anti-abortion law in Mississippi. If the law were allowed to take effect, it could shut down the state&apos;s only abortion clinic and make it nearly impossible for a woman to get an abortion in Mississippi. More &gt;&gt; 
 Jimmy Lewis re-vote possible 

 Jimmy Lewis re-vote possible 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 8:04 PM EDT 2012-07-12 00:04:42 GMT WLBT News has learned that the Hinds County Board of Supervisors might re-vote on whether to keep Emergency Operations Director Jimmy Lewis on the job. At the last meeting, Lewis was fired by a vote More &gt;&gt; A discussion on the EOC Director job is on the proposed agenda for Monday&apos;s Board of Supervisors meeting. More &gt;&gt; 
 Judge extends restraining order allowing abortion clinic to operate 

 Judge extends restraining order allowing abortion clinic to operate 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 6:28 PM EDT 2012-07-11 22:28:02 GMT It got its day in court and now Mississippi&apos;s only abortion clinic will be staying open, at least for now. This is despite a new law which some lawmakers were hopeful would shut it down. U.S. District More &gt;&gt; It got its day in court and now Mississippi&apos;s only abortion clinic will be staying open, at least for now. This is despite a new law which some lawmakers were hopeful would shut it down. More &gt;&gt; 
 Mayor Johnson: The state of the city is good 

 Mayor Johnson: The state of the city is good 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 5:25 PM EDT 2012-07-11 21:25:38 GMT Jackson Mayor Harvey Johnson thinks the city is on the right track and &quot;moving ahead.&quot; That&apos;s what he said to hundreds of people gathered at the Medical Mall to hear his State of the City address. Mayor More &gt;&gt; Jackson Mayor Harvey Johnson thinks the city is on the right track and &quot;moving ahead.&quot; That&apos;s what he said to hundreds of people gathered at the Medical Mall to hear his State of the City address. More &gt;&gt; 
 Robber with toy gun remains in jail 

 Robber with toy gun remains in jail 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 4:52 PM EDT 2012-07-11 20:52:36 GMT In the latest developments, the young armed robbery suspect who used a fake gun to rob a convenience store in Brandon was in court Wednesday afternoon. 22 year old Roy Mitchell waived his preliminary hearing More &gt;&gt; The young armed robbery suspect who used a fake gun in a robbery attempt at a convenience store in Brandon was in court Wednesday afternoon. Twenty-two-year-old Roy Mitchell waived his preliminary hearing in Brandon Municipal Court. More &gt;&gt; 
 Rain Continues Today 

 Rain Continues Today 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 2:44 PM EDT 2012-07-11 18:44:15 GMT The streets are going to be wet as soon as you step out the door for this morning. Today we&apos;ll have a 90% chance of scattered showers. There&apos;s only a slight chance of those same storms becoming severe; More &gt;&gt; The streets are going to be wet as soon as you step out the door for this morning. Today we&apos;ll have a 90% chance of scattered showers. There&apos;s only a slight chance of those same storms becoming severe; winds SW 10-15 mph, temps near mid 80s. More &gt;&gt; 
 Clerk held up at gunpoint by toy gun speaks out 

 Clerk held up at gunpoint by toy gun speaks out 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 12:14 PM EDT 2012-07-11 16:14:01 GMT Nearly all of the customers that come through D&apos;s One Stop Convenience Store on Highway 80 in Brandon shop at the store regularly. However, on Tuesday, July 3rd, a clerk named Shanell said she rang up More &gt;&gt; Roy Mitchell&apos;s July 3 rd armed robbery attempt failed after a very close relative snatched his gun away. Now, the convenience store clerk who Mitchell held up is speaking out about her frightening experience. More &gt;&gt; 
 MS Scout leader accused of sexual battery 

 MS Scout leader accused of sexual battery 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 11:48 AM EDT 2012-07-11 15:48:27 GMT Authorities say sexual battery charges against a Boy Scouts leader in north Mississippi are not related to his work with the organization. More &gt;&gt; Authorities say sexual battery charges against a Boy Scouts leader in north Mississippi are not related to his work with the organization. More &gt;&gt; 
 Sendoff ceremonies for deploying Guard soldiers 

 Sendoff ceremonies for deploying Guard soldiers 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 9:27 AM EDT 2012-07-11 13:27:13 GMT Sendoff ceremonies are planned Friday and Saturday for a group of Mississippi Army National Guard soldiers who are headed to Afghanistan. More &gt;&gt; Sendoff ceremonies are planned Friday and Saturday for a group of Mississippi Army National Guard soldiers who are headed to Afghanistan. More &gt;&gt; 
 Good Samaritan fatal crash results in multiple lawsuits 

 Good Samaritan fatal crash results in multiple lawsuits 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 11:05 PM EDT 2012-07-11 03:05:14 GMT The aftermath of an accident that killed one twin sister and left the other critically injured is headed to federal court. A wrongful death lawsuit was expected in the case, but now there are legal filings More &gt;&gt; The aftermath of an accident that killed one twin sister and left the other critically injured is headed to federal court. A wrongful death lawsuit was expected in the case, but now there are legal filings against lawyers, a Hinds County Constable and the father of the deceased woman&apos;s child. More &gt;&gt; 
 Finding Jackson attractions made easy 

 Finding Jackson attractions made easy 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 10:10 PM EDT 2012-07-11 02:10:23 GMT If you are looking for a ticket to fun in the capital city, there&apos;s now one stop shopping for just that. The Jackson Convention and Visitors Bureau has launched the attractions passport program. You&apos;ll More &gt;&gt; If you are looking for a ticket to fun in the capital city, there&apos;s now one stop shopping for just that. The Jackson Convention and Visitors Bureau has launched the attractions passport program. More &gt;&gt; 
 New book details shooting rampage at Jackson fire station 

 New book details shooting rampage at Jackson fire station 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 8:44 PM EDT 2012-07-11 00:44:23 GMT It was the darkest day in the history of the Jackson Fire Department. A disgruntled firefighter walked into the main fire station downtown and started shooting. Four of his colleagues were killed. Now, More &gt;&gt; It was the darkest day in the history of the Jackson Fire Department. A disgruntled firefighter walked into the main fire station downtown and started shooting. Four of his colleagues were killed.  More &gt;&gt; 
 Report of dog fighting turns out to be untrue 

 Report of dog fighting turns out to be untrue 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 8:12 PM EDT 2012-07-11 00:12:24 GMT Police officers converged on a Jackson neighborhood after receiving a call about dog fighting. Seven patrol units responded to Duncan Avenue and Wightman Street Tuesday afternoon. That&apos;s in the Millsaps More &gt;&gt; Police officers converged on a Jackson neighborhood after receiving a call about dog fighting.  More &gt;&gt; 
 State will be forced to create restrictions on welfare spending 

 State will be forced to create restrictions on welfare spending 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 6:20 PM EDT 2012-07-10 22:20:08 GMT Many states across the nation are enacting or considering new laws placing restrictions on what can be purchased with money received through welfare benefits, but Mississippi is not one of the states. More &gt;&gt; Across the country restrictions are being put in place to stop welfare recipients from spending benefits on items like lottery tickets, liquor and cigarettes and in places like casinos, bars and businesses for adult entertainment. More &gt;&gt; 
 3 latin king gang members convicted in violent assault 

 3 latin king gang members convicted in violent assault 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 6:16 PM EDT 2012-07-10 22:16:59 GMT Three members of one of the largest street gangs in the country, the Latin Kings, have been convicted for their part in a violent assault. A jury found Marshall Chandler guilty of kidnapping, aggravated More &gt;&gt; Three members of one of the largest street gangs in the country, the Latin Kings, have been convicted for their part in a violent assault.  More &gt;&gt; 
 Four die in Marion County car crash 

 Four die in Marion County car crash 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 5:22 PM EDT 2012-07-10 21:22:06 GMT Four people died, including three teenagers from the same family, in a single-car accident in Marion County on Monday. Sheriff Erkley Hall identified the victims as Cody, Dustin, and Brittany Young - More &gt;&gt; Four people died, including three teenagers from the same family, in a single-car accident in Marion County on Monday. More &gt;&gt; 
 State sued over special education in Jackson 

 State sued over special education in Jackson 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 4:39 PM EDT 2012-07-10 20:39:12 GMT Disability advocates have sued the Mississippi Department of Education, saying state officials haven&apos;t done enough to solve special education problems in the Jackson city schools. More &gt;&gt; Disability advocates have sued the Mississippi Department of Education, saying state officials haven&apos;t done enough to solve special education problems in the Jackson city schools. More &gt;&gt; 
 Alleged puppy mill found in Stone County 

 Alleged puppy mill found in Stone County 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 4:22 PM EDT 2012-07-10 20:22:28 GMT Authorities say they have seized 50 to 70 dogs at an alleged puppy mill in Stone County. More &gt;&gt; Authorities say they have seized 50 to 70 dogs at an alleged puppy mill in Stone County. The alleged mill was raided Tuesday by deputies and officials with the Humane Society of South Mississippi. More &gt;&gt; 
 One dead in Jackson house fire 

 One dead in Jackson house fire 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 3:47 PM EDT 2012-07-10 19:47:19 GMT Jackson Fire officials have confirmed one person was killed in a house fire Tuesday morning. More &gt;&gt; One man is dead after an early morning house fire in Jackson. The fire started in a house located at 1039 Marine Street. That&apos;s near the intersection of Martin Luther King Jr. Drive. More &gt;&gt; 
 Body found in Richland field identified 

 Body found in Richland field identified 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 12:42 PM EDT 2012-07-10 16:42:07 GMT Richland Police have identified the body of a 48-year-old man found Monday afternoon in a field. Police Chief Russel James says the man is Jeffrey W. Roy of 260 Lowe Circle, in Richland. Chief James More &gt;&gt; Richland Police have identified the body of a 48-year-old man found Monday afternoon in a field. Police Chief Russel James says the man is Jeffrey W. Roy of 260 Lowe Circle, in Richland. More &gt;&gt; 
 Yarber elected Jackson City Council President 

 Yarber elected Jackson City Council President 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 12:23 PM EDT 2012-07-10 16:23:30 GMT The Jackson City Council has elected Tony Yarber of Ward 6 to be its new president. Yarber was the council&apos;s former VP. Four council members voted for Yarber, while Charles Tillman voted for Frank Bluntson. More &gt;&gt; The Jackson City Council has elected Tony Yarber of Ward 6 to be its new president. Yarber was the council&apos;s former VP. More &gt;&gt; 
 Father accused in daughter&apos;s death made initial appearance 

 Father accused in daughter&apos;s death made initial appearance 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 11:38 AM EDT 2012-07-10 15:38:20 GMT The Jackson man accused of beating his young daughter to death made his initial court appearance on Capital Murder charges Monday. Twenty eight year old Johnny Williams turned away from cameras and had More &gt;&gt; The Jackson man accused of beating his young daughter to death made his initial court appearance on Capital Murder charges Monday. More &gt;&gt; 
 More Rain&amp;More Muggy 

 More Rain&amp;More Muggy 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 11:04 AM EDT 2012-07-10 15:04:05 GMT The early morning hours have already feature some scattered showers coming out of the Louisiana boot heel, slow traffic slightly. Expect highs to stay below the norm for this time of the year. But because More &gt;&gt; The early morning hours have already feature some scattered showers coming out of the Louisiana boot heel, slow traffic slightly. Expect highs to stay below the norm for this time of the year. But because of the increase in humidity, it will still&apos;feel like&apos;the 90s. More &gt;&gt; 
 Taking Back Our Neighborhood - East Street blight 

 Taking Back Our Neighborhood - East Street blight 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 12:10 AM EDT 2012-07-10 04:10:10 GMT This taking back our neighborhood report takes us to a south Jackson subdivision called Alta Woods, specifically 2015 East Street. A homeowner who lives across the street called 3 On Your Side for help More &gt;&gt; This taking back our neighborhood report takes us to a south Jackson subdivision called Alta Woods, specifically 2015 East Street. A homeowner who lives across the street called 3 On Your Side for help getting someone to do something about the eyesore. More &gt;&gt; 
 Search for murder suspect continues 

 Search for murder suspect continues 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 10:21 PM EDT 2012-07-10 02:21:39 GMT A murder warrant has been issued in the death of a 32-year-old Jackson man killed last month. Rayco Davenport was found lying in the street at Lynda and Daniels streets June 10. More &gt;&gt; Police are searching for 28-year-old Larry Lewis in connection with the murder of a Jackson man last month. More &gt;&gt; 
 Jackson couple arrested with drugs, guns and cash 

 Jackson couple arrested with drugs, guns and cash 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 10:10 PM EDT 2012-07-10 02:10:15 GMT A Jackson couple is behind bars, facing a number of drug charges and a child endangerment. Shermedrick Day, 28, and his girlfriend Charity Barton, 26, are charged with possession of marijuana with the More &gt;&gt; A Jackson couple is behind bars, facing a number of drug charges and a child endangerment.
Shermedrick Day, 28, and his girlfriend Charity Barton, 26, are charged with possession of marijuana with the intent to distribute. More &gt;&gt; 
 Jackson church helps homeowners with major home repairs 

 Jackson church helps homeowners with major home repairs 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 9:54 PM EDT 2012-07-10 01:54:08 GMT Jackson resident Ginnette Robinson has lots of extra company and noise in her house this week. Robinson&apos;s house, located in the Broadmoor neighborhood is the site of a major make-over. On Monday cracked More &gt;&gt; Imagine receiving thousands of dollars worth of home renovations for free! Well, thanks to a local church, that&apos;s what&apos;s happening for some well-deserving homeowners in Jackson. More &gt;&gt; 
 School menus are about to change 

 School menus are about to change 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 9:41 PM EDT 2012-07-10 01:41:31 GMT The folks responsible for what goes on the serving tray when school kids file through lunch and breakfast lines across the state were at the Clyde Muse Center Monday getting ready for the school year. They More &gt;&gt; The folks responsible for what goes on the serving tray when school kids file through lunch and breakfast lines across the state were at the Clyde Muse Center Monday getting ready for the school year. More &gt;&gt; 
 Former NW Rankin coach remembered 

 Former NW Rankin coach remembered 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 8:34 PM EDT 2012-07-10 00:34:59 GMT A memorial service for David Coates was held Monday morning at Pinelake Church in Brandon. More &gt;&gt; A memorial service for David Coates was held Monday morning at Pinelake Church in Brandon. More &gt;&gt; 
 House burglars caught by Jackson police 

 House burglars caught by Jackson police 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 8:05 PM EDT 2012-07-10 00:05:47 GMT Three house burglars were caught in the act in northeast Jackson Monday afternoon. It happened at 5428 Jamaica Drive, just east of I-55 near the intersection of Wayneland Drive.  More &gt;&gt; Three house burglars were caught in the act in northeast Jackson Monday afternoon. It happened at 5428 Jamaica Drive, just east of I-55 near the intersection of Wayneland Drive.  More &gt;&gt; 
 Delayed outlet center finally gets green light 

 Delayed outlet center finally gets green light 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 7:14 PM EDT 2012-07-09 23:14:35 GMT A new outlet center is headed to the metro area, and it will be open for business in just over a year. The outlets at Bloomfield have been in the works since 2004, but in recent years the project lost More &gt;&gt; A new outlet center is headed to the metro area, and it will be open for business in just over a year. The outlets at Bloomfield have been in the works since 2004, but in recent years the project lost steam as the economy slumped. More &gt;&gt; 
 Body found near Richland Walmart 

 Body found near Richland Walmart 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 7:03 PM EDT 2012-07-09 23:03:52 GMT Richland Police have found a body on East Harper Street, in the field across from Walmart. Officers responded to a call about buzzards in the area. When they searched the field they the partially decomposed More &gt;&gt; Richland Police have found a body on East Harper Street, in the field across from Walmart. Officers responded to a call about buzzards in the area. More &gt;&gt; 
 Person of interest held in Rankin County woman&apos;s death 

 Person of interest held in Rankin Co. woman&apos;s death 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 6:46 PM EDT 2012-07-09 22:46:35 GMT One person is in custody in connection with the death of a Rankin County woman found in an Issaquena County lake. Sheriff Richard Jones identified the victim as Colleen Jane Parkman, 52, of Richland. More &gt;&gt; One person is in custody in connection with the death of a Rankin County woman found in an Issaquena County lake. Sheriff Richard Jones identified the victim as Colleen Jane Parkman, 52, of Richland. More &gt;&gt; 
 Rubenstein to be honored with award 

 Rubenstein to be honored with award 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 6:29 PM EDT 2012-07-09 22:29:02 GMT The Mississippi Sports Hall of Fame in Jackson will honor its late director, Michael Rubenstein, with a new award. More &gt;&gt; The Mississippi Sports Hall of Fame in Jackson will honor its late director, Michael Rubenstein, with a new award. More &gt;&gt; 
 AG&apos;s office warns against scams with utility company 

 AG&apos;s office warns against scams with utility company 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 12:52 PM EDT 2012-07-09 16:52:19 GMT A rural electricity cooperative has stopped taking electronic checks because scammers are taking advantage of customers. Southern Pine Electric Power Association isn&apos;t the only utility company being More &gt;&gt; A rural electricity cooperative has stopped taking electronic checks because scammers are taking advantage of customers. More &gt;&gt; 
 Former police officer appeals rape conviction 

 Former police officer appeals rape conviction 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 12:49 PM EDT 2012-07-09 16:49:58 GMT A former Jackson police officer sentenced to 75 years in prison for statutory rape involving his girlfriend&apos;s daughter has appealed his conviction. More &gt;&gt; A former Jackson police officer sentenced to 75 years in prison for statutory rape involving his girlfriend&apos;s daughter has appealed his conviction. More &gt;&gt; 
 Renardo Sidney takes responsibility for issues on-and-off floor 

 Renardo Sidney sits down with Rob Jay 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 11:29 AM EDT 2012-07-09 15:29:06 GMT Embattled former Mississippi State basketball player Renardo Sidney sat down with WLBT Sports Director Rob Jay for a candid interview about what went wrong in his two years in Starkville. More &gt;&gt; Embattled former Mississippi State basketball player Renardo Sidney sat down with WLBT Sports Director Rob Jay for a candid interview about what went wrong in his two years in Starkville. More &gt;&gt; 
 Not So Hot; afternoon showers possible 

 Not So Hot; afternoon showers possible 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 11:26 AM EDT 2012-07-09 15:26:21 GMT The additional clouds for today will play in our favor in avoiding the oppressive heat that we dealt with last week. There&apos;s a 50-60% chance of spot showers during the afternoon hours. Highs will be closer More &gt;&gt; The additional clouds for today will play in our favor in avoiding the oppressive heat that we dealt with last week. There&apos;s a 50-60% chance of spot showers during the afternoon hours. Highs will be closer to the norm for today and slightly below this entire work week; staying in the lower 90s. More &gt;&gt; 
 Rankin County woman&apos;s body found in lake 

 Rankin County woman&apos;s body found in lake 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 11:21 AM EDT 2012-07-09 15:21:52 GMT The body of a Madison county woman was found early Sunday morning in a lake in Issaquena county, and now authorities are trying to determine how she died. Issaquena County Coroner Angela Williams said More &gt;&gt; The body of a Rankin County woman was found early Sunday morning in a lake in Issaquena County, and now authorities are trying to determine how she died. More &gt;&gt; 
 Warren County posts to get pay hikes 

 3 Warren County posts to get pay hikes 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 8:44 AM EDT 2012-07-09 12:44:59 GMT Warren County supervisors have voted to raises the salaries of the next fire coordinator and two positions in which some of the job&apos;s old duties will be handled. More &gt;&gt; Warren County supervisors have voted to raises the salaries of the next fire coordinator and two positions in which some of the job&apos;s old duties will be handled. More &gt;&gt; 
 Wet roads may have caused a south Jackson car accident 

 Wet roads may have caused a south Jackson car accident 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 12:53 AM EDT 2012-07-09 04:53:52 GMT Sunday evening thundershowers may have played a role in an I-55 car accident. The unidentified driver of a white Chevrolet Malibu lost control of the vehicle near the Elton Road exit, in the northbound More &gt;&gt; Two women escape injury after the vehicle they were riding in slams into the median on I-55, and wet roads my have played a role in the accident. More &gt;&gt; 
 Woman seeks $1.5 million in lawsuit against Vicksburg mayor 

 Woman seeks $1.5 million in lawsuit against Vicksburg mayor 
 Updated: Sunday, July 8 2012 8:22 PM EDT 2012-07-09 00:22:58 GMT The former Chief Of Staff to Vicksburg&apos;s mayor is seeking $1.5 million in a sexual harassment lawsuit. Kenya Burks is asking for back wages and compensatory damages. Burks claims she faced a hostile More &gt;&gt; The former Chief Of Staff to Vicksburg&apos;s mayor is seeking $1.5 million in a sexual harassment lawsuit. More &gt;&gt; 
 Man whose mother stops robbery is headed to court 

 Man whose mother stops robbery is headed to court 
 Updated: Sunday, July 8 2012 7:53 PM EDT 2012-07-08 23:53:34 GMT The man who was stopped from robbing a convenience store by his mother is scheduled to go to court Wednesday. Roy Mitchell was caught on video attempting to rob D&apos;s One Stop Convenience Store on Highway More &gt;&gt; The man who was stopped from robbing a convenience store by his mother is scheduled to go to court Wednesday. More &gt;&gt; 
 Wet Week Ahead 

 Wet Week Ahead 
 Updated: Sunday, July 8 2012 7:33 PM EDT 2012-07-08 23:33:07 GMT Good Evening, Storms are continuing to develop to the south of I-20 this afternoon. As these storms move to the north, it will help with the development of storms in and around the Jackson area. Brief More &gt;&gt; Hit-an-miss storms are possible through mid-evening. Brief lightning and gusty winds are the main threat with this activity More &gt;&gt; 
 Father arrested in connection with child&apos;s beating death 

 Father arrested in connection with child&apos;s beating death 
 Updated: Sunday, July 8 2012 1:16 AM EDT 2012-07-08 05:16:36 GMT The Jackson man wanted in connection with the beating death of his child is behind bars. J.P.D. Officer Colendula Green said 28 year old Johnny Williams was arrested Friday on capital murder charges. According More &gt;&gt; The Jackson man wanted in connection with the beating death of his child is behind bars. More &gt;&gt; 
 10th Annual Black Rodeo comes to Jackson 

 10th Annual Black Rodeo comes to Jackson 
 Updated: Sunday, July 8 2012 1:05 AM EDT 2012-07-08 05:05:00 GMT Saturday morning the Mississippi Black Rodeo Parade pranced through the streets of downtown Jackson. This afternoon cowboys thrilled the crowds straight out of the gate. It is billed &quot;the baddest show More &gt;&gt; Saturday morning the Mississippi Black Rodeo Parade pranced through the streets of downtown Jackson. More &gt;&gt; 
 Car engulfed in flames in Attala County 

 Car engulfed in flames in Attala County 
 Updated: Sunday, July 8 2012 12:28 AM EDT 2012-07-08 04:28:46 GMT A vehicle fire lit up the night sky and kept firefighters busy late Friday night in Attala County . This information comes to us from kosyonline.com. It happened around 10:45 on Highway 35 south at More &gt;&gt; A vehicle fire lit up the night sky and kept firefighters busy late Friday night in Attala County . More &gt;&gt; 
 Jackson crash sends at least one to the hospital 

 Jackson crash sends at least one to the hospital 
 Updated: Sunday, July 8 2012 12:06 AM EDT 2012-07-08 04:06:19 GMT A serious car accident on Clinton Boulevard, in west Jackson, sends at least one person to the hospital Saturday night. It happened shortly after 9 P.M. Two cars landed in a ditch, after what appears More &gt;&gt; A possible head on collision in west Jackson sends at least one person to the hospital.

  More &gt;&gt; 
 Death penalty weighed for inmates charged in death 

 Death penalty weighed for inmates charged in death 
 Federal prosecutors have until July 30 to decide whether to seek the death penalty for two inmates charged with kidnapping and killing an Ohio businessman in Mississippi after escaping from a prison work program in... More &gt;&gt; Federal prosecutors have until July 30 to decide whether to seek the death penalty for two inmates charged with kidnapping and killing an Ohio businessman in Mississippi after escaping from a prison work program in Louisiana. More &gt;&gt; 
 Increasing rain chances; decreasing temperatures 

 Increasing rain chances; decreasing temperatures 
 Updated: Saturday, July 7 2012 8:29 PM EDT 2012-07-08 00:29:21 GMT The weather pattern across the country will undergo some changes. This is great news for many people, including those of us in Mississippi as it means some relief to the heat and the drought. I expect More &gt;&gt; The weather pattern across the country will undergo some changes. This is great news for many people, including those of us in Mississippi as it means some relief to the heat and the drought. I expect More &gt;&gt; 
 Driver jumps before 18-wheeler collides with train 

 Driver jumps before 18-wheeler collides with train 
 Updated: Saturday, July 7 2012 6:21 PM EDT 2012-07-07 22:21:24 GMT Emergency responders were on the scene of an accident involving a train and an 18 wheeler in Rankin County. It occurred around 9 p.m. Friday night. Pelahatchie Police confirm the 18 wheeler was struck More &gt;&gt; Emergency responders were on the scene of an accident involving a train and an 18 wheeler in Rankin County. More &gt;&gt; 
 Judge denies JPD officer bond 

 Judge denies JPD officer bond 
 Updated: Saturday, July 7 2012 4:48 PM EDT 2012-07-07 20:48:07 GMT A federal judge has denied bond for a Jackson Police Officer who wanted out of jail to await trial on charges that he and two other officers took bribes. U.S. District Judge Daniel Jordan refused to grant More &gt;&gt; A federal judge has denied bond for a Jackson Police Officer who wanted out of jail to await trial on charges that he and two other officers took bribes. More &gt;&gt; 
 Jackson church hosts food giveaway 

 Jackson church hosts food giveaway 
 Updated: Saturday, July 7 2012 3:18 PM EDT 2012-07-07 19:18:38 GMT A long line of cars waited in the heat along Prentiss Street Saturday morning. 400 families were pre-screened, their need confirmed, and they&apos;re all getting at least three boxes per family of food and More &gt;&gt; Members of the Jackson Revival Center Church have filled thousands of boxes with food and toiletries, and families in need are the recipients. More &gt;&gt; 
 Burnt toast prompts evacuation 

 Burnt toast prompts evacuation 
 Updated: Saturday, July 7 2012 1:03 PM EDT 2012-07-07 17:03:09 GMT Burnt toast created a scare at the Waterford Retirement Home in Ridgeland Saturday morning. Smoke detectors went off, and Ridgeland firefighters responded just after 8am. Waterford Executive Director More &gt;&gt; A smoking piece of toast at the Waterford at Highland Colony Retirement Community led to an evacuation. More &gt;&gt; 
 Graves appeals, fights to stay on ballot 

 Graves appeals, fights to stay on ballot 
 Updated: Saturday, July 7 2012 9:18 AM EDT 2012-07-07 13:18:03 GMT An incumbent Hinds County Election Commissioner who missed the deadline to file for re-election, continues her fight to get her name on the ballot. On Friday, District 2 Election Commissioner Bobbie More &gt;&gt; District 2 Election Commissioner has filed notice that she&apos;s appealing Hinds Supervisors&apos;vote that will keep her off the ballot. More &gt;&gt; 
 Thunderstorms possible this afternoon 

 Thunderstorms possible this afternoon 
 Updated: Saturday, July 7 2012 7:33 AM EDT 2012-07-07 11:33:07 GMT Like the past few afternoons, I expect some of you will have to deal with storms. Most of the storms will be scattered in nature, but they may be strong. The main severe threat will be in the form of straight-line More &gt;&gt; Like the past few afternoons, I expect some of you will have to deal with storms. Most of the storms will be scattered in nature, but they may be strong. The main severe threat will be in the form of straight-line More &gt;&gt; 
 Jackson councilman speaks about JFD investigation&amp;rap video 

 Jackson councilman speaks about JFD investigation&amp;rap video 
 Updated: Saturday, July 7 2012 1:08 AM EDT 2012-07-07 05:08:29 GMT In the first few scenes of Hollywood Luck&apos;s rap video, &quot;A Pole in my Pants,&quot; you see a fire truck slowly turn in to a parking lot. A man wearing a fireman&apos;s gear gets out of the fire engine, then he takes More &gt;&gt; A Jackson city councilman speaks out about the fire department&apos;s investigation into the possible misuse of a fire engine in a rap video. More &gt;&gt; 
 Arrest made in fatal July 4th shooting 

 Arrest made in fatal July 4th shooting 
 Updated: Saturday, July 7 2012 12:57 AM EDT 2012-07-07 04:57:52 GMT Authorities have arrested a man wanted in connection to a deadly shooting in the Capital City on the 4th of July. Jeremy Walters was taken into custody Friday by officials with the department of corrections. Walters More &gt;&gt; Authorities have arrested a man wanted in connection to a deadly shooting in the Capital City on the 4th of July. More &gt;&gt; 
 Vehicle fire slowed 5 p.m. traffic Friday evening 

 Vehicle fire slowed 5 p.m. traffic Friday evening 
 Updated: Friday, July 6 2012 10:49 PM EDT 2012-07-07 02:49:27 GMT A vehicle fire delayed the evening commute for motorists traveling on I-220 Friday. Skycopter 3 captured video just before 5 p.m. It shows a vehicle so badly burned, we couldn&apos;t tell what it was. It More &gt;&gt; A vehicle fire delayed the evening commute for motorists traveling on I-220 Friday.  More &gt;&gt; 
 Where does Homestead Heights stand? 

 Where does Homestead Heights stand? 
 Updated: Friday, July 6 2012 10:06 PM EDT 2012-07-07 02:06:19 GMT Two years ago this month, the Jackson Medical Mall Foundation held a groundbreaking for its first-ever housing development, on the corner of Prosperity and Easy Streets in the Homestead Heights neighborhood. More &gt;&gt; Two years ago, the Jackson Medical Mall Foundation broke ground for a new and improved Homestead Heights subdivision. The project aimed to provide quality, low cost housing with the construction of 24 new homes. Did the project ever take off? More &gt;&gt; 
 Traveling the world to make a difference 

 Traveling the world to make a difference 
 Updated: Friday, July 6 2012 9:20 PM EDT 2012-07-07 01:20:33 GMT J. D. Lewis has enough bracelets on his arm to make any world traveler jealous. &quot;This one is from Australia and that&apos;s from Haiti,&quot; Lewis says pointing out the various bands. His journey however, through More &gt;&gt; J. D. Lewis has enough bracelets on his arm to make any world traveler jealous. His journey however, through 12 countries in 12 months, is more than just an extended vacation. More &gt;&gt; 
 Florence man arrested for child molestation 

 Florence man arrested for child molestation 
 Updated: Friday, July 6 2012 8:30 PM EDT 2012-07-07 00:30:31 GMT A Florence man has been arrested for molesting children. 46 year old Harvey Eugene Langdon was taken into custody Thursday by Richland police and charged with four counts of molestation. Some incidents More &gt;&gt; Florence man arrested on multiple counts of child molestation. More &gt;&gt; 
 Remembering William Faulkner 

 Remembering William Faulkner 
 Updated: Friday, July 6 2012 7:25 PM EDT 2012-07-06 23:25:53 GMT Friday marked the 50th anniversary of the death of world famed Mississippi author William Faulkner. More than 23,000 people a year, from all over the world, still visit his Oxford home. Ole Miss students More &gt;&gt; Friday marked the 50th anniversary of the death of world famed Mississippi author William Faulkner. More than 23,000 people a year, from all over the world, still visit his Oxford home. More &gt;&gt; 
 Attempted robbery at Jackson bank 

 Attempted robbery at Jackson bank 
 Updated: Friday, July 6 2012 6:37 PM EDT 2012-07-06 22:37:07 GMT A bank robber came away empty handed Friday morning when he tried to rob the Regions Bank at 947 North State, in Jackson. The man, described as a black male wearing all black, passed the teller a note More &gt;&gt; A bank robber came away empty handed Friday morning when he tried to rob the Regions Bank at 947 North State, in Jackson. More &gt;&gt; 
 Millions available to help pay summer utility bills 

 Millions available to help pay summer utility bills 
 Updated: Friday, July 6 2012 12:51 PM EDT 2012-07-06 16:51:21 GMT If the summer heat is putting a strain on your thermostat and your utility bills are soaring you might consider applying for a portion of $13 million in federally funded LIHEAP money. &quot;It&apos;s going More &gt;&gt; Relief could be available for those of you struggling to pay your summer utility bills. The state of Mississippi has millions of dollars to help qualified families keep cool this summer. More &gt;&gt; 
 More rain&amp;lower temps?? 

 More rain&amp;lower temps?? 
 Updated: Friday, July 6 2012 9:32 AM EDT 2012-07-06 13:32:15 GMT A slight chance of rain will go on the increase for this afternoon as we raise our chances from a meager 20% to an impressive 40% chance of isolated T-storms. Highs will reach into the upper 90s and the More &gt;&gt; A slight chance of rain will go on the increase for this afternoon as we raise our chances from a meager 20% to an impressive 40% chance of isolated T-storms. Highs will reach into the upper 90s and the Heat Advisory for northern Mississippi counties will stay in effect for today. More &gt;&gt; 
 J.F.D. ladder truck possibly used in music video 

 J.F.D. ladder truck possibly used in music video 
 Fire department leaders in Mississippi&apos;s capital city say they&apos;re investigating whether a department truck and gear were used in a local rapper&apos;s suggestive music video. More &gt;&gt; Fire department leaders in Mississippi&apos;s capital city say they&apos;re investigating whether a department truck and gear were used in a local rapper&apos;s suggestive music video. More &gt;&gt; 
 Vicksburg church catches fire due to lightning strike 

 Vicksburg church catches fire due to lightning strike 
 Updated: Thursday, July 5 2012 10:35 PM EDT 2012-07-06 02:35:12 GMT Lightning struck a powerline and a church in Vicksburg and caused the church to catch fire Thursday afternoon. Rose Hill M.B. Church is located at 683 Stenson Road near Highway 27. Check back for updates More &gt;&gt; Lightning struck a powerline and a church in Vicksburg and caused the church to catch fire Thursday evening. More &gt;&gt; 
 More counties issue burn restrictions 

 More counties issue burn restrictions 
 Updated: Thursday, July 5 2012 10:25 PM EDT 2012-07-06 02:25:21 GMT Burn bans have been issued for 33 counties in Mississippi because of the dry conditions. That number is expected to continue rising until there is a long period of rain. The fire danger was lessened More &gt;&gt; Burn bans have been issued for 33 counties in Mississippi because of the dry conditions. That number is expected to continue rising until there is a long period of rain.  More &gt;&gt; 
 Former JPD officer accused of taking bribes is denied bond 

 Former JPD officer accused of taking bribes is denied bond 
 Updated: Thursday, July 5 2012 10:10 PM EDT 2012-07-06 02:10:51 GMT A former Jackson police officer, charged with accepting bribes, has once again been denied bond. According to court documents, Federal Judge Linda Anderson believes Monyette Q. Jefferson poses a serious More &gt;&gt; A former Jackson police officer, charged with accepting bribes, has once again been denied bond. According to court documents, Federal Judge Linda Anderson believes Monyette Q. Jefferson poses a serious risk of endangering the public. More &gt;&gt; 
 I-55 Exit Ramp in Madison County back open 

 I-55 Exit Ramp in Madison County back open 
 Updated: Thursday, July 5 2012 10:04 PM EDT 2012-07-06 02:04:19 GMT The I-55 northbound exit ramp at Highway 16 (Exit 124) in Madison County is back open after being shut down for several hours. More &gt;&gt; The I-55 northbound exit ramp at Highway 16 (Exit 124) in Madison County is back open after being shut down for several hours. More &gt;&gt; 
 Jackson mother charged with capital murder in child&apos;s death 

 Jackson mother charged with capital murder in child&apos;s death 
 Updated: Thursday, July 5 2012 8:27 PM EDT 2012-07-06 00:27:18 GMT A young Jackson mother is facing capital murder charges in the death of her 18 month old child. July 3 police responded toCentral Mississippi Medical Center after reports of suspected child abuse. Police More &gt;&gt; A Jackson mother is facing capital murder charges in the death of her 18-month-old child. The child&apos;s father is wanted by Jackson police. More &gt;&gt; 
 FDA approves over-the-counter HIV tests 

 FDA approves over-the-counter HIV tests 
 Updated: Thursday, July 5 2012 8:15 PM EDT 2012-07-06 00:15:20 GMT By gliding a swab on her gums, Prevention Counselor Charlotte Norwood showed how easy it is to test for HIV. &quot;It&apos;s important to get tested and know your status,&quot; Norwood told WLBT. Within just twenty More &gt;&gt; For the first time, the federal government has approved the sale of over the counter HIV testing kits. However, state governments, including Mississippi, must adopt the law before the tests are made available locally More &gt;&gt; 
 JPD investigates deadly 4th of July shooting 

 JPD investigates deadly 4th of July shooting 
 Updated: Thursday, July 5 2012 7:59 PM EDT 2012-07-05 23:59:49 GMT Jackson police are investigating a 4th of July shooting. It happened just before 10pm at 5255 Manhattan Road. 21 year-old Fredrick Williams was pronounced dead on the scene. Anyone who can help provide More &gt;&gt; Jackson police are investigating a 4th of July shooting. It happened just before 10pm at 5255 Manhattan Road. More &gt;&gt; 
 Lawmakers vow for push in Medicaid expansion 

 Lawmakers vow for push in Medicaid expansion 
 Updated: Thursday, July 5 2012 6:43 PM EDT 2012-07-05 22:43:05 GMT When members of Mississippi&apos;s Legislative Black Caucus, all democrats, vowed to push for Medicaid expansion next year, senator and caucus chairman Kenneth Jones of Canton knew it wouldn&apos;t be easy. &quot;We More &gt;&gt; When members of Mississippi&apos;s Legislative Black Caucus, all democrats, vowed to push for Medicaid expansion next year, senator and caucus chairman Kenneth Jones of Canton knew it wouldn&apos;t be easy. More &gt;&gt; 
 Car breakins rattle apartment tenants 

 Car breakins rattle apartment tenants 
 Updated: Thursday, July 5 2012 4:33 PM EDT 2012-07-05 20:33:25 GMT The Highland View Apartment complex in Jackson is a port in a storm residents say -- a quaint haven among other neighborhoods that are crime-ridden and run down. It&apos;s a U.S. Department of Housing and More &gt;&gt; The Highland View Apartment complex in Jackson is a port in a storm, residents say -- a quaint haven among other neighborhoods that are crime-ridden and run down. But in the past few weeks, two cars have been stolen and two others were vandalized. More &gt;&gt; 
 Woman injured in purse snatching 

 Woman injured in purse snatching 
 Updated: Thursday, July 5 2012 1:03 PM EDT 2012-07-05 17:03:08 GMT Jackson Police are investigating a purse snatching that left a woman injured Thursday morning. It happened just after 10 AM at World Health Industries at 1485 Livingston Lane. Police say a black male More &gt;&gt; Jackson Police are investigating a purse snatching that left a woman injured Thursday morning. It happened just after 10 AM at World Health Industries at 1485 Livingston Lane.  More &gt;&gt; 
 Clinton man drives car into tree 

 Clinton man drives car into tree 
 Updated: Thursday, July 5 2012 11:29 AM EDT 2012-07-05 15:29:37 GMT A Clinton man suffered minor injuries this morning at the Regions Bank on Clinton Boulevard. Firefighters at the scene say the man had just left the drive-thru, when his car crashed into at tree. The More &gt;&gt; A Clinton man suffered minor injuries this morning at the Regions Bank on Clinton Boulevard. Firefighters at the scene say the man had just left the drive-thru, when his car crashed into at tree. More &gt;&gt; 
 Reports: DHS response to child abuse too slow 

 Reports: DHS response to child abuse too slow 
 Updated: Thursday, July 5 2012 10:25 AM EDT 2012-07-05 14:25:27 GMT A new report finds Mississippi is failing to investigate most child abuse complaints from children in its care within the required 24 hours or complete most investigations within 30 days. More &gt;&gt; A new report finds Mississippi is failing to investigate most child abuse complaints from children in its care within the required 24 hours or complete most investigations within 30 days. More &gt;&gt; 
 Could We See More Spot Storms?????? 

 Could We See More Spot Storms?????? 
 Updated: Thursday, July 5 2012 6:35 AM EDT 2012-07-05 10:35:02 GMT The luxury of a spot shower cooled us down to tolerable afternoon conditions on yesterday, and we&apos;re expecting close to the same today. Highs will reach into the upper 90s with the winds from the north More &gt;&gt; The luxury of a spot shower cooled us down to tolerable afternoon conditions on yesterday, and we&apos;re expecting close to the same today. Highs will reach into the upper 90s with the winds from the north west at 5-10 mph. There will still be a 20% chance of a quick developing and random afternoon shower. More &gt;&gt; 
 July 4th celebration at the Craft Center 

 July 4th celebration at the Craft Center 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 4 2012 10:16 PM EDT 2012-07-05 02:16:54 GMT Attendance for this year&apos;s Fourth of July celebration at the Mississippi Craft Center in Ridgeland was the best it&apos;s ever been. The Craft Center is a 20,000 square foot facility that was open this holiday More &gt;&gt; Attendance for this year&apos;s Fourth of July celebration at the Mississippi Craft Center in Ridgeland was the best it&apos;s ever been. The Craft Center is a 20,000 square foot facility that was open this holiday from 11 a.m. to 2 p.m. More &gt;&gt; 
 Leake Co. man dies after crashing into creek 

 Leake Co. man dies after crashing into creek 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 4 2012 9:42 PM EDT 2012-07-05 01:42:52 GMT A Carthage man was killed in a one vehicle accident overnight in Rankin County. According to the Rankin County Sheriff&apos;s Department, Brelan Alexander, 83, was traveling on Andrew Chapel Road More &gt;&gt; A Carthage man was killed in a one vehicle accident overnight in Rankin County. According to the Rankin County Sheriff&apos;s Department, Brelan Alexander, 83, was traveling on Andrew Chapel Road when his 2008 Chevrolet Colorado left the roadway and crashed into a creek.  More &gt;&gt; 
 Chilling at the Jackson Zoo 

 Chilling at the Jackson Zoo 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 4 2012 8:19 PM EDT 2012-07-05 00:19:29 GMT With a heat index of 104 degrees, one of the coolest places to be was the Jackson Zoological Park. Animals at the zoo, like a 300 pound tiger, sought out a shady spot. More &gt;&gt; With a heat index of 104 degrees, one of the coolest places to be was the Jackson Zoological Park. Animals at the zoo, like a 300 pound tiger, sought out a shady spot. More &gt;&gt; 
 VIDEO: Man busted by his mom during robbery 

 VIDEO: Man busted by his mom during robbery 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 4 2012 7:30 PM EDT 2012-07-04 23:30:39 GMT A Brandon man sits in jail tonight after a failed robbery attempt. He has his mother to thank for that. She stopped him during the middle of his crime, taking away his weapon he had aimed at the clerk. More &gt;&gt; A Brandon man is in jail after a failed robbery attempt, and he has his mother to thank. Twenty-two-year-old Roy Mitchell&apos;s mother stopped him during the middle of his crime by taking away the weapon he had aimed at the clerk. It was all caught on video. More &gt;&gt; 
 Bryant puts focus on state tourism 

 Bryant puts focus on state tourism 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 4 2012 5:23 PM EDT 2012-07-04 21:23:08 GMT Whether it&apos;s for vacation or a holiday getaway, this is prime time for Mississippi to cash in on tourism dollars and if you ask Governor Phil Bryant, it&apos;s a crucial time for the state&apos;s economy. &quot;We&apos;re More &gt;&gt; 
Whether it&apos;s for vacation or a holiday getaway, this is prime time for Mississippi to cash in on tourism dollars and if you ask Governor Phil Bryant, it&apos;s a crucial time for the state&apos;s economy. More &gt;&gt; 
 SLIDESHOW: July 4, 2012 - Your Pictures 

 SLIDESHOW: July 4, 2012 - Your Pictures 
 Here are the pictures you sent us, showing how you celebrated the 4th of July. We&apos;ll be adding pictures throughout the day. More &gt;&gt; 
 Clinton neighborhood celebrates 4th of July 

 Clinton neighborhood celebrates 4th of July 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 4 2012 4:08 PM EDT 2012-07-04 20:08:22 GMT The Billy Byrd neighborhood in Clinton held its traditional 4th of July parade Wednesday morning. Children grabbed candy thrown by Clinton fire trucks and families rode on bicycles and ATV&apos;s, and classic More &gt;&gt; The Billy Byrd neighborhood in Clinton held its traditional 4th of July parade Wednesday morning. More &gt;&gt; 
 List of counties issuing burn bans growing 

 List of counties issuing burn bans growing 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 4 2012 3:04 PM EDT 2012-07-04 19:04:48 GMT Scorching temperatures and dry conditions have forced areas across Mississippi to impose restrictions on burning.  More &gt;&gt; Scorching temperatures and dry conditions have forced areas across Mississippi to impose restrictions on burning.  More &gt;&gt; 
 Brandon woman to carry Olympic flame 

 Brandon woman to carry Olympic flame 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 4 2012 2:52 PM EDT 2012-07-04 18:52:59 GMT A Brandon woman will carry the Olympic flame in her hometown of London. More &gt;&gt; A woman who calls Brandon home for half of the year is heading back to her other home in London, England on Saturday for a very important event. Jacky Stimpson is leaving for her native home, because she was selected to carry the Olympic torch. More &gt;&gt; 
 Bullet goes through Jackson store window 

 Bullet goes through Jackson store window 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 4 2012 2:10 PM EDT 2012-07-04 18:10:13 GMT A bullet went through the window of a south Jackson convenience store around noon Wednesday. It happened at the Quickstop at 1503 W. McDowell Road. No one was injured in the incident. Jackson police More &gt;&gt; A bullet went through the window of a south Jackson convenience store around noon Wednesday. More &gt;&gt; 
 Runners celebrate the 4th with a 5K 

 Runners celebrate the 4th with a 5K 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 4 2012 1:24 PM EDT 2012-07-04 17:24:13 GMT Independence Day is off to an early start for racers in the Watermelon Classic 5K. More &gt;&gt; Many of you started your Fourth of July off by lacing up your tennis shoes and enjoying some fresh watermelon. The &quot;Watermelon Classic,&quot; one of Jackson&apos;s most popular, family friendly races got underway bright and early Wednesday morning. A record crowd turned out for this year&apos;s event. More &gt;&gt; 
 SLIDESHOW: Watermelon Classic 5K 

 SLIDESHOW: Watermelon Classic 5K 
 The 30th annual Watermelon Classic 5K kicked off at 7:30 a.m., outside the Mississippi Sports Hall of Fame Museum in Jackson. More &gt;&gt; 
 State to get hundreds of millions for restoration 

 State to get hundreds of millions for restoration 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 4 2012 11:38 AM EDT 2012-07-04 15:38:01 GMT The oil may be gone from Mississippi&apos;s coast line, but the impacts are still lingering and thanks to congressional passage of the RESTORE Act, BP&apos;s financial penalties are set to restore the damage. &quot;They More &gt;&gt; The oil may be gone from Mississippi&apos;s coast line, but the impacts are still lingering and thanks to congressional passage of the RESTORE Act, BP&apos;s financial penalties are set to restore the damage. More &gt;&gt; 
 Starkville woman accused of drugging kids at daycare 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 4 2012 10:42 AM EDT 2012-07-04 14:42:20 GMT A Starkville city judge has scheduled for Sept. 20 the trial of a former child care provider accused of felony abuse. More &gt;&gt; A Starkville city judge has scheduled for Sept. 20 the trial of a former child care provider accused of felony abuse. More &gt;&gt; 
 More Heat, Yet Again... 

 More Heat, Yet Again... 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 4 2012 6:47 AM EDT 2012-07-04 10:47:05 GMT Scattered Clouds are expected for today with the muggy conditions being a main part of the forecast overall picture. There&apos;s a slight chance of spot showers for this afternoon, with winds from the west More &gt;&gt; Scattered Clouds are expected for today with the muggy conditions being a main part of the forecast overall picture. There&apos;s a slight chance of spot showers for this afternoon, with winds from the west at 5-10 mph. Watch for a 20-30% chance of isolated T-storms during the afternoon hours. More &gt;&gt; 
 Women unearth their worth at buried treasures home ministry 

 Women unearth their worth at buried treasures home ministry 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 3 2012 11:55 PM EDT 2012-07-04 03:55:16 GMT A small group of women gather together daily for Bible study and devotion. With eyes closed and heads bowed each woman says a prayer. There&apos;s something unique and special about the women sitting together. More &gt;&gt; A retired husband and wife have dedicated their lives to uncovering many of Mississippi&apos;s &quot;buried treasures.&quot; The buried treasures we&apos;re talking about aren&apos;t lifeless underground objects, but they&apos;re living among us every day. More &gt;&gt; 
 Black lawmakers support Medicaid expansion 

 Black lawmakers support Medicaid expansion 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 3 2012 11:54 PM EDT 2012-07-04 03:54:12 GMT Black lawmakers in Mississippi say they support an expansion of the Medicaid program as part of the federal health care overhaul. The lawmakers say they will seek legislation to ratify covering more More &gt;&gt; Black lawmakers in Mississippi say they support an expansion of the Medicaid program as part of the federal health care overhaul. More &gt;&gt; 
 Driver killed in fiery Attala Co. crash identified 

 Driver killed in fiery Attala Co. crash identified 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 3 2012 11:07 PM EDT 2012-07-04 03:07:33 GMT Officials have now identified the man killed in a fiery crash in Attala County Monday. According to coroner Sam Bell, the victim is Rickey D. Patterson, 53, of Ethel. Emergency crews responded to More &gt;&gt; Officials have now identified the man killed in a fiery crash in Attala County Monday.   More &gt;&gt; 
 Suspect in murder of homeless woman freed 

 Suspect in murder of homeless woman freed 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 3 2012 10:53 PM EDT 2012-07-04 02:53:28 GMT 
In March, a homeless Jackson woman died of a fatal stab wound. Her boyfriend was charged with murder but after three months is now free. The victim&apos;s son tells WLBT that he wants justice. More &gt;&gt; 
In March, a homeless Jackson woman died of a fatal stab wound. Her boyfriend was charged with murder but after three months is now free. The victim&apos;s son tells WLBT that he wants justice. More &gt;&gt; 
 Arrests made in Jackson home invasion 

 Arrests made in Jackson home invasion 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 3 2012 9:44 PM EDT 2012-07-04 01:44:54 GMT Jackson police continue their investigation into the frightening home invasion in northeast Jackson last week. Robert Butler, 23, has been charged with auto theft. He was one of four men who found keys More &gt;&gt; Jackson police continue their investigation into the frightening home invasion in northeast Jackson last week. Robert Butler, 23, has been charged with auto theft. He was one of four men who found keys to the Maurey Road home inside the owner&apos;s vehicle. More &gt;&gt; 
 Old plantation house in Warren County coming down 

 Old plantation house in Warren County coming down 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 3 2012 8:33 PM EDT 2012-07-04 00:33:12 GMT A plantation house dating back to the 1830&apos;s is about to be torn down in Warren County. The Ceres Plantation Home, which has been owned by Warren County since 1986, is located near the Flowers exit off Interstate 20.  More &gt;&gt; A plantation house dating back to the 1830&apos;s is about to be torn down in Warren County. The Ceres Plantation Home, which has been owned by Warren County since 1986, is located near the Flowers exit off Interstate 20.  More &gt;&gt; 
 Jackson Mayor: Attempt made to keep Capital City Classic 

 Jackson Mayor: Attempt made to keep Capital City Classic 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 3 2012 8:22 PM EDT 2012-07-04 00:22:55 GMT Alcorn State University President M. Christopher Brown II announced Tuesday the university&apos;s decision to discontinue the annual football matchup between Alcorn and Jackson State University in Jackson. &quot;The More &gt;&gt; Jackson Mayor Harvey Johnson Jr., said Tuesday he is disappointed this year&apos;s Alcorn State University and Jackson State University football game will be played in Lorman. More &gt;&gt; 
 Brandon residents asked to refrain from watering yards 

 Brandon residents asked to refrain from watering yards 
 The City of Brandon is asking residents to refrain from watering their yards due to a waterline break. More &gt;&gt; 
 Miss. officials report 1st West Nile cases of 2012 

 Miss. officials report 1st West Nile cases of 2012 
 The Mississippi Health Department is reporting two human cases of West Nile virus, the first confirmed cases in the state for 2012. More &gt;&gt; The Mississippi Health Department is reporting two human cases of West Nile virus, the first confirmed cases in the state for 2012. More &gt;&gt; 
 Police: Mother foils son&apos;s armed robbery attempt 

 Police: Mother foils son&apos;s armed robbery attempt 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 3 2012 4:01 PM EDT 2012-07-03 20:01:32 GMT Three people are in custody after an incident at a Brandon convenience store. Two females and a male were arrested after the male reportedly waved a plastic gun at a store clerk at D&apos;s 1 Stop on Highway More &gt;&gt; Brandon police say a mother foiled an armed robbery attempt committed by her son this morning. More &gt;&gt; 
 2 inmates injured in disturbance at prison in Rankin Co. 

 2 inmates injured in disturbance at prison in Rankin Co. 
 Corrections officials say a state prison in central Mississippi is on lockdown after a &quot;disturbance&quot; left two inmates injured. More &gt;&gt; Corrections officials say a state prison in central Mississippi is on lockdown after a &quot;disturbance&quot; left two inmates injured. More &gt;&gt; 
 Thousands injured by fireworks each year 

 Thousands injured by fireworks each year 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 3 2012 2:45 PM EDT 2012-07-03 18:45:06 GMT A variety of colorful and toy-like looking fireworks are on sale, but the miniature sparkling explosives are far from playful. Jim Pollard from the American Response Medical paramedics blew up a M-150 More &gt;&gt; Every year thousands of Americans get injured when a firework demonstration goes wrong. In this 3 On Your Side report, WLBT reminds you how dangerous explosive fireworks are when you get too close. More &gt;&gt; 
 Family escapes trailer fire 

 Family escapes trailer fire 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 3 2012 1:13 PM EDT 2012-07-03 17:13:47 GMT An Edwards family escaped a trailer fire Tuesday morning. More &gt;&gt; An early morning fire destroyed a trailer home in Edwards Tuesday. Fire crews arrived to the home located at 1157 Jones Road about 6 a.m. More &gt;&gt; 
 Hernando Pastor sentenced in child porn case 

 Pastor sentenced in child porn case 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 3 2012 10:55 AM EDT 2012-07-03 14:55:58 GMT A Hernando pastor who pleaded guilty to child exploitation will be sentenced Oct. 13 in Panola County. More &gt;&gt; A Hernando pastor who pleaded guilty to child exploitation has been sentenced to two years. More &gt;&gt; 
 Teen dies in workplace accident 

 Teen dies in workplace accident 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 3 2012 10:09 AM EDT 2012-07-03 14:09:06 GMT George County sheriff&apos;s deputies say a 15-year-old died in a workplace accident in Lucedale. More &gt;&gt; George County sheriff&apos;s deputies say a 15-year-old died in a workplace accident in Lucedale. More &gt;&gt; 
 Highway Patrol gears up for July 4 holiday 

 Highway Patrol gears up for July 4 holiday 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 3 2012 10:04 AM EDT 2012-07-03 14:04:15 GMT The Mississippi Highway Patrol will have an additional 80 state troopers on the roads during the short July 4 holiday. More &gt;&gt; The Mississippi Highway Patrol will have an additional 80 state troopers on the roads during the short July 4 holiday. More &gt;&gt; 
 Warning issued for utility customers 

 Warning issued for utility customers 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 3 2012 10:01 AM EDT 2012-07-03 14:01:18 GMT Mississippi&apos;s public utilities and the attorney general&apos;s office are warning customers about phone scams that have been reported. More &gt;&gt; Mississippi&apos;s public utilities and the attorney general&apos;s office are warning customers about phone scams that have been reported. More &gt;&gt; 
 Staying Warm With Spot Showers Possible... 

 Staying Warm With Spot Showers Possible... 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 3 2012 6:01 AM EDT 2012-07-03 10:01:17 GMT We are expecting temps to climb well above the norm for this time of the year, despite the fact it&apos;s already summertime. Highs will reach into the upper 90s; pushing the heat index to 102 or slightly above. More &gt;&gt; We are expecting temps to climb well above the norm for this time of the year, despite the fact it&apos;s already summertime. Highs will reach into the upper 90s; pushing the heat index to 102 or slightly above. We may see an isolated T-storm fire up during the afternoon hours with winds from the northwest at 5 mph. More &gt;&gt; 
 Taking Back Our Neighborhoods - 1418 Palmyra Street 

 Taking Back Our Neighborhoods - 1418 Palmyra Street 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 3 2012 12:02 AM EDT 2012-07-03 04:02:03 GMT Rats, snakes and insects are always a concern with abandoned, overgrown property. But there&apos;s an even bigger, more dangerous threat to folks who live across the street from 1418 Palmyra Street in west More &gt;&gt; Rats, snakes and insects are always a concern with abandoned, overgrown property. But there&apos;s an even bigger, more dangerous threat to folks who live across the street from 1418 Palmyra Street in west Jackson. More &gt;&gt; 
 Group cites ongoing failures at DHS 

 Group cites ongoing failures at DHS 
 Updated: Monday, July 2 2012 10:58 PM EDT 2012-07-03 02:58:44 GMT A scathing new report has been released on the Division of Family and Children Services at the Department of Human Services. According to Children&apos;s Rights a national advocacy group that filed a class More &gt;&gt; A scathing new report has been released on the Division of Family and Children Services at the Department of Human Services. More &gt;&gt; 
 Miss Mississippi: Looking ahead 

 Miss Mississippi: Looking ahead 
 Updated: Monday, July 2 2012 10:17 PM EDT 2012-07-03 02:17:03 GMT The 2012 Miss Mississippi pageant is now in the history books. Marie Wicks came to Vicksburg last week as Miss Dixie, she now holds the title of Miss Mississippi 2012.  More &gt;&gt; The 2012 Miss Mississippi pageant is now in the history books. Marie Wicks came to Vicksburg last week as Miss Dixie, she now holds the title of Miss Mississippi 2012.  More &gt;&gt; 
 Cooper-Stokes will appeal to Mississippi Supreme Court 

 Cooper-Stokes will appeal to Mississippi Supreme Court 
 Updated: Monday, July 2 2012 10:16 PM EDT 2012-07-03 02:16:36 GMT Larita Cooper-Stokes says she will appeal to the Mississippi Supreme Court to get a new trial. Special Judge Richard McKenzie denied her initial request for a new trial, but Cooper-Stokes says that was More &gt;&gt; Larita Cooper-Stokes says she will appeal to the Mississippi Supreme Court to get a new trial. Special Judge Richard McKenzie denied her initial request for a new trial, but Cooper-Stokes says that was just the first step. More &gt;&gt; 
 Election Commissioner not allowed on ballot 

 Election Commissioner not allowed on ballot 
 Updated: Monday, July 2 2012 8:38 PM EDT 2012-07-03 00:38:29 GMT Hinds County supervisors reject election commissioner&apos;s attempt to get on ballot after missing the qualifying deadline. More &gt;&gt; Hinds County supervisors reject election commissioner&apos;s attempt to get on ballot after missing the qualifying deadline. More &gt;&gt; 
 State must decide whether to expand Medicaid 

 State must decide whether to expand Medicaid 
 Updated: Monday, July 2 2012 8:23 PM EDT 2012-07-03 00:23:46 GMT As the poorest state in the country, Mississippi is on the verge of an important decision, expand its Medicaid program or leave it alone. &quot;It&apos;ll impact a large segment of our society,&quot; executive director More &gt;&gt; As the poorest state in the country, Mississippi is on the verge of an important decision, expand its Medicaid program or leave it alone. More &gt;&gt; 
 $1.3 million to rehab Raymond Detention Center 

 $1.3 million to rehab Raymond Detention Center 
 Updated: Monday, July 2 2012 8:04 PM EDT 2012-07-03 00:04:23 GMT Hinds County supervisors approve $1.3 million to improve Raymond Detention Center. More &gt;&gt; Hinds County supervisors approve $1.3 million to improve Raymond Detention Center. More &gt;&gt; 
 Hinds E.O.C. Director fired 

 Hinds E.O.C. Director fired 
 Updated: Monday, July 2 2012 7:55 PM EDT 2012-07-02 23:55:02 GMT The Hinds County supervisors have fired Emergency Operations Center Director Jimmy Lewis. In a three to one vote Lewis was let go at Monday morning&apos;s meeting. He was hired in 2009 to replace Larry More &gt;&gt; The Hinds County supervisors have fired Emergency Operations Center Director Jimmy Lewis. In a three to one vote Lewis was let go at Monday morning&apos;s meeting. He was hired in 2009 to replace Larry Fisher. More &gt;&gt; 
 Bill paying scam hits metro 

 Bill paying scam hits metro 
 Updated: Monday, July 2 2012 7:16 PM EDT 2012-07-02 23:16:20 GMT The Mississippi Attorney General&apos;s office and utility services are warning about a scam offering to pay bills for residents. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation&apos;s consumer protection agency, says More &gt;&gt; The Mississippi Attorney General&apos;s office and utility services are warning about a scam offering to pay bills for residents. More &gt;&gt; 
 &apos;Butch&apos; Brown sworn in for third term as Natchez Mayor 

 &apos;Butch&apos; Brown sworn in for third term as Natchez Mayor 
 Updated: Monday, July 2 2012 6:16 PM EDT 2012-07-02 22:16:25 GMT Natchez has a new mayor tonight, but he&apos;s very familiar to the people of the river city. Former mayor Larry L.&apos;Butch&apos;Brown was sworn in Monday morning, for a third term. Brown served two terms as mayor More &gt;&gt; Natchez has a new mayor tonight, but he&apos;s very familiar to the people of the river city. Former mayor Larry L.&apos;Butch&apos;Brown was sworn in Monday morning, for a third term. More &gt;&gt; 
 Fiery crash leaves one dead 

 Fiery crash leaves one dead 
 Updated: Monday, July 2 2012 3:28 PM EDT 2012-07-02 19:28:56 GMT Jackson, MS (WLBT) - The Mississippi Highway Patrol and Attala County authorities are investigating a fiery crash that left one person dead. It happened early Monday morning on Highway 12 East. Witnesses More &gt;&gt; The Mississippi Highway Patrol and Attala County authorities are investigating a fiery crash that left one person dead. It happened early Monday morning on Highway 12 East.   More &gt;&gt; 
 $1.3M sought for Hinds Co. Jail fixes 

 $1.3M sought for Hinds Co. Jail fixes 
 Updated: Monday, July 2 2012 10:47 AM EDT 2012-07-02 14:47:12 GMT The Hinds County Board of Supervisors is set to discuss just over $1.3 million dollars in repairs to the county jail in Raymond. More &gt;&gt; The Hinds County Board of Supervisors is set to discuss just over $1.3 million dollars in repairs to the county jail in Raymond. More &gt;&gt; 
 Innocence Project involved in assault case 

 Innocence Project involved in assault case 
 Updated: Monday, July 2 2012 10:42 AM EDT 2012-07-02 14:42:00 GMT A judge has thrown out the aggravated assault convictions of two Columbus women. More &gt;&gt; A judge has thrown out the aggravated assault convictions of two Columbus women. More &gt;&gt; 
 Jackson abortion clinic to stay open... for now 

 Jackson abortion clinic to stay open... for now 
 Updated: Monday, July 2 2012 9:28 AM EDT 2012-07-02 13:28:58 GMT Mississippi&apos;s only abortion clinic will remain open, for now. U.S. District Judge Daniel Jordan III a preliminary injunction Sunday evening. The action temporarily blocks House Bill 1390 from taking More &gt;&gt; Mississippi&apos;s only abortion clinic will remain open, for now. U.S. District Judge Daniel Jordan III issued a preliminary injunction Sunday evening. The action temporarily blocks House Bill 1390 from taking affect, according to the Center for Reproductive Rights. More &gt;&gt; 
 Above Normal Temps Expected...AGAIN... 

 Above Normal Temps Expected...AGAIN... 
 Updated: Monday, July 2 2012 6:47 AM EDT 2012-07-02 10:47:21 GMT We have a bit of good news this morning, we&apos;re no longer under a Heat Advisory! However, we&apos;ll still have temps above the norm for this time of the year with a high of 96 degrees expected for today. Winds More &gt;&gt; We have a bit of good news this morning, we&apos;re no longer under a Heat Advisory! However, we&apos;ll still have temps above the norm for this time of the year with a high of 96 degrees expected for today. Winds will push from the north west, which will help with a slight amount of heat relief. More &gt;&gt; 
 3 On Your Side Investigates: Convicted Contractor 

 3 On Your Side Investigates: Convicted Contractor 
 Updated: Monday, July 2 2012 12:44 AM EDT 2012-07-02 04:44:15 GMT You might remember the moment from March 2010 when our news crew confronted contractor Benjamin White at a home show at the Mississippi Trademart. &quot;Are you the same Benjamin White who was convicted of More &gt;&gt; A word to the wise if you&apos;re looking for home repair. Always check references, and research whether the contractor you&apos;re hiring is licensed. More &gt;&gt; 
 Reward offered in double homicide 

 Reward offered in double homicide 
 Updated: Monday, July 2 2012 12:18 AM EDT 2012-07-02 04:18:26 GMT A reward is being offered for information on a double homicide that happened a couple of months ago. Crime Stoppers is offering a $2,500 reward for information leading to an arrest in the deaths of Barbara More &gt;&gt; A reward is being offered for information on a double homicide that happened a couple of months ago. More &gt;&gt; 
 A toast to stronger beer! 

 A toast to stronger beer! 
 Updated: Sunday, July 1 2012 10:12 PM EDT 2012-07-02 02:12:08 GMT Beer drinkers across the state were toasting to stronger spirits Sunday. A number of celebrations were held across the state, including Hal and Mal&apos;s in Jackson. This is the first day beer with 8% alcohol More &gt;&gt; Beer drinkers across the state were toasting to stronger spirits Sunday. More &gt;&gt; 
 Hinds deputies to get new cars 

 Hinds deputies to get new cars 
 Updated: Sunday, July 1 2012 10:02 PM EDT 2012-07-02 02:02:01 GMT Some Hinds County deputies will soon have a new ride to replace an aging fleet of vehicles. Sheriff Tyrone Lewis says a number of patrol cars and transport vans have high mileage and need to be replaced. More &gt;&gt; 
Some Hinds County deputies will soon have a new ride to replace an aging fleet of vehicles. More &gt;&gt; 
 Not quite as hot or muggy this week 

 Not quite as hot or muggy this week 
 Updated: Sunday, July 1 2012 9:16 PM EDT 2012-07-02 01:16:17 GMT I expect just some slight relief to the heat wave this week. We&apos;ll generally have highs in the middle 90s every day this week. Our heat indices will be lower as well, generally in the upper 90s. Lows will More &gt;&gt; I expect just some slight relief to the heat wave this week. We&apos;ll generally have highs in the middle 90s every day this week. Our heat indices will be lower as well, generally in the upper 90s. Lows will More &gt;&gt; 
 Miss Mississippi held first news conference 

 Miss Mississippi held first news conference 
 Updated: Sunday, July 1 2012 7:41 PM EDT 2012-07-01 23:41:53 GMT Marie Wicks met the media Sunday afternoon during her first press conference as Miss Mississippi 2012. The 23 year old Ocean Springs native sat down at Miss Mississippi Headquarters in Vicksburg to talk More &gt;&gt; Marie Wicks met the media Sunday afternoon during her first press conference as Miss Mississippi 2012. More &gt;&gt; 
 Coroner says Jack Lacy died of gunshot wound to head 

 Coroner says Jack Lacy died of gunshot wound to head 
 Updated: Sunday, July 1 2012 7:17 PM EDT 2012-07-01 23:17:24 GMT Rankin County Coroner Jimmy Roberts says Jack Lacy, former Deputy U.S. Attorney, died Friday of a gunshot wound to the head. The autopsy report will not be ready until Monday, but Roberts suspects Lacy&apos;s More &gt;&gt; Rankin County Coroner Jimmy Roberts says Jack Lacy, former Deputy U.S. Attorney, died Friday of a gunshot wound to the head. More &gt;&gt; 
 Miss Mississippi 2012 crowned 

 Miss Mississippi 2012 crowned 
 Updated: Sunday, July 1 2012 1:41 AM EDT 2012-07-01 05:41:30 GMT Well the judges have spoken and only one young lady walked away with the title of Miss Mississippi 2012 Over 40 contestants from around the state competed in this year&apos;s pageant. The newly crowned Miss More &gt;&gt; 
Well the judges have spoken and only one young lady walked away with the title of Miss Mississippi 2012. More &gt;&gt; 
 Small crowd takes advantage of open community shelters 

 Small crowd takes advantage of open community shelters 
 Updated: Sunday, July 1 2012 12:51 AM EDT 2012-07-01 04:51:20 GMT The city of Jackson opened two community centers, Northside and Smith-Robertson, on Saturday for residents who do not have air conditioning. The centers provided water and several activities to those More &gt;&gt; The city of Jackson opened two community centers, Northside and Smith-Robertson, on Saturday for residents who do not have air conditioning.

The centers provided water and several activities to those who took advantage of a rare Saturday opening.  More &gt;&gt; 
 Boat parade on the Reservoir 

 Boat parade on the Reservoir 
 Updated: Sunday, July 1 2012 12:30 AM EDT 2012-07-01 04:30:14 GMT Thousands lined the shores Saturday for the first Independence Day Celebration at the Barnett Reservoir. Boats were decorated for a parade on the water. In a salute to our military, Wounded Warriors More &gt;&gt; Thousands lined the shores Saturday for the first Independence Day Celebration at the Barnett Reservoir.
Boats were decorated for a parade on the water. More &gt;&gt; 
 Driver ejected in fatal crash 

 Driver ejected in fatal crash 
 Updated: Sunday, July 1 2012 12:28 AM EDT 2012-07-01 04:28:36 GMT A Simpson county man was killed at the scene of a one vehicle crash Saturday morning. Corporal Odis Easterling with the Mississippi Highway Patrol said the fatal accident happened at 6:20 a.m. On Highway More &gt;&gt; 
A Simpson county man was killed at the scene of a one vehicle crash Saturday morning. More &gt;&gt; 
 Hot air balloons a big hit in Canton 

 Hot air balloons a big hit in Canton 
 Updated: Sunday, July 1 2012 12:25 AM EDT 2012-07-01 04:25:28 GMT Canton was glowing Saturday evening, as more than 20 balloons took center stage. The 26th annual Mississippi Championship Balloon Fest is a special fundraiser for The Good Samaritan Center. The group More &gt;&gt; Canton was glowing Saturday evening as more than 20 balloons took center stage.
The 26th annual Mississippi Championship Balloon Fest is a special fundraiser for The Good Samaritan Center. More &gt;&gt; 
 Two of three escaped inmates captured 

 Two of three escaped inmates captured 
 Updated: Sunday, July 1 2012 12:16 AM EDT 2012-07-01 04:16:47 GMT A second inmate, who escaped from the Washington County Correctional Facility Friday, was captured Saturday afternoon. Washington County Assistant Chief Billy Barber said three men fled the detention More &gt;&gt; A second inmate, who escaped from the Washington County Correctional Facility Friday, was captured Saturday afternoon. More &gt;&gt; 
 Heat advisory through Sunday evening 

 Heat advisory through Sunday evening 
 Updated: Saturday, June 30 2012 9:35 PM EDT 2012-07-01 01:35:13 GMT A heat advisory remains in place over all of central and much of south Mississippi through Sunday evening. This means little relief from the extreme heat and muggy conditions is expected tonight, with More &gt;&gt; A heat advisory remains in place over all of central and much of south Mississippi through Sunday evening. This means little relief from the extreme heat and muggy conditions is expected tonight, with More &gt;&gt; 
 Armed robbery at Jackson gas station 

 Armed robbery at Jackson gas station 
 Updated: Saturday, June 30 2012 7:04 PM EDT 2012-06-30 23:04:48 GMT The Jackson Police Department is investigating an armed robbery that happened at a Downtown Jackson gas station Saturday afternoon. According to police, shortly before 5 p.m., a black male walked into More &gt;&gt; The Jackson Police Department is investigating an armed robbery that happened at a Downtown Jackson gas station Saturday afternoon. More &gt;&gt; 
 Miss Mississippi- A Week Of Winners 

 Miss Mississippi- A Week Of Winners 
 Updated: Saturday, June 30 2012 6:54 PM EDT 2012-06-30 22:54:34 GMT In about two hours the 55th Edition of the Miss Mississippi Pageant begins at the Vicksburg Convention Center. A broken water pipe delayed the start of Friday night&apos;s preliminary competition by almost More &gt;&gt; The 55th Edition of the Miss Mississippi Pageant has included three days of preliminary competition. We look back at a week of winners. More &gt;&gt; 
 Authorities investigate death of Choctaw Deputy A.G. 

 Authorities investigate death of Choctaw Deputy A.G. 
 Updated: Saturday, June 30 2012 6:40 PM EDT 2012-06-30 22:40:42 GMT The Rankin County Sheriff&apos;s Department is investigating the death of Jack Lacy, Deputy Attorney General for the Mississippi Band of Choctaw Indians, and former Deputy U.S. Attorney. The call to 911 came More &gt;&gt; The Rankin County Sheriff&apos;s Department is investigating the death of Jack Lacy, Deputy Attorney General for the Mississippi Band of Choctaw Indians, and former Deputy U.S. Attorney. More &gt;&gt; 
 MDEQ issues temporary advisory for Lynch Creek in Jackson 

 MDEQ issues temporary advisory for Lynch Creek in Jackson 
 Updated: Saturday, June 30 2012 4:39 PM EDT 2012-06-30 20:39:27 GMT The Mississippi Department of Environmental Quality (MDEQ) issued a temporary water contact advisory Friday for a portion Lynch Creek in the City of Jackson. The advisory is a result of a break in a More &gt;&gt; The Mississippi Department of Environmental Quality (MDEQ) issued a temporary water contact advisory Friday for a portion Lynch Creek in the City of Jackson. More &gt;&gt; 
 Juveniles on probation take part in Governor&apos;s 5K 

 Juveniles on probation take part in Governor&apos;s 5K 
 Updated: Saturday, June 30 2012 4:17 PM EDT 2012-06-30 20:17:22 GMT Governor Phil Bryant held the first-ever Governor&apos;s 5-K for health Saturday morning, beginning at the Governor&apos;s Mansion in Jackson. Along with state employees and others trying to get healthy, a group More &gt;&gt;  Team of young people in the Juvenile Detention Alternatives Initiative have been training three days a week for the run. More &gt;&gt; 
 Mendenhall man killed in Hwy 49 wreck 

 Mendenhall man killed in Hwy 49 wreck 
 Updated: Saturday, June 30 2012 4:16 PM EDT 2012-06-30 20:16:50 GMT A 24-year-old Mendenhall man was killed in a one-vehicle accident Saturday morning. The wreck happened on Highway 49 southbound about five miles north of Mendenhall, according to the Mississippi Highway More &gt;&gt; A 24-year-old Mendenhall man was killed in a one-vehicle accident Saturday morning. More &gt;&gt; 
 Mississippi Ag Museum hosts &apos;Summer Reading Party&apos; 

 Mississippi Ag Museum hosts &apos;Summer Reading Party&apos; 
 Updated: Saturday, June 30 2012 4:05 PM EDT 2012-06-30 20:05:50 GMT Children got out Saturday, enjoying the&apos;Summer Reading Party&apos;at the Mississippi Agriculture Museum in Jackson. The Natural Science Museum was on hand, allowing folks to get up close and personal with More &gt;&gt; Children got out Saturday, enjoying the&apos;Summer Reading Party&apos;and&apos;Electric Company Live&apos;at the Agriculture Museum in Jackson. More &gt;&gt; 
 SLIDESHOW: Balloon glow in Ridgeland 

 SLIDESHOW: Balloon glow in Ridgeland 
 Photos from the Celebrate America Balloon Glow in Ridgeland Friday night. More &gt;&gt; 
 Miss Delta Blues and Miss Spirit of the South score preliminary wins 

 Miss Delta Blues and Miss Spirit of the South score preliminary wins 
 Updated: Saturday, June 30 2012 11:06 AM EDT 2012-06-30 15:06:23 GMT The final night of preliminary competition at Miss Mississippi started almost two hours late Friday night due to a broken water pipe. The problem cut off water to the Vicksburg Convention Center and the More &gt;&gt; The final night of preliminary competition at Miss Mississippi started almost two hours late Friday night due to a broken water pipe. The problem cut off water to the Vicksburg Convention Center and the audience was not allowed in until the problem was fixed. More &gt;&gt; 
 Tracking the heat 

 Tracking the heat 
 Updated: Saturday, June 30 2012 8:53 AM EDT 2012-06-30 12:53:37 GMT Today will be another day full of sunshine and blazing temperatures. 100 is the expected high for today. A weak disturbance will move closer to us, giving us a slight chance for a few thunderstorms. Since More &gt;&gt; Today will be another day full of sunshine and blazing temperatures. 100 is the expected high for today. A weak disturbance will move closer to us, giving us a slight chance for a few thunderstorms. Since More &gt;&gt; 
 Walt&apos;s Look Around: The Ol&apos; fashioned swimming hole 

 Walt&apos;s Look Around: The Ol&apos; fashioned swimming hole 
 Updated: Saturday, June 30 2012 12:59 AM EDT 2012-06-30 04:59:41 GMT Some of us who were alive before the cell phone era and laptop computers and the Internet often wonder how we ever got along without such things. But when we have a heat wave like the one we&apos;re having More &gt;&gt; When we have a heat wave like the one we&apos;re having right now, we MOST wonder how we ever survived without air conditioning. More &gt;&gt; 
 Brewers and distributors rush stronger beer into Mississippi 

 Brewers and distributors rush stronger beer into Mississippi 
 Updated: Saturday, June 30 2012 12:48 AM EDT 2012-06-30 04:48:46 GMT Brewers and distributors are poised to rush stronger beer into Mississippi early Sunday. July 1st marks the start of a new law that allows higher-alcohol beer to be made and sold in the Magnolia State. More &gt;&gt; Brewers and distributors are poised to rush stronger beer into Mississippi early Sunday. More &gt;&gt; 
 Good Samaritan turned victim 

 Good Samaritan turned victim 
 Updated: Saturday, June 30 2012 12:34 AM EDT 2012-06-30 04:34:45 GMT A Brandon man tells 3 On Your Side he is a Good Samaritan turned victim. Allen Turner says he witnessed an accident at Highway 80 and Crossgates when a man, Turner, identified as Michael Porter left the More &gt;&gt; A Brandon man tells 3 On Your Side he is a Good Samaritan turned victim. Allen Turner says he witnessed an accident at Highway 80 and Crossgates when a man, Turner, identified as Michael Porter left the More &gt;&gt; 
 &quot;Celebrate America Balloon Glow&quot; 

 &quot;Celebrate America Balloon Glow&quot; 
 Updated: Saturday, June 30 2012 12:24 AM EDT 2012-06-30 04:24:17 GMT The 22nd annual &quot;Celebrate America Balloon Glow&quot; brought thousands out to Ridgeland on Friday night. 20 hot air balloons were inflated for the festivities. Many of the pilots and their crew were from More &gt;&gt; The 22nd annual &quot;Celebrate America Balloon Glow&quot; brought thousands out to Ridgeland on Friday night.

 More &gt;&gt; 
 Miss Mississippi Day 5 

 Miss Mississippi Day 5 
 Updated: Saturday, June 30 2012 12:06 AM EDT 2012-06-30 04:06:37 GMT There is a magic mirror with former Miss Mississippis. More than 80 children perform each night and each night three different groups of contestants compete in talent, swimsuit and evening wear. In More &gt;&gt; More than 80 children perform each night and each night three different groups of contestants compete in talent, swimsuit and evening wear. More &gt;&gt; 
 Miss Mississippi Pageant begins competition 

 Miss Mississippi Pageant begins competition 
 Updated: Friday, June 29 2012 9:45 PM EDT 2012-06-30 01:45:10 GMT There will be a delay at the Miss Mississippi Pageant Friday night. A water main has broken at the Vicksburg Convention Center. No one is allowed inside the building until the water issued is fixed. More &gt;&gt; A water main broke at the Vicksburg Convention Center, causing a delay in Friday pageant activities. Doors are now open. More &gt;&gt; 
 The Art of Commemoration in Vicksburg 

 The Art of Commemoration in Vicksburg 
 Updated: Friday, June 29 2012 9:31 PM EDT 2012-06-30 01:31:24 GMT There&apos;s something new and informative at the Vicksburg Military Park. A new guidebook entitled The Art of Commemoration was unveiled this morning on the steps of the park&apos;s Illinois monument. The book More &gt;&gt; There&apos;s something new and informative at the Vicksburg Military Park. A new guidebook entitled The Art of Commemoration was unveiled this morning on the steps of the park&apos;s Illinois monument. The book More &gt;&gt; 
 Belhaven Fitzhugh Hall demolished 

 Belhaven Fitzhugh Hall demolished 
 Updated: Friday, June 29 2012 8:17 PM EDT 2012-06-30 00:17:15 GMT One of the oldest buildings, in one of Jackson&apos;s oldest neighborhoods is coming to the ground. Friday the east wing of Fitzhugh Hall at Belhaven University was demolished. The building is over 100 years More &gt;&gt; Part of Belhaven&apos;s Fitzhugh Hall torn down to make way for new science hall. More &gt;&gt; 
 Mississippi could be abortion free by Monday 

 Mississippi could be abortion free by Monday 
 Updated: Friday, June 29 2012 6:03 PM EDT 2012-06-29 22:03:06 GMT The clock is ticking down on the Jackson Women&apos;s Health Organization and when the time it up, the clinic could be shutting its doors, putting a stop to abortions in Mississippi. That&apos;s if a lawsuit filed More &gt;&gt; The clock is ticking down on the Jackson Women&apos;s Health Organization. When the time is up, the clinic could be shutting its doors, putting a stop to abortions in Mississippi. More &gt;&gt; 
 1 hospitalized after attempted carjacking 

 1 hospitalized after attempted carjacking 
 Updated: Friday, June 29 2012 5:23 PM EDT 2012-06-29 21:23:46 GMT Jackson police are investigating a shooting that hospitalized two people Friday. The two victims arrived at University of Mississippi Medical Center in a tan 2002 Cadillac DeVille Friday. Preliminary More &gt;&gt; Jackson police are investigating a shooting that hospitalized one person Friday. More &gt;&gt; 
 Former NW Rankin AD facing drug charges has died 

 Former NW Rankin AD facing drug charges has died 

 Former NW Rankin AD facing drug charges has died 
 Updated: Friday, June 29 2012 4:55 PM EDT 2012-06-29 20:55:00 GMT David Coates, the former Northwest Rankin Athletic Director who was facing drug charges has died. Sources close to the family have told WLBT that Coates, 57, died from a heart attack at his home at around More &gt;&gt; David Coates, the former Northwest Rankin Athletic Director who was facing drug charges has died. Sources close to the family have told WLBT that Coates, 57, died from a heart attack at his home at around 11am today. More &gt;&gt; 
 Mississippi firefighters head to Tennessee to fight blaze 

 Mississippi firefighters head to Tennessee to fight blaze 
 Updated: Friday, June 29 2012 4:48 PM EDT 2012-06-29 20:48:41 GMT About twenty firefighters with the Mississippi Forestry Commission are packed up and headed to eastern Tennessee. The group will help put out a blaze in the Cherokee National Forest. The firefighters met More &gt;&gt; Local firefighters are headed to fight a major blaze outside of Mississippi. More &gt;&gt; 
 A night of honors at Miss Mississippi pageant 

 A night of honors at Miss Mississippi pageant 
 Updated: Friday, June 29 2012 3:59 PM EDT 2012-06-29 19:59:54 GMT The 55th edition of the Miss Mississippi pageant is underway and there were many celebrations on the stage of the Vicksburg Convention Center Wednesday night, including recognizing a former More &gt;&gt; The 55th edition of the Miss Mississippi pageant is underway and there were many celebrations on the stage of the Vicksburg Convention Center Wednesday night, including recognizing a former Miss Mississippi who wore the crown 50 years ago. More &gt;&gt; 
 Jackson McDonald&apos;s robbed 

 Jackson McDonald&apos;s robbed 
 Updated: Friday, June 29 2012 1:49 PM EDT 2012-06-29 17:49:30 GMT An armed man robbed the McDonald&apos;s on Highway 18 early Friday morning. Police say he walked into the restaurant around 5 AM, displayed a weapon and took off with an undisclosed amount of money. The man More &gt;&gt; An armed man robbed the McDonald&apos;s on Highway 18 early Friday morning. More &gt;&gt; 
 Hot Air Balloon Festival in Madison County 

 Hot Air Balloon Festival in Madison County 
 Updated: Friday, June 29 2012 1:47 PM EDT 2012-06-29 17:47:11 GMT Hot air balloon pilots gathered in Canton Friday morning to show off some of their balloons to the media. The pilots are in town for the annual Mississippi Championship Hot Air Balloon Fest which takes More &gt;&gt; Hot air balloon pilots from across the country are in the metro area this weekend. They&apos;re preparing to compete and show off their balloons during the annual Mississippi Championship Hot Air Balloon Fest. More &gt;&gt; 
 1 killed, 1 injured in Rankin Co. wreck 

 1 killed, 1 injured in Rankin Co. wreck 
 One person was killed and another was injured in a one-vehicle accident in Rankin County Thursday night. More &gt;&gt; 
 Miss USM and Miss Natchez Trace win Thursday preliminaries 

 Miss USM and Miss Natchez Trace win Thursday preliminaries 
 Updated: Friday, June 29 2012 12:38 PM EDT 2012-06-29 16:38:01 GMT Two more winners at the miss Mississippi pageant. Miss university of southern Mississippi won the talent preliminary. And miss Natchez trace took first place in swimsuit. Grace Claire cordes was diagnosed More &gt;&gt; Two more preliminary winners were selected at the Miss Mississippi Pageant Thursday. Miss University of Southern Mississippi won the talent preliminary and Miss Natchez Trace took first place in swimsuit. More &gt;&gt; 
 Two people injured in Friday morning shooting 

 Two people injured in Friday morning shooting 
 Updated: Friday, June 29 2012 12:26 PM EDT 2012-06-29 16:26:35 GMT At least two people were injured after gunfire erupted in Jackson early Friday morning. The shooting happened around 1:48am in or near the 2700 block of Utah Street. According to Jackson Police, two More &gt;&gt; At least two people were injured after gunfire erupted in Jackson early Friday morning. The shooting happened around 1:48am in or near the 2700 block of Utah Street. More &gt;&gt; 
 Ruling expected soon on Stokes&apos; retrial request 

 Ruling expected soon on Stokes&apos; retrial request 
 Updated: Friday, June 29 2012 10:50 AM EDT 2012-06-29 14:50:12 GMT A Hinds County judge says he is not yet ready to make a decision as to whether a new trial should be held in a Jackson City Council election dispute. More &gt;&gt; A Hinds County judge says he is not yet ready to make a decision as to whether a new trial should be held in a Jackson City Council election dispute. More &gt;&gt; 
 Miss. Supreme Court upholds conviction 

 Miss. Supreme Court upholds conviction 
 Updated: Friday, June 29 2012 9:10 AM EDT 2012-06-29 13:10:04 GMT The Mississippi Supreme Court has upheld the conviction of a man for his role in a burglary, rape, kidnapping and extortion of a Lake, Miss., woman. More &gt;&gt; The Mississippi Supreme Court has upheld the conviction of a man for his role in a burglary, rape, kidnapping and extortion of a Lake, Miss., woman. More &gt;&gt; 
 HEAT ADVISORY: For Central&amp;North Mississippi 

 HEAT ADVISORY: For Central&amp;North Mississippi 
 Updated: Friday, June 29 2012 9:01 AM EDT 2012-06-29 13:01:09 GMT The heat for our area is indeed so serious that a newly issued Heat Advisory is now in full effect. All counties along the I-20 corridor (including Hinds/Madison/Rankin/Warren). We are expecting a high More &gt;&gt; The heat for our area is indeed so serious that a newly issued Heat Advisory is now in full effect. All counties along the I-20 corridor (including Hinds/Madison/Rankin/Warren). We are expecting a high of 99 degrees with winds from the W 10-15 mph. And just in case you were wondering, there&apos;s NO CHANCE of rain in the forecast. More &gt;&gt; 
 
How would you grade the state of the city of Jackson?
 A B C D F 
Thank you for participating in our poll. Here are the results so far:
 A 2% B 2% C 7% D 21% F 68% 
 
 Most Popular Videos Most Watched More&gt;&gt; 
 
 Good Samaritan fatal crash results in multiple lawsuits 

 Good Samaritan fatal crash results in multiple lawsuits 
 
 Parents arrested, girl allegedly forced to live in chicken coop 

 Parents arrested, girl allegedly forced to live in chicken coop 
 
 Body found near Richland Walmart 

 Body found near Richland Walmart 
 
 More details on girl allegedly forced to live in chicken coop revealed 

 More details on girl allegedly forced to live in chicken coop revealed 
 
 New book details shooting rampage at Jackson fire station 

 New book details shooting rampage at Jackson fire station 
 
 
 
 Inside KLTV.com More&gt;&gt; 
 
 SpotCrime.com - Online source of crime information 

 SpotCrime.com - Online source of crime information 
 
 
 
 Top 5 News Stories More&gt;&gt; 
 
 Services set for Tyler teacher who drowned in Dallas lake 

 Services set for Tyler teacher who drowned in Dallas lake 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 7:10 PM EDT 2012-07-10 23:10:29 GMT The funeral arrangements are set for a TJC teacher who drowned over the weekend in a lake in Dallas.
 More &gt;&gt; The funeral arrangements are set for a TJC teacher who drowned over the weekend in a lake in Dallas.
 More &gt;&gt; 
 FedEx truck overturns on busy ETX roadway 

 FedEx truck overturns on busy ETX roadway 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 10:27 PM EDT 2012-07-10 02:27:35 GMT An accident is slowing traffic in north Tyler. More &gt;&gt; An accident is slowing traffic in north Tyler. More &gt;&gt; 
 BREAKING NEWS 

 Tyler Police request assistance locating 18-year-old 

 Tyler Police request assistance locating 18-year-old 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 9:41 PM EDT 2012-07-10 01:41:24 GMT The Tyler Police Department has asked for the public&apos;s assistance in locating a missing 18-year-old. More &gt;&gt; The Tyler Police Department has asked for the public&apos;s assistance in locating a missing 18-year-old man. More &gt;&gt; 
 Lightning strike spooks E. Texans at Rangers Stadium 

 Lightning strike spooks E. Texans at Rangers Stadium 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 8:01 PM EDT 2012-07-10 00:01:24 GMT You may have been watching the Rangers game Sunday when the crowd heard something much louder than the crack of a bat. You might even say it was electrifying. More &gt;&gt; You may have been watching the Rangers game Sunday when the crowd heard something much louder than the crack of a bat. You might even say it was electrifying. More &gt;&gt; 
 Tyler toddler dies in rollover crash in Wyoming 

 Tyler toddler dies in rollover crash in Wyoming 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 7:25 PM EDT 2012-07-09 23:25:49 GMT A Tyler family is mourning the loss of their two-year-old after the family was involved in a major single-vehicle accident in Wyoming. More &gt;&gt; A Tyler family is mourning the loss of their two-year-old after the family was involved in a major single-vehicle accident in Wyoming. More &gt;&gt; 
 
 
Explore KLTV.com
 Home Big Red Box See It, Snap It, Send It KLTV.com Mobile Email Alerts News Tips Who’s on 7 RSS Feeds America Now News Texas Headlines Love It or Hate It Education News Politics Business News Technology News Telemundo Weekly News Archives Weather Interactive Radar National Radar Hurricane Tracker Current Radar Image Personal Forecast Pollen Center ThunderCall Sports Sports 7 Sports Smackdown Texas Sports Headlines Sports Video Love It or Hate It Race Day Challenge Pro Pigskin Pick’em Video Better East Texas Check this out! Crimefighters Does it Work? Restaurant Reports Contact Us News Team Advertise With Us Jobs @ KLTV All content©Copyright 2000 - 2012 WorldNow and KLTV, a Raycom Media Station .
All Rights Reserved. For more information on this site, please read our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service .
	</body>
</document>
