<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001961" url="http://www.mylot.com/w/discussions/1531257.aspx" time="2012-07-12-17:52" support="1" score="0.0015566714053928889" bingtitle="myLot - frosty float" webtitle="myLot - frosty float">
			<query id="001035" bing-rank="140"/>
	<description>myLot earnings; referrals; website banners; payment history ... My mom&apos;s favorite fast food restaurant is Wendy&apos;s. ... have noticed that when i pre heat the oven my food ...</description>
	<body>
		sign in  •  sign up 
 
 home interests 
 edit interests my interests all interests 
 discussions 
 today&apos;s top my interests new recent started responded friends started hot no responses new user best responses unresolved 
 tasks 
 available 
 blogs 
 blogs home recent subscribed commented on friends commented on manage subscriptions add your blog! blogger tools 
 messages 
 compose all messages unread messages messages i&apos;ve created messages i&apos;ve received 
 friends 
 my friends create new friend request approve new friends my pending friend requests 
 photos 
 my photos all photos 
 earnings 
 myLot earnings referrals website banners payment history 
 myLot 
 myLot discussion guidelines photo guidelines about earnings about friends about messages about tasks faq 
 fun stuff 
 quizzes games 
 
 
 
 web     discussions     tasks     blogs     photos messages   
 
 
 today&apos;s top my interests new recent started responded friends started hot no responses new user best responses unresolved 
 
 
 
 
 frosty float     
 
 
   jiffys_frog_woman (2905)   ranked 397 out of 2,829 in ice cream 5 years ago 
 
 
 
 
 what do you think of wendy&apos;s frosty floats? ? I tried one the other day I think they did not put enough root beer in mine and it upset my stomach. what do think of them? do you have a favortie flavor? 
 
   
 
 
 
 ice cream 
 
 
 

 
 
 WANDALIE44 (674) response was accepted on 1/26/2009.
 denotes best response, click it to go to the best response. respond to this discussion 
 
 
 
 tags:  cooking , fast foods , floats , foods , fries 
 
 
 
 
   
 
 1.     WANDALIE44 (674)   ranked 812 out of 2,829 in ice cream     5 years ago 
 
 i was reading your post out loud and as soon as i said frosty floats, my son said ohohoh i want one lol, my child loves those floats and hes always dragging me down to wendys for one...im hocked on thier cheese fries and hes kocked on frosty floats lol. its a win win situation..
 
 
 
 
 
 
 

   jiffys_frog_woman (2905)   ranked 397 out of 2,829 in ice cream   5 years ago 
 lol does sound like a win win situation i have not tried there cheese fries
 
 
 
 

   mtdewgurl74 (11338)   ranked 244 out of 2,829 in ice cream   5 years ago 
 My grandma loved the fries from Wendy&apos;s and the BigMacs from McDonalds. I say I was in total agreement with her. My mom&apos;s favorite fast food restaurant is Wendy&apos;s. Yepper&apos;s a win win situation you get your fries he gets his frosty floats.
 
 
 
 

   WANDALIE44 (674)   ranked 812 out of 2,829 in ice cream   5 years ago 
 very true , i like big mac even tho i dont eat them all the time
 
 
 
 
   add comment 
 
   
 
 2.     danishcanadian (25298)   ranked 37 out of 2,829 in ice cream     5 years ago 
 
 I have never been a fan of rootbeer. Do they have any other flavours?

When did they start with the Frosty Floads? This must be a relatively new thing, as I&apos;ve never heard of them before respondin to this discussion.
 
 
 
 
 
 
 

   jiffys_frog_woman (2905)   ranked 397 out of 2,829 in ice cream   5 years ago 
 you can get whatever flavor of pop that they have which is usually coke products. they started them about couple months ago
 
 
 
 
   add comment 
 
   
 
 3.     mtdewgurl74 (11338)   ranked 244 out of 2,829 in ice cream     5 years ago 
 
 I love Wendy&apos;s but havne&apos;t been there in awhile, But I haven&apos;t tried the frosty floats yet. I do love the ones Mcdonalds used to sell and you got a free Cocoa cola glass with it. Does Wendy&apos;s give a free glass also? I will have to check this out especially with warm weather coming on we will need it to keep cool.
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
   add comment 
 
   
 
 
 
 
similar discussions
 

 Enjoys My vacation in Kitchen... 
Hai friends..
I am passing through the last days of my vacation time..Now I turned back to see... 

 I use to cook healthy foods since I got married 
Since I got married I realized that it would be healthy for my family to cook healthy foods. Now we... 

 Seriously?!! 4 oclock in the morning now!!! 
here it is nearly 6am. Im up again. Ive always been an insomniac, but with this young bunch here, I... 

 I cant perfectly cook a shrimp tempura!!! 
I always cook a shrimp tempura but I can&apos;t get it done perfectly! I always watch youtube and... 

 My fish is burned...hix hix... 
I cooked fish with brine in this early morning. 
Fish and spiciness are mixed together and then I... 

 Sweet Genius...cooking show... do you watch it? 
It is weird.. this guy, some chef guy, has 4 chefs/cooks/bakers and gives them a task to bake... 

 bread making 
That is one of the things i enjoy doing when im not on MyLot or cleaning my house or taking care of... 
 
 
 

 myLot population:   243,566  | myLot time:  home  |  interests  |  discussions  |  tasks  |  blogs  |  messages  |  friends  |  photos  |  earnings  |  myLot privacy  |  terms  |  about myLot  |  legal  |  contact  |  FAQs  |  RSS  |  guidelines  |  advertise with us     ©2012 myLot ® . All Rights Reserved. 
 
 
 
 We are loading a word from our sponsors. No thanks, cancel loading.
	</body>
</document>
