<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001041" url="http://www.trulia.com/property/3014384638-5-Round-Table-Rd-New-Milford-CT-06776" time="2012-07-12-16:27" support="2" score="0.018738184955967945" bingtitle="5 Round Table Road, New Milford CT - Trulia" webtitle="5 Round Table Road, New Milford CT - Trulia">
			<query id="001487" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="001010" bing-rank="37"/>
	<description>If so, claim this home and add facts. With more facts, we can provide better ... Location Information near 5 Round Table Rd</description>
	<body>
		Homes ▼
 Homes Rentals Local Info Advice Professionals Mortgages Advanced Search 
 Buy 
 More Search Options FREE List a property 
 Rent 
 More Search Options FREE List a property 
 Advice 
 California Q&amp;A California Blogs California Advice Q&amp;A Advice Blogs Guides Ask a Question Write a Blog Post 
 Mortgage 
 Home Loans Mortgage Refinance Mortgage Trends Mortgage Advice Mortgage Calculators 
 Local Info 
 Local Home Foreclosure Center Directory 
 Find a Pro 
 Real Estate Agents Brokers Mortgage Brokers or Lenders Builders/Developers Property Managers 
 
 Help Log in Sign up 
 
 Trulia Mobile For Professionals 
It looks like Javascript is disabled in your browser.
 Trulia requires Javascript to be enabled in order to use our site.
 Please follow these instructions to enable Javascript. 
 unknown 
5 Round Table Road, New Milford CT 06776
 housing 41.60416 -73.38031 Home Facts Photos 6 Map&amp;Nearby Sales Trends Schools 
 Photos of 5 Round Table Road, New Milford CT 
 View large photos (6) 
 
 
 Status: Unknown Bedrooms:  Bathrooms:  Property type: Lot/Land Size:  Lot: 23,522 sqft Year built:  Added on Trulia: 180+ days ago Zip: 06776 Are you the owner? If so, claim this home and add facts. With more facts, we can provide better price estimates. 
 Contact an agent Follow home Share 
 Send email Share on Facebook 
 Check your credit Get Prequalified More 
 Print this page Ask a question 
 Description provided by Trulia This Lot/Land is located at 5 Round Table Road, New Milford CT. 5 Round Table Rd is in the 06776 ZIP code in New Milford, CT. The average listing price for ZIP code 06776 is $368,957. 
Listing Info for 5 Round Table Rd 
 Most recent information provided by CENTURY 21: 
 Price: $13,000 Status: Unknown Lot/Land Lot Size: 23,522 sqft 
 
Location Information near 5 Round Table Rd 
 
 Schools Estimates Crimes Amenities Transit 
 Property Estimates Schools Crimes Amenities Transit $1,099,500 4 br / 2 ba Single-Family Home OPEN HOUSE Sun Oct 16, 2pm to 4pm New Milford local info 
 Elementary Schools Middle Schools High Schools Type GreatSchools Rating Distance Nearby Schools No public schools where found for this property and grade level. Northville Elementary School View Homes Public 7 1.2 mi John Pettibone Elementary School View Homes Public 6 3.3 mi Sara Noble Intermediate School View Homes Public - 3.4 mi Washington Primary School View Homes Public 7 4.0 mi Burnham School View Homes Public - 5.0 mi Schaghticoke Middle School View Homes Public 6 1.3 mi Shepaug Valley Middle School View Homes Public 7 3.8 mi Sherman School View Homes Public 8 6.3 mi Kent Center School View Homes Public 7 9.8 mi Whisconier Middle School View Homes Public 9 11.3 mi Shepaug Valley High School View Homes Public 8 3.8 mi New Milford High School View Homes Public 8 5.8 mi Brookfield High School View Homes Public 8 8.6 mi Pawling High School View Homes Public 7 10.7 mi Bethel High School View Homes Public 8 15.5 mi Private Schools No private schools where found for this property and grade level. Rumsey Hall School View Homes Private - 6.8 mi Faith Preparatory School View Homes Private - 7.2 mi Washington Montessori School View Homes Private - 8.1 mi St Joseph School View Homes Catholic - 9.5 mi St Gregory The Great School View Homes Catholic - 12.6 mi Rumsey Hall School View Homes Private - 6.8 mi Faith Preparatory School View Homes Private - 7.2 mi Washington Montessori School View Homes Private - 8.1 mi St Joseph School View Homes Catholic - 9.5 mi St Gregory The Great School View Homes Catholic - 12.6 mi Canterbury School View Homes Catholic - 2.1 mi Gunnery School View Homes Private - 4.0 mi South Kent School View Homes Private - 7.0 mi Faith Preparatory School View Homes Private - 7.2 mi Woodhall School View Homes Private - 9.5 mi 
 indicates schools assigned
 to this home. School data provided by OnBoard Informatics.
 Boundaries provided by Maponics. 
Home Estimates near 5 Round Table Rd 
 Loading data 
Individual Crimes near 5 Round Table Rd 
 Loading data 
Nearby Restaurants, Banks, and Grocery Stores
 Loading data 
Transit Stops near 5 Round Table Rd 
 Loading data 
What Trulia users think of this area
 Overall area rating: 

 Good We need more ratings to calculate an average. Top rated categories: 

 Safety 

 Pet-friendly 

 Schools 

 Parks&amp;Recreation We need more ratings to calculate top categories. Total ratings: 554 | View all ratings Last updated 7 hours ago Rate this area: Rate it Rate these categories: 
 Safety Rate it Pet-friendly Rate it Walkability Rate it Restaurants&amp;Shopping Rate it 
 Rate and Review Read 3 reviews » 
Brokered by
 CENTURY 21 Home Services Scalzo Realty 123 Danbury Road, New Milford, CT, 06776 (860) 355-7797 Thank you, your email has been sent to the agent. Sorry -- An error occurred. Please try again. 
Contact local agents near 5 Round Table Rd 
 From Subject Schedule a viewing Property still available? Learn more details Alert me on similar homes Make an offer Other Message I am searching for a home in 06776 and I found 5 Round Table Rd, New Milford CT 06776. Please send me more information about this or other similar listings in this area. 
By sending, you agree to Trulia&apos;s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy .
 Salvatore Leo (203) 490-6885 CT Dream Team... (203) 403-6226 Marvin Beninson (203) 779-6687 Robert Morey (203) 433-5462 Want to be listed here? Learn more Done «See similar homes Prev Next Sponsored Resource Center Buying a Home? Check your Credit Score today for - $0 Unpack discounts up to 40% with Discount Double Check. Get A Quote. This property may be overpaying their property taxes. Check For Free Discussions in New Milford, CT 225 followers Ask Question Recent Activity Sorry guys, this is my house and always will be so ya 1 answer Interested in knowing what the commute would be from New mIlford to NYC. Is there public transportation&amp;how long is the commute? 4 answers I am interested in the property at 6 lakewood terrace in New Milford. The listing says sale pending. I heard it is in forclosure. I wanted to know if 3 answers A house at 3 Greenfield CT recently sold for $375K or so. Yet it had only about 1,280 sq ft. Why so expensive when larger homes cost less? 3 answers Any opinions on the impact of the finally finished Route 7 extension in New Milford on real estate prices on southern New Milford? 1 answer what is the current market for a seller with a candlewood lake home with super lake views? 6 answers exactly how many bedrooms and how many bathrooms,, information is conflicting.. thanks 3 answers View recent questions More local advice More Advice: 
 Recent Q&amp;A in New Milford, CT Recent blog posts in New Milford, CT Find a real estate professional New Milford, CT 
 
 Send this property to a friend 5 Round Table Rd, New Milford CT , , Lot/Land Friend&apos;s email: [+] Add another friend&apos;s email Your email: Your name:
 (optional) Message:
 (optional) Cancel Send 
By sending, you agree to Trulia&apos;s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy .
 Done       

 My Notes Done Save a personal note that only you can view. Clear Save my note       

 Report Listing Error 5 Round Table Road, New Milford CT Error Type: Please select... Property Sold/Withdrawn Price has changed Incorrect Agent/Broker Link Doesn&apos;t Work Incorrect Photo Incorrect Property Details Incorrect Map Other   Current Revised Price: $13,000 $ Property Type: Lot/Land Select One Single-Family Home Condo Townhouse Coop Apartment Loft TIC Apartment/Condo/Townhouse Mobile/Manufactured Farm/Ranch Lot/Land Multi-Family Income/Investment Houseboat Unknown Listing Type: -- Select One Resale New Home Beds: n/a Baths: n/a Sqft: n/a Lot size:
 (acres) 23,522 sqft Year Built: n/a     Please remove this listing
until this issue is resolved Details: Your name Your email
 (optional): 
 Cancel Send 
 Done       

 Ask a question about this property Sorry, we couldn’t find contact information for this agent. Try asking your question on Trulia Voices below. 
 Did you know? You can ask the Trulia Voices community about this property to get information and advice from real estate experts and locals .
 150 characters left Question Ask real estate experts,locals, and friends... 1000 characters left More Details (Optional) Optional details about your question This question is about this property: http://www.trulia.com/property/3014384638-5-Round-Table-Rd-New-Milford-CT-06776   Get email alerts as people answer my question ASK!       

 Success! DONE       
 Nearby homes 
 7 Round Table Rd New Milford, CT 20 Round Table Rd New Milford, CT 8 Round Table Rd New Milford, CT 22 Round Table Rd New Milford, CT 19 Round Table Rd New Milford, CT 1 Saxony Dr New Milford, CT 11 Rolling Glen Dr New Milford, CT 7 Spice Ln New Milford, CT 75 Upper Reservoir Rd New Milford, CT 200 Chestnut Land Rd New Milford, CT 
 Show more a1e147de46f3422e1915b93bf2231bfb 
 What do you think of this area? 
Thanks! Your review has been submitted

Thanks! Both your review and ratings have been submitted
 
Thanks! Your changes have been saved
 Done We are collecting ratings for the surrounding area, not for this or any other specific property or listing.       
 
 Communities near 5 Round Table Rd, New Milford 
 New Milford Real Estate New Milford Real Estate New Milford Foreclosures New Milford Lot/Land 06776 Real Estate 06776 Lot/Land 06776 Apartments for Rent New Milford Apartments for Rent 
 
 Nearby Cities Homes for Sale Northville Homes for Sale Sherman Homes for Sale Gaylordsville Homes for Sale Washington Homes for Sale Bridgewater Homes for Sale Roxbury Homes for Sale See All Nearby Cities 
 
 Real Estate and Mortgage Guides New Milford Real Estate Guide New Milford Schools Litchfield County Home Prices Heat Map Connecticut Home Prices Heat Map New Milford Mortgage New Milford Refinance New Milford Home Loan 
 

 Nearby Cities Homes for Sale Northville Homes for Sale Sherman Homes for Sale Gaylordsville Homes for Sale Washington Homes for Sale Bridgewater Homes for Sale Roxbury Homes for Sale South Kent Homes for Sale Marble Dale Homes for Sale New Preston Homes for Sale Washington Depot Homes for Sale       

Residential Real Estate

 San Francisco real estate  |  New York real estate  |  Los Angeles real estate  |  Orlando real estate  |  Miami real estate  |  Philadelphia real estate  |  Phoenix real estate  |  San Diego real estate  |  San Jose real estate  |  Chicago real estate  |  Arizona real estate  |  California real estate  |  Florida real estate  |  Illinois real estate  |  Massachusetts real estate  |  New Jersey real estate  |  Pennsylvania real estate  |  Texas real estate  |  Other local real estate  |  California apartments  |  New York apartments  |  Texas apartments  |  Apartments for rent  |  Home price maps  |  Real estate community  |  U.S. Property records 
 
Explore Trulia

 Homes for Sale  |  Homes for Rent  |  Stats&amp;Trends  |  Real Estate Advice  |  Real Estate Apps  |  Trulia Labs  |  Trulia API  |  Trulia Estimates 
 
For Professionals

 Agents  |  Brokers  |  MLS  |  Advertisers&amp;Partners  |  Tools&amp;Widgets  |  Submit Your Listings  |  Real Estate Leads 
 
Corporate

 About Trulia  |  News Room  |  Trulia Blog  |  Careers  |  Privacy  |  Terms of Use  |  Subscription Terms of Use  |  Community Guidelines 
 This Lot/Land is located at 5 Round Table Road, New Milford CT. 5 Round Table Rd is in the 06776 ZIP code in New Milford, CT. The average listing price for ZIP code 06776 is $368,957. Copyright©2012
 Trulia, Inc. All rights reserved. |  Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity Have a question? Visit our Help Center to find the answer 
 
 5 Round Table Road, New Milford CT
 Follow Share Contact agent
	</body>
</document>
