<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001313" url="http://wiki.answers.com/Q/How_do_you_file_an_%27answer%27_to_a_mortgage_foreclosure_summons" time="2012-07-12-16:48" support="2" score="0.0010471799564514984" bingtitle="How do you file an &apos;answer&apos; to a mortgage foreclosure summons" webtitle="How do you file an &apos;answer&apos; to a mortgage foreclosure summonsHow do you file an &apos;answer&apos; to a mortgage foreclosure summons">
			<query id="000583" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="001055" bing-rank="217"/>
	<description>... legal counsel by means of a certified letter with receipt ... may have different critieria regarding this time frame. ... Bankruptcies Near 5 Year-High MoneyWatch News 08/18/2010</description>
	<body>
		Unanswered Questions New Answers Q&amp;A;Categories Coupons Guides 

 Sign In | Sign Up Home Search Settings Top Contributors Help Center English▼ 
 English Français Deutsch Italiano Español Tagalog 
 
 Home Answers.com &gt; Wiki Answers &gt; Categories &gt; Business&amp;Finance &gt; Personal Finance &gt; Debt and Bankruptcy &gt; How do you file an &apos;answer&apos; to a mortgage foreclosure summons? 
How do you file an &apos;answer&apos; to a mortgage foreclosure summons?
 In: Debt and Bankruptcy , Loans , Mortgages , Debt Collection , Civil Lawsuits , Foreclosure , Money Management [ Edit categories ] 

 Answer: 
 Answer 

A summons for a foreclosure is a lawsuit by the plaintiff/lender against the defendant/borrower.
All civil suits are basically the same and therefore the process of filing an answer or &quot;first pleading&quot; by the defendant is the same.
Read the summons very carefully and then respond to each paragraph either as being in agreement or disputing the claim for whatever valid reason you may have.
For example, if you have made all the payments in the prescribed manner of the mortgage contract and the plaintiff is claiming a default due to non payment, you dispute that charge on the grounds that you have proof of payment.
DO NOT, make a claim that is not true and/or cannot be substantiated.
File a copy of your response within the required time limit with the clerk of the court and the plaintiff&apos;s legal counsel by means of a certified letter with receipt requested.
In some states it is also necessary to file an answer of appearance with the court issuing the summons.
You can go to SummonsReply.com to get help if you are trying to write an answer on your own. The site will provide you with a template and an example of an answer to a summons written by a certified lawyer, which will guide you to write your own answer in order to stall foreclosure. Note: There are comments associated with this question. See the discussion page to add to the conversation. 

 First answer by Macky . Last edit by Pitsy43 . Contributor trust : 3 
 [ recommend contributor recommended ]. Question popularity : 13 [ recommend question ]. [ report abuse ] 
Sources and related links: [ Edit ] 
 
 Answering a Foreclosure Summons on Your own 
 
Can you answer these Debt and Bankruptcy questions?
 
 What happens to accounts included in bankruptcy after bankruptcy is removed from my credit report? Answer it! What will happen if you do not proceed with your application for bankruptcy but paid the bankruptcy fee? Answer it! What is the group that is with jury? Answer it! How long do you have to wait to file bankruptcy again in Indiana? Answer it! Can debt be reported without social security number? Answer it! 
 
Relevant answers:
 
 Can you file bankruptcy to stop a foreclosure if your name is not on the mortgage ? 
 No, sorry, that wouldn&apos;t help a bit, and just damage your credit score. 
 Can you file foreclosure on first and second mortgage ? 
 It is not the homeowners themselves who file foreclosure on a house, nor do they decide when to file the paperwork, nor do they decide how it will be pursued in the local court system. All of these... 
 When a second mortgage is in foreclosure does the first mortgage show as a foreclosure ? 
 No, they are two separate loans. If the second mortgage is foreclosed the lender takes possession of the property subject to the first mortgage. The borrower no longer owns the property. 
 How long do you have to wait to get a mortgage after you file bankruptcy and foreclosure ? 
 Depends on the Lender. Lenders have their own guidelines regrading when they will consider someone for loan after a bankruptycy. The guidelines will distinguish and be different depending on the type... 
 After foreclosure how can you obtain a new mortgage ? 
 Contact a lender who specializes in lending to people with low credit scores. Your community bank might also be interested in lending you money, so contact them too. Another perspective Responsible... 
 
 Sign in using: Answers members: Username Lost password? Password Remember me Sign in 
Home
 
 Recent site activity Browse categories 
 Animal Life Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Vehicles Entertainment&amp;Arts Food&amp;Cooking Health History, Politics&amp;Society Hobbies&amp;Collectibles Home&amp;Garden Humor&amp;Amusement Jobs&amp;Education Law&amp;Legal Issues Literature&amp;Language Relationships Religion&amp;Spirituality Science Shopping Sports Technology Travel&amp;Places WikiAnswers Local 
 Random question Promoted questions Community forum Unanswered questions Advanced search Top contributors Q&amp;A;categories Coupons Guides Settings 
 
 Answer these 
 How fast can a cheetah run up to its prey? In: Cheetahs Answer it! How did the frog scheme to break the birds spirit and destroy her? In: Frogs and Toads Answer it! What is the possessive form of the table of the teacher? In: Pronouns Answer it! Is using the verb spectating appropriate? In: Pronouns Answer it! » more 
Recent questions
 
 Does sainsburies have good quality produce? Does sainsburys bank offer free savings accounts? Does safe auto insurance offer home insurance? Does Safe Auto always have the cheapest auto insurance quotes? Does Saga offer insurance in Upstate New York? 
 
Featured guides
 
 Which Foods Cause Constipation? How to Cook Prime Rib GPS Tracking Online Camera Tripod Reviews How to Become a Real Estate Agent 
 » More 
Answers Properties
 
 Answers Wiki Answers Video Answers Guides Coupons 

 Local Answers Online Answers Shop Answers Blog Sitemap 
 
Company
 
 About Terms of Use Privacy Policy IP Issues Disclaimer 
 
Community
 
 Guidelines Reputation Roles Help 
 
Updates
 
 Email Watchlist RSS 
 
 
International sites
 English | Deutsch | Español | Français | Italiano | Tagalog 
 
 Copyright©2012 Answers Corporation facebook twitter youtube blog
	</body>
</document>
