<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001930" url="http://services.oodle.com/local/restaurants-clubs-food/" time="2012-07-12-17:50" support="1" score="0.0006666867714871548" bingtitle="Restaurants, Clubs &amp; Food in United States Area | Services on ..." webtitle="Restaurants, ClubsFood in United States Area | Services on Oodle Marketplace">
			<query id="000429" bing-rank="141"/>
	<description>... LADIES NO FLATS - AGE 21 AND OVER - BIRTHDAYS RECIEVE FREE ... hits -- Oreo Cupcakes w/ cookie crust and Reese Cup ... con la certificacion de &quot;National Registry of Food ...</description>
	<body>
		United States 
 
 Browse 
 Merchandise Cars Rentals Real Estate Jobs Pets Tickets All Vehicles Motorcycles Boats RVs All Rentals Office Space Vacation Rentals All Pets Dogs Cats Horses Services Personals Community 
 
 Post Sign In 
 Services 
 Home Merchandise Cars Rentals Real Estate Jobs Services More 
 Merchandise Cars Rentals Real Estate Jobs Pets Tickets All Vehicles Motorcycles Boats RVs All Rentals Office Space Vacation Rentals All Pets Dogs Cats Horses Services Personals Community 
 
 Login Ask Search Post Search Services &gt; Food&amp;Restaurants Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Foods on Oodle Auto Services Cleaning Services Coupons Financial Services Health Services Home Repair Services Moving Services Pet Services Tech Services Transportation Services Best Match 
 Best Match Posted Date Price: low&gt;high Price: high&gt;low 
 
Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Food in United States Area
 (1 - 25 of 149) 
 
 $10 Certificate For $20 Toward Dinner At The JetPort Restaurant 
 Niagara Falls, NY Restaurants Details When you walk into a locally owned eatery with a fully-stocked bar and a full menu, you know you&apos;ve hit food heaven. Feel like you&apos;re flying high with today&apos;s group deal: $10 for $20 Towards Dinner at JetPort Restaurant.
JetPort Restaurant, located in Niagara Falls, has been locally owned and operated for over 40 years. Serving some of the best food in town, their large menu includes beef on weck, grilled prime rib, steak, salads, wraps, and finger foods. The atmosphere of the JetPort is casual and comfortable, due to the friendly and convenient staff. This quaint restaurant offers fish fry daily, along with a fully stocked bar to keep your favorite drinks flowing. Locals would say that for the reasonable prices for such delicious food, you can&apos;t go wrong!
Get This Certificate At http://deals.finditquick.com/deal/JetPort-Restaurant---10-for-20-Towards-Dinner-Niagara-Falls.html?acc=19ca14e7ea6328a42e0eb13d585e4c22. See more Restaurant . When you walk into a locally owned eatery with a fully-stocked bar and a full menu, you know you&apos;ve hit food heaven. Feel like you&apos;re fly... Deals.FinditQuick.com · 816 friends Like · Respond · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · Pro Seller · 2 days ago Tools 
 X Tools Certificate For $20 To... for $10 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 $10 Voucher For $20 Toward Food&amp;Drink At Taste Of India 
 Niagara Falls, NY Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Foods Details Sometimes going out of your comfort zone and trying a new cuisine turns out to be a bright idea. Try new ideas or old favorites at home or in house with today&apos;s group deal: $10 for $20 Worth of Food and Drinks at Taste of India.
Taste of India, located in Niagara Falls, is locally owned and operated. They specialize in delicious and reasonably priced cuisine, including their house specialties and other customer favorites. Entrees are served in a relaxed and welcoming setting that you and your friends or family are sure to enjoy. Their inventive menu and attentive service will leave you truly satisfied with stepping out of the box and trying something different. Taste of India is the first and only pure vegetarian South Indian Restaurant only walking distance from the historic Niagara Falls.
Get This Voucher At http://deals.finditquick.com/deal/Taste-of-India---10-for-20-Worth-of-Food-and-Drinks-Niagara-Falls.html?acc=19ca14e7ea6328a42e0eb13d585e4c22. See more Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Food . Sometimes going out of your comfort zone and trying a new cuisine turns out to be a bright idea. Try new ideas or old favorites at home o... Deals.FinditQuick.com · 816 friends Like · Respond · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · Pro Seller · 3 days ago Tools 
 X Tools Voucher For $20 Toward... for $10 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 $8 Voucher For $16 Toward Food&amp;Drink At The Wine Trail Cafe 
 Niagara Falls, NY Restaurants Details When it comes to dining out, location is important. A unique location along a wine trail really gets your taste buds excited. Sit back and enjoy beautiful scenery with today&apos;s group deal: $8 for $16 Worth of Food and Drinks at The Wine Trail Cafe.
The Wine Trail Cafe, located in Cambria, is a family-owned and operated restaurant that after visiting several wine trails realized that the convenience of good food was missing. Their mission is to offer the quality of a sit-down restaurant and the convenience of fast-food through the prime wine trail location. Offering a variety of favorite fare from breakfast and lunch to wine ice cream, you can dine in or take out. Cruisin&apos; in the Grove is held on Sundays in the summer at The Wine Trail Cafe, with live music, hot rods, and great food! Whether you&apos;re touring with a bus group, a limo, or charter company, let the chef worry about lunch. Just sit back and enjoy the beautiful scenery of the Niagara.
. See more Restaurant . When it comes to dining out, location is important. A unique location along a wine trail really gets your taste buds excited. Sit back an... Deals.FinditQuick.com · 816 friends Like · Respond · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · Pro Seller · 3 days ago Tools 
 X Tools Voucher For $16 Toward... for $8 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 $8 Certificate For $16 Toward Food&amp;Drink At Victoria Square Restaurant 
 Lackawanna, NY Restaurants Details During the hottest, most humid months of WNY, the last thing you want to do is use the oven. Escape from the sauna your kitchen will become from cooking and running the dishwasher by dining out instead. Stay cool while enjoying great food with today&apos;s group deal: $8 for $16 Towards Food&amp;Drink at Victoria Square Restaurant.
Victoria Square Restaurant, located in Lackawanna, has been locally owned and operated near the Bascilica for 30 years. With catering and takeout available, Victoria Square makes it easy to enjoy daily specials and great eats including hot sandwiches, porkchops, N.Y. strip steak, souvlakis and more. Banquet room is available which seats 100 guests. Visit this family business to savor breakfast, lunch, or dinner on your next outing.
Get This Certificate At http://deals.finditquick.com/deal/Victoria-Square-Restaurant---8-for-16-Towards-Food-amp-Drink-Lackawanna.html?acc=19ca14e7ea6328a42e0eb13d585e4c22. See more Restaurant . During the hottest, most humid months of WNY, the last thing you want to do is use the oven. Escape from the sauna your kitchen will beco... 
Find out if you and Fiq P. have mutual friends.
 Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · 2 hours ago Tools 
 X Tools Certificate For $16 To... for $8 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Decorated Cakes 
 Miami, FL Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Foods Details Beautifull decorated cakes, cup cakes, cake pops, decorated gelatins and mini desserts for all your events.. See more Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Food . Beautifull decorated cakes, cup cakes, cake pops, decorated gelatins and mini desserts for all your events. Lilliam S. · 503 friends Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · 12 hours ago Tools 
 X Tools Decorated Cakes Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 $10 Certificate For $20 Toward Food&amp;Drink At Metzger&apos;s Pub 
 West Seneca, NY Bars, Pubs&amp;Clubs Details Finding a Western New Yorker who has never heard of beef on weck is rare. Finding a restaurant that serves the best beef on weck is even more rare, but don&apos;t worry, we found it for you. Give your taste buds the true Buffalo experience with today&apos;s group deal: $10 for $20 Towards Food&amp;Drink from Metzger&apos;s Pub.
Metzger&apos;s Pub, located in West Seneca, is a local favorite that has been family owned and operated for over 50 years since 1955 when Sonny and Liz Metzger opened the doors and ran the business for 12 years. They&apos;ve been serving Buffalo traditions throughout three generations of Metzgers and perfecting each dish along the way. Check out Metzger&apos;s Pub for their famous fish fry and roast beef on weck and see what all the fuss is about!
Get This Deal At http://deals.finditquick.com/deal/Metzgers-Pub---10-for-20-Towards-Food-amp-Drink-West-Seneca.html?acc=19ca14e7ea6328a42e0eb13d585e4c22. See more Bars, Pubs&amp;Club . Finding a Western New Yorker who has never heard of beef on weck is rare. Finding a restaurant that serves the best beef on weck is even ... Deals.FinditQuick.com · 816 friends Like · Respond · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · Pro Seller · 1 week ago Tools 
 X Tools Certificate For $20 To... for $10 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Advertisement, Website Design, Clowns, Face painter, Cartoon Characters&amp;more 
 Coney Island (Brooklyn, NY) Restaurants Details For kid&apos;s party entertainers-Entertainments-Party or other Advertisement or for a Website Design please visit www.advertisepapaparty.com or call us at 1.800.341.8809
We do Party Advertisement-Website Design-Entertainments- Entertainers. There for, we can provide you with many Entertainer-Entertainments or any other related items. We can help you with your next upcoming party events finding Clowns-Magicians-Cartoon Characters-Face Painters-Balloonists-Machines like Cotton Candy- Popcorn- Sno-Cones&amp;Don&apos;t Forget Princess/Fairy Tale Characters for girls&amp;Superhero for boys. Party Event Baby Sitters- Party events Cleaning Services- Residential Cleaning Services! Barbie Collections- Avon Representatives/products- Handy Man&amp;so much more at: www.advertisepapaparty.com. See more Restaurant . For kid&apos;s party entertainers-Entertainments-Party or other Advertisement or for a Website Design please visit www.advertisepapaparty.com ... Jessica T. · 1,703 friends Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · 2 days ago Tools 
 X Tools Advertisement, Website... Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 $10 Amazing Salsa and Bachata Classes - 3 for ONLY 
 Westlake Village, CA Restaurants Details Come enjoy another great LATIN NIGHT at Bogie&apos;s this and every Thursday!
Come and see why people from Thousand Oaks, Ventura, Oxnard, Santa Barbara, Pasadena, L.A., Santa Monica, The Valley, Valencia, Arcadia, and EVERYWHERE ELSE are coming out and talking about Latin Thursdays hosted by Jose Hernandez, Eva Baseova, Dj. Rey Cua, and the entire Salseros-LA team!
Salsa&amp;Bachata Lessons from 6-9pm
3 Lessons for ONLY $10 ... an hour long each! What a deal!
(with Expert Instructors, Jose Hernandez&amp;Eva Baseova)
No partner necessary!
NO COVER CHARGE after 9pm
Plenty of Free and Safe Parking
Amazing Food
Drink Specials
This is the kind of place you can bring a date (but certainly not necessary) ... Plenty of great people to dance with in the most spectacular environment... Gorgeous venue, romantic fireplace, 2 bars, the lighting, the lake, and so much more!
32001 Agoura Road in Westlake Village, CA 91361
See you on the dance floor!
Have an upcoming event, let us help you celebrate it!
. See more Restaurant . Come enjoy another great LATIN NIGHT at Bogie&apos;s this and every Thursday!
Come and see why people from Thousand Oaks, Ventura, Oxnard, Sa... Jose H. · 1,426 friends Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · 2 days ago Tools 
 X Tools Amazing Salsa and Bach... for $10 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Los Angeles Kitchen Exhaust Hood Cleaning Services 
 Los Angeles, CA Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Foods Details 888-784-0746 Los Angeles Kitchen Restaurant Exhaust Hood Cleaning - Los Angeles Kitchen Exhaust Hood Cleaning - Hood Cleaning Los Angeles - Restaurant Exhaust Hood Cleaning
Los Angeles Kitchen Exhaust Hood Cleaning
888-784-0746
Serving ALL of So. California
http://www.supremeairductservice.com
Bonded&amp;Insured 
Restaurant Kitchen Exhaust Hood Cleaning Services
As every restaurant owner knows, Federal Law NFPA #96 Sections 8-3-1, requires any commercial establishment such as a Restaurant, Hospital, University, Country Club and others who have commercial kitchens, to clean their Kitchen Exhaust Hoods to prevent fires.
Member of the International Kitchen Exhaust Cleaning Association (IKECA)
Owned&amp;Operated by Retired Law Enforcement Officers!
We can beat most of our competitor’s prices across the board and we offer Great Customer Service Always!
According to the National Fire Protection Association most restaurant fires originate on kitchen cooking appliances as well as Kitchen Exhaust Hood fires.
. See more Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Food . 888-784-0746 Los Angeles Kitchen Restaurant Exhaust Hood Cleaning - Los Angeles Kitchen Exhaust Hood Cleaning - Hood Cleaning Los Angeles... Supreme Air Duct Services · 51 friends Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · 2 days ago Tools 
 X Tools Los Angeles Kitchen Ex... Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Haitian Restaurant in Winter Haven 
 Winter Haven, FL Restaurants Details Bon Appetit Family Restaurant
Haitian-Jamaican Restaurant
854 6th Street Northwest Winter Haven, FL 33881
(863) 294-3094. See more Restaurant . Bon Appetit Family Restaurant
Haitian-Jamaican Restaurant
854 6th Street Northwest Winter Haven, FL 33881
(863) 294-3094 Demosthene J. · 123 friends Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · 2 days ago Tools 
 X Tools Haitian Restaurant in ... Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 Connect for
more listings 
 Click to view View more Food&amp;Restaurants in the USA 
 There may be more food&amp;restaurants in the USA exclusively for Marketplace on Facebook members! Log in with Facebook 
 $8.99 Ourgv has partnered with Coffee Alliance Organic Coffee Fair Trade Certified 
 Evansville, IN Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Foods Details One purchase will help in providing clean water, schools, churches help farmers and more all from coffee- go to: www.ourgvmall.com/prospernow
scroll down&amp;you will see Ourgv Coffee- Use Id # 39588 when asked- Let us extend our hands of love and do great things simply by purchasing a bag of coffee-. See more Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Food . One purchase will help in providing clean water, schools, churches help farmers and more all from coffee- go to: www.ourgvmall.com/prospe... Debbie W. · 617 friends Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet · 3 days ago Tools 
 X Tools Ourgv has partnered wi... for $8.99 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 $160,000 Quiznos Restaurant 
 Houston, TX Restaurants Details Only Quiznos restaurant in Cypress. Very good location @ 290 and Barker Cypress rd. 5k weekly business. Rent 2697 plus NNN. call or text 281-7o4-two658 Serious buyer only. or best offer.. See more Restaurant . Only Quiznos restaurant in Cypress. Very good location @ 290 and Barker Cypress rd. 5k weekly business. Rent 2697 plus NNN. call or text ... Rafiq M. Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet · 11 hours ago Tools 
 X Tools Quiznos Restaurant for $160,000 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 WIN BIG! Brand New Hot Items for Pennies 
 Cincinnati, OH Restaurants Details Save up to 90% Off Popular Electronics. Bidding Starts at 1 cent on TV&apos;s, Cameras, Jewelry and More. http://www.got20seconds.com/claimpeace/Cst.aspx. See more Restaurant . Save up to 90% Off Popular Electronics. Bidding Starts at 1 cent on TV&apos;s, Cameras, Jewelry and More. http://www.got20seconds.com/claimpea... Shakir B. Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet · 12 hours ago Tools 
 X Tools WIN BIG! Brand New Hot... Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Restaurant Design Solution ---- 
 Dallas, TX Restaurants Details Online Design package with 100% customer satisfaction PROVEN! 
Please call 1 (888) 788-1034, or visit us at: http://www.projectsatoz.com/services/interior-design.php
We offer commercial interior remodeling services and design ideas for restaurants. 
Our inclusive services include: restaurant kitchen layout, restaurant equipment planning, restaurant space planning, restaurant furniture selection, restaurant interior design, restaurant 3D rendering,restaurant permit and license, brand development, restaurant website design, restaurant construction and construction management.
Whether you are building, remodeling or renovating your restaurant, deli, cafe, coffee shop, bakery shop, yogurt shop, lounge, bar, nightclub, and lounge, we will be happy to guide you from point A to point Z of your restaurant project.. See more Restaurant . Online Design package with 100% customer satisfaction PROVEN! 
Please call 1 (888) 788-1034, or visit us at: http://www.projectsatoz.com... Projects_AtoZ Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · 1 day ago Tools 
 X Tools Restaurant Design Solu... Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Google+Local services 
 Torrance, CA Bars, Pubs&amp;Clubs Details ATTENTION: Small Business Owners!! If you aren&apos;t using a Google + Local Page to market your business on the internet, then you are Seriously missing out on an unparalleled opportunity and if you don&apos;t have a Google+ Local Page&quot;Google is not going to show your business in your local search results&quot;. Please do your research on this topic! A Google+ Local Page can be one of the most powerful money-making tools you have! If you are considering just setting a Google+ Local Page yourself or outsourcing it....You&apos;d better consider what&apos;s below, these are just a FEW STRATEGIES YOU MUST implement to have your best foot forward to achieve a successful Google+ Local Page and have more customers walking through your doors.
Google+ Local Design&amp;Layout
Optimization in Google+ Local, Bing&amp;Yahoo
Local Optimization Report
Customized Monthly Reporting
Includes Placement&amp;Trending
Optimized Search Keywords
Ongoing Custom Citation Building
SEO Link Building Directory Submission
Social BookmarkingWeb 2.0 . See more Bars, Pubs&amp;Club . ATTENTION: Small Business Owners!! If you aren&apos;t using a Google + Local Page to market your business on the internet, then you are Seriou... Steven C. Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet · 1 day ago Tools 
 X Tools Google+Local services Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Ad 
 Coconut Creek, FL Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Foods Details Introducing Noca Now in 2012
 Natures Organic Concentrated
 Alternative. Taste like Coke/Pepsi.
 This revolutionary, healthful drink 
will Noca your socks off! Best part
 earn commissions like NEVER before!
 http://tastelikecoke.NOCANow.com. See more Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Food . Introducing Noca Now in 2012
 Natures Organic Concentrated
 Alternative. Taste like Coke/Pepsi.
 This revolutionary, healthful drink 
wil... Antoinette E. Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet · 2 days ago Tools 
 X Tools Ad Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Restaurant for sale 
 Coconut Creek, FL Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Foods Details ITALIAN RESTAURANT&amp;PIZZERIA TRAINING&amp;OWNER FINANCING AVAILABLE GREAT OPPORTUNITY !!!!!!!. See more Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Food . ITALIAN RESTAURANT&amp;PIZZERIA TRAINING&amp;OWNER FINANCING AVAILABLE GREAT OPPORTUNITY !!!!!!! Angelo V. · 97 friends Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · 5 days ago Tools 
 X Tools Restaurant for sale Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Zingo Tacos Al Carbon-Catering Services 
 Los Angeles, CA Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Foods Details We are a catering company that specializes in Tacos. We use charcoal to cook our meets (beef, chicken, pork); this gives it a very distinguished flavor that all of our customers love. We top our tacos with cilantro, onions, guacamole and salsa. 
The best part of it, is that our customers don&apos;t worry about any of the hassles that come with cooking for a party/event. We take everything the taco includes (meet, tortilla, guacamole, salsa, cilantro, onions), as well as plates, napkins, radishes and lemons. 
We are perfect for any event, big or small.
Call us for more information at 323.201.1786.
Our prices range from location of event, but we are very affordable.. See more Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Food . We are a catering company that specializes in Tacos. We use charcoal to cook our meets (beef, chicken, pork); this gives it a very distin... Marketplace User Like · Comment · Share ( 3 ) Email Share Tweet Pin It · 2 days ago Tools 
 X Tools Zingo Tacos Al Carbon-... Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 $27.97 BBQ Secrets E-book from the Top Grill Masters 
 Washington, DC Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Foods Details Go to http://Grilldom.com for all of the details and to order.
Here&apos;s just a glimpse of what you&apos;ll discover...
The Secrets of Lo&amp;Slow Smokin for Ultimate Flavor 
Heat Control: What You MUST Know before you Start
Make Your Foods Come Alive with Rubs, Oils and Marinades
How to Make The Most Mouth Watering Sauces
9 Secret BBQ Sauce Recipes to Die For
How to Season Meat For Ultimate Flavor and Taste
Over 60 of the Best Closely Graded BBQ Recipes that will Shock you Guests!
7 Amazing Recipes and Techniques for Grilling&quot;Fall Off the Bone Ribs&quot;. See more Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Food . Go to http://Grilldom.com for all of the details and to order.
Here&apos;s just a glimpse of what you&apos;ll discover...
The Secrets of Lo&amp;Slow ... Eddie E. · 238 friends Like · Comment · Share ( 1 ) Email Share Tweet Pin It · 6 days ago Tools 
 X Tools BBQ Secrets E-book fro... for $27.97 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Restaurant Buiseness - 21617 
 Pompano Beach, FL Restaurants Details Small Italian Restaurant serving Italian and Peruvian cuisine with catering services and lunch and dinner served daily. Business occupies 2,500 sq. ft. 4 years are remaining on the lease with a 5 year option. Owner can train for 2 weeks after sale. Restaurant has capacity for 28 inside seatings and also has available outside seatings. Kitchen is very ample and restaurant has granite countertops. Business has been operating for 2 years and has established clientele. Opens 7 days per week with variable hours and has 5 employees. This business benefits from all office buildings in the area and the beautiful shopping center plaza where it is located. Property has ample parking.Great upside potential due to its location. 
 FOR MORE INFORMATION PLEASE CONTACT SANDRA OSORNO @ 954-260-5009. See more Restaurant . Small Italian Restaurant serving Italian and Peruvian cuisine with catering services and lunch and dinner served daily. Business occupies... CAPITAL COMMERCIAL REAL ESTATE GROUP, INC Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · 5 days ago Tools 
 X Tools Restaurant Buiseness -... Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 What are your friends and neighbors
doing on Marketplace? 

 
 $6 Royal Pizza A Taste of Europe [phone removed] 
 San Antonio, TX Restaurants Details Royal Pizza is a unique Swedish pizza with a European flavor. Over 60 options of handmade thin crust pizza. We are known for great customer service, reasonable prices, and great unique pizzas. We use real mozzarella and secret family recipes for the crust and sauce that make an amazing nutritious pizza where you can actually taste the fresh toppings. Made in the tradition of original old world pizzas. Our pizza combinations include traditional pizza toppings but we also have specialty toppings that make wonderfully unique flavor combinations. Specialty pizza toppings include: spinach, curry, artichoke hearts, kebab meat, shrimp, basil, béarnaise sauce, and many many more. No other pizza like it in San Antonio. 12 inch pizzas starting at $6. In addition to pizza we serve salads and kebabs. For delivery call 210-607-9413. To order online: www.diningdeliveryondemand.com.
http://www.royalpizzasanantonio.com. See more Restaurant . Royal Pizza is a unique Swedish pizza with a European flavor. Over 60 options of handmade thin crust pizza. We are known for great custom... David F. Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · 6 days ago Tools 
 X Tools Royal Pizza A Taste of... for $6 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Upscale sushi catering service 
 Placentia, CA Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Foods Details Gourmet sushi with unique Fusion style for any occasions (Birthdays, Special Events, Corporate, Weddings ) We also offer our popular Drop off catering (customized, designer sushi platers) at your locations.. See more Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Food . Gourmet sushi with unique Fusion style for any occasions (Birthdays, Special Events, Corporate, Weddings ) We also offer our popular Drop... Jack M. · 393 friends Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · 1 week ago Tools 
 X Tools Upscale sushi catering... Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Cupcakes, Jarcakes, Cookies and more 
 Brownsburg, IN Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Foods Details B.A. Sweets is a cupcake business...we do all kinds of events from every day yummy cupcakes to weddings and birthdays. Our prices vary from $1.75 to $50. we do now offer cookies, Woopie cookie pies and caramel apples on top of cupcakes!. See more Restaurants, Clubs&amp;Food . B.A. Sweets is a cupcake business...we do all kinds of events from every day yummy cupcakes to weddings and birthdays. Our prices vary fr... B.A. Sweets Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · 1 week ago Tools 
 X Tools Cupcakes, Jarcakes, Co... Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 $4.99 events 
 The South End (Charlotte, NC) Restaurants Details Weekly Specials at Parkway Cafe 
Starting Monday July 2, 2012 Parkway Cafe will be offering 
FREE !! LARGE FRENCH FRY / with the Purchase of any Sandwich or Entree
Also this week: 
FREE 16.oz DRINK with any 
CHEF SALAD or GRILLED CHICKEN GARDEN SALAD for only $4.99** ALL WEEK 
**offer includes fountain drinks only
Tuesday July 3rd Come One Come All Join us for the Independence Day Grand Opening Celebration/ We will be Hosting a BBQ on site 
From 11:30am-2:00pm 
• 2 HOT DOGS w/ BEANS AND SLAW $2.00
• BBQ CHICKEN w/ Garden Salad&amp;BEANS $3.00
• FREE LEMONADE !!!!!!!!!!!!!
**WE WILL BE CLOSED WED. FOR JULY 4th
• THURSDAY SPECIAL HAM AND CHEESE OR TURKEY/CHEESE WRAP $4.99
• FRIDAY SPECIAL GRILLED BURGER OR PULLED PORK SANDWICH 4.49
• SERVED w/ fries //. See more Restaurant . Weekly Specials at Parkway Cafe 
Starting Monday July 2, 2012 Parkway Cafe will be offering 
FREE !! LARGE FRENCH FRY / with the Purchas... Parkway Cafe · 453 friends Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet · 1 week ago Tools 
 X Tools events for $4.99 Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 Free The Latest Food Blog 
 Charlotte, NC Restaurants Details This blog is essentially here to edutain you on some of her outings, adventures and experiences in the world of food. More specifically it is to introduce you to her world of obsessions which lie within fat, sugar, carbs, caffeine, and beverages that could strengthen the heart or seal up a wound. Depending on her appetite and budget, the food variations may go from greasy to healthy, happy hour to a la carte, or brown paper bag and styrofoam to white linen and China. Levon&apos;s foodie adventures are completely indiscriminate yet entertaining. So enjoy. Just don&apos;t visit this site on an empty stomach.. See more Restaurant . This blog is essentially here to edutain you on some of her outings, adventures and experiences in the world of food. More specifically i... Thomas S. · 1 listing · 346 friends Like · Comment · Share Email Share Tweet Pin It · 1 week ago Tools 
 X Tools The Latest Food Blog for Free Respond Stop Fraud Report Learn More 
 

 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 …of 6 pages Next 
 Find Listings on Oodle Marketplace Baltimore Services | Cincinnati Services | Colorado Springs Services | Dallas Services | Denver Services | Detroit Services | Fort Myers Services | Fresno Services | Grand Rapids Services | Indianapolis Services | Orlando Services | Phoenix Services | Sarasota Services | Winter Haven Services | Woodbridge Services .

Oodle Marketplace is a great place to find used cars , used motorcycles , used RVs , used boats , apartments for rent , homes for sale , job listings , and local businesses . 
SET LOCATION
 United States [change location] 
Posted By

 Everyone My Connections 
 
Category 
 
 Merchandise Cars Rentals Real Estate Jobs Pets Tickets 

 All Vehicles Motorcycles Boats RVs All Rentals Office Space Vacation Rentals 

 All Pets Dogs Cats Horses Services Personals Community 
 
 Services Food&amp;Restaurants 
 
 Bars, Pubs&amp;Clubs (9) Restaurants (102) 
 
Refine By Keyword
 Show all options 
Price
 to 
Photo

 With Picture Only (112) 
 
 About Us Blog Help Safety Center Privacy Policy Terms of Use Send us Feedback 

 Add my listings to a Facebook Page Get Marketplace on your Phone 
 ©Copyright 2012 Oodle, Inc. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
