<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001052" url="http://www.franchisedirect.com/foodfranchises/2010foodfranchiseindustryreport/14/267" time="2012-07-12-16:28" support="4" score="0.004330054237958744" bingtitle="2010 Food Franchise Industry Report | FranchiseDirect.com" webtitle="2010 Food Franchise Industry Report | FranchiseDirect.com">
			<query id="001145" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000293" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000305" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="001120" bing-rank="35"/>
	<description>A fast food restaurant, also known as a quick-service restaurant, is an establishment where ... With more than 400 billion cups consumed per day coffee is the most popular ...</description>
	<body>
		Follow Franchise Direct
 
 
2010 Food Franchise Industry Report

Hungry for a taste of franchising success? Read Franchise Direct&apos;s comprehensive report on food franchising today. Inform yourself on every strand of this diverse and powerful franchise sector. These reports will tell you everything you need to know about food franchising.
 
 Home › 
 
 Ireland Canada UK France Germany Europe Spain Mexico South Africa 
 
 Home ›  Food Franchises › 2010 Food Franchise Industry Report
 View all Food Franchises 
 

 Food is a franchising force . When it&apos;s time to eat, people want a restaurant they can identify and trust. Entrepreneurs know this and today food franchises of all flavors and cuisines enjoy global prominence. Choosing the right food franchise involves extensive research, and so  Franchise Direct has performed definitive analysis on the entire food franchising industry to make this decision easier for you. For our food franchise reports , we have assessed the Franchise Disclosure Documents (FDDs) of food franchises of all shapes, tastes and sizes, while carefully studying published industry sources. These reports are essential reading as you find the food franchise that is perfect for you. 

 

 We have produced the following 9 exclusive food franchise reports:   

 Full service restaurant Fast food Fast casual Pizza Coffee Ice-cream  Food retail Health food restaurant Take-out and delivery   

 

 Combined, these reports explain food franchising in full. These studies provide a comprehensive data breakdown on each food category. You&apos;ll find industry information as well as an overview of the estimated initial investment to open each food franchise. You&apos;ll also find individual franchise profiles with in-depth, specified information on each restaurant.    

Food franchises are a major player in the American economy, and as such continue to be a compelling investment . The food industry serves over 135 million Americans every day and generates half a trillion dollars in annual sales. The sales for the food industry outnumber the US agricultural industry, airline industry and the motion picture industry combined. The food industry, which has created 2 million jobs in the last decade, has employed over half of all Americans at some stage in their lives, and now employs over 13 million Americans [1].  

 Before deciding to invest in a food franchise, it is necessary to research the franchise and the industry carefully. These 9 reports provide a top-down examination of food franchising, from fast-food to full service and beyond. Explore our reports to find out which food franchise will suit your dreams of success. 

 [1] National Restaurant Association   

 

 Abstracts from food reports:  

 

 Full Service 

The term“full service”can encompass anything from a family-style eatery to an elegant restaurant; from casual dining to fine dining. With over 250,000 restaurants, full service restaurant industry sales were projected to reach $182.9 billion in 2009, up 1% over 2008. 

 

 Fast Food 

A fast food restaurant, also known as a quick-service restaurant, is an establishment where food is packaged for immediate consumption, on or off the restaurant premises. The US leads the global fast food market, accounting for over 50% of the market&apos;s overall value. 

 

 Fast Casual Restaurant 

 The fast casual restaurant sector, while being the newest and the fastest growing sector of the food industry, is a recent phenomenon. The fast casual industry caters to current consumer needs by offering a cheaper alternative to more expensive restaurants while offering customization and quality ingredients. The fast casual restaurant industry outperformed all other categories of the restaurant industry in 2009. 

 

 Take-out and Delivery 

Take out and delivery sales account for approximately 6% to 12 % of total sales in restaurant franchises that primarily cater for on premises business. Nine in ten family and casual-dining operators and three-quarters of fine-dining operators offer food for takeout, according to the National Restaurant Association

 

 Pizza 

The US pizza market is a mature, developed market and highly competitive. Franchised pizza chains account for around 60% of the market and 93% of Americans eat at least one pizza per month. This indicates that there is still a huge demand for pizza, whether it is delivered to your home or at a restaurant.

 

 Coffee 

The coffee industry includes 20,000 stores with combined revenue of $11 billion. Daily consumption of coffee beverages among consumers remained consistent in 2009 with 54% of the overall American adult population partaking. With more than 400 billion cups consumed per day coffee is the most popular beverage in the world.

 

 Ice Cream 

Ice cream shops are situated in an affordable treat niche market. The main target market for ice cream is children and families. 34% of such households consume 4 or more quarts of ice cream per month which is significantly higher than the 20% of the family-units without children.  

 

 Food Retail 

The term‘Retail-Food’encompasses many types of store outlets, including candy stores, bakery stores, sandwich stores and convenience stores. The U.S. retail specialty food industry includes approximately 20,000 businesses, accounting for revenue of $20 billion annually.
 

 Health Food 

Restaurant franchises across the U.S. are removing fat and calorie-filled menu items and introducing lighter, healthier options as more Americans choose a healthy diet. According to the National Restaurant Associations’2009 restaurant industry fact sheet, 76% of adults said they are trying to eat healthier at restaurants than they did two years ago.
 
Food Franchises...
 
 

 The Brass Tap - Crafted Beer and Wine Bar The Brass Tap has the vital ingredients for success in the fast growing craft beer market! Minimum Cash Required: $100,000. 
 
 

 Bakeria This takeaway bakery café gives customers everything they want - affordable, gourmet food, freshly brewed... Minimum Cash Required: $136,000. 
 
 

 FreshBerry Frozen Yogurt Cafe Own your own self-serve natural frozen yogurt store with FreshBerry, and sell the healthy option! Minimum Cash Required: $50,000. 
 
 
 

 Dickey&apos;s Barbecue Pit Dickey&apos;s - founded in 1941 on a family&apos;s passion for barbecue and still serving the best. Come join our family! Minimum Cash Required: $50,000. 
 
 

 Huddle House, Inc. Huddle up with Huddle House and benefit from an unbeatable development incentive for a limited time only! Minimum Cash Required: $300,000. 
 
 

 The Extreme Pita Be a purveyor of the perfect pita with this sizzling opportunity. You&apos;re in the right place! Minimum Cash Required: $75,000. 
 
 
 View all Food Franchises 
 Tweet 
 

 Focus on...
   Food Franchises 
 Asian Food Franchises Bakery&amp;Donut Franchises Bar&amp;Pub Franchises Barbeque Franchises Burger Franchises Candy Franchises Catering Franchises Chicken Franchises Cupcake Franchises Deli Franchises Drive Thru Franchises Fast Food Franchises Frozen Yogurt Franchises Gourmet Food Franchises Health Food Franchises Ice Cream Franchises Italian Food Franchises Mexican Food Franchises Pizza Franchises Sandwich&amp;Bagel Franchises Seafood Franchises Smoothie Franchises Water Franchises 
 Industry 
 Accounting&amp;Financial Franchises Advertising&amp;Marketing Franchises ATM Franchises Automotive Franchises Business Opportunities Business Services Franchise Children&apos;s Franchises Cleaning Franchises Coffee Franchises Computer&amp;Internet Franchises Consultant&amp;Business Broker Franchises Courier Franchises DVD&amp;Video Franchises Employment&amp;Staffing Franchises Entertainment Franchises Fitness Franchises Food Franchises Health&amp;Beauty Franchises Healthcare&amp;Senior Care Franchises Home Services Franchises Home-based Franchises Industrial Franchises Mailing&amp;Shipping Franchises Moving&amp;Storage Franchises Pet Franchises Printer, Copying&amp;Sign Franchises Real Estate Franchises Restaurant Franchises Retail Franchises Security Franchises Sports Franchises Tax Franchises Training Franchises Travel Franchises Vending Franchise Opportunities 
 Location 
 US Franchises International Franchises 
 Investment 
 Less Than $15,000 $15,000 to $50,000 $50,000 to $75,000 $75,000 to $150,000 $150,000 to $300,000 More Than $300,000 
 More Franchise Lists 
 New Franchises Top Franchises Master Franchises Franchise Resales Franchises for Women Franchises for Veterans Special Financing Offers Green Franchises Mobile Franchises Small Business Administration Approved Multi-unit Franchises Discovery Days Cheap Franchises International Businesses Franchise Directory 
 Franchise Advice 
 Franchise Consultants 
 Franchise Direct Top 100 Global Franchises 
 Top 100 Global Franchises Report Top 100 Global Franchises Rankings 
 Franchise Portfolio 
 Franchise News Testimonials Franchise Videos Franchise Direct Blog Franchise Success Stories Franchise Information Center Franchise Expos and Events 
 
 
Franchise Direct is a member of the IFA
 
 
 Franchise Opportunities Site Map RSS Directory Terms&amp;Disclaimer Privacy Policy About Us Advertise 


 Copyright © 2003-2012 Franchise Direct. All Rights Reserved. 
 Te encuentras en México? Visita nuestro portal www.FranquiciaDirecta.com.mx! Te encuentras en España? Visita nuestro portal www.FranquiciaDirecta.com! In Deutschland? Besuchen Sie www.FranchiseDirekt.com! Vous cherchez une franchise en France ? Visitez le site www.FranchiseDirecte.fr. In South Africa? Visit www.FranchiseDirect.co.za! In Canada? Visit www.FranchiseDirectCanada.com! In Ireland? Visit www.FranchiseDirect.ie! In the UK? Visit www.FranchiseDirect.co.uk! In the USA? Visit www.FranchiseDirect.com! 
 
 
 
 
 
YOUR REQUEST LIST
 
 WHAT IS THIS? 
 
 Your Request List

You can add items by clicking the &quot;Add to Request List&quot; button or checkbox when you find something you&apos;re interested in.

You may add up to 15 items to your Request List

Your request list will follow you around the site.

When you are ready to complete your request for free information, click&quot;Submit&quot; in your Request List.

Why not get started by browsing our New Franchise Opportunities or Low Cost Franchise Directory ?
 
You may only enter 15 items in your Request List.

 Would you like to submit your request now? Click&quot;Yes&quot;to submit your request or&quot;No&quot;to continue browsing.

 Yes | No 
 
 VIEW / SUBMIT 

 HIDE LIST 
 
I would like more information from the following franchises:

   
 
Contact Information
 
Full Name * 
   Mr Mrs Ms 
Email Address * 
 
Telephone Number * 
 
Mailing Information
 
Street * 
 
City * 
 
State/Province * 
 
Zip/Postal Code * 
 
Country * 
 --Select-- Afghanistan Albania Algeria American Samoa Andorra Angola Anguilla Antigua Argentina Armenia Aruba Australia Austria Azerbaijan Bahamas Bahrain Bangladesh Barbados Barbuda Belarus Belgium Belize Benin Bermuda Bhutan Bolivia Bosnia Botswana Brazil Brunei Darussalam Bulgaria Burkina Faso Burundi Caicos Island Cambodia Cameroon Canada Cape Verde Cayman Islands Central African Republic Chad Chile China Christmas Island Cocos Islands Colombia Comoros Congo Cook Islands Coral Sea Islands Costa Rica Croatia Cuba Cyprus Czech Republic Denmark Djibouti Dominica Dominican Republic East Timor Ecuador Egypt El Salvador Equatorial Guinea Eritrea Estonia Ethiopia Faeroe Islands Falkland Islands Fiji Finland France French Guiana French Polynesia Futuna Island Gabon Gambia Gaza Georgia Germany Ghana Gibraltar Greece Greenland Grenada Grenadines Guadaloupe Guam Guatemala Guinea Guinea-Bissau Guyana Haiti Herzegovina Honduras Hong-Kong Hungary Iceland India Indonesia Iran Iraq Ireland Israel Italy Ivory Coast Jamaica Japan Jordan Kazakhstan Kenya Kiribati Kosovo Kuwait Kyrgyzstan Laos Latvia Lebanon Lesotho Liberia Libyan Arab Jamahiri Liechtenstein Lithuania Luxembourg Macau Macedonia Madagascar Malawi Malaysia Maldives Mali Malta Malvinas Marshall Islands Martinique Mauritania Mauritius Mexico Micronesia Moldova Monaco Mongolia Montenegro Montserrat Morocco Mozambique Myanmar Namibia Nauru Nepal Netherlands Netherlands Antilles Nevis New Caledonia New Zealand Nicaragua Niger Nigeria Niue Norfolk Island North Korea Northern Mariana Islands Norway Oman Pakistan Palau Panama Papua New Guinea Paraguay Peru Philippines Pitcairn Island Poland Portugal Principe Puerto Rico Qatar Republic of Serbia Reunion Romania Russian Federation Rwanda Saint Helena Saint Kitts Saint Lucia Saint Pierre and Miquelon Saint Vincent Samoa San Marino Sao Tome Saudi Arabia Senegal Seychelles Sierra Leone Singapore Slovakia Slovenia Solomon Islands Somalia South Africa South Korea Spain Sri Lanka Sudan Suriname Swaziland Sweden Switzerland Syrian Arab Republic Taiwan Tajikistan Tanzania Thailand Tobago Togo Tokelau Tonga Trinidad Tunisia Turkey Turkmenistan Turks Island Tuvalu Uganda UK - England UK - Northern Ireland UK - Scotland UK - Wales Ukraine United Arab Emirates United Kingdom United States of America Uruguay US Outlying Islands Uzbekistan Vanuatu Venezuela Viet Nam Virgin Islands (British) Virgin Islands (US) Wake Islands Wallis Island West Bank Western Sahara Yemen Yugoslavia Zaire Zambia Zimbabwe 
Investment Interest
 
Desired Investment * 
 --Select-- Less than $25,000 $25,000 to $50,000 $50,000 to $75,000 $75,000 to $100,000 $100,000 to $150,000 $150,000 to $200,000 $200,000 to $250,000 $250,000 to $500,000 $500,000 to $1,000,000 More than $1,000,000 
Desired Location * 
 --Select-- US - Alabama US - Alaska US - Arizona US - Arkansas US - California US - Colorado US - Connecticut US - Delaware US - District of Columbia US - Florida US - Georgia US - Hawaii US - Idaho US - Illinois US - Indiana US - Iowa US - Kansas US - Kentucky US - Louisiana US - Maine US - Maryland US - Massachusetts US - Michigan US - Minnesota US - Mississippi US - Missouri US - Montana US - Nebraska US - Nevada US - New Hampshire US - New Jersey US - New Mexico US - New York US - North Carolina US - North Dakota US - Ohio US - Oklahoma US - Oregon US - Pennsylvania US - Rhode Island US - South Carolina US - South Dakota US - Tennessee US - Texas US - Utah US - Vermont US - Virginia US - Washington US - West Virginia US - Wisconsin US - Wyoming   CA - Yukon Territory CA - Nunavut CA - Northwest Territories CA - Saskatchewan CA - Quebec CA - Prince Edward Island CA - Ontario CA - Nova Scotia CA - Newfoundland and Labrador CA - New Brunswick CA - Manitoba CA - British Columbia CA - Alberta   Afghanistan Albania Algeria American Samoa Andorra Angola Anguilla Antigua Argentina Armenia Aruba Australia Austria Azerbaijan Bahamas Bahrain Bangladesh Barbados Barbuda Belarus Belgium Belize Benin Bermuda Bhutan Bolivia Bosnia Botswana Brazil Brunei Darussalam Bulgaria Burkina Faso Burundi Caicos Island Cambodia Cameroon Canada Cape Verde Cayman Islands Central African Republic Chad Chile China Christmas Island Cocos Islands Colombia Comoros Congo Cook Islands Coral Sea Islands Costa Rica Croatia Cuba Cyprus Czech Republic Denmark Djibouti Dominica Dominican Republic East Timor Ecuador Egypt El Salvador Equatorial Guinea Eritrea Estonia Ethiopia Faeroe Islands Falkland Islands Fiji Finland France French Guiana French Polynesia Futuna Island Gabon Gambia Gaza Georgia Germany Ghana Gibraltar Greece Greenland Grenada Grenadines Guadaloupe Guam Guatemala Guinea Guinea-Bissau Guyana Haiti Herzegovina Honduras Hong-Kong Hungary Iceland India Indonesia Iran Iraq Ireland Israel Italy Ivory Coast Jamaica Japan Jordan Kazakhstan Kenya Kiribati Kosovo Kuwait Kyrgyzstan Laos Latvia Lebanon Lesotho Liberia Libyan Arab Jamahiri Liechtenstein Lithuania Luxembourg Macau Macedonia Madagascar Malawi Malaysia Maldives Mali Malta Malvinas Marshall Islands Martinique Mauritania Mauritius Mexico Micronesia Moldova Monaco Mongolia Montenegro Montserrat Morocco Mozambique Myanmar Namibia Nauru Nepal Netherlands Netherlands Antilles Nevis New Caledonia New Zealand Nicaragua Niger Nigeria Niue Norfolk Island North Korea Northern Mariana Islands Norway Oman Pakistan Palau Panama Papua New Guinea Paraguay Peru Philippines Pitcairn Island Poland Portugal Principe Puerto Rico Qatar Republic of Serbia Reunion Romania Russian Federation Rwanda Saint Helena Saint Kitts Saint Lucia Saint Pierre and Miquelon Saint Vincent Samoa San Marino Sao Tome Saudi Arabia Senegal Seychelles Sierra Leone Singapore Slovakia Slovenia Solomon Islands Somalia South Africa South Korea Spain Sri Lanka Sudan Suriname Swaziland Sweden Switzerland Syrian Arab Republic Taiwan Tajikistan Tanzania Thailand Tobago Togo Tokelau Tonga Trinidad Tunisia Turkey Turkmenistan Turks Island Tuvalu Uganda UK - England UK - Northern Ireland UK - Scotland UK - Wales Ukraine United Arab Emirates United Kingdom Uruguay US Outlying Islands Uzbekistan Vanuatu Venezuela Viet Nam Virgin Islands (British) Virgin Islands (US) Wake Islands Wallis Island West Bank Western Sahara Yemen Yugoslavia Zaire Zambia Zimbabwe 
Additional Information (Optional) 
 
Timeframe to Invest
 --Select-- Within 3 Months Within 6 Months Within 12 Months Just Making an Inquiry 
Preferred Method of Contact
 --Select-- Telephone Email 
Best Time to Call
 --Select-- Morning Afternoon Evening 
Alternate Telephone Number
 
Comments? Questions?
 * required field. 
  Yes, send me updates on new franchise opportunities!
 
This advertisement does not constitute a franchise offering. Please read our terms and conditions for full details.
	</body>
</document>
