<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001835" url="http://www.gdsourcing.com/statslinkcanada/SampleManufacturing.asp?description=milk" time="2012-07-12-17:37" support="1" score="0.0008060444638266668" bingtitle="GDSourcing - Stats Link Canada - Free Trial - Manufacturing" webtitle="GDSourcing - Stats Link Canada - Free Trial - Manufacturing">
			<query id="000864" bing-rank="237"/>
	<description>... when they purchased fro ma café vs. fast food restaurant, ... outlets, Following politics, Using your credit card ... trans fats, Many varieties of ready-to-eat meals ...</description>
	<body>
		Advanced Search 
 Keyword Search Search by ID# 
 Search by Subject 
 A - D E - L M - R S - Z Retail Commodity Reports Market Overview Reports Household Spending Reports 
 Free Trial Version 
 Trial Search Trial Subject index Trial Search by ID# 
 Need Help? 
 About Stats Link Canada Dead Links / Request archived copy 
 Report a Dead Link Resurrecting Dead Links 
 QueryDesk Explanation of Reference Fields Sector Glossary Search Help CANSIM More Help Forgot Your Username and/or Password? 
 Subscribe / Sign-in 
 Subscribe Now Subscribers Sign-in 
 
 
 

Search 
 Results for Manufacturing Sector

 

 ID #:   39273346 Title:   This information 
 available to subscribers only. For more information click here Source:       Description:   % of Canadian males report drinking chocolate milk to recover after a workout (June 2011 vs. Nov 2008) [sports drinks]     Pub Date:   7/1/2012 Frequency:     Location Type:   Online / Offline Geography:   Canada     Hyperlink 1:   $6 for full access.
For more information click here   Hyperlink 2:   Location 1:   Location 2:       Notes:   Posted/Updated:   7/6/2012                   ID #:   39273083 Title:   This information 
 available to subscribers only. For more information click here Source:       Description:   Average annual food expenditures per household. Includes: Dairy products and eggs - Cheese, Cheddar cheese, Mozzarella cheese, Process cheese, Other cheeses, Milk, Butter, Ice cream and ice milk (including novelties), Other dairy products, Dairy product substitutes, Eggs and other egg products     Pub Date:   4/25/2012 Frequency:   Annual Location Type:   Online Geography:   Canada     Hyperlink 1:   $6 for full access.
For more information click here   Hyperlink 2:   Location 1:   Location 2:       Notes:   Posted/Updated:   4/25/2012                   ID #:   174 Title:   This information 
 available to subscribers only. For more information click here Source:       Description:   Cash receipts from milk and cream sold off farms, production of selected products by dairy manufacturers (Cheddar cheese, Ice cream, Yogurt, Cottage cheese, Pizza cheese, Swiss Cheese, Havarti etc), Milk production and utilization, Commercial sales of milk and cream, butter     Pub Date:   4/17/2012 Frequency:   Monthly Location Type:   Online Geography:   Canada, Provinces     Hyperlink 1:   $6 for full access.
For more information click here   Hyperlink 2:   Location 1:   Location 2:       Notes:   Hyperlink 1 to latest highlights. Hyperlink 2 to full report. Posted/Updated:   4/17/2012                   ID #:   39271956 Title:   This information 
 available to subscribers only. For more information click here Source:       Description:   Report on coffee and tea in Canada. Includes the top two fastest growing coffee, tea&amp;other beverage chains in Canada (year-over-year sales increases), Growth rates of selected beverage chains, % increase in entire coffee, tea&amp;other beverage chain sales vs. all QSR [coffee shops]
Top beverages purchased at fast food restaurants and at a café by meal (breakfast, lunch, dinner, between meals/snacks)) - Carbonated soft drinks, regular hot coffee, Carbonated diet soft drinks, Fruit juice, Milkshake, Hot tea, Bottled water, Iced tea in a bottle/can, Iced tea in glass, Cold/ iced or blended coffee made from scratch
% of Canadians have had a hot coffee or hot tea in the last month, % have purchased it away form home, % purchased food along with the beverage when they purchased fro ma café vs. fast food restaurant,     Pub Date:   8/1/2011 Frequency:     Location Type:   Online Geography:   Canada     Hyperlink 1:   $6 for full access.
For more information click here   Hyperlink 2:   Location 1:   Location 2:       Notes:   Posted/Updated:   8/9/2011                   ID #:   39271868 Title:   This information 
 available to subscribers only. For more information click here Source:       Description:   % of Canadians feel like they are being cheated by companies that appear to be selling ice cream when they are not, % say they can taste the difference between real ice cream and frozen dessert, % prefer ice cream made from milk
% believe there is a big difference between the products, when a product is labeled &apos;ice cream&apos;, and another is labeled &apos;frozen dessert&apos;, % are aware a product labeled as ice cream must be made from milk or cream, % prefer a bowl of real Ice cream.
% are confused about the ingredients in ice cream and frozen dessert, Once people became aware of the difference between ice cream and frozen dessert, % said they would pay more attention to the type of product they are buying, % are swayed to purchase frozen dessert instead of ice cream mainly because they are familiar with the brand on the package.     Pub Date:   7/13/2011 Frequency:     Location Type:   Online Geography:   Canada     Hyperlink 1:   $6 for full access.
For more information click here   Hyperlink 2:   Location 1:   Location 2:       Notes:   Posted/Updated:   7/14/2011                   ID #:   39271619 Title:   This information 
 available to subscribers only. For more information click here Source:       Description:   Data on the organic dairy industry in Canada. Includes: Number of organic dairy producers, Organic milk production, Provincial share of organic milk production, Total value of organic milk and organic yogurt sales in Canada in 2009, organic milk imports, Outlook to 2014     Pub Date:   1/1/2011 Frequency:     Location Type:   Online Geography:   Canada, provinces     Hyperlink 1:   $6 for full access.
For more information click here   Hyperlink 2:   Location 1:   Location 2:       Notes:   Posted/Updated:   1/1/2011                   ID #:   39270720 Title:   This information 
 available to subscribers only. For more information click here Source:       Description:   Annual statistical profile of dairy industry. Covers: Farms with Shipments of Milk or Cream, Dairy cows, heifers by province, Farm cash receipts from dairying, Industrial and fluid quotas, Dairy cattle registrations, Registrations of animals from artificial insemination sires, from embryo transfer, Herds enrolled in &quot;Publishable&quot; milk recording program,
Average volume of milk produced per farm, Production of Certified Organic milk and number of producers
Fluid milk sales (Chocolate milk, Buttermilk, 1%, 2%, 3.25%, Cream sales (Sour, Whipping, table), Cheese by variety (e.g. cheddar, mozzarella, parmesan, cottage, feta, processed cheese), Yogurt, Butter, Ice cream, Milk powders, Evaporated milk, Whey products
Per capita consumption of dairy products, milk, cream
Imports and exports of dairy products including semen, embryos, cattle.
International comparisons of milk consumption / production, cheese consumption / production.     Pub Date:   1/1/2011 Frequency:   Annual Location Type:   Online Geography:   Canada, provinces     Hyperlink 1:   $6 for full access.
For more information click here   Hyperlink 2:   Location 1:   Location 2:       Notes:   Posted/Updated:   1/1/2011                   ID #:   39270799 Title:   This information 
 available to subscribers only. For more information click here Source:       Description:   % of energy drink sales held by energy shots, total value of energy shot market in Canada, % change in energy drink sales in 2009 and total sales at c-stores by province/region
% share of non-alcoholic drink sales at c-stores held by milk, pop, energy drinks     Pub Date:   10/1/2010 Frequency:     Location Type:   Online Geography:   Canada, some provincial detail     Hyperlink 1:   $6 for full access.
For more information click here   Hyperlink 2:   Location 1:   Location 2:       Notes:   Posted/Updated:   10/1/2010                   ID #:   39270582 Title:   This information 
 available to subscribers only. For more information click here Source:       Description:   Certified Organic operators in Canada by province (farms, farms in transition, processors, handlers), Certified Organic acreage, Acreage by crop (Wheat/Durum, Oats, Lentils and dry peas, Barley, Flax, Grains, Soybeans, Rye, Spelt, Corn, Oilseeds, Mustard, Buckwheat, Hemp, Canola, Alfalfa and alfalfa/grass, Hay/pasture/forage crops, Clover, Vegetables, Potatoes, Sweet Corn, Tree fruit, Small fruit/berries, Grapes, nuts, Milk, Beef cattle, Dairy cattle, Goats, Sheep, Pigs, Bees, Laying hens, Turkeys, Chicken, Maple syrup)     Pub Date:   6/8/2010 Frequency:     Location Type:   Online Geography:   Canada     Hyperlink 1:   $6 for full access.
For more information click here   Hyperlink 2:   Location 1:   Location 2:       Notes:   Posted/Updated:   10/14/2010                   ID #:   8891 Title:   This information 
 available to subscribers only. For more information click here Source:       Description:   This publication contains information on food available for consumption and food nutrition. Includes: Food available by major group, per person, Food available by commodity, Total nutrients available from the Canadian food supply.
Covers the commodities: Fresh fruit (Apples, Apricots, Avocados, Bananas, Berries other, Blueberries, Cherries, Other citrus, Coconut
Cranberries, Dates, Figs, Grapefruits, Grapes, Guavas, mangoes, Kiwis, Lemons, Limes, Mandarins, Muskmelons, cantaloups, Other melons, Melons total, Nectarines, Oranges,
Papayas, Peaches, Pears, Pineapples, Plums, Quinces, Strawberries, Unspecified fresh fruits, Watermelons, Wintermelons), Processed fruit (canned, dried, frozen)
Fresh vegetables (Artichokes, Asparagus, Beans green and wax, Beets, Broccoli, Brussels sprouts, Chinese cabbage, Cabbage, Carrots, Cauliflower, Celery, 
Corn, Cucumbers, Other edible roots, Eggplants, Garlic, Kohlrabi, Leeks, Other leguminous vegetables, Lettuce, Manioc, Mushrooms, Okra, Olives, Onions and shallots, Parsley, Parsnips, Peas, Peppers, Potatoes sweet fresh, Potatoes white fresh and processed, fresh equivalent, Pumpkins and squash, Radishes, Rappini
Rutabagas and turnips, Spinach, Tomatoes), Processed vegetables (frozen, canned)
Beverages: Ale, beer, stout and porter, Bottled water, Coffee, Distilled spirits, Soft drinks, Tea, Wines, Apple juice, Grape juice, Grapefruit juice, Lemon juice, Orange juice, Pineapple juice, Tomato juice
Dairy: Cheddar cheese, Cheese cottage, Cheese processed, Cheese variety, Cream cereal 10%, litres, Cream sour, litres, Cream table 18%, litres, Cream whipping 32% or 35%, litres, Ice cream, litres, Ice milk, litres, Milk buttermilk, litres, Milk chocolate drink, litres, Milk concentrated skim, litres, Milk concentrated whole, litres, Milk other whole products, Milk partly skimmed 1%, litres, Milk partly skimmed 2%, litres, Milk skim, litres, Milk standard 3.25%, litres, Milk sweetened concentrated skim, litres, Milkshake, litres, Powder buttermilk, Powder skim milk, Powder whey, Sherbet, litres, Yogurt, litres, Fluid milk, litres, Eggs
Beef, Mutton and lamb, Offal, Pork, Veal, Poultry, Chicken, Stewing hen, Turkey, Fresh and frozen sea fish, Freshwater fish, Processed sea fish, Shellfish, Butter, Margarine, Salad oils, Shortening and shortening oils, Breakfast food, Corn flour and meal, Oatmeal and rolled oats, Pot and pearl barley, Rice, Rye flour, Wheat flour, Baked and canned beans, Dry beans, Peanuts, Dry peas, Tree nuts, Honey, Maple sugar, Sugar.     Pub Date:   5/27/2010 Frequency:   DISCONTINUED Location Type:   Online Geography:   Canada     Hyperlink 1:   $6 for full access.
For more information click here   Hyperlink 2:   Location 1:   Location 2:       Notes:   Hyperlink 1 to full report. Hyperlink 2 to latest highlights. Posted/Updated:   5/27/2010                   ID #:   39270811 Title:   This information 
 available to subscribers only. For more information click here Source:       Description:   % share of non-alcoholic beverage sales in c-stores / c-gas by type (Carbonated soft drinks, Milk, Energy drinks, Juices, Flat water [bottled water], Carbonated water, Vegetable juices, Coffee (2009), total market value of Energy shits (2007-2009)
% share of profit in c-stores by category (Tobacco, Lottery, Beverage, Confectionery, Dairy, Snack foods, Groceries, Foodservice, Other     Pub Date:   5/1/2010 Frequency:     Location Type:   Online Geography:   Canada     Hyperlink 1:   $6 for full access.
For more information click here   Hyperlink 2:   Location 1:   Location 2:       Notes:   Posted/Updated:   5/1/2010                   ID #:   39271786 Title:   This information 
 available to subscribers only. For more information click here Source:       Description:   Annual overview of the Canadian dairy industry. Includes: Import&amp;Exports, % share of trade from cheese, butter, fats&amp;oils, milk, whey products, yogurt)     Pub Date:   1/1/2010 Frequency:   Annual Location Type:   Online Geography:   Canada     Hyperlink 1:   $6 for full access.
For more information click here   Hyperlink 2:   Location 1:   Location 2:       Notes:   Posted/Updated:   1/1/2010                   ID #:   39270581 Title:   This information 
 available to subscribers only. For more information click here Source:       Description:   % of grocery products are organic, Total value of sales of organic products (2008), % share of organic products that are private label, % are certified organic
Organic sales by retail channel (conventional retail, direct to consumer, other conventional specialty outlets
Organic sales by scanned product (Prepared Foods, 
Refrigerated (Food and Beverages), 
Dairy, Beverages (Non-Refrigerated) , Condiments, dressings, spreads,
relishes&amp;sauces, Snacks, Frozen Foods, 
Baby Foods, Bakery, Baking Needs, Confectionery, Produce (Pre-packaged), 
Desserts, Deli (Luncheon Meat), Meat (Wieners)
Top ten largest organic grocery segments sales volume (Soya Drinks, Milk, Refrigerated Yogurt, Ready-to-Eat Cereals, Coffee - Roast&amp;Ground, Soup, Eggs, Bread - Commercial, Baby Food, Juices&amp;Drinks - Shelf Stable)
Top ten with the greatest sales increases - sales volume (Rice Drinks, Baby Food, Icing Products, Fruit&amp;Apple Sauce - Single Serving, Infant Cereal, Meat&amp;Seafood Sauces, Vegetables - Frozen, Soup, Vinegar, Bread-Dry, Dry Fruit)
Organic items by country of origin, Organic imports by product type,     Pub Date:   1/1/2010 Frequency:     Location Type:   Online Geography:   Canada     Hyperlink 1:   $6 for full access.
For more information click here   Hyperlink 2:   Location 1:   Location 2:       Notes:   Hyperlink 1 to current report. Posted/Updated:   10/14/2010                   ID #:   39268821 Title:   This information 
 available to subscribers only. For more information click here Source:       Description:   Survey on health and nutrition. Includes: How serious a threat to your health and that of your family do you consider each of the following: Pollution, Waiting times in the health care system, The use of hormones in animals for human consumption, The amount of sodium/salt in processed foods, Additives and preservatives in processed foods, Food safety concerns such as E. coli, salmonella or listeria, Pesticide use with vegetables and fruit, Additives and preservatives in meat products, Lack of physical activity, Being obese, The use of antibiotics in animals for human consumption, Poor care from health care providers, Food goods imported from China, The use of coal to produce electricity, Swine flu [H1N1], Use of nuclear energy to produce electricity
% over the last two years have changed their behaviour in: Cooking meals at home, Buying healthier foods when grocery shopping, Being environmentally friendly, Worrying about your health, Exercising, Ordering healthier foods at non-fast food restaurants, Ordering healthier foods at fast food outlets, Following politics, Using your credit card, Investing for your retirement, Attending religious services
Top factors used when determining whether a food is healthy or not, Top reasons to eat healthy food, Level of physical activity, % consider the following positive developments in grocery stores: Local produce available [locally grown], Organic produce available, Reduced-calorie foods, Fewer foods with trans fats, Many varieties of ready-to-eat meals that simply require reheating
% comfortable with modified foods (e.g. Farmed salmon [aquaculture], Genetically modified wheat, Adding Omega-3 to foods, Shelf-stable milk)
% consider healthy: fish, chicken, pork, beef, eggs, tofu, Meal times and situations where Canadians eat the healthiest (includes families with children), Awareness of the Canada Food Guide, Top obstacles to eating healthy, Confidence in package information (labelling)     Pub Date:   9/18/2009 Frequency:     Location Type:   Online Geography:   Canada     Hyperlink 1:   $6 for full access.
For more information click here   Hyperlink 2:   Location 1:   Location 2:       Notes:   Posted/Updated:   9/19/2009                   ID #:   39267894 Title:   This information 
 available to subscribers only. For more information click here Source:       Description:   % of Canadians report going without fresh fruit, vegetables, dairy products, whole grain products, lean meat or fish because they are too expensive, % identified price as &quot;extremely&quot; or &quot;very&quot; important when choosing which items make it into their grocery cart.
Comparison of specific food prices for selected communities across the country. (Covers: Milk, 1% (4L), Cheddar Cheese, Medium (520g), Processed Cheddar Cheese (24 slices), Yogurt, 1% (650g), Bread, White (1 loaf), Bread, Whole Wheat (1 loaf), Pasta, White (900 g), Pasta, Whole Wheat (900 g), Kraft Dinner, Original (1 box), Cereal, Cheerios (525 g), Rice, White (1 kg), Rice, Brown (1 kg)     Pub Date:   2/9/2009 Frequency:     Location Type:   Online Geography:   Canada, Selected Communities     Hyperlink 1:   $6 for full access.
For more information click here   Hyperlink 2:   Location 1:   Location 2:       Notes:   Posted/Updated:   2/10/2009                   [1/4]
	</body>
</document>
