<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001312" url="http://www.activediner.com/diener&apos;s/restaurant/mechanicsburg/pa/us/profile/503151" time="2012-07-12-16:48" support="1" score="0.001296413719386616" bingtitle="Diener&apos;s Restaurant Overview, 135 West Main Street, Mechanicsburg ..." webtitle="Diener&apos;s Restaurant Overview, 135 West Main Street, Mechanicsburg, PA, 17055, (717) 766-6913 - ActiveDiner">
			<query id="000394" bing-rank="77"/>
	<description>Indian, Indian/Pakistan, Pakistani, Fast Food Restaurant in ... Don&apos;t waste your time on this place. Delivered ... me more and say it was a glitch with the credit card ...</description>
	<body>
		CUISINE OR RESTAURANT   CITY/STATE OR ZIP     
 
 
 Destinations 

 Atlanta Austin Boca Raton Boston Charleston Charlotte Chicago Dallas Denver Detroit Fort Worth Ft. Lauderdale Greensboro (Triad) Hartford Houston Indianapolis Kansas City Las Vegas Los Angeles Louisville Miami Minneapolis Nashville New Orleans New York Orlando Philadelphia Phoenix Pittsburgh Portland Raleigh San Diego San Francisco Seattle Washington DC  -------------------------- Browse by Map   
 

 
 Sign Up for Specials 
 

 
 Add Your Restaurant 
 

 
 ActiveDiner Blog 
 
 
Cuisine
 All Restaurants 
 American 
 Chinese 
 Burger 
 Italian 
 Mexican 
 Japanese 
 American Traditional 
 Asian 
 Chicken 
 
 more... 
 24 Hours American American Traditional Asian Banquet/Party Room Bar Barbecue Billiard/Pool Tables Breakfast Brewery/Pub/Tavern Brunch Buffet Burger Cafeteria Casual/Family Catering Chicken Children&apos;s Menu Chinese Continental Country Dance Floor Darts Deli/Sandwich/Subs Delivery Dim Sum Diner Dinner Fast Food Fun and Games Happy Hour Health Indian Italian Japanese Karaoke Kids Friendly Late Night Dining Live Entertainment Lunch Mexican Moroccan Organic Outdoor Seating Pizzeria Romantic Seafood Senior Discount Smoking/Non Smoking Sports Bar and Grill Steak House Sushi Bar Take Out/Carry Out Thai TV/Satellite Vegetarian Wheelchair Access Wi-Fi/Internet Access 
 
 


Nearby Cities
 Harrisburg 
 Carlisle 
 Lebanon 
 Camp Hill 
 Hershey 
 
 more... 
 Annville Boiling Springs Campbelltown Dauphin Duncannon Elizabethville Enola Fredericksburg Grantville Gratz Halifax Highspire Ickesburg Jonestown Liverpool Loysville Lykens Millersburg Mount Gretna Mount Holly Springs Myerstown New Bloomfield Newburg Newville Ono Palmyra Quentin Richland Shermans Dale Wormleysburg 
 
 



 
Dining Specials
 Sunlight Diner 
 - American 
 Las Delicias Restaurant 
 - American, Latin, Spanish, Casual/Family Restaurant in
Harrisburg 
 
5.0|The food is absolutely delicious, the staff are very friendly and the restaurant is clean. It&apos;s... 
 
 





 
 United States &gt; Pennsylvania &gt; Mechanicsburg Restaurant Guide 
Diener&apos;s
 (717) 766-6913 
 135 West Main Street, Mechanicsburg, PA 17055 | MAP 
   | Share | 

 
 Overview 
   
 Map 
   
 



 UPDATE THIS LISTING 
 
 Aangan Indian Cuisine 
 Indian, Indian/Pakistan, Pakistani, Fast Food Restaurant in
Harrisburg 
 Angies Family Restaurant&amp;Lng 
 American Restaurant in
Harrisburg 
 Beni&apos;s Pizza and Restaurant 
 American, Pizzeria Restaurant in
Palmyra 
   »   See All Mechanicsburg Restaurant Coupons &amp; Deals 
 
 advertisements 




 
Reviews of Similar Restaurants
 Jo-Jo Pizzeria&amp;Restaurant   
 Chinese 
  Friendly service, fair price and excellent pizza and subs. Al&apos;s Pizza&amp;Subs Hampden   
 Chinese 
  Don&apos;t waste your time on this place. Delivered the wrong order and had an awful time trying to get a refund. Stated he was going to &quot;call the cops&quot; and also stated he was going to charge me more and say it was a glitch with the credit card system. Wh
 
 ... New Forest Chinese Restaurant   
 Chinese 
  If your looking for a chinese buffet this is a good place. The selections they have are a bit limited but they have all the standard chinese dishes you love. The price more then reasonable and the food is hot and wonderful. I prefer this over alot of
 
 ... Caddy Shack   
 Chinese 
  Great bar and Grill--great staff and they have the BEST wings--located on a great little golf course--play and eat for next to nothing--great value--big deck and welcoming dining experience Old Country Buffet   
 Chinese 
  Our dining experience was great. The food was kept hot and the apearance was very nice. We enjoyed the friendly atmosphere. This is buffet style and very well organized. This is a great family afforable place to eat. At this resturant the beverag
 
 ... 

   »  Read More:   Mechanicsburg Restaurant Reviews 
 Copyright 1996-2012 ActiveDiner.com All rights reserved.      About Us  |  Contact Us  |  Disclaimer  | Privacy Policy  | Terms of Service
	</body>
</document>
