<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001451" url="http://www.shopping.com/pizza-sign-light/products" time="2012-07-12-17:13" support="6" score="0.014714064935407781" bingtitle="&quot;pizza sign light&quot; - Shopping.com" webtitle="pizza sign light- Shopping.com">
			<query id="000380" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000287" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000161" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000410" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="001133" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000536" bing-rank="171"/>
	<description>- Hooks pivots to allow for snow or trash removal ... 16x28 Animated Led Pizza Sign Neon Italian Fast Food Restaurant ... signs Neon pizza signs Yard sale signs LED Menu Board ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to Shopping.com! Other Shopping.com sites: Close 
 
 
 
 
 
 Shop By Department 
 Clothing 
 Women Men Girls Boys Infants and Toddlers See all... Shop by Brands 
 Shoes 
 Womens Mens Kids See all... Shop by Brands 
 Computers 
 Cartridges and Toners Flash Memory Monitors PC Laptops PDAs Printers Software See all... Shop by Brands 
 Electronics 
 Camcorders Cellular Phones Digital Cameras GPS Devices MP3 Players Flat Panel Televisions Speakers and Subwoofers Buying Guides See all... Shop by Brands 
 At Home 
 Furniture Garden Home Furnishings Kitchen Pet Supplies Building Supplies See all... Shop by Brands 
 Health 
 Cosmetics Fragrances Health Aids Nutrition Personal Care See all... Shop by Brands 
 Kids 
 Baby Care Car Seats Cribs and Bassinets Strollers Toys Video Games See all... Shop by Brands 
 Community Shop by Brands See all 
 
 Sign In   Join   My Lists Search Related: Vintage pizza sign ,  Pizza neon sign ,  Pizza sign car ,  Outdoors pizza sign ,  more» Pizza banner ,  Pizza vintage ,  Led pizza sign ,  Pizza decal ,  Pizza neon ,  Pizza stone ,  Pizza slice sign ,  Pizza sign outdoor ,  Pizza sign wood ,  Pizza car ,  Pizza ,  Ice sign ,  Car topper ,  Pizza hut ,  Car top carrier    less» Shopping 
 pizza sign light 
 Showing results for &quot;
pizza sign light
&quot; Show on Sale Results 1 - 40 of 1500+ -16% 
 Gold Medal 5884 Lighted &quot;Pizza&quot; Menu Sign Gold Medal 5884 Lighted &quot;Pizza&quot; Menu Sign 
 In Stock ( In stock ) 
Attract patrons to your pizza shop with this Gold Medal 5884 &quot;Pizza&quot; menu sign! Its bold fluorescent backlit illumination plus bold letters and graphics lets customers know you offer the... More 

Attract patrons to your pizza shop with this Gold Medal 5884 &quot;Pizza&quot; menu sign! Its bold fluorescent backlit illumination plus bold letters and graphics lets customers know you offer the tasty dish they crave! This lighted sign&apos;s 24 1/2&quot;W x 13 1/2&quot;H size is easy to read, even from the road. A cord and NEMA 5-15P plug are included. 5884 From Gold Medal Less 
 The WEBstaurant Store 267 store reviews See Store Info /gold-medal-5884-lighted/Gmk302UAOAKVGYsBAdgLXQ==/info The WEBstaurant Store $150.00 $125.99 16% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store 
 Int. Patterns Super City Lights &quot;pizza&quot; Illuminated Signage - CL-36-PI Int. Patterns Super City Lights &quot;pizza&quot; Illuminated Signage - CL-36-PI 
 ( Out of stock ) 
Int. patterns super city lites pizza light box this super city lites illuminated sign provides dynamic visibility even during the day. this sign features (1) 20 watt fluorescent lamp, (2)... More 

Int. patterns super city lites pizza light box this super city lites illuminated sign provides dynamic visibility even during the day. this sign features (1) 20 watt fluorescent lamp, (2) &quot;d&quot; rings for hanging, on/ off switch, built-in easel, black snaplock frame, double wall scratch resistant plastic chassis. standard features: manufacture: international patterns super city lites light box pizza sign (1) 20 watt fluorescent lamp (2) &quot;d&quot; rings for hanging on/ off switch built-in easel black snaplock frame illuminated sign provides dynamic visibility visibility even during the day double wall scratch resistant plastic chassis dimensions: 36&quot; x 20&quot; (w x h) model #: cl-36-pl 281653 Less 
 Wasserstrom Restaurant Supply Store not rated See Store Info /int-patterns-super-city/amgml21tN9o_uVSObZCXHA==/info Wasserstrom Restaurant Supply $262.99 No Shipping Info Visit Store 
 LED message display boards neon pizza signs LED neon tattoo LED message display boards neon pizza signs LED neon tattoo signs &amp; Light Box 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
Specifications: Whole Board Size: 25&quot; x 17&quot;LogoBox Size: 16.2&quot; x 5.9&quot;Photo film Size: 15.9&quot; X 4.9&quot;Material: Acrylic + aluminum frame on the front.LED Color: white LED for light box / RGB... More 

Specifications: Whole Board Size: 25&quot; x 17&quot;LogoBox Size: 16.2&quot; x 5.9&quot;Photo film Size: 15.9&quot; X 4.9&quot;Material: Acrylic + aluminum frame on the front.LED Color: white LED for light box / RGB LED for writing boardStructure: Board made of acrylic, frameless. LogoBox (light box) made of aluminum alloy. Metal hanger on the upper rear for hanging on walls or other solid surfaces.Input: AC 120V / 50Hz, Out put DC 12V / 800MAFeatures: The LogoBox writing pad is the perfect combination of the Flashing Board and a commercial light box.It is beautifully designed to be slim&amp; light for convenient carrying and transport.The changing LED colors will help you target customers with messages that they won¡¯t be able to avoid checking out.The backlit LED changes colors automatically in the following order: switch on ¨C white ¨C aqua ¨C purple ¨C blue ¨C yellow ¨C green ¨C red ¨C switch off. Ideal for bars, restaurants, shops and hotels.Package Include:1x Writing Board1x Marker Pen1x Wiper1x Power AdapterPerfect for the following businesses: Coffee ShopsSandwich ShopsIce Cream ParlorsFast Food OutletsWine&amp;Cocktail BarsMarketplacesP ubs&amp;RestaurantsHotels Hair&amp;Beauty SalonsBookmakersR eal Estate AgentsTravel AgentsConvenience StoresFloristsRet ail outletsBoutiques Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /led-message-display/mFjAZN3q0KrphWN9Qnh02Q==/info $119.00 +$8.99 shipping Visit Store -59% 
 Pizza LED Neon Sign With Transparent Cover 
 Pizza LED Neon Sign With Transparent Cover from $63.99 59% Off 7 stores See Details 
 Neonetics Pizza Neon Sign pizza-neon-sign 
 Neonetics Pizza Neon Sign pizza-neon-sign from $238.00 Free Shipping 2 stores See Details 
 Light Box Sign &quot;pizza By The Slice&quot; Free Shipping Lb046 Led Neon Open Light Box Sign &quot;pizza By The Slice&quot; Free Shipping Lb046 Led Neon Open 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
Features Package included 32&quot; Wide 13&quot; Tall 3&quot; Deep Design for indoor use only. One Year Warranty Visible day and night A strong lightweight plastic housing Low energy consumption... More 

Features Package included 32&quot; Wide 13&quot; Tall 3&quot; Deep Design for indoor use only. One Year Warranty Visible day and night A strong lightweight plastic housing Low energy consumption. Interchangeable message panel Sign comes with hanging materials Easy to install Ships in 3 business days Proudly made in the USA 1 custom message panel 1 cover front translucent graphic 1 bag hanging chain (36&quot;) 6&apos; ft cord include with power switch On Jun-16-08 at 21:27:20 PDT, seller added the following information: Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /light-box-sign-pizza-by/Fk7v15SwguJpU7VHDHlmQA==/info $179.00 Free Shipping Visit Store 
 International Patterns 24&quot; X 13&quot; &quot;pizza&quot; Neon Sign - NFR-PZ-2413- International Patterns 24&quot; X 13&quot; &quot;pizza&quot; Neon Sign - NFR-PZ-2413- 
 ( Out of stock ) 
International patterns 24&quot; x 13&quot; &quot;pizza&quot; neon sign when it comes to graphic impact, no incandescent or fluorescent sign can match our neon signs. eye-catching neon signs are certain to... More 

International patterns 24&quot; x 13&quot; &quot;pizza&quot; neon sign when it comes to graphic impact, no incandescent or fluorescent sign can match our neon signs. eye-catching neon signs are certain to stand out and grab attention, even in the busiest retail locations. premium quality; finest glass and phosphors. energy efficient, uses less power that an 75 watt bulb. rubber-tipped metal frame holds the unit off the glass. standard features: manufacture: international patterns neon &quot;pizza&quot; sign eye-catching premium quality and finest glass and phosphors energy efficient includes hanging kit for easy mounting mounted on black acrylic backing large tube diameters, greater distance visibility uses less power than a 75 watt bulb rubber-tipped metal frame holds unit off the glass dimensions: 24&quot; x 13&quot; plugs into any standard 110v outlet ul/ cul approved 1 year warranty model #: nfr-pz-2413-rg 318277 Less 
 Wasserstrom Restaurant Supply Store not rated See Store Info /international-patterns/Mew1fyPwkI35PKNiWmzmYA==/info Wasserstrom Restaurant Supply $133.33 No Shipping Info Visit Store 
 LED Pizza Sign for Restaurants LED Pizza Sign for Restaurants 
 Same-day shipping before 1:00PM EST on most products. ( In stock ) 
This LED pizza sign illuminates in red to draw attention to a restaurant&apos;s front entryway. The 23.5 x 11.75 display includes a 30-inch hanging chain for easy installation in a window or... More 

This LED pizza sign illuminates in red to draw attention to a restaurant&apos;s front entryway. The 23.5 x 11.75 display includes a 30-inch hanging chain for easy installation in a window or doorway. This LCD pizza sign blinks to capture the focus of guests. This food display is an LED pizza sign that is an incredible value! What makes this signage such a great deal? Simple, this LED pizza sign that is energy efficient saves money for customers on power expenses, in addition to having a low upfront price point. Restaurants can rest assured they meet any green-standards set by corporate offices when using this signage, as the energy efficiency makes these units environmentally friendly. In addition to being a great bargain, this LED pizza sign is very effective at capturing passing traffic, and patrons into a dinner, parlor or restaurant. The text is formed by a double row of red-color bulbs. This LED pizza sign that has red lights is very easy for potential customers to read, as the text pops-out from the black background and frame. An animation option comes standard on this unit as well. Pull the chain once to turn the LED pizza sign on for a non-animated illumination. Pull the chain a second time to animate the signage. Finally, pull a third time to turn the LED pizza sign off. (1) 30&quot; long chain is included with the purchase of this food display for hanging the unit in a storefront window. This restaurant fixture, led pizza sign includes a power supply with a 69&quot; long cord. The long power cord ensures users can hang the signage high in a window, while still plugging the unit into a standard height wall outlet. The light box features a plastic construction. As a result, these signs weight approximately 5 lbs, which makes them easy to mount. Illuminated window displays add new life to any storefront advertising campaign. If your parlor depends on walk-in customers for any portion of revenue, then this illuminated signage will help generate sales! Save money and buy this illuminated signage over more expensive neon signage! Dimensions: Overall: 23-1/2&quot;w x 11-3/4&quot;h x 1-5/8&quot;d Power Cord Length: 69&quot;l Hanging Chain Length: 30&quot;l [hook on each end] Weight: 5 lbs. Less 
 Displays2go Store not rated See Store Info /led-pizza-sign-for/PinD_YSr2cmVuE4Yd0m5ug==/info $68.64 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di103.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/6e/6d/70/2d73544f4c304857425731553661345a624951-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=9&amp;d;=69.99&amp;rt;=mr 
 Pizza L.E.D. Sign Pizza L.E.D. Sign 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
High Visibility PIZZA sign, shaped to blend in any variety of decors and storefronts. - Low Energy Cost: Uses ONLY 10 Watts of power. - 10 foot long cord and UL listed power adapter... More 

High Visibility PIZZA sign, shaped to blend in any variety of decors and storefronts. - Low Energy Cost: Uses ONLY 10 Watts of power. - 10 foot long cord and UL listed power adapter included. - High Visibility, even in daylight. - Easy to clean&amp;install, slim&amp; light in weight. - High quality material, sturdy&amp;impact resistant. - Cool&amp;Safe to the touch&amp;environmentally safe. - Maintenance free. 10 years life expectancy or longer. - Assembled by hand, tested prior to shipping. COMPARE TO NEON SIGNS, VISIBILITY, VALUE, COST&amp;LIFETIME. Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /pizza-led-sign/nmp-sTOL0HWBW1U6a4ZbIQ==/info $69.99 +$20.49 shipping Visit Store http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/64/73/54/53685150494c5f2d62446c4973475f6a4f4667-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=10&amp;d;=159.95&amp;rt;=mr 
 Pizza Lightbox Sign Pizza Lightbox Sign 
 ( In stock ) 
Hang this sign for pizza in your window and get ready for more sales than ever before! Illuminated from within for an eye-catching glow, this lightbox signage is sure to convince anyone... More 

Hang this sign for pizza in your window and get ready for more sales than ever before! Illuminated from within for an eye-catching glow, this lightbox signage is sure to convince anyone passing by to stop in for a slice. Features: Screened face allows the light through. Internally illuminated with two straight line fluorescent bulbs (included). Easy to hang on the wall or in the window. UL listed for indoor use only. . Specs: Dimensions: 30 W x 15 H x 4 D. Weight: 11 lb. Watts: 40. Shipping: Ships within 7 business days. Includes: Hanging kit. (2) Straight line fluorescent bulbs. Less 
 Buy.com Marketplaces 4,766 store reviews See Store Info /pizza-lightbox-sign/dsTShQPIL_-bDlIsG_jOFg==/info $159.95 +$21.95 shipping Visit Store http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/4c/47/56/6a74686e6359526e5352714c504d366f6b7651-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=11&amp;d;=179.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Light Box Sign &quot;pizza&quot; Free Shipping Lb045 Led Neon Open Light Box Sign &quot;pizza&quot; Free Shipping Lb045 Led Neon Open 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
Features Package included 32&quot; Wide 13&quot; Tall 3&quot; Deep Design for indoor use only. One Year Warranty Visible day and night A strong lightweight plastic housing Low energy consumption... More 

Features Package included 32&quot; Wide 13&quot; Tall 3&quot; Deep Design for indoor use only. One Year Warranty Visible day and night A strong lightweight plastic housing Low energy consumption. Interchangeable message panel Sign comes with hanging materials Easy to install Ships in 3 business days Proudly made in the USA 1 custom message panel 1 cover front translucent graphic 1 bag hanging chain (36&quot;) 6&apos; ft cord include with power switch On Jun-16-08 at 21:27:20 PDT, seller added the following information: Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /light-box-sign-pizza/LGVjthncYRnSRqLPM6okvQ==/info $179.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di108.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/2d/52/2d/3373575165316d563753336e414b5a48314a77-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=12&amp;d;=39.95&amp;rt;=mr 
 &quot;Pizza&quot; in Red with Green - Large 24&quot; x 13&quot; LED Business Light Sign &quot;Pizza&quot; in Red with Green - Large 24&quot; x 13&quot; LED Business Light Sign 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
This ultra bright LED sign from NEOPlex is ready to use right out of the box. Wire hanger and power cord is included. Just plug it in and get noticed. At a large 24&quot; x 13&quot;, (312 square... More 

This ultra bright LED sign from NEOPlex is ready to use right out of the box. Wire hanger and power cord is included. Just plug it in and get noticed. At a large 24&quot; x 13&quot;, (312 square inches) it is 39% larger than the standard 19&quot; x 10&quot; (190 square inches) signs. It has the brightest LED bulbs available, but the LED technology keeps the energy consumption very low. For indoor use only! Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /pizza-in-red-with-green/-R-3sWQe1mV7S3nAKZH1Jw==/info $39.95 +$7.00 shipping Visit Store http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/56/79/5a/36713364524947546f76383169466543444e77-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=13&amp;d;=104.01&amp;rt;=mr 
 Pizza&quot; Backlit Lighted Imitation Neon Sign Pizza&quot; Backlit Lighted Imitation Neon Sign 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 13&quot;x 24&quot; Lighted imitation neon window signs. Backlit with two circular fluorescent bulbs. Wording = &quot;Pizza&quot;Item Option: Sign Options=Complete Single Sided Sign - light box included Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /pizza-backlit-lighted/VyZ6q3dRIGTov81iFeCDNw==/info $104.01 +$12.65 shipping Visit Store http://di111.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/46/72/75/332d4f76504b6f41654f52675364466d5f6941-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=14&amp;d;=104.29&amp;rt;=mr 
 Acrylic Light Up Open Sign Acrylic Light Up Open Sign 
 Same-day shipping before 1:00PM EST on most products. ( In stock ) 
This light up open sign is an illuminated display that highlights an 11 by 8.5 inch Duratrans poster with the word &quot;open&quot; in neon-style print. The light up open sign is made of clear... More 

This light up open sign is an illuminated display that highlights an 11 by 8.5 inch Duratrans poster with the word &quot;open&quot; in neon-style print. The light up open sign is made of clear acrylic. Mount the frame using the standoffs, suction cups or chains. The light up open sign, also known as an illuminated business display, is for indoor use. These signs go in a window by sticking to the glazing or can be hung with the enclosed chain. Additionally, this backlit business display, light up open sign mounts directly to the wall with the standoff and screw set that comes with the unit. The standoffs have a stylish chrome finish. LED signage can go above an interior door, such as an entry way to a bar. The backlit light-up open sign can go just about anywhere within a business. The switch is easy to get to, being right on the cord itself. Whether this display is needed for a shop, bank or restaurant, the light-up open sign will effectively notify everyone that the establishment is open for business. Attract customers with these bright LED displays. The light-up open sign has graphics that are styled after neon signs. However, these backlit LED signs are not as likely to break and not as costly as traditional neon signs. The light up open sign that looks like a neon display has a modern look thanks to the transparent and silver border. These signs look best in a modern or contemporary environment. The color of the graphics will make the light up sign that plugs in very noticeable. The backlit LED panel causes the lettering to glow. This light up sign that hangs with a chain will get people to come into a bar or restaurant. Other 2-color LED business displays just don&apos;t have the refined look that these signs have. This glass mount light up open sign is the best choice for stores or bar owners that care about the visual aesthetics of their business. Click here for wall mounting instructions. Dimensions: Overall: 15-1/2&quot;w x 13-3/4&quot;h x 1-1/8&quot;d (includes depth of stand-off) Poster Size: 11&quot;w x 8-1/2&quot;h Cord Length: 107&quot; Weight: 5 lbs Hardware: Vinyl Cup Quantity: (4) Screw, Anchor&amp;Standoff Quantity: (4) Chain Quantity: (2) 24&quot;l Less 
 Displays2go Store not rated See Store Info /acrylic-light-up-open-sign/Fru3-OvPKoAeORgSdFm_iA==/info $104.29 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/34/36/65/6b386c464d6a616c4d5734426a5f4b74755f67-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=15&amp;d;=119.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Led Oval Pizza Sign Open Lamp Light Flashing Neon Led Oval Pizza Sign Open Lamp Light Flashing Neon 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
NEW LED plexiglass enclosed Pizza sign NIB Great for inside of window !!!SUPER BRIGHT !!!!!!!!!This is a brand NEW LED sign , with a powerful transformer. It is very,very bright so if you... More 

NEW LED plexiglass enclosed Pizza sign NIB Great for inside of window !!!SUPER BRIGHT !!!!!!!!!This is a brand NEW LED sign , with a powerful transformer. It is very,very bright so if you are not prepared for a real LED sign, please do not get it. This is a brand new, factory new, never used, zero hours on it LED sign!It either stays on all the time or the red Pizza flashes and the lights outside run they are blue green and yellow. Quite a display !!! This is not a dusty, smoke smelling old bar Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /led-oval-pizza-sign-open/46ek8lFMjalMW4Bj_Ktu_g==/info $119.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di108.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/66/39/68/45794a6232394b676b476169686b5a57726a51-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=16&amp;d;=139.95&amp;rt;=mr 
 Pizza By The Slice Lightbox Sign Pizza By The Slice Lightbox Sign 
 ( In stock ) 
You ve found the perfect sign for pizza joints! Backlit light boxes really stand out and these ones let everyone know you ve got hot, delicious slices for sale. Don t forget to put an extra... More 

You ve found the perfect sign for pizza joints! Backlit light boxes really stand out and these ones let everyone know you ve got hot, delicious slices for sale. Don t forget to put an extra pie in the oven! Your walk-in business is sure to to increase whenever you illuminate this enticing and eye-catching window sign. Features: Screened face allows the light through. Internally illuminated with two fluorescent bulbs (included). Easy to hang on the wall or in the window. UL listed for indoor use only. . . Specs: Dimensions: 30 W x 15 H x 4 D. Weight: 11 lb. Watts: 40. Shipping: Ships within 7 business days. Includes: Hanging kit. (2) Fluorescent bulbs. . Less 
 Buy.com Marketplaces 4,766 store reviews See Store Info /pizza-by-the-slice/f9hEyJb29KgkGaihkZWrjQ==/info $139.95 +$14.95 shipping Visit Store http://di108.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/75/5f/4a/754b5631342d47796d51654a425558574b5567-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=17&amp;d;=39.95&amp;rt;=mr 
 &quot;PIZZA&quot; in Red and Blue - Large 24&quot; x 13&quot; Oval Shaped LED Motion Business Light &quot;PIZZA&quot; in Red and Blue - Large 24&quot; x 13&quot; Oval Shaped LED Motion Business Light Sign 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
This ultra bright LED sign from NEOPlex is ready to use right out of the box. Wire hanger and power cord is included. Just plug it in and get noticed. At a large 24&quot; x 13&quot; oval, it is much... More 

This ultra bright LED sign from NEOPlex is ready to use right out of the box. Wire hanger and power cord is included. Just plug it in and get noticed. At a large 24&quot; x 13&quot; oval, it is much larger than the standard 19&quot; x 10&quot; oval shaped signs. It has the brightest LED bulbs available, but the LED technology keeps the energy consumption very low. For indoor use only! Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /pizza-in-red-and-blue/u_JuKV14-GymQeJBUXWKUg==/info $39.95 +$7.00 shipping Visit Store http://di108.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/4b/56/6f/4e31653635486c6e5f61412d484a5f76696c41-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=18&amp;d;=117.82&amp;rt;=mr 
 Pizza Sign, Lighted, Led, International Patterns Model Led-pz-2412-rg Pizza Sign, Lighted, Led, International Patterns Model Led-pz-2412-rg 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
LED-PZ-2412-RG LED Sign, Pizza, 24&quot;W x 12&quot;H x 1-1/2&quot;D, red&amp;green LED&apos;s, programmed motion sequences, aluminum frame, includes hanging kit, plugs into standard 110v outlet, UL, cUL 12(h) x... More 

LED-PZ-2412-RG LED Sign, Pizza, 24&quot;W x 12&quot;H x 1-1/2&quot;D, red&amp;green LED&apos;s, programmed motion sequences, aluminum frame, includes hanging kit, plugs into standard 110v outlet, UL, cUL 12(h) x 24(w) x 1.5(d) Built-in, pre-programmed motion sequences: Steady Blinking Chasing Flashing Lightweight, slim cabinets. Hanging kit included. Very reliable - Rated at 50,000+ hours. Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /pizza-sign-lighted-led/KVoN1e65Hln_aA-HJ_vilA==/info $117.82 +$9.69 shipping Visit Store http://di110.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/79/50/67/374a426e6f5470437262753048623964716177-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=19&amp;d;=409.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Neon Sign &quot;open Pizza By The Slice&quot; 20&quot; X 37&quot; 15570 Free Shipping Neon Sign &quot;open Pizza By The Slice&quot; 20&quot; X 37&quot; 15570 Free Shipping 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
Handcrafted Real Glass Tube Neon Sign High impact, eye catcing, real glass tube neon sign. This characteristic glow can attract customers like nothing else, virtually burning your identity... More 

Handcrafted Real Glass Tube Neon Sign High impact, eye catcing, real glass tube neon sign. This characteristic glow can attract customers like nothing else, virtually burning your identity into the minds of potential and future customers. Neon signs can be left on 24 hours a day, seven days a week, 365 days a year... for decades! There is no light form in existence that has the visual impact of neon! OUR NEON SIGNS ARE PROUDLY MANUFACTURED IN THE USA! This is the REAL THING, 100% Handcrafted real glass tube neon. We manufactuer the most vibrant neon avaliable. Look for the &quot;REAL NEON&quot; certification to guaranteed top quality neon! Comes complete with everything you need to use immediately Made with a solid state transformer backed by a full 1 year warranty * 37&quot; wide by 20&quot; tall by 3&quot; deep * The sign is mounted on a unbreakable black backing. * Top and bottom protective sides * 110 volt U.L. listed transformer that plug into a standard outlet * Hanging hardware and chain are included * 6&apos; power cord * For indo Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /neon-sign-open-pizza-by/yPg7JBnoTpCrbu0Hb9dqaw==/info $409.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/51/59/41/6937593356415775693562384f66616a586e67-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=20&amp;d;=99.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 LED Neon Write-On Boards pizza signs retail store LED Neon Write-On Boards pizza signs retail store signs hanging signs personalized corporate gifts 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
Specifications: Size: 32&quot;x24&quot;.Simple button control with 7 color lights, changing in rotation, for multicolor combinations.The writing surface is a rigid abrasion resistant PMMA board, easy... More 

Specifications: Size: 32&quot;x24&quot;.Simple button control with 7 color lights, changing in rotation, for multicolor combinations.The writing surface is a rigid abrasion resistant PMMA board, easy to write-on and wipe-off.Large firm writing area for unlimited creative choices. Portable, easy to set up by hanging vertically. Energy-saving, environmentally- friendly, durable and long-lasting.No computer necessary to create powerful graphic images and text.Package Includes:1x Message Board1x White Fluorescent Marker Pen1x Wiper1x Power Adapter1x Hanging ChainPerfect for the following businesses: Coffee ShopsSandwich ShopsIce Cream ParlorsFast Food OutletsWine&amp;Cocktail BarsPubs&amp;RestaurantsHotels&amp;Convention CentersHair&amp;Beauty SalonsBookmakers BookstoresEstate Agents Real Estate Agents Travel AgentsConvenience Stores Convenient StoresFloristsRet ail outletsBoutiquesL ED Flashing Board is the latest form of commercial promotion device to cater your needs in marketing, with contents subject to various needs. Provides a lot of flexibility in the type of fonts, patterns, drawings, designs, as far as your imagination takes flight and sky is the limit. It is excellent in seasonal promotion, marketing for festivity, boosting sale, discount, special offer, opening of business, latest special events, etc.The change of colorful display by the unique flashes is appealing to the eyes of passers-by, whom you will turn into the customers for your business. Note: This listing is for the Writing Board only and does not include the Easel or Re-chargeable Battery. You may purchase these items separately from our store. Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /led-neon-writeon-boards/QYAi7Y3VAWui5b8OfajXng==/info $99.00 +$12.49 shipping Visit Store http://di1-3.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/89/64/a7/121141352-100x100-0-0_neonetics+pizza+neon+sign+by+neonetics+5pizza.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=21&amp;d;=218.99&amp;rt;=mr 
 Pizza Neon Sign - By Neonetics - 5pizza 
 Pizza Neon Sign - By Neonetics - 5pizza from $218.99 Free Shipping 2 stores See Details http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/30/39/57/324b757434676a49577342436374326e784c41-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=22&amp;d;=124.82&amp;rt;=mr 
 Pizza Sign, Lighted, Neon, International Patterns Model Nfr-pz-2413-rg Pizza Sign, Lighted, Neon, International Patterns Model Nfr-pz-2413-rg 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
NFR-PZ-2413-RG Packed: each Neon Sign, Pizza, 24&quot;W x 13&quot;H x 4&quot;D, red&amp;green tempered glass tubes, mounted on black acrylic&amp;metal frame, built in shock absorbers, window bumpers, includes... More 

NFR-PZ-2413-RG Packed: each Neon Sign, Pizza, 24&quot;W x 13&quot;H x 4&quot;D, red&amp;green tempered glass tubes, mounted on black acrylic&amp;metal frame, built in shock absorbers, window bumpers, includes hanging kit, plugs into standard 110v outlet, UL, cUL 13(h) x 24(w) x 4(d) inkfrog terapeak Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /pizza-sign-lighted/09W2Kut4gjIWsBCct2nxLA==/info $124.82 +$10.98 shipping Visit Store http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/36/4c/5a/423559736a6a6e425936676b50707463794967-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=23&amp;d;=97.4&amp;rt;=mr 
 Chef Pizza Restaurant Menu Sign Flashing Advertising LED writing Board Neon Chef Pizza Restaurant Menu Sign Flashing Advertising LED writing Board Neon Sign 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
Specifications&amp;Special Features:Size of Board:27&quot; x 23&quot;Surface : Made of rigid abrasion resistant acrylic board, with superb translucency for efficient lighting. Large firm writing area... More 

Specifications&amp;Special Features:Size of Board:27&quot; x 23&quot;Surface : Made of rigid abrasion resistant acrylic board, with superb translucency for efficient lighting. Large firm writing area for unlimited creative choices. Easy to write-on and wipe-off. Durable for repeated use.LED: Best-in-class, with light emission up to twice as bright as other products. Energy-saving, environmentally- friendly, extended longevity Outer Frame : Fabricated from supreme quality of aluminum alloy. Galvanized for protection. Flashing Modes : Simple button control with 7 lighting LED colors. Various flashing modes, speeds, with multicolor combinations to grab public attention.. Portability : Lightweight but sturdy. Easy to carry and set up anywhere. Can be hung on the wall or placed on a stand. Avoid moisture, rain, snow, and prolonged exposure to sunlight for outdoor location. Package Includes:1x Flashing LED Board1x Marker Pen1x Wiping Cloth1x Power Adapter 1x Controller1x Hanging Chain1x extension cord The LED Flashing Board is the latest in commercial promotions and caters to your marketing needs with easily changeable content. This provides you with flexibility in the fonts, patterns, drawings, and other designs used as the only limiting factor is your imagination. It is excellent for use in seasonal promotions, marketing festivities, boosting sales, showcasing discounts and special offers, grand openings, marking special events, and more.The announcement written thereon will not be missed with the flashing and color changing features, and will thus capture the public attention to boost sales. Note: This listing is for the Writing Board only and does not include the 6-color Marker Set, the Easel, or Re-chargeable Battery. You may purchase these items separately from our store. Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /chef-pizza-restaurant/6LZB5YsjjnBY6gkPptcyIg==/info $97.40 +$10.49 shipping Visit Store http://di110.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/59/76/37/74754869345a496e4d4f6a426d5474412d3141-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=24&amp;d;=59.99&amp;rt;=mr 
 &quot;Pizza&quot; Italian Restaurant Led Neon Business Motion Light Sign. On/off with Chain 22*13*1 Blt216 &quot;Pizza&quot; Italian Restaurant Led Neon Business Motion Light Sign. On/off with Chain 22*13*1 Blt216 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
Product Specification: Bright LEDs, Operating Voltage: 110 VAC Up to 100,000 hours of operation Time. Animation ON/OFF switch button. UL approval power cord. High Energy Efficiency, 10... More 

Product Specification: Bright LEDs, Operating Voltage: 110 VAC Up to 100,000 hours of operation Time. Animation ON/OFF switch button. UL approval power cord. High Energy Efficiency, 10 watt power consumption which is at a very good energy efficiency. Light weight and easy to install. Safe to touch and operate. For indoor use only. Dimension Measurement: 22&quot;L x 13&quot;W x 1&quot;H A metal hanging chain is included. Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /pizza-italian/Yv7tuHi4ZInMOjBmTtA-1A==/info $59.99 +$6.99 shipping Visit Store http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/54/56/5a/556630314747664a2d57386458677541594867-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=25&amp;d;=395.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Neon Sign &quot;pizza By The Slice&quot; 26&quot; Round 11163 Free Shipping Open Neon Sign &quot;pizza By The Slice&quot; 26&quot; Round 11163 Free Shipping Open 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
Handcrafted Real Glass Tube Neon Sign High impact, eye catcing, real glass tube neon sign. This characteristic glow can attract customers like nothing else, virtually burning your identity... More 

Handcrafted Real Glass Tube Neon Sign High impact, eye catcing, real glass tube neon sign. This characteristic glow can attract customers like nothing else, virtually burning your identity into the minds of potential and future customers. Neon signs can be left on 24 hours a day, seven days a week, 365 days a year... for decades! There is no light form in existence that has the visual impact of neon! Comes complete with everything you need to use immediately! OUR NEON SIGNS ARE PROUDLY MANUFACT Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /neon-sign-pizza-by-the/TVZUf01GGfJ-W8dXguAYHg==/info $395.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/5f/34/4c/6c685841736a4a4b696e6a5831495942563877-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=26&amp;d;=305.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 &quot;pizza By The Slice&quot; Flashing Neon Sign 30x17x3 &quot;pizza By The Slice&quot; Flashing Neon Sign 30x17x3 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
THIS IS A QUALITY NEONSIGN PROUDLY MANUFACTURED IN THE USA BACKED BY A ONE YEAR WARRANTY!! Comes complete with everything you need to use immediately! High impact, eye catching, real... More 

THIS IS A QUALITY NEONSIGN PROUDLY MANUFACTURED IN THE USA BACKED BY A ONE YEAR WARRANTY!! Comes complete with everything you need to use immediately! High impact, eye catching, real flashing NEON sign. With a characteristic brightness that can attract customers like nothing else and a moving light that draws the eye right to it, it will virtually burn your identity into the minds of potential and future customers. NEON signs can be left on 24 hours a day, seven days a week, 365 days a year. Th Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /pizza-by-the-slice/_4LlhXAsjJKinjX1IYBV8w==/info $305.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di1-4.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/89/09/ed/120696629-100x100-0-0_neonetics+neonetics+pizza+led+sign+5pzled.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=27&amp;d;=134.99&amp;rt;=mr 
 Neonetics Pizza LED Sign 5PZLED 
 Neonetics Pizza LED Sign 5PZLED $134.99 Free Shipping 1 store See Details http://di111.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/38/43/4f/707a6a37715f6544636e615635355836374351-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=28&amp;d;=49.99&amp;rt;=mr 
 Pizza LED Sign - Modern Neon Replacement - Highly Visible Pizza LED Sign - Modern Neon Replacement - Highly Visible 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
Size 19&apos;&apos;L x 9 3/4&apos;&apos;H x 1 1/2 &apos;&apos;D LED signs are the most cost effective advertising tool that a business store owner can use to attract customers. Our signs are all animated, employ the... More 

Size 19&apos;&apos;L x 9 3/4&apos;&apos;H x 1 1/2 &apos;&apos;D LED signs are the most cost effective advertising tool that a business store owner can use to attract customers. Our signs are all animated, employ the best quality and long lasting LEDs possible. There is not a single more cost effective way to make your business visible, an LED sign that would last you 10 years or longer at a negligible electricity cost, with a much lower energy consumption rate than neon sign products. Leave them on for 24 hours a day, 7 days a week!. LED signs are a must have for any business store owner. All of RockBottom Signs are backed by our 100% quality guarantee and defective exchange policy! Hanging chain is included. Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /pizza-led-sign-modern/8COpzj7q_eDcnaV55X67CQ==/info $49.99 +$14.49 shipping Visit Store http://di104.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/6d/77/67/454d7145553542546357324d68645a6c795951-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=29&amp;d;=24.99&amp;rt;=mr 
 Animated Led Pizza Neon Business Sign Deluxe 19x10 106 Animated Led Pizza Neon Business Sign Deluxe 19x10 106 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
Jewelingerie Store ANIMATED LED PIZZA Neon Business SIGN Deluxe 19x10 106 Prev Stop Play Next Description 19&quot; x 10&quot; Bright LED Light PIZZA Sign Multi Color Deluxe Design In Motion Animation... More 

Jewelingerie Store ANIMATED LED PIZZA Neon Business SIGN Deluxe 19x10 106 Prev Stop Play Next Description 19&quot; x 10&quot; Bright LED Light PIZZA Sign Multi Color Deluxe Design In Motion Animation On/Off Function NEW !!Model: BLT106 (19&quot; x 10&quot;)This Aution is for a brand new Bright LED 19&quot;x10&quot;PIZZA Sign with animation On/Off functions and Power On/Off Switches. These ultra bright LED signs are brighter than the neon sign and highly visible even under daylight.Your business will have higher visibility a Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /animated-led-pizza-neon/mwgEMqEU5BTcW2MhdZlyYQ==/info $24.99 +$9.99 shipping Visit Store http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/5f/30/4e/6f744a514948534941414c7866656a78646f77-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=30&amp;d;=99.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 LED portable business signs Neon pizza signs Yard sale... LED portable business signs Neon pizza signs Yard sale signs LED Menu Board As Xmas Gift 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
Specifications: Size: 32&quot;x24&quot;.Simple button control with 7 color lights, changing in rotation, for multicolor combinations.The writing surface is a rigid abrasion resistant PMMA board, easy... More 

Specifications: Size: 32&quot;x24&quot;.Simple button control with 7 color lights, changing in rotation, for multicolor combinations.The writing surface is a rigid abrasion resistant PMMA board, easy to write-on and wipe-off.Large firm writing area for unlimited creative choices. Portable, easy to set up by hanging vertically. Energy-saving, environmentally- friendly, durable and long-lasting.No computer necessary to create powerful graphic images and text.Package Includes:1x Message Board1x White Fluorescent Marker Pen1x Wiper1x Power Adapter1x Hanging ChainPerfect for the following businesses: Coffee ShopsSandwich ShopsIce Cream ParlorsFast Food OutletsWine&amp;Cocktail BarsPubs&amp;RestaurantsHotels&amp;Convention CentersHair&amp;Beauty SalonsBookmakers BookstoresEstate Agents Real Estate Agents Travel AgentsConvenience Stores Convenient StoresFloristsRet ail outletsBoutiquesL ED Flashing Board is the latest form of commercial promotion device to cater your needs in marketing, with contents subject to various needs. Provides a lot of flexibility in the type of fonts, patterns, drawings, designs, as far as your imagination takes flight and sky is the limit. It is excellent in seasonal promotion, marketing for festivity, boosting sale, discount, special offer, opening of business, latest special events, etc.The change of colorful display by the unique flashes is appealing to the eyes of passers-by, whom you will turn into the customers for your business. Note: This listing is for the Writing Board only and does not include the Easel or Re-chargeable Battery. You may purchase these items separately from our store. Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /led-portable-business/_0NotJQIHSIAALxfejxdow==/info $99.00 +$12.49 shipping Visit Store http://di110.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/6d/73/46/484554735a4135585878735463614e32684c41-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=31&amp;d;=295.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 &quot;pizza&quot; Flashing Neon Sign 30x17x3 14469 Free Shipping &quot;pizza&quot; Flashing Neon Sign 30x17x3 14469 Free Shipping 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
THIS IS A QUALITY NEONSIGN PROUDLY MANUFACTURED IN THE USA BACKED BY A ONE YEAR WARRANTY!! Comes complete with everything you need to use immediately! High impact, eye catching, real... More 

THIS IS A QUALITY NEONSIGN PROUDLY MANUFACTURED IN THE USA BACKED BY A ONE YEAR WARRANTY!! Comes complete with everything you need to use immediately! High impact, eye catching, real flashing NEON sign. With a characteristic brightness that can attract customers like nothing else and a moving light that draws the eye right to it, it will virtually burn your identity into the minds of potential and future customers. NEON signs can be left on 24 hours a day, seven days a week, 365 days a year. Th Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /pizza-flashing-neon/msFHETsZA5XXxsTcaN2hLA==/info $295.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di104.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/41/4d/64/6c46544b46714349553059427a4e734a695651-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=32&amp;d;=49.99&amp;rt;=mr 
 Animated Pizza Led Sign Neon Italian Restaurant Business Running Deluxe 216 Animated Pizza Led Sign Neon Italian Restaurant Business Running Deluxe 216 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
Jewelingerie Store ANIMATED LED Light PIZZA Neon SIGN Running Deluxe 216 Description Bright LED Light PIZZA Sign Multi Color Deluxe Design In Motion Animation On/Off Function NEW !!Model:... More 

Jewelingerie Store ANIMATED LED Light PIZZA Neon SIGN Running Deluxe 216 Description Bright LED Light PIZZA Sign Multi Color Deluxe Design In Motion Animation On/Off Function NEW !!Model: BLT216 Want it NOW!! Need other designs!! This Auction is for a brand new Bright LED Deluxe PIZZA Sign with animation On/Off functions and Power On/Off Switches. These ultra bright LED signs are brighter than the neon sign and highly visible even under daylight.Your business will have higher visibility and the Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /animated-pizza-led-sign/AMdlFTKFqCIU0YBzNsJiVQ==/info $49.99 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di101.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/52/78/33/4d76516b7931467636337938416d566b796567-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=33&amp;d;=59.99&amp;rt;=mr 
 &quot;PIZZA&quot; Italian Restaurant Led Neon Business Motion Light Sign. On/off with Chain 16*28*1 Blt8058 &quot;PIZZA&quot; Italian Restaurant Led Neon Business Motion Light Sign. On/off with Chain 16*28*1 Blt8058 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
Product Specification: Bright LEDs, Operating Voltage: 110 VAC Up to 100,000 hours of operation Time. Animation ON/OFF switch button. UL approval power cord. High Energy Efficiency, 10... More 

Product Specification: Bright LEDs, Operating Voltage: 110 VAC Up to 100,000 hours of operation Time. Animation ON/OFF switch button. UL approval power cord. High Energy Efficiency, 10 watt power consumption which is at a very good energy efficiency. Light weight and easy to install. Safe to touch and operate. For indoor use only. Dimension Measurement: 16&quot;L x 28&quot;W x 1&quot;H A metal hanging chain is included. Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /pizza-italian/Rx3MvQky1Fv63y8AmVkyeg==/info $59.99 +$6.99 shipping Visit Store http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/59/2d/66/4863666b3041513450765676664b355a475751-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=34&amp;d;=119.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 LED writing board with lightbox Pizza Shop Store Sign Signboard LED writing board with lightbox Pizza Shop Store Sign Signboard 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
Specifications: Whole Board Size: 25&quot; x 17&quot;LogoBox Size: 16.2&quot; x 5.9&quot;Photo film Size: 15.9&quot; X 4.9&quot;Material: Acrylic + aluminum frame on the front.LED Color: white LED for light box / RGB... More 

Specifications: Whole Board Size: 25&quot; x 17&quot;LogoBox Size: 16.2&quot; x 5.9&quot;Photo film Size: 15.9&quot; X 4.9&quot;Material: Acrylic + aluminum frame on the front.LED Color: white LED for light box / RGB LED for writing boardStructure: Board made of acrylic, frameless. LogoBox (light box) made of aluminum alloy. Metal hanger on the upper rear for hanging on walls or other solid surfaces.Input: AC 120V / 50Hz, Out put DC 12V / 800MAFeatures: The LogoBox writing pad is the perfect combination of the Flashing Board and a commercial light box.It is beautifully designed to be slim&amp; light for convenient carrying and transport.The changing LED colors will help you target customers with messages that they won¡¯t be able to avoid checking out.The backlit LED changes colors automatically in the following order: switch on ¨C white ¨C aqua ¨C purple ¨C blue ¨C yellow ¨C green ¨C red ¨C switch off. Ideal for bars, restaurants, shops and hotels.Package Include:1x Writing Board1x Marker Pen1x Wiper1x Power AdapterPerfect for the following businesses: Coffee ShopsSandwich ShopsIce Cream ParlorsFast Food OutletsWine&amp;Cocktail BarsMarketplacesP ubs&amp;RestaurantsHotels Hair&amp;Beauty SalonsBookmakersR eal Estate AgentsTravel AgentsConvenience StoresFloristsRet ail outletsBoutiques Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /led-writing-board-with/Y-fHcfk0AQ4PvVvfK5ZGWQ==/info $119.00 +$8.99 shipping Visit Store http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/57/46/62/526533566462344836385359317a7379456a77-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=35&amp;d;=262.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 &quot;pizza&quot; Flashing Neon Sign 30x17x3 14068 Free Shipping &quot;pizza&quot; Flashing Neon Sign 30x17x3 14068 Free Shipping 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
High impact, eye catching, real flashing NEON sign. This NEON sign will make a great impact on your customers. 30&quot; Wide x 17&quot; Tall x 3&quot; Deep Mounted on a Black Lexan Backing This sign can... More 

High impact, eye catching, real flashing NEON sign. This NEON sign will make a great impact on your customers. 30&quot; Wide x 17&quot; Tall x 3&quot; Deep Mounted on a Black Lexan Backing This sign can flash or be solid Cool, Quiet Energy- Efficient, Uses the same amount of power as a 75 Watt light bulb High Visibility Easy To Clean - Easy Installation - Comes With All Hanging Hardware. Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /pizza-flashing-neon/WFbRe3Vdb4H68SY1zsyEjw==/info $262.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/61/35/4c/31554b56496b2d6b4431484b586c6b756f3867-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=36&amp;d;=148.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Neon Sign &quot;pizza&quot; 8&quot; X 24&quot; X 3&quot; 12281 Neon Sign &quot;pizza&quot; 8&quot; X 24&quot; X 3&quot; 12281 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
Handcrafted Real Glass Tube Neon Sign High impact, eye catcing, real glass tube neon sign. This characteristic glow can attract customers like nothing else, virtually burning your identity... More 

Handcrafted Real Glass Tube Neon Sign High impact, eye catcing, real glass tube neon sign. This characteristic glow can attract customers like nothing else, virtually burning your identity into the minds of potential and future customers. Neon signs can be left on 24 hours a day, seven days a week, 365 days a year... for decades! There is no light form in existence that has the visual impact of neon! OUR NEON SIGNS ARE PROUDLY MANUFACTURED IN THE U S A !! This is the REAL THING, 100% Handcrafte Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /neon-sign-pizza-8-x/a5L1UKVIk-kD1HKXlkuo8g==/info $148.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/73/73/39/536f6f4765774c37574763386f6f39784b6767-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=37&amp;d;=134.99&amp;rt;=mr 
 Neonetics Pizza LED Sign Neonetics Pizza LED Sign 
 ( In stock ) 
NEO1447 Features: Plugs into regular outlets Ready to hang 100pct L.E.D. lights Black plastic frame Includes: 12V AC adapter operates energy efficient LED lights (included) Assembly... More 

NEO1447 Features: Plugs into regular outlets Ready to hang 100pct L.E.D. lights Black plastic frame Includes: 12V AC adapter operates energy efficient LED lights (included) Assembly Instructions: No assembly required Dimensions: Dimensions: 12&apos;&apos; H x 24&apos;&apos; W x 1&apos;&apos; D Less 
 Walmart 470 store reviews See Store Info /neonetics-pizza-led-sign/ss9SooGewL7WGc8oo9xKgg==/info $134.99 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/6f/62/7a/414748584f3441394d7836445a645076514767-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=38&amp;d;=129.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Pizza Ultra Bright Neon Led Merchandising Sign, Lit Merchandiser Lighted Display Pizza Ultra Bright Neon Led Merchandising Sign, Lit Merchandiser Lighted Display 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
 Pizza Ultra-Bright Neon Lighted Sign Pizza Ultra-Bright Neon LED Merchandising Sign Brand New - 3 Year Manufacturer Warranty - Factory Direct Whether you&apos;re looking to bring life to your... More 

 Pizza Ultra-Bright Neon Lighted Sign Pizza Ultra-Bright Neon LED Merchandising Sign Brand New - 3 Year Manufacturer Warranty - Factory Direct Whether you&apos;re looking to bring life to your home&apos;s rec room, or attract and draw customers to your business, this PIZZA Ultra-Bright Neon Lighted Sign is cut out for the job. The Ultra Bright line of high quality signs feature bright LED back lighting, so that they can be seen even in the harshest lighting conditions. Not only are they environmentally fr Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /pizza-ultra-bright-neon/obzAGHXO4A9Mx6DZdPvQGg==/info $129.00 +$35.00 shipping Visit Store http://di1-3.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/75/5a/65/118679402-100x100-0-0_aarco+products+high+visibility+led+sign+sign+messa.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=39&amp;d;=53.45&amp;rt;=mr 
 Aarco Products High Visibility LED Sign Sign Message: Pizza, Size: 6 .75&quot; H x... 
 Aarco Products High Visibility LED Sign Sign Message: Pizza, Size: 6 .75&quot; H x 16.125&quot; W from $53.45 3 stores See Details http://di101.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/45/46/67/6262774b724a3230324536516550542d4a5f67-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=S7OxJ0aJ3O&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2011%3A13%3A01%20AM&amp;r;=40&amp;d;=30.44&amp;rt;=mr 
 Open Pizza Led Neon Business Motion Light Sign. On/off with Chain 19*10* Open Pizza Led Neon Business Motion Light Sign. On/off with Chain 19*10* 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) High quality led neon sign.19X10 &quot; On/Off switch , hanging chain included Up to 100,000 UP TO HOURS OF OPERATION Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /open-pizza-led-neon/EFgbbwKrJ202E6QePT-J_g==/info $30.44 Free Shipping Visit Store 1 2 3 4 5 ... 38 Next  » Why are these stores listed?   
 
Sponsored Listings
 
   
 Pizza Online bestellen 
 Riesen Auswahl bei Lieferando! In 2 min online bestellen. 
 www.lieferando.de/Pizza-bestellen 
 pizza.de - Die Auswahl. 
 Pizza in Kassel! Auswählen, bestellen, genießen 
 www.pizza.de/Kassel 
 Par Sign Lighting 
 American-made, low voltage lights lighting a sign or restaurant menu 
 www.barnlightelectric.com/sign 
 Light bei OTTO 
 Immer voll im Trend - Mit Mode von Light bei OTTO! 
 www.otto.de/Markentrends 
 Pizza Sign Info 
 Get Info on Pizza Sign. Access 10 Search Engines At Once. 
 www.info.com/de 
 
   
Related Guides:
 
 Dallas Cowboys 1994 Michael Irvin White Jersey With 75th Patch 
 by ospop If you are an avid football fan, you will probably have a... 0 
 Dallas Cowboys 1971 Roger Staubach Throwback White Jersey 
 by ospop If you are an avid football fan, you will probably have... 0 
Prices are provided by the merchants. We assume no responsibility for accuracy of price information provided by merchants. Please alert us to any pricing discrepancies and we will alert the merchant. Sales taxes are estimated at the zip code level. Shipping costs are estimates. Please check store for exact shipping costs. To learn more about why certain stores are listed on the site, click here 

Product specifications are obtained from third parties, and while we make every effort to assure the accuracy of product information, we do not assume any liability for inaccuracies. Store ratings and product reviews are written and submitted by online shoppers to assist you as you shop. They do not reflect our opinions. We take no responsibility for the content of ratings and reviews submitted by users.
 
Products on Sale
 -59%
	</body>
</document>
