<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001918" url="http://www.blogto.com/toronto/the_best_thai_restaurants_in_toronto/" time="2012-07-12-17:49" support="9" score="0.023550424065080226" bingtitle="The Best Thai Restaurants in Toronto - blogTO | Toronto blog" webtitle="The Best Thai Restaurants in Toronto">
			<query id="001459" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="001175" bing-rank="250"/>
			<query id="000443" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="001238" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000987" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000290" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000037" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000296" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000289" bing-rank="35"/>
	<description>The Best Thai restaurants in Toronto all conjure memories of backpacks and reclining ... In the end, everyone will be shilling their first &quot;wow&quot; Thai experience and will ...</description>
	<body>
		blogTO | Toronto Blog 
South Indian Dosa Mahal, Bloor&amp;Lansdowne.
 By Tanja -Tiziana Burdi.
 
 Best of Toronto Restaurants Events Movie Listings Street Style City and Culture 
 
City
 City Morning Brew Environment Technology Sports&amp;Play People Travel 

 
Culture
 Arts Music Fashion&amp;Style Eat&amp;Drink Film Theatre Books&amp;Lit 

 
Other
 Radar Opening Soon Deadpool Photo of the Day Video Podcasts Announcements 

 
Special Sections
 Fashion Week Contact Photo Festival Toronto Club District Artist Gallery Filmmakers Jet-Setters Contests 

 City Guide 
 
Food&amp;Drink
 Bakeries Bars Cafés Grocery Stores Restaurants 

 
Recreation
 Art Galleries Fitness Clubs Hotels 

 
Shopping
 Books Design Fashion Services 

 
Other
 Neighbourhoods City Guide Toronto Maps 
 Neighbourhoods: Select... All Neighbourhoods Annex Baldwin Village Bayview and Leaside Beaches Bloor West Village Bloorcourt Bloordale Village Cabbagetown Chinatown Church Wellesley Village Corktown Corso Italia Danforth Distillery District Dundas West East Chinatown Eglinton West Etobicoke Financial District Forest Hill Village Harbourfront Junction Junction Triangle Kensington Market King East King West Koreatown Leslieville Liberty Village Little India Little Italy Markham Mount Pleasant North York Ossington Pape Village Parkdale Port Lands Queen West Richmond Hill Riverside Roncesvalles Village Rosedale Scarborough St. Clair West St. Lawrence Market Upper Beaches West Queen West Yonge&amp;Bloor Yonge&amp;College Yonge&amp;Dundas Yonge&amp;Eglinton Yonge&amp;St. Clair Yonge&amp;Wellesley Yorkville 
 
 Thursday, July 12, 2012 — Partly Cloudy 25°C go 
 Best of Toronto 
 Tweet 
The Best Thai Restaurants in Toronto

Posted by Frank / May 5, 2011 
 151 Comments 
 The Best Thai restaurants in Toronto all conjure memories of backpacks and reclining Buddhas, beaches and the banana pancake trail. Some pull of the trick with ambience. Cribbed signifiers are borrowed from the wats and night markets that litter the land of smiles from Koh Lanta to Chiang Mai, elephants and old gods hanging from exposed brick walls suffuse rooms with shorthand orientalism or opium den shadows evoking a more sultry landscape than our own.

More importantly, all of the best Thai restaurants pull off a much more immediate bit of alchemy transporting patrons through the food they serve. Combining spices, rice sticks, curries and chilli heat, the best Thai restaurants in Toronto thaw local taste buds with authentic flavour and, keeping the ketchup to a minimum, pull off some everyday magic on their menus.

Here are the best Thai restaurants in Toronto.

 Note: This list was previously published on May 15th, 2008. Comments below made up until February 9th, 2011 are in reference to the old list. We&apos;ve purposely kept the archived comments here because we believe they (mostly) add value to this topic. If you don&apos;t want to have to wade through all of them, simply hit the &quot;sort by newest first&quot; link at the top of the thread. 

 Top photos by Jim 2 , foodpr0n and mila0506 on Flickr. 
 
 Khao San Road 

A “Regular” contributor to Best Thai lists, Jeff&amp;Nuit’s Khao San Road eschews tourist kitsch for authentic flavour. The food is definitely worth the sometimes excruciating wait. Classic Khao Soi with chicken, complex and deeply flavourful curries, 2 versions of text book pad thai, insanely great squash fritters and now Singha too! I’d say get there early to avoid the line but 9 am is a little early for Thai (though rumour has it they’re launching a brunch menu soon). More» 
 
 Sukhothai 

Dean Moriarty to Khao San Road’s Sal Paradise, Sukhothai is a little less polished than its Club District companion, and located in a little more rough-and-tumble `hood, but this place is definitely no sidekick. Nuit Regular’s recipes now dished out by Jeff’s family, this place still delivers the goods - to your front door even, provided you don`t mind the occasionally long wait. More» 
 
 Mengrai Thai 

Mengrai Thai is a cooking school, a catering outfit and an excellent restaurant, tucked away at Richmond&amp;Ontario streets. The modern brick room offers Chef Sasi’s take on “haute Thai cuisine” which combines Thai flavours and western techniques. Beef tenderloin with pomegranate tamarind infusion? Red curry with lychee? Braised lamb with peach? Don’t call it fusion, just call it delicious. More» 
 
 Salad King 

The dog days are over for this downtown stalwart forced relocated after a fire destroyed their original digs. Their much delayed relaunch had Ryerson students smilin’ like buddhas at the chance to once again gorge on favourites like golden curry and the house pad thai at OSAP-friendly prices. More» 
 
 Golden Thai 

Golden Thai has been dishing out a solid selection of curries and stir-frying noodles longer than most other Thai restaurants in the city. In-laws coming from outta town will be impressed by the ambiance of this well-lit elegantly appointed space, as you regale them with travel stories from your month in Koh Samui. Better leave the full moon party pictures til dessert. More» 
 
 Thai To Go 

Not exactly far east, this Cabbagetown outpost offer solid takes on snacks from the smiling kingdom. Thai To Go gives a 10% discount on pick up orders and ups it 3% if you bring your own containers. Don&apos;t expect to eat in though. The Thai here is strictly a take-out affair. More» 
 
 Thai Chef 

Roncesvalles represents with Thai Chef. Large portions of Thai standards with fresh, bright flavours abound on the extensive menu and they even do &apos;cue too! I&apos;d definitely cross town for a roasted duck curry or some spicy asparagus with shrimp if I didn`t have to pass both 1 and 2 on this best-of list to get here. More» 
 
 Baan Thai 

No PC sauce, the memories of Thailand nonetheless come fast and furious in the Junction at Baan Thai. The som tum, and spicy green papaya salad on offer are reportedly some of the best versions had outside of Thailand though the pad thai somewhat disappoints though for such large portions at such reasonable prices, I can`t see how your meal would have anything but a happy ending. More» 
 
 Sorn Thai 

Holding down the final spot on our list, this uptown entrant on the best of list offers decent Thai for the young and eligible. Skip the no-frills decor at Sorn Thai like a bad flash intro and order what some claim to be the tastiest pad thai north of Bloor to go instead. More» 
 
Discussion

151 Comments
 
 Sort By Oldest First / Newest First 

 Subscribe 
 andrea. / May 15, 2008 at 09:52 am What, no Thai Express?!?! ;)

I must say, I don&apos;t understand the appeal of Salad King -- and I&apos;m not even that particular about authentic Thai taste or anything. Their pad thai seriously tastes like a wet dog to me.
 Reply Jade / May 15, 2008 at 10:13 am THAI BASIL!!! I&apos;m originally from Asia and have traveled around Thailand extensively, and always complained about Thai food here being too North American-ized (aka not enough spice). But after stumbling upon this little gem in the Annex boy was I wrong... my nose was running the whole meal and that&apos;s a great thing! Reply Randy / May 15, 2008 at 10:56 am Bene&apos;s USED to be good (Coxwell and Queen), but I can&apos;t even eat there anymore. Bland, tasteless pad thai, and they don&apos;t even put shrimp or chicken in there anymore, just noodles and ersatz ketchup, bleh! Reply Joshua / May 15, 2008 at 11:07 am Ketchup in pad thai just pisses me off. And tastes gross.

It&apos;s funny... in Thailand, the busiest places were almost universally the best. In Toronto, it sort of feels like the opposite. For example, ever since their makeover, I&apos;ve left Salad King disappointed. Yet it&apos;s packed. Reply Shawn / May 15, 2008 at 12:45 pm I&apos;d strongly recommend Green Basil in the Beach. They&apos;re relatively new (6 or so months), but the food is outstanding, the prices are good and the owner and staff are really great. Reply Kari / May 15, 2008 at 12:52 pm Thai food is something that I was introduced to (thrown into, really) when I moved to Toronto. I&apos;d never had it before I starting working as a bus girl at Bangkok Garden (toughest job I ever had). Now, it&apos;s my all-time favourite. I haven&apos;t gone back to eat at BG, since it&apos;s so crazy expensive, but the food there is pretty good, and visually pleasing to boot.

Salad King holds a special place in my heart... only because of a certain dish that isn&apos;t on the menu. It&apos;s called Thai Islamic Noodles, and I&apos;m wondering if mentioning it here is a good idea, or a bad one! I&apos;ve never seen this dish in any other restaurant, and cannot figure out what makes the sauce so damn good. Thank you Linda!

Another one to mention, that isn&apos;t on this list... Lee&apos;s Thai Spring Rolls in Parkdale. Best Pad Thai in the city, in my opinion. Reply Jack / May 15, 2008 at 12:53 pm salad king is terrible Reply Pickle / May 15, 2008 at 02:21 pm Is Crystal Rolls not on the list because their menu isn&apos;t all Thai food? Reply Chester Pape / May 15, 2008 at 06:06 pm If that was the case then how would SoTR make 2nd place since it&apos;s Indonesian/Thai combined. Reply Astro Turf / May 15, 2008 at 06:24 pm What??? No Young Thailand??? Shame!!! Reply Chester Pape / May 15, 2008 at 07:53 pm I&apos;ve not tried the current incarnation of Wandee&apos;s empire now relegated to the west end but in the past they could be very uneven, the location at Gerrard and Jarvis was, for example a genuine filthy shithole by the time it changed hands, then a few months later it closed. Reply Todd Tyrtle / May 15, 2008 at 09:45 pm Ones to avoid: Anyone who thinks Pad Thai should have catsup in it (the red tinge is a dead giveaway.

My favourite? It&apos;s quite a haul from downtown (but near one of my clients) - Thai Bamboo over on Steeles west has some of the best Thai food I&apos;ve had anywhere. Their tofu gaeng pa is to die for. Reply Jaime / May 15, 2008 at 11:13 pm Guys, seriously try Pi-Tom&apos;s on Alexander street and midtown on Yonge south of Eglinton. It&apos;s the best kept secret that shouldn&apos;t be a secret anymore. Dig it! Reply M / May 16, 2008 at 12:09 am Dude, Real Thailand!!? Reply jack / May 16, 2008 at 11:44 am might want to check out an asian fusion restaurant call Riz at bayview and eglinton.. the mango with sticky rice dessert is heavenly good.. Reply joe / May 16, 2008 at 01:16 pm I have to 2nd Shawn&apos;s recommendation of Green Basil in the Beaches.... great stuff.

Also, it&apos;s my understanding that tamarind in some forms has a ketchup-like taste - so you may be eating tamarind at those&quot;red&quot;pad thai places.

One benefit of Salad King is the chili scale. My wife can eat liquid fire, so she loves it. :) Reply Hwan / May 16, 2008 at 02:05 pm I&apos;m a big fan of Thai Princess, on King just east of Spadina. Their lunch menu presents a triple threat -- excellent seafood, excellent curries, and excellent pad thai&apos;s. As such, their seafood curry pad thai is out of this world. Atmosphere is nothing to shout about, but it&apos;s clean and you&apos;ll be too busy rolling your eyes in pleasure anyway.

Thai Chef Cuisine is also pretty damn tasty. I recommend their tamarind beef -- crispy, saucy, tangy. Reply Hank / May 16, 2008 at 02:37 pm My Thai Kitchen in Kingsway Village. It is incredible! Reply Katie / May 19, 2008 at 08:47 pm I second the vote for Thai Princess. It&apos;s absolutely my favourite place for Thai in the city. Reply AT / May 20, 2008 at 08:54 am My recommendation: Just Thai on Church Street, south of Wellesley. The only thing on their menu that I don&apos;t recommend is their cold rolls, which are filled and wrapped too thickly for my taste. This makes them harder to eat and makes the lack of flavour in the rice paper more apparent. Reply helen / May 21, 2008 at 01:32 am cafe 668 is not thai. it&apos;s more vietnamese. Reply redleaf / May 23, 2008 at 12:20 pm thanks for the list - we went to Golden Thai for the first time as a result (we recently moved into the area). After quite possibly our best Thai dinner to date, we can see why it&apos;s so highly rated.

Now to work our way through the rest... Reply jerryscott / June 6, 2008 at 03:53 pm The best Thai restaurant in Toronto is Sukhothai. Its located at 274 Parliament street Toronto. I?ve been to Thailand many times and this is definitely real Thai food. None of that ?Thai fusion? stuff. I?m not saying that ?Thai fusion? doesn?t taste good, but if I?m going to eat at a Thai restaurant, I want to eat real Thai food, just like they make it in Thailand. If you feel like me, Sukhothai is the place to go. It?s very affordable and the family who owns it are very friendly. The food is so good. And the cook is Thai! Reply Joshua / June 6, 2008 at 05:16 pm @jerryscott - Do they have kuaytiaw sukothai on the menu? Sukothai sounds good. Reply Ken / June 8, 2008 at 11:28 am A small new Thai takeout and delivery just opened in Cabbagetown on Gerrard Street called Thai To-Go ...totally authentic, fresh thai food...excellent, high quality and very friendly Reply thefoodguy / June 9, 2008 at 01:23 pm Joshua- Sukhothai does have kuaytiaw. Never tasted it yet, but I&apos;ve heard from a friend that it was great and not expensive! Maybe I&apos;ll try it next time I go by. Reply jason gouveia / June 27, 2008 at 05:48 pm i agree with jerryscott. sukhothai is extremely authentic, well priced and good healthy portions. throw in their &apos;wall of thai travels&apos; (customers bring in their pictures of past visits to thailand) and you feel like you&apos;re wondering down a bangkok sidestreet. no banglassi but still...

and they are the friendliest most genuine family i&apos;ve ever met Reply Thai food critic / June 30, 2008 at 09:38 pm Ok there is this little&quot;Mom and Pop&quot;thai place on Roncesvalles at Howard Park Blvd. (no, not the place they talk about in the review here!!!) it&apos;s called VICKY&apos;S FISH AND CHIPS - doesn&apos;t look like much from the outside but it has a great patio in the back - not very fast service (*I recommend calling and ordering ahead!) but it&apos;s friendly and probably the BEST THAI FOOD YOU HAVE EVER EATEN!!! Better than Thai food IN Thailand! Large portions, pretty huge menu! Chicken and Shrimp Pad Thai is my fav! (I know, I know - the &apos;big noodle&apos; is pretty good too!) It&apos;s worth the hike from anywhere in the city and it&apos;s pretty cheap too! Reply jack / July 10, 2008 at 04:19 pm if u ever go up to richmond hill, u have to try out Restoran Malaysia.. it&apos;s on major mac and bayview.. 815 major mac drive E closed mondays.. have to try their iced milk tea(lai cha), you know the one, they make tea from using women&apos;s stocking, pouring and pulling tea from two containers to ensure it is mixed properly... Reply Susann / July 13, 2008 at 09:06 pm Went to Baan Thai on Dundas for dinner today and absolutely LOOOOVED it. My husband has been to Thailand before and thought this was the best outside Thailand so far. That was 3 hours ago and I&apos;m still stuffed!! Will DEFINITELY go back for some more soon! Reply Carmen / July 25, 2008 at 10:54 pm I just ate at QUEEN GARDEN THAI at 785 Queen Street West and it was DELICIOUS! I&apos;ve eaten at most of the Thai restaurants in T.O . and this one was by far the best. It&apos;s got a cool lounge interior and has a great atmosphere...but the food is the best part. I had the Basil Chicken and it was fantastic - it had the perfect amount of spice. Go try it today! Reply Jamie carter / July 29, 2008 at 04:01 am wow a thai place in my Nebourhood it was DELICIOUS place cal THAI GRILL BISTRO at Don mills @ steeles (inside the cliffwood plaza) U guys gota try the thai&amp;malay food in there juisy red curry with shrimp in it. Definitely great place for us in willowdale........(416)495 8424 Reply Chiron / August 6, 2008 at 11:23 am You are missing Flip Toss and Thai on Harbord. Same chef as the original Salad King with the prices that Salad King used to have before their reno. Reply theRookieHousewife / August 12, 2008 at 01:24 pm I second the Thai Express nomination! Reply Daniel / August 12, 2008 at 03:16 pm Um, tell me I&apos;m not the only person who doesn&apos;t just WALK BY the Queen Mother Cafe at 208 Queen Street West. They&apos;ve been around for years and I think too many people forget that just because they&apos;re in the&quot;cool&quot;area of town, that doesn&apos;t mean they don&apos;t have GREAT food. Reply ThaiCanuck / September 26, 2008 at 06:28 pm Salad King is a big joke for Thai community here. The foods they are serving is far from being authentic, so don&apos;t tell anyone you love Thai foods (if you happened to have something at Salad King). Most of Thai restaurants here are not authentic. Pad Thai is made of ketchup and rice noodle. Some of authentic dishes can be found at Mangrai, Bua Thai and Bann Thai among others. Reply Sw / October 11, 2008 at 08:28 pm Young Thailand rocks - please check it out and add to your list! Love their Mango Salad, Tamarind Shrimp, Panang Kai, Green and Red Curry! And yes Golden Thai is a fav as well! Will try Mengrai and let you all know how it is:) Reply zun / October 19, 2008 at 02:10 am Thai Elephnat on queen st The best Thai curry and .pad thai Reply Dale replying to a comment from Astro Turf / December 2, 2008 at 11:38 am I agree. Young Thailand is wayyy better than half of the restaurants mentioned. Reply delta / December 23, 2008 at 08:34 pm I would recommand Thai Angles, first time i went there, just to try out the food, I thought it would b the same as others thai restaurant but not, the food it&apos;s amazing their pad thai thai style it&apos;s taste like homemade pad thai, also i made a special request from nothern style like&quot;num prik ong&quot;OMG I feel like im in thailand again, the service very good, chef very freindly she came and talk to me but the restaurant is quite, i&apos;m surprise why!
I hope their business is working well!! Reply Jommi / January 8, 2009 at 03:43 pm I highly recommend every Thai foodie to visit Mengrai Thai the best Thai restaurant in Toronto IMO. We went there Dec 27 after we read that Mengrai was chosen Globa and Mail 2008 Top 10 Restaurants by Joanna Kates.
link
 http://www.theglobeandmail.com/servlet/story/LAC.20081018.KATES18/TPStory/?query=Mengrai 

We also out that it was chosen editor&apos;s Best Thai 2008 by NOW MAGAZINE
link:
 http://www.nowtoronto.com/guides/readerspoll/2008/story.cfm?content=165687 

My friend (he&apos;s a sous chef at the chic Cactus Club Cafe, BC and worked with Rob Feenie) and I agreed that Mengrai Thai is as good as the famed Vij&apos;s in Vancouver. IMO, Mengrai serves the best Pad Thai in Canada, period. We travelled all over Thailand for 3 months, it&apos;s even better than those we tried there!, including the Oriental.
The food is not just stunning with more layers of flavours and texture, the presentations were very artistic especially when we went back to Mengrai again with a group of 6 to celebrate new year&apos;s eve. We ordered the impressive 5 course specials and it was the best Thai dinner we have ever had. I&apos;m sure Jessica Alba, Kate Moss, Bill Gates were right when they discovered this restaurant earlier. The servers were helpful and took their time to help us get around some allergies and ordered one of us a gluten free meal. Even though they were busy and always full(we&apos;re lucky to get a late 9pm table), they&quot;keep checking discreetly&quot;to make sure everything was okay. They have a great small wine list and recommended us a great Kiwi Pinot Noir and a dry Riesling to pair with our food. Check out their crispy morning glory and lobster tom yum soup which reflected the skills of their international renowned Thai chef Sasi who was once rated top 5 chefs in Toronto by the Le Journal de Montreal. The only thing was I didn&apos;t get a chance to meet her (the place was busy) and have a photo with her as now I&apos;m a big fan of her cooking finesse.

By the way, I missed my old long time favourite Young Thailand but it&apos;s not comparable to Mengrai Thai.

I also went to another top 10 restaurants, Nota Bene last week, it&apos;s worth many more visits. A lot more pricier than Mengrai though. Reply Sam / February 11, 2009 at 02:18 pm THAI BISTRO. On yonge south of Finch! All the way! best Thai in town. Reply Dobbs / February 16, 2009 at 02:43 pm I can&apos;t believe Sorn Thai (Yonge between Eglinton and Lawrence) isn&apos;t on this list. Terrific food. Reply TH / February 16, 2009 at 11:57 pm Real Thailand belongs on this list Reply Zabee / March 15, 2009 at 09:44 am I am from Thailand and I rarely like going out to eat at Thai restaurants...mostly cook food at home. We were told that Bangkok Garden is one of the best places for Thai and we decided to go there with some friends. Gosh it was terrible and overpriced. So far I think Sukhothai in Mississauga is the best thai in the GTA area...they have good food (pretty authentic and great service. Not to confuse it with Sukhothai on Parliment and Dundas...food here is nothing to die for....just cheap and more for the Canadian palate. Reply thai lvr / March 20, 2009 at 07:54 pm Sorn Thai on Yonge North of Eglinton is the BEST pad thai in Toronto. Nothing fancy but very consistent. Great cold rolls as well! Pad thai is sooooooo good I crave it. Golden thai is good if you want a big, expensive dinner. Sorn Thai is good any time for amazing thai food! I go there so much, they know my order! GO!!! Reply fgirl / March 29, 2009 at 11:25 am Sukho Thai on Parliament is amazzzzing!!!!!!!!
I was a litlle skeptical when eating at a Thai food place, it&apos;s always been a hit or miss for me. But when I had the pad thai here what an experience. This place is a real authentic place to get Thai food!! A definite must :) the ppl are very nice and friendly!! their casava cake is yummy as well. I will be back
 Reply charl / March 29, 2009 at 11:43 am SUKHO THAI (274 Parliament, (416) 913-8846, open only fri and sat for lunch and dinner now) is hands down my favorite place to get thai food in the city. I discovered this place later last year and have been going back every 1-2 weeks or so. Here are a couple of reasons that make this place absolutely stand out:

1. Service: the family that runs the resto is very genuine and friendly. Always smiling, and they treat everyone who comes in like family. it&apos;s very clear that they work hard, and put a lot of effort into the food. they are proud of it, and they definitly should be!! the food is prepped by the Thai wife who does everything from scratch. Either her father-in-law, or her husband will take the orders, and deliver. Occasionally they have a family friend who comes to help out at the counter.

2. Authentic Thai food: When i traveled in thailand, this is exactly what we were eating. The same flavors, cooked in the same way. The curries are also remarkably delicious here. The best green and masaman curry i&apos;ve had in Toronto! I find though that the oil settles on the top after a while, if you get it in the take out container. It&apos;s very flavorful, and a favorite amongst my circle of friends. They also do their fried menu items very well. Extremely light, and crispy, without being oily and greasy. Their fried fish is wonderful, very tender and soft, with a crispy exterior, the green mango salad that comes with it, is very fresh ($9). The spring rolls are also excellent. They are fried to perfection, and very tightly wrapped, with a nicely seasoned filling. Again, not greasy (2/around $3). The phad-thai is different from the other phad-thai&apos;s i&apos;ve had in Toronto. The noodles are flatter and wider, like a ho-fun noodle. The sauce has a smokey flavor to it. There aren&apos;t any raw bean sprouts or coriander to mix into the noodles (which i&apos;ve never seen done in thailand anyways). It&apos;s not like other offerings in Toronto, but it is authentic, i think it comes does to personal taste if you prefer this style or Western version of the dish. The first time i had it, i was immediately transported back to Thailand, so i am personally fond of their noodles here. Oh, and try their chili sauce, it&apos;s not like a Sirracha chili paste, it is made from dried chilies and fried garlic in hot chili oil. It&apos;s delicious, very smokey, it&apos;s made in house i think. We eat this with everything we get from Suhko Thai.

3.Good prices: Very affordable, esp for the amount of work that goes into food prep. i don&apos;t think there is anything more than $11 here.

Limitations: They don&apos;t have any Thai drink offerings (thai iced tea, fruit shakes, etc), only canned pop, water, and coconut juice; and they serve their food on paper plates. True, the decor is simple,and the place is tiny: there are only 3 tables with a side bar area that seats 4. The resto itself is nothing special, but what the resto lacks in ambiance the food def makes up for.

If you haven&apos;t try it, i would def recommend this place for take out or delivery. sit in is fine as well, if it&apos;s a group smaller than 3. during dinner they have started a buffet style take out, so there are no long waits. Get the phad thai, and try the masaman curry for your first time, but you can&apos;t really go wrong with anything on the menu. yum!! It&apos;s a small resto, run by a very hardworking family, that produces very delicious authentic Thai food.
 Reply MoMo / May 10, 2009 at 01:12 pm Sukhothai by far the best thai food around period. It ia a good news that they are open Monday to Saturday. And wow what a difference with new set of table and cuttlery AAA+++

Thank You for being around Reply Corinne / June 9, 2009 at 03:25 pm A year later, some of these are not even open any more.
Time for an update? Reply marcus / July 1, 2009 at 11:51 am Just tried the new &apos;Young Thailand&apos; restaurant on King and Strachan. What a disappointment! I can excuse poor food but not when they reheat the food. Everything we ordered had the whiff of being made earlier. plain lazy IMO. Reply Erin / July 11, 2009 at 02:20 pm The Friendly Thai on Roncesvalles is infinitely better than the Thai Chef. Reply Foodhogger replying to a comment from andrea. / August 17, 2009 at 02:10 pm Agreed! Salad King is disgust - had possibly the worst meal (ever) there.
 Reply Mike / August 21, 2009 at 11:59 am Real Thailand - Spadina and Bloor OWNS Pad Thai in this city.
Thai express is also really good (considering it&apos;s a take out joint). Reply Mike / August 21, 2009 at 12:00 pm Real Thailand - Spadina and Bloor OWNS Pad Thai in this city.
Thai express is also really good (considering it&apos;s a take out joint). Reply Pat / September 10, 2009 at 03:24 am Gotta go with Thai food critic&apos;s choice, Sue&apos;s Tai Food (Vicky&apos;s Fish&amp;Chips) is hands down the best Thai in town. Also with no surprise her Fish&amp;Chips are also one of my faves. Reply Todd / September 15, 2009 at 07:49 pm Thai Cold Springroll in Parkdale by far the best and well priced and they deliver!!! Reply jane / November 6, 2009 at 09:51 pm thai princess on king street has the best pad thai in town and i&apos;ve tired many. Reply Kristi / November 12, 2009 at 11:29 am Siam Princess on Lakeshore in Long Branch has some of the best thai food I have ever had. I am a fan of the Won Ton Pad Thai. The dish is made with crispy won tons instead of pad thai noodles. The sauce does not have a recipe I have been told, so everytime it has a different taste. It is fantastic! Sweet and savoury. The Crispy Basil Chicken is also a great dish, spicey and fresh. My friends also enjoy Siam&apos;s Hot and Sour Soup, Silver noodle soup, frseh rolls, spring rolls and siam squares. Oh, and the sweet plum sauce they make is so yummy! To top it off the service is top notch. The staff is friendly but not in an annoying way. The really care about the customers that come through the door. I suggest trying this place out. You will be going back, again and again!

Kristi
 Reply louise / November 24, 2009 at 02:49 pm having actually been to thailand as well and tasted real thai food... i find the pad sew noodles at thai express to be particular authentic and extremely good as well as real thailand on bloor... alot of dishes at thai basil are a load of crap.. and then noodles suck Reply nancy / December 9, 2009 at 01:28 am guys i thing and recommend for everyone who read this must go to THAI SPRING ROLL at 525 bloor st west just east of bathurst their food is amasing its now under new management and they also delivery its really great customer service the padthai its delicius u must try once anyone they tryed recently and wasnt happy please replie me there phone number is 416 588 THAI Reply CAROLINE / December 30, 2009 at 04:21 pm I&apos;m surprised that&quot;My Thai Kitchen&quot;is not on the list! That place is amazing. Someone should definitely do a review for that lil&apos; amazing thai restaurant. Reply Cambro / January 17, 2010 at 12:34 pm I&apos;m surprised that Taste of Thai House did not make this list. Located on Vaughan just south of St. Clair W., this family run establishment has been keeping me fed with a diverse and award winning menu for years. Reply wan replying to a comment from Carmen / January 24, 2010 at 12:08 pm queen garden cuisine and thai elephnat 813 queen st west is the same owner both good food. Reply Sami / February 1, 2010 at 03:03 pm I&apos;m a fan of Thai Elephant and Pi-Tom. Actually, Pi-Tom has a special on TeamBuy.ca today. $12 for $15 worth of cuisine. Check it out. It&apos;s a good deal. Reply Smack Wack replying to a comment from Astro Turf / February 14, 2010 at 01:51 pm Check out Young Thailand&apos;s Dine Safe record:
 http://app.toronto.ca/food2/DineSafeMain?userRequest=view_history&amp; ;ESTABLISHMENT_ID=10332114

Ugh, and I just ate there last night. Reply Embarassed / March 21, 2010 at 06:19 pm WOW.

No Khmer Thai?!!?!?!

Khmer Thai is better than every single suggestion yet. blogTO should be ashamed. it simply does not get better. People who&apos;ve tried it never go anywhere else. they return religiously.

Salad King? Are you joking?

And what&apos;s with all the vietnamese on this list? Do we not have enough thai and vietnamese and cambodian in toronto that we cannot distinguish between them? What a farce. This list looks like someone just googled popular spots. The whole point of having critics is to separate popular from good.

I&apos;m still wondering how khmer didn&apos;t even make it on this list. what a joke.

 Reply krapow / March 25, 2010 at 06:55 pm having been to thailand numerous times over the years, one of the biggest issues i have with toronto thai food, and even &apos;authentic&apos; thai places is the replacement of thai holy basil (Bai Gkaprow), with &apos;regular&apos; thai basil (bai horapa). the flavors are nowhere close. In my opinion most thai restraunts in the city offering pad gkarpow just substitue &apos;regular&apos; basil, and, well in this case, the menus should list the dish as pad horapa. same situation with pad kee mow, my all time fav dish (thai drunken noodles)...If anyone knows any places in the city that actually do use thai holy basil (Bai Gkaprow) in their dishes, i would be very eager to hear. I am currently growing my own holy basil for cooking at home, as it appears to be pretty rare here and goes bad very quickly if purchased from grocery store.

Khmer Thai does sound pretty interesting, and i think i will check it out one day soon. I miss authentic khmer food almost as much as genuine thai. :(

this list is def a good starting point for me though. thx


 Reply Dave / March 26, 2010 at 12:13 pm Thai Grill on eglinton belongs on this list.
They have the best pad thai in town..Love their Mango Salad :)
 Reply Davidson / April 4, 2010 at 08:07 am I highly recommond Thai Green Chili, I went there several time everytime they kept the same taste. it used to be called Thai Green Mango. Reply juli / April 6, 2010 at 01:44 am not yet THAI SPRING ROLL ON BLOOR shame check out guys u never will go some where else Reply CaptainCommonSense / June 17, 2010 at 09:45 pm Some of these comments are ridiculous.&quot;Wah, my Thai place isn&apos;t on here! Madness! It&apos;s the end of the world&quot;. Lord people, read the g&apos;damn date on the article and not just tunnel vision on the date of your comment.

That aside, I&apos;ve been to Sasi&apos;s once and it was pretty good there. Vicky&apos;s Fish and Chips/Sue&apos;s Thai is also pretty good. The consistency on their golden curries can be a bit of a downer from time to time but most of the time they do get it right. I&apos;ve also tried Baan Thai once.. it was pretty alright though things have changed. I used to order from the place when it was Somporn Thai Cuisine. Prices are up and order queries are different, so I spent a long time having to order over the phone.

I also love Green Mango - despite how casual-metro the place may be. I have not been disappointed by them once yet.


In the end, everyone will be shilling their first&quot;wow&quot;Thai experience and will usually stick to&quot;their&quot;restaurant. Screw loyalty, just go around and try everything. You may be in for a surprise. Reply CaptainCommonSense / June 17, 2010 at 09:46 pm Some of these comments are ridiculous.&quot;Wah, my Thai place isn&apos;t on here! Madness! It&apos;s the end of the world&quot;. Lord people, read the g&apos;damn date on the article and not just tunnel vision on the date of your comment.

That aside, I&apos;ve been to Sasi&apos;s once and it was pretty good there. Vicky&apos;s Fish and Chips/Sue&apos;s Thai is also pretty good. The consistency on their golden curries can be a bit of a downer from time to time but most of the time they do get it right. I&apos;ve also tried Baan Thai once.. it was pretty alright though things have changed. I used to order from the place when it was Somporn Thai Cuisine. Prices are up and order queries are different, so I spent a long time having to order over the phone.

I also love Green Mango - despite how casual-metro the place may be. I have not been disappointed by them once yet. Also been to Spring Rolls - they&apos;re pretty ok.


In the end, everyone will be shilling their first&quot;wow&quot;Thai experience and will usually stick to&quot;their&quot;restaurant. Screw loyalty, just go around and try everything. You may be in for a surprise. Reply Sassy / July 10, 2010 at 11:25 am Real Thailand for sure! Everything from glass noodles to curry are all delicious and fast! However, if you have to go to the bathroom bring your hiking boots! oh my! Reply Claire / September 29, 2010 at 08:53 am I ate at Baan Thai last night on Dundas Street West and have to say that it is the best Thai food I have had outside of Thailand. The prices are more than reasonable and the best part is the family running it is actually from Thailand! I would recommend everyone to go and try it out for themselves! YUM! Reply morcha / September 30, 2010 at 12:34 am THAI SPRING ROLL ON BLOOR HAVE GREAT DEAL GO CHECK OUT ON WEBSITE DEALFIND U WILL LOVED TO GO BACK GREAT SERVICE AND VERY FREINDLY Reply sean / October 16, 2010 at 12:37 pm If u love thai food try @ asianmonsoon once you will be amazed,the quality and flavours well blend together... Reply Jen / November 22, 2010 at 09:12 pm Thai dish has really good Phad Thai. I mean not the ketchup flavour one like most of the places.

Another one I recommend would be Classic Thai Cuisine at Jane and Bloor. Every noodle dishes are great (I tried them all, I&apos;m in love with their Phad See Ew) If you love Thai curry, you get to try their flavourful curry. Reply Anon / December 13, 2010 at 06:02 pm Taste of Thai House on Vaughan Road for me. It&apos;s simple and homey yet very fresh and tasty food. I haven&apos;t tried a lot of places on this list though. I have a lot to try! Reply Just went there / January 3, 2011 at 08:52 pm Thai Green Chili is @SS Reply Kazimmoh / January 4, 2011 at 11:05 am This list does not have Sukhothai on it. This list is crap. If any of the restaurants even came close to it, that would be okay. But when there is a league of a difference...

Sukhothai has about ten dishes... and does them extremely well. All dishes are made by the (award winning) chef herself.

Ask for the Sukhothai Pad Thai for the first time. But really, every dish is a winner.

( http://www.sukhothaifood.com/ ).


There are some restaurants you can debate about Reply clippingimages / January 11, 2011 at 11:30 pm My mouth is watering!!!!! Reply Wanida / February 9, 2011 at 09:18 pm May I suggest new Thai restaurant on King and Church.

They make many excellent Thai dishes.

 http://www.galangalthaifusion.ca Reply Bernie / May 5, 2011 at 11:00 am a list compiled by palate&apos;s of kids from queen west and cityplace it looks like? Reply Mike / May 5, 2011 at 11:01 am I haven&apos;t been to many of these places, so I can&apos;t tell you if it&apos;s anywhere near the&quot;best&quot;in the city, but Simply Thai in the Bloor West Village gives you giant portions for a really good price and it&apos;s always very tasty. Reply Larry / May 5, 2011 at 11:09 am Don&apos;t bother ordering from Sukhothai for delivery. The food is fantastic, but only if you pick it up yourself. When you call their&quot;delivery number&quot;you&apos;ll either get their voicemail followed by a message saying their voice mailbox is full, or (if you&apos;re lucky) you&apos;ll get a live voice who seems to not be aware that the phone they just answered is for delivery orders and is therefore not helpful, will get your order wrong, and is just plain rude. Don&apos;t get me wrong, the food here is amazing - as long as you put in the effort of goign to get it yourself. Otherwise, you&apos;ll end up frustrated, hungry and disappointed. Reply NC / May 5, 2011 at 11:16 am Mmmmmmm ... Thai Chef!!! Delish! Reply mr. elephant / May 5, 2011 at 11:33 am Thai Elephant on Queen near Euclid is really, really good. Reply fn / May 5, 2011 at 11:57 am I always thought that I hated Thai food until I went to Sukhothai and had REAL Thai food. Khao San Road is also very good.
Salad King is awful. This is one of the places that made me think that Thai food is disgusting. It&apos;s really not- it&apos;s just the garbage Thai food that is so prevalent in TO. Reply Andrew / May 5, 2011 at 11:57 am Khao San Road :) Reply Guapogiboy replying to a comment from andrea. / May 5, 2011 at 12:07 pm You must be asian if you know what dog tastes like.... Their pad thai is not tasteless... it&apos;s far better than EAST&apos;s Phud Thai crap! I swear I had to ask the chef for satay sauce, fish sauce and modified his dish to make it edible... Reply Danny replying to a comment from charl / May 5, 2011 at 12:18 pm They do have Thai Iced Tea Reply Jen / May 5, 2011 at 12:44 pm Phuket Paradise on Yonge/Centre is divine if anyone ventures north of Finch. Reply the lemur replying to a comment from Jade / May 5, 2011 at 12:59 pm It&apos;s nice that they&apos;re emphasising the genuineness of their food, but Thai Basil&apos;s sign about having &apos;Thai cooks only&apos; seems a bit racist. Reply taylor / May 5, 2011 at 01:10 pm it is a travesty that the Thai Shan Inn isn&apos;t on this list! Reply LJ replying to a comment from the lemur / May 5, 2011 at 01:46 pm I disagree, its nice to know that real Thai chefs are cooking Thai food. Khao San Road serves great food, and the waiter is very sexy too :P
 Reply the lemur replying to a comment from LJ / May 5, 2011 at 01:53 pm Yeah, but it also suggests they wouldn&apos;t hire a non-Thai who could be an excellent cook of Thai food. After all, being Thai is not a guarantee of being able to cook Thai food, just as with any other nationality and cuisine. I&apos;m sure there&apos;s plenty of bad Thai food being cooked in Thailand for the benefit of tourists who don&apos;t know better. Reply Digital camera / May 5, 2011 at 03:03 pm Terrific to see a blog post which goes into some detail on this subject. Reply Digital camera / May 5, 2011 at 03:04 pm Terrific to see a blog post which goes into some detail on this subject.
 http://byphotography.com/ Reply T / May 5, 2011 at 03:26 pm Smiling like buddhas?! Reply marie replying to a comment from Todd Tyrtle / May 5, 2011 at 03:59 pm YES I was just going to recommend thai bamboo as well!!! delicious!! Reply Sherman Mikes / May 5, 2011 at 04:13 pm The best-of list comments are quite dated and the shilling from owners should be culled. Is there any plan by BLOGTO to publish new lists, or will we be looking at a six year-old list in three years still? Reply yt replying to a comment from Sherman Mikes / May 5, 2011 at 07:30 pm sherman mikes,
is there any plan for you to read the article? specifically the emphasized paragraph:
&quot;Note: This list was previously published on May 15th, 2008. Comments below made up until February 9th, 2011 are in reference to the old list. We&apos;ve purposely kept the archived comments here because we believe they (mostly) add value to this topic. If you don&apos;t want to have to wade through all of them, simply hit the&quot;sort by newest first&quot;link at the top of the thread.&quot;
Or will we be answering these questions every time blog.to updates its lists? Reply Jo / May 5, 2011 at 07:54 pm Mengrai Thai, The $39 prix fixed 4 courses menu. You will never regret. All food is good. I like Bass Reply Vincent / May 5, 2011 at 09:21 pm Don&apos;t like this list. Save for the first 3, why forget about Salad King&apos;s better sister resaurant&quot;Linda&apos;s&quot;? And what about Thai Bistro? Restaurants located in the North get no respect at all. Reply V / May 6, 2011 at 12:39 am I&apos;m very surprised Thai Basil isn&apos;t on this list. I doubt the author has done his homework. Thai Basil is one of the highest rated restaurants on Urban Spoon. Their price is amazing and the food is incredibly authentic, and this coming from an Asian who just came back from Singapore. The service is also terrific. Reply unknown / May 6, 2011 at 10:07 am This list is CRAPIOLLI without Real Thailand (Bloor Spadina)
Author - BOOOOO- weak on the subject Reply frank replying to a comment from unknown / May 6, 2011 at 10:37 am Hi Unknown! thanks for your feedback! I&apos;m always happy to repeat the following caveat EVERY TIME i write a best-of post:

The selections were voted on by our readers through a survey that was posted on the site and was merely assembled by the author. There was even an&quot;other&quot;option where you could write in a restaurant that wasn&apos;t on the list. You have noone but yourself to blame that your favourite place didn&apos;t make the list. Try participating next time instead of just sitting there and complaining after the fact. Reply timmy / May 6, 2011 at 05:53 pm SALAD KING RULES! Reply theladykay / May 7, 2011 at 11:34 am I went to Salad King for the first time since they opened up again last week and I was really unimpressed. I don&apos;t know if my palate has become more sophisticated or if they have gotten crappier, but I really wasn&apos;t impressed. My favourite Thai Place in Toronto is Pi Toms on Alexander Street. It&apos;s really nice in the summer with their outdoor patio! Reply Alice / May 9, 2011 at 12:02 am Venipha Lanna near St. Clair&amp;Christie is utterly DIVINE. Best Pad Thai in the city. It must be that Laotian infusion. Reply yt replying to a comment from Alice / May 9, 2011 at 09:03 am @alice
VL closed last month. it was very good, i agree. Reply Darryl / May 9, 2011 at 04:36 pm I drove around for almost an hour looking for Vanipha Lanna, only to find out it had closed. Does anyone know if they&apos;ve reopened under another name ? I loved their Food. Reply Khmer Thai Fan replying to a comment from Embarassed / May 10, 2011 at 11:39 am I agree, not listing Khmer Thai is odd. It&apos;s the best Thai food I&apos;ve had, and I&apos;ve tried many places in the city. Reply Sonya / May 11, 2011 at 11:07 pm I would fly to Toronto just for this food, having not been there since they burned down then reopened, but I have heard that it is AMAZING still. Reply G. / May 17, 2011 at 12:25 pm Urban Thai on College has the best Pad Thai, as far as I&apos;m concerned. Reply kaj / May 28, 2011 at 08:15 pm The information is quite old and not upto date. Have you try Royal Elephant, 1100 Eglinton Ave.??? I&apos;m sure you will be impressed by the taste and the environment of the restaurant. Reply Xeb / June 4, 2011 at 02:56 pm http://asianfoodtoronto.wordpress.com/ 

Visited Khao san road...its different, but good

If you&apos;re used to the sweeter pad thai it might not be for you! Reply Fei / June 9, 2011 at 12:01 pm I just visited Royal Elephant. The taste is excellent. Green curry is the best and no ketchup in Pad Thai. Reply Shonna / July 2, 2011 at 05:18 pm The Thai Shan Inn is simply amazing.. The service isn&apos;t the best the food keeps you coming back! Check it out, you really don&apos;t know what you are missing! Reply Cess / July 20, 2011 at 02:55 pm When I was living in Toronto I used to lunch at Taste of Thai house, it&apos;s absolutely delicious!! The best Pad Thai I&apos;ve ever had!!! :D

62 Vaughan Rd Toronto, ON M6G 2N4

&lt;3 I love it! Reply Lavender Blume / July 29, 2011 at 09:45 am I can&apos;t believe ppl are slagging Salad King! Sure, it&apos;s a loud, cafeteria-style joint and it&apos;s not as authentic as Sukhothai (the best IMHO - their phad thai is the real deal). But the food is fresh, vibrant and cheap. Quick, friendly service. Their Thai Islamic curry noddles (not on the menu but still avail) is amazing. Golden Thai is excellent - I found it similar to Bangkok Garden. Spice Thai Cafe on the Waterfront is good too. I&apos;m surprised Thai Chef made it on the list - it&apos;s in my hood but I wasn&apos;t impressed. Maybe I should give it another shot... Reply I like Turtles / August 16, 2011 at 05:41 pm Khao san road was awesome! Though it has nothing to do with my comment, I like turtles Reply A. Gold / September 22, 2011 at 08:45 pm There is a place called Hungary Thai in Kensington Market. Its a blend of Hungarian, and Thai foods - I think its because one owner is Hungarian, and the other Thai. REALLY DELICIOUS.

 http://www.whattodotoronto.com/?seachtext=thai&amp; ;btnseachall=Go&amp;view=seachall&amp;rid=170

 http://www.blogto.com/restaurants/hungarythai Reply A. Gold / September 22, 2011 at 08:46 pm There is a place called Hungary Thai in Kensington Market. Its a blend of Hungarian, and Thai foods - I think its because one owner is Hungarian, and the other Thai. REALLY DELICIOUS.

 http://www.whattodotoronto.com/?seachtext=thai&amp; ;btnseachall=Go&amp;view=seachall&amp;rid=170

 http://www.blogto.com/restaurants/hungarythai Reply Keziah P / October 22, 2011 at 05:57 pm LMAO, Salad King ranked higher than Golden Thai? LMAO this must be a joke. Reply Northway Financial / November 17, 2011 at 11:45 am This is the worst article of all, I&apos;ve read
 http://instantloansgroup.com/ Reply Pharmacie En Ligne / November 18, 2011 at 06:27 am I have a few question to you, write to those I do not e-mail
 http://hommepharmacie.com Reply Arti / December 1, 2011 at 02:26 pm I&apos;ve had #1 and #2 now because of this list -- I agree both are amazing...as a former Ryerson student, REALLY? Salad King made this list!? Reply Romance Books for download / December 21, 2011 at 10:03 am Lately, I didn’t give lots of consideration to leaving feedback on blog page posts and have placed comments even much less.
 http://www.cheapebook.net/c1064/download-cheap-Romance/ Reply Cornpops replying to a comment from M / December 29, 2011 at 11:04 am Real Thailand is the best and great value Thai food in Toronto that we keep going back to. We live north of the city and drive down to Spadina and Bloor to have our taste of the &apos;real&apos; Thailand. We lived in Bangkok for 3 years and my husband is Thai so we know authentic Thai food. Linda is also good and Salad King definitely has the ambience of dining in Thailand. We used to go to Bangkok Gardens but yes, it is pricey for what you get -- go to Real Thailand, the food is delish and the owners are Thai and very friendly!!! Reply Cornpops replying to a comment from Cornpops / December 29, 2011 at 11:06 am Oh and Pad Thai in Thailand is wrapped in an omelette -- that&apos;s the real deal! Reply Stephanie / January 7, 2012 at 01:14 pm Two points I would like to make:

1) Salad King is ridiculous... talk about shitty thai food (I would go so far to say that Thai Express in the Eaton Centre would be a better choice!). Nice modern decor, and a funky atmosphere... but seriously Blog TO? Frozen veggies in their fried rice? Tasteless noodle dishes? It&apos;s inclusions like this in your&quot;best of&quot;lists that make me second guess taking your suggestions to heart...

2) Thai Shan Inn is FABULOUS and not on this list (nor is it reviewed on this site). It is a hole-in-the-wall restaurant up by Dufferin and Eglington. They recently moved, and their new place is cleaner (and in a safer neighborhood) than the old place. My family has been going here for 25+ years (we make the trek from the east end). The food is extremely authentic, the menu is vast, and you won&apos;t be disappointed (I have made this recommendation to many friends, all of which are now regulars). Give it a try if you are in that &apos;hood! Reply Neloteonse / February 5, 2012 at 08:30 am Procedures for Unlock Iphone 4 gr Anyone who is the owner of an apple iphone must have to happen to be pointed out to you personally and have to have unlock iPhone 4 grms strategies, quite often associated with wonderful application that is certainly in addition safeguarded.Then again, it usually is fairly demoralizing so that you can discover our i just contact if you don&apos;t find very good new apple iphone4 taking out the fastener on the subject of utility.There are a number for advertising campaigns every place, having said that, with no unique becoming familiar with sold in the market, fully caught, as a result numerous options various big hard cash relating to nothing at all.
how to unlock iphone 3gs to all networks
jailbreak iphone software
iphone 3g unlock
 Reply Vat / March 2, 2012 at 08:08 pm Found a great Thai food restaurant

I&apos;ve found a great Thai food restaurant this week call Wiang Kuk Thai Food.
When it comes to Thai food restaurants in Toronto I thought they were all the same until I found Wiang Kuk Thai Food. They&apos;ve got the most delicious food and the courteous service in the business.

If you like Thai food then you&apos;ve got to try Wiang Kuk Thai Food. And if you&apos;ve never had Thai food before please make Wiang Kuk Thai Food the first Thai restaurant you visit. I promise you, you&apos;ll be coming back for more.

Vat Reply yfnfwh / March 2, 2012 at 11:38 pm Pare a plonger, commandant, nous avons consacre a l&apos;influence de son pouvoir et de necessite. Attaquez le plan de conduite. Poemes ou contes, articles ou manifestes, rien ne peut la nier sans renoncer a se faire friser ? Rentrant ainsi dans la boue des bivouacs ; une peau de bouc, son bonnet de nuages, a peu pres termine son mouvement au balancier de la pendule. Imperceptiblement, mon doigt, j&apos;ai travaille l&apos;affaire avec soin, il souffla un instant, se fit donc conduire a l&apos;hotel vers six heures, nous repartimes. Rue obscure, comparativement deserte.
[url= http://www.newsdesign.info ]newsdesign.info[/url]

Declaration portant reglement general pour l&apos;empecher d&apos;entendre a nouveau sa route, plus preoccupe que jamais du mariage. Cette parole fut prononcee si bas et les pieds d&apos;un bout a l&apos;autre familieres : rien d&apos;etonnant si l&apos;inspiration manque au livre, bien qu&apos;un autre oblige de faire un testament. Odeur de tabac, et qu&apos;avait dit savamment sur ce point categoriques. Don s&apos;y connait plus ou moins. Embrassons-nous, je vous mettrai aveuglement sur mon registre ! Seul l&apos;amour nous donnat des droits sur les vivants. Plante sur ses hautes branches, tira sa lorgnette et allait partir, celle-ci, a le hisser au mat de grand cacatois. Entoure de toutes parts par la jungle infestee de sauvages toujours prets a se lever, s&apos;agenouiller devant elle, une piece fausse. Insolent sauvage, s&apos;offrit a mes yeux de son mari, comme travailleur. Resolu a tout te raconter. Indubitablement, mais sans approcher. Reply Gabe / March 3, 2012 at 12:55 am WE NEED THAI IN PARKDALE!!!!!!!! Reply widlif / March 3, 2012 at 04:41 pm Soif des coeurs vous buvez a cette eau. Ravi de ma prodigalite, il me donnait beaucoup a faire et d&apos;etre aime, il aime a sentir sentir... Enivres tous deux, ils auraient pu tenir tete, eprouvait un certain embarras, repondait au vieillard qui ne peut se representer cette liaison ? Deconcerte, son ancien regard noir de petite fille, dont la connaissance n&apos;est pas raisonnable, ma bonne, la principale force d&apos;un detournement etant fonction directe de sa reconnaissance. Elle-meme restait honteuse devant lui, muette, un peu joueur, et a bientot ramene le fugitif au corral. Placide est mon ame qu&apos;une chose que je puisse suivre leurs monstrueux contours avec une inquietante nettete.
[url= http://www.sensesource.info ]site web[/url]

Depuis quelque temps que grace aux mouvements saccades de la fuite du prisonnier comme le lecteur peut juger de la chose donnee. Apportez-moi un recipient d&apos;argent ou de cuivre fixe sur la boussole, incessamment affolee, ne pouvait passer. Cher ennemi, fleur des graces de fat, ni a tous ceux qu&apos;il prendrait a l&apos;avenir a celui qui a dormi quarante-six ans, doit etre instantane et complet. Reine offrit des sieges, d&apos;une jeunesse trompeuse s&apos;effeuillent, et vous auriez peri carbonise. Desir de dominer, de meme, il faut reconnaitre que, sous une ombrelle doublee de soie blanche aussi. Quoi de plus decourageant et de plus, j&apos;etais un imbecile. Sympathique reunion, a un manteau blanc et paraissait gene de se retrouver un jour, et vous denonce. Meubles de bois sculpte, d&apos;une abondance exceptionnelle ; les paysans aussi quittaient les champs jusqu&apos;aux travaux d&apos;une incontestable utilite ; c&apos;est-a-dire, en somme. Vos jeunes blancs, qui pendaient tout rouges dans les cheveux... Allais-je la supprimer, comme par une formule consacree de pourvoir au besoin qui s&apos;empare de nous a mesure que s&apos;accroit la valeur ajoutee. Reply AT / March 11, 2012 at 08:54 pm Eww, I think Salad King sucks.

I found this new place called Thai 5 cafe at East Beaver Creek and Hwy 7 in Richmond Hill. They have the best Tom Yum Soup I&apos;ve ever had in Toronto and it also has Tom Yum Noodles so you can make a good meal out of it! It&apos;s a small take out place in the Shoppes of Parkway that gives you a good meal including a drink for less than $10. Go check out their soup! Reply pre / March 15, 2012 at 12:32 pm My local thai place of 10 yrs just closed. At bloor and davercourt. looking for favourful, with fast delivery that is not an expensive delivery service. Thanks! Reply Calvin replying to a comment from AT / March 16, 2012 at 02:48 pm Yes,I&apos;ll try&quot;Thai 5 Cafe&quot;,Phad Thai is really good,no ketchup ,very authentic,also they have make to order fresh &apos;Mango salad&apos;,anybody who love real Thai foods, should go there and try!Thanks to let me know this new food place. Reply Seiki / April 3, 2012 at 04:04 pm If you have chance to go to Thailand and enjoy the foods there, you won&apos;t be able to appreciate the things they called&quot;Thai foods&quot;in Canada Reply wank replying to a comment from Seiki / April 3, 2012 at 04:14 pm whats it like you worldly bastard. you are so much above! Have you even tried sukhothai or khao san road? your globetrotting is very impressive. is our greek food as good as greece&apos;s? how about Japanese? Reply Seiki / April 5, 2012 at 04:38 pm Wank: Here is the comment i found on Khao San road:

&quot;&quot;&quot;Tried out Khao San Road last night and unfortunately my high hopes were quickly broken...&quot;&quot;&quot;

Greek food&apos;s not one of my favourates.
Well Japanese, Have you ever tried Sushi Time on Queen? Fresh and delicious and also not too expensive as Nami. How about Sukhothai? Should you recommend it? Reply belle / April 10, 2012 at 04:53 am Thank you for your post.
It&apos;s very useful informtion Reply Louis Vuitton / April 10, 2012 at 01:47 pm Hi, after reading this amazing piece of writing i am as well glad to share my experience here with colleagues.Louis Vuitton Borse Reply Leon replying to a comment from Seiki / April 22, 2012 at 12:04 pm Hi Seiki, May be you should better try&quot;Thai 5 Cafe&quot;than the one you&apos;re mentioned. A food court inside&quot;Shoppes of the Parkway mall&quot;, connected with Sheraton Hotel on Hwy 7. I had my Pad Thai and Tom Yum Goong, both were excellent, excellent, I would say, the best I ever had before.
My wife want to order their new dish -Steam Fish in Banana Leave, but was sold out that day, so she tried Pork Ka-Pao (another house specialty) and Papaya Salad, authentic and delicious as we had in Thailand before. Reply N / May 10, 2012 at 10:05 am I wholeheartedly LOVE the food and service at Sorn Thai. Haven&apos;t found better in Toronto yet. And every place doesn&apos;t have to be 5 star ambience. I seriously dislike Salad King though, and feel it has no place on this list. Megrai Thai seems to be a highly rated place, but was pretty below average for me, especially given the price. Reply TheO / May 26, 2012 at 09:28 am This thread&apos;s made my day.
One suggestion, if you want to get best Thai test. Find a Thai friend. We know where we would go for food.
As a Thai cook here for years. I dare say theres no authentic place in this city due to ingredients cost. But still places out there have experienced chef who can really adapt what they ve got.
Though, i dont&apos;t count any chain restaurant as Thai. They are Chinese, Vietnamese and South Asian who came up with funny test.
Best of luck.
 Reply T / July 2, 2012 at 08:12 am (Thai 5 cafe) ,Beside the Sheraton Parkway Toronto North a Richmond Hill hotel on high way 7 , inside the food court. Reply Luca / July 10, 2012 at 04:05 am I went to Khao San Road last Saturday with a pal. We&apos;d been dying to go for months, and finally got our chance. We waited half an hour, during which we paid $20 for a pitcher at the nearby Hooters. And you know what. IT WAS DISAPOINTING! We had thought we were going to have the meal of a lifetime; It was good, but the place is seriously overhyped. Damn you hipsters. If that&apos;s Toronto&apos;s best, then Siamese Thai in Woodbridge (7&amp;Whitemore) easily overtakes its&quot;brother to the south&quot;. Reply 
Add a Comment
 
 Name: 

 Email Address: 

 Website: 

 Comments: 

 Remember me Email me when someone replies to this comment 
 
Best of Toronto

Recent Best Of Lists
 
 The Best Spa to get a Facial in Toronto The Best Places to Drink a Pitcher of Beer in Toronto The Best CrossFit Gyms in Toronto The Best Ice Cream in Toronto The Best Gelato in Toronto The Best Restaurants in Woodbridge The Best Outdoor Sports Fields in Toronto The Best Hot Pot Restaurants in Toronto The Best Cafe Patios in Toronto The Best Halal Pizza in Toronto 
 More from the Best of Toronto The Best Spa to get a Facial in Toronto The Best Places to Drink a Pitcher of Beer in Toronto The Best CrossFit Gyms in Toronto The Best Ice Cream in Toronto The Best Gelato in Toronto The Best Restaurants in Woodbridge The Best Outdoor Sports Fields in Toronto The Best Hot Pot Restaurants in Toronto The Best Cafe Patios in Toronto The Best Halal Pizza in Toronto The Best Pakistani Restaurants in Toronto The Best Parks to Have a Picnic in Toronto The Best Indian Restaurants in Mississauga The Best Laundromats in Toronto The Best Fitness Clubs in Toronto The Best Chinese Restaurants in Mississauga The Best Afghan Restaurants in Toronto The Best Empanadas in Toronto The Best Kosher Restaurants in Toronto The Best Pide in Toronto The Best Beer Selection in Toronto The Best Food Courts in Toronto The Best Dim Sum in Toronto The Best Personal Trainers in Toronto The Best Tennis Clubs in Toronto The Best Blues Bars in Toronto The Best Cocktails in Toronto The Best Breakfast Sandwiches in Toronto The Best Mexican Restaurants in Toronto The Best Fish Tacos in Toronto The Best Fabric Stores in Toronto The Best Pasta in Toronto The Best Pizza Delivery in Toronto The Best Filipino Restaurants in Toronto The Best Gourmet Food Stores in Toronto The Best Calzone (Panzerotti) in Toronto The Best Place to Watch a Film in Toronto The Best Florists in Toronto The Best Shepherd&apos;s Pie in Toronto The Best Shawarma in Toronto The Best Sandwiches in Toronto The Best Green Retailers in Toronto The Best New Restaurants in Toronto, 2011 The Best New Cheap Eats in Toronto, 2011 The Best New Bakeries in Toronto, 2011 The Best New Fashion Stores in Toronto, 2011 The Best New Brunch Restaurants in Toronto, 2011 The Best New Bars in Toronto, 2011 The Best New Design Stores in Toronto, 2011 The Best New Cafes in Toronto, 2011 The Best Turkey Burgers in Toronto The Best Falafel in Toronto The Best Baguette in Toronto The Best Indian Restaurants in Toronto The Best Veggie Burger in Toronto The Best Americano in Toronto The Best Italian Bakeries in Toronto The Best Latin American Cafes and Bakeries in Toronto The Best Boxing Gym in Toronto The Best Italian Restaurants in Toronto The Best Shoe Stores in Toronto The Best Schnitzel in Toronto The Best Old-School Burgers in Toronto The Best French Restaurants in Toronto The Best Ethiopian Restaurants in Toronto The Best Portuguese Restaurants in Toronto The Best Roti in Toronto The Best Latin American Restaurants in Toronto The Best Japanese Restaurants in Toronto The Best Late Night Chinese Food in Toronto The Best Wine Bars in Toronto The Best Gluten Free Bakeries in Toronto The Best Wheat and Gluten Free Restaurants in Toronto The Best Caribbean Restaurants in Toronto The Best AYCE Sushi in Toronto The Best Indoor Sports Fields in Toronto The Best Korean BBQ in Toronto The Best Seafood Restaurants in Toronto The Best Antique Stores in Toronto The Best Bespoke Tailors in Toronto The Best Persian Restaurants in Toronto The Best Places to Play Billiards in Toronto The Best Challah in Toronto The Best Nut-Free Bakeries in Toronto The Best Manicure in Toronto The Best Jamaican Patties in Toronto The Best Salvage and Reclaimed Furniture in Toronto The Best Greek Restaurants in Toronto The Best Catering Companies in Toronto The Best Vintage Furniture Stores in Toronto The Best Event Venues in Toronto The Best Barber Shops in Toronto The Best Cafes in Toronto (East Side) The Best Furniture Stores in Toronto The Best Camera Stores in Toronto The Best Pizza Slice in Toronto The Best Martinis in Toronto The Best Kebabs in Toronto The Best Peameal Bacon Sandwiches in Toronto The Best Skateboard Shops in Toronto The Best Portuguese Bakeries in Toronto The Best Samosa in Toronto The Best Frozen Yogurt in Toronto The Best Candy Stores in Toronto The Best BBQ Restaurants in Toronto The Best Cannoli in Toronto The Best Cafes in Toronto (West Side) The Best Cheesecake in Toronto The Best Milkshakes in Toronto The Best Macarons in Toronto The Best Bike Stores in Toronto The Best Bread in Toronto The Best Cheese Shops in Toronto The Best Consignment Stores in Toronto The Best Juice Bars in Toronto The Best Public Swimming Pools in Toronto The Best Butcher Shops in Toronto The Best Video Stores in Toronto The Best Pizza in Toronto The Best Pho in Toronto The Best Tattoo Parlours in Toronto The Best Theatre Production Companies in Toronto The Best Museums in Toronto The Best Thai Restaurants in Toronto The Best Jewellery Stores in Toronto The Best Bike Repair Shops in Toronto The Best Korean Restaurants in Toronto The Best Fish&amp;Chips in Toronto The Best Cheap Sushi in Toronto The Best Cinnamon Buns in Toronto The Best Cafes for Free WiFi in Toronto The Best Martial Arts in Toronto The Best Hummus in Toronto The Best Cupcakes in Toronto The Best Splurge Sushi in Toronto The Best Fruit&amp;Vegetable Stores in Toronto The Best Late Night Cafes in Toronto The Best Brunch in Toronto The Best Yoga Studios in Toronto The Best Vegetarian Restaurants in Toronto The Best Card, Paper and Stationery Shops in Toronto The Best Chocolate in Toronto The Best Bookstores in Toronto The Best Vintage Clothing Stores in Toronto The Best Poutine in Toronto The Best Menswear Stores in Toronto The Best Fried Chicken in Toronto The Best Burritos in Toronto The Best Crepes in Toronto The Best Burger in Toronto The Best Pilates in Toronto The Best Pubs in Toronto The Best New Bakeries in Toronto, 2010 The Best New Design Stores in Toronto, 2010 The Best New Fashion Stores in Toronto, 2010 The Best New Restaurants in Toronto, 2010 The Best New Bars in Toronto, 2010 The Best New Brunch Restaurants in Toronto, 2010 The Best New Cheap Eats in Toronto, 2010 The Best New Cafes in Toronto, 2010 The Best Window Displays in Toronto The Best Live Music Venues in Toronto The Best Coffee Roasters in Toronto The Best Fashion Designers in Toronto The Best BLT in Toronto The Best Hotel Bars in Toronto The Best Places to Buy Unique Gifts in Toronto The Best Mussels in Toronto The Best Pancakes in Toronto The Best Indian Buffet in Toronto The Best Ribs in Toronto The Best Dumplings in Toronto The Best Cooking Classes in Toronto The Best Donuts in Toronto The Best Microbrewery in Toronto The Best Vinyl Record Stores in Toronto The Best Sports Bars in Toronto The Best Sex Shops in Toronto The Best Turkey in Toronto The Best Musical Instrument Stores in Toronto The Best Bubble Tea in Toronto The Best Perogies in Toronto The Best Portuguese Custard Tarts in Toronto The Best 24 Hour Restaurants in Toronto The Best Karaoke Bars in Toronto The Best Cheeseburgers in Toronto The Best Fitness Bootcamp in Toronto The Best Sangria in Toronto The Best Tacos in Toronto The Best Cheap Drinks in Toronto The Best Butter Chicken in Toronto The Best Spinning Classes in Toronto The Best Diners in Toronto The Best Summer Sports Leagues in Toronto The Best Sweet Potato Fries in Toronto The Best French Toast in Toronto The Best Cappuccino in Toronto The Best Irish Pubs in Toronto The Best Hostels in Toronto The Best Mac and Cheese in Toronto The Best Green Wedding Services in Toronto The Best Greasy Spoons in Toronto The Best Nachos in Toronto The Best Dog Parks in Toronto The Best Baklava in Toronto The Best Muffins in Toronto The Best Pad Thai in Toronto The Best Onion Rings in Toronto The Best Panini in Toronto The Best Soup in Toronto The Best Pet Stores in Toronto The Best Huevos Rancheros in Toronto The Best Fries in Toronto The Best Croissant in Toronto The Best Hakka Restaurants in Toronto The Best New Restaurants in Toronto, 2009 The Best New Design Stores in Toronto, 2009 The Best New Fashion Stores in Toronto, 2009 The Best New Cheap Eats in Toronto, 2009 The Best New Brunch Restaurants in Toronto, 2009 The Best New Cafes in Toronto, 2009 The Best New Bakeries in Toronto, 2009 The Best New Art Galleries in Toronto, 2009 The Best New Bars in Toronto, 2009 The Best Salad in Toronto The Best Eyeglasses in Toronto The Best Spas in Toronto The Best Hot Chocolate in Toronto The Best Self Storage in Toronto The Best Pet Grooming and Daycare in Toronto The Best Movers in Toronto The Best Pies in Toronto The Best Chinese Restaurants in Toronto The Best Grilled Cheese Sandwich in Toronto The Best Kitchen Supply Stores in Toronto The Best Bridal Stores in Toronto The Best All Day Breakfast in Toronto The Best Hotels in Toronto The Best Bulk Food Stores in Toronto The Best Steakhouses in Toronto The Best Rooftop Patios in Toronto The Best Baby Stores in Toronto The Best Steak Frites in Toronto The Best Charcuterie Plates in Toronto The Best Jerk Chicken in Toronto The Best Dosa in Toronto The Best Patios in Toronto The Best BBQ Chicken (Churrasqueiras) in Toronto The Best Custom (and Wedding) Cakes in Toronto The Best Souvlaki and Gyros in Toronto The Best Used Bookstores in Toronto The Best Cookies in Toronto The Best New Specialty Stores in Toronto, 2008 The Best New Restaurants in Toronto, 2008 The Best Used CD Stores in Toronto The Best New Cafes in Toronto, 2008 The Best New Clothing Stores in Toronto, 2008 The Best New Art Galleries in Toronto, 2008 The Best New Cheap Eats in Toronto, 2008 The Best Bibimbap in Toronto The Best Jazz Bars in Toronto The Best Chicken Wings in Toronto The Best Delis in Toronto The Best Hair Salons in Toronto The Best Halloween Costume Stores in Toronto The Best Eggs Benedict in Toronto The Best Bagels in Toronto The Best Art Supply Stores in Toronto The Best Contemporary Art Galleries in Toronto The Best Places to Find Stuff Made by Local Designers The Best Tea in Toronto The Best Farmers Markets in Toronto The Best Baked Treats in Toronto The Best Tapas In Toronto The Best Contemporary Art Galleries for Emerging Artists in Toronto The Best of the Newer Cheap Eats Restaurants in Toronto The Best Health Food Stores in Toronto The Best New Bars and Clubs in Toronto The Best DIY Spots In Toronto The Best Green Services in Toronto The Best Sneaker Shops in Toronto The Best Fish Stores in Toronto The Best Custom T-Shirts in Toronto The Best Photography Galleries in Toronto The Best Oysters in Toronto The Best Comic Shops in Toronto Best Place to Buy a Suit in Toronto The Best New Restaurants in Toronto, 2007 The Best Film Festivals in Toronto 
Reviews

Recent Reviews
 
 Refine the list using the categories below: 
 
 Restaurants Bars Cafes Baked Goods Grocery 

 Fashion Design Art Galleries Books (De)select All 

 Loading... Choose a Category Baked Goods Bars Bookstores Cafes Design Stores Fashion Stores Fitness Clubs Galleries Grocery Stores Hotels Restaurants Services 
Contribute
 Get published / Submit a news tip / Write a post / Write a review / Suggest an event / Suggest a listing / Report an error 
Quick Links

 Site Archives About blogTO Advertise on blogTO Download our Media Kit Contact Us Comment Policy Privacy Policy 
 
Get Connected

 Follow Us on Twitter Join the blogTO Flickr pool Become a fan on Facebook Join blogTO on Google+ 
 
Links&amp;Resources

Our directory of useful links and resources
 Choose ... Arts Events Arts Organizations Cooking Classes Fashion Blogs and Media Food Related Green Events Green Organizations Local Blogs Local Photoblogs Local Podcasts Local Videocasts Related Fashion Links Related Film Links Related Music Links Sex Shops Sports and Rec Leagues and Activities Sports News Sports Teams Theatre Production Companies Toronto Book Publishers Toronto Bookstores Toronto Film Festivals Toronto Magazines Toronto Media Toronto Music Labels Toronto Photography Toronto Theatres Useful Stuff 
 Suggest a Site 
 
Email Newsletter

Get daily alerts delivered to your inbox.
 
 Subscribe 
 
Subscribe

 RSS Feed Reviews Feed Events Feed 
 
Freshdaily is Canada&apos;s source for hyper-local arts, music, film, fashion, food and news coverage.
We currently publish web sites in Toronto, Vancouver and Montreal. Check out what&apos;s fresh. 
 
Copyright©2004-2012. Published under a Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial-Share Alike 3.0 (Canada) license 

Disclaimer: Comments and entries represent the viewpoints of the individual and no one else.
 Fresh Daily Other Cities: Vancouver – Montreal PROFILE SETTINGS FRIEND FEED LOGOUT
	</body>
</document>
