<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001745" url="http://www.insiderpages.com/b/3720218540/la-prima-trattoria-portland" time="2012-07-12-17:31" support="1" score="0.0018703265723757619" bingtitle="La Prima Trattoria - Portland - Insider Pages - Restaurant Reviews ..." webtitle="La Prima Trattoria - Portland">
			<query id="001197" bing-rank="133"/>
	<description>I then had to find someone to take my order. Then, I ... instead I thought about stopping by a fast food restaurant on the ... now while writing this and looking at the receipt I ...</description>
	<body>
		join sign in 
 Find Near Browse Categories 
recommendations that matter most 
 Health&amp;Medical Home&amp;Garden Hair&amp;Beauty Auto
 Services Pets follow us Advertise With Us 
 Portland, OR &gt; Restaurants &gt; Italian Restaurants &gt;La Prima Trattoria 

 

 

 

 
La Prima Trattoria
 ★★★★☆ 33 Reviews Write a Review 
503-297-0360
 4775 SW 77TH Ave Portland , OR 97225 www.laprimaportland.com 

 
 Add Photo Edit Business Claim Business 
 
About La Prima Trattoria
 Categories 
 Catering Companies Restaurants Italian Restaurants Pizza Restaurants 
 Details 
 Happy Hour 
 
Food
 More choices in Portland: 
 Iorio Restaurant 
912 SE Hawthorne Blvd Portland, OR
 
 Pastini Pastaria 
1506 Northwest 23rd Avenue Portland, OR
 
 Reviews 
 
Insider Pages Reviews for La Prima Trattoria

Have experience with this business? Write a Review. 
 ★★★★☆ Fine Dining you would not expect 
 Tia R. | Insider Guru
| Rank: 599 4 La Prima Trattoria 
 
La Prima Trattoria has alway offered my husband and I a place to eat where not only the food is incredible but the ambiance and attitude of those who serve us. We never feel rushed and have sat for hours enjoying a bottle of wine and the atmosphere.
 February 16, 2010 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★★★★☆ Good italian food in a strip mall 
 WildCat H. | Insider Guru
| Rank: 297 4 La Prima Trattoria 
 
La Prima sits in a strip mall behind Fred Meyers and is nothing to look at. So when I had dinner there I was pleasantly surprised by the quality&amp;menu. Their lasagne was excellent as was the pasta primavera my husband had. Would recommend them to a friend.
 December 10, 2008 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 
Latest reviews from Citysearch .
 ★★☆☆☆ The thrill is gone 
by pdxwilson at Citysearch 2 La Prima Trattoria 
 September 19, 2010 
La Prima used to be one of our favorite haunts. The food was wonderful and the atmosphere was warm and inviting. I love to sit there for hours with my husband and sip wine, unwinding from a long work week. We hadn&apos;t been in a couple years and missed it. So when my sisters were into this stormy weekend, I wanted to treat them to a special dinner close to home. I knew something was wrong when we walked into the door and were immediately seated during prime hour on a Saturday night. The inside rather was now stark and cold. A bright big screen TV was now in the bar, with the sound blaring and clashing with the music in the dining area. The beautiful art work on the divider, the hanging pans /basket around the kitchen, which made it homey were gone. The owner who seated us was very welcoming and cheery. I asked him if the place had recently changed hands and he said yes, two years ago. He said the food is much better, he guaranteed. Gone was the wonderful baskets of fresh baked focccia bread served with delicious extra virgin oil oil and balsamic vinegar, that they used to greet you with when you first sat down. Also gone was the wonderful wine list. The owner told us they missed they wine delivery, but they had a Chianti, a Cab Blend, and a Chardonnay by the bottle or glass if we liked. I was disappointed as in the past La Prima always had nice selection of wines to chose in glass or bottle.

The one saving grace of our dining experience was the meal itself, It was all very good, albeit much more expensive than I remember (pasta dishes ranged from $15-20). They were all cooked ot perfection&amp;served piping hot. For starters were all tried a different salad. My sister loved the stack mozzarella salad with tomato, eggplant, cucumber, etc. It was odd to see that rather than using the kalamata olives - it was sprinkled with plain ol&apos; canned black olives. These same olives were also used in the Puttanesca sauce. My pasta bolgnese was delcious, rich and with lots of flavor. My sister rave&apos;d abut the Penne ai Gamberi. I would have ordered another bottle of wine, but there was nothing ot keep us there. I won&apos;t be going back. It&apos;s sad.. because it&apos;s nothing that someone with a decorator&apos;s touch couldn&apos;t fix; to make the surroundings fit for the food, would bring the people back and then maybe the kitchen wouldn&apos;t need to skimp on the ingredients.


 ★★☆☆☆ False Advertising!! 
by youngandgray at Citysearch 2 La Prima Trattoria 
 September 19, 2010 
I&apos;m giving this place a poor review primarily because the pricing on their website is completely misleading. Example: Fettucini w/Chicken -- website menu says...$13.00 - actual price...$19.00 (45% difference in case you were wondering) Oh, and the Sausage Pizza -- website menu says...$13.00 - actual price...$18.00 (38% difference). I chose not to say anything to the staff about this because our hosts picked up the tab and I felt that to bring up the pricing issue in front of them would have just been bad form.
We were also completely shocked when they began turning off lights in the restaurant at 9:20. We were still ordering drinks and we felt like we were being chased out of the joint....on a Friday night!! I&apos;ve been to bingo games that don&apos;t close that early.
Service was not great, about the level you would expect at Denny&apos;s. Our server was sweet, but incompetent.
On a good note, the pizza was fantastic (but my wife is not a big pizza fan so we probably won&apos;t be going back)


 ★★★★☆ Really delicious food, but don&apos;t sit in the bar 
by Kelmar4 at Citysearch 4 La Prima Trattoria 
 February 04, 2010 
I&apos;ve thoroughly enjoyed the food when I&apos;ve come to La Prima. The atmosphere is lovely, the food is wonderful, and I&apos;ve had delicious meals there.

However, I&apos;ve sat in the bar twice in a row, and the service has been terrible. I&apos;ve walked in, been briefly acknowledged, and then the servers have disappeared. I had to stand up, look around for people, and then ASK for a menu. I then had to find someone to take my order. Then, I had to get up yet again to find someone to give my money to.

The few times I&apos;ve sat in the restaurant portion of the establishment, the service has been fine.

Don&apos;t forget about your bar patrons, folks!

Pros: The best marinara I&apos;ve ever had. Amazing

Cons: The bar&apos;s service is terrible. The restaurant side is ok.


 ★★★★★ Awesome homemade bread 
by Billy the kid at Citysearch 5 La Prima Trattoria 
 September 07, 2009 
Friends of ours recommended a restaurant call La Prima, in Beaverton, and we decided to give it a try.

Upon entering we were warmly greeted by several of the staff. Although located in a strip center behind the Fred Meyer. Once inside the atmosphere is warm and inviting. A large bar on one side and a dinning area on the other with booths and tables to choose from.

We opted to go into the dinning room after a cocktail in the bar. . We were then informed by the bartender that it was recently sold and under new ownership. The menu is accommodating with pizzas from a wood burning oven and pasta dishes. The open kitchen lends a feel of a true Italian Trattaria .

We decide on a Cesar salad and a Bistro salad which consisted of warm Northern white beans, shrimp and fresh arugula. It was delightful. The next course for me was penne with bolognaise sauce. An ample portion with a sauce that you could tell took hours to prepare. My friend opted for veal picatta , the veal melted in your mouth and the lemon caper wine sauce was excellent over the angel hair pasta served with this dish.

The wine list mostly Italian, with a few new world selections from Oregon and California. We had a bottle of Sangiovace, which was great with our meal. And get this, they bake their own bread. Olive bread with fennel, I would return just for the bread.

No room for dessert, they had a nice menu and on our next visit we will definitely say room for the tiramisu. The couple behind us had one, and said it is something not to miss. We were fortunate to meet the owner/chef as we were about to leave, and asked how we enjoyed out meal. He told us his ideas for his restaurant, and the fact that he wanted to reconnect to the neighborhood. Although we live in NW Portland we plan on returning to this delightful new find often, we highly recommend it. Dont fill up on the bread.



Pros: Excellent menu, friendly staff, and wonderful atmosphere

Cons: Location, but you can over come it.


 ★★★★☆ Very good food in the suburbs! 
by missS at Citysearch 4 La Prima Trattoria 
 August 21, 2009 
This place is excellent. Food compares to fancy down town/NE italian places. Never had a bad meal here.

The prices are a bit high, but the quality is outstanding. The portions, like other&apos;s have complained are small for the price. You would expect to pay $12-15 for pasta (ala carte) this good and the small portion, but it&apos;s about $19+.

I will still go back, but only when I have the budget and looking for a light meal.

Amazing flavors can&apos;t be beat!

Pros: Excellent, unique taste, Chef is wonderful

Cons: Small portions, pricey


 ★★★★★ Amazing pasta! 
by pdxwinefood at Citysearch 5 La Prima Trattoria 
 July 27, 2008 
La Prima is wonderful. We couldn&apos;t decide where to go (last minute on a Saturday night) and phoned La Prima and surprisingly, they were not too busy to accommodate us. Atmosphere is reminiscent of a non-suburban hip bistro. The wine list is small, but focused (mostly Italian, Spanish with smattering of other regions) and moderately priced. Now on to the food. I ordered the Fettuccine, with chicken and porcini mushrooms, it was to die for! I adore mushrooms, and this dish was earthy, creamy and cooked to perfection. It was in pure harmony with the bottle of barbera wine we ordered. In all honesty, it was one of the best pasta dishes I&apos;ve had in YEARS (probably since our last trip to Italy). !!! Prices are a bit on the moderate to high side ($14-19 for pasta), but worth the extra because the taste is divine. My husband ordered the sausage risotto. He acclaimed it was amazing, and he is a very hard to please person when it comes to ordering pasta dishes, risotto, etc. The flavors were described as unique and wonderful, all prepared perfectly. I think his only complaint was, &quot;there wasn&apos;t enough&quot;. From both dishes, we wanted more!! Service was good, friendly and pleasantly relaxed. For some constructive criticism: we would love to see some meat dishes on the menue. When we dined at the Trattoria a long while ago, there were meat dishes and they were great, but since removed. Menu is small, just as the wine list, but there are no 2 dishes alike. Would love to see some Italian meat dishes, but perhaps the owners want to focus on a few one-of-a kind dishes and perfect them. ?? We look forward to coming back. La Prima is a wondeful place and would give any downtown, East or West side Italian restaurant a marathon run for it&apos;s money. It&apos;s THAT good!


 ★☆☆☆☆ Formerly - Some of Portland&apos;s best Italian food (no more) 
by hoopla_pdx at Citysearch 1 La Prima Trattoria 
 May 06, 2008 
Sept 2010 update -
We recently ate at La Prima for the first time in a year or so and what a disappointment. It isn&apos;t even a shadow of its former self, and appears to be simply getting by purely by being one of the only non-pizza/burger/asian food options in this area.

Of the items that have remained on the menu, better ingredients have been dropped and the quality has plummeted. We got off to a bad start with the greens salad; the candied walnuts were gone, and the blue cheese was awful stuff that probably came pre-crumbled and cheap. The meat options on the menu are clearly down to just those that can be defrosted. I&apos;m not sure whether that is due to low turnover or laziness. We ordered a pizza and pasta, both of which were mediocre at best. Gone were the delicate touch and fresh ingredients. Instead it was heavy and bland at the same time.

The wine list has also gone to pot. The only wines by the glass were terrible &quot;house&quot; dreck, and the carefully selected small Italian producers were completely gone from the list.

As you can see from my old review below, we used to love this place, and I&apos;m very sad to see it having fallen so far. SW Portland and Beaverton really need some decent fine-dining restaurants, but this one doesn&apos;t qualify any more.

--
Original review:

I&apos;ve eaten at La Prima many times over the last few years, and it has remained consistent as one of the best restaurants of any type in town. It is disappointing that they have simplified the menu recently and dropped some of the meat dishes (the pork chops were always wonderful), but the food is still just as good.

On my most recent visit, both the braised pork and crab ravioli were excellent, with subtle layering of flavors and respect for the basic ingredients.

The Fred Meyer parking lot strip mall location is a bit odd, but they have done an excellent job of creating a warm and separate ambiance inside. You really forget what is outside the doors and focus on the food and wine. It is worth the trip to Raleigh Hills if you are a Portlander who loves good Italian food, and the prices make it easy to go often.

Pros: Food, ambiance, parking, wine list


 ★★★★★ A true Gem! 
by redroxy5 at Citysearch 5 La Prima Trattoria 
 March 02, 2008 
I recently found out about this place and I couldn&apos;t be happier! It is located in a strip mall next to Fred Meyers and from the outside I was a little weary but I was wrong. The service was prompt and very friendly and the food is delicious. A couple of my favorites.....the lamb chops for a starter they are finger lickin&apos; good as well as the risotto fritters...yum. The pizzas are thin crusted just the way I like! The Pork chop is one of their best items on the menu and they always have a wonderful fish special. I hope you don&apos;t waste any more time and get down to La Prima for a wonderful dining experience!

Pros: the food and service

Cons: none


 ★★★★★ Excellent food, great wine and really nice people that run the place 
by PLocal at Citysearch 5 La Prima Trattoria 
 February 01, 2008 
I can&apos;t say enough about this place. I hope they&apos;re there for years to come. Because they&apos;re in a shopping center, you don&apos;t expect them to be a nice romantic place to dine, but it is! My husband have lived nearby for 3 years now and just finally went in a few months ago, but we go back time and time again now. They also have a great happy hour menu and so I meet my girlfriends for drinks and happy hour often too now. It&apos;s just not expected, a great little restaurant, the type you find all over Portland, located in Beaverton!! When we&apos;ve actually gone out in Beaverton before we usually stick with Hall Street or McCormicks, nothing else is good enough. It&apos;s great to see this happen. Here&apos;s to many good nights at La Prima, either with the one you love or all your friends!


 ★★★★★ Amazing food, great place. 
by sugarcookie70 at Citysearch 5 La Prima Trattoria 
 January 30, 2008 
Love it!!!! The food is great, loved the chicken caesar salad. The servers were friendly and prompt. I&apos;d definitely recommend La Prima to everyone I know.

For everyone who has bad things to say about service.... in certain cases, you may very well be right, however, if you&apos;re as rude as you&apos;re coming across in your reviews, it&apos;s no wonder you get crappy service. (Bet it happens in more places than one, right?)

As a long time server, if you treat your servers badly, don&apos;t expect to be treated well in return. Look around you, and take into account how busy your server is before you condemn them for being slow. There&apos;s a very good chance you aren&apos;t the only table they have. Servers are human, to the person who was overcharged... why didn&apos;t you look at your bill when you paid it?


 ★★★★★ Still real Italian cuisine in a warm, inviting environment. 
by whitenoyse at Citysearch 5 La Prima Trattoria 
 October 19, 2007 
After dining at La Prima&apos;s for the fourth or fifth time and being again very impressed with the quality of the food and atmosphere, I happened to be randomly looking up places of interest on my computer when I thought, &quot;I wonder what other folks have to say about the place.&quot; The overall rating is certainly high as deserving, but a couple of the comments below are absurdly out of line. But first the review:

I am fortunate to have enjoyed fine Italian foods all my life since both my parents&apos; heritage is northern Italian, and I still have fond memories old SW Portland, pre urban renewal, where the Italian and Jewish neighbors created some of the most exquisite dishes imaginable. The emphasis wasn&apos;t on presentation only. It had to taste good and be good for you. And it was. That&apos;s why I appreciate a restaurant like La Prima. Their risotto is even better than what I remember eating as a child. It was pretty late and they lacked some of the ingredients for the sausage risotto I would normally order, so the personable waitress suggested I try the shrimp version of the risotto instead. What a wonderful surprise! A very reasonable portion arrived garnished with long, thin diagonal slices of asparagus perfectly blanched to retain some body. Arrayed around the perimeter were four or five VERY large peeled prawns, also cooked to perfection. The first bite disclosed a gentle hint of lemon in the sauce that permeates the risotto, accompanying the green accent of the asparagus, and complimenting the light, fresh sea flavor of the shrimp. Elegance. The dish was light mildly seasoned (a touch of basil) as is appropriate for the ingredients, and was served at just the right temperature. If I had known at the time I would be writing a review, I might have paid more attention to the details, but frankly, I?m happy I was left to simply enjoy an outstanding meal. I will be returning soon.


 ★★★★☆ good food for the burbs, good dinner 
by foodie86 at Citysearch 4 La Prima Trattoria 
 September 10, 2007 
We tried La Prima the other night and were pleasantly surprised for a restaurant in a strip mall. It&apos;s wasn&apos;t dirt cheap, but quality food generally isn&apos;t. I wasn&apos;t sure about the fettucini with pancetta ,corn and mushroom, but I gave it a shot at our waiters recommendation and really enjoyed it. It may not be all you can eat for 7.95, but you also don&apos;t get bland, soggy pasta and canned sauce. My husband and I thought the food was fresh and well prepared, we also really liked the bistro salad. Bottom line ,we had a nice dinner with good service and good food, You get what you pay for. And after reading other reviews, I do wonder why people who notice something that they didn&apos;t have on their bill don&apos;t say something or inquire about it when there, or let someone know.

Pros: Something different for the area, fresh pasta

Cons: Located in a strip mall


 ★☆☆☆☆ Great linguine but we wont be going back because the waitress added items to our bill FOR HER OWN CONSUMPTION! 
by nwfamilyreviews at Citysearch 1 La Prima Trattoria 
 August 20, 2007 
I&apos;ve tried this place twice now and I&apos;m mixed and frustrated on my opinion.

1) Their seafood linguine is honestly one of the best I&apos;ve had in a restaurant but for $19 I&apos;d like double the portion. Most other restaurants at this price point do a better job at getting you proper portions - instead I thought about stopping by a fast food restaurant on the way home. It might fill someone used to eating a light dinner salad for dinner though.

2) If you order a soda, expect a glass filled to the top with crushed ice and 2-3oz of soda for $2/each, no refills.. I have no problem paying $2 for a soda ... but not a cup of ice.

3) Ok service but nothing worth getting excited over

4) The complimentary bread is good but not served with butter - I&apos;d imagine they&apos;ll bring you some butter for a few bucks. Be glad the bread is there though, you&apos;ll need it to get full.

On a 1-10 Scale where 10 is perfect:
Food quality: 9
Food value: 4
Drink quality: 1
Drink value: 1
Desert quality: 6 (There isn&apos;t a number low enough for the Tiramisu, avoid that one)
Desert value: 6
Service speed: 5
Service attitude: 7

Rating 48.75% or 2.4 stars, so I rounded down to 2, until now while writing this and looking at the receipt I see they charged for things we didn&apos;t get (mentioned below) taking this place down to a 1 star rating and a zero for service attitude.

---

Bottom line: Avoid it... Oh and just to mention it. My wife and I don&apos;t drink coffee - ever - so the fact that they also charged us for a Cappuccino $2.75 and Coffee $2.25 ticks me off.. I hope the Waitress or her friends enjoyed them. Because of this there will be no third try - they lost a customer - make sure they don&apos;t over charge you too!

For the record, the cashier was Raquel P according to the slip, order 18148....

Pros: Excellent Linguine

Cons: Thieving waitress and small portions.. oh and 2oz of soda for $2/each


 ★★☆☆☆ Not very good... 
by greenbar at Citysearch 2 La Prima Trattoria 
 August 12, 2007 
I can not see where this place would get anything above 3 stars. The pasta did sound good but in the long run it was only so so.. Noodles were under cooked and taste was no better than something I would get at a mall foodcourt. The pizza was like one I opened from the fridge. Yes it is cooked in their brick oven but the taste of the sauce and the other items on it were just like a frozen one.

Overpriced for what you get. I would go on down the street a bit and get much better at Ernesto&apos;s.

Pros: Nice inside

Cons: Ragu for the sauce


 ★★★☆☆ Wonderful atmosphere, exceptional food, and jazz on Thursdays 
by sydneyk at Citysearch 3 La Prima Trattoria 
 June 07, 2007 
I love coming to this family run restaurant which always feels warm and friendly. The menu is interesting and creative. I had a wonderful green salad with strawberries, chevre cheese and balsamic vinaigrette. It is a special treat to come on most Thursdays when there is live jazz to enhance the evening. I definitely recommend it.

Pros: Ambience, parking, food


 ★★★★★ Good atmosphere, good food. 
by dodoherty at Citysearch 5 La Prima Trattoria 
 June 07, 2007 
I&apos;ve eaten at La Prima half a dozen times and the food has always been delicious and does not err on the side of blandness as many Italian restaurants in Portland seem to do. My pasta favorite is the spicy sausage pasta. Favorite appetizer is the calimari. Wines I&apos;ve had there (at least the reds which I usually drink) have been very good as well. Food and drink prices here are consistent with the quality. The atmosphere is warm and comfortable, not at all what you&apos;d expect when seeing the restaurant from the outside (in a shopping mall).


 ★★★★★ Quality worth the price 
by cdanek at Citysearch 5 La Prima Trattoria 
 June 06, 2007 
Recent posts prompt me to write this review. My wife and I have been dining at this establishment since it opened a number of years ago. The original owner did a great job. The new owners built on an already solid foundation and have served us a variety of excellent Italian and Northwest-influenced meals (and desserts). The baseline of quality is a consistent 8 out of 10. Most hover closer to 9. While some customer may rant about price, you get what you pay for in my opinion. Sure, the wine is a little spendy, but its quality stuff. Sure, the entree prices run into the mid teens. But, considering we typically get two meals worth every time we dine at La Prima, it meets my criteria for solid value on good eats.

PS- The Brasato of Beef and Shrimp pizza, which we&apos;ve had recently, rock!


 ★★★☆☆ Not recommended - food horrible 
by elarsen7 at Citysearch 3 La Prima Trattoria 
 March 11, 2007 
This restaurant used to be a favorite for a Friday night dinner. Not anymore... After eating there last night , we were sorely disappointed ( as my husband said, we paid $65 for this??). The interior has been
redecorated, and is warm and welcoming. Service was ok. It is the food that I had a problem with. I ordered the special salad ( pears, nuts and cheese), it was lacking in any kind of flavor. Then, went to my old standbye Chicken Marsala - it came out rubbery, with an orange sauce over it. I did complain to the waitress that I didn&apos;t taste a hint of marsala wine in this dish. My husband had pasta and what looked like well done meat on the side, the meat was rubbery as well. Needless to say, we will not go back - change in ownership?? Improve the menu.


 ★★☆☆☆ Overpriced pasta decent pizza 
by westsidechuck at Citysearch 2 La Prima Trattoria 
 December 23, 2006 
Both pasta dishes were inedible. (Salty , rubbery clams etc) Pizza was good. Service fair. For the price ??

Cons: high prices lousy pasta dishes


 ★☆☆☆☆ Et tu, Brute? 
by rayalida at Citysearch 1 La Prima Trattoria 
 September 15, 2006 
I hadn&apos;t eaten at La Prima for a long time but had fond memories. Tonight I ordered their &quot;special salad&quot;, a chicken caesar. No price was listed and that should have been a big red flag. The salad bowl held at least a full head of romain lettuce, a few croutons, some tasty chunks of tomato, little sieces of grilled chicken, and was topped with shaved cheese. Nothing special but perfectly okay. Then the bill came and I almost gagged. It was $17.00 for this &quot;special salad&quot;. I was digusted and will never go back again. I felt ripped off like I haven&apos;t felt in years of restaurant eating. If I want a nice caesar salad there are many better choices for half the price. And for the same price I could have had a much nicer meal (hopefully) at La Prima. The owner should be ashamed.


 ★★★★☆ Not Bad 
by vlcgoddess at Citysearch 4 La Prima Trattoria 
 September 05, 2006 
We decided to try La Prima after driving by it for nearly 2 years. The space itself is very cute, but a bit open and drafty. Service was very slow, but seemed to be a fluke; they said they were quite busy and weren&apos;t expecting so many customers on a Tuesday night. My spinach salad with pine nuts, pancetta bits and a citrusy dressing was very tasty. My entree of angel hair puttanesca was large, spicy and very flavorful. My husband&apos;s fish dish was served in a very unique sauce spiced with cinnamon, and he enjoyed it. The worst part of our experience was the service, but I&apos;d be willing to venture in again to give it another try.

Pros: Decor, interesting dishes

Cons: Drafty, slow service


 ★★★★☆ Native Italian Portlander cooks with passion 
by grapedog at Citysearch 4 La Prima Trattoria 
 May 26, 2006 
First, there was Ristorante Medici, then Paparazzi, now La Prima. Nick Medici, his wife Sarah, her sister Eve and other family members work to make La Prima a great place to get a bite of Northern Italian food. Nick isn&apos;t trying to be restaurant of the year or be on Food Network. He&apos;s just cooking the pizzas, pasta, meat and fish dishes that he knows people love after so many years in the business. His prices are reasonable and the wine list has a number of bottles that are good and also affordable. Thursday night is Jazz Night, a way to start the weekend a bit early. I&apos;m not associated with La Prima, just a long time fan of the food. Reservations for large groups only.

Pros: Family cooking, Good Pasta, Wood-fired oven pizza

Cons: May be hard to find


 ★★★★★ Upscale restaurant in a surprising location 
by mehtasarah at Citysearch 5 La Prima Trattoria 
 February 14, 2006 
I LOVE La Prima and eat here often. I drove by many times before finally trying it and very glad I finally did!! The food is always magnificent, the atmopshere quaint and comfortable yet on the upscale side. I have absolutely NO complaints about this eatery.

Pros: Fantastic Food, Great Ambiance, Romantic


 ★★★★★ A very nice surprise! 
by cliffnotes at Citysearch 5 La Prima Trattoria 
 January 05, 2006 
After driving by this little gem of a restaurant for years, I finally decided to make reservations for my book club&apos;s January meeting. I had asked for a table in the corner, where we wouldn&apos;t disturb other diners during our (sometimes) rather loud table talk. We were given a lovely large table in our own little alcove - WOW! The service was fabulous as soon as we stepped through the door, our waitress was very attentive without being annoying. And the food was marvelous! I had the cesar salad, 3 Penne Pasta, and the Boccone Dolce - everything was great. We loved the atmosphere, food and service. We will be coming back very soon!

Pros: food, service, atmosphere


 ★★★★★ Simply great for the money! 
by whencedarsfall at Citysearch 5 La Prima Trattoria 
 June 23, 2005 
It&apos;s simply great food, great environment and reasonably priced. Never had a bad meal here... also a great hidden gem for take out.

The pizza is great too!


 ★★★★★ Great little place 
by bbpr5 at Citysearch 5 La Prima Trattoria 
 June 06, 2005 
Food was amazing, prices very reasonable and atmosphere was great. Nicely decorated, seems out of place in it&apos;s location near the Fred Meyer but that doesn&apos;t matter at all. This is a upper tier quality place.


 ★☆☆☆☆ Change in Ownership Change in Quality 
by sholm at Citysearch 1 La Prima Trattoria 
 February 15, 2005 
La Prima changed ownership not long ago. Unfortunately, it brought a huge decline in the menu and quality. The breakfast menu is much reduced and overly gourmet (pesto hollandaise eggs?). They don&apos;t even serve bacon anymore. The almond french toast is described as being accompanied by toasted almonds, but the almond comes from amaretto whip cream, not actual almonds. And dinner? Overpriced and bad - I had a steak that cost $19.95 and was overcooked, dry, tough and fatty. The pototoes that came with it tasted instant (I&apos;m sure they weren&apos;t, they just weren&apos;t any good). The service is still great, but we won&apos;t be back to what used to be one of our favorite restaurants. We&apos;ll go to Basta&apos;s instead.

Pros: Service, Not too Crowded

Cons: Bad Food, Overpriced


 ★★★★★ awesome 
by bustabeans at Citysearch 5 La Prima Trattoria 
 October 22, 2004 
Food is excellent, servers are down to earth, friendly, and offer great service w/out being annoying. Managment also serves so they know how the &quot;front of the house&quot; works. Chef is a Purdue Graduate and it shows!!!!!!

A+++++

Pros: excellent food, affordable, take passport


 ★★★★★ mwah! 
by oregoncoastgirl at Citysearch 5 La Prima Trattoria 
 July 29, 2004 
Love love LOVE this place- one of the best in Portland, and a diamond in the rough that is a strip mall... the service is friendly and unpretentious, the food is divine, and although a little pricey, worth every penny! I felt welcomed here, and taken care of.

Pros: romantic, great food


 ★★★★★ Excellente!!!! 
by winefoodpdx at Citysearch 5 La Prima Trattoria 
 June 22, 2004 
Wow! What a find. Service is great, atmosphere is open, friendly and off beat. Food is very, very good!!! Recommend breakfast and dinner. Wine list is great and affordable, as well as meals! Didn&apos;t know this place existed until the dineout card! Will return and recommend to friends!

Pros: affordable, food excellent, service, parking


 ★★★★★ 10 - Excellent food! 
by keatonmurray at Citysearch 5 La Prima Trattoria 
 July 18, 2002 
We&apos;ve been to this restaurant several times and love to take friends there. The food is really wonderful. We&apos;re always seated right away and well taken care of. Although the entrees are reasonable, I always feel compelled to get several courses including salad (spinach is a favorite), wine, entree, dessert, and espresso because it is all so good. As a result, we spend a lot on a dinner for two. But I just hate to miss out on anything. If you haven&apos;t been here yet, you should try it.


 Write a Review Get Map&amp;Directions 
Modify or Try Another Search For:
 
Italian Restaurants - Portland, OR
 Find Near Home | About Us | FAQ | Blog | Help/Contact Us | Feedback | Store Finder | Doctor Finder | Sitemap | Privacy Policy (updated) | Terms &amp; Conditions ©2004–2012 Insider Pages. All rights reserved. Partner Sites: MyAutismTeam | Ask Answers | Ask Kids | Life123 | Citysearch | MerchantCircle | Urbanspoon
	</body>
</document>
