<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001455" url="http://www.jiskha.com/search/index.cgi?query=hands+out+4+bills%2E+how+many+different+sets+of+4+bills" time="2012-07-12-17:13" support="3" score="0.002086856318528486" bingtitle="Jiskha Homework Help - Search: hands out 4 bills. how many ..." webtitle="Jiskha Homework Help - Search: hands out 4 bills. how many different sets of 4 bills">
			<query id="000623" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="001296" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="001302" bing-rank="163"/>
	<description>... used to have the line item veto power for which types of bills a ... How much would her medical bills be in bills in order ... Lefkios went to a fast food restaurant for ...</description>
	<body>
		Thursday 
July 12, 2012 School Subjects 
 Art Business Computers English Foreign Languages Health Home Economics Math Music Physical Education Science Social Studies 
 Grade Levels 
 Preschool Kindergarten Elementary School 1st Grade 2nd Grade 3rd Grade 4th Grade 5th Grade 6th Grade 7th Grade 8th Grade High School 9th Grade 10th Grade 11th Grade 12th Grade College Adult Education 
 
 Post a New Question Current Questions Chat With Live Tutors 

 
Search: hands out 4 bills. how many different sets of 4 bills 
 
 
 math - combinations 
Each hand in the game of bridge has 13 cards dealt from a regular deck of 52 cards. a) How many different bridge hands are possible? b) How many different bridge hands have all pour aces in them? c) How many different bridge hands have no aces in them? I figured out part A, ...
 Tuesday, April 13, 2010 at 8:43pm by CL 
 Finite Math 
A&quot;hand&quot;consists of a set of 5 cards selected from an ordinary deck of 52 cards: (1) How many different hands contain exactly 4 diamonds? = 27885 (2) How many different hands contain exactly 4 cards of the same suit (any of the four suits)? (3) How many different ...
 Tuesday, February 24, 2009 at 8:15pm by Zoe 
 math 
Let F=number of 5 dollar bills.&quot;daniel has twice as much money in one-dollar bills as he does in five-dollar bills.&quot;means that if he had 1 5-dollar bill, he has 10 dollars worth of $1-bills. That makes 11 bills. If he had 2 $5-bills, he would have $20 worth of 1 ...
 Tuesday, September 8, 2009 at 9:43pm by MathMate 
 government 
the president used to have the line item veto power for which types of bills a. any bills b. bills passed by a congressional override of a veto c. spending and tax bills d. military bills d
 Wednesday, January 16, 2008 at 1:32pm by jere 
 Algebra 
I have 18 bills that equal $100.00 (5-$10 bills, 9-$5 bills, 3-$1 bills, 1-$2 bill). How can this be expressed in an algebric equation?
 Tuesday, September 28, 2010 at 9:00am by Sue 
 Algebra 
Translate to an equation: h $100 bills and t $20 bills total $400 Graph the equation and use the graph to determine three different combinations of $100 bills and $20 bills that total $400. Submit your graph through the dropbox.
 Sunday, October 16, 2011 at 9:21pm by Lynn 
 statistics 
I have 6 bills that total $63 and there are no $1 or coins? what are the bills? In US or Canadian currency there is no way to create $3 with no coins or $1 bills. How bout 2 20-dollar bills, 1 10-dollar bill, 1 5-dollar bill and 4 2-dollar bills. (Yes, the Treasury dept prints...
 Friday, March 30, 2007 at 11:43am by katrica 
 math 
Let F=number of 5 dollar bills.&quot;daniel has twice as much money in one-dollar bills as he does in five-dollar bills.&quot;means that if he had 1 5-dollar bill (worth $5), he has twice that amount in $1-bills, i.e. 10 dollars worth of $1-bills. That makes a total of 11 ...
 Tuesday, September 8, 2009 at 9:43pm by MathMate 
 math 
let x = the number of $5 bills. let y = the number of $10 bills.&quot;a bank teller had $2750 in 10 dollar bills and5 dollar bills&quot;5x + 10y = 2750&quot;he had twice as many 10 dollar bills as 5 dollar bills&quot;y = 2x Solve for x and y. Substitution is likely easiest.
 Friday, January 8, 2010 at 3:55pm by Marth 
 algebra 
Money Mixtures. Elaine has $194, consisting of $20, $5, and $1 bills. The number of $1 bills is 1 less than the total number of $20 and $5 bills. If she has 39 bills in her purse, how many of each denomination does she have?
 Friday, February 12, 2010 at 10:15am by Sarah Mae B. Oquindo 
 Math 
let&apos;s go with the minimums and see what we get 3 20&apos;s + 1 10 + 1 5 + 7 1&apos;s = $82 ---&amp;gt; 12 bills so we are short $18 using the least number of bills, I can fill that with $10 + $5 + 3($1) --&amp;gt; 5 bills total bills = 17
 Monday, January 9, 2012 at 5:31pm by Reiny 
 algebra 
a bank teller has 52 $5 and $10 bills in her cash drawer. the value of the bills is $460. how many $5 bills are there?
 Wednesday, April 18, 2012 at 11:20pm by kc 
 algebra2/trigonometry 
a bank teller has 52 $5 and $10 bills in her cash drawer. the value of the bills is $460. how many $5 bills are there?
 Wednesday, April 18, 2012 at 11:20pm by kc 
 reading/writing 
Thank you for using the Jiskha Homework Help Forum. What have you dont on this question? It isn&apos;t that difficult and if you find it is,&quot;brainstorm&quot;with your friends and/or family. I&apos;ll get you started with one of each. Advantage: not having to worry about ...
 Sunday, November 18, 2007 at 2:27pm by SraJMcGin 
 Data Management 
How many different sums of money can be formed from one $2 bill, three $5 bills, two $10 bills, and one $20 bill? the answer at the back of the book is 23, but i don&apos;t know how to solve it.
 Saturday, March 6, 2010 at 5:15am by John 
 Data Management 
How many different sums of money can be formed from one $2 bill, three $5 bills, two $10 bills, and one $20 bill? the answer at the back of the book is 23, but i don&apos;t know how to solve it.
 Saturday, March 6, 2010 at 3:22am by John 
 math 
Please show me how to solve: Sharon has some one-dollar bills and some five-dollar bills. She has 14 bills. The value of the bills is $30. Solve a system of equations using elimination to find how many of each kind of bill she has.
 Thursday, December 29, 2011 at 6:12pm by Jane 
 6th 
I would focus on the word bills If I had 2002 dollar bills, as in 2002 one dollar bills, would that be worth more than 2001 bills? Yes.
 Wednesday, September 10, 2008 at 2:01am by bobpursley 
 algebra 
Set up your given: Let x be $5 Let y be $1 Amount: 5x + y = 26 Number of bills: x + y = 14 Solve the equations by elimination: (multiply the first equation by -1 to make y negative.. it would then cancel out) -5x - y = -26 x + y = 14 -4x = -12 x = 3 Plug in x to any of your ...
 Monday, March 28, 2011 at 5:19pm by E* 
 Finance 
$700 000 in $100 bills = 7 000 bills 1 sheet of paper = 6 bills 1 ream = 500 sheets = 3000 bills 1 carton = 10 reams = 30 000 bills Your suitcase can hold 30 000 bills , so far we only used space for 7000 $100 bills. for the remaining $300 000 , you don&apos;t say how many 20&lt;!
	</body>
</document>
