<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001000" url="http://www.gamerswithjobs.com/node/51793" time="2012-07-12-16:24" support="78" score="0.16770590101306748" bingtitle="Your worst restaurant/fast food experience | Gamers With Jobs" webtitle="Your worst restaurant/fast food experience | Gamers With Jobs">
			<query id="000765" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="000579" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="001168" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="000569" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="000754" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000415" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000566" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000592" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000572" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="001300" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="000158" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000286" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="000545" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="001488" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000860" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000297" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="000634" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="000923" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000206" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="001425" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000192" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000443" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000045" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000265" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000327" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000253" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="001173" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000264" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="001330" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000954" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000331" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000752" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000320" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="001143" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000284" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000255" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001318" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="001323" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="001177" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000315" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="001295" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="000451" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000190" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000221" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000014" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="001287" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="000281" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="000639" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="000234" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000160" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="000891" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000108" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000769" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000009" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000643" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000757" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000202" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000733" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000317" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000577" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="001111" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="000195" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="000358" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000204" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="000002" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="000292" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000516" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="000564" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000018" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000507" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000590" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000260" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000266" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="001334" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="000514" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000504" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000585" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000608" bing-rank="60"/>
	<description>He decided that the only place to sit was at the table next to ... the fifth page, the man stood up with an empty tray ... I&apos;m asking someone else to bring me my food, put up ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome!

 Login 
 
 Gamers With Jobs 
 
 
 
Search
 
User login
 Username: * Password: * 
 Create new account Request new password 
 
Support GWJ
 
 Amazon.com Widgets Home » Forums » Everything Else 
Your worst restaurant/fast food experience
 Puce Moose Once Bit Your Sister Location: In a long, low house, persisting with discredited beliefs Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 1:42am 
I eat too much fast food, and I&apos;m no stranger to sub-par dining. I had an experience at the closest Taco Bell yesterday that really put all of my less than positive experiences to shame.

The Taco Bell is in a rather small, rural town, and I&apos;ve never seen more than two or three people inside the dining area (though the drive-through is often crankin&apos;). That should have been a good warning against what I was planning; to sit, eat a meal, and read a book.

As soon as I walked in, I was treated to the lovely combination of country music played blaring from cheap speakers and a manager yelling at an employee. I walked up to the counter and waited to be waited on.
And waited...
And... waited.

An employee sat there eating a bag of chips, and finally, after I stood there, clearing my throat and shifting from foot to foot for a few minutes, let out a world-weary sigh and arose, ambled over, and asked me what I wanted (I guess he was on break, so perhaps the screaming manager/other employees were to blame here). &apos;What do you want?&apos; was the exact phrase. Awesome. Order placed, drink cup received. Okay, we&apos;re rolling now. I went over to the drink machine to get a diet pepsi. Sadly, the Diet Pepsi wasn&apos;t working; nothing at all from the little bar you press to get your beverage (I imagine these things have some sort of fancy name). I went back to the counter and said &apos;It looks like something&apos;s wrong with the diet pepsi - it&apos;s not working.&apos; Two of the employees turned their heads, grunted, then returned to whatever they were doing. After thirty awkward seconds I piped up and said &apos;Uh.. could you get a diet pepsi for me from the drive-through drink machine?&quot; Looking agitated, the drive-through girl hurried over, grabbed my cup (my DRINK cup - it&apos;s not that kind of story), hastily filled my drink, and returned to the drive-through without a word.

Now I had a drink! Hooray! Surprisingly fast, I received my food. I looked at the back line workers; one of them had only one glove on, which I found amusing. I&apos;m no hygiene-snob, but if you&apos;re only going to put one of those little protective plastic gloves before fondling my taco, why bother putting on any at all?

The nacho bellgrande was a... creative interpretation, to say the least. While they did get the &apos;no beans&apos; request correct, they platter was neatly divided in half; half of it had toppings, while the other half was a barren wasteland of stale, cold chips. It was almost eerie how perfectly they bisected the dish with toppings; from rags to riches, along a neat vertical line. Chilling, really.

I took a seat, pulled out my book (a collection of &apos;mind-blowing science fiction short stories&apos;, according to the cover, which featured an incredible crab riding on a mecha-space-ray (we&apos;re talking Batoidea here, not laser, making it quite the saucy image.)) Moments later, I was treated to one of the employees screeching, running out, and squatting behind the condiment island . She stayed that way for most of the time I was there, before another employee came out into the dining area, saw her, and literally dragged her back behind the counter across the work area to the back line by one arm. If they hadn&apos;t been giggling like crazy I probably would have tried to intervene. The shrieking manager was nowhere to be seen during the dragging.

Meanwhile, another customer came in, one of those weird guys that laughs after saying anything (do you know anyone like that? I guess we all do.) He ordered six tacos (laugh) and a small drink (chortle.) He decided that the only place to sit was at the table next to me, which, considering the entire dining room was empty except for squatting/hiding employees, was only logical.

I started reading the story &apos;The Pevatron Rats&apos; (which I couldn&apos;t help but wish had been named &apos;The Pervatron Rats&apos;), and, before I had reached the fifth page, the man stood up with an empty tray, laughed, and left. That&apos;s *six tacos* in under two minutes. I&apos;m not the world&apos;s fastest reader (nor the slowest), and I average about thirty seconds a page - but holy cow, that&apos;s got to be at least a bronze medal for taco eating. Actually, it probably isn&apos;t, but I was still vaguely alarmed/impressed.

I left in a hurry after that. How about you? Any amusing restaurant stories?
 
 8-bit quizzes 
 My Fallout 3 mods 
New Vegas: Tales from the Burning Sands , Tweak and Balance 
 
 Login or register to post comments 
 1 2 next page last page dhelor Suck My Diction Location: Oregon Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 3:17am 
I&apos;ve led a relatively mundane life when it comes to dining experiences. I can&apos;t off the top of my head think of anything of note happening to or around me while at any kind of restaurant. Hell, I can&apos;t even recall ever having an order gotten wrong (at least, mine anyway - my mother however has an uncanny ability to get her order wrong on a regular basis, sometimes multiple times on the same order).
 
&quot;And now I&apos;m off home to my castle for tea, biscuits and wenches. Tally ho!&quot; - Jonman
&quot;Dhelor + intarwebs = Great ideas.&quot; - wordsmythe
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 FedoraMcQuaid has invited you to play Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 4:32am 
A few weeks ago I was in one of those chinese mongolian buffet places. You know, the place that has food that SHOULD be good sitting under heat lamps for hours but there&apos;s a lot of it and it&apos;s cheap so you eat there anyway. Actually... it&apos;s not even cheap... why the hell do we eat at these places? Whatever, anyway. So I&apos;m sitting there chowing down when one of the waitresses comes over and takes my drink which was about 1/5th full. As a clarification (and this is important) it was Dr. Pepper. I was slightly annoyed that she just took my drink without a word but it didn&apos;t seem like too big a deal. She comes back, puts my drink down and I take a sip. Ah, cool refreshing Dr. Pepper, slightly watered down but still- wait a minute.... oh my god. WHAT. THE. f*ck!!!? Upon my first sip I immediately realize that she had filled my glass alright but she had filled it with ROOT BEER. &quot;YOU INCOMPETENT WHORE!!!&quot; (I imagine I would have yelled if I was cool). I don&apos;t really mind root beer though so I drank it.

TL;DR waitress gave me wrong drink and I drank it.
...Yeah, I generally have pretty decent food experiences I guess.
 
 Podunk wrote: Fedora pretty much wins. 
 wordsmythe wrote: If you don&apos;t want soft men, I say stop keeping them from being with the ones who make them hard. 
 Friend me up 
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 LockAndLoad The Emperor&apos;s Pimp Hand Location: The dawn has arrived... in Cleveland, OH Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 8:21am 
I took my wife to a Wasabi restaurant for Mother&apos;s Day earlier this year. Wasabi is a sort of peppy modern interpretation of a Japanese hibachi / sushi restaurant. We get in and get seated around a large hibachi grill with 8 other people. Four of them are middle age women, obnoxious&amp;drunker than hell, celebrating a birthday with all of that &quot;Cougar&quot; style that&apos;s popular. The other four are celebrating their daughter&apos;s 18th birthday and seem to be very laid back and casual.

Ok, so we all get seated at the same time and we wait&amp;wait (10 minutes) for a waitress to arrive. She finally shows up to take our drink orders and apologizes saying she was on break. We wait&amp;wait again (5 minutes) before our drinks finally show up. Now, at this point, she should be taking our food orders, right? Nope. Instead, the Cougars ask for a bottle of wine&amp;some mixed drinks and the waitress runs off to get it. 5 minutes later, and she returns with the Cougars&apos; drink order and FINALLY we get to put in our dinner orders. The Cougars all order lobster&amp;steak entrees ($30 each), the Casual family ordered their meals, I order my steak and my wife orders her shrimp&amp;scallops. And guess what... we start playing the Waiting Game again. 10 more minutes go by before the chef arrives to prepare our meals. When it comes to serve us, everyone gets their orders correct except my wife. We didn&apos;t notice it until it was too late but the chef didn&apos;t have her scallops at all. So, he promises us he&apos;ll go into the back kitchen and prepare some scallops for her and bring them out and he even flags down our waitress and tells us this. So, we all start eating...

And then the waiting game starts up again. 30 plus minutes go by and everyone&apos;s done eating their meals. The waitress never returned during that entire time with my wife&apos;s scallops or to refresh our drinks. The Cougars at this point are completely blitzed, the Casuals are looking frustrated, my wife&apos;s upset and I&apos;m in full on Irish Anger mode. When the waitress does finally show up with a water pitcher, I ask her for my wife&apos;s scallops, she apologizes and runs into the kitchen and comes out with... well, at some point they might have been scallops. They looked like shrunken, dried out corn cake from being baked under a heat lamp. Disgusting. I start getting mad at the waitress saying we&apos;re not paying for that and she said okay, that she&apos;ll just charge us for the shrimp dinner and give us a 10% discount. At this point, we&apos;ve been there for an hour and a 45 minutes and the waitress starts collecting plates and I very emphatically&amp;loudly state &quot;Excuse me, can you clear the dishes later and just bring us our checks now please.&quot;. The waitress runs off to get our checks and the Casual family starts thanking me for saying that and my wife&amp;I have this great conversation with them... but while we&apos;re talking, we don&apos;t notice that the Cougars have disappeared. The waitress returns, hands us the check, hands the casuals the check, and then she turns towards where the Cougars have been feasting&amp;drinking themselves into oblivion and realizes they&apos;re gone. They skipped out on the check... And this waitress, man, I really felt bad for her because this had to have been over $200 lost. She apologizes, turns and literally runs out of the dining area sobbing.

So... 5 more minutes go by, and I&apos;m impatiently holding my check. A check that I notice does not have the 10% discount applied. Yes, I&apos;m a heartless bastard at times but babysitters aren&apos;t cheap and we&apos;re getting up to two hours for a dinner that should have taken half that. A new waitress shows up and collects them and I point out the omission of the discount (I should have just shut up) and she promises she&apos;ll take care of it. And guess what, its the Waiting Game Bonus Round! 5 more minutes go by, New Waitress returns, and what a surprise, the discount wasn&apos;t applied but the New Waitress catches this and flags down a manager. At the same time, the original waitress shows up and begins clearing the plates and the New Waitress is telling the manager we didn&apos;t get our discount. I had already signed the credit card slip and just want out of there but the manager reaches into the original waitress&apos;s apron, pulls out a wad of cash (assuming her tip money) and gets out a $20 and hands it to me. Now, I&apos;m tired, pissed, and just want to leave now but I&apos;m not going to kick the original waitress down any further (because she probably had to cover the Cougar&apos;s tab as it is) by taking money from her tips. I tell him no, we&apos;re finished, good bye. The manager starts following me out saying &quot;Take it, take it&quot; and I&apos;m telling him &quot;No, Goodbye&quot;. We&apos;re in the lobby and he actually starts shoving the money into my pocket and I have to push him back away from me. And finally he shuts up and leaves me alone. I storm out of there, and that was probably my single worst dining experiences of all time. Haven&apos;t been back since and we found a little Mom&amp;Pop owned sushi restaurant closer to home that we love going to now. 
 
 Steam: RiverRatMatt 
 League of Legends: RiverRatMatt 
 I&apos;m addicted to Twitter 
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 Parallax Abstraction From A Certain Point of View Location: Ottawa, Ontario, Canada Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 9:36am 
There&apos;s this local desert cafe in Ottawa called Oh So Good. I haven&apos;t gone in years because it&apos;s a shadow of the place it used to be. But back in its heyday, my friends and I used to go there far more often than we should have both for our wallets and our stomachs. At one of their old locations, they had this waitress who was usually quite good to us but always came across as a bit odd.

One night we went there and got a lot of our typical stuff. It took longer than usual for the items to arrive but the place was rammed so we understood. Then it came time for our bill. We asked her for it and she said she&apos;d bring it right over. It took no word of a lie, 90 minutes to get it. We didn&apos;t have plans for the evening but it was still ridiculous that it took that long. All the waitresses were running around like crazy so we had a hard time flagging one down and the manager wasn&apos;t there that night. When our waitress would go by, we&apos;d keep asking her for the bill and she kept saying she&apos;d bring it and never did. After about 45 minutes, I think we would have been within our rights to just leave but we aren&apos;t that type of people. It got so long that we literally started singing made up songs to ourselves about where the bill was.

When she finally came back with the bill, we asked if it was possible to get any kind of discount because we&apos;d been kept waiting so long. We put thousands into that place between us and figured it was a fair request. The waitress completely lost her temper and yelled at us how we were unreasonable, it didn&apos;t take that long, how we were just trying to rip her off etc. We were all stunned and just paid and left. One of us contacted the manager the next day and relayed our experience. Every time we went back there in the future (this was the only place of its kind in town and we loved it other than this one thing), the waitress gave us an evil look and would always get someone else to serve us, even if we were in her section.

I&apos;ve had bad service in restaurants before but nothing quite like that.
 
 Staats wrote: Parallax is both generous and wise. 
 Geek Bravado | Twitter | Flickr 
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 Paleocon This tag has been moved to P&amp;C; Location: Columbia, MD Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 10:02am 
When I was in Taipei, I went to a buffet style restaurant that are common near the central train station. When I got nearly through my meal, I lifted up a piece of tofu to reveal half of an inch long cockroach. I nearly gagged.

When I brought it to the attention of the buffet line worker, she, completely expressionlessly, dumped it out, and handed me another piece of tofu from the same warming plate.
 
I think Paleocon is right about pretty much everything. -- Mex

Paleocon is entirely right --DanB

I agree with everything that Paleocon said... --Boudreaux

Paleo is right on. --Legion

I love Paleocon. --- SallyNasty
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 Blondish83 Intern Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 10:18am 
I was a small town Sonic. This a Sonic story because any small town in Rural KS is not a &quot;mecca&quot; until it has a Sonic. But, I ordered a Rte 44 Cherry Limeade and noticed 3 teenage girls in a convertible VW Beetle enter the parking lot. They were acting crazy, and flew into a parking spot like they knew what they were doing. They order their food while I&apos;m listening to a podcast. Suddenly, I hear a crunch. I look over, and a new driver was driving and had put the car on the island with the call box. She screams and starts crying, throws it in reverse and pounds the gas. The car doesn&apos;t move at first, until it suddenly lurches away ripping the driver side door clean off. She then speeds out of the driveway leaving most everyone there in a state of shock. Even the support bar holding the speaker box is bent at around a 15 degree angle. A female carhop goes and a man steps out of his truck to help her pull the door onto the center area until the police can arrive. At that time, my drink was empty so I left the show.

I went back probably 6 months later, the skid marks still on the spot in question. The bar was still bent but more like a V as they had try to adjust it back and a well placed sign at the entrance that said, &quot;Please drive slowly while exiting stall.&quot;

Probably the saddest and funniest thing I have ever seen. And they had fun, fun, fun till their daddy took the V-Dub away. 
 
If my cats had thumbs, they&apos;d be able to game with me. Then again, they&apos;d also be able to feed themselves and complete their plan to overthrow me and take over the house...
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 Rob_Anybody Ye&apos;ll tak&apos; the high road an&apos; I&apos;ll tak&apos; yer wallet! Location: Linotype-Hell Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 10:19am 
Don&apos;t eat much fast food these days. At least not from the big chains like McDonalds, Burger King, Wendys, etc. I got food poisoning twice from the McDonalds near my house when I was in High School, and basically gave up McDonalds entirely ever since. I can&apos;t even look at their food without bile coming up. Fool me once, fool me twice and all that. I&apos;ll do Chick Fil&apos;A or Chipotle every once in a while, and there&apos;s a Taco Bell that I&apos;ll stop at after I deposit my paycheck, because it&apos;s right there, but other than that not much.
 
A conversation with Goodjer the IRC bot.
Peron- Goodjer enjoys cartoon bewbs
Goodjer- Peron: sh*t was on the cartoon.
Peron- That&apos;s just nasty.
Asz- Goodjer: sh*t boobs?
Goodjer- Asz:I like boobs and technology... Now if only there were more boobs.

 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 KillerTomato Bacon, Lettuce and DEATH! Location: Florida, USA Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 10:28am 
Wow, what a nutty scene, Moose. Big fast-food chains are usually pretty obsessive about standards for service. It sounds like the manager was woefully undertrained for dealing with his/her employees.

My worst experience was with a Piccadilly Cafeteria. My wife and in-laws had fond memories of eating in this restaurant when she was a kid, and decided it&apos;s be a good place to grab dinner. When I saw that the shopping center around it was now 75% empty, now holding only low-end grocery stores and hair/nail salons, I got worried. The fact that this huge restaurant was nearly deserted was another warning sign.

As we walked through the line, nothing looked good. Everything looked like it&apos;d been cooked many hours, if not days, before. Swimming in a sea of grease or so dry that it looked as if a stiff breeze would blow it away - your pick. The employees looked like homeless people - no uniforms, wild hair, dentally challenged, and with a southern dialect so strong that I, a lifelong southerner, had no idea what they were telling me. The prices were surprisingly high for a cafeteria, too.

The food was the worst I&apos;ve ever had in a restaurant. My shrimp were tiny shriveled things in a huge, hard shell of blackened coating. The bread would already have been thrown out, had it been my kitchen. The fries were cold, as if they&apos;d been thrown, frozen, in to a microwave and only partially cooked. My rice somehow managed to simultaneously be greasy, undercooked, and partly burned to a crisp. My companions&apos; food was similarly godawful.

Oddly, the service was excellent. I wanted to ask the waitress why she still worked there.

The place was still there the last time I passed by. I cannot imagine how it stays in business.
 
Twitter: ohsotwitty 
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 Quintin_Stone Not Without Incident Location: Cary, NC Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 11:04am 
My wife and I got engaged in Williamsburg, VA. The night after we got home, we went out to eat at Olive Garden. We both got food poisoning and spent the whole night throwing up and miserable.

I can&apos;t remember exactly when this next story happened. It may have been in SC on the first leg of our honeymoon, or one of our other road trips to FL. We weren&apos;t on a tight schedule, so we were in no great hurry. We went into an Applebees for an early dinner and the place was completely empty of customers. We were seated and then we waited. And waited. We saw some wait staff in the back, but no one at all came to take even our drink order. The wait became so ridiculous that it somehow transformed into kind of humorous. Obviously we could have left at any time, since we hadn&apos;t even ordered drinks, but like I said, no hurry and it was so silly.

After like 30 minutes waiting in a completely empty restaurant, we think we can overhear a conversation between our supposed waitress and her co-workers where she&apos;s telling them that she can&apos;t wait on us, it&apos;s been so long she&apos;s mortified and/or she knows we&apos;ll be furious with her. It ends up being the bartender that comes to wait on us finally. The rest of the meal was uneventful. 
 
 Certis wrote: Quintin is both smart and attractive. 
 Fedaykin98 wrote: Good lord, I wouldn&apos;t have expected brilliance like that from that nemeslut Quintin Stone! 
&lt;+katisu&gt;Q-Stone is an internet genius

 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 Mimble Executive Location: Whiffling through the tulgey wood Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 11:29am 
 Parallax Abstraction wrote: There&apos;s this local desert cafe in Ottawa called Oh So Good... 

I wonder if it&apos;s owned by the same people who run Cafe WIM in Ottawa.

I went for desert there one night with a boyfriend. The place was pretty dead and yet it still took the waiter 20 minutes to get around to taking our order. He was sullen, sulky and rude. We ordered two teas and two waffle thingies with fruit on them; a simple order that took 45 minutes to get to our table.

We finished and the waiter sauntered by and said he&apos;d get us our bill. So we waited. And waited and waited and waited. 30 minutes later we see our waiter leading some girl into a dark little corner of the restaurant where they start swallowing each others faces.

My boyfriend was all for leaving cash on the table; I said no. I wrote a note on the back of the bill about the whole episode and why we didn&apos;t pay, and we left.

I&apos;ve never walked out on a bill before or since.
 
XBL: Mimble75 | Steam: Mimble75 

 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 Grenn Awesomeville Crier Location: Sitting uncomfortably close to your girlfriend Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 11:37am 
Most of my bad experiences have been with working at a restaurant. I worked at a White Castle my senior year. I&apos;d been there maybe 2 months and had distinguished myself from the others as being able to add and subtract (multiply and divide, even). As such they naturally put me on floor mopping duty. One night, as I was cleaning right be for shift&apos;s end, three very unattractive and heavyset girls came in giggling like it was their job. They order some food and proceed to joke around and keep running in the bathroom and come out laughing their heads off. I start mopping so I can finish my shift and they approach me and one says, &quot;Hey. Would you like to see these two girls make out?&quot; I pause for time, hitch on my best sh*t-eating grin and respond &quot;I&apos;d like to finish mopping and go home.&quot; And I do just that.

Once, when working at Applebee&apos;s in college, I had a girl come in and it was obvious she was waiting on a party. I walk up to great her and take her drink order. She seems nice, but very young. Now official policy is to offer a Mucho size alchoholic beverage to EVERY table. At this point, its a reflex. So I do. And had she ordered one, I would have carded her. She gets a Pepsi or whatever. Her family comes in, and its the same pitch. So I get their food to them. I&apos;m attentive. I listen well. I make sure they&apos;ve got everything they need. As I bring them their check, the mom asks to see the manager. Completely out of left field. So I bring her up. And attend to another table. Manager comes and says, &quot;You&apos;re not in trouble with me. But she&apos;s angry you offered an alchoholic beverage to her daughter. Please just go apologize and get them out of here.&quot; I go up. I explain the procedures of offering drinks and inform them that there are real ramifications if I don&apos;t offer a Mucho sized drink (which includes being fired), and apologize for making them feel uncomfortable in any way. Lady responds, &quot;She&apos;s sixteen .&quot; I tell her that I would have carded her, but again, I&apos;m sorry. The daugher looks mortified. Lady, &quot;Just so you know,&quot; looks at my nametag, &quot;Seth, I&apos;ll be informing the police about this. I don&apos;t care what you do in your own time, but you won&apos;t be corrupting my daughter.&quot; They get their change back. No tip. As it is, I actually hold the door open as they leave. The daughter actually mouths &quot;I&apos;m sorry.&quot; as she goes and I giver her a wink. Two weeks later, plainclothes cops send their underage kids in to order drinks and we card them. They then explain that the lady is notorious for this, but they have to follow up. I&apos;ve got more, but I have to remember them.
 
 Justin McElroy on tracking pubtards down IRL wrote: When you act like a sh*thead to someone twice your size, they may try to kill you. Welcome to the last 2.5 million years of human evolution. 
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 oldmanscene24 What Is Your Quest? Location: Watauga, TX Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 12:08pm 
One night I went to Jack-In-The-Box to get a burger for me and some egg rolls for my wife. They had a pretty decent line at the drive-thru, but I was next in line to place my order so I didn&apos;t worry about it and stayed in the line. About 5 minutes later, I rolled up to the microphone and placed my order. I then waited, and waited, and waited. It took over 30 minutes from the time I placed my order for me to arrive at the window. I thought about bailing from the line, but I was boxed in with a car behind me, a building to my left, and a high curb and landscaping to my right.

When I arrived at the window, the attendant was apologetic, but did not offer me any type of compensation for my wait. At this point I just wanted to get my food and leave, so I didn&apos;t really care. I paid for my food and waited for it to be handed to me. Ten minutes later, I flagged down the attendant and ask what&apos;s taking so long. It turns out that the cook neglected to drop the egg rolls in the fryer. The attendant asked me if I would like a free dessert for my trouble. I told him that I did not want a dessert and that I just wanted to get my food and leave. A few minutes later, I pulled out of the drive-thru with food and the phone number for JITB&apos;s customer service line, which I called on the way home. I had to leave a message since it was after hours.

I got home and opened the bag. Lo and behold, they screwed up my burger. I don&apos;t remember if it was the wrong type of cheese or what, just that it was wrong. I called the service line again and left another message relaying this new development. A couple of days later, I received a call on my cell phone from a number I did not recognize, so I let it go to voice mail. It was a JITB representative who wanted to make up for the problem. She left a call back number. I called the number. It was a child&apos;s voice on a recording informing me that I had reached her Brittney Spears voice mail and to leave her a message. This began the JITB boycott for me.

A couple of months later, I wanted a shake. I&apos;ve always liked JITB&apos;s Oreo cookie shakes, so I thought I would give them another chance. I pulled into the same drive-thru and ordered my shake. &quot;I&apos;m sorry. Our shake machine isn&apos;t working today.&quot; Resume boycott. F*ck you Jack-In-The-Box. F*ck you very much!
 
Xbox LIVE: oldman GWJ 

2007 GWJFFL2 Champion
2008&amp;2011 GWJFFL Champion

 LobsterMobster wrote: Gnomish prostitutes look like bunches of grapes. 


 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 Secret Asian Man Always Delivers Location: San Francisco Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 12:14pm 
I entered a Taco Bell and walked up to the register. The employee, whom I&apos;m going to call Fred. greeted me tersely and looked hurried although there was nobody else there.

Fred: What do you want. (As a statement not a question)
SAM: Uh, I&apos;ll take a #4.
Fred: What do you want to drink with that?
SAM: Not sure yet. I&apos;ll figure it out ( I gesture over to the self serve pop machine.)
Fred: Well I have to enter something. What are you going to drink?
SAM: I don&apos;t know. Just press anything its all the same price right? (Looks deliberately at the self serve machine)
Fred: I can&apos;t choose for you. What should I enter?
SAM: Coke, I&apos;m going to have a Coke.
Fred: We don&apos;t have Coke. Is Pepsi OK?
SAM: ....facepalm. Yes, it&apos;ll be fine.
Fred: Are you sure? I can put in something else.
SAM: .....
 

 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 Bonus_Eruptus Biggest Darryl Location: Gotham City Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 12:34pm 
I don&apos;t really have a &quot;worst&quot; story. I did learn from working at McDonald&apos;s as a teen that unless you special order your food, you&apos;re getting something from under the heat lamp most of the time. The downside, I&apos;ve recently learned, is that you MUST check your order before going home, as it really sucks to have your food getting cold while you have to drive back to get the half of the order they forgot to put in the bag.
 
m0nk3yboy:To quote a McElroy, he Supermaned the sh*t out of me on the handlebars. He bleeped the bleep, out of my bleep, bleep bleep, bleep, bleep. That man has STAMINA!
 Steam | XBL 
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 Amoebic Divide and Conquer Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 12:58pm 
Yesterday, I overheard a group of teenagers discuss their not wanting to tip me because the food is already expensive enough, and because their server was &quot;kind of fat and had ugly hair,&quot; which the rest of the table agreed with. So they all paid me separately, in exact change, with cash.

That&apos;s pretty tame. I&apos;ve had worse, but that was just the most recent. I don&apos;t really remember the worst, because I have a pretty severe mental block in order to get out of bed in the morning and go to work.

PSA: On the subject of foods and restaurants...if you&apos;re going to pay by credit card, and there are two blank spots on the signage slips, one for the tip and one for the total, don&apos;t just sign it at the bottom and leave the spots blank. Fill it out completely . I run into this more often than I should. It amazes me that people are so trusting. (often, this is accompanied by a cash tip. Sometimes, though, it&apos;s just getting stiffed without confirming the total). Some dishonest asshole out there can fill that in with the very same pen you used and your signature is there to confirm it. I&apos;ve seen people fired over this. I can&apos;t help but wonder how many get away with it. It amazes me that I have to explain this to someone at least once a week. It amazes me even more when they get offended or irritated at me for it. I don&apos;t care if your mad, I don&apos;t care if you stiff me on your $16 tab. I&apos;m just trying to look out for your silly ass.
 
&quot;And thus did it come to pass, as was foretold, that the picture thread became like unto the spider thread...there was much gnashing of teeth and lamentations. Dogs lay down with Cats. Bears began riding sharks and lo, there was war.&quot; -Oilypenguin
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 ClockworkHouse Eh, I Got Nothing Location: The cushiest police state in history. Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 1:25pm 
 Amoebic wrote: Yesterday, I overheard a group of teenagers discuss their not wanting to tip me because the food is already expensive enough, and because their server was &quot;kind of fat and had ugly hair,&quot; which the rest of the table agreed with. So they all paid me separately, in exact change, with cash.

That&apos;s pretty tame. I&apos;ve had worse, but that was just the most recent. I don&apos;t really remember the worst, because I have a pretty severe mental block in order to get out of bed in the morning and go to work. 

People who don&apos;t tip or don&apos;t tip well frustrate me.

I have only once shorted a server on a tip and that was because the service was the worst I&apos;ve ever received. I&apos;m asking someone else to bring me my food, put up with the tweaks I make to the order, and otherwise make it so that I don&apos;t have to cook my own meal that night. I had damn well better pony up for that.
 

 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 baggachipz All that and a Location: Home office, awwww yeah Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 2:26pm 
 Grenn wrote: (Story about mom angry for offering alcohol to daughter) 
Heh, I was a waiter at Ruby Tuesday for a few years. And, like most people who wait tables, I stayed up most of the night drinking with other waiters/waitresses. I was in on a Sunday morning shift, the only server on staff for the first couple hours. I was so hungover I could barely see straight. A table with two women gets seated and I approach them, barely able to stay vertical.

Me: &quot;What can I get you ladies to drink this morning?&quot;
Lady 1: &quot;Diet Coke for me.&quot;
Lady 2: &quot;Do you have daiquiris?&quot;
My inner voice: &quot;Sweet, a table ordering alcohol! Bigger tip for me!&quot;
Me: &quot;Sure!&quot;

I bring their drinks out, and take their food order. Later on, I go back to the table to check on them.

Lady 1: &quot;Is this daiquiri alcoholic?&quot;
Me: &quot;Of course. If it&apos;s not enough, I can get the bartender to throw in an extra shot.&quot;

At this point, I look up and notice that Lady 1 has taken possession of the daiquiri. I look over at Lady 2, who is... actually more of a Pre-Teen 1. The manager comped their meal and called me a dumbass all day. Lady 1 finished the daiquiri and enjoyed it.
 
 I called it, just sayin&apos;. 
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 Feeank Expropriates your women Location: CCS, Venezuela Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 3:00pm 
 Amoebic wrote: Yesterday, I overheard a group of teenagers 
That was your problem right there, I suggest avoiding those over-entitled, puke-inducing entities as most as possible.

 Amoebic wrote: PSA: Advice I throw a line over both those tags invalidating them, the tip goes to the waiter/ress directly in cash and the credit card tab already indicates the total. Not sure if you can do that over there though.

Not Worst, but most embarrasing restaurant experience was two years ago around christmas time, a group from the office decided to have lunch out, we went to a nearby fancy pizza place and the maitre there suggested us to order the Venezuelan Christmas Special, (&quot;Hallaca&quot;, &quot;Pan de Jamón&quot;, Chicken Salad, and &quot;Pernil&quot;, for the cuisine afficionados among you), we all declined in favour of pizza and I added &quot;we&apos;ll save that for another time&quot; which in spanish could be loosely understood to mean &quot;I&apos;ll have it later/after the pizza&quot;. Apparently the maitre hearing this scribbled more on his order paper and went off, while my coworkers jokingly pointed out that he had in fact wrote down the Christmas special, which I refused to believe, I was loud and clear when I said &quot;another time&quot;, as in, if I ever come back to this place in a nearby future, which I doubt, but I don&apos;t want to tell that to the people making the suggestion. 5 minutes later, as you could have guessed, here comes the maitre with 5 pizzas and a Christmas Special for yours truly. Hillarity ensued, Maitre looked crossed when I told him I didn&apos;t ordered it, got all red and ofuscated, everyone around was laughing, making the already bad incident even worst. At the end I got my pizza allrigth and came to the maitre before leaving and apologized for the confussion, I still see him from time to time since that pizza place has several sister locations around town and this guy seems to work there like an itinerant maitre. Funny story
 
&quot;Catwoman and the ninjago crew were piloting the black pearl this morning in my son&apos;s bedroom. Luckily, Anakin Skywalker and Dracula were after them to stop all the nonsense.&quot;

Toddland on Lego sets
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 complexmath cos(♥)=? Location: Bay Area, CA Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 3:22pm 
 Amoebic wrote: Yesterday, I overheard a group of teenagers discuss their not wanting to tip me because the food is already expensive enough, and because their server was &quot;kind of fat and had ugly hair,&quot; which the rest of the table agreed with. So they all paid me separately, in exact change, with cash. 
At least you peed in their food when you heard they weren&apos;t going to tip you, right?
 

 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 KrazyTaco[FO] Attention Whore Location: Silver Spring, MD Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 4:26pm 
 ClockworkHouse wrote: People who don&apos;t tip or don&apos;t tip well frustrate me. 

I will tip anywhere from 0%-30% depending on the service. It is based on the type of service I receive. For instance when the waiter is very courteous and checks up on me very frequently and pays attention to everything I need I will give upwards to 30%. But when the only thing he did was take my order (after sitting for 10 mins or more) and then some other person brings me my food, and I don&apos;t get another drink even though I drank my first one 30 mins ago, and you never check on us a single time during our meal and then I have to actively walk around to find someone to give me my check you get 0% tip with a note attached on why I gave him no money for a tip.

This instance is what happened a couple weeks ago in Philly... Good food but horrible service.
 
 &quot;Thanks, KrazyTaco, thanks. I&apos;d put it in your pooper too.&quot; -Mex
 &quot;Oh, KrazyTaco, you fulfill all my wishes.&quot; -pneuman
 &quot;I sometimes hang awake at night dreaming of being called a dumbass by KrazyTaco.&quot; -Gravey
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 LobsterMobster Claw Shrimp Location: On a picnic, going &quot;La la la!&quot; Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 4:24pm 
I&apos;ve found a staple in my food before. From what I gather, that&apos;s not all that uncommon.

I think the worst was when I ordered a chicken sandwich at UCONN&apos;s burger place. Normally, those were decent. That one time, it was basically a knot of fat with something hard in the middle. I grew up with a couple chickens hanging around the yard and I had no idea where something like that could possibly have come from. Tumor?
 
NOTE: Not a doodle bug.

 Steam - XBox -PSN: Lobstermancer
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 Amoebic Divide and Conquer Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 7:28pm 
 complexmath wrote: Amoebic wrote: Yesterday, I overheard a group of teenagers discuss their not wanting to tip me because the food is already expensive enough, and because their server was &quot;kind of fat and had ugly hair,&quot; which the rest of the table agreed with. So they all paid me separately, in exact change, with cash. 
At least you peed in their food when you heard they weren&apos;t going to tip you, right? 

They&apos;re not worth the effort of any kind of retaliation. They never are. If they&apos;re going to be despicable, I&apos;m not lowering myself to their level. f*ck &apos;em. For every turd, there&apos;s at least 10 more tables of people who are a delight to work with.
 
&quot;And thus did it come to pass, as was foretold, that the picture thread became like unto the spider thread...there was much gnashing of teeth and lamentations. Dogs lay down with Cats. Bears began riding sharks and lo, there was war.&quot; -Oilypenguin
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 complexmath cos(♥)=? Location: Bay Area, CA Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 7:43pm 
You&apos;re too well-adjusted for the food service industry. Please consult Naomi for tips on how to better meet customer expectations:

 
 

 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 Amoebic Divide and Conquer Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 7:48pm 
Haha, I used to get all pissed off, but then I realized those small-minded people had a kind of power if I let it get to me. I&apos;d rather they be as useless and as ineffective as I want them to be. Nothing I do is actually going to change them, so any sort of retaliation isn&apos;t worth it; it would only justify their behavior.

Who...who is Naomi? *ducks*
 
&quot;And thus did it come to pass, as was foretold, that the picture thread became like unto the spider thread...there was much gnashing of teeth and lamentations. Dogs lay down with Cats. Bears began riding sharks and lo, there was war.&quot; -Oilypenguin
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 mrwynd is recording this. Location: Littleton, Colorado Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 7:55pm 
After being a restaurant manager for several years I can tell you that workers who cook food day and night (they typically work two jobs so literally day and night) have no respect for your food beyond what&apos;s enforced by someone above them who can make their life hell. If you spot bad management in a restaurant, your food probably has bad sh*t in it, this is not an exaggeration. I&apos;ll also point out that many places such as Denver do not have gloves as a requirement for handling food.

I&apos;m a big tipper even sometimes when the service isn&apos;t that good, depending on the establishment. There are a lot of places where the bussers/expediters/etc get a portion of the tips so don&apos;t tip on the server&apos;s performance alone.
 
SteamID: mrwynd Starcraft 2: mrwynd.954 Diablo 3: MrWynd#1658 How to record a video game 


 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 Amoebic Divide and Conquer Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 8:28pm 
 mrwynd wrote: ...many places such as Denver do not have gloves as a requirement for handling food... 

WHAT!?
Apparently, Denver&lt;3&apos;s Hepatitis and fecal particle garnishes.
 
&quot;And thus did it come to pass, as was foretold, that the picture thread became like unto the spider thread...there was much gnashing of teeth and lamentations. Dogs lay down with Cats. Bears began riding sharks and lo, there was war.&quot; -Oilypenguin
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 boogle the pot and the kettle Location: Austin Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 8:48pm 
When I worked at a bakery, I usually worked the back. I helped make bread, did all the dishes, made deliveries. Other people didn&apos;t like the dish pit (Thunderdome) so I was fine to do that all day while they had to think. My normal attire was the Bakery t-shirt, and dickies shorts. I was told I appeared a mixture of surly, high and aloof.
One of those busy days I have to take a delivery (1 pm). Some asshat had parked in front of the damn van in his convertible and was walking into the bar across the street as I walked out. I yelled please move your car sir, he wouldn&apos;t. Said that my business could wait so he could do his lawyering at the bar. The tow truck was going to take 30 minutes, and after being on shift since 4 that particular day, I wasn&apos;t in the mood to catch it coming and going for screwing the bread cart at one of the down town hotels. With help of the remaining baker on staff, we popped the handbrake, shifted into neutral and pushed that sucker down the block into the methadone clinic parking lot.
I got wrote up but it was so worth it.
 
 pretend boogle wrote: tweed jacket + pedestrian = Parisian dandy 
 drdoak wrote: I&apos;m mr. in the dumps boogle. Nothing is ever fun or exciting to me. Hrmmm market trends. Waah waaah. 
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 mrwynd is recording this. Location: Littleton, Colorado Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 9:36pm 
 Amoebic wrote: mrwynd wrote: ...many places such as Denver do not have gloves as a requirement for handling food... 

WHAT!?
Apparently, Denver&lt;3&apos;s Hepatitis and fecal particle garnishes. 

The restaurants I worked in all required gloves for any worker touching food and we were very strict about what that person touched with the gloves other than food as well. It makes sense to avoid lawsuits but even more for repeat customers. Most people who get sick don&apos;t do anything other than never return or worse, tell a friend why. I can tell you that the Chipotle I worked near did not use gloves, nor did the family owned Chinese Food restaurant. I know this because I became buddies with other nearby managers to get a feel for their customer counts and same store sales. Their argument against it was the cost and for many managers your quarterly bonus is a direct percentage of your profit. I&apos;ve worked for many different chains and all of them used gloves so I think the majority do.

Ok so I actually didn&apos;t give a story which is what the OP asked for, so here goes!

Back in High School I worked at a fast food chain working the drive through. The manager that I worked with most was a guy who dropped out of school (before I did), we were the same age. We lived and our work was located in a really nice area, suburban white people land, houses on golf courses, double wide sidewalks that no one walks on, get that image in your head. My manager is this really big white dude, I mean tall and muscular. He&apos;s already got a few tattoos (we&apos;re like 16), piercings and dresses like he&apos;s Snoop Dogg. He walks and acts like he&apos;s the gangsta rapper of the century as well. I spent the first 12 years of my life in an almost entirely black school in a poor area and figure this guy for some dumbass wannabe.

It&apos;s somewhere around 9:30pm which for some reason seems like the time where weird sh*t happens in food service. So my manager and I both have the drive through headset on and a guy pulls up, makes some sort of order. I punch it all in, start making the drink, etc. I collect the fries and turn around to see my manager&apos;s face as he comes racing toward me. It&apos;s that face that a man makes when you know he&apos;s about to damage something or someone. I have an image of that 16 year old boy&apos;s face permanently etched into my mind because in that moment I thought it was meant for me as he was coming straight at me. I instinctively turned sideways, I definitely wasn&apos;t thinking in that moment. The car had just pulled up to the window. He passes by me and does a one fist forward LEAP through the window. I mean Superman style all the way through the window, face first into the customer&apos;s car. I of course run up to the window to see him face down on top of two white guys also dressed as gangstas and he&apos;s just punching these two guys like his life depended on it. The car runs into the side of the building as he&apos;s seemingly randomly pressing on the gas as my manager is punching him in the face. There was no discretion to his punches. This was not a playground style fight or something done to impress bystanders, he was out for blood and he got it. The passenger grabs the wheel and slams the gas pedal. I see the car disappear around the corner and I run to the front to see but have to go out the front doors because of the glare of the indoor lights.

I see the car go across the middle of the parking lot - the fast food place was off to the side in the same area as a super market, so it&apos;s a big parking lot but very few cars - if you don&apos;t know, in rich areas people are somehow able to do everything during the day and everything closes by 10pm. So my manager is still in the car though I can&apos;t see the melee from here and the car turns around a corner rather well and speeds right through a red light. I lose sight of it all and sit there for the next 30 minutes. My manager has the keys and has to count the drawer, etc. He shows back up around 10:20 with his shirt inside out but obviously there&apos;s blood on it and it&apos;s soaked through. It seemed like a lot of blood to have soaked through like that AND it didn&apos;t look like any of it was his. It didn&apos;t look like he had a single bruise on him. I asked over and over what the hell just happened and he never gave any explanation, at all. His only response was &quot;I don&apos;t know what you&apos;re talking about&quot;. He even refused to accept there was blood on his shirt when I tried to argue with him.
 
SteamID: mrwynd Starcraft 2: mrwynd.954 Diablo 3: MrWynd#1658 How to record a video game 


 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 complexmath cos(♥)=? Location: Bay Area, CA Wednesday, September 22nd, 2010 - 11:48pm 
 Amoebic wrote: Who...who is Naomi? *ducks* 
She&apos;s a character in the movie Waiting . She&apos;s been in the food industry for far too long and is about one more bad tip from going absolutely postal. Great movie, by the way.
 

 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 Amoebic Divide and Conquer Thursday, September 23rd, 2010 - 1:40am 
 complexmath wrote: Amoebic wrote: Who...who is Naomi? *ducks* 
She&apos;s a character in the movie Waiting . She&apos;s been in the food industry for far too long and is about one more bad tip from going absolutely postal. Great movie, by the way. 

I was so tempted to see it, but I can&apos;t bring myself to do so. I&apos;ve compartmentalized a lot of the negative feelings I had about waiting tables back when I was in school, and I&apos;m kind of afraid that movie might do some damage to the tenuous barriers I&apos;ve put up between my soul and that world.
 
&quot;And thus did it come to pass, as was foretold, that the picture thread became like unto the spider thread...there was much gnashing of teeth and lamentations. Dogs lay down with Cats. Bears began riding sharks and lo, there was war.&quot; -Oilypenguin
 
 Login or register to post comments link 
 1 2 next page last page Home » Forums » Everything Else
	</body>
</document>
