<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001727" url="http://purpleslinky.com/Jokes/Pranks/Best-Places-to-Prank-Call.743817" time="2012-07-12-17:30" support="2" score="0.00490924105306456" bingtitle="Best Places to Prank Call | PurpleSlinky" webtitle="Best Places to Prank Call | PurpleSlinky">
			<query id="000120" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="000683" bing-rank="22"/>
	<description>This is my second prank call article about places to ... Go to McDonalds or some fast food restaurant during it’s busy ... wait to hear back from you.-Resounding Glass</description>
	<body>
		Home About Contact Advertise with us Submit an Article 
 
 Humor Jokes Offbeat Trivia 
 Home » Jokes » Pranks » Best Places to Prank Call Follow us on Twitter 

Best Places to Prank Call


 Published by Littlekid137 in Pranks 
 June 1st, 2009 
 

This is my second prank call article about places to prank call. Great laughs!


 
 Ultimate Prank Click Here 

My first article was published about 3 months ago now I want to do a new one!

USE AT YOUR OWN RISK.

 First article  

Any Pizza Joint

This is my new favorite. Order a lot of pizzas lets say 10 get different toppings on each and tell them to deliver it. Give them an address of someone who you don’t like so much or simply a random address. I’d call with *67 which blocks the number before doing this.

Not a call but 
 
Go to McDonalds or some fast food restaurant during it’s busy hours. Make a very very big complicated order. Just on a side note: unless you don’t want to loose money in this process go to a drive thru with just one window where you pay and get your food. Pull up to the window and wait a bit like your fumbling finding money. After a bit (the food should be ready) just drive off.

Target

Ask if they have any wii’s most likely they will say yes, then ask what colors they have. Then say you want a rainbow one and just yell and scream until he hangs up or something else happens.

Car Dealership

Ask for a hover car. They will say they haven’t invented them yet. Tell them that they are fat for not inventing it. Hang up and recall on a different phone and use a different accent. Use as many times as you like.
 Flag It Spam Adult Content Plagiarism Insufficient Quality Wrong Category Select the Right Category About Writing Autos Books Business Computers Creative Writing Domestic Gaming General Health Internet Movies Music News Offbeat Pets Poetry Recipes Religion Science Short Stories Society Sports Television Travel Women 
 11 
 Liked it I Like It 
Tags.
 call fail great more Places prank to 
 Submit this to Script&amp;Style Share this on Blinklist Share this on del.icio.us Digg this! Post this on Diigo Share this on Reddit Buzz up! Stumble upon something good? Share it on StumbleUpon Share this on Technorati Share this on Mixx Post this to MySpace Submit this to DesignFloat Share this on Facebook Tweet This! Email this to a friend? Subscribe to the comments for this post? Share this on Linkedin Seed this on Newsvine Share this on Devmarks Add this to Google Bookmarks Add this to Mister Wong Add this to Izeby Share this on Tumblr Share this on Tipd Share this on PFBuzz 
 4 Comments 
 Cathy Saunders Posted June 1, 2009 at 9:07 am 
I thought the whole thing was funny. I was laughing hysterically about McDonalds!
 Resounding Glass Posted June 1, 2009 at 6:59 pm 
haha nice. off to read the first one now.

Just as a piece of advice I found it usually helps to space out publishing your articles as too many articles all at once will overwhelm your readers which will result in less hits for you.

Hope you got my message earlier and I can’t wait to hear back from you.

-Resounding Glass


 Resounding Glass Posted June 1, 2009 at 7:04 pm 
By the way, nice job on making the front page of purple slinky.

Sorry for the double post.

-Resounding Glass
 adam Posted July 2, 2009 at 10:15 am 
walmart is the bomb for prank calling. start out like its a serious call then start yelling or something
 
 Leave a Reply 
 Search PurpleSlinky
 Loading 
 Popular Articles

 Cuneiform The Art of The Oxymoron Good Call: 30 Compile: One The Other Aerobics: 9Aerobics.: Nine Movie Review of The Lucky One The Crash: Eight The Drive: 33 Factor: 20 Gaze: Four 
 
Navigate

 Home About Contact Advertise with us Submit an Article 
 
You can find us on Twitter 

 
 Powered by Copyright© PurpleSlinky 2012. All Rights Reserved.    Terms of Use     Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
