<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001196" url="http://cordeledispatch.com/local/x2001447392/Fast-food-restaurant-feud-leads-to-attack-on-couple" time="2012-07-12-16:38" support="14" score="0.02570911122784635" bingtitle="Fast food restaurant feud leads to attack on couple » Local news ..." webtitle="Fast food restaurant feud leads to attack on coupleLocal newsCordele Dispatch, Cordele, GA">
			<query id="001041" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="001044" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000686" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000916" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="000919" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="000676" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="001049" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001430" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000928" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="000934" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="000924" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="001059" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="001053" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000667" bing-rank="163"/>
	<description>Fast food restaurant feud leads to attack on couple ... the driver of that vehicle kept changing his order. ... male presented four counterfeit $100 bills as payment ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Main Content Find a Job Post a Resume Career Advice Employers Select Price $100K or less $100K - $150K $150K - $200K $200K - $250K $250K - $300K $300K - $600K $600K or more Cars AG and HD Equipment Recreational 
 
 
 Homepage Local news Local Sports Opinion Obituaries Special Sections Celebrations Entertainment Online Extras Home Décor by Me Movie Tickets Free Coupons&amp;Recipes Local TV Listings Subscriber Services Submit 
 Letter to the editor Obit 
 CLASSIFIEDS BUY A CLASSIFIED Public Notices Contact Us Advertiser Index 
 
 Local news 
 Search 
Search Results
 Close Previous Now showing: of Next Previous Next Close August 1, 2011 
 Fast food restaurant feud leads to attack on couple 

 Staff Writer Cordele Dispatch The Cordele Dispatch Mon Aug 01, 2011, 04:38 PM EDT 
 
Cordele—A confrontation that started at the drive-through window at McDonald’s wound up with two persons being punched by an irate driver on the Walmart parking lot late Friday night.

Cordele Police Department Sgt. Dean Brown said the male and female victims in the attack told him they were in line behind a gold KIA SUV just before midnight when they became irritated as the driver of that vehicle kept changing his order.

When one of the two admitted remarking to the offender,“Dude, come on, I got kids to feed,”he responded with an obscene command to shut up and said he would“get out of the way when I’m ready.”He then pulled his vehicle over, exited it and approached the couple’s car while cursing.

The victims said that in an effort to avoid further trouble they drove off and upon reaching the traffic light near Walmart saw the driver of the car behind them flashing its lights.

Thinking they were being signaled by police to pull over, they did so a short distance away. The angry motorist walked up to their vehicle punched the male in the face, leaving him with a bleeding lip and a damaged tooth.

The female victim said she was struck on the right side of the head and thrown to the ground by the offender who has been described as a balding black male estimated to be about 5’5”tall and 160 pounds in weight. Authorities are making attempts to locate the subject.

Another battery incident led Ptl. Kyle Barfield to note he is requesting that a warrant for that offense be issued against Anthony Pickens.

The officer said he was told Pickens allegedly punched another man in the mouth and busted his lip during a Saturday night altercation at 801 13th St. S.

In other activity during the weekend and early Monday, officers:

—Investigated a fraud case involving Walmart locations here and in Perry.

Sgt. Charles Hill said he was called to the local store when an employee reported a black male presented four counterfeit $100 bills as payment for an assortment of garden tools he had purchased.

A loss prevention officer for Walmart furnished the officer with a CD containing recordings of the suspect who later returned the garden tools to the Perry Store and received a cash refund.

The suspect was wearing a black T-short with a white Adidas logo, black pants with white vertical stripes and black and white shoes.

—Investigated a pair of residential burglaries.

A resident of the 800 block of 21st Ave. W. told Sgt. Charles Dennard that sometime between 1-10 p.m. Saturday someone entered her home through a previously damaged door to gain access to a Hewlett Packard desktop computer and monitor that was stolen.

A resident of the 1500 block of Flint Dr. told Sgt. Wayne Hubbard that during the brief period of time he was away from his home just after 1 a.m. Monday someone gained entry by removing a window air conditioner.

The culprit(s) stole a Playstation 2 system valued at approximately $150 and a 19-inch Sanyo television set valued at $200.

—Received five theft complaints.

Hardest hit was a N. Bay St. resident who told Sgt. Jesse Barfield just after 2 p.m. Sunday that someone had removed a Yamaha Big Bear 4X4 all-terrain vehicle from a trailer in the back yard of his home.

The $3,500 ATV had gold paint on it as well as two additional lights on the rear and a gun rack on the front.

A resident of the 1600 block of Drayton Lane told Ptl. Kyle Barfield just after 9:30 p.m. Sunday that someone stole a black and yellow go-kart from behind his home. Its value was listed as $1,000.

The owner of a wallet apparently turned in Friday by an unidentified finder said a portion of its contents was missing. Listed as taken were $40 in cash and a piece of paper that had a bank account number written on it.

The victim told Pt. Andrew Roufs that in checking with her bank she learned charges of $35 to Gas’N’Go, $10 to Krystal and $10 to McDonald’s had been made on her debit card. An attempt also had been made to use the card to make a $180 transaction at Walmart, but it was denied.

Still another theft was reported by a 13th St. S. resident who told Sgt. Hubbard someone stole a brown and burgundy Huffy bicycle from the garage area of her home. The bike is valued at $300.

—Responded to five incidents in which cash and/or items were stolen from vehicles.

One victim was a woman who told Ptl. Roufs an unspecified amount of money went missing from a purse she left on the passenger seat of her car while it was parked in Holsey Cobb Village just before 2:30 a.m. Saturday.

The victim gave police the identity of two people who had been in the vehicle. One of them denied knowledge of the money and the other has not yet been questioned.

Another such theft was reported by a man who told Ptl. K. Barfield just after 6 p.m. Saturday that his driver’s license and $6 in cash was removed from his truck while he was changing the tires on a trailer he was towing.

A resident of the 1200 block of 15th St. S. told Sgt. Hill just before 9 a.m. Sunday that someone broke the driver’s side window of his 1998 Dodge pickup truck and stole a non-functioning cell phone and four CDs valued at a total of $80.

Still a fourth person told Lt. Lloyd Anderson just before 5 p.m. Sunday that while she stopped at McDonald’s and went inside someone stole from the cargo bed an 8-foot fiberglass ladder valued at $168.

The fifth victim in such theft cases was a First Ave. E. resident who came to police headquarters just before 5:30 p.m. Sunday and told Sgt. Hill someone entered her vehicle on Friday and took a leather purse that contained a Chase debit card, a driver’s license and a Social Security card.

—Took into custody two persons wanted for previous violations.

Lt. Louis New said he arrested Aline Brown Mitchell, 46, of 603-E 23rd Ave. W., upon being informed she had two outstanding warrants pending against her.

The officer learned of Mitchell’s whereabouts when he was called to a home in the 600 block of First St. N. where she had gotten into an argument with another woman over potato chips.

Sgt. Hubbard said he was informed a man who had gotten into a fight with another subject first at The Other Place and later at Best Western had outstanding warrants against him from an undisclosed city in Florida and Taylor County (Butler).

Florida authorities declined to extradite Gary Wayne Currington, 27, of Lilly for their case but Taylor County officials said they did wish to assume custody of him. Currington also was charged locally with disorderly conduct.

—Filed disorderly conduct charges against three of four female teen-agers of attacking another teen Sunday night in the 11th Street-20th Avenue area.

Lt. New listed those cited as Shyquisses Tarver, 17, of 515 17th Ave. W.; Veronica Pickens, 17, of 607 17th Ave. W., and Shonteria (Feria) L. Williams, 17, of 315 Ninth St. N. All three were also issued notices they were being banned from further visits to Cordele Housing Authority property.

—Looked into a property damage complaint.

A resident of the 500 block of Fourth Ave. E. told Sgt. Hill just before noon Friday that someone did an estimated $300 damage to the frame of a front door they had forced open.

—Issued a probation violation citation to Clayton Timothy Brewton 49, of 1006 14th St. S. Sgt. Dedra Davis was the officer taking Brewton into custody just before 2 p.m. Friday.

—Responded to a pair of shoplifting incidents.

A 60-year-old woman and a 16-year-old girl were arrested Saturday afternoon after they were caught allegedly trying to conceal merchandise in their purses while shopping Saturday afternoon at Wal-Mart.

Cited by Sgt. Hill were Willie Mae McKenzie, 60, of 511 Ninth Ave. E., and an apparent juvenile relative.

No arrests were made in a Saturday night shoplifting at Beall’s Outlet where store personnel told Sgt. Hubbard several individuals grabbed four Union Bay backpacks valued at $24.99 each, ran from the store and got into a vehicle that sped away eastbound on 16th Avenue.

Police plan to view store surveillance video in an effort to identify the offenders. A lookout also has been placed for the car in which they were traveling.





 

 

 Text Only Copyright
 2012
 Cordele Dispatch, Cordele, GA. All rights
 reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast,
 rewritten or redistributed. Local news 
 Beauty spot of month 
Keep Crisp Beautiful Director Catherine Mays recognizes Colony Bank on 24th Ave. as the beauty spot of the month for July.

 July 10, 2012 1 Photo 
 Ballots have questions 
Voters who go to the polls between now and July 31 to cast their ballots in the primary elections will have to choose either a Democratic or Republican ballot.

 July 11, 2012 
 LOST negotiations begin 
Crisp County, Cordele and Arabi officials met Tuesday for the purpose of beginning LOST (local option sales tax) re-negotiations. They accomplished little more, however, than setting another meeting.

 July 11, 2012 
 BOE accepts resignations 
Crisp County Board of Education formally accepted the resignation of Crisp County High School Principal Toriano Gilbert as well as that of Assistant Principal LaShonda Flanders at their Tuesday meeting. Both administrators were to leave their positions Wednesday, July 11.

 July 11, 2012 
 Suspect in June stabbing incident apprehended by police 
City police officers arrested Wednesday a suspect they had been seeking for over a month in connection with a stabbing incident that sent a man to the hospital for treatment.

 July 11, 2012 
 WEATHER ALERT! 
The National Weather Service is predicting 40 mile an hour winds and pea-size hail for parts of Crisp County until 3 p.m.

 July 11, 2012 
 Police charge teen with child molestation 
An aggravated child molestation charge has been made against a 17-year-old Cordele youth.

 July 11, 2012 
 Cordele police make pair of battery arrests 
Battery charges have been levied against two persons involved in recent incidents Cordele Police Department officers were called to investigate.

 July 10, 2012 
 Coleman death ruled as accidental drowning 
Accidental drowning has been ruled as the cause of the swimming pool death this past weekend of a 39-year-old Sumter County man with Wilcox County family ties.

 July 10, 2012 
 Teen faces multiple charges 
A 19 year old local teen faces multiple charges after he was involved in a hit and run crash Thursday, July 5, according to Cordele Police reports.

 July 9, 2012 
 More Local news Headlines 
 Business Marquee AP Video US, China Square Off Over South China Sea Florida A&amp;M President Resigns in Wake of Scandal Research Murky on Danger of Asian Carp Invasion SOS Call for Historic Ship Docked in Philly New York Sees &apos;Manhattanhenge&apos; Sunset Rep. Jesse Jackson Treated for &apos;Mood Disorder&apos; Olympic Quest Began in H.S. for Female Wrestler Another California City Opts for Bankruptcy Investor: Missing Bank Director &apos;Stole&apos; My Money Columbus, OH Mayor: Glad Derailment Wasn&apos;t Worse Pelosi Expects Rep. Jackson to Explain Absence OH Woman Vanished on NC Vacation; Reward Offered Two Workers Rescued High Above Manhattan House Ads More Weather Radar Video Gallery Hyperlocal Search 
 
 
 
 Maps, Menus, Store hours, Coupons, and more...
 
 Popular Searches Apartments in cordele 
 Attorneys in cordele 
 Auto Dealers in cordele 
 Auto Parts in cordele 
 Auto Repair in cordele 
 Beauty Salons in cordele 
 Car Rental in cordele 
 Dentists in cordele 
 Doctors in cordele 
 Flowers in cordele 
 Hotels in cordele 
 Insurance in cordele 
 Loans in cordele 
 Mortgages in cordele 
 Movers in cordele 
 Pizza in cordele 
 Realtors in cordele 
 Restaurants in cordele 
 Storage in cordele 
 Tax Preparation in cordele 
 Travel in cordele 
 Featured 
 More... 
Powered by Local.com Community Calendar Loading… Events by evie says.com Seasonal Content Poll 
Do you think that Obamacare should be repealed?
 A. Yes
 B. No
      View Results 
 Maps, Menus, Store hours, Coupons, and more... Find a business
 Location
 
 Popular Searches Apartments in cordele 
 Attorneys in cordele 
 Auto Dealers in cordele 
 Auto Parts in cordele 
 Auto Repair in cordele 
 Beauty Salons in cordele 
 Car Rental in cordele 
 Dentists in cordele 
 Doctors in cordele 
 Flowers in cordele 
 Hotels in cordele 
 Insurance in cordele 
 Loans in cordele 
 Mortgages in cordele 
 Movers in cordele 
 Pizza in cordele 
 Realtors in cordele 
 Restaurants in cordele 
 Storage in cordele 
 Tax Preparation in cordele 
 Travel in cordele 
 Featured 
 More... 
Powered by Local.com 
Site Map
 NEWS 
 Local news • Local Sports • Opinion • Obituaries • Online Extras 
 MORE 
 Special Sections • Celebrations • Entertainment • Online Extras • Local TV Listings • Coupons • Home Décor by Me 
 SUBMIT 
 Letter to the editor • Obit 
 SUBSCRIBE 
 Subscribe Today 
 CLASSIFIEDS 
 Classifieds • Buy a classified • Public Notices 
 OTHER PUBLICATIONS 
 Americus Times Recorder • The Moultrie Observer • Suwannee Democrat • Thomasville Times Enterprise • Tifton Gazette • The Valdosta Daily Times 
 
 Contact Us 
 General 229-273-2277 Publisher 229-273-2277 ext.201 Advertising Manager 229-273-2277 ext.203 News Editor 229-273-2277 ext.201 Web Developer 229-269-4012 
 ©2012 Community Newspaper Holdings, Inc. · CNHI Classified Advertising Network · CNHI News Service 
Associated Press content©2012. All rights reserved. AP content may not be published, 
 broadcast, rewritten or redistributed.
Our site is powered by Zope . Some parts of our site may require 
 you to download the Flash Player Plugin .
 Privacy Policy | AP News Registry privacy policy 
 Terms and Conditions 
 Advertiser Index 
 Events by evie says.com Back to top 
Cordele Dispatch, Cordele, GA
 306 13th Avenue West
 Cordele, GA
 31015
	</body>
</document>
