<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001457" url="http://ca.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20111014115535AAe1FNi" time="2012-07-12-17:13" support="2" score="0.0034361117050362927" bingtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - Does the restaurant chick-fil-a deliver?" webtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - Does the restaurant chick-fil-a deliver?">
			<query id="001188" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="001168" bing-rank="194"/>
	<description>They only deliver catered orders. No fast food restaurant ... they delivered. Though it was a very large order. ... by bill Member since: July 03, 2009 Total points: ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Canada Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog (USA) 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Fast Food &gt; Resolved Question 
 Lois Griffin Member since: May 28, 2011 Total points: 2,163 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Does the restaurant chick-fil-a deliver?
 I called a chick-fil-a restaurant and asked them if they deliver....and they said&quot;yes&quot;.......

being a former chick-fil-a employee........this is news to me! lol.
I mean, I knew they sell things in&quot;catering trays&quot;but I didn&apos;t know they actually drive out and deliver them.

Do they use their own car? Are these minimum wage employees making the deliveries or does the boss do them? How come I never knew this? 
 9 months ago Report Abuse 
 by cuidich&apos;n righ Member since: October 07, 2011 Total points: 1,813 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 sometimes, the big ones have cars moded to look like cows 
 9 months ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: . 
 Action Bar: 1 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; Does the restaurant … &quot;was originally asked in Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (4)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by anu0202 Member since: October 21, 2007 Total points: 500 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 No - Chick-fil-a do not deliver. They only deliver catered orders. 
 9 months ago Report Abuse 
 by mccoyblu... Member since: June 01, 2007 Total points: 133,364 (Level 7) Badge Image: 
 Add Contact Block 
 They only deliver catered orders. No fast food restaurant delivers individual orders. 
 9 months ago Report Abuse 
 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by natalie Member since: July 26, 2011 Total points: 816 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Maybe when you worked they didnt have it or no one else knew in that area so no one asked. When I was in Denver they delivered. Though it was a very large order. 
 9 months ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by bill Member since: July 03, 2009 Total points: 2,471 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Yes, but only to the tables in their restaurant. 
 9 months ago Report Abuse 
 
 
Discover Questions in Fast Food 

 Interview questions for McDonalds? ? What time does Mcdonalds stop serving apple pies UK? New at working at Sonic Drive-Inn? Any Tips? Will i get hired at McDonald&apos;s ? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

 DR.R.Luxemburg 
 
Sponsor Results
 Action Scaffolding Buy Scaffolding online today. www.actionscaffolding.com Ship US Purchases Buy Online from Multiple Retailers, Combine in 1 Package&amp;... www.MyUS.com See your message here... 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Canada Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Canada Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines
	</body>
</document>
