<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001009" url="http://www.experts123.com/q/what-is-justin-biebers-favorite-fast-food-restaurant.html" time="2012-07-12-16:25" support="1" score="0.0006337960501053341" bingtitle="What Is Justin Biebers Favorite Fast Food Restaurant?" webtitle="What Is Justin Biebers Favorite Fast Food Restaurant?">
			<query id="000305" bing-rank="107"/>
	<description>- Watch Egypt vs Mozambique Live Stream Online Video: African Cup of Nations ... Thank you for your question. According to Seventeen, his favourite fast food restaurant is ...</description>
	<body>
		Questions Articles Videos Ask Experts Polls 
 
 Login Sign Up 
 
 Health Parenting Cooking Travel Pets 
 Q: 
What Is Justin Biebers Favorite Fast Food Restaurant?
 2 Like Unlike Answer Comment Flag Widget Tags: 
 restaurant justin favorite fast food biebers 
 
Related Questions

 How Do You Be Justin Biebers One Love And Win The Golden Ticket To Atlantis Bahamas? 
  - Justin Bieber will be at the Atlantis Resort on June 12 in Bahamas! He will be performing live and you could ... Did justin timberlake write the song&quot;what goes around comes around&quot;about britney? 
  - he did cause if you listen to the lyrics he is referring to her relationship with Kevin basically he cheats ... what was the role of justin bieber in the roosevelt field mall riot?&quot; 
  - Fans of Tween King Justin Bieber Cause Mall Riot In Celebs by Jeffery , on Tuesday, November 24, 2009, 4:41 ... Should anyone attempt to watch the Egypt vs Mozambique game online on Justin TV or Sopcast?&quot; 
  - Watch Egypt vs Mozambique Live Stream Online Video: African Cup of Nations 2010 – Today’s another much ... Should Justin Bieber Be Threatened By Greyson Chance? 
  - We were blown away when we saw 13-year-old Greyson Chance’s performance of Lady Gaga’s Paparazzi and we weren’ ... 
 Is this page helpful to you? Your anonymous feedback will help us improve. Helpful Not helpful Thanks for your feedback! A: 
1 Answer
 rank 1 1 Like Unlike Comment Flag Edit 
 G&apos;day Guest, Thank you for your question. According to Seventeen, his favourite fast food restaurant is Subway.  more 
 blurtit.com /q7289930.html   
Related Videos
 
 Add your answer... 
 
Top Related Experts
 1. Tom Wagner Restaurants expert · Articles · 187 Likes 2. Sheryl Faber Restaurants expert · Articles · 0 Likes 3. Jonathan Weerts Restaurants expert · Articles · 0 Likes 4. Lia Reconsal Restaurants expert · Articles · 0 Likes 5. Dawn Merrow Restaurants expert · Articles · 0 Likes Apply to be an expert » 
Top Answerers
 1. Brody Adrien 9 Answers in the past week 2. Alfraid Jones 8 Answers in the past week 3. Grafin Endi 6 Answers in the past week More Top Answerers » 
Top Askers
 1. wu ting 2 Questions in the past week 2. Shayna Belcher 1 Question in the past week 3. shekhar pokkuri 1 Question in the past week More Top Askers » 
Top Supporters
 1. Alex Schett 2 Likes given in the past week 2. Zac Gady 2 Likes given in the past week 3. Melanie Hope 2 Likes given in the past week More Top Supporters » 

 
Please flag with care:

 Offensive or Abusive Spam Ambiguous Garbage Duplicate Inaccurate or Outdated 
 Comment (optional): 
 Flag Cancel 

 
What&apos;s wrong with this link?
 If there&apos;s a problem with the answer itself, please flag the answer instead. 
 This URL is broken This is a duplicate The answer is no longer found at this URL This is not the original source for this answer (please enter the original URL below) 
 Comment or suggest a replacement URL: 
 Flag Cancel 

 
Suggest a new URL
 Has this answer moved? You could help us by suggesting a new URL where this answer can be found. If there&apos;s a problem with the answer itself, please flag the answer instead. Suggest a replacement URL: 
 Ok Cancel 

 Developer API | Blog | Experts123 Widget | About Us | FAQ | Terms of Use | Privacy Policy Copyright©2011 All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
