<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001097" url="http://www.shopping.com/frigo-drink-by-cecilware/products" time="2012-07-12-16:31" support="1" score="0.0018873482667309887" bingtitle="&quot;frigo drink by cecilware&quot; - Shopping.com" webtitle="frigo drink by cecilware- Shopping.com">
			<query id="000213" bing-rank="137"/>
	<description>... 8&quot; x 24 1/4&quot; x 40 1/2&quot; Plumbing: 1/4&quot; water line ... impulse sales at your snack bar, buffet, or fast food restaurant ... Moisture &amp; Powder Collection Tray Prevents excess ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to Shopping.com! Other Shopping.com sites: Close 
 
 
 
 
 
 Shop By Department 
 Clothing 
 Women Men Girls Boys Infants and Toddlers See all... Shop by Brands 
 Shoes 
 Womens Mens Kids See all... Shop by Brands 
 Computers 
 Cartridges and Toners Flash Memory Monitors PC Laptops PDAs Printers Software See all... Shop by Brands 
 Electronics 
 Camcorders Cellular Phones Digital Cameras GPS Devices MP3 Players Flat Panel Televisions Speakers and Subwoofers Buying Guides See all... Shop by Brands 
 At Home 
 Furniture Garden Home Furnishings Kitchen Pet Supplies Building Supplies See all... Shop by Brands 
 Health 
 Cosmetics Fragrances Health Aids Nutrition Personal Care See all... Shop by Brands 
 Kids 
 Baby Care Car Seats Cribs and Bassinets Strollers Toys Video Games See all... Shop by Brands 
 Community Shop by Brands See all 
 
 Sign In   Join   My Lists Search Related: Cecilware parts ,  Cecilware coffee ,  Cecilware cappuccino ,  Cecilware fryer ,  more» Vintage cecilware ,  Cecilware oven ,  Cecilware granita ,  Cecilware slush ,  Cecilware thermostat ,  Coffee urn ,  Cecilware urn ,  Espresso machine ,  Cecilware cup ,  Cecilware pot ,  Antique cecilware ,  Karma cappuccino    less» Shopping 
 frigo drink by cecilware 
 Showing results for &quot;
frigo drink by cecilware
&quot; Show on Sale Results 1 - 40 of 1500+ -49% 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware Cecilware MT 2 ULAF MT Auto Fill Granita Dispensers 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware Cecilware MT 2 ULAF MT Auto Fill Granita Dispensers from $2,822.23 49% Off 4 stores See Details -49% 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware GIANT2 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware GIANT2 from $2,526.39 49% Off 5 stores See Details -49% 
 Cecilware GB5MF-HC-IT-LD - 12-Drink Multi-Flavor Cappuccino Dispenser, (2) 5-lb&amp;(3) 2-lb Capacity 120 V Cecilware GB5MF-HC-IT-LD - 12-Drink Multi-Flavor Cappuccino Dispenser, (2) 5-lb&amp;(3) 2-lb Capacity 120 V 
 Multi-Flavor Cappuccino Dispenser, makes 12 hot drinks from 5 ingredients, manual dispense oper., 8-1/2&quot;cup clearance, power whip, 3.5 gallon water tank capacity, (2) 5lb&amp;(3) 2lb powder product capacity each, (1) 112 burst capacity, lit. display, black. texture finish, 1/4&quot;water (Cecilware) 120 V ( Cecilware - GB5MF-HC-IT-LD ) ( In stock ) 
Multi-Flavor Cappuccino Dispenser, makes 12 hot drinks from 5 ingredients, manual dispense oper., 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 3.5 gallon water tank capacity, (2) 5lb&amp;(3) 2lb powder... More 

Multi-Flavor Cappuccino Dispenser, makes 12 hot drinks from 5 ingredients, manual dispense oper., 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 3.5 gallon water tank capacity, (2) 5lb&amp;(3) 2lb powder product capacity each, (1) 112 burst capacity, lit. display, black. texture finish, 1/4&quot; water (Cecilware) 120 V ( Cecilware - GB5MF-HC-IT-LD ) Less 
 KaTom Restaurant Supply 177 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-gb5mfhcitld/kL_xXVnS0uLLYNpTM3B0_A==/info KaTom Restaurant Supply $4,200.00 $2,151.66 49% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store -49% 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware Cecilware MT 2 UL FrigoGranita Slush Machine 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware Cecilware MT 2 UL FrigoGranita Slush Machine from $2,321.66 49% Off 5 stores See Details -49% 
 Cecilware GB1CP 
 Cecilware GB1CP from $644.91 49% Off 5 stores See Details -49% 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware MT-2-UL-BL 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware MT-2-UL-BL from $2,321.66 49% Off 5 stores See Details 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware GB2SKI-HC 2 dispenser Ski Whipper Grindmaster- Cecilware GB2SKI-HC 2 dispenser Ski Whipper 
 ( In stock ) 
Super Ski High Volume Dispenser Series Designed for anywhere unusually high volumes of hot beverages are sold - Ski Resorts, Airports, Stadiums,&amp;Casinos, these units are designed to... More 

Super Ski High Volume Dispenser Series Designed for anywhere unusually high volumes of hot beverages are sold - Ski Resorts, Airports, Stadiums,&amp;Casinos, these units are designed to accomodate continuous extra heavy volume. Power Whip - Whips the product into a delicious creamy drink. Variable Speed Auger - Simple dial adjustment for drink strength. Uniquely Designed Water Tank - Extra capacity 8 1/2 gallon tank. Maintains perfect brew temperature readiness at all times Hopper Capacity:(2) 14lbsTank Capacity: 8 1/2 gallonsDimensions : 14 1/8&quot; x 24 1/4&quot; x 40 1/2&quot;Plumbing: 1/4&quot; water lineElectrical: 120V/240V, 6KW, 25A Less 
 ARCO Coffee Co. Store not rated See Store Info /grindmastercecilware/0O18H7Q5kgccMggVJWkIFg==/info ARCO Coffee Co. $1,860.00 No Shipping Info Visit Store -49% 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware GB3CP 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware GB3CP from $914.97 49% Off 5 stores See Details http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/34/73/31/306a307044316c656d505851644b6d49756677-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Cecilware NHV2-UL NHT Granita Dispenser Cecilware NHV2-UL NHT Granita Dispenser 
 Contact Us ( In stock ) Granita Dispenser, double 2-1/2 gal. cap. clear bowls w/graphic top, manual fill, s/s exterior finish, suction cup compression seal system, programmable defrost timer, 115v/60/1, (2) 1/2 hp, 15amps w/cord Restaurant Equipment World 5 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-nhv2ul-nht/4s10j0pD1lemPXQdKmIufw==/info $2,766.04 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/41/45/52/7975364f6f66794f34686c5646664e74724a67-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Cecilware Single Flavor Hot Chocolate/Cappuc cino Machine Cecilware Single Flavor Hot Chocolate/Cappuc cino Machine 
 ( In stock ) 
 Cecilware Single Flavor Hot Chocolate/Cappucc ino Dispenser MPN 4914-0. This machine has a cappuccino picture on the front. Fast Flow Dispenses beverages 30% faster, reducing wear and tear... More 

 Cecilware Single Flavor Hot Chocolate/Cappucc ino Dispenser MPN 4914-0. This machine has a cappuccino picture on the front. Fast Flow Dispenses beverages 30% faster, reducing wear and tear on major dispenser components. PowerWhip Carefully whips the product into a delicious, creamy drink. 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 2.0 gal. water tank capacity, (1) hopper w/8 lb. powdered product capacity. Dimensions: 21&quot;H x 9&quot;W x 18&quot;D Electrical: 120V 50/60Hz This is a PRE- OWNED machine.Comes with a 30 day warranty. It has been cleaned, serviced, and inspected by qualified technicians and is in excellent working condition. Purchase this refurbished Cecilware Cappuccino Machine and receive a free case (6/2lb. bags) of our delicious ARCO hot chocolate cocoa mix. Less 
 ARCO Coffee Co. Store not rated See Store Info /cecilware-single-flavor/AERyu6OofyO4hlVFfNtrJg==/info ARCO Coffee Co. $379.00 No Shipping Info Visit Store -48% http://di111.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/63/6b/4a/6262326f49475f413559786252493137794477-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Cecilware GB5MF-IT-LD Multi-Flavor Five Hopper Powdered Cappuccino Dispenser with Illuminated Front -... Cecilware GB5MF-IT-LD Multi-Flavor Five Hopper Powdered Cappuccino Dispenser with Illuminated Front - 120V 
 In Stock ( In stock ) 
Easily create an array of delicious beverages with the Cecilware GB5MF-IT-LD multi-flavor powdered cappuccino dispenser! This versatile machine allows you to make lattes, steamers,... More 

Easily create an array of delicious beverages with the Cecilware GB5MF-IT-LD multi-flavor powdered cappuccino dispenser! This versatile machine allows you to make lattes, steamers, cappuccino, and more with the simple push of a button! This unit is great for operator or self-serve use, making it perfect for your convenience store, snack bar, cafe, hotel, or other establishment. - Makes up to 12 different drinks with just 5 ingredients - One, 10 lb. hopper and four, 2 lb. hoppers - 3.5 gallon tank capacity - LED display allows operator to select various functions including water temperature and records of cups dispensed - Fast flowing dispensing is 30% faster than traditional units, reducing wear and tear on parts - Power whip creates a delicious creamy beverage - Stainless steel drip tray catches spills and overflow - Vacuum steam removal system keeps powdered mix dry to eliminate clogging - Moisture and powder collection tray keeps vacuum motor clean - Self cleaning cycle rinses whipper chamber at the end of each cycle - Easy-to-change &quot;cappuccino&quot; graphic on illuminated front panel The Cecilware GB5MF-IT-LD is UL and NSF Listed and requires a 1/4&quot; water line and 120V electrical connection for operation. Please consult the Specification Sheet for additional details and installation requirements. Overall Dimensions: Left to Right: 14&quot; Front to Back: 25&quot; Height: 37 1/2&quot; GB5MF-IT-LD 120 From Grindmaster Cecilware Less 
 The WEBstaurant Store 267 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-gb5mfitld/ckJbb2oIG_A5YxbRI17yDw==/info The WEBstaurant Store $4,200.00 $2,179.00 48% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/70/6e/35/484a6c53715038315252416d49344830703477-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware GB2 -SKI-BL-LD-HC Ski Whipper Dispenser Grindmaster- Cecilware GB2 -SKI-BL-LD-HC Ski Whipper Dispenser 
 ( In stock ) 
Super Ski High Volume Dispenser Series Designed for anywhere unusually high volumes of hot beverages are sold - Ski Resorts, Airports, Stadiums,&amp;Casinos, these units are designed to... More 

Super Ski High Volume Dispenser Series Designed for anywhere unusually high volumes of hot beverages are sold - Ski Resorts, Airports, Stadiums,&amp;Casinos, these units are designed to accomodate continuous extra heavy volume. Power Whip - Whips the product into a delicious creamy drink. Variable Speed Auger - Simple dial adjustment for drink strength. Uniquely Designed Water Tank - Extra capacity 8 1/2 gallon tank. Maintains perfect brew temperature readiness at all times Hopper Capacity:(2) 14lbs Tank Capacity: 8 1/2 gallons Dimensions: 14 1/8&quot; x 24 1/4&quot; x 40 1/2&quot; Plumbing: 1/4&quot; water line Electrical: 120V/240V, 6KW, 25ABlack Less 
 ARCO Coffee Co. Store not rated See Store Info /grindmastercecilware-gb2/pn5HJlSqP81RRAmI4H0p4w==/info ARCO Coffee Co. $2,100.00 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/32/64/79/5a662d564c374b426c42614e37633635776d41-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 GRINDMASTER- CECILWARE CORP. GB3MD10-LD Hot Beverage Dispenser, powdered,3 Flavor 12D147 GRINDMASTER- CECILWARE CORP. GB3MD10-LD Hot Beverage Dispenser, powdered,3 Flavor 12D147 
 ( In stock ) 
Hot Beverage Dispenser, 3 Flavor, Capacity 3-1/5 Gal., Max. Cup Height 8 In., Width 11-1/2 In., Depth 22 In., Height 34 In., Voltage 120, Amps 15, Watts 1800, Material Steel, Color Black,... More 

Hot Beverage Dispenser, 3 Flavor, Capacity 3-1/5 Gal., Max. Cup Height 8 In., Width 11-1/2 In., Depth 22 In., Height 34 In., Voltage 120, Amps 15, Watts 1800, Material Steel, Color Black, Holds (1) 10 Lb. (2) 5 Lb., Includes Cappuccino Graphic, Standards Ul,nsf,cul Less 
 Grainger 32 store reviews See Store Info /grindmastercecilware/2dyZf-VL7KBlBaN7c65wmA==/info Grainger $2,996.00 +$49.12 shipping Visit Store -49% http://di1-3.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/f0/6a/4d/114541499-100x100-0-0_grindmaster+cecilware+multi+flavor+cappuccino+disp.jpg 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware Multi-Flavor Cappuccino Dispenser 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware Multi-Flavor Cappuccino Dispenser from $2,149.69 49% Off 6 stores See Details -48% http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/69/33/35/32566752584a3473455a3371316f37477a6851-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Cecilware GB5MF-HC-IT-LD Multi-Flavor Five Hopper Powdered Hot Chocolate Dispenser with Illuminated... Cecilware GB5MF-HC-IT-LD Multi-Flavor Five Hopper Powdered Hot Chocolate Dispenser with Illuminated Front - 120V 
 In Stock ( In stock ) 
Easily create an array of delicious beverages with the Cecilware GB5MF-HC-IT-LD multi-flavor powdered hot chocolate dispenser! This versatile machine allows you to make a variety of... More 

Easily create an array of delicious beverages with the Cecilware GB5MF-HC-IT-LD multi-flavor powdered hot chocolate dispenser! This versatile machine allows you to make a variety of delicious chocolatey treats with the simple push of a button! This unit is great for operator or self-serve use, making it perfect for your convenience store, snack bar, cafe, hotel, or other establishment. - Makes up to 12 different drinks with just 5 ingredients - Two, 5 lb. hoppers (one for milk) and four, 2 lb. hoppers - 3.5 gallon tank capacity - LED display allows operator to select various functions including water temperature and records of cups dispensed - Fast flowing dispensing is 30% faster than traditional units, reducing wear and tear on parts - Power whip creates a delicious creamy beverage - Stainless steel drip tray catches spills and overflow - Vacuum steam removal system keeps powdered mix dry to eliminate clogging - Moisture and powder collection tray keeps vacuum motor clean - Self cleaning cycle rinses whipper chamber at the end of each cycle - Easy-to-change &quot;cappuccino&quot; graphic on illuminated front panel The Cecilware GB5MF-HC-IT-LD is UL and NSF Listed and requires a 1/4&quot; water line and 120V electrical connection for operation. Please consult the Specification Sheet for additional details and installation requirements. Overall Dimensions: Left to Right: 14&quot; Front to Back: 25&quot; Height: 37 1/2&quot; GB5MF-HC-IT-LD 120 From Grindmaster Cecilware Less 
 The WEBstaurant Store 267 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-gb5mfhcitld/i352VgRXJ4sEZ3q1o7GzhQ==/info The WEBstaurant Store $4,200.00 $2,179.00 48% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store -49% http://di1-4.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/b6/17/0d/54731230-100x100-0-0_Cecilware+GB2CP.jpg 
 Cecilware GB2CP 
 Cecilware GB2CP from $730.89 49% Off 4 stores See Details http://di1-4.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/ea/99/21/56699176-100x100-0-0_Cecilware+Model+A.jpg 
 Cecilware Model A 
 Cecilware Model A from $179.82 4 stores See Details http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/45/4d/4d/365070664e65673230626f4a457a4a36756751-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware GB4MV-210-LD 4 flavor cappuccino dispenser Grindmaster- Cecilware GB4MV-210-LD 4 flavor cappuccino dispenser 
 ( In stock ) 
 Cecilware cappuccino/hot chocolate dispenser machine Standard Features: Fast Flow Dispenses beverages 30% faster, reducing wear&amp;tear on major dispenser components. Vacuum Steam Removal... More 

 Cecilware cappuccino/hot chocolate dispenser machine Standard Features: Fast Flow Dispenses beverages 30% faster, reducing wear&amp;tear on major dispenser components. Vacuum Steam Removal SystemVSRS Ensures the powdered mix remains dry to eliminate clogging, caking and bridging. Moisture&amp;Powder Collection Tray Prevents excess moisture&amp;product powder from reaching the vacuum motor. Direct Drive Auger System Ensures perfect hopper alignment&amp;silent running . PowerWhip Carefully whips the product into a delicious, creamy drink. Self Cleaning Rinse system is touch button easy&amp;rinses the entire whipper chamber with hot water at the end of each cycle. Quick Change Transparency Simply lift up 2 tabs and pull out the graphic. Hopper Capacity:(2)10lbs, 1 5lbsTank Capacity: 6 gallonsBurst Capacity 98Dimensions: 18&quot; x 22&quot; x 35 Plumbing 1/4&quot; waterlineElectric al: 120V, 1.8KW, 15A Contact us if you are interested in these and we will check. Less 
 ARCO Coffee Co. Store not rated See Store Info /grindmastercecilware/EMM6PpfNeg20boJEzJ6ugQ==/info ARCO Coffee Co. $1,936.00 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di111.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/47/59/44/68446974645a5a5839686b5562513344575841-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware Ski GB1SKI-HC 1 cappuccino dispenser Grindmaster- Cecilware Ski GB1SKI-HC 1 cappuccino dispenser 
 ( In stock ) 
 Cecilware cappuccino/hot chocolate dispenser machine Standard Features: Fast Flow Dispenses beverages 30% faster, reducing wear&amp;tear on major dispenser components. Vacuum Steam Removal... More 

 Cecilware cappuccino/hot chocolate dispenser machine Standard Features: Fast Flow Dispenses beverages 30% faster, reducing wear&amp;tear on major dispenser components. Vacuum Steam Removal SystemVSRS Ensures the powdered mix remains dry to eliminate clogging, caking and bridging. Moisture&amp;Powder Collection Tray Prevents excess moisture&amp;product powder from reaching the vacuum motor. Direct Drive Auger System Ensures perfect hopper alignment&amp;silent running . PowerWhip Carefully whips the product into a delicious, creamy drink. Self Cleaning Rinse system is touch button easy&amp;rinses the entire whipper chamber with hot water at the end of each cycle. Quick Change Transparency Simply lift up 2 tabs and pull out the graphic. Non lit door Hopper Capacity: 14lbsTank Capacity:3 1/2 gallonsBurst Capacity: 93Dimensions: 8 1/2&quot; x 22&quot; x 37 1/2&quot;Plumbing 1/4&quot; water lineElectrical: 120V, 1.8KW, 15A Less 
 ARCO Coffee Co. Store not rated See Store Info /grindmastercecilware-ski/GYDhDitdZZX9hkUbQ3DWXA==/info ARCO Coffee Co. $1,071.05 No Shipping Info Visit Store -48% http://di103.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/63/70/79/6745375846522d45354639792d5a346c443851-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Cecilware Arctic Economy 20/4PE Four Bowl 5.4 Gallon Premix Cold Beverage Dispenser Cecilware Arctic Economy 20/4PE Four Bowl 5.4 Gallon Premix Cold Beverage Dispenser 
 In Stock ( In stock ) 
Your customers are parched! Quench their thirst and boost impulse sales at your snack bar, buffet, or fast food restaurant with this Cecilware Arctic Economy 20/3PE four bowl 5.4 gallon... More 

Your customers are parched! Quench their thirst and boost impulse sales at your snack bar, buffet, or fast food restaurant with this Cecilware Arctic Economy 20/3PE four bowl 5.4 gallon premix cold beverage dispenser. At only 28 1/2&quot; wide, this 4 bowl premix cold beverage dispenser features four 5.4 gallon refrigerated bowls for long-lasting refreshment while sacrificing minimal countertop space! With the ability to set the dispenser for fast or gentle agitation to accommodate fruit juice and dairy products, it is perfect for serving fruit juice, iced tea, iced coffee, and other refreshingly chilled drinks. The Cecilware Arctic Economy 20/4PE beverage dispenser&apos;s 1/7 hp compressor that uses R134A refrigerant will keep your beverages chilled and ready for consumption for hours at a time. It requires a 120V electrical connection and is UL and NSF Listed. Dimensions Height: 26 1/2&quot; Width: 28 1/2&quot; Depth: 18 1/2&quot; Also known as 20-4PE, 20 4PE, and 204PE. 20/4PE From Grindmaster Cecilware Less 
 The WEBstaurant Store 267 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-arctic-economy/cpygE7XFR-E5F9y-Z4lD8Q==/info The WEBstaurant Store $2,650.00 $1,389.00 48% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/4a/38/59/77515943704a576877637a7849347962744441-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware GB2HC-CP 2 dispenser Compact Whipper Grindmaster- Cecilware GB2HC-CP 2 dispenser Compact Whipper 
 ( In stock ) 
Compact Whipper Series Cecilware incorporates its leading technology into a line of dispensers for all types of accounts and a variety of products: Hot Chocolate, Cappuccino, Steamers... More 

Compact Whipper Series Cecilware incorporates its leading technology into a line of dispensers for all types of accounts and a variety of products: Hot Chocolate, Cappuccino, Steamers and...more. Only 24&quot; Tall and 7.75&quot; Wide Power Whip - Carefully whips the product into a delicious, creamy drink. Uniquely Designed Water Tank - Maintains perfect brew temperature readiness at all times. Flexible Dispensing - Capable of handling 8 1/2&quot; cups. Hopper Capacity: (2) 4lbsTank Capacity: 2 gallonsDimensions :7 3/4&quot; x 19&quot; x 24&quot;Plumbing: 1/4&quot; water lineElectrical: 120V, 1.8KW, 15A Less 
 ARCO Coffee Co. Store not rated See Store Info /grindmastercecilware/J8YwQYCpJWhwczxI4ybtDA==/info ARCO Coffee Co. $802.40 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di110.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/52/78/35/70513342472d68614d794a6c4f334f6a434751-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware GB3HC-CP 3 dispenser Compact Whipper Grindmaster- Cecilware GB3HC-CP 3 dispenser Compact Whipper 
 ( In stock ) 
Compact Whipper Series Cecilware incorporates its leading technology into a line of dispensers for all types of accounts and a variety of products: Hot Chocolate, Cappuccino, Steamers... More 

Compact Whipper Series Cecilware incorporates its leading technology into a line of dispensers for all types of accounts and a variety of products: Hot Chocolate, Cappuccino, Steamers and...more. Only 24&quot; Tall and 7.75&quot; Wide Power Whip - Carefully whips the product into a delicious, creamy drink. Uniquely Designed Water Tank - Maintains perfect brew temperature readiness at all times. Flexible Dispensing - Capable of handling 8 1/2&quot; cups. Hopper Capacity: (3) 4lbsTank Capacity: 2 gallonsDimensions :10&quot; x 19&quot; x 27&quot;Plumbing: 1/4&quot; water lineElectrical: 120V, 1.8KW, 15A Less 
 ARCO Coffee Co. Store not rated See Store Info /grindmastercecilware/Rx5pQ3BG-haMyJlO3OjCGQ==/info ARCO Coffee Co. $974.55 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/36/57/32/7233586c43304d47783262414c674164464441-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 GRINDMASTER- CECILWARE CORP. 7776E Amw Twin Midline Pump Urns 12D170 GRINDMASTER- CECILWARE CORP. 7776E Amw Twin Midline Pump Urns 12D170 
 ( In stock ) 
Coffee Urn, Twin, Capacity (2) 6 Gal., Max. Cup Height 9-3/4 In., Width 34 In., Depth 16-3/4 In., Height 33-1/10 In., Voltage 220, Amps 50, Watts 8500, Material Stainless Steel, Color... More 

Coffee Urn, Twin, Capacity (2) 6 Gal., Max. Cup Height 9-3/4 In., Width 34 In., Depth 16-3/4 In., Height 33-1/10 In., Voltage 220, Amps 50, Watts 8500, Material Stainless Steel, Color Stainless Steel, Includes 25 Paper Filters, Standards Nsf, Ul Less 
 Grainger 32 store reviews See Store Info /grindmastercecilware/6W2r3XlC0MGx2bALgAdFDA==/info Grainger $5,468.00 +$107.52 shipping Visit Store -49% http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/4d/4a/52/683042495856615f72454257424535442d3177-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Cecilware 5311 - Counter Model Single Flavor Crathco Frozen Drink Machine, 1.5... Cecilware 5311 - Counter Model Single Flavor Crathco Frozen Drink Machine, 1.5 gal 
 Crathco Frozen Drink Machine, counter model, air-cooled self-contained refrigeration, single flavor, 1-1/2 gallon frozen, 5 gallon storage capacity, 3/4 HP, illuminated dispensing valve,&quot;Mix Low&quot;light, stainless steel construction, 3/4&amp;1/4 hp, UL, cU ( Cecilware - 5311 ) ( In stock ) 
Crathco Frozen Drink Machine, counter model, air-cooled self-contained refrigeration, single flavor, 1-1/2 gallon frozen, 5 gallon storage capacity, 3/4 HP, illuminated dispensing valve,... More 

Crathco Frozen Drink Machine, counter model, air-cooled self-contained refrigeration, single flavor, 1-1/2 gallon frozen, 5 gallon storage capacity, 3/4 HP, illuminated dispensing valve, &quot;Mix Low&quot; light, stainless steel construction, 3/4&amp;1/4 hp, UL, cU ( Cecilware - 5311 ) Less 
 KaTom Restaurant Supply 177 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-5311-counter/MJRh0BIXVa_rEBWBE5D-1w==/info KaTom Restaurant Supply $7,586.00 $3,886.31 49% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store -48% http://di108.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/50/6c/49/4135367a324255744b32494f4d6e32377a7877-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Cecilware Arctic Deluxe 20/4PD Four Bowl 5.4 Gallon Premix Cold Beverage Dispenser Cecilware Arctic Deluxe 20/4PD Four Bowl 5.4 Gallon Premix Cold Beverage Dispenser 
 In Stock ( In stock ) 
Your customers are parched! Quench their thirst and boost impulse sales at your snack bar, buffet, or fast food restaurant with this Cecilware Arctic Deluxe 20/4PD four bowl 5.4 gallon... More 

Your customers are parched! Quench their thirst and boost impulse sales at your snack bar, buffet, or fast food restaurant with this Cecilware Arctic Deluxe 20/4PD four bowl 5.4 gallon premix cold beverage dispenser. Because each bowl has its own motor, the four bowls operate independently of one another so that you have greater control over your beverages. At only 28 1/2&quot; wide, this 4 bowl premix cold beverage dispenser features four 5.4 gallon refrigerated bowls for long-lasting refreshment while sacrificing minimal countertop space! With the ability to set the dispenser for fast or gentle agitation for juice or dairy beverages, it is perfect for serving three types of fruit juice, iced tea, iced coffee, and other refreshingly chilled drinks. The Cecilware Arctic Deluxe 20/4PD beverage dispenser&apos;s 1/7 hp compressor that uses R134A refrigerant will keep your beverages chilled and ready for consumption for hours at a time. It requires a 120V electrical connection and is UL and NSF Listed. Dimensions Height: 26 1/2&quot; Width: 28 1/2&quot; Depth: 18 1/2&quot; Also known as 20-4PD, 20 4PD, and 204PD. 20/4PD From Grindmaster Cecilware Less 
 The WEBstaurant Store 267 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-arctic-deluxe/PlIA56z2BUtK2IOMn27zxw==/info The WEBstaurant Store $3,008.00 $1,579.00 48% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/32/56/62/49687a4e6b79784335556e625643634d625651-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Cecilware GB4M-5.5-LD-PC Space Saver Series Cecilware GB4M-5.5-LD-PC Space Saver Series 
 Contact Us ( In stock ) 
Space Saver Hot Cappuccino Dispenser, 4 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 4.2 gal. water tank cap., (4) hoppers w/5-1/2 lb. powder product cap. ea, 78... More 

Space Saver Hot Cappuccino Dispenser, 4 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 4.2 gal. water tank cap., (4) hoppers w/5-1/2 lb. powder product cap. ea, 78 burst cap, lit. display, black texture finish, 1/4&quot; water with Portion Control Less 
 Restaurant Equipment World 5 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-gb4m55ldpc/2VbIhzNkyxC5UnbVCcMbVQ==/info $2,035.16 No Shipping Info Visit Store -44% http://di1-1.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/20/64/95/22057640-100x100-0-0_Cecilware+CS+3.jpg 
 Cecilware CS-3 12-Cups Coffee Maker 
 Cecilware CS-3 12-Cups Coffee Maker Coffee Maker, Office, 12 Cups, 1800 Watts from $376.40 44% Off Free Shipping 2 stores See Details http://di1-3.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/c6/d9/8d/122351503-100x100-0-0_grindmaster+cecilware+gb5mv+10+ld.jpg 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware GB5MV-10-LD 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware GB5MV-10-LD from $2,300.00 2 stores See Details -49% http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/55/46/6d/7a63614551367a636c507a6f4a2d762d656e67-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Crathco Frozen Drink Machine, Counter Model, Air-cooled Self-contained Refrigeration, One Crathco Frozen Drink Machine, Counter Model, Air-cooled Self-contained Refrigeration, One 
 ( In stock ) 
Crathco Frozen Drink Machine, Counter Model, Air-cooled Self-contained Refrigeration, One Flavor, 1-1/2 Gallon Frozen, 5 Gallon Storage Capacity, &quot;mix Low&quot; Light, Flavorlight Backlit Sign,... More 

Crathco Frozen Drink Machine, Counter Model, Air-cooled Self-contained Refrigeration, One Flavor, 1-1/2 Gallon Frozen, 5 Gallon Storage Capacity, &quot;mix Low&quot; Light, Flavorlight Backlit Sign, Stainless Steel Construction, 3/4 Hp&amp;1/2 Hp, Ul, Cul, Nsf (grindmaster) Less 
 Hotel Restaurant Supply Store not rated See Store Info /crathco-frozen-drink/UFmzcaEQ6zclPzoJ-v-eng==/info Hotel Restaurant Supply $7,314.00 $3,743.52 49% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/32/5a/64/53495568504b566a704b492d66425364595541-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Cecilware GB4M-5.5-W-LD Space Saver Series Cecilware GB4M-5.5-W-LD Space Saver Series 
 Contact Us ( In stock ) 
Space Saver Hot Cappuccino Dispenser, 4 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 4.2 gal. water tank cap., (4) hoppers w/5-1/2 lb. powder product cap. ea, 78... More 

Space Saver Hot Cappuccino Dispenser, 4 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 4.2 gal. water tank cap., (4) hoppers w/5-1/2 lb. powder product cap. ea, 78 burst cap, lit. display, black texture finish, 1/4&quot; water with Hot Water Dispense Button Less 
 Restaurant Equipment World 5 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-gb4m55wld/2ZdSIUhPKVjpKI-fBSdYUA==/info $1,899.41 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/50/51/45/686c34484e594b4e343563755a6e6e665a6e77-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Cecilware CRS 33 Automatic Coffee Urn Pre-owned Cecilware CRS 33 Automatic Coffee Urn Pre-owned 
 ( In stock ) 
 Cecilware CSR 33 Automatic Coffee Urn. This is very similar to an FE-100. It doesn&apos;t have a by-pass or an agitator like the FE-100. Cecilware is well known in the industry for it&apos;s fine... More 

 Cecilware CSR 33 Automatic Coffee Urn. This is very similar to an FE-100. It doesn&apos;t have a by-pass or an agitator like the FE-100. Cecilware is well known in the industry for it&apos;s fine quality Coffee Urns. Quality designed, engineered and constructed stainless steel. Ideal for restaurants or large events, brews 600(5oz) cups per hour. Up to 25 gallons of coffee per hour. Brews consistently perfect coffee batch after batch. Uses paper filters,(we sell 3 gallon filters for the urn under &quot;coffee related items&quot; then &quot;coffee brewing filters&quot;). Brews in convenient one pound coffee batches. Two 3 gallon liners. This machine is seller refurbished, used, PRE-OWNED. It has been cleaned, serviced, and inspected by qualified technicians and is in excellent condition. Mistake-proof, push button - coffee/water formula is automatically locked into brewing cycle. Thermometer on front of urn indicates when water is at optimal temperature( 197- 204 degrees)for brewing. Electrical: 120/240V AC, 60Hz, single phase, 3 wireWater Connection: 1/4&quot; tubingDimensions: 17 1/2&quot;D X 28 1/2&quot;H X 33 1/2&quot;W This is PRE-OWNED machine.Comes with a 30 day warranty. We are offering a Super Savings Sample on our Restaurant Special Coffee with the purchase of the Urn. If you are interested in purchasing it by the case please contact us. Less 
 ARCO Coffee Co. Store not rated See Store Info /cecilware-crs-33/PQEhl4HNYKN45cuZnnfZnw==/info ARCO Coffee Co. $1,151.88 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di104.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/41/33/35/37496f313345484d5a6270686259756c647567-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 GRINDMASTER- CECILWARE CORP. GB5M10-LD-RH Hot Beverage Dispenser, powdered,5 Flavor 12D148 GRINDMASTER- CECILWARE CORP. GB5M10-LD-RH Hot Beverage Dispenser, powdered,5 Flavor 12D148 
 ( In stock ) 
Hot Beverage Dispenser, 5 Flavor, Capacity 6 Gal., Max. Cup Height 8 In., Width 18 In., Depth 22 In., Height 34 In., Voltage 120, Amps 15, Watts 1800, Material Steel, Color Black, Holds (1)... More 

Hot Beverage Dispenser, 5 Flavor, Capacity 6 Gal., Max. Cup Height 8 In., Width 18 In., Depth 22 In., Height 34 In., Voltage 120, Amps 15, Watts 1800, Material Steel, Color Black, Holds (1) 10 Lb. (4) 5 Lb., Includes Cappuccino Graphic, Standards Ul,nsf,cul Less 
 Grainger 32 store reviews See Store Info /grindmastercecilware/A357Io13EHMZbphbYuldug==/info Grainger $4,263.00 +$78.00 shipping Visit Store http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/50/42/6c/5154564730425342517a304b30456b65305267-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Cecilware 3 Gallon Twin Automatic Coffee Urn Cecilware 3 Gallon Twin Automatic Coffee Urn 
 ( In stock ) 
Automatic Coffee Urn; Stainless steel construction; Twin 3 gallon capacity; Brews in 1 lb batches; Adjustable by-pass; Automatic push button agitator; Cycle stop switch; Side mounted... More 

Automatic Coffee Urn; Stainless steel construction; Twin 3 gallon capacity; Brews in 1 lb batches; Adjustable by-pass; Automatic push button agitator; Cycle stop switch; Side mounted control panel; Solid state timer&amp;new liquid level control system; 1/4&quot; water line required; Specify voltage when ordering; (3-phase voltage available); 120V/208V/60/1- ph; 29A/6,000W; 120V/240V/60/1- ph; 34A/8,000W; 33.5&quot;W x 28.5&quot;H x 17.5&quot;D; One year parts&amp;labor warranty; ETL listed; NSF certified Less 
 Tundra Specialties Store not rated See Store Info /cecilware-3-gallon-twin/PBlQTVG0BSBQz0K0Eke0Rg==/info Tundra Specialties $2,041.58 No Shipping Info Visit Store -49% http://di1-3.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/29/c9/c8/41966893-100x100-0-0_Cecilware+Cecilware+Mt+2+Mini+2+Bowl+Granita+Bever.jpg 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware MT-2-MINI 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware MT-2-MINI from $1,747.39 49% Off 4 stores See Details -49% http://di1-1.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/1c/00/d7/41077090-100x100-0-0_Cecilware+EL6.jpg 
 Cecilware EL6 Deep Fryer 
 Cecilware EL6 Deep Fryer With Adjustable Thermostat, Without Filtration system from $200.82 49% Off Free Shipping 3 stores See Details -49% http://di1-1.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/6b/df/9e/53624703-100x100-0-0_Cecilware+Cecilware+MT+1+MINI+1+Bowl+Frozen+Bevera.jpg 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware MT-1-MINI 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware MT-1-MINI from $1,370.68 49% Off 6 stores See Details -49% http://di1-1.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/7d/8b/4a/53624806-100x100-0-0_Cecilware+Cecilware+MT+3+MINI+3+Bowl+Granita+Bever.jpg 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware MT-3-MINI 
 Grindmaster- Cecilware MT-3-MINI from $2,418.91 49% Off 5 stores See Details http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/33/72/6d/777839664857736e364148386453686d694677-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Cecilware GB5M-210-LD-U Feature Flavor Series Cecilware GB5M-210-LD-U Feature Flavor Series 
 Contact Us ( In stock ) 
Feature Flavor Hot Cappuccino Dispenser, 5 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 6.0 gal. water tank cap., (3)5lb.&amp;(2) 10lb hopper powder product cap. ea, 98... More 

Feature Flavor Hot Cappuccino Dispenser, 5 flavor manual dispense operation, 8-1/2&quot; cup clearance, power whip, 6.0 gal. water tank cap., (3)5lb.&amp;(2) 10lb hopper powder product cap. ea, 98 burst cap., lit. display, vertical lift door, black texture finish Less 
 Restaurant Equipment World 5 store reviews See Store Info /cecilware-gb5m210ldu/3rmwx9fHWsn6AH8dShmiFw==/info $2,280.60 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/56/30/52/354d495453444850716a49464c63714a666b77-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Cecilware CRS 33 Automatic Coffee Urn Pre-owned Cecilware CRS 33 Automatic Coffee Urn Pre-owned 
 ( In stock ) 
 Cecilware CSR 33 Automatic Coffee Urn. This is very similar to an FE-100. It doesn&apos;t have a by-pass or an agitator like the FE-100. Cecilware is well known in the industry for it&apos;s fine... More 

 Cecilware CSR 33 Automatic Coffee Urn. This is very similar to an FE-100. It doesn&apos;t have a by-pass or an agitator like the FE-100. Cecilware is well known in the industry for it&apos;s fine quality Coffee Urns. Quality designed, engineered and constructed stainless steel. Ideal for restaurants or large events, brews 600(5oz) cups per hour. Up to 25 gallons of coffee per hour. Brews consistently perfect coffee batch after batch. Uses paper filters,(we sell 3 gallon filters for the urn under &quot;coffee related items&quot; then &quot;coffee brewing filters&quot;). Brews in convenient one pound coffee batches. Two 3 gallon liners. This machine is seller refurbished, used, PRE-OWNED. It has been cleaned, serviced, and inspected by qualified technicians and is in excellent condition. Mistake-proof, push button - coffee/water formula is automatically locked into brewing cycle. Thermometer on front of urn indicates when water is at optimal temperature( 197- 204 degrees)for brewing. Electrical: 120/240V AC, 60Hz, single phase, 3 wireWater Connection: 1/4&quot; tubingDimensions: 17 1/2&quot;D X 28 1/2&quot;H X 33 1/2&quot;W This is PRE-OWNED machine.Comes with a 30 day warranty. We are offering a Super Savings Sample on our Restaurant Special Coffee with the purchase of the Urn. If you are interested in purchasing it by the case please contact us. Less 
 ARCO Coffee Co. Store not rated See Store Info /cecilware-crs-33/V0R5MITSDHPqjIFLcqJfkw==/info ARCO Coffee Co. $1,151.56 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di111.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/5a/62/55/514c507353356b497a596c306a65514b6d5041-100x100-0-0.jpg 
 Cecilware CRS 33 Automatic Coffee Urn Pre-owned Cecilware CRS 33 Automatic Coffee Urn Pre-owned 
 ( In stock ) 
 Cecilware CSR 33 Automatic Coffee Urn. This is very similar to an FE-100. It doesn&apos;t have a by-pass or an agitator like the FE-100. Cecilware is well known in the industry for it&apos;s fine... More 

 Cecilware CSR 33 Automatic Coffee Urn. This is very similar to an FE-100. It doesn&apos;t have a by-pass or an agitator like the FE-100. Cecilware is well known in the industry for it&apos;s fine quality Coffee Urns. Quality designed, engineered and constructed stainless steel. Ideal for restaurants or large events, brews 600(5oz) cups per hour. Up to 25 gallons of coffee per hour. Brews consistently perfect coffee batch after batch. Uses paper filters,(we sell 3 gallon filters for the urn under &quot;coffee related items&quot; then &quot;coffee brewing filters&quot;). Brews in convenient one pound coffee batches. Two 3 gallon liners. This machine is seller refurbished, used, PRE-OWNED. It has been cleaned, serviced, and inspected by qualified technicians and is in excellent condition. Mistake-proof, push button - coffee/water formula is automatically locked into brewing cycle. Thermometer on front of urn indicates when water is at optimal temperature( 197- 204 degrees)for brewing. Electrical: 120/240V AC, 60Hz, single phase, 3 wireWater Connection: 1/4&quot; tubingDimensions: 17 1/2&quot;D X 28 1/2&quot;H X 33 1/2&quot;W This is PRE-OWNED machine.Comes with a 30 day warranty. We are offering a Super Savings Sample on our Restaurant Special Coffee with the purchase of the Urn. If you are interested in purchasing it by the case please contact us. Less 
 ARCO Coffee Co. Store not rated See Store Info /cecilware-crs-33/ZbUQLPsS5kIzYl0jeQKmPA==/info ARCO Coffee Co. $1,152.50 No Shipping Info Visit Store 1 2 3 4 5 ... 38 Next  » Why are these stores listed? 
Prices are provided by the merchants. We assume no responsibility for accuracy of price information provided by merchants. Please alert us to any pricing discrepancies and we will alert the merchant. Sales taxes are estimated at the zip code level. Shipping costs are estimates. Please check store for exact shipping costs. To learn more about why certain stores are listed on the site, click here 

Product specifications are obtained from third parties, and while we make every effort to assure the accuracy of product information, we do not assume any liability for inaccuracies. Store ratings and product reviews are written and submitted by online shoppers to assist you as you shop. They do not reflect our opinions. We take no responsibility for the content of ratings and reviews submitted by users.
 
Products on Sale
 -49% Cecilware GB5MF-HC-IT-LD - $2,151.66 $4,200.00 KaTom Restaurant Supply -49% Cecilware GB5MF-IT-LD - $2,151.66 $4,200.00 KaTom Restaurant Supply -48% Cecilware FrigoGranita MT2MINI $1,779.00 $3,414.00 The WEBstaurant Store -48% Cecilware FrigoGranita MT1MINI $1,389.00 $2,678.00 The WEBstaurant Store 
Guides from our Merchants
 
 Gifts for the Beer Drinker 
 Instead of a cheesy foam koozie or frat-worthy Bud Light... 1 
 Gifts for the Hostess With the Mostest 
 She (or he) throws the best parties without ever breaking a... 0 
 
 
About
 Home About Us Jobs Contact Us Privacy User Agreement 
Work with us
 Join our Partner Program Merchant Login Join our Merchant Program Advertise with Us 
Helpful Stuff
 Merchant Directory Brand Directory Site Index Popular Pages Shopping Guides 
eBay Family
 eBay Free Local Classifieds PayPal Apartments for Rent Tickets 
Shopping Sites
   France   Germany   United Kingdom   Australia   USA 
Copyright©2000-2012 Shopping.com
 http://img.shoppingshadow.com/jfe/JavaFrontEnd-fe121.rtb15.dt_seotags-9011 http://img.shopping.com/jfe/JavaFrontEnd-fe121.rtb15.dt_seotags-9011
	</body>
</document>
