<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001655" url="http://www.worldcrops.com/about/news/" time="2012-07-12-17:26" support="3" score="0.006852590356801077" bingtitle="Agri Commodity News | Agriculture Climate Change | WorldCrops.com" webtitle="Agri Commodity News | Agriculture Climate Change | WorldCrops.com">
			<query id="001441" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="001436" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="001424" bing-rank="89"/>
	<description>Agriculture climate change and its impact on the ... with 186.5 bushels per acre compared to La Salle County ... Soy ends 10-day rally, but still near 5-month top</description>
	<body>
		Skip to navigation 
 Welcome Sign Up   Log In 
 
 Home Grains of Truth Research News Events About Us Contact Us 
 LOG IN Search COMMODITIES: 
 Cocoa Coffee Sugar Cotton Corn Wheat Soybeans Palm Oil 
 
NEWS
 Select a commodity: Top Stories Cocoa Coffee Sugar Cotton Corn Wheat Soybeans Palm Oil 
Glencore International profits hit by tumbling cotton prices
 Monday 5th March, 2012 
 StockMarketWire.com - Swiss commodities trader Glencore International said adjusted EBIT increased 2% to $5.398bn in 2011 compared to 2010. The 2011 results benefited from generally higher average prices for key commodities. Mostly greater volumes were ... 
 Read more 
Speculative Wagers on Agriculture Surge to a Five-Month High: Commodities
 Monday 5th March, 2012 
 A measure of speculative positions across 11 farm goods jumped 26 percent to 607721 futures and options in the week ended Feb. 28, US Commodity Futures Trading Commission data show. Corn bets increased the most in eight weeks, and sugar holdings ... 
 Read more 
Companies Selling GM Seeds, Herbicides
 Monday 5th March, 2012 
 The vast majority of commodity GM crops--including corn, soybeans, canola, cotton and now alfalfa--have been bred to resist one best-selling herbicide called glyphosate. Glyphosate is what is known as a broad-spectrum herbicide, meaning it disrupts ... 
 Read more 
India bans cotton exports effective immediately
 Monday 5th March, 2012 
 &quot;Export of cotton has been prohibited till further orders,&quot;the DGFT said in a statement. India is the world&apos;s second largest producer of cotton and most of its shipments go to China, the world&apos;s largest user of the fibre.&quot;Export against registration ... 
 Read more 
China&apos;s commodity demand declining: Credit Suisse
 Monday 5th March, 2012 
 The commodity super-cycle underpinned by China has drawn to a close, according to new research by Credit Suisse, which says the Chinese commodity needs have peaked as the nation transitions to domestic consumption and away from exports and infrastructure building as a driver of the economy. 
 Read more 
Changing Asian monsoon would adversely impact kharif yield: Study
 Sunday 4th March, 2012 
 Put together, it would lead to a lower yield of kharif crops like rice, maize, cotton, oilseeds, soybean and coarse grains ... Heavy rainfall during soyabean harvest led to crop loss in 2010. High humidity levels resulted in bacterial disease ... 
 Read more 
Economists: Corn crop could satisfy demand
 Sunday 4th March, 2012 
 The US Department of Agriculture forecasts a record US corn crop in 2012. The USDA estimates US farmers will produce a record corn crops this year, topping 14 billion bushels for the first time. And one ag economist believes this might be the year corn ... 
 Read more 
China still holds untapped potential
 Sunday 4th March, 2012 
 Mr Calder said WA wheat exports over the last five years had averaged 180000 tonnes, just 2.6pc of WA wheat exports. He said although there was currently better market for WA wheat, there were emerging opportunities in China. 
 Read more 
CWB signs grain deal with Cargill
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 By Rod Nickel, Reuters March 1, 2012 11:00 PM The Canadian Wheat Board said on Thursday that it has agreed with Cargill Ltd to move the CWB&apos;s 2012/13 grains through its grain elevators and port facilities, the first such deal as the board moves to ... 
 Read more 
APNewsBreak: USDA unveils new conservation program
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 By idling the erodible land and planting it in grasses and other vegetation, the program also creates wildlife habitat. Roger Wolf, director of environmental programs for the Iowa Soybean Association, said farmers must weigh their options when land comes ... 
 Read more 
Cote d&apos;Ivoire Look to Join the Oil Rich Neighborhood in West Africa
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 By John Daly | Thu, 01 March 2012 23:33 | 0 Cote d&apos;Ivoire (“Ivory Coast” in English), is the world&apos;s largest producer and exporter of cocoa beans. What will the nation do with its newly discovered oil riches? Astronomers spend their entire lives ... 
 Read more 
Wheat falls for 2nd day, soy dips after 9-session rally
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 &quot;Grain markets are overbought and we are seeing a little bit of correction as there is not much fundamental support at the moment,&quot;said Lynette Tan, an analyst with Phillip Futures in Singapore.&quot;There is some support from Iran&apos;s purchase of US wheat, ... 
 Read more 
Brazil Feb sugar, soy, coffee, iron exports rise
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 (Corrects figure for raw sugar exports) * Soy, corn harvest starting to peak, exports to pick up * Iron ore exports higher but Carnival may have slowed trade SAO PAULO, March 1 (Reuters) - Brazilian sugar, soybean, coffee and iron ore exports rose in ... 
 Read more 
NY sugar settles lower, cocoa and coffee perk up
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 March 1 (Reuters) - Raw sugar futures closed lower for the third straight session Thursday, backtracking from a recent four-month high, as investors sold amid the expectation for coming bumper supplies. Arabica coffee changed direction and closed ... 
 Read more 
UPDATE 2-Argentine grains ports hit by dock workers&apos; strike
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 The South American country also provides about 12 percent of soybean exports and it is the world&apos;s No. 2 corn exporter after the United States. One grains exporting company had its Rosario dock free and ready to tie up two cargo ships for ... 
 Read more 
Commodity companies face difficult trading environment as margins shrink
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 ... Indofood Agri are already planning to ramp up their Indonesian refining capacity. A saving grace for some producers is the ongoing strength of crude oil prices, which may push up demand for biofuel and biodiesel, and help bolster crude palm oil demand. 
 Read more 
Wilmar buys stake in Goodman Fielder, eyes more
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Singapore headquartered palm oil company Wilmar International said it has acquired a 10.1% stake in Goodman Fielder Ltd , Australia&apos;s largest listed food company, for $124 million and added its brands were a good fit. The news sent Goodman Fielder ... 
 Read more 
New urea investment policy aims to ramp up capacity
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 A Group of Ministers on Friday recommended a new fertiliser investment policy which envisages creation of new urea production capacity of up to 6 million tonnes. The policy will have to be cleared by the Cabinet Committee on Economic Affairs (CCEA) before ... 
 Read more 
Cooking-Oil Imports by India Seen Climbing to Record as Harvests Decline
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 About 80 percent of India&apos;s purchases consist of palm oil. It&apos;s “a cheaper option for India,” Ryan Long, vice president of futures and options at OSK Investment Bank Bhd., said by phone from Kuala Lumpur. “Higher demand from India will support palm-oil ... 
 Read more 
Liberia: The Plantation Blues
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 In October 2011, community leaders in western Liberia wrote to the Roundtable on Sustainable Palm Oil (RSPO), the global association ... of land-grabbing and buying up crops at knockdown prices, emphasizes its recruitment of Liberians and issues a strong ... 
 Read more 
Grim toil as third of farmers earn less than minimum wage
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 “As a committee we are actively looking at novel ways to boost farm incomes through bed and breakfasts, through payments for water storage, and looking at the Common Agricultural Policy. “But we need to make sure they have a viable future for their ... 
 Read more 
What is the grain market telling us?
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 by Alan Guebert As corn and soybeans cash prices flutter around their post-harvest highs, a farmer telephones with a question: How do February&apos;s stronger prices compare to 2010 season average prices for corn, soybeans, wheat and cotton? 
 Read more 
Bacteria may help oil palm decrease GHG emissions and improve carbon storage
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 A recent CIFOR study quantified the atmospheric effects on changes in land use from biofuel production and found that for palm oil grown on peatlands, the carbon emissions generated from land conversion would take hundreds of years to reverse. 
 Read more 
Ron Paul Tells Bernanke He Killed The Dollar, Silver Coin In Hand
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Bernanke&apos;s QE Pickle: Rising Oil Prices And Vicious Feedback Loops Agustino Fontevecchia Forbes Staff Why More Foreclosures And Falling Home Prices Are A Good Thing Agustino Fontevecchia Forbes Staff Fed Chairman Ben Bernanke had an interesting ... 
 Read more 
China’s Meat Demand Boon to Corn, Bean Producers
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Bernanke&apos;s QE Pickle: Rising Oil Prices And Vicious Feedback Loops Agustino Fontevecchia Forbes Staff Why More Foreclosures And Falling Home Prices Are A Good Thing Agustino Fontevecchia Forbes Staff Fed Chairman Ben Bernanke had an interesting ... 
 Read more 
Study focuses on bee deaths
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 Neonicotinoids are a class of insecticides commonly used to coat corn, soybean and other annual crop seeds prior to planting. These compounds act on the insect nervous system, causing paralysis and ultimately, death. Almost all of the corn seed planted in ... 
 Read more 
UPDATE 1-ICE says policy has cut risky high-frequency trades
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 The policy, implemented in January 2011, applies to ICE&apos;s cocoa, arabica coffee, cotton No. 2, sugar No. 11, U.S. dollar and Russell Index futures contracts; to firms that have direct access to the electronic platform; and who enter more than ... 
 Read more 
Agricultural season in Morocco under threat
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 By Siham Ali for Magharebia in Rabat – 29/02/12 Morocco is bracing itself for low yields in its harvest this year, as a lack of rainfall and low temperatures over the past several weeks damaged crops. According to Agriculture Minister Aziz Akhennouch, ... 
 Read more 
Africa for Sale: The Land Grab Landmine Patrick Mugo Mugo
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 Referred to as land leasing, land selling or land grabbing, it affects Africa more than any other region, where land is more than a factor of production, but a lifeline to an individual&apos;s wellbeing, the family unit, the community at large and the ... 
 Read more 
Floods take $250m cotton toll
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 Cotton Australia chief executive Adam Kay says the untimely flooding forced this year&apos;s cotton production forecasts to be slashed from 4.9 million bales down to 4.4 million bales, with picking due to start in the affected areas in about one month. 
 Read more 
USDA&apos;s outlook for crop prices In 2012
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 But he added that soybeans would be lower in price had it not been for Chinese demand and the lower Brazilian supply. The USDA projections were based on expansion of planted acres domestically and globally in 2012, a higher corn yield, less corn being ... 
 Read more 
The US Agriculture after the Closing Bell Report
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 Wheat futures chopped around unchanged most of the day Wednesday and finished mid-range with Chicago and Minneapolis Wheat pennies higher in most contracts and Kansas City Wheat 0.005 to 0.0275 lower. A sharply higher USD index made it difficult for the ... 
 Read more 
Update Australia’s dietary guidelines to consider sustainability
 Monday 27th February, 2012 
 When eating for health and the environment, not all foods are created equal. The consumption of seafood has led to the over-exploitation of three quarters of the world’s oceans. Meat and dairy foods require more water, energy and phosphorus to produce ... 
 Read more 
U.S. stocks open higher on Greece optimism; Dow up 0.45%
 Monday 13th February, 2012 
 Forexpros - U.S. stock markets were higher after the open on Monday, as market sentiment improved ... 
 Read more 
Monsanto guilty of chemical poisoning in France
 Monday 13th February, 2012 
 * Case against Monsanto (MON) 1st such claim to reach French court. * Pesticide makers see no evidence of major health risk. By Marion Douet. A French court on Monday declared U.S. biotech giant Monsanto (MON) guilty of chemical poisoning of a French farmer, a judgment that could lend weight to other ... 
 Read more 
Greece still to convince Europe after rescue deal
 Monday 13th February, 2012 
 * Greek parliament passes unpopular package of cuts. * Papademos accepts implementation will be tough. * Violence, petrol bombs thrown. * World markets gain modestly. By Renee Maltezou. 
 Read more 
Market Rises although Greek Deal Still not Confirmed
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 Despite the delay of a meeting between Greece and the IMF/EU/ECB troika due to &apos;missing paperwork&apos; and the unexpected decline in Germany industrial production, market sentiment was 
 Read more 
Exclusive: Malaysian exporters halt palm oil supply to Iran
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 KUALA LUMPUR (Reuters) - Malaysian palm oil exporters have stopped supplying Iran with most of the 30000 tonnes of the food staple the Middle Eastern country buys each month, or about half its demand, as Western financial curbs on Tehran stymie ... 
 Read more 
ICE sugar, cocoa edge higher as dollar weakens
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 LONDON Feb 8 (Reuters) - Raw sugar, cocoa and arabica coffee futures on ICE rose in early trade on Wednesday, buoyed by a weaker dollar and an improved risk appetite linked to hopes a second bailout of Greece was close. * Sugar prices were ... 
 Read more 
Report shows strong growth in GM crops
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 The United States remained the primary backer of biotech crop technology in 2011, but adoption spread internationally as the total global planted area of genetically modified seeds grew 8% from a year ago, a new report says. EU plans to move towards a ... 
 Read more 
UPDATE 2-Sappi earnings tick up as cost cuts help
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 * Says Q2 profit to rise quarter-on-quarter

 (Adds details, quotes, analyst) 
 Read more 
New Way to Map Drought and Water Use
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 Besides drought monitoring, water management and irrigation scheduling, uses of the ALEXI/satellite package include crop yield prediction. “If crops suddenly show stress, we can ask whether that will affect yield, which will depend on the crop and ... 
 Read more 
Farmland on the rise: 2011 brought big increases in tillable land prices
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 If they stop buying, commodity (corn, soybean) prices would fall quickly ... Houston County utilizes a different system called &quot;crop equivalent rating,&quot; to classify land, but sales averaged $3,010 for typical (70 percent CER) tillable land at the beginning ... 
 Read more 
Farmers Plan Biggest Crops Since 1984, Led by Corn: Commodities
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 Feb. 7 (Bloomberg) -- U.S. farmers will plant the most acres in a generation this year, led by the biggest corn crop since World War II, taking advantage of the highest agricultural prices in at least four decades. They will sow corn ... 
 Read more 
Will Drought Break in 2012?
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 Feb. 7 (Bloomberg) -- U.S. farmers will plant the most acres in a generation this year, led by the biggest corn crop since World War II, taking advantage of the highest agricultural prices in at least four decades. They will sow corn ... 
 Read more 
Food Bubble Is Expanding U.S. Waistlines: Vikram Mansharamani
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 There&apos;s reason to think that the low price of food has led people to eat more of it, and especially the kinds of foods that are subsidized by US agricultural policy. Consider that overconsumption is not spread evenly across food groups, ... 
 Read more 
More big companies disclosing impacts on forests
 Tuesday 7th February, 2012 
 Eighty-seven global corporations disclosed their&quot;forest footprint&quot;in 2011, according to the third Forest Footprint Disclosure (FFD), which asks companies to report on their impact on forests based on their use of five commodities: soy, palm oil, ... 
 Read more 
Glencore commodity trading earnings slump in 2011
 Tuesday 7th February, 2012 
 Cotton was a key reason behind quarterly losses at rival Noble Group in the aftermath of a roaring rally that quadrupled cotton prices in six months only to see them falling by more than half. Glencore&apos;s metals and minerals trading fared better ... 
 Read more 
Era of Falling Food Prices Seen at End on Growth in Population
 Monday 6th February, 2012 
 Cargill, based in Minnesota, trades all kinds of farm commodities, including cocoa ... export bans and create a crop database to tackle what French President Nicolas Sarkozy called the “plague” of rising food prices. Hungry People As ... 
 Read more 
INTERVIEW: We&apos;re always ready to compromise
 Monday 6th February, 2012 
 This is a new segment for us that opens new markets. For example, one of the key crops in Latin America - soybean, which above all needs phosphorous and potassium. Production of sodium tripholyphosphate will probably stop in the medium-term, as more and ... 
 Read more 
Ivorian port eyes revival after civil war
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 Ivory Coast aims to boost traffic at its main port of Abidjan by 43 percent in 2012, after a post-election civil war in 2011 halted shipping for months, a port official said on Thursday.&quot;2011 was a difficult year,&quot;port manager Hien Sie told a news ... 
 Read more 
Ivory Coast cocoa prices up
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Cocoa farmgate prices in Ivory Coast&apos;s main growing regions rose last week as exporters competed for scarce supplies at the end of the main crop and international markets climbed, farmers and buyers said on Tuesday. 
 Read more 
THE COCOA FARMER&apos;S TASTELESS “FREE LUNCH”
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Since then, government has on yearly basis apportioned millions of cedis for the running of the program, with the 2012 budget allocating GH¢100.2 million for the 2011/2012 cocoa crop season ... bought at highly subsidized prices by all cocoa farmers. 
 Read more 
UPDATE 1-Indonesia&apos;s Sulawesi Feb cocoa bean exports fall 20 pct y/y- industry
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 (Recasts, adds detail, comment, table) JAKARTA, March 1 (Reuters) - Indonesia&apos;s cocoa beanexports from its main growing island of Sulawesi slipped 20percent in February from the same month a year ago, ... 
 Read more 
Indonesia&apos;s Sulawesi Feb cocoa bean exports fall 20 pct y/y- industry
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 JAKARTA, March 1 (Reuters) - Indonesia&apos;s cocoa beanexports from its main growing island of Sulawesi slumped 20percent to 7,917.7 tonnes in February from 9,871.4tonnes a year earlier, industry data showed ... 
 Read more 
NY sugar slips off 4-month peak, cocoa changes course
 Tuesday 28th February, 2012 
 Feb 28 (Reuters) - Raw sugar closed lower Tuesday, falling from the previous session&apos;s four-month high as investors sold and dealers eyed the March contract&apos;s coming expiration on Wednesday. U.S. cocoa changed direction and settled lower while ... 
 Read more 
Patchy downpour keeps mix outlook for Ivorian cocoa
 Monday 13th February, 2012 
 ABIDJAN, Feb 13 (Reuters) - Irregular rainfall
punctuated by hot weather last week in most of Ivory Coast&apos;s
principal cocoa-growing regions left farmers uncertain over the
development of their crops ahead of the April-September mid-crop
harvest, farmers said on Monday. 
 Read more 
UPDATE 1-Exporters, I.Coast move toward cocoa reform accord
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 * Cocoa reform key to IMF-backed debt relief

 (Adds details and background) 
 Read more 
Ivory Coast Cocoa-Bean Exports Rise 53% in December
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 Cocoa-bean exports from the port of Abidjan in Ivory Coast, the world&apos;s largest producer of the chocolate ingredient, increased 53 percent in December, according to data from the harbor. Shipments rose to 125816 metric tons in December from 82082 tons ... 
 Read more 
Exporters,I.Coast say close to cocoa reform accord
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 ABIDJAN, Feb 8 (Reuters) - Leading export companies
and authorities in Ivory Coast are closer to solving a dispute
threatening to derail the top cocoa grower&apos;s planned reform of
the sector, officials from both sides said after talks that
ended late on Tuesday. 
 Read more 
Cocoa crop sputters in Ivory Coast
 Tuesday 7th February, 2012 
 The bull market in cocoa came unglued in early 2011 when it became apparent that the Ivory Coast was going to grow, harvest and export a record crop despite violent political turmoil that engulfed the country. Prices plunged as bullish bets were ... 
 Read more 
Nigeria: the story of lost potential
 Monday 6th February, 2012 
 It now imports palm oil from Malaysia. It imports rice from Hong Kong ... President Jonathan more than doubled the price of fuel, is that with that kind of increase in the price of fuel, it means literally more than doubling—probably tripling, as ... 
 Read more 
I.Coast debt relief possible in Q2: IMF
 Friday 3rd February, 2012 
 By Ange Aboa ABIDJAN (Reuters) - Ivory Coast will not be able to achieve completion of an IMF-backed debt relief accord as it hopes in the first quarter of this year, but a deal is possible in the second quarter, the Fund&apos;s local official said on ... 
 Read more 
Ivorian cocoa prices rise as farmers see shortages
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 ABIDJAN (Reuters) - Cocoa farmgate prices ticked up in Ivory Coast&apos;s main growing regions ... but a number of leading exporters stayed away from the process. Meanwhile, this year&apos;s crop is expected to fall from last year&apos;s bumper harvest due ... 
 Read more 
Hershey to invest $10 million in Ivory Coast
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 ABIDJAN: The Hershey Company says it will invest USD 10 million in Ivory Coast to reduce child labour and improve the cocoa supply in the West African nation. Spokesman Andy McCormick says the measure will bring higher productivity for farmers and will ... 
 Read more 
Facebook Group Used To Make Hershey Act On Child Slavery
 Wednesday 1st February, 2012 
 Monday, January 31st marked the day the Hershey company made its commitment to buy slave-free cocoa for its chocolate, meaning that the cocoa attained was not harvested by child slaves. Hershey&apos;s was recently bowing under pressure created by social ... 
 Read more 
Cameroon Targets Unlicensed Cocoa Buyers With Seizure of Beans
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 Jan. 31 (Bloomberg) -- Cameroon’s cocoa agencies have started a joint effort to eradicate unlicensed buyers and end purchases of low-quality beans sold by farmers who need money quickly, according to the Cocoa and Coffee Interprofessional ... 
 Read more 
Europe must move to stamp-out cocoa child labour, MEPs tell Commission
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 A committee of MEPs is calling on the European Commission (EC) to consider legislating against use of child labour in cocoa plantations that fuel the EU&apos;s demand for chocolate, while the world&apos;s largest food firm Nestle has outlined its measures to safeguard against the problem. 
 Read more 
I.Coast launches cocoa reform with first auction
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 ABIDJAN (Reuters) - Ivory Coast opened its electronic forward-sales auction for the 2012-13 cocoa crop on Tuesday, exporters said, marking the official start of a top-to-bottom overhaul of the top grower nation&apos;s sector. The West African state ... 
 Read more 
Cocoa rises, eyes on Ivory Coast auction
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 LONDON Jan 31 (Reuters) - Cocoa futures on ICE edged higher on Tuesday after falling more than 5 percent the previous session, as dealers eyed the start of top producer Ivory Coast&apos;s forward sales of its 2012/13 crop. Coffee and sugar rose inline with ... 
 Read more 
Drought hits cocoa output
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 The lack of rains, coupled with last week&apos;s hot weather conditions in most parts of Ivory Coast&apos;s cocoa-growing regions, extended a dry season that could trim cocoa output as the country enters the last stage of its main crop harvest. 
 Read more 
ICCO pegs rise in global cocoa stocks
 Monday 30th January, 2012 
 &quot;The share of Liffe stocks has declined to around 20 percent; it used to be 40 to 50 percent&quot;, of the total stocks held in European warehouses, Pipitone said. In November the ICCO estimated a record global cocoa surplus of 341000 tonnes for the 2010/11 ... 
 Read more 
Big business pushes for higher cocoa yields
 Sunday 29th January, 2012 
 Firms such as Nestlé and Barry Callebaut argue that improving cocoa crop yields presents a win-win situation for corporations, farmers and consumers. But watchdog groups warn that initiatives often come with damaging side effects. A rapidly expanding ... 
 Read more 
Barry Callebaut AG : Barry Callebaut launches Cameroon chocolates and cocoa ...
 Sunday 29th January, 2012 
 The Cameroon cocoa powders are perfectly suited for use in bakery applications and are available under the Bensdorp brand. Barry Callebaut launched its Quality Partner Program, QPP, with cocoa farmer cooperatives in 2005 in Ivory Coast. 
 Read more 
Cocoa butter ratios edge up in Asia
 Sunday 29th January, 2012 
 Cocoa butter, a key chocolate ingredient, was offered at ratios of 1.05 to 1.15 times London futures, up from 1.0 to 1.05 in early January. Ratios plunged to an all-time low of 0.92 in December on ample supply.&quot;There is probably an expectation that ... 
 Read more 
Farmers urged to allow infected cocoa trees to be cut down
 Friday 27th January, 2012 
 ... Ghana to re-capture the position of the world&apos;s leading cocoa producer. Mr De-graft Fokuo, the District Chief Executive (DCE), reiterated the need for cocoa farmers to heed technical advice of the extension officers to increase crop yield and returns. 
 Read more 
ICoast president on state visit to France
 Wednesday 25th January, 2012 
 &quot;Without France, there would have been in Ivory Coast a genocide worse than in Rwanda.&quot;Still, tensions in the cocoa-rich country linger. At least one person died at the weekend when a meeting in Abidjan of Gbagbo supporters was broken up by people ... 
 Read more 
DJ Nigeria Cross River Cocoa Price Up As World Market Prices Rise
 Wednesday 25th January, 2012 
 The price of graded cocoa from the main crop is higher again in Nigeria&apos;s southeastern Cross River state following the rise in world market cocoa prices, traders said Wednesday. Cocoa is now selling in Cross River state at 340,000 naira ($2,112 ... 
 Read more 
Ivory Coast Sees 8.9% Growth in 2012, Minister Says in Les Echos
 Wednesday 25th January, 2012 
 Ivory Coast is planning to invest 629 billion CFA francs ($1.2 billion) as private investment begins to return, Diby said, according to Les Echos. The country hopes its progress in reforming the coffee and cocoa sectors will earn it International ... 
 Read more 
Agriterra Ltd
 Wednesday 25th January, 2012 
 ﻿ Agriterra Ltd / Ticker: AGTA / Index: AIM / Sector: Agriculture25 January 2012Agriterra Ltd (&apos;Agriterra&apos;or&apos;the Company&apos;)Expands Cocoa Operations in Sierra Leone Agriterra Ltd, the AIM listed pan African ... 
 Read more 
Cocoa jumps over 5 pct in short covering rally
 Tuesday 24th January, 2012 
 March robusta coffee on Liffe was up $4 at $1,893 a tonne. The contract hit $1,712 on Jan. 9, the lowest level for the benchmark second month since October 2010. (Additional reporting by David Brough; editing by James Jukwey) 
 Read more 
Defaulted Ivory Coast Eurobonds Rally Before Investor Talks
 Monday 23rd January, 2012 
 The world&apos;s largest cocoa producer hasn&apos;t paid interest on its international debt since January 2011 when the refusal of former President Laurent Gbagbo to cede power after the November 2010 election sparked a civil war. 
 Read more 
Cocoa consolidates, uncertain demand outlook weighs
 Monday 23rd January, 2012 
 Benchmark March arabica coffee futures on ICE were down 1 cent or 0.4 percent at $2.244 per lb. * Robusta physical trading was quiet with the celebration of Vietnam&apos;s Lunar New Year limiting activity. * March robusta coffee on Liffe stood $3 or 0.2 ... 
 Read more 
Barry Callebaut and Unilever sign long-term partnership agreement
 Monday 23rd January, 2012 
 Barry Callebaut to become strategic Unilever partner Barry Callebaut to become global partner of Unilever for cocoa and chocolate, doubling its current Unilever volumes Delivery of 70% of Unilever&apos;s global cocoa and chocolate needs ... 
 Read more 
One dead after attack on Ivorian opposition meeting
 Monday 23rd January, 2012 
 ABIDJAN (Reuters) - Ivory Coast&apos;s main opposition party said on Sunday one of its supporters had died after a rally the day before was attacked by stone-throwing youths it said were linked to the government. The United Nations peacekeeping mission ... 
 Read more 
DJ Central Cameroon Cocoa Trees Threatened By Insect Pests -Farmers
 Monday 23rd January, 2012 
 YAOUNDE, Cameroon, Jan 23, 2012 (Dow Jones Commodities News via Comtex) -- Hundreds of cocoa farms in Cameroon&apos;s Center Region are facing infestations of sap-sucking insects that are threatening to kill some of the crops, leaders of cocoa cooperatives said Sunday. 
 Read more 
DJ Cocoa Price In Southwest Cameroon Rises; Farmers Withhold Crop
 Sunday 22nd January, 2012 
 Prices being paid this week for a kilogram of cocoa beans sold in Cameroon&apos;s main cocoa-producing southwestern region have risen to 900 to 910 Central African CFA francs ($1.77 to $1.79), up from XAF700-850/kg for sales nearly a fortnight ago, farmers and ... 
 Read more 
Ivorian San Pedro cocoa arrivals 365,817 T by Jan 15-BCC
 Friday 20th January, 2012 
 ABIDJAN, Jan 20 (Reuters) - Cocoa arrivals at Ivory Coast&apos;s 
port of San Pedro reached 365,817 tonnes by Jan. 15 since the 
start of the season in October, according to data from the 
Coffee and Cocoa Bourse (BCC) obtained by Reuters on Friday. 
 That compared with 358,147 tonnes delivered to the port 
during the same period of the 2010/11 season. 
 The figures showed that 16,626 tonnes arrived at San Pedro 
port from January 9 to 15, down from 20,442 tonnes in the same
period of th 
 Read more 
Hot Commodities: Cocoa Futures Surge In 2012
 Thursday 19th January, 2012 
 “Cocoa arrivals at ports in top grower Ivory Coast are down nearly 4 percent to around 763000 tonnes by Jan 15, exporters estimated on Monday, compared with 793772 tonnes in the same period of the previous season as dry harmattan hits farm output” ... 
 Read more 
COTE D&apos;IVOIRE: Public health risk as taps run dry
 Thursday 19th January, 2012 
 
 Read more 
Clinton commends Ivory Coast justice effort
 Wednesday 18th January, 2012 
 Once one of the most prosperous nations in Africa, Ivory Coast was brought to its knees by the election dispute, its port closed, its bank accounts frozen. Since Ouattara took office, trade has resumed including in the profitable cocoa sector. ... 
 Read more 
Cameroon cocoa exports at end-Dec down 11 pct yr/yr
 Tuesday 17th January, 2012 
 That is down about 11 percent from the 148,973 tonnes exported by the world&apos;s No. 5 cocoa grower during the same period a year earlier, according to the figures. The central African state exported 32,541 tonnes in December, down from 39,928 ... 
 Read more 
Côte d&apos;Ivoire: UN relief official reviews situation nine months after poll violence
 Monday 16th January, 2012 
 The 21st century Ivoirian economy is largely market-based and relies heavily on agriculture, with smallholder cash crop production being dominant ... Coffee, cocoa and palm oil crops were soon planted along the coast. stood out as the only ... 
 Read more 
COCOBOD to revoke four buyers&apos; licences
 Monday 16th January, 2012 
 But COCOBOD is worried about falling cocoa prices in the world market. Cocoa prices dropped by 36 percent last year after production exceeded demand by 341,000 tonnes for the 2010/11 season, according to the International Cocoa Organisation (ICO). 
 Read more 
Lindt sales behind expectations with Nestle takeover possible – analyst
 Monday 16th January, 2012 
 Cox added: “I expect a solid year from supply side perspective - cocoa prices, and other commodities, are falling while the dollar has strengthened,” he said. “However, the demand side is the big question - I presume slow Easter business given ... 
 Read more 
Strong harmattan winds damage Ivorian cocoa: farmers
 Monday 16th January, 2012 
 Ivorian farmers are currently harvesting the main seasonal cocoa crop, which runs from October to March. Some moisture and spells of sunshine around this period are necessary for a good size and quality of the crop and to ensure a strong start ... 
 Read more 
Ivorian cocoa arrivals down 3.8 pct by Jan 15
 Monday 16th January, 2012 
 Figures from Ivory Coast&apos;s cocoa regulator Bourse du Cafe et Cacao (BCC) on Monday showed that arrivals reached 738462 tonnes by January 8, up from 736696 tonnes in the same period a year ago. Two major factors are responsible for the decline in output ... 
 Read more 
Nigerian unions suspend strike
 Monday 16th January, 2012 
 ABUJA, Jan 16 (Reuters) - Nigeria&apos;s trade union
leaders said on Monday they had suspended a strike over fuel
sbsidies that crippled the economy last week and threatened to
shut down the country&apos;s vital oil production. 
 Read more 
Ghana Rainfall Report for Cocoa Regions, Jan. 1-10
 Monday 16th January, 2012 
 The Ivory Coast, which neighbors Ghana, is the world&apos;s largest cocoa producer. Weather Station Rainfall in Millimeters Western Region: Sefwi Bekwai 0.0 Bogoso 0.0 Enchi 0.0 Ashanti Region: Kumasi 0.0 Agogo 0.0 Effiduase 0.0 Obuasi 0.0 Ashanti Bekwai ... 
 Read more 
Cameroon cocoa prices surge on tight supplies
 Monday 16th January, 2012 
 YAOUNDE, Jan 16 (Reuters) - Farmgate cocoa prices rose
between five and 25 percent in Cameroon, the world&apos;s fifth
largest producer&apos;s main growing regions on the back of tight
supplies as the main cocoa harvest season tails off, farmers
said on Monday. 
 Farmers said prices rose to about 980 CFA francs ($1.89)
from 930 CFA francs per kg in Kumba, in the South West region
and from 800 CFA francs to 1000 CFA francs in Ebolowa in the
South region. 
 &quot;We have seen a significant increase in pri 
 Read more 
Coffee Crop in Indonesia Poised for Highest in Three Years
 Monday 5th March, 2012 
 The coffee harvest in Indonesia, the third-biggest grower of the robusta variety used in instant drinks and espressos, is set to climb to the largest in three years, potentially capping a 12 percent rally. Production may increase 20 percent to ... 
 Read more 
Indonesia&apos;s February cocoa bean exports fall 20 percent
 Sunday 4th March, 2012 
 Sulawesi cocoa exports were at 7917.7 tonnes in February from 9871.4 tonnes a year ago, data from the Indonesia Cocoa Association showed. Indonesia is the world&apos;s third-largest cocoa producer after Ivory Coast and Ghana but its industry is battling ... 
 Read more 
Vietnamese farmers sell up to 55 pct of coffee crop, Volcafe says
 Saturday 3rd March, 2012 
 Farmers in Vietnam, the world’s largest robusta coffee producer, have sold 50 percent to 55 percent of the 2011-12 crop, according to Volcafe, the coffee unit of commodities trader ED&amp;F Man Holdings Ltd. Vietnam will produce a record 22.1 million bags in ... 
 Read more 
Jamaica&apos;s famed coffee industry facing hard times
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 &quot;We used to make a living, but now we&apos;re working hungry,&quot; said Colin McLaren, standing in his sloping farm of flowering coffee trees in Jamaica&apos;s wild eastern mountains, where his father grew the gourmet arabica beans before him. &quot;It&apos;s tough and ... 
 Read more 
Climate change hurts coffee revenue
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 By Monitor Correspondent (email the author) Coffee exports have earned the country about TShs1 trillion ($725.2 billion) in the past six years, but future prospects may be dimmed by the recent drought. The income was derived from direct coffee exports ... 
 Read more 
Brazil Coffee Exports Fall 4.3% in February, Ministry Says
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Coffee exports from Brazil, the world’s largest producer and exporter, declined 4.3 percent in February from a year earlier, Brazil’s Trade Ministry said. Exports fell to 1.99 million bags from 2.08 million bags a year earlier, the ministry ... 
 Read more 
International Coffee Organization: Trade Statistics
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 In the twelve months ending January 2012, exports of Arabica totalled 65.96 million bags compared to 66.18 million bags last year; whereas Robusta exports amounted to 37.53 million bags compared to 31.98 million bags. 
 Read more 
Indonesia Coffee Output to Rise 38% in 2012-13, Volcafe Says
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 Coffee production in Indonesia, the world’s third-largest producer of the robusta variety, will jump 38 percent in the season starting in April, according to Volcafe, the coffee unit of ED&amp;F Man Holdings Ltd. Production will total 9.1 million ... 
 Read more 
Three Commodity ETFs That Have Not Surged
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 In that year, Brazil produced 48.5 million bags of Arabica coffee, while this year’s harvest could see close to 55 million bags, potentially putting more pressure on prices. Beyond Brazil, exports could also be surging from the second-biggest ... 
 Read more 
Credit Suisse revises down coffee forecasts
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 ... market to a growing consensus among investors that the 2012-13 Brazil coffee crop will probably ease market tightness, as 2012 is an on-year for Brazilian arabica coffee plants. This is the year of the large harvest in the coffee trees ... 
 Read more 
Starbucks&apos; thirst for Yunnan coffee growing
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 The new joint venture will be controlled by Starbucks and will focus on buying and exporting high-quality arabica coffee beans grown in Yunnan. It will also operate multiple dry mills around the province. The Starbucks-Ai Ni alliance deepens the coffee ... 
 Read more 
Tanzania: Boon Awaits Coffee Growers
 Tuesday 7th February, 2012 
 He said the price of Arabica coffee is coordinated by the New York &apos;C&apos; market while that of Robusta is coordinated by the London International Future Exchange market. &quot;Our strategy is to ensure that farmers receive 80 per cent of the price on the world ... 
 Read more 
Robusta Shipments From Indonesia&apos;s Sumatra Fall 28% in January
 Friday 3rd February, 2012 
 3 (Bloomberg) -- Coffee-bean exports from Indonesia&apos;s main growing regions on southern Sumatra fell 28 percent in January from a month earlier because of lower output. Shipments from Lampung, Bengkulu and South Sumatra provinces, which mostly grow ... 
 Read more 
Robusta Shipments From Indonesia’s Sumatra Fall 28% in January
 Friday 3rd February, 2012 
 Sales were 17,957.5 tons in January last year. Falling supplies from the world’s third-largest grower may help to support robusta prices, which have declined about 19 percent in London in the past year on concern the European debt crisis may ... 
 Read more 
Coffee Futures Rebound From 13-month Low in NY; Sugar Declines
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 In London, robusta-coffee futures for March delivery fell 1 percent to $1800 a metric ton on NYSE Liffe. The price dropped for the sixth straight session, the longest slump since early September. Raw-sugar futures for March delivery declined 0.5 ... 
 Read more 
Some &apos;at-home baristas&apos; see single-cup coffee as costly, Mintel
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 While single-cup coffee made using pods is still a popular choice among devotees of the drink in the developed world, recent Mintel research suggests that cost may be a barrier to further uptake of the technology. 
 Read more 
Coffee exports pick up in Jan after three-month lull
 Wednesday 1st February, 2012 
 According to Coffee Board data, exports of robusta variety coffee were higher at 8,319 tonnes in January in comparison to 7,450 tonnes in the year-ago period, but arabica and instant coffee shipments were down. Arabica exports fell to 5,482 tonnes in ... 
 Read more 
Kenyan Average Coffee Price Falls 15% as Supplies Increase
 Wednesday 1st February, 2012 
 Feb. 1 (Bloomberg) -- Kenyan coffee prices fell 15 percent at an auction yesterday as supplies increased and as demand was subdued, the Nairobi Coffee Exchange said. The average price for all coffee sold dropped to $280.87 a 50-kilogram (110 ... 
 Read more 
Coffee exports down 7.5% in Oct-Jan
 Wednesday 1st February, 2012 
 According to Coffee Board statistics as of January 31, arabica parchment constituted 4121 tonnes (last year&apos;s exports stood at 5723 tonnes), arabica cherry 1361 tonnes (1469 tonnes), robusta parchment 670 tonnes (2104 tonnes) and robusta cherry 7649 ... 
 Read more 
Price hikes brewing for Starbucks drinkers
 Wednesday 1st February, 2012 
 Commodity prices, especially for agricultural commodities, surged to multi-year highs in 2010. Raw sugar futures were at a 30-year high, while the price of arabica beans touched a 14-year high in New York in May as heavy rain caused by the La Nina weather ... 
 Read more 
Vietnam&apos;s coffee trading resumes at a slow pace
 Wednesday 1st February, 2012 
 Farmers finished harvesting the 2011/12 crop early this month, and only a small volume of arabica beans are now under work. Robusta beans fell to 37 million dong ($1763) a tonne in Daklak on Tuesday from 37.4 million dong before Tet, ... 
 Read more 
Brazil Coffee Growers Hoard Supply to Boost Price, Tristao Says
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 Coffee has plunged 25 percent in the past five months in New York partly because of expectation growers in Brazil, the world’s largest producer, will reap a record crop. The price of Brazilian coffee currently exceeds that of countries in ... 
 Read more 
Starbucks sees 10% rise in profit
 Friday 27th January, 2012 
 US coffee chain Starbucks posts a 10% rise in net profits for the three months to 1 January 2012, benefiting from new stores and new products. 
 Read more 
Fil-Am investor eyes 10000-hectare coffee plantation in Bukidnon
 Friday 27th January, 2012 
 He also vouched for Arabica coffee&apos;s ready market as 80 percent of the world drinks Arabica coffee. Arabica coffee, he said, is the most expensive coffee variety. It is aromatic and has milder caffeine content compared to the Robusta variety common in ... 
 Read more 
Lower Vietnam Robusta Sales May Lift Brazil’s Prices, Cepea Says
 Thursday 26th January, 2012 
 Jan. 26 (Bloomberg) -- Robusta coffee prices in Brazil, the world’s second-largest producer of the variety after Vietnam, may get a boost this year as farmers in the Asian nation slow sales, according to Cepea, a University of Sao Paulo research group. 
 Read more 
Mexico Coffee Crop Is Escaping Record Drought, Group Says
 Thursday 26th January, 2012 
 Jan. 26 (Bloomberg) -- Mexico’s coffee crop is escaping the country’s worst drought, with production expected to increase about 8 percent this crop year, the head of the country’s coffee association said. “We still have our original ... 
 Read more 
Brazil brewing more coffee as beans get tastier -- ABIC
 Wednesday 25th January, 2012 
 Firm prices all year due to a global shortage of good quality arabicas pushed coffee export revenues in 2011 up by more than ... ahead of the global average of 1.5%-2% a year. New York ICE arabica futures have been trading at more than $2 a pound, nearly ... 
 Read more 
Kenya coffee prices rise at latest sale
 Wednesday 25th January, 2012 
 NAIROBI (Reuters) - The top price for Kenyan benchmark grade AA coffee jumped to $526 per 50-kg bag at this ... it saw coffee output rising 6 percent in the 2011/12 (Oct-Sept) crop year to 54,000 tonnes. The NCE said 23,369 bags were offered ... 
 Read more 
Tanzania: Lessons From Coffee Tasting Competition
 Wednesday 25th January, 2012 
 Tanzania&apos;s coffee production increased to about 917,000 bags during last season, a six-year highest record, compared to 810,000 bags recorded during the previous season. An official of one of Tanzania Coffee Association (TCA) recently said ... 
 Read more 
Tanzania coffee prices rise on higher demand
 Tuesday 24th January, 2012 
 All the robusta coffee offered at the auction was bought ... where the auctions are being held. &quot;We expect prices at our auctions to remain above the terminal market heading to February-March, since there will be a shortage of coffee harvests ... 
 Read more 
To cut imports, more coffee farms eyed
 Sunday 22nd January, 2012 
 If all stakeholders work together, they can plant 4 million seedlings of the Arabica variety alone this year, according to Pacita Juan of Philippine Coffee Board (PCB). A total of 8 million seedlings of different varieties, if planted, would help ease ... 
 Read more 
US workers spend $1000 a year on coffee, $2000 a year on lunch
 Sunday 22nd January, 2012 
 You know that, for the sake of your budget, you should kick the ever-more-expensive Coffee habit. And, for that matter, that you should make yourself a brown-bagged BLT to bring to work rather than getting Chipotle for the third time this week ... 
 Read more 
Starbucks closing in on retail deal with Tata Coffee
 Friday 20th January, 2012 
 Madurai is in the southern India state of Tamil Nadu, near where they also have plantations. Tata coffee exports 60 percent of its instant coffee to Russia and the rest to Singapore and Japan. Instant coffee division contributes about 50 percent to its ... 
 Read more 
DJ Vietnam 11-12 Coffee Exports -13% On Year At 1 Mln Tons -Vicofa
 Thursday 19th January, 2012 
 LONDON (Dow Jones)--Vietnam&apos;s coffee exports in the 2011-12 crop year will likely fall 13% from the previous crop year, to 1 million metric tons, as farmers hold back harvested beans in anticipation of higher domestic prices, traders and industry officials ... 
 Read more 
Scope for developing coffee industry in India, says Montek
 Thursday 19th January, 2012 
 Coffee production in India is expected to rise by about 7 per cent to 5.4 million bags (about 3,24,00 tonnes) in 2011-12 coffee year, according to a recent report by the International Coffee Organisation (ICO). 
 Read more 
Uganda coffee exports to rise 7 pct in January
 Thursday 19th January, 2012 
 Ranked as one of Africa&apos;s leading exporters of the beans, the east African producer mainly cultivates the robusta variety, with earnings from the crop constituting a major source of foreign currency. The source said Uganda was likely to ship 230000 ... 
 Read more 
Uganda Coffee Exports May Rise 6.9% This Month, Authority Says
 Wednesday 18th January, 2012 
 The country&apos;s coffee exports in the 12 months through September may rise to 3.3 million bags, from 3.15 million bags in 2010-11, because of a bigger crop, the authority said on Oct. 10 without providing production forecasts. 
 Read more 
Indonesia&apos;s coffee exports up 14 percent in 2012
 Tuesday 17th January, 2012 
 Coffee exports from Indonesia, the world&apos;s third-largest producer, are likely to climb 14.3 percent to 400000 tonnes this year, the Indonesia Coffee Exporters and Industries Association (AEKI) said on Tuesday.&quot;It is difficult to predict our coffee ... 
 Read more 
Coffee production in Colombia shrinks
 Tuesday 17th January, 2012 
 Coffee production in Colombia, the world&apos;s second-largest supplier of arabica beans after Brazil, shrank to a 35-year low after excess rainfall, diseases and a lack of sunshine curbed yields. The harvest tumbled 12 percent to 7.81 million bags in 2011, ... 
 Read more 
Coffee Crop in Colombia Shrinks to Lowest Level Since 1976
 Tuesday 17th January, 2012 
 Arabica coffee for March delivery slid 0.1 percent to $2.2500 a pound at 9:35 a.m. on ICE Futures U.S. in New York, after earlier gaining as much as 1.8 percent. Export Decline Exports from Colombia declined 1.2 percent to 7.73 million bags in ... 
 Read more 
Kenyan 2010-11 Coffee Output Fell 13% on Drought, Group Says
 Tuesday 17th January, 2012 
 Kenya&apos;s coffee production declined 13 percent in the 2010-11 season after drought cut yields, a coffee traders&apos;group said. Output in the 12 months to Sept. 30 fell to 36629 metric tons from 42096 tons a year earlier, Isaac Muchomba, an official at the ... 
 Read more 
Cameroon: Coffee Production Dropped in 2011
 Tuesday 17th January, 2012 
 Despite good performance on the international market, disease and climate change have their grips on coffee plants. One of the cash crops that climbed the production ladder in the 60s and 70s was coffee. In the past 21 years coffee production is ... 
 Read more 
Vietnam Coffee Farmers Curb Pre-Tet Sales to Push Price Higher
 Tuesday 17th January, 2012 
 The withholding of the beans used to make instant drinks may help boost prices that tumbled 14 percent ... Dak Lak province-based October Coffee, Cocoa Co. “I would expect only about a third of the crop to be sold by Tet, while it was about ... 
 Read more 
Vietnam Coffee-Trade slowing before holidays, premiums narrow
 Tuesday 17th January, 2012 
 HANOI Jan 17 (Reuters) - Premiums of Vietnamese coffee prices to London futures narrowed in ... The rise tracked a gain in London&apos;s robusta futures market, where the March contract ended $22, or 1.2 percent, higher at $1,854 a tonne on Monday. 
 Read more 
Vietnam Coffee-Trade slowing before holidays, premiums narrow
 Tuesday 17th January, 2012 
 HANOI Jan 17 (Reuters) - Premiums of Vietnamese coffee prices to London futures narrowed in recent ... beans for several weeks until their loading,&quot; he said. On Tuesday robusta beans rose to between 37.3 million and 37.4 million dong ($1.78 ... 
 Read more 
UPDATE 1-ICO raises estimate for 2011/12 global coffee crop
 Monday 16th January, 2012 
 LONDON Jan 16 (Reuters) - The International Coffee Organization on Monday raised its estimate of the global coffee crop in 2011/12 to 132.4 million 60 kg bags as Ethiopia overtook Colombia as the world&apos;s number three producer. The crop was ... 
 Read more 
Brazil’s Next Coffee Crop May Fall Short of Demand, Broker Says
 Monday 16th January, 2012 
 The next coffee crop in Brazil, the world’s largest producer, may not be enough to meet domestic and export demand even with record production forecast, according to Escritorio Carvalhaes, a Santos, Brazil-based broker. Coffee output in Brazil ... 
 Read more 
Vietnam Coffee Farmers Curb Pre-Tet Sales to Push Price Higher
 Monday 16th January, 2012 
 The March-delivery contract rose as much as 0.9 percent to $1848 per ton on NYSE Liffe, extending last week&apos;s 6.5 percent rally, the biggest weekly climb since the five days to Aug. 12. Vietnamese prices fell to 36000 dong ($1.71) per kilogram on Jan. ... 
 Read more 
It&apos;s the shit
 Sunday 15th January, 2012 
 Unlike coffee exports from countries such as Brazil and Ethiopia, Vietnamese beans are typically used in cheap instant Western coffee, which earns scant international commendation. His country, he declares, needs to market a trendy style of coffee ... 
 Read more 
Liberian cocoa and coffee farmers to benefit from UN financing
 Wednesday 11th January, 2012 
 The United Nations rural development arm is to provide a $24.9 million loan to Liberia to improve the West African country’s cocoa and coffee production in an effort to alleviate poverty among rural communities recovering from the effects of past conflicts. 
 Read more 
Sudan to Launch $1 Billion Sugar Plant, Eyes Exports from 2014
 Sunday 4th March, 2012 
 Sudan plans to increase sugar production by 450000 tonnes annually with the help of a $1 billion plant, aiming to end dependency on imports and start exporting sugar by 2014, officials and executives said. Boosting sugar production is a top priority as ... 
 Read more 
Central America Poised to Fill Sugar Gap
 Sunday 4th March, 2012 
 By JEAN GUERRERO MEXICO CITY—Central America&apos;s top sugar-growing countries are poised to fill a gap in production after drought damaged Mexico&apos;s sugar-cane fields. The assist from Central America is likely to keep sugar futures prices stable in the ... 
 Read more 
Kenya&apos;s 2012 sugar output forecast to rise 13 percent
 Sunday 4th March, 2012 
 Kenya&apos;s 2012 sugar production is forecast to rise 13 percent to a potential record high buoyed by expected good weather and bigger factory crushing capacity, the industry regulator said. The east African nation of 39 million people has an annual sugar ... 
 Read more 
Thailand sees steady growth in sugar output
 Sunday 4th March, 2012 
 Thai sugar production is forecast to rise by around 5 percent per year over the next five years and reach 12 million tonnes by around 2017, a senior official at the Office of Cane and Sugar Board (OCSB) said on Tuesday.&quot;We aim to have steady growth of ... 
 Read more 
Sugar leaders draw timeline to finalize action plans
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 In its position paper, NFSP pushed for the establishment of sugarcane ecozones not only to secure the country&apos;s self-sufficiency in sugar but also to promote production and use of organic fertilizer. “Organic fertilizers not only enrich the quality of ... 
 Read more 
300000 tonnes less
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Salendra Naidu at his aunt Nilu Prasad&apos;s cane farm which was damaged by the recent flood at Drasa in Lautoka. Picture: BALJEET SINGH Cane Growers Council acting chief executive officer Sundresh Chetty expects cane production to fall by 300000 tonnes ... 
 Read more 
Rabobank Report: The Future of Ethanol
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Indeed, if world sugar prices continue to decline in 2012, Brazilian millers may well react by increasing the share of cane that is milled for ethanol production. The most important short and medium term challenge for the Brazilian cane industry ... 
 Read more 
ICE March sugar deliveries highest in 10 months
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 March 1 (Reuters) - The sugar delivered at the expiration of the March raw sugar contract reached 17325 lots or 880151 tonnes, the biggest amount brought to the board since the May sugar contract expired in 2011, ICE Futures US data showed on Thursday. 
 Read more 
Kenya 2012 sugar production forecast to rise 13 pct
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 NAIROBI (Reuters) - Kenya&apos;s 2012 sugar production is forecast to rise 13 percent to a potential record high buoyed by expected good weather and bigger factory crushing capacity, the industry regulator said. The east African nation of 39 million people ... 
 Read more 
ICE sugar eases, big delivery reported
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Arabica coffee futures firmed in light volumes with upside potential limited by expectations of a big crop in Brazil, and cocoa edged up in light volumes during a seasonal lull in cocoa exports between its main crop and mid crop. 
 Read more 
ICE sugar eases, big delivery reported
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 That would be the biggest delivery since the May contract expiry in 2011. Arabica coffee futures firmed in light volumes with upside potential limited by expectations of a big crop in Brazil, and cocoa edged up in light volumes during a seasonal lull ... 
 Read more 
DJ India Oct-Feb Sugar Output Up 15% At 18.65 Mln Tons -Trade Body
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 ... Commodities News via Comtex) -- India&apos;s sugar output in the first five months this marketing year rose 15% to 18.65 million metric tons, mainly due to increased cane crushing in key growing regions, the Indian Sugar Mills Association said Thursday. 
 Read more 
Kazakhstan plans to raise sugar beet production 5-fold by 2020
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Kazakhstan plans to raise its production of sugar beets to an annual 960000 metric tons from 200000 metric tons by 2020 to help shrink the dependence on imported sugar. The increase will be achieved by increasing the land under cultivation as well as ... 
 Read more 
What Mystery Disease is Killing Thousands in Central America?
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Now, chronic kidney disease is claiming the lives of many of these young workers -- to the extent that some are labeling the condition&quot;Sugar Cane Kidney Disease&quot;-- and researchers are scrambling to uncover the cause as the death toll steadily rises. 
 Read more 
Sugar stays down
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 &quot;All eyes will be on the spread,&quot;said Pierre Sebag of London-based consultancy Sugar K. ICE Futures US said open interest in the March contract stood at 18371 lots as of Tuesday, down 10506 lots from the previous session. That is equivalent to 933290 ... 
 Read more 
Sugar down as March expires, rest mostly off
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 * Sugar trade eyes delivery of 300000-500000 tonnes * London March cocoa options expire * Dollar strength keeps complex on defensive (Adds news on delivery in March contract) By David Brough and Rene Pastor NEW YORK/LONDON, Feb 29 (Reuters) - Raw sugar ... 
 Read more 
Brazil Ethanol Mills Get $2.6 Billion of Loans to Store Fuel
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 Several brief interim governments succeeded after Vargas&apos;s suicide. Juscelino Kubitscheck became president in 1956 and assumed a conciliatory posture towards the political opposition that allowed him to govern without major crises. The economy and ... 
 Read more 
Strong real to push Brazil sugarcane mills to etha
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 Industry likely to shift toward ethanol production for domestic market --Appreciation of Brazilian real this year has largely neutralized rebound in sugar prices SAO PAULO (MarketWatch) -- The appreciation of the Brazilian real this year is ... 
 Read more 
White Sugar Money Managers Double Bets on Rising Prices
 Monday 13th February, 2012 
 Money managers more than doubled their net-long positions, or bets on higher prices, in London white sugar futures and options, according to NYSE Liffe, the derivatives arm of NYSE Euronext. Net-long positions totaled 9,034 futures and options ... 
 Read more 
How to grow sugar cane: Some sweet choices
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 As he pours fresh sugar cane juice through a filter, John Guettler says it&apos;s important not to confuse the plant with what it becomes after processing. “Sugar cane has been demonized in Western cultures because it is turned into sugar,” Guettler, right, ... 
 Read more 
India allows extra sugar exports
 Tuesday 7th February, 2012 
 At 1346 GMT, raw sugar futures for March fell 1 cent to 24.22 cents a lb on Tuesday. London March white sugar futures were down 0.1 percent to $641.8 per tonne. Abinash Verma, director-general of the Indian Sugar Mills Association, a producers&apos;body, ... 
 Read more 
Sugar surplus expected to shrink by 43%
 Tuesday 7th February, 2012 
 Raw sugar traded in New York is up 4.9 per cent this year after last year&apos;s decline. The March futures contract was down 0.2 per cent at 24.45 cents a pound at 6:46am London time on ICE Futures US in New York. Sugar usage is also rising due to ... 
 Read more 
UP mills get less sugar despite paying more for cane
 Tuesday 7th February, 2012 
 Low sugar recoveries are adding to the woes of sugar mills in Uttar Pradesh (UP), already battling the effects of a record cane price hike announced by the State Government ahead of the Assembly elections. The top sugar combines in UP have crushed more ... 
 Read more 
Sugar May Fall to 18 Cents a Pound This Year, Macquarie Says
 Monday 6th February, 2012 
 Feb. 5 (Bloomberg) -- Sugar prices may fall to as low as 18 cents a pound this year as a forecast surplus for the 2011-12 season becomes available, according to Macquarie Group Ltd. Sugar supplies are set to outpace demand by 9 million metric ... 
 Read more 
Dubai sugar refinery operates start-stop strategy
 Sunday 5th February, 2012 
 &quot;Whenever the silos get filled, we stop. And when the silo becomes almost empty, then we start again.&quot;  Al-Khaleej Sugar exports to some 40 countries.  Al-Ghurair said offers of Indian sugars were now undercutting Brazilian sugars by around $ ... 
 Read more 
Sugar Market May Develop a Second Surplus Next Season, Olam Says
 Sunday 5th February, 2012 
 Feb. 5 (Bloomberg) -- Sugar production may outpace demand by as much as 8 million metric tons next season, a second consecutive surplus that could help send prices down further, according to commodities trader Olam International Ltd. Output will ... 
 Read more 
DJ Indian Govt To Approve Extra Sugar Exports
 Sunday 5th February, 2012 
 DUBAI, Feb 05, 2012 (Dow Jones Commodities News via Comtex ... But he cautioned that this will depend on the level of international sugar prices compared with domestic prices. &quot;Will the international prices continue to give us the return that we ... 
 Read more 
Egypt&apos;s Nile Sugar to up capacity in 2013: CEO
 Sunday 5th February, 2012 
 By Maha El Dahan DUBAI (Reuters) - Egyptian refiner Nile Sugar plans to increase its crushing capacity by over 40 percent next year to help meet strong demand in the country, its chief executive said on Sunday. Egypt produces around 2 million tonnes of ... 
 Read more 
Indian miller says conditions favour sugar export approval
 Sunday 5th February, 2012 
 Verma said India, the world&apos;s number 2 sugar producer after Brazil, has a sugar surplus of 3-4 million tonnes available for export in 2011/12. He reiterated his view that India, the world&apos;s largest sugar consumer, would produce 26 million tonnes of ... 
 Read more 
Sugar Should Be Regulated As Toxin, Researchers Say
 Friday 3rd February, 2012 
 Added sugar, more so than the fructose in fiber-rich fruit, hits the liver more directly and can cause more damage — in laboratory rodents ... After all, high-fructose corn syrup is ubiquitous in food in part because it is so cheap and serves as a ... 
 Read more 
The Little Economy That Could
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 To the contrary: the British economist James Meade (who would go on to win a Nobel Prize) concluded that&quot;the outlook for peaceful development is poor&quot;because of its high population density, reliance on a single crop (sugar cane), and ethnic conflict. 
 Read more 
Russia May Produce 4 Million Tons of Sugar, Ros Agro Says
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 (Updates with estimate for raw-sugar imports in third paragraph.) Feb. 2 (Bloomberg) -- Russian production of sugar from beets may fall to 4 million metric tons in the coming marketing year, said Maxim Basov, chief executive officer of Ros Agro Plc. 
 Read more 
EU Preferential Sugar Imports Rose 15% So Far, Czarnikow Says
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 Czarnikow Sugar Futures Ltd. The 27-nation bloc had issued licenses to import 611,000 metric tons of the sweetener as of the second week of January, the London-based company said in a report e-mailed today. That compares with 533,000 tons a year ... 
 Read more 
Brazilian Sugar Is Destined for Middle East, Vessel Data Shows
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 Santos is Brazil&apos;s biggest port. White, or refined, sugar for March delivery dropped 0.2 percent to $628.50 a ton by 12:42 pm on NYSE Liffe in London. Raw sugar for March delivery slid 0.4 percent to 23.51 cents a pound on ICE Futures US in New York. 
 Read more 
Thai Sugar Output Drops 1.9% in First 78 Days of Season
 Wednesday 1st February, 2012 
 Thailand&apos;s sugar production declined 1.9 percent to 4.57 million metric tons in the first 78 days of the crushing season that began on Nov. 15, according to data from the Office of Cane and Sugar Board as of Jan. 31. The 2011-2012 season began two ... 
 Read more 
ECC approves sugar export to ward off glut
 Wednesday 1st February, 2012 
 ... the expected surplus was estimated at 1.5 million tons at the end of the current season. - File photo ISLAMABAD: After lifting the almost entire sugarcane stocks, the government has allowed export of 100000 tons of sugar to improve sugar industry&apos;s ... 
 Read more 
Should sugar be regulated like alcohol?
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 Editor&apos;s note: Laura Schmidt and her colleagues, Robert Lustig and Claire Brindis, are the authors of &quot;The toxic truth about sugar.&quot; To read the full commentary, visit the science journal Nature. I am a medical sociologist, which means I study ... 
 Read more 
Beet lobby beats all others in Congress
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 EUCLID, Minn. - Paul Rutherford stared over his tilled fields of sugar beets, his gaze focused on hundreds of acres in the midst of harvest. As heavy machinery plucked beets from the ground, they emerged a dull shade of tan. 
 Read more 
Al Khaleej Dubai refinery buys Indian sugar
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 Raja said that due to export selling pressure, from India the local or free on board price of low-quality white sugar had dropped recently by around $50 per tonne to ICE raw sugar futures plus $20 per tonne. Raja said that the white sugar premium, ... 
 Read more 
Brazil Will Favor Sugar at 21 Cents, Morgan Stanley Says
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 Jan. 31 (Bloomberg) -- Sugar millers in Brazil, the world’s largest producer, will favor production of sugar over ethanol with prices at or above 21 cents a pound, Morgan Stanley said. Producers in the South American country can make either ... 
 Read more 
End of beet quota would harm English growers
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 Increases in sugar beet productivity and higher world sugar prices had combined to make beet sugar competitive against cane sugar imports, opening up the opportunity for EU producers to fill the gap, he suggested. But for the UK beet industry to take ... 
 Read more 
Centre hikes levy sugar prices
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 However, it is being sold at about Rs 35 per kg in the retail market. Meanwhile, the government may also allow an additional one million tons of sugar exports in the 2011-12 marketing year, which started in October, to improve cash flows for mills and ... 
 Read more 
Other groups not rejecting Sugar Act
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 National Federation of Sugarcane Planters president, Enrique Rojas, Sunday said the NFSP stand is that there is no need for the Sugar Act to address the concerns of the sugar industry. The NFSP has instead come up with a position paper on measures to ... 
 Read more 
Sugar cane farmers hit again
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 Heavy rain that&apos;s soaked the northern New South Wales coastline over the past week has not only flooded rivers and cut off communities, but also hit sugar cane farmers for a second year in a row. Many who face losing their crops are appealing for ... 
 Read more 
Government may allow further export of 1 mn tonnes of sugar this year
 Monday 30th January, 2012 
 NEW DELHI: The government may allow an additional one million tonnes of sugar exports in the 2011-12 marketing year, which started in October, to improve cash flows for mills and enable timely payment to cane farmers. With estimates of sugar ... 
 Read more 
Sugar decontrol: We need policy action, not committees
 Sunday 29th January, 2012 
 States set the minimum price that should be paid to farmers growing sugarcane. Before elections, incumbent governments try to sweeten the deal for farmers by pushing for high cane rates. In years of glut, when sugar prices fall, mills delay payments. 
 Read more 
DAP asks if sugar subsidy hike fattens politically-linked firms
 Sunday 29th January, 2012 
 Sugar futures fell by 27 per cent last year, the most in a decade after a glut emerged following three consecutive annual shortages. But traders are expecting this year&apos;s harvest to shrink, with prices rising as much as 12 per cent to US$27 per hundred ... 
 Read more 
Sugar beet &apos;could become one of the country&apos;s most important food and energy ...
 Sunday 29th January, 2012 
 Sugar beet could become one of the country&apos;s most important food and energy crops, growers were told at a major industry conference. To send a link to this page to a friend, simply enter their email address below. The message will include the name and ... 
 Read more 
Maharashtra confirms fall in sugar prod estimate
 Friday 27th January, 2012 
 &quot;Earlier, we had estimated that the sugar cane production would be 825 lakh tonnes while the sugar production 93 lakh tonnes. We we held a series of meeting with our officials and a detailed assessment of the field level situation and revised our ... 
 Read more 
Sugar subsidy balloons to 54 sen
 Friday 27th January, 2012 
 Malaysia’s sugar imports, however, are minimal — it buys some three million tonnes of sugar every three years — and analysts said the subsidy increase was driven by the government’s desire to avoid stoking already low inflation ahead of a ... 
 Read more 
Ghanaian Govt Signs Agreement With Companies To Revive Cotton Industry
 Monday 5th March, 2012 
 ACCRA, March 5 (BERNAMA-NNN-GNA) -- The Ghanaian government&apos;s commitment to revive the cotton industry has received a boost after three companies signed a business agreement with the assurance to cotton farmers that their labour and investment will ... 
 Read more 
Lacklustre business witnessed on cotton market
 Monday 5th March, 2012 
 According to the Reuters, on Friday, the NY cotton futures ended lower for the third session in a row in the face of a stronger dollar and investor selling, and analysts said the weak tone should persist into next week. Benchmark May cotton on ICE ... 
 Read more 
Global cotton stocks to continue accumulating in 2012/13
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 International Cotton Advisory Committee (ICAC) reported that as 2012 plantings are starting in the northern hemisphere, prices of cotton are much reduced from last year, making competing crops more attractive to farmers. World cotton area is expected ... 
 Read more 
Global cotton production to decline 5% to 25.7 mn tons in 2012: ICAC
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 WASHINGTON (Commodity Online): World cotton acreage is expected ... driven by improving economic growth and lower cotton prices. Of course, any setback in the global economy could affect this projection. Production will therefore exceed ... 
 Read more 
Power crisis takes toll on spinning mills
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 And, the spinning and ginning mills in the state utilise almost 30 lakh bales of cotton of the total production of 55 lakh bales.&quot;The state government has neither the planning nor the vision to combat this crisis. It has displayed utter callousness in ... 
 Read more 
Cotton rates come too close to the minimum support price
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 But as they are expected to eventually offload the cotton, prices may come down further,&quot; said Hirani. Experts say the farmers in Vidarbha - where most of the cotton is grown - are facing a typical problem of low yields and low prices. 
 Read more 
Cotton ticks down, but shows strong support
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 New York. May cotton futures on ICE are holding above the 10-day moving average of 91.76c/pound, which Penson Futures&apos; Sharon Johnson says could indicate a change in the short-term trend from negative to positive. GDP data in the US and India provide a ... 
 Read more 
Spot rate reduced to Rs 5350 on cotton market
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 The traders were surprised over the slow activity in the cotton market despite the rising trend in the NY cotton futures during last couple of sessions, they said. The ginners did not lower the asking prices to attract the mills and spinners in ... 
 Read more 
Textile exporters criticise hike in power tariff
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 Textile exporters have strongly criticised the massive 39 percent raise in electricity and Rs 4 in petrol prices, saying that it would hit trade and industry hard besides jacking up the graph of inflation further high and demanded a relief package for ... 
 Read more 
New York cotton settles lower
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 Cotton futures settled lower on Wednesday on investor liquidation after the market stalled in its advance while the firm dollar and weak outside markets undermined fibre contracts, analysts said. Benchmark May cotton on ICE Futures US dropped 1.80 ... 
 Read more 
Cotton prices down, but clothing costs won&apos;t be
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 Carter&apos;s made $114 million in 2011, a 22 percent decrease from the $146.5 million it made in 2010. In its fourth quarter, Carter&apos;s made $34.8 million, a slight decrease from the $34.9 million it made for the same period in 2010. High cotton prices were ... 
 Read more 
Drought-weary Texans welcome rains, flowers
 Monday 27th February, 2012 
 Even non-food items like clothing were pushed up by the dry spell, as much of the state&apos;s cotton crop was destroyed. Texas produces 55 percent of the nation&apos;s cotton. &quot;Planting is going on in much of Texas and fields are being prepared ... 
 Read more 
Maximize cotton through planting dates, water efficiency
 Friday 17th February, 2012 
 The first day water is put to cotton seed is the critical day for performance in cool soils, says University of Arizona&apos;s Paul Brown. The metabolic processes associated with early germination are very sensitive to temperature during the first 24-to-48 hours after moisture reaches the seed. If the soil temperature is too cold, these mechanisms get out of whack.


 
 
 
 
 

read more 
 Read more 
Cotton rebounds from USDA-fuelled losses as sentiment improves
 Monday 13th February, 2012 
 Forexpros - Cotton futures rose for the first time in six days on Monday, rebounding from losses ... 
 Read more 
Cotton merchants seek US government support to stem defaults
 Monday 13th February, 2012 
 Cotton prices hit a record $2.27 a pound last March as demand soared ... The price swing crushed margins at apparel companies, commodity firms and textile mills. The Liverpool, U.K.-based International Cotton Association, which sets the rules for most ... 
 Read more 
Cluster-based farming to help cotton farmers of Gujarat
 Monday 13th February, 2012 
 The Gujarat government is experimenting with the concept of cluster-based community farming with focus on the cotton crop. The aim of this idea is to encourage drip irrigation. Sources in the state agriculture department have indicated that the first phase ... 
 Read more 
Textile export to get boom after WTO trade waiver
 Monday 13th February, 2012 
 Cotton prices rose to an all-time high of 229.67 cents a pound in March, and although they have since retreated to a modest 87 cents a pound, it is good news for Hussain, who says he exports 25 percent of his goods to Britain and Germany. There was also a ... 
 Read more 
Short-staple cotton imports may rise to meet denim requirements
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 HIgher Bt cotton crop is also responsible for lower short staple cotton output as Bt crop is of similar length and midium staple. Cotton Advisory Board (CAB) has put India&apos;s cotton production estimate at 34.5 million bales for October-September 2011-2012 season. 
 Read more 
China stockpiles 2.5 mln tons of cotton; may exceed 3 mln tons
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 The government&apos;s program has supported domestic cotton prices. The most actively traded cotton contract on the Zhengzhou Commodity Exchange has risen 11% since the program began. Meanwhile, ICE cotton prices have fallen 14%. However, the upside for ... 
 Read more 
Cotton Costs Cut Into Levi&apos;s Profit
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 Levi Strauss&amp;Co., one of the world’s largest blue-jeans makers, saw a 12 percent dip in its 2011 profit due to sky-high cotton prices that more than doubled in a two-year period. Net income for the fiscal year ending Nov. 27 was $138 million ... 
 Read more 
Cotton market may operate in narrow range till next couple of months
 Tuesday 7th February, 2012 
 Latest position of seed-cotton arrivals and estimated balance crop in the fields strongly support season&apos;s cotton production estimates around 14.5 million local weight bales, estimated to carry average weight around 155 Kgs per bale whereas standard ... 
 Read more 
Australia floods fail to dampen big cotton crop
 Tuesday 7th February, 2012 
 New York cotton futures settled lower in the last session, awaiting release of the US Agriculture Department&apos;s monthly supply/demand report on Thursday. Benchmark March cotton on ICE Futures US slipped 0.03 cent to finish at 96.31 cents per lb. 
 Read more 
Australians Flee Homes as Floods Threaten to Engulf Parts of the Northeast
 Monday 6th February, 2012 
 The deluge may damage as much as 10 percent of the cotton crop in Australia, the world’s third- biggest shipper, according to Olam International Ltd. “The next week will be quite important to see how high the water gets,” Richard Haire ... 
 Read more 
Cotton crops in NSW ruined by flooding rains
 Monday 6th February, 2012 
 NSW cotton producers think they&apos;ve lost anything between 10 to 100 per cent of their crop in the floods. Joe Robinson is surrounded by water from the Mehi River, on his farm west of Moree. &quot;Ten days of overcast weather and it can&apos;t produce carbohydrate so ... 
 Read more 
Cotton arrival up by 22.61pc to 13.615 million bales
 Saturday 4th February, 2012 
 KARACHI: Cotton production in the country has recorded a significant increase of 22.61 percent to more than 13.615 million bales till January 31, 2012, despite a decline of 30.33 percent in Sindh due to floods. According to a consolidated statement of ... 
 Read more 
DJ US Cotton Export Sales Cancellations Hint At Unraveling Demand
 Friday 3rd February, 2012 
 --It is the largest net cancellation in five months --Demand for cotton is expected to be lower in
2011-12 --Shipments rose 83% on week By Leslie Josephs Of DOW JONES NEWSWIRES NEW YORK (Dow
Jones)--The U.S.... 
 Read more 
China&apos;s Cotton Planting Area Would Decrease Substantially 2012
 Friday 3rd February, 2012 
 Domestic growers&apos;planting enthusiasm has been chilled greatly, mainly due to the depressed purchase price of unginned cotton and the rising planting cost in 2011, according to CCM International&apos;s January Issue of Seed China News. 
 Read more 
World cotton mill use may resume increasing in 2012/13
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 International Cotton Advisory Committee reported international cotton prices have steadied at around $1 per pound in January 2012 after decreasing for almost ten months. The main reasons behind this price stabilization seem to be the support provided ... 
 Read more 
Pakistan gets trade waiver for EU
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 Pakistan&apos;s efforts to revive its exports have received a boost after some of its goods were given duty free access to the EU. 
 Read more 
Cotton Prices to Come Under Pressure
 Wednesday 1st February, 2012 
 Also, keep in mind, from the perspective of the farmer, he has several options in crop rotation this year given still relatively high cotton prices than in the last 2-3 years. Assuming all goes well with planting season weather in the Mid-South and Texas ... 
 Read more 
Deferment of cotton procurement through TCP: PCGA terms decision anti ginners
 Wednesday 1st February, 2012 
 He said that millions of cotton growers are suffering from huge financial losses due to the monopoly of textile sector. He added that they were being fleeced by the only buyer, which had made a cartel to keep cotton prices at the lowest ebb. 
 Read more 
One million bales of cotton: MoC, MoF oppose procurement from ginners
 Monday 30th January, 2012 
 The Ministry of Commerce and the Ministry of Finance have reportedly opposed procurement of one million bales of cotton from ginners, arguing that market forces should be allowed to determine cotton prices in the country, sources close to the Textile ... 
 Read more 
Bayer CropScience&apos;s TwinLink cotton technology receives full authorization in ...
 Saturday 28th January, 2012 
 When commercialized, TwinLink technology will be offered to US cotton growers as a stack with GlyTol, the company&apos;s proprietary glyphosate tolerance technology. This stacked product will be the industry&apos;s first dual-gene herbicide tolerance, ... 
 Read more 
DJ Little Change Expected In West-Texas Cotton Acres In 2012
 Friday 27th January, 2012 
 --Insurance payouts for unusable crops are likely to be high again this season --West Texas farmers
have few alternative crops for dry soil --Dry weather raises uncertainty over U.S.... 
 Read more 
U.S. Organic Cotton Acreage Continues to Grow, Survey Shows
 Thursday 26th January, 2012 
 26, 2012 /PRNewswire-USNewswire/ -- The US organic cotton market continues to grow, encouraged by consumer demand, price premiums, and regulatory shifts that will ease marketing restrictions for organic cotton products, according to the 2010 and ... 
 Read more 
Textile exports down by 19.2 per cent YoY
 Wednesday 25th January, 2012 
 Going forward, we believe the materialisation of the GSP plus status (expected to be finalised by end of February – with Bangladesh now lifting the objection) can aid textile exports in the future, said Bilal Qamar at JS. Cotton prices outlook: ... 
 Read more 
Big summer crop would prefer sun to rain
 Wednesday 25th January, 2012 
 A very large summer crop is on the cards if the weather conditions are right. Estimates show it could be on of the biggest crops for at least 10 years. That is if the rain holds off. Summer crop sowings are estimated at 660,000 ha (excluding rice) compared ... 
 Read more 
Global economics can trump cotton fundamentals
 Tuesday 24th January, 2012 
 Over the last few years, factors like liquidity injections, banking crises and world economic troubles have pushed prices into trading ranges far beyond what fundamentals would suggest.
read more 
 Read more 
India Cuts Cotton Production Estimate as Disease Hurts Crop
 Tuesday 24th January, 2012 
 Maharashtra and Andhra Pradesh are the second- and third-largest growers after Gujarat. Indian cotton prices, which climbed to a record 63,000 rupees ($1,260) per candy (356 kilograms) in February last year, have fallen to 36,500 rupees as of ... 
 Read more 
Sums don&apos;t add up for cotton, farmers warn Karimov
 Tuesday 24th January, 2012 
 Islam Karimov says that cotton revenues in 2011 were US$100 million short of the planned for 2011, and blamed the loss on farmers who he said had failed to fulfil the plan. Cotton producers have told Karimov to do the sums again… 
 Read more 
Cotton crops trialed in north eastern NSW
 Monday 23rd January, 2012 
 But high rainfall and hot temperatures are too tempting for dryland cotton growers, who say the region provides ideal growing conditions. Agronomist with Cotton Seed Distributors Bob Ford says the biggest concern is too much rain, particularly around ... 
 Read more 
Pakistan hit by growing trade deficit
 Sunday 22nd January, 2012 
 The ongoing domestic energy crisis and low productivity are also responsible for decline in exports.” Exports put up a good show in fiscal year-2011 when the world wide commodity prices — including cotton — were ruling high and Pakistani textiles had ... 
 Read more 
New varieties, better weather may help cotton rebound in 2012
 Sunday 22nd January, 2012 
 2011 was not a year for the faint of heart in much of the Cotton Belt. Justin Cariker had to replant 1,100 acres of cotton, something that hadn’t happened on his farm in many years. But Cariker believes current prices and new varieties could help cotton ... 
 Read more 
Textile, clothing exports dip 20pc
 Friday 20th January, 2012 
 The only area, where some impressive growth was recorded was in export of yarn other than cotton yarn and tents during the month under review over last year. Last year, textile and clothing exports reached $15 billion, mainly driven by rise in cotton ... 
 Read more 
Cotton output heading towards record level
 Thursday 19th January, 2012 
 The possible cotton output in record numbers in Pakistan this year will be because of larger acreage, better inputs applied by the growers and record high prices received by the farmers last season (2010-2011). It may be remembered that a very high ... 
 Read more 
India&apos;s exploited child cotton workers
 Thursday 19th January, 2012 
 Child labour has been reported in all the major cotton growing countries - China, India, Pakistan, Brazil, Uzbekistan and Turkey. In response to the BBC findings in Gujarat, the British government said businesses were encouraged to remain vigilant ... 
 Read more 
19 percent increase in 2011-12 cotton arrivals
 Wednesday 18th January, 2012 
 Despite earlier apprehensions of low cotton production during 2011-12 cotton season in Pakistan due to damage to cotton crop in lower Sindh by heavy rains and floods, the Pakistan Cotton Ginners Association has reported a 19 percent increase in cotton ... 
 Read more 
Tanzania: Cotton Board Challenges Extension Officers
 Wednesday 18th January, 2012 
 There has been public outcry that TCB and other relevant authorities have not done enough to protect farmers from fraudulent practices and other negative forces that ultimately undermine cotton production and productivity in their respective areas. ... 
 Read more 
Competition for cotton planting area increases in Brazil
 Wednesday 18th January, 2012 
 The profitability is still positive, however, lower than that in the previous crop and similar to the profitability observed for other cultures competitors for planting areas, such as corn and soybean. Therefore, the increase in the cotton planted area ... 
 Read more 
US CPI Preview: Apparel Prices Rise on Wages, Raw Materials
 Tuesday 17th January, 2012 
 March cotton futures on the New York Mercantile Exchange traded at 96.45 cents a pound on Jan. 11 compared with an all-time peak of $2.43 in the benchmark&quot;A Index&quot;in March, 2011. Further price declines are being prevented by the Chinese government ... 
 Read more 
Argentine grains to get rain, but will it be enough?
 Monday 19th March, 2012 
 Rains are expected in Argentina’s main farm areas this week, but climatologists question whether the amount of water to hit the drought-stricken Pampas will be enough to revive key corn and soy crops. Grains-exporting powerhouse Argentina has been hit by ... 
 Read more 
Insight into Korea&apos;s Corn Market Sectors
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 SOUTH KOREA - According to Byong Ryol Min, US Grains Council director in Korea, the United States supplied 77.6 per cent of Korea&apos;s corn imports in 2011. Korea&apos;s total 2011 imports of feed grains and substitutes, including feed wheat, ... 
 Read more 
Russia is producing more soybeans and corn
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 Market experts announced their forecasts at the recent conference Prospects of development of soybean culture in Russia, that soybean production in Russia would grow by a factor of five to about 6 million tons per year in 2016. Soybean export stands ... 
 Read more 
La Salle County leads nation in corn production
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 Despite a slow start to the planting season last year ... year with 186.5 bushels per acre compared to La Salle County’s 177.3 bushels per acre. In soybean production, Knox County’s yield of 61.2 bushels per acre beats McLean’s average of 55.4 ... 
 Read more 
China’s Meat Demand Boon to Corn, Bean Producers
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 
 Read more 
Softer Corn Landing in 2012
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 In total, 93.5 million acres will be planted to corn in the U.S., displacing soybean acres, which Rabo forecasts to fall to a five-year low. A record 5.1 billion bushels of corn will be used in ethanol production in 2011/12 as distillers operate at full ... 
 Read more 
Beef to be pricey for next two years
 Monday 13th February, 2012 
 The soaring feed costs come amid heightened demand for corn to produce ethanol and to meet a growing ... a livestock analyst with KIS Futures in Oklahoma City. Broadbent said worldwide demand for U.S. beef also could increase in the next couple of years ... 
 Read more 
Corn Imports by Korea to Rebound in 2012 as Hog Herd Builds
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 Corn futures for March delivery climbed 0.3 percent to $6.4425 a bushel by 4:21 pm in Seoul on the Chicago Board of Trade and March-delivery wheat rose 0.5 percent to $6.6550 a bushel. “The hog industry is on a recovery path,” Korea Feed&apos;s Kim said ... 
 Read more 
Top Argentine grains company poised for hefty corn losses
 Sunday 5th February, 2012 
 Argentina&apos;s MSU, one of South America&apos;s biggest grain producers, says this season&apos;s sharp drought will slash 30 percent off its corn harvest although soy crops should escape largely unscathed. MSU also farms in neighbouring Brazil, Uruguay and Paraguay ... 
 Read more 
Argentina Corn Crop to Get Significant Rain After Drought
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 Corn for March delivery fell half a cent to $6.4415 a bushel at 12:38 p.m. on the Chicago Board of Trade, while soybeans for March delivery rose 0.1 percent to $12.165 a bushel. Corn output is forecast at 22 million metric tons, with soybean ... 
 Read more 
Southern Brazilian Drought Costs Billions
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 Nothing like a drought to get you thinking about crop insurance. One Brazilian consultancy says main-crop corn yields in Brazil&apos;s southernmost state of Rio Grande do Sul are going to be down 45% from last year, to as low as 48½ bushels per acre. 
 Read more 
Goldman Raises Corn, Soybean, Wheat Estimates on South America
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 and most constructive on soybean prices over the medium term (12 months). We remain bearish wheat prices over the medium term.” For now, corn will have to climb to encourage more planting to rebuild U.S. inventories, Goldman said. Investor ... 
 Read more 
Corn Market Is Entering a Key Marketing Window
 Wednesday 1st February, 2012 
 
 Read more 
Corn-Soybean Planting Decisions and Longer Run Returns
 Wednesday 1st February, 2012 
 Source: University of Illinois farmdoc
 

In many areas of central Illinois, corn-after-corn yields were substantially below corn-after-soybean yields in 2010 and 2011. These yield drags, along with large increases in corn costs, have led some farmers to reevaluate corn-soybean cropping decisions. For land productivities that predominate in Illinois, corn-after-corn and continuous corn usually have higher budgeted returns than soybeans. 


 
 
 
 
 

read more 
 Read more 
U.S. grains rise on fears of export curbs
 Wednesday 1st February, 2012 
 U.S. soybean futures rose 0.46 percent to $12.04-1/2 per bushel ... 3 percent driven by concerns that cold weather in western and eastern Europe may hurt crops and joining gains in other commodities and shares on hopes the euro zone crisis ... 
 Read more 
Corn Prices May Decline in Next Decade on Yields, CBO Says
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 Wheat, soybean and cotton prices paid to farmers by 2022 will also be lower than last year, according to the nonpartisan CBO. The report doesn’t estimate high or low prices for the year, only averages. Corn prices are expected to stay low even ... 
 Read more 
Corn that Fights Drought
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 
 Read more 
Do not panic during euro debt crisis
 Monday 30th January, 2012 
 The corn table on this page and the soybean table on the next page show the extremes of what carryout could do this year as you plug in different yield scenarios for 2012. 
 Read more 
High volatility, acreage war ahead for growers
 Monday 30th January, 2012 
 During AFBF’s session on the outlook for corn, soybeans, wheat and cotton ... Given a significant increase in cotton ending stocks for 2011 and concurrently healthy crops out of Australia, Pakistan and India, corn or wheat likely will grab more southern ... 
 Read more 
Weather Pattern Scary for 2012 Crop
 Tuesday 24th January, 2012 
 He warns that traders at the CBOT may interpret an early pace of planting as a sign of high yields, but warns that may not be the case, “As we all know, an early pace of planting due to dry conditions will not mean a high yields. 
 Read more 
Drought-hit Argentine crops refreshed by downpours
 Tuesday 24th January, 2012 
 * Monday&apos;s storms reach key grains provinces, more seen * Farmers calculate crop losses from&quot;the perfect drought&quot;* Argentina supplies nearly half the world&apos;s soyoil By Hugh Bronstein BUENOS AIRES, Jan 24 (Reuters) - Argentine corn and soy benefited ... 
 Read more 
Corn, soybeans, wheat close strong -- can it continue?
 Tuesday 24th January, 2012 
 Corn ... markets trading higher they gave the wheat pit some spillover support. On the technical side the March contract took out the 50-day moving average on Monday and that added to the positive tone to today’s market. As for price outlooks ... 
 Read more 
What&apos;s the next mover in corn market?
 Monday 23rd January, 2012 
 March corn futures dropped the limit 40 cents the day of the report, and 12 cents the next day. It was not so much that the updated numbers were different from prior USDA estimates, as that they were different than the market expectations. 
 Read more 
Wheat, Corn Rally for Third Day on Optimism Over Demand for U.S. Exports
 Monday 23rd January, 2012 
 Record U.S. production this year and increasing global output may push down corn prices, Bill Biedermann, co-founder of Allendale Inc., said at Allendale’s annual outlook conference in Crystal Lake, Illinois on Jan. 21. Futures may trade ... 
 Read more 
Food-vs.-fuel debate eases; corn harvest up
 Sunday 22nd January, 2012 
 &quot;In terms of the crop mix ... a lot has changed,&quot; said Halcomb, who was one of the 300 or so farmers in Bowling Green on Friday at the Kentucky Commodity Conference. His farms also produce soybeans, wheat and other crops. Walnut Grove has about 3,000 acres ... 
 Read more 
Argentina Corn, Soy Forecasts Cut on ‘Disastrous’ Drought
 Thursday 19th January, 2012 
 The La Nina weather pattern brought excessive heat and dryness to crops in parts of Argentina, Brazil and Mexico over the past two months. Output losses in Argentina include grain planted in October that suffered irreparable damage and corn that ... 
 Read more 
Corn Advances on ‘Irreversible’ Damage to Crops in Argentina
 Thursday 19th January, 2012 
 Rains in Argentina this week that helped ease stress on crops won’t reverse damage from months of hot, dry weather, said Christopher Gadd, an analyst at Macquarie Bank Ltd. in London. The effect on corn is ... the lowest price since Dec ... 
 Read more 
U.S. May Expand Corn Output to Offset Argentina&apos;s Drought Losses, FAO Says
 Thursday 19th January, 2012 
 While Argentina&apos;s corn crop will decline because of a drought, curbing exports from the world&apos;s second-largest shipper, US farmers may expand planting and make up for the potential damage, the United Nations said. The crop may drop to 21.4 million ... 
 Read more 
High corn price drives South African feed makers to wheat
 Thursday 19th January, 2012 
 Corn prices in South Africa have surged after national stocks of the grain dropped 40% as of the end of November, the biggest fall in at least a decade, because of a surge in exports. “This is happening for the first time in roughly 10 years,” he said. 
 Read more 
South Africa Exporting Corn Risks Depleting Domestic Supplies: Commodities
 Wednesday 18th January, 2012 
 Facing a record surplus two years ago after the biggest crop in almost three decades, farm bodies such as Grain SA, which represents 7,000 commercial growers, pushed the government into helping find new corn markets ranging from South Korea to I ... 
 Read more 
Better profit, more Argentine corn hectares
 Wednesday 18th January, 2012 
 Area planted with corn surged in Argentina this autumn, reported Kurt Shultz, US Grains Council director in Latin America, who explained that Argentine farmers will make a better profit from corn than from soybeans for the first time ever. “The estimate ... 
 Read more 
Corn rises for 2nd day, soy dips on LatAm rain f&apos;cast
 Wednesday 18th January, 2012 
 Prices at 0317 GMT Contract Last Change Pct chg Two-day chg MA 30 RSI CBOT wheat 604.25 -0.50 -0.08% +0.33% 617.28 32 CBOT corn 604.75 0.75 +0.12% +0.88% 616.90 30 CBOT soy 1180.00 -3.50 -0.30% +1.88% 1171.80 44 CBOT rice $14.82 $0.01 +0.07% +1.68% ... 
 Read more 
Understanding the Surprise in the USDA Corn Stocks Estimate
 Wednesday 18th January, 2012 
 
 Read more 
Argentine Corn Farmers Prepare for Heatwave as Crops Shrivel
 Tuesday 17th January, 2012 
 Argentina&apos;s “severe” lack of rain over the last few weeks will lower the corn crop yield to about 6 tons per hectare (2.5 acres) from the 6.9 tons initially expected, the Rosario Cereals Exchange said in a Jan. 13 report. Rain on Jan. ... 
 Read more 
US corn, soy rebound as Argentine drought worsens
 Tuesday 17th January, 2012 
 Weeks of unforgiving Southern Hemisphere summer sun have toasted grains fields in the world&apos;s No. 2 corn-exporting country, killing expectations that Argentina might replenish global corn supplies depleted by a lackluster US harvest. ... 
 Read more 
Indonesia: Feed consumption predicted to increase in 2012
 Monday 16th January, 2012 
 For example, the amount of corn imports continues to rise. Based on Indonesian Feed Mill Association data, corn imports in 2009 only about 334 thousand tonnes. Then in 2010 increased to 1.9 million tonnes and in 2011 it is estimated at about 3 million ... 
 Read more 
End of Blenders Tax Credit to Shave 25¢ off Corn Price
 Monday 16th January, 2012 
 
 Read more 
Argentina - Grain farmers desperate for rain
 Monday 16th January, 2012 
 The corn crop is 88% planted, soybeans are 89% planted and wheat is 91% harvested, according to the report. “The situation could improve slightly if there is significant rainfall over the next few days,” the ministry said, “though the probability of ... 
 Read more 
Corn prices plunge on supply info
 Friday 13th January, 2012 
 The price of corn plunged Thursday after the government said corn supplies were higher than traders expected. Investors had bid the price up, expecting tighter supplies because of weather damage to crops. Corn for March delivery fell 40 cents ... 
 Read more 
South Africa’s Surging Corn Prices Drive Livestock Feed Producers to Wheat
 Friday 13th January, 2012 
 South African livestock feed producers are turning to wheat as an alternative to corn for the first time in a decade after prices of the grain surged, the country’s biggest feed company said. While yellow corn is still being used, the ... 
 Read more 
US corn at 3-week low on supply surprise, soy rebounds
 Friday 13th January, 2012 
 Corn loses more ground after falling by its limit * Soy recoups some losses as bargain hunters step in * US paints rosier picture for global grain supply * More rain seen for drought-hit Argentine grains (Adds details, quotes) By Naveen Thukral ... 
 Read more 
Corn Declines After USDA Unexpectedly Increases Global Supply Estimates
 Friday 13th January, 2012 
 March-delivery corn declined as much as 1.1 percent on the Chicago Board of Trade to $6.05 a bushel, the lowest price for a most-active contract since Dec. 21. Futures traded at $6.0975 a bushel at 9:32 am Singapore time, after plunging 6.1 percent ... 
 Read more 
Japan Doubles Corn Purchases From Europe as US
 Thursday 12th January, 2012 
 European corn imports by Japan exceeding 1.5 million tons would be the most ever, said Ippei Araki, an official at the livestock production and feed division of the Ministry of Agriculture, Forestry and Fisheries. Japan imported 10.8 million tons of ... 
 Read more 
EU wheat follows US futures down, awaits USDA report
 Wednesday 11th January, 2012 
 U.S. corn, wheat and soybeans fell on Wednesday ... big in the USDA reports to rise further,&quot; a French futures dealer said. * A fresh fall for the euro provided background support to Paris prices and boosted the prospects for French wheat ... 
 Read more 
US corn up for 2nd day, soy dips after rally
 Tuesday 10th January, 2012 
 The funds may also buy 16000 soyoil contracts, 2600 Kansas City Board of Trade wheat, and sell 600 CBOT soybean contracts. Prices at 0417 GMT Contract Last Change Pct chg Two-day chg MA 30 RSI CBOT wheat 642.25 0.50 +0.08% +2.80% 617.55 58 CBOT corn ... 
 Read more 
Farmland boom alters 40-year Iowa corn yield model
 Tuesday 10th January, 2012 
 In response to surging Midwest farmland prices, researchers in Iowa are overhauling a decades-old formula used to predict corn yields, which will allow farmers and tax officials to more accurately value property. The corn suitability rating (CSR) has ... 
 Read more 
Uncertainty ahead as maize market to dictate wheat prices in 2012 – analyst
 Tuesday 10th January, 2012 
 while a strong yield would push prices lower. As of today, May 12 LIFFE wheat futures are up to £154.50 per tonne driven by fears for developing crops in Brazil and Argentina. 
 Read more 
Scattered rains headed for dry Brazil&apos;s grain areas
 Monday 9th January, 2012 
 Chicago&apos;s CBOT corn futures have rallied about 15 percent and soybeans about 13 percent from their respective mid-December lows. Last week Parana, Rio Grande do Sul and Santa Catarina states lowered their estimates for their grain crops. ... 
 Read more 
Ukraine exports 9.65 million tonnes of grain in 2011-12
 Monday 9th January, 2012 
 Shipments of Barley accounted for 1.87 million tonnes; corn exports were 5.18 million tonnes, according to Korrespondent. These numbers are 2.86 million tonnes higher than the index for the same date of the previous marketing year (July 1, 2010-June 30 ... 
 Read more 
Corn, soy up on Argentine crop concerns; wheat rises
 Monday 9th January, 2012 
 SINGAPORE, Jan 9 (Reuters) - U.S. corn rose 0.7 percent on Monday, while soybeans recovered after two straight sessions of losses with harsh hot and dry weather threatening to curb crop-yields in Argentina, a top global supplier of grains and ... 
 Read more 
Tunisia grain crop hit by floods: officials
 Monday 5th March, 2012 
 TUNIS (Reuters) - The grain harvest in Tunisia will be affected by recent floods, which destroyed about 14,000 hectares of land devoted to the cultivation of cereals, officials said on Sunday. &quot;About 14,000 hectares of grain area was damaged ... 
 Read more 
Iran buys US wheat despite nuclear tensions
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 News of the sale helped limit declines in US wheat futures traded at the Chicago Board of Trade, which were down about 0.5 percent shortly before the market close. The United States has imposed sanctions targeting Iran&apos;s oil trade and central bank ... 
 Read more 
Russian wheat escapes damage
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 Adverse weather prompted Russia and the Ukraine to curb grain exports in July, 2010, resulting in wheat prices skyrocketing. FARM advisers have an opportunity to learn about the management of cereal foliar diseases at workshops across Australia. 
 Read more 
Many factors affect marketing of 2012 US wheat crop
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 “Feed demand and corn prices are pretty much a floor under wheat prices,” he said. The fourth issue affecting 2012 exports is the cold weather situation and its impact on the winter wheat crop in Ukraine and Russia. “If it gets too cold and they don&apos;t ... 
 Read more 
Wheat Declines as Snow May Help Ease Drought Conditions in Parts of U.S.
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 “The better seasonal conditions should translate into an increase in U.S. spring wheat planting,” Luke Mathews ... Exporters in the U.S., the world’s largest soybean grower, sold 285,000 metric tons of the oilseed to China and 120,000 ... 
 Read more 
Wheat Futures Fall as U.S. Northern Plains Snow May Boost Crop Outlook
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Wheat futures slid from a four-week high on speculation that winter storms in the northern US will boost soil moisture before farmers begin planting spring crops in the next two months. Storms in the past two days brought as much as 8 inches (20 ... 
 Read more 
GrainWorld: Which wheat futures are best?
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 The CBOT currently accounts for 74 per cent of the wheat futures volumes in the US and 89 per cent of the options, said Andriesen, noting that liquidity allows for traders to get in and out of a market with ease and allows for a diversity of product. 
 Read more 
Wheat exports to more than double in 2012-13 on record harvest
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 Pointing out that the Indian Government will be under tremendous pressure of inadequate storage facilities for the new wheat crop, the USDA said: “The Government is unlikely to subsidise exports of Government wheat due to local political and World Trade ... 
 Read more 
Wheat Price in Japan May Dip Most Since 2009, Cutting Food Costs
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 Wheat in Chicago retreated after reaching a 29-month high in February 2011, as high prices spurred more planting and boosted a global glut. Wheat futures lost 17.8 percent last year on the Chicago Board of Trade, the biggest decline since 2008. 
 Read more 
Warm Winter Not a Serious Threat to Wheat...Yet
 Tuesday 7th February, 2012 
 This has been especially true in southern Kansas and Oklahoma where wheat pasture has started growing again and where they&apos;ve also benefited from some moisture. But if you&apos;re in the business of growing wheat for grain, the warm temperatures aren&apos;t exactly ... 
 Read more 
U.S. grains mixed on Europe&apos;s cold snap and exports
 Monday 6th February, 2012 
 Wheat hit a 4-1/2 month high in early February as a cold snap threatened Europe&apos;s winter wheat crop and on concerns that Russia could curb exports. Soybeans held gains on Monday after rallying to a three-month high on Friday amid growing export ... 
 Read more 
Wheat output to be record high at 88.31 MT this year
 Friday 3rd February, 2012 
 In the cash crop basket, cotton production is estimated to be a record 34.08 million bales (of 170 kg each), as compared with 33 million bales last year. Jute output is estimated to 11.61 million bales (of 180 kg each) in 2011-12 as against 10.6 ... 
 Read more 
US wheat, corn lower; soybean up
 Friday 3rd February, 2012 
 Grains prices at 0451 GMT Contract Last Change Pct chg Two-day chg MA 30 RSI CBOT wheat 662.25 -0.50 -0.08% -1.78% 635.47 65 CBOT corn 641.75 -1.25 -0.19% -0.04% 631.93 65 CBOT soy 1217.50 0.50 +0.04% +0.19% 1202.58 60 CBOT rice $13.75 $0.11 +0.77% ... 
 Read more 
European wheat falls as weather concerns recede
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 Only a fall in grain prices can change matters or a rise in meat, which is improbable because farmers will want to maintain output,&quot;a dealer said. Prompt feed wheat in Tarragona, Spain&apos;s top grains port, was quoted at up to 225 euros a tonne , up 6 ... 
 Read more 
Wheat Drops on Favorable U.S. Weather Forecast as 4.6% Rally Spurs Selling
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 Mainly favorable conditions are forecast for the soft red winter wheat crop of the east and south Midwest and the Delta, forecaster Telvent DTN said in a report yesterday. Moderate to locally heavy rain and snow is also probable in the next few ... 
 Read more 
US grains pull back after rally on Russia, cold snap
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 March soybean futures fell 0.35 percent to $12.11 per bushel. March corn futures fell 0.27 percent at $6.40-1/4. FUNDAMENTALS * Chinese demand for US soybeans increased this week for shipments through March. Brazilian soybeans were cheaper for shipment ... 
 Read more 
All kinds of wheat output records
 Wednesday 1st February, 2012 
 Deliveries of wheat and other winter grains to Western Australia-based Cooperative Bulk Handling&apos;s facilities will reach a record 15.0 million metric tons, boosting national output figures while a strong export program is on track, Mick Daw, acting ... 
 Read more 
Business Recorder: Weather hits grain exports from Ukraine
 Wednesday 1st February, 2012 
 Severe frosts across most Ukrainian regions have dramatically slowed the pace of grain exports from the country&apos;s Black Sea ports, traders said on Monday. Frosts at about minus 20 degrees Celsius (minus 4 Fahrenheit) make it impossible to load grain ... 
 Read more 
US wheat futures up on fears over Russia export curbs
 Wednesday 1st February, 2012 
 SYDNEY, Feb 1 (Reuters) - U.S. Chicago Board of Trade
Wheat futures rose 1.1 percent in early Asian trade on
concerns that Russia may look to curb exports and as a cold snap
in the Black Sea region and other parts of Europe threats some
of the crop. 
 Read more 
UPDATE 1-EU wheat at 5-mo high on cold spell, possible Russia export curb
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 MILAN Jan 31 (Reuters) - Euronext milling wheat futures&lt;0#BL2:&gt;rose to a fresh 5-month high on Tuesday powered by concerns that a cold snap in Europe may hurt more advanced than normal winter crops and Russia may soon curb exports, traders said. 
 Read more 
Punjab,Haryana eye higher wheat output amid favourable weather
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 Echoing similar views, Haryana is also anticipating a record wheat yield this time due to the favourable winter conditions.&quot;We have projected a wheat yield of 47.35 quintals per hectare for the current season. But looking at prevailing weather, ... 
 Read more 
Russia’s Feed Wheat Prices Rose 3.5% Last Week, SovEcon Says
 Monday 30th January, 2012 
 Russia’s feed wheat rose 3.5 percent to 5,850 rubles ($193) a metric ton last week, SovEcon said. The fourth-grade milling wheat rose 2.4 percent to 6,300 rubles a ton and the third-grade milling wheat rose 2 percent to 6,400 rubles a ton, the ... 
 Read more 
US wheat firm on output concerns; corn, soy dip
 Monday 30th January, 2012 
 Analyst ProAgro said on Thursday the grain harvest of major exporter Ukraine was likely to come in at about 40 million tonnes in 2012, about 29 percent down from a record of 56.7 million in 2011, due to a fall in acreage because of bad weather when ... 
 Read more 
US wheat dips from 3-week top, Russian crop in focus
 Friday 27th January, 2012 
 * Wheat falls 0.8 percent, snaps six-session rally * Soy, corn dip, but markets on track for weekly gains * Lower-than-normal temperatures may harm Black Sea crops * Argentine soy, corn crops seen shrinking this year (Adds details, quotes) By ... 
 Read more 
Wheat Climbs for Sixth Days as Dwindling Russian Supply May Boost Demand
 Thursday 26th January, 2012 
 Corn and soybeans gained. Wheat for March delivery climbed ... grain exports have increased quite significantly,” Lynette Tan, an analyst at Phillip Futures Pte., said by phone from Singapore today. Russia may impose export restrictions ... 
 Read more 
Outlook for wheat prices is weak over the next 18 months.
 Thursday 26th January, 2012 
 WA FARMERS may have produced a record harvest, but economists are warning the outlook for wheat prices is weak over the next 18 months. CBA agri commodities analyst Luke Matthews said the country&apos;s record crop level had helped lift world wheat stocks ... 
 Read more 
Indonesia&apos;s 2012 wheat flour consumption seen up 5%-6%
 Wednesday 25th January, 2012 
 But Australia, expected to see a record wheat crop and exports in 2011/12, has had a deluge of rain in some areas that will reduce the quality of the crop. Welirang said he was unconcerned by the wet weather as Indonesia largely imported from Australia&apos;s west coast. 
 Read more 
Russia Lacks Export Wheat in South, Pushing Up Prices, Ikar Says
 Tuesday 24th January, 2012 
 Jan. 24 (Bloomberg) -- Russian supplies of milling wheat available for export from the Southern Federal District declined, pushing up prices, the Institute for Agricultural Market Studies said. “We see a stormy price increase because grain ... 
 Read more 
ETF strategy: the wheat bear case gets more compelling
 Tuesday 24th January, 2012 
 The US is preparing for a bright outlook on the 2012 wheat crop as adequate snow fall is covering winter wheat varieties and residual fertiliser could push 2012 yields higher in the southern plains after the poor yielding 2011 season.’ 
 Read more 
US grains rise on export outlook
 Monday 23rd January, 2012 
 SYDNEY Jan 23 (Reuters) - US grain futures rose in early Asian trade on Monday, in line with a late rally last week in corn and wheat as worries about weather conditions in South America affecting crops were seen underpinning demand for exports. ... 
 Read more 
UPDATE 1-Algeria 2011 wheat imports rise 41.5 pct -customs
 Sunday 22nd January, 2012 
 Algeria at the start of this year decided to speed up wheat imports to boost stocks in the wake of rioting in January, sparked by food prices rises. The government is wary that any food unrest could escalate into the kind of nationwide revolt ... 
 Read more 
WA breaks grain harvest record
 Wednesday 18th January, 2012 
 Deliveries yesterday pushed the total amount of binned grain to 14700000 tonnes, surpassing the 2003 record of 14600000. Colin Tutt from grain handler Cooperative Bulk Handling is expecting more grain to be delivered in coming days from areas where ... 
 Read more 
Asian hunger for US noodle wheat may bolster prices
 Wednesday 18th January, 2012 
 Minneapolis wheat prices weakened this month, but analysts said that was largely to do with funds rebalancing their portfolios, and little to do with actual demand. US wheat markets outperformed corn last week on weather-related worries. ... 
 Read more 
Iraq Plans to Raise Wheat Output by 74% to 3 Million Tons
 Tuesday 17th January, 2012 
 Iraq will harvest about 200,000 tons of yellow fodder corn this year, up from 90,000 tons in 2010, he said. The output increase is due to new irrigation and planting methods, he said. It will cover 30 percent to 40 percent of local needs ... 
 Read more 
Ukraine&apos;s Grain Exports May Be Less Than Government&apos;s Target
 Monday 16th January, 2012 
 Ukraine&apos;s grain exports won&apos;t exceed 12 million metric tons from now until the end of June, possibly missing the government&apos;s target for the whole season, said Volodymyr Klymenko, head of the country&apos;s Grain Association. The state target of 26 million ... 
 Read more 
EU wheat firm on weak euro, US holiday cuts volume
 Monday 16th January, 2012 
 PARIS Jan 16 (Reuters) - Wheat prices in major western European markets edged higher on Monday as export-boosting weakness in the euro offset pressure from pre-weekend losses in Chicago, but a holiday closure in U.S. markets kept activity light. 
 Read more 
Russia Sets Minimum Grain Prices for State Purchases in 2012
 Friday 13th January, 2012 
 Feed wheat prices are 4100 rubles for the Asian part and 4300 rubles a ton for the European side and milling rye is at 3900 rubles a ton, feed barley at 4000 rubles a ton and corn at 4400 rubles a ton for the entire country, it said. ... 
 Read more 
WASDE: USDA Starts Year Off With a Surprise
 Thursday 12th January, 2012 
 
 Read more 
Viterra&apos;s Volumes and Earnings to Increase from Grain Marketing Freedom in Canada
 Wednesday 11th January, 2012 
 Viterra anticipates the additional volumes at primary grain elevators and port terminals will generate higher revenue from the fixed cost facilities and earn additional merchandising margins. Viterra expects to capture supply chain efficiencies as it ... 
 Read more 
EU wheat follows US futures down, awaits USDA report
 Wednesday 11th January, 2012 
 HAMBURG, Jan 11 (Reuters) - European wheat prices were pressured by a fall in U.S. grain futures on Wednesday in cautious trade ahead of a key U.S. government crop report. * Losses in Europe were limited by the corresponding drop in the euro ... 
 Read more 
EU wheat follows US futures down, awaits USDA report
 Wednesday 11th January, 2012 
 HAMBURG, Jan 11 (Reuters) - European wheat prices were pressured by a fall in U.S. grain futures on Wednesday in cautious trade ahead of a key U.S. government crop report. * Losses in Europe were limited by the corresponding drop in the euro ... 
 Read more 
U.S. Winter Wheat Extends Gain From 97-Year Low as Glut Looms
 Wednesday 11th January, 2012 
 U.S. farmers, the world’s biggest wheat exporters, probably planted the most winter grain in three years, expanding acreage from a century-low reached in 2009 just as a global supply glut swells to its biggest in a decade.
About 41.02 million acres, an area bigger than Illinois, were sown from September to November, 0.9 percent more than a year earlier, according to the average of 16 analyst estimates compiled by Bloomberg. That will add to world inventories set to rise 4 percent to 207.7 million metric tons, the most since 2000, the survey showed. Winter wheat accounts for 74 percent of the U.S. crop, and the government gives its first estimate tomorrow.
Wheat traded in Chicago fell 30 percent since reaching a 29-month high in February as a 47 percent surge in 2010 spurred more planting. That helped global food prices tracked by the United Nations drop 9.6 percent from a record, easing costs that drove global inflation higher. The second most widely held option gives owners the right to sell wheat at $6 a bushel by February, 6.2 percent lower than now, Chicago Board of Trade data show.
“We have ample supplies of wheat, and we just keep on producing more,” said Shawn McCambridge, the senior grain analyst at Jefferies Bache Commodities LLC in Chicago, who anticipates declining prices. “We’ll need normal-type weather conditions this spring, but in general, we’re going over the winter without really much of a dramatic concern.”
Trailing Equities
Wheat extended its drop this year to 2 percent, trading at $6.3875 today in Chicago. Its 18 percent decline in 2011 was worse than the 1.2 percent retreat in the Standard&amp;Poor’s GSCI Total Return Index of 24 commodities. The MSCI All-Country World Index of equities fell 9.4 percent and Treasuries returned 9.8 percent, a Bank of America Corp. index shows.
The S&amp;P GSCI Agriculture Index of eight farm commodities tumbled 15 percent last year as slowing economies hurt demand for everything from cotton to soybeans. The gauge rose 44 percent in 2010 as drought decimated crops from Russia to Australia. At the end of 2009, the U.S. planted 37.33 million acres of winter wheat, the fewest sown since the fall of 1912, as excessive rains swamped fields from Ohio to Illinois.
Russian wheat farmers, once the world’s second-biggest producers, reaped 35 percent more last year than in 2010, recovering from the worst drought in more than 50 years, the U.S. Department of Agriculture estimates. Ukraine’s output jumped 31 percent, supply rose 9 percent in Canada and Australian production gained 1.5 percent to a record, according to the USDA. India, the largest grower after China, harvested its biggest crop ever.
Futures Trading
Hedge funds and other money managers have been betting on lower wheat prices since mid-September, having been mostly bullish since July 2010, data from the Commodity Futures Trading Commission show. They are holding a net-short position, or wagers on a decline, of 27,097 futures and options, compared with a net-long position of 51,787 contracts in February.
Growth in world demand this year may still exceed the 4 percent anticipated by the USDA, driving prices higher, as farmers substitute more for corn in livestock feed. Wheat is trading at a 12.25 cent-a-bushel discount to corn, compared with a premium of about $1.78 over the past five years, data compiled by Bloomberg show. Feed use for wheat will rise 16 percent this year, almost 12 times the rate of expansion in food use, the USDA estimates.
Corn rose 13 percent to $6.515 a bushel since Dec. 15 on mounting concern that dry weather is damaging crops in Brazil and Argentina, historically the largest exporters after the U.S. The lack of rain may spur more damage than the 2008-2009 drought that was the worst in 70 years, the Argentine Association of Regional Consortia for Agricultural Experimentation said Jan. 6.
‘Bearish’ Fundamentals
“Wheat is competitive as a feed grain with corn, so as corn goes, so goes wheat,” said Dan Manternach, a wheat economist with researcher Doane Advisory Services in St. Louis. “The fundamentals for wheat itself are bearish.”
Prospects for U.S. winter wheat have improved, with parts of Kansas, Oklahoma and Texas, the biggest producing states, getting three times the normal rainfall in the past 30 days, according to the National Weather Service. That is compensating for last year’s drought, the worst on record for Texas. Some areas of the Plains had half the normal rain in 2011.
Winter wheat is grown from the Midwest to the Great Plains, goes dormant until about March and is harvested from May.
Farmers “think we’re in far better shape than we were last year,” said Bill Spiegel, a spokesman for Kansas Wheat, a state growers group. “Last year, we didn’t have any moisture and the crop hadn’t really emerged. We’ve seen this year’s crop is up, and it went into dormancy in really good shape.”
Top Ratings
As of Jan. 1, 53 percent of the winter wheat in Kansas, the biggest growing state, was in good or excellent condition, compared with 47 percent a month earlier, the USDA said Jan. 3. In Oklahoma, 63 percent got the top ratings, up from 56 percent.
“We have good moisture in the top soil, but the subsoil is not as full as we’d like,” Paul Penner, a farmer in Hillsboro, Kansas, said in a telephone interview. “It looks great right now. But when it breaks dormancy in our area in late February and early March, that’s when it’s going to be critical that we get the rain we need as the temperatures rise.”
In Texas, about 25 percent of the crop was in good or excellent condition as of Jan. 8, unchanged from the end of November, the USDA said. Still, more fields were rated fair, and less were very poor, the worst rating.
Some farmers increased planting amid last year’s dry weather because government-subsidized crop-insurance rates set in September, based on futures prices, allowed them to lock in profits, Manhattan, Kansas-based Spiegel said.
“I’m bearish on wheat prices now on into harvest,” said Mark Welch, an agricultural economist at Texas A&amp;M University in College Station, who expects prices in Chicago may drop as low as $5.75 by July. “Wheat is a resilient crop. If you give it a little rain to help it along, it’s surprising what it will do.”
To contact the reporter on this story: Whitney McFerron in Chicago at wmcferron1@bloomberg.net
To contact the editor responsible for this story: Steve Stroth at sstroth@bloomberg.net 
 Read more 
India Wheat Crop Unaffected By Storm
 Monday 9th January, 2012 
 NEW DELHI – Hailstorms and heavy rains over the weekend in India&apos;s northern breadbasket state of Punjab haven&apos;t affected the winter-sown crop, a senior state agriculture department official said Monday. &quot;The crop is fine. Rather, the weather ... 
 Read more 
Warm threat to US winter crop
 Monday 9th January, 2012 
 UNSEASONALLY warm weather in North America may damage US winter wheat production, according to a meteorological service. The warmer conditions have seen snow falls well below normal in both Canada and the US. According to AccuWeather.com, the lack of snow ... 
 Read more 
Argentina Relaxes Wheat-Export System After Farm Group Pressure
 Friday 6th January, 2012 
 Growers will now be able to export wheat crops “as they please” providing they meet conditions, such as being able to deliver the physical goods or holding certain futures contracts, Yauhar said in Buenos Aires. Similar measures are likely to be taken ... 
 Read more 
Wheat near record exports
 Friday 6th January, 2012 
 AUSTRALIAN wheat exports fell just three per cent below record levels for the 2010-11 export year. There were 18.5 million tonnes of wheat exported last year, according to Wheat Exports Australia, compared to 19.1mt in 1996-7, which is the Australian ... 
 Read more 
Wheat falls for 2nd day on risk aversion; soy steady
 Thursday 5th January, 2012 
 Traders said the market was technically overbought after prices rallied 13.4 percent in the last 2-1/2 weeks, mostly due to short covering. For corn and soybeans, dry weather in Argentina, the world&apos;s second largest corn exporter and the biggest soyoil ... 
 Read more 
Wheat falls for 2nd day on risk aversion; soy steady
 Thursday 5th January, 2012 
 Prices at 0348 GMT Contract Last Change Pct chg Two-day chg MA 30 RSI CBOT wheat 647.00 -3.00 -0.46% -1.52% 614.23 67 CBOT corn 656.75 -1.75 -0.27% -0.27% 610.47 82 CBOT soy 1229.25 -0.75 -0.06% +0.14% 1155.21 82 CBOT rice $14.66 $0.01 +0.03% +0.07% ... 
 Read more 
Qaim fears Sindh may miss wheat target
 Thursday 5th January, 2012 
 KARACHI - There is a possibility of less yield of wheat crop in 2012 as compare to the last year’s production, therefore prompt strategy be evolved to achieve the wheat procurement target, the Sindh chief minister directed a meeting. Presiding over the ... 
 Read more 
Sharad Pawar sees record 2012 wheat output
 Monday 19th December, 2011 
 The wheat crop looks better than last year. As the acreage is higher and the weather conditions have become very favourable it would be a record crop this year, Pawar said New Delhi: India is on track to produce a record wheat crop in 2012, agriculture ... 
 Read more 
Soy ends 10-day rally, but still near 5-month top
 Monday 5th March, 2012 
 * Soybean uptrend seen intact on firm demand, low supply * USDA may lift US soy export sales forecast, cut SAmerican crop * Coming Up: US non-manufacturing PMI, 1500 GMT By Manolo Serapio Jr SINGAPORE, March 5 (Reuters) - US soybeans retreated on ... 
 Read more 
Soy ends 10-day rally, but still near 5-month top
 Monday 5th March, 2012 
 The most-traded CBOT May wheat slipped 0.2 percent to $6.73-1/4 per bushel, still pressured by abundant wheat stocks globally. Corn dropped 0.3 percent to $6.57 a bushel. Overall, Credit Suisse says grain prices could be at risk of falling further. 
 Read more 
Seed Selection Key to Managing Soybean Disease, Achieving High Yields
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Source: Ohio State University
 

As spring planting season approaches, soybean growers should be aware that one of the best ways to manage soybean disease is to make sure they plant the right varieties, says Anne Dorance, an Ohio State University Extension soybean expert. In fact, seed selection is one of the most important decisions Ohio soybean farmers can make to ensure the best yield outcomes, says Dorrance, a plant pathologist with joint appointments with OSU Extension and Ohio Agricultural Research and Development Center.


 
 
 
 
 

read more 
 Read more 
Monsanto to add dicamba-tolerant trait to RR soybeans
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Accompanying the new dicamba soybean trait will be a dicamba and glyphosate herbicide premix called Roundup Xtend. Roundup Xtend will be available for application before planting and over-the-top in season. The new herbicide offers dual modes of action ... 
 Read more 
CBOT soybeans end higher for ninth straight session
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Argentina&apos;s 2011/12 soy harvest is expected to come in at 48 million tonnes and the corn crop is projected at 22 million tonnes, President Cristina Fernandez said. * Argentine dock workers went on strike, port chamber CAPYM said, slowing the country&apos;s ... 
 Read more 
China buys U.S. corn, soybeans
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Soybean prices have rallied almost 15 percent since Jan. 1, boosted by news of heat and drought in Brazil and increased acres for corn planting in the United States this spring. “Of that soybean purchase, 175,000 metric tons were from the old ... 
 Read more 
Soy posts best month in a year on export demand
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 Soybean futures rose more than 9 percent in February in the largest monthly gain since December 2010, while corn posted a monthly rise of about 2.5 percent and wheat ended the month flat in the third straight month without a decline. 
 Read more 
Soybean Seed Treatment Return on Investment
 Wednesday 29th February, 2012 
 Source: University of Wisconsin-Madison
 

With soybean commodity prices at record high prices, the number of questions regarding key management considerations also remains high. One of the questions we often receive regards the use of seed treatments, in particular the use of seed treatment fungicides and/or insecticides. Since 2008, we have conducted trials throughout Wisconsin to examine if seed treatments are economically viable for soybean production. In particular, we are most interested in trying to answer the following question: “What is the probability that if I use a seed treatment, the cost of the application is covered?”


 
 
 
 
 

read more 
 Read more 
EU soybean trade heavy-handed
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 As United States Trade Representative Ron Kirk moves to consider ways to improve the nation&apos;s trade relationship with the European Union (EU) as part of the recently-formed US-EU High Level Working Group on Jobs and Growth, the American Soybean ... 
 Read more 
Soy rises for 5th session on LatAm drought, wheat dips
 Monday 6th February, 2012 
 Export shipments of U.S. soybeans were above 1 million tonnes for the third ... Still, rains soaked parched Argentine 2011/12 soy crops and helped recovery of even hard-hit early-seeded fields after weeks of drought. Argentina&apos;s vast Pampas ... 
 Read more 
Soybeans: Brazilian Weather Not the Whole Story for Soybean Bulls
 Friday 27th January, 2012 
 It used to be that for soybean price analysis, the US crop and growing season was the whole ball game. Not anymore. Brazil overtook the US earlier last decade as the worlds #1 producer and exporter of soybeans. 
 Read more 
U S soybean exports lags 27% during 2011 12 marketing year
 Monday 23rd January, 2012 
 U.S soybean exports for 2011-12 marketing year had lagged 27% as China and other buyers cut back purchases on global economic slowdown, USDA report. 
 Read more 
Uneven rains trouble Brazil soy farmers
 Sunday 22nd January, 2012 
 Soybean growers in the states of Parana, Goias and No. 1 producer Mato Grosso are reporting the first outbreaks of Asian rust, a fungus that can cause crop yields to fall, local consultancy Celeres said in a weekly bulletin. The disease occurs amid ... 
 Read more 
UPDATE 2-Argentina sees soy area, corn yields hurt by drought
 Thursday 19th January, 2012 
 is taking a toll on Argentine corn and soy crop expectations, the government said on Thursday. The drought has caused concern about world food supplies. Argentina is the No. 2 global corn exporter and the No. 3 supplier of soybeans, which serve ... 
 Read more 
Severe Drought In Central Argentina&amp;Paraguay Effects Crop Prices
 Wednesday 18th January, 2012 
 Hope has meanwhile faded that Argentina might be able to replenish global corn supplies depleted by a poor United States harvest. Hamburg-based oilseeds analysts Oil World cut its forecasts of soybean crops in Argentina and Brazil by a combined 3.8 million ... 
 Read more 
ISU professor weighs in on potential changes on soybean exports to China
 Wednesday 18th January, 2012 
 Although the adverse weather in large parts of Argentina and South Brazil at the end of 2011 gives U.S. corn and soybean futures a chance to go bullish on prospects of lower production in South American, Brazil has been a close partner in soybeans. 
 Read more 
Soybeans, Corn Climb on Forecasts for Dry Weather in Argentine Crop Areas
 Tuesday 17th January, 2012 
 March-delivery soybeans rallied as much as 1.7 percent to $11.775 a bushel on the Chicago Board of Trade before trading at $11.77 at 2:27 pm in Singapore. The price dropped 3.2 percent last week. Corn for March delivery rose as much as 1.3 percent to ... 
 Read more 
Soybeans Gain First Time in Four Days as USDA Trims Global Supply Forecast
 Friday 13th January, 2012 
 Soybean futures advanced, paring a second weekly loss, after the US Department of Agriculture lowered its estimates for global supplies. March delivery soybeans gained as much as 1 percent to $11.945 a bushel on the Chicago Board of Trade, after losing ... 
 Read more 
Soybeans Gain First Time in Four Days as USDA Trims Global Supply Forecast
 Friday 13th January, 2012 
 March-delivery corn traded little changed at $6.1125 a bushel, after declining as much as 1.1 percent to $6.05, the lowest price for a most-active contract since Dec. 21. Futures are set for a 5 percent loss this week, the biggest such slump ... 
 Read more 
UPDATE 2-More rain seen for drought-hit Argentine grains
 Thursday 12th January, 2012 
 Weeks of dryness have toasted grains fields in the world&apos;s No. 3 soybean- and No. 2 corn-exporting country, prompting crop estimate cuts and denting ... marking scant progress of 1.3 percentage points during the week. The report also said ... 
 Read more 
U.S. soy edges up after tumble on Argentine rains
 Thursday 12th January, 2012 
 SYDNEY, Jan 12 (Reuters) - U.S. soy futures were a touch higher in early Asian trade on Thursday ... tonnes of corn, 55,000 tonnes of feed wheat and 55,000 tonnes of soybean mealfor April and May delivery via tenders. MARKET NEWS * The euro ... 
 Read more 
Soybean prices rise
 Tuesday 10th January, 2012 
 Soybean prices rose Monday on continued worries that hot, dry weather in South America could cut global supplies. Wheat and corn prices also rose. Forecasts last week predicted more rain in Argentina, a major corn and soybean exporter. But the rains appear ... 
 Read more 
Corn, soy up on Argentine crop concerns; wheat rises
 Monday 9th January, 2012 
 SINGAPORE, Jan 9 (Reuters) - U.S. corn rose 0.7 percent on Monday, while soybeans recovered after two straight sessions of losses with harsh hot and dry weather threatening to curb crop-yields in Argentina, a top global supplier of grains and ... 
 Read more 
Palm Oil Surges as Tighter Soybean Supplies May Increase Demand
 Wednesday 4th January, 2012 
 Palm oil rallied to the highest level in more than six weeks on concern that hot, dry weather in South America may damage crops of soybeans, crushed to make an alternative edible oil, and as demand may rise in China. The March-delivery contract ... 
 Read more 
Soybeans climb to 2-week high on South America crop woes
 Monday 19th December, 2011 
 Forexpros - Soybean futures were up for a third day on Monday, trading at a two-week high as poor ... 
 Read more 
Soybeans Advance as Hot Weather in Parts of South America May Hurt Crops
 Friday 16th December, 2011 
 Soybeans for March delivery climbed 0.5 percent to $11.265 a bushel on the Chicago Board of Trade at 2:13 p.m. Singapore time. Futures have gained 1.8 percent this week and are set for a 20 percent decline this year. Argentina’s soybean, corn ... 
 Read more 
Agri commodity outlook from SMC Global
 Thursday 15th December, 2011 
 Soybean prices, pressured throughout the fall by weak exports, fall to lowest level since Oct. 2010. CBOT Jan. soybeans end down 18 1/2c, to 1.7%, to USD 11 per bushel. Other commodities: Sugar futures may trade sideways holding support above 2870 ... 
 Read more 
US soy rises for 2nd day on LatAm weather concerns
 Tuesday 13th December, 2011 
 Commodity funds bought a net 4,000 CBOT soybean futures contracts on Monday, trade sources said. They were even in corn and sold 1,000 wheat. Prices at 0257 GMT Contract Last Change Pct chg Two-day chg MA 30 RSI CBOT wheat 595.75 1.50 +0.25% -0 ... 
 Read more 
China: Soybean imports bounces back 49.6% to 5.7mn tons in November
 Monday 12th December, 2011 
 China’s Corn exports at 1.947Kt were down 95.3% m/m from October’s exports of 41.4Kt. China’s Sugar exports meanwhile came in at 4.3Kt, up 41.2% m/m but down 61.4% y/y. Due to a poor domestic crop, China’s sugar imports are likely to stay elevated ... 
 Read more 
China rapeseed imports to pick up on rising capacity
 Monday 12th December, 2011 
 Large rapeseed imports could take market share away from soybean, of which China is the world&apos;s top ... more incentives to boost grain production, traders said. &quot;The planting acreage is not looking very optimistic again this season because ... 
 Read more 
US soy rises from 14-month low, corn dips
 Monday 12th December, 2011 
 Prices at 0344 GMT Contract Last Change Pct chg Two-day chg MA 30 RSI CBOT wheat 596.25 0.25 +0.04% -0.13% 622.59 32 CBOT corn 592.75 -1.50 -0.25% -1.25% 625.20 38 CBOT soy 1110.75 3.75 +0.34% -1.92% 1160.56 34 CBOT rice $14.10 $0.09 +0.64% -0.84% ... 
 Read more 
Brazil Soy Crop Forecast Cut to 71.3 Million Tons Next Year
 Thursday 8th December, 2011 
 Soybean growers in Brazil, the world’s second-largest producer ... The forecast was lowered from a Nov. 9 estimate of as much as 73 million tons, the ministry’s crop-forecasting agency, known as Conab, said today in an e-mailed report. 
 Read more 
US corn, soybeans up on Europe hopes, bargain hunting
 Wednesday 7th December, 2011 
 Grains prices at 0615 GMT Contract Last Change Pct chg Two-day chg MA 30 RSI CBOT wheat 610.50 -2.50 -0.41% -0.16% 628.33 44 CBOT corn 597.75 1.25 +0.21% +1.14% 630.58 36 CBOT soy 1132.25 2.75 +0.24% +0.53% 1171.98 41 CBOT rice $14.69 $0.09 +0.62% ... 
 Read more 
Corn, Soybean Futures Climb on Speculation Demand Will Increase
 Tuesday 6th December, 2011 
 Corn futures for March delivery rose 0.9 percent to close at $5.965 a bushel at 1:15 pm on the Chicago Board of Trade, snapping a three-day decline. Earlier, the price fell to $5.80, the lowest since Oct. 4. The grain dropped 6 percent in November as ... 
 Read more 
South America 2012
 Tuesday 6th December, 2011 
 Strong domestic prices in Brazil, Argentina, and Paraguay are encouraging farmers to expand both first-crop corn and soybean acreage. With some early planting in September in parts of the three Latin American countries, fieldwork rolls on through the end of November. 
 Read more 
US soybeans rise on dry weather, European summit hopes
 Monday 5th December, 2011 
 Grains prices as of 0530 GMT Product Last Change Pct Move END 2010 Ytd Pct move CBOT corn 586.25 -0.25 -0.04 629.00 -6.80 CBOT soy 1139.25 3.50 +0.31 1393.75 -18.26 CBOT wheat 612.75 0.50 +0.08 794.25 -22.85 CBOT rice 14.43 -0.03 -0.21 13.88 3.93 US ... 
 Read more 
China - Major buyer of Brazilian meat
 Sunday 4th December, 2011 
 “Most of this increase in imports of about 46 million tonnes has been met by ... we believe Africa could benefit from increased global demand for maize, palm oil and other crops.” “China – and the world in general – does not just need Africa ... 
 Read more 
Improved basis indicates demand for soybeans late in 2011
 Thursday 1st December, 2011 
 With this year’s 3.05 billion bushel soybean crop in the bin for the U.S., cash and futures prices moved significantly lower. Back in late July, the markets were concerned about dry conditions affecting much of the Soybean Belt. The January ... 
 Read more 
US Soybean Market Share Eroded by South American Competition
 Tuesday 29th November, 2011 
 US soybean exports and crushings declined 22 percent in September and October compared with a year earlier as buyers instead purchased South American stockpiles, Oil World said. ... 
 Read more 
U.S. wheat dips on improved crop conditions; corn steady
 Tuesday 29th November, 2011 
 Brazil&apos;s new soybean crop now being planted is seen at 74.8 million tonnes ... having been boosted by hopes that European officials will finally make some progress in tackling their debt crisis this week. * Oil prices rose on Monday as another ... 
 Read more 
UPDATE 1-US corn, soy crop insurance rates to drop in 2012-USDA
 Monday 28th November, 2011 
 WASHINGTON, Nov 28 (Reuters) - U.S. corn and soybean growers will pay lower rates from crop insurance in 2012 -- down by an average 7 percent for corn and 9 percent for soybeans, the federal overseer said on Monday. The U.S. Agriculture ... 
 Read more 
Excessive heat, rain hurt region’s harvests
 Monday 28th November, 2011 
 Each November at the end of the harvest cycle, Americans take time to give thanks for ... According to More, he would have harvested at least 80 percent of his soybean crop by late October, but only about 25 percent of the crop had been harvested by ... 
 Read more 
US soy rebounds from 13-month low on Italy aid hopes
 Monday 28th November, 2011 
 US wheat has lost almost 8 percent this month, corn is down nearly 9 percent and soybeans have given up 7.3 percent so far in November. The decline in grain prices has not led to a strong increase in export demand. US corn export sales at 350000 tonnes ... 
 Read more 
US soy rebounds from 13-month low on Italy aid hopes
 Monday 28th November, 2011 
 &quot;It is mainly Europe which is impacting the market but the bullish sentiment is that China is expected to increase soybean imports,&quot; Ker said. &quot;There are expectations that China could also buy more corn at these levels.&quot; China is expected to see ... 
 Read more 
CGG is setting up a soybean base in Brazil
 Thursday 24th November, 2011 
 Currently, nearly 80 percent of agricultural oil producing crops in China are imported, mostly from the US and Brazil. Last year, China imported 54.8 million tons of soybeans, and the volume this year will hit 60 million tons, according to the China Nation ... 
 Read more 
Soybeans Reach 13-Month Low as Debt Crises May Be Sapping Demand
 Wednesday 23rd November, 2011 
 Shipments have slid 19 percent for corn and 5 percent for wheat, USDA data show. Investors may be avoiding agricultural commodities until the outlook is clearer for the U.S. and European economies. “We’re seeing a continued level of concern ... 
 Read more 
Soybeans Decline to 13-Month Low on Improved Supplies
 Wednesday 23rd November, 2011 
 helping accelerate planting of soybeans, corn and wheat, Telvent DTN Inc. said in a forecast yesterday. In Brazil, hotter and drier weather was expected next week followed by rains and “no significant” crop concerns were seen, it said. 
 Read more 
Corn May Advance on Speculation Price Declines Will Help Increase Demand
 Tuesday 22nd November, 2011 
 Corn futures may gain on speculation that declining prices will increase demand for raw materials used to make food and biofuels. Wheat and soybeans may rise. Corn has dropped 3.6 percent this year, ... 
 Read more 
Soybeans Rebound as Rains May Delay South American Planting
 Tuesday 22nd November, 2011 
 In Brazil, soybean areas are forecast to get rains this week, delaying sowing, while benefiting crops that are already planted, according to Sao Paulo-based Somar Meteorologia. “Certainly, weather issues do have an impact on prices at the moment,” ... 
 Read more 
Argentina forecasts 49.5 million tons of soybeans 12 million tons of wheat
 Monday 21st November, 2011 
 Soybeans are a key source of hard currency and tax revenue for the Argentine government. The country is the world&apos;s top soy-meal and soy-oil exporter and ranks third in global soybean exports. Planting is in full swing after showers earlier in November ... 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Falls, Hits 6-Week Low; Export, MPOB Data In Focus
 Friday 4th May, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange fell for a fourth consecutive day and touched a six-week low Friday as disappointing economic data this week generated worries about global economic growth. Most market participants refrained from making aggressive bets ahead of a slew of data due to be released next week. The benchmark July [...] 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Ends Down; Fundamentals Limit Declines
 Wednesday 2nd May, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange ended lower Wednesday, as investors booked profits following recent declines on the CBOT soy complex, although expectations for improving export demand and reduced stockpiles limited the fall. The market also took support from positive U.S. economic data Tuesday, trade participants said. The benchmark July contract on Bursa [...] 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Ends Mostly Lower On Production Outlook
 Thursday 26th April, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange ended mostly lower Thursday due to investor caution amid concerns over global economic growth and forecasts for higher palm oil output in April, trade participants said. The benchmark July contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives ended 0.3% lower at MYR3,500 a metric ton after moving in a [...] 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Ends Down Ahead Of Key Reports; May Rise In 2Q
 Friday 30th March, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange ended lower Friday for the third consecutive day as investors liquidated riskier positions ahead of key crop report by the U.S. Department of Agriculture Friday and March palm oil export data. The benchmark June contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives ended 0.7% lower at MYR3,433 a metric [...] 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Falls On Profit-Taking; USDA Crop Data In Focus
 Friday 30th March, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange ended lower Thursday as investors continue to book profits from gains earlier this week, although worries about soybean production deficits in South America curbed declines. The benchmark June contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives exchange ended 0.5% lower at MYR3,457 a metric ton after moving in a [...] 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Retreats From 1-Year High On Profit-Taking
 Wednesday 28th March, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange retreated Wednesday as investors locked in profits after prices hit a one-year high, although declines were limited on expectations that March CPO output will remain weak. The benchmark June contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives exchange ended 0.2% lower at MYR3,473 a metric ton after moving both [...] 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Hits Fresh 9-Month High On Demand Prospects
 Tuesday 27th March, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange rebounded Friday to a nine-month high, fueled by improving demand prospects for the cooking oil and gains in regional vegoil markets during Asian trading hours. The benchmark June contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives ended 2.5% higher at MYR3,426 a metric ton after rising as much as [...] 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Hits One-Year High On Tight Vegoil Supplies
 Tuesday 27th March, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange rose to a one-year high Monday amid worries that lower soybean output in South America and the U.S. may limit soyoil availability and tighten global vegoil supplies. The benchmark June contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives rose as much as 1.5% to MYR3,479 a metric ton, the [...] 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Falls To One-Week Low; China Data Weigh
 Tuesday 27th March, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange slipped Thursday as investors continue to liquidate riskier positions after a gauge of manufacturing activity in major consumer China indicated its economy is slowing, raising concerns that the country may reduce consumption of raw materials. Palm oil, a key ingredient used to produce a wide variety of [...] 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Ends Up On Supplies, Bullish Forecast
 Tuesday 27th March, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange rose to a one-year high again on the back of hopes that tight soyoil supply could boost demand for palm oil, trade participants said. The benchmark June contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives exchange ended 0.8% higher at MYR3,481 a metric ton after rising as much as [...] 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Marches Higher On Surging Malaysian Exports
 Thursday 15th March, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange continued their recent rally Thursday, reaching a nine-month high for a third consecutive day, fueled by a surge in exports and gains in other commodity markets. The benchmark May contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives ended 0.5% higher at MYR3,403 a metric ton after rising as much [...] 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Rises To Fresh 9-Month High On US Data, Demand
 Wednesday 14th March, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange rose to a fresh nine-month high Wednesday as positive U.S. economic data in the U.S. and improving demand boosted sentiment. The benchmark May contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives exchange ended 0.6% higher at MYR3,385 a metric ton after rising as much as 0.9% to MYR3,395/ton, the [...] 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Rises; Sentiment Gains On 1H Price Forecasts
 Thursday 8th March, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange ended higher Thursday, due to bullish price forecasts by top market analysts and optimism that Greece would succeed in reaching a debt-swap deal with private creditors. The benchmark May contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives ended 1.1% higher at MYR3,303 a metric ton after moving in a [...] 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Higher On Analysts’ Outlooks; USDA Report In Focus
 Wednesday 7th March, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange ended higher Wednesday following bullish outlooks from prominent vegetable oil analysts at an industry conference Wednesday. The benchmark May contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives exchange ended MYR22 higher at MYR3,266 a metric ton, off an intraday low of MYR3,224/ton. The analysts&apos;forecasts created&quot;buying confidence&quot;in [...] 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Slightly Lower; Focus on Market Forecasts
 Tuesday 6th March, 2012 
 The benchmark crude palm oil futures contract on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange ended slightly lower Tuesday, paring a morning decline as market participants covered short positions due to expectations of a bullish forecast Wednesday by prominent vegetable oil analyst Dorab Mistry. Leading vegetable oil analysts Thomas Mielke and James Fry will also likely deliver market outlooks [...] 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Falls; Analysts’ Outlooks In Focus
 Monday 5th March, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange fell Monday, reflecting investor caution ahead of the release of price outlooks by eminent vegetable oil analysts Wednesday. The benchmark May contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives exchange ended 0.4% lower at MYR3,246 a metric ton, on mild profit-taking. Palm oil prices may trade in a range [...] 
 Read more 
Sustainable palm oil consumption to double this year
 Monday 5th March, 2012 
 KUALA LUMPUR: The Roundtable on Sustainable Palm Oil (RSPO) foresees total global sustainable palm oil consumption to double this year from five per cent last year, given the increasing demand and awareness. Secretary-General Darrel Webber said ... 
 Read more 
CPO Ends Down On Crude; Investors Await Price Outlook
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange fell Friday due to concerns about high palm oil inventory levels after February exports slumped. The benchmark May contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives exchange ended 0.8% lower at MYR3,259 a metric ton, after moving in a MYR3,256-MYR3,283 range. CPO prices also reflected weakening crude oil. April [...] 
 Read more 
Palm oil drops as soy, crude-oil driven rally pauses
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 * Traders booking profit from recent rally * Demand strong but Malaysia not really benefiting-traders * China imports of palm oil strong despite high stocks (adds details, comments) By Niluksi Koswanage KUALA LUMPUR, March 2 (Reuters) - Malaysian crude ... 
 Read more 
Mandiri to lend Rp 189b to oil palm cooperatives
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 Mandiri agreed to lend a total of Rp 189 billion (US$20.79 million) to four cooperatives fostered by the Sinar Mas Group, one of Indonesia&apos;s major palm oil producers. The four cooperatives are: Kopsa Puyang Gana, which will receive Rp 56.8 billion to ... 
 Read more 
Smart spends Rp 1.35t on new plantation
 Friday 2nd March, 2012 
 ... fruit bunches into crude palm oil (CPO) and palm kernels, and refining CPO into derivative products such as cooking oil, margarine and shortening. Susanto said that the company expected its CPO production to grow by about 10 percent this year. 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Recovers; Spillover Buying As Crude Prices Recover
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange recovered lost ground to end higher Thursday due to spillover buying interest following a recovery in crude-oil prices, trading executives said. The benchmark May contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives settled 0.5% higher at MYR3,285 a metric ton after moving both ways. After moving in negative territory [...] 
 Read more 
China palm oil stocks at nearly 1 mln tonnes, more imports eyed-Reuters survey
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 By Chew Yee Kiat SINGAPORE, March 1 (Reuters) - China&apos;s palm oil stocksprobably rose to nearly a million tonnes in February with afurther build-up seen as traders keep buying cargoes fromMalaysia and Indonesia ... 
 Read more 
Palm oil edges up; weak Malaysia exports cap gains
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 SINGAPORE, March 1 (Reuters) - Malaysian crude palm oil futures edged up on Thursday, spurred by positive factory data from second-largest importer China but gains were capped as export trends showed weaker demand. Malaysian export numbers eased ... 
 Read more 
CPO Ends Down On Profit-Taking After February Exports Disappoint
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange fell Wednesday, as investors booked profits on the back of a slide in export demand. If the take-up by euro area banks at the European Central Bank&apos;s long-term refinancing operation later in the day meets expectations, it could prove supportive for CPO. The benchmark May contract on [...] 
 Read more 
Sime plans to list division in 2013
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Sime yesterday announced a group net profit of RM1.16 billion for 2QFY12 ended Dec 31, up from RM922.9 million previously due to higher realised crude palm oil (CPO) prices and strong, all-round financial performance in its other core businesses. 
 Read more 
GLOBAL GREEN PALM OIL OUTPUT MAY RISE ON INDIA, CHINA DEMAND
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 NEW DELHI,  — Global production of green palm oil is expected to surge sharply in the coming years on likely rise in demand from India and China, the world’s biggest consumers of cooking oils. Green palm oil is produced in an environment-friendly and socially responsible way. “If India and China send strong signal, global production [...] 
 Read more 
Health benefits to keep soy products prices high
 Thursday 1st March, 2012 
 Soy product prices are likely to experience upward movements as increasing awareness of the health benefits of soy foods has raised the demand for the soy based products world.According to the studies, health benefits from soy products includes heart and bone health, as well as protection from cancer. 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Ends Down On Greek Debt Worries
 Thursday 16th February, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange ended lower Thursday amid fresh concerns of a Greek debt default but declines were limited by increasing weather worries about Brazil&apos;s soy crop. The benchmark May contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives exchange ended MYR11 lower at MYR3,190 a metric ton after moving in a MYR3,169-MYR3,202 range. [...] 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Ends Off Lows As CBOT Soyoil Rebounds
 Wednesday 15th February, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange ended off lows Wednesday, with weather worries in South America and a recovery in Chicago soyoil futures limiting declines. The benchmark April contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives exchange ended 0.2 lower at MYR3,197 metric ton after moving between positive and negative territory. March soyoil on the [...] 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Ends At 1-Month High On South America Weather
 Tuesday 14th February, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange rose to a one-month high Monday, propelled by short covering amid concerns that dry weather in major soybean growing areas in South America could further damage yields and boost demand for rival vegoils. The benchmark April contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives exchange ended 1.2% higher at [...] 
 Read more 
Palm oil hits near 3-week high as Greece passes bill
 Monday 13th February, 2012 
 * Greece lawmakers pass unpopular austerity bill * Palm oil to rise to 3190-3196 ringgit - technicals (Updates prices, adds details) By Chew Yee Kiat SINGAPORE, Feb 13 (Reuters) - Malaysian crude palm oil futures rose to near three-week high on Monday ... 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Ends Down On Profit-Taking; Industry Data In Focus
 Thursday 9th February, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange fell Thursday as investors booked profits from recent gains and amid weak sentiment due to ongoing uncertainty over the euro-zone debt situation. The benchmark April contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives exchange settled 0.2% lower at MYR3,148 a metric ton after trading in a narrow MYR3,135-MYR3,162/ton range. [...] 
 Read more 
CPO Rises To Two Week High; Industry Data In Focus
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange rose to a two-week high Wednesday, as investors covered short positions amid broad gains in Chicago soyoil and improving sentiment over a debt restructuring deal in Greece. The benchmark April contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives exchange ended 2.3% higher at MYR3,155 a metric ton, just short [...] 
 Read more 
Palm oil hits near three-week high, USDA report eyed
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 &quot;We can expect some short term rally ahead of the USDA reports tomorrow,&quot; added the dealer. Benchmark April palm oil futures on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives Exchange gained 2.3 percent to close at 3,155 ringgit ($1,051) per tonne, but off the ... 
 Read more 
Palm Oil Stockpiles in Malaysia May Drop to Five-Month Low
 Wednesday 8th February, 2012 
 8 (Bloomberg) -- Palm oil inventory in Malaysia, the world&apos;s second-biggest supplier after Indonesia, probably declined to a five-month low in January after production fell for a third month, according to a Bloomberg News survey. 
 Read more 
Indonesia Q4 GDP rises 6.5 pct y/y, above forecast
 Monday 6th February, 2012 
 The drop showed that the global slowdown is starting to bite in the world&apos;s top exporter of thermal coal, tin and palm oil. In the third quarter ... about inflationary pressure from higher fuel prices with concerns that a sluggish global economy could ... 
 Read more 
Malaysia Sets 2012 Duty-Free CPO Export Quota At 3.6M Tons -Sources
 Monday 6th February, 2012 
 KUALA LUMPUR (Dow Jones)–Malaysia, the world’s No. 2 palm oil producer has set its duty-free export quota for crude palm oil at 3.6 million metric tons for the year ahead after several weeks of delay, industry executives said late Saturday. Three industry executives said separately major palm oil exporters Wilmar, IOI Corp. and Felda were [...] 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Ends Up On Weekend Short Covering; Upside Limited
 Friday 3rd February, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange rebounded to end higher Friday, as investors covered short positions ahead of the long weekend, although expectations for demand to stay weak capped gains, trade participants said. The benchmark April contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives exchange ended 0.9% higher at MYR3,085 a metric ton after bouncing [...] 
 Read more 
Indonesia to set up $5.6bn plantation firm
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 The sprawling archipelago of 17,000 islands is the world’s biggest exporter of palm oil, second biggest producer of rubber and robusta coffee and third biggest ... regional markets last year with hefty imports from Thailand and Vietnam. 
 Read more 
Palm oil hits new six-week low on strong ringgit
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 On the demand side, Malaysian palm oil exports for January eased close to 12 percent, according to cargo surveyor Intertek Testing Services. Another cargo surveyor, Societe Generale de Surveillance, said Malaysian exports for the same period fell 13 ... 
 Read more 
UPDATE: Unilever Warns On Global Economy, Profit Flat
 Thursday 2nd February, 2012 
 palm oil, petrochemicals and plastics, the company, which also competes with Switzerland&apos;sNestle SA (NESN.VX), is streamlining packaging, paring its logistics, sourcing and purchasing costs, and selectively increasing prices to stem margin losses. 
 Read more 
AP cane farmers shifting to palm oil
 Wednesday 1st February, 2012 
 Farmers in water-rich Andhra area expect that over 30 per cent of sugarcane area would be converted to palm oil, maize and sunflower. Farmers never lose hope. If one crop fails, they quickly turn to another. Sugarcane growers in Andhra Pradesh, ... 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Recovers Late On Short Covering
 Wednesday 1st February, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange rebounded recouped most of its early loss Tuesday as investors covered shorts ahead of a public holiday and expectations of lower production growth in January supported bullish sentiment. The benchmark April contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives exchange ended MYR4 lower at MYR3,078 a metric ton, a [...] 
 Read more 
Palm oil ends off 6-week low on weak exports
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 Exports also fell due to a delay by Malaysia in issuing tax free crude palm oil export quotas, sources said. This has made it difficult for licence holders to supply overseas refiners with cheap feedstock and meet existing export contracts. 
 Read more 
Belgian food industry mimics Dutch 2015 palm oil pledge
 Tuesday 31st January, 2012 
 All palm oil designated for the Belgian market will be produced based on the sustainability criteria of the Roundtable on Sustainable Palm Oil (RSPO) by 2015, claims a new pledge from the food sector in that country. The Belgian Alliance for ... 
 Read more 
Crude Palm Oil Ends Down As Demand Prospects Weaken
 Monday 30th January, 2012 
 Crude palm oil futures on Malaysia&apos;s derivatives exchange ended lower Monday amid expectations that export demand will stay weak and as investors liquidated riskier positions ahead of a European summit later in the global day. The benchmark April contract on the Bursa Malaysia Derivatives exchange ended 1.7% lower at MYR3,082 a metric ton, after falling [...] 
 Read more 
EPA Rejects Palm Oil-based Biofuels as Renewable Fuel
 Monday 30th January, 2012 
 6 shows the processing of palm oil fruits at a factory in Medan in Indonesia. The EPA announced a regulatory filing last week which said that palm-oil based biofuels do not meet the agency&apos;s renewable Fuel Standard (RFS). (ATAR/AFP/Getty Images) ... 
 Read more 
Palm oil hits two-week low on slowing demand, EU summit
 Monday 30th January, 2012 
 * Investors eye EU summit for Greece debt swap deal * Malaysia delays issuing CPO export quotas for 2012-sources (Updates prices, adds details) By Chew Yee Kiat SINGAPORE, Jan 30 (Reuters) - Malaysian ... 
 Read more 
UPDATE 2-Malaysia delays tax free crude palm oil export quotas
 Monday 30th January, 2012 
 (Adds more details, comments) * Govt still studying plans to counter Indonesia&apos;s exporttax move * Licence holders say unable to supply overseas refineries * Local refiners say delay adds to supply but ... 
 Read more OUR SPONSORS 
 
 
CONTACT US
 www.worldcrops.com World Crops Ltd
100-101 Ashmill Street
London NW1 6RA
UK Registered Company Number: 07304833 
ABOUT US

 WorldCrops.com is an invaluable agricommodities resource, providing intra-day and historical agricultural commodity prices, research and data, crop-specific weather forecasts; plus independent news and analysis from major agricultural commodity producing regions around the world, via &apos;Grains of Truth.&apos; 
 
SITEMAP

 Home Grains of Truth Research News Events My Account About Us Contact Us 
 
COMMODITIES

 Cocoa Coffee Sugar Cotton Corn Wheat Soybeans Palm Oil 
 
©2004-2012 World Crops Ltd. All rights reserved
 Privacy Policy Terms and Conditions 

 Website design by Spring Digital Back to top
	</body>
</document>
