<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001280" url="http://abcnews.go.com/blogs/business/2011/09/fast-food-chains-getting-into-the-food-stamp-act/" time="2012-07-12-16:43" support="109" score="0.4623816710969376" bingtitle="Fast Food Chains Getting Into the Food Stamp Act - ABC News" webtitle="Fast Food Chains Getting Into the Food Stamp Act - ABC News">
			<query id="001506" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000181" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000397" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000182" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000173" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000909" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="001409" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="001286" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000236" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="001122" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000898" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000427" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000183" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000376" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="001126" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="000187" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000055" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000373" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000186" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="001207" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="001432" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000164" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000057" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000059" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000056" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="001399" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000176" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000430" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000434" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000351" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="001407" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="000345" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="000377" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="001035" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000220" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="000060" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000896" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000431" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="001526" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="001524" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000052" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000416" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000425" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000178" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="001104" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="001098" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="001535" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000167" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="001107" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="001116" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="001113" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000050" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="001531" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000743" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="001411" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000867" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="001219" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000532" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000887" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000405" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="000038" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000740" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000365" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="001404" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="001191" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="001396" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000878" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="001405" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000158" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="001123" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000910" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="001192" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="001380" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000374" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000032" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000721" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="001287" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="001534" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="001408" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000363" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000903" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000047" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="001387" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="001216" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000407" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000422" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000907" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="001381" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000435" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000061" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000413" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="001118" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000847" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="001160" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="001220" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000392" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000041" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000902" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="001403" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="001127" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="001215" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="001034" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000906" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000436" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000241" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000185" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000432" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="000735" bing-rank="94"/>
	<description>Now that my food stamps are cut to nothing (income increases) I find out that ... the food stamp “user” is responsible for being able to go to the fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		ABC News Blogs &gt; Business &gt; Consumer Report 
 Consumer Report 
 Headlines Politics Entertainment Health Lifestyle Business Technology 
 Previous
 U.S. No. 5 in Global Competitiveness, Falls Third Year in a Row Next
 Fed’s Ben Bernanke Still Mum About Stimulus 
 By Nina Terrero
 Sep 7, 2011 5:34pm 
Fast Food Chains Getting Into the Food Stamp Act
   Email 54 Smaller Font Text Larger Text | Print 
In an ever-growing number of states, if you crave a taco or fried chicken from a fast-food restaurant, you can pay for it with food stamps.

Food stamps - known more formally as the USDA’s Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program -  have been in use for grocery staples, such as bread and milk, since 1934, but now, for the first time, they can be used for fast food  in four states across the country.

The number of businesses–including convenience and discount stores, gas stations and pharmacies–that have been approved to accept food stamps has increased by a third over the course of three years from 2005 to 2010, USA Today  reports, and fast-food chains are working hard to get a cut of the federal dollars in Florida, California, Arizona and Michigan.

 The funds allocated to the food stamp program have increased exponentially, from $28.5 billion to $64.7 billion in that same time frame, according to USA Today, and at a time when people have less money to spend, the bump in federal dollars can mean a lot to the fast-industry.

Yum! Brands, based in Louisville, Ky., which operates a string of restaurants that includes Taco Bell, KFC, Long John Silver’s and Pizza Hut, are among those applying for inclusion in the food stamp program, saying that elderly, disabled and homeless people have difficulty preparing meals, ABC affiliate WHAS reported .

Here’s a quick list of fast food restaurants in states that already accept food stamps for restaurant meals:

 Michigan : 

Church’s Chicken

Kentucky Fried Chicken

McDonald’s

Subway

Grandma’s Famous Chicken

Eight Mile Pancake House

Mr. T’s BBQ

Vito’s Pizza

 California : 

Jack in the Box

Subway

El Pollo Loco

Papa Murphy’s Pizza

 Florida 

KFC

Taco Bell

Pizza Hut

Papa Murphy’s Pizza

 Arizona 

Domino’s Pizza

Golden Corral

Southern Cuisine

Rally’s Hamburger
   Email 54 Smaller Font Text Larger Text | Print 
 Related Videos 
 Woman Learns Her&apos;Junk&apos;Jewelry Worth More Than $8,000 High-Fashion Shoes for Low Cost Previous
 U.S. No. 5 in Global Competitiveness, Falls Third Year in a Row Next
 Fed’s Ben Bernanke Still Mum About Stimulus 
 User Comments 
 
Just my opinion but I feel that food stamps should be used to buy basic but nutritious basics like bread, milk, fruits, vegetables and not junk food because as we all know, junk food leads to more health problems down the line which taxpayers will have to pay for. also, it is cheaper to buy the basics and COOK or prepare your own food instead of eating out. Why eat out if you are poor? I’m not poor and even I cook at home because it’s cheaper. It’s about being fiscally responsible and making healthy choices that won’t have negative repercussions down the line (and fast food certainly does!)
 
Posted by: Cfo Guy | September 8, 2011, 12:42 pm 12:42 pm
 
This is welfare. Who in their right mind thinks that people on welfare should be eating in fast food restaurants? In my opinion, the food stamp program should be abolished. Get in your welfare-provided car, drive down to the office, and get your bags of beans, flour, and rice, some powdered milk, some gubmint cheese and peanut butter, and go home and COOK some food for your illegitimate kids. You’ve got plenty of time on your hands, since you don’t work.

It kind of irks me to see people buying steak and lobster at the grocery store with their card, when I work for a living and can’t afford that. I also couldn’t afford to support the hordes of kids that these broodmares are putting out. It’s got to stop, and now would be a good time.
 
Posted by: Lester | September 8, 2011, 3:02 pm 3:02 pm
 
We should live in a society where we have jobs to buy our food so people wouldn’t need Food Stamps
 
Posted by: Charles | September 8, 2011, 4:21 pm 4:21 pm
 
Fast food chains have a high mark-up on their products. All we are doing is giving tax-payer money to these corporations. Surely our anti-fatfood Prez. and his wife cannot be advocating this subsidy to specific corporations while at the same time spending MORE taxpayer dollars to TAKE AWAY similiar lunches from school children and mandatorily teach them about the value of veggies!
 
Posted by: Nonne | September 8, 2011, 4:51 pm 4:51 pm
 
While I don’t agree with allowing food stamps to go toward fast food, I also understand that there are“food deserts”scattered throughout America. A food desert is a district with little or no access to foods needed to maintain a healthy diet but often served by plenty of fast food restaurants. I know that gas is very expensive and for those who are on welfare because they have to be (just got laid off, lost the breadwinner of the household, left in a bad situation with a child that can’t be properly cared for, etc.) I believe that food stamps are a great idea. They allow essentials to be bought. But what if those essentials are out of reach, say, if you live in a food desert and the only thing around you is fast food restaurants? Either the grocery stores must move into neighborhoods where they know they can’t maintain profit…or gas credits could be provided so that welfare recipients can reach said grocery stores…or food stamps are expanded to cover fast food.
The welfare requirements laid out by most states specify that recipients should be seeking employment or training (such as school). These are not people just sitting on their bottoms collecting taxpayers’money. These are people at the bottom and I’m glad they have options and ways of obtaining food that are not outside the law. While fast food might not be the best choice, sometimes it is the only choice.
 
Posted by: Abra | September 8, 2011, 5:01 pm 5:01 pm
 
Foodstamps for fast food!!??? Why??? They should not even be able to use them to buy chips and other junk food, but now they are gonna let them use it for fast food?! Unbelievable.
 
Posted by: Brandy | September 8, 2011, 5:29 pm 5:29 pm
 
Wow, soon fs will be able to be used tor gas to go help crack heads find jobs….this sux
 
Posted by: MeghanEnNc | September 8, 2011, 5:37 pm 5:37 pm
 
I have food stamps and think this is crazy. If I could afford to go to these places, I wouldn’t need food stamps. They won’t let me buy a prepared chicken at the grocery store, but they would let me go get a Big Mac? That makes total sense!
 
Posted by: Ames | September 8, 2011, 5:45 pm 5:45 pm
 
I understand the frustration when it comes to food stamps, but there are people out there who need them. The elderly, the handicapped, and people with children in am emergency type situation in my opinion are the only one’s who should have them. Should they be used for fast food? Never! Not in my opinion.
 
Posted by: Daymon | September 8, 2011, 5:48 pm 5:48 pm
 
WHAT THE HELLLLLL!!!!
ENOUGH IS ENOUGH…THIS IS WRONG.LIKE IT HAS BEEN SAID..YOU CANT WORK..NOW YOU CANT COOK..LAZY AMERICANS GET A JOB AT THE FAST FOOD PLACE IF YOU WANT FAST FOOD..EAT OUT THE DAMN TRASH CANS BUT FOOD STAMPS ARE FOR THE NEEDY…QUIT USING THEM TO PURCHASE MILK AND RETURNING IT AT THE LOCAL STORE SO YOU CAN BUY CIGS…GET A JOB..WRONG WRONG WRONG
 
Posted by: ez69069 | September 8, 2011, 5:51 pm 5:51 pm
 
@ Abra, I myself got foodstamps. I worked for 5 years as a LVN. I was laid off my job due to my patient’s mom being laid off from her job and my nursing hours were cut. I looked for a job for two month”s. I had a choice to let my kids go without food or apply for foodstamps while I looked for a job. Please don’t make it out that everybody that get’s foodstamp is trash with a bunch of kids and no jobs that don’t want to work. We are people too. I can say that I’m working again and things are good for us. I will never look down on anybody who get’s foodstamps. You don’t know their story. By the way. My husband, yes I said husband died from cancer 4 years ago. Please people try and be kind. You never know when you might need a hand. Good day and God bless……
 
Posted by: Marie | September 8, 2011, 6:47 pm 6:47 pm
 
I’m sorry Abra. I didn’t mean to put @ your name.
 
Posted by: Marie | September 8, 2011, 6:51 pm 6:51 pm
 
this also gives people with food stamps another outlet to make money-their friends want fast food so they buy it with fs and trade it for the money!!!
 
Posted by: bill davies | September 8, 2011, 6:56 pm 6:56 pm
 
Since half of the country is unemployed and on food stamps, i see nothing wrong with buying fast food with food stamps. I use to go into Mcdonalds and the lines would be long, now i just walk up to the counter. No one has any money these days&amp;stamps for gas is good, cant find a job without gas in the car. Only people against food stamps are those that cant get approved&amp;those that are working and cant get them. You would have to be crazy not to want free food……
 
Posted by: William | September 8, 2011, 7:04 pm 7:04 pm
 
I work damn near full time and still need food stamps to get by, let us not forget there are still decent people using this program and not abusing it. this new implement seems a bit silly to someone who uses this program on a monthly basis just to survive, i don’t see the need for any“luxury”items when i can barely afford the essentials.
 
Posted by: JG | September 8, 2011, 7:41 pm 7:41 pm
 
The use of Welfare benefits at fast food restaurants is eyebrow raising; however, if you look at the cost of food from the grocery stores on some meals you can save money to choose fast food. It is sad that food with little nutritional value and bad for a person health is more affordable than healthy foods. People make statements to get rid of welfare as they condemn the recipients from obtaining money from the government. What most people fail to realize welfare recipients are not banking the money for personal gain. In most cases, the money is used to sustain life. To get rid of welfare would create a financial problem for many of the small business that depends on the welfare benefits money being spent. The reality is welfare is money that goes back into the greater economy. No one is getting rich off of welfare or really having a good life on it. The benefits are minimum at best. There are social economic dynamics that creates cycle of people who get trapped in that lifestyle but these people have social, psychological, and economic issues that keep them out of the mainstream. Before you make blanket statements review all the factors involved. Unfortunately, fast food is not as bad as a choice of food for what the welfare recipients receive from local grocery stores when it comes to poor nutrition which impacts us as we have to pay for the healthcare for the poor nutrition available for these individuals.
 
Posted by: Salina J | September 8, 2011, 8:05 pm 8:05 pm
 
Ok. Some of these responses are really appalling to me. I am a single mother, of twin girls, who DOES work, and I go to school full time…And I receive food stamps. If I didn’t receive the help I do, I wouldnt be able to feed my children. Although I agree that allowing this program to be accepted in fast food chains is absolutely absurd, and will only aide in childhood obesity, I still don’t think that everyone that uses it, abuses it. So, please, think before you speak next time, because some of those comments were hurtful.
 
Posted by: Jess | September 8, 2011, 8:12 pm 8:12 pm
 
yes some people make statements without using there brain first. i worked for the welfare office and was still eligable for their benefits! people think before you judge. people who live in glass houses shouldn’t throw stones.
 
Posted by: butterfly | September 8, 2011, 8:33 pm 8:33 pm
 
WTH??? Food stamps are to purchase foods, not PREPARED HOT READY TO EAT food, food that needs to be prepared, even if only made into sandwiches. I have always understood that I can purchase a cold rotisserie chicken but not the hot one.

Now that my food stamps are cut to nothing (income increases) I find out that my local KFC accepts food stamps?? I can’t fry chicken…have tried every recipe and piece of advice for over 30 years…I have been saving my splurge money for fried chicken at KFC…I could have been using my stamps? NOT FAIR!!!

As to the fact that they allow this usage of food stamps at all? It shouldn’t be allowed. If a person has difficulty preparing food there are plenty of volunteers and medicaid paid help for that. I suffer from arthritis in the winters that puts my hands into unusable claws for days at at time. I have a chore services worker come over and prepare meals for me and my son. She puts them in the freezer so all we have to do is microwave or bake our meals. These people can do the same. Senior citizens, especially, do not need to eat the fast food offered because the sodium and fat content could kill them…unless this is the government’s way of doing just that.
 
Posted by: Elizabeth Fox | September 8, 2011, 8:53 pm 8:53 pm
 
Why not use food stamps for junk food/fast food-at 7/11 they buy red bull etc. so why not,what a joke.
 
Posted by: beth moore | September 8, 2011, 8:58 pm 8:58 pm
 
wrong wrong wrong–another way to waste taxpayer dollars.
 
Posted by: V A in N Y | September 8, 2011, 9:15 pm 9:15 pm
 
GREAT!!!! Sounds like a BRILLIANT Democratic idea….MORE oBESITY…more FREE healthcare hard-working Americans hace to pay for!!!! UGH….Hurry up 2012….he is KILLING us ALL!!!
 
Posted by: Sissy | September 8, 2011, 9:27 pm 9:27 pm
 
It really upsets me that there are sooo many ignorant people in the world who think that the only people who receive food stamps are people who dont want to work and who have tons of kids. not true. i am a 20 year old who has no kids and was looking for a job for more than 3 months! i receive no help from either of my parents and the only way for me to have food was to get food stamps. while i dont agree that food fast should be bought with food stamps, you must admit that it will be cheaper to go and get food from taco bell than to grocery shop. and with me not having a car i have to find a ride to the grocery store and have people wait for me while i shop. when it might be just a little easier for someone to pull into a drivethru
 
Posted by: sieswill | September 8, 2011, 9:39 pm 9:39 pm
 
ATTENTION !!!!! Only Homeless Welfare recepiants can purchase food at Restaurants not regular welfare recipients!! Some people are hurting and hungry GOD HELP US. So now you know , its for people who have no Access to a stove and refrigerator. Homeless people remember them
 
Posted by: Sunny Delight | September 8, 2011, 10:29 pm 10:29 pm
 
ABC News left that out of the Article!!
 
Posted by: Sunny Delight | September 8, 2011, 10:31 pm 10:31 pm
 
I can honestly say that allowing the food stamps to be used on fast food is ridiculous but to say that everyone on food stamps must have loads of children and don’t work is even more ridiculous and shows just how little you really know about that whole system. It takes alot of work and documentation to even be considered let alone approved. I am a single mom of twin toddlers and I work my butt off full-time just to make enough in a month to provide what is needed let alone be able to provide food for my girls. I can honestly say that if I didn’t have the help of the food stamps I would probably be starving right about now because my children always have and always will come first in anything that I do.
 
Posted by: MommaX2Angels | September 9, 2011, 3:36 am 3:36 am
 
Hey, all you food stamp recipients who claim you are the true needy, and worthy recipients of food stamps–get over yourself. No one begrudges the truly worthy recipients any assistance–but you are by NO means the average recipient! Believe me, I’ve lived most of my life next door to welfare recipients, and they are MILKING the system, and living a MUCH more lavish lifestyles than their neighbors who are NOT on welfare. I can’t afford to go out to eat, so why in the hell should my income be stolen from me, and given to them so THEY can go out? Geez, I have the $10/mo basic cable package, eat at home every night, wear home-made dresses, and my neighbor on welfare wears designer jeans, has HBO AND Cinimax, and now will be eating out regularly?!!! WTH!!?

If they need food stamps, then they don’t Need to be eating at a restaurant! Period!
 
Posted by: KAM | September 9, 2011, 7:28 am 7:28 am
 
OK seriously? I was born in an OLD log cabin where you could literally feel the wind blowing through the logs. My dad died when I was 5 months old&amp;my mother had me, and 2 little boys to raise alone. We had a cistern that caught rain water, we had an outhouse, we raised a garden in the summer&amp;canned that food for consumption in the winter. We heated with wood that WE cut&amp;hauled,&amp;we had goats for milk, oil lamps&amp;candles for light,&amp;never, EVER got welfare or food stamps. We ate rabbits&amp;sqirrels, but never missed a meal. My point is….we FOUND a way.
Then as an adult my husband left me with our newborn baby, a huge mountain of debt with collectors nearly leaving US homeless, and no family available to help me out. I did not get welfare or foodstamps then either. I have always found a job. They may not have paid what I wanted to get paid, and may have had horrible working conditions&amp;atrocious hours….but I did it, and anyone else can do it too…..if they try hard enough. The REAL problem is that nobody wants to even try when they can have everything HANDED TO THEM!!!! It is ridiculous. $64billion dollars in food stamps last year alone, and that’s just ONE gov’t assistance program. Yeah, I wonder WHY this country is in financial crisis????? If we don’t contact our elected officials about these atrocities, they will continue to get worse. It needs to STOP.
 
Posted by: MR | September 9, 2011, 7:35 pm 7:35 pm
 
Typical in a state like Michigan, where a million dollar lottery winner can collect food stamps“legally”…and an economically–and common sense bankrupt state like California…the mass of retiree’s in FL and AZ explains those states…As restaurant food costs about 10x as much per calorie than store bought–an obvious example of big lobbying over common sense in government.
 
Posted by: yeah.i.said.it | September 10, 2011, 9:53 am 9:53 am
 
Why is Papa Murphy’s considered a fast food chain? Depending on what you order and bake at home, their pizzas can be quite nutritious and cost-effective.
 
Posted by: Publius | September 12, 2011, 3:26 pm 3:26 pm
 
The whole argument about food deserts doesn’t hold water with me either. There are plenty of corner stores where you can buy food instead of restaurants. If you can’t afford gas, then take the bus.
 
Posted by: Michelle | September 23, 2011, 7:35 pm 7:35 pm
 
Restaurants should not be able to accept food stamps. This is corporate welfare. In fact, food stamps should be for the basics: Fresh fruits and vegetables, eggs, dairy products (milk, cheese, yogurt), and basic meat, poultry, and fish (fresh or frozen). I used to work at a grocery store and with people who use WIC, there are only certain things that they could buy. It should be the same way with food stamps. I know there are worthy recipients who if they did not receive food stamps, they would go hungry. However, they will get more bang for their buck using it at the supermarket or even the corner store.
 
Posted by: Michelle | September 23, 2011, 7:52 pm 7:52 pm
 
There are a lot of people who milk the system. I live in Philadelphia and spend a lot of time in inner city, high-poverty areas. I know people who misuse food stamps. One person has a baby’s mother and children who receive food stamps, yet each child has a flat screen TV and cable and he spent money on a lavish birthday party for his son. In poor neighborhoods, there are a lot of people who don’t report cash income that they make through things like doing tattoos or doing hair. On top of that, a lot of kids don’t live with both parents, so the food stamps are based on the one parent’s income, even if the other parent is contributing money.
 
Posted by: Michelle | September 23, 2011, 8:00 pm 8:00 pm
 
I’m willing to help poor people, but they have to do their part. If you have a bunch of tattoos, expensive hairstyles (e.g. weave, color), a smart phone, or go to the salon to get manicures and pedicures, you need not be on food stamps. If you buy the latest Jordans for your child or a new backpack every year (even if the backpack they had was fine), you don’t need to be on food stamps. If you’re out at the club, paying for drinks and a cover charge, you don’t need to be on food stamps. If you have a 40 inch flatscreen TV, you need not be on food stamps.
 
Posted by: Michelle | September 23, 2011, 8:00 pm 8:00 pm
 
With foreclosures and unemployment being at its highest (by the way these 4 states are in the top 10 for foreclosures) the government is redistributing tax dollars to our depressed economy. I have NEVER been able to find employment quickly&amp;have a Masters Degree. Why would I want to work greater than 40 hrs/week when I qualify for programs in place. I like my free time&amp;a balanced life. Working 60-80-120 hrs/week is obsurd!!! Many free hobbies can take up free time (ie reading, beach, exercising, etc). Just because our fore fathers“walked up hill, both ways, in a blizzard doesn’t mean we have to do it too!”Otherwise, we’d all b living in log cabins with no lights and hunting bear. Get real“behind the times!”It’s time for change and the majority of the American people stepped up to the plate&amp;wanted to be counted….YOU VOTED FOR OBAMA–CHANGE! Allow it to happen. Change is difficult. You always know when someone is doing his job because people complain: let Obama do his! If you don’t like the change, then show up at the polls again 2012&amp;CAST YOUR VOTE YOU UNCOUNTED SILENT PEOPLE who might be tired of being silent???? I like my qualified programs that allow me to enjoy life while I am broke instead of being anesthetized thru it by having to work 80+ hrs/wk. Thank you! Designer clothes??? Ever heard of a Thrift Store? Anyone can shop there including people who don’t qualify for any program.

Cinderella
Thank you to my programs which allows me to enjoy my life journey without having to work 80+ hrs/week and work thru it all to my death!
 
Posted by: Cynthia Waters | September 27, 2011, 8:43 am 8:43 am
 
I would like to say that being able to buy fast food with food stamps is rediculous! I live in AZ, and had food stamps for almost a year before the federal dolloars were cut from the program, which is when they implemented the new rules here which makes me unelligible because I don’t have children and I go to school full time. That is whack and I am very upset about this. When they learned I started going to college fulltime actually is when they said I am no longer eligible. Now, somedays I have to figure out how I am supposed to survive on a pack of M&amp;M’s a day. It is sad but true. College is something that I did to better myself and make something of myself in hopes that one day I can make a family and be able to provide for them too. So, what little help I did get from any resource (in this case the government) is gone. Thanks, now the government has given a whole new meaning to the term“starving college student”.
 
Posted by: Kristin | October 11, 2011, 11:08 pm 11:08 pm
 
there are actually people like me that live with there parents that have a nice house and recieve foodstamps because PARENTS WILL NOT FEED ME!!! I am over 18 disabled and unable to work, so you people that think“we”are using the system WAKE UP and smell the coffee and actually listen to the“slum bag”peoples stories, and then maybe you will agree with why we have food stamps. And in florida you only get $200 a month, WOOPIE DOO wtf is that gonna buy you? NOTHING not 3 meals a day. people on welfare get $400 a month for each child…. Ok and free housing. why dont you try to survive on $400 a month and feed yourself on $200 and well see if your still bickering!!!
 
Posted by: travis | October 14, 2011, 12:49 am 12:49 am
 
and why dont you people feed yourself the essentials like meat, and vegetables. Well see how far your money goes on that. Chicken is like $2.00 a LB and tomatoes are like $4.00 a LB the reason why food stamp recipients are buying junk food is because its CHEAPER!!!!!!! As said before the state doesn’t give you enough money to live“luxuriously”as you may say they do!!!!
 
Posted by: travis | October 14, 2011, 12:52 am 12:52 am
 
I notice how everyone is complaining as if the food stamp“user”is responsible for being able to go to the fast food“restaurant”. Did you NOT read the article? The fast food suppliers are the ones who LOBBIED congress to allow this practice. Why does NO ONE BLAME THEM? Have you noticed that these corporations are getting their way? How they are getting more and more taxpayer dollars shifted to their coffers? It is time to speak up and STOP this practice.
 
Posted by: scoobiejim | October 20, 2011, 12:54 pm 12:54 pm
 
I’m 22, work full time, and on food stamps with no kids.

I have my own apartment and pay all my bills, alone. I also have dietary restrictions (allergic to dairy) thus my groceries do cost more to find items without milk products in them. I also maintain a healthy diet to keep my weight under control. Not everyone on FS buys junk. I do buy some chips, diet soda, and gum, and the occasional Oreo cookie (dairy free chocolate fix!). I have every single right to buy a little junk like everyone else. However, I stock whole grain bread, brown rices, dark greens, lean meats, etc and cook at home.

Being able to buy fast food is pretty crazy, but the companies are trying to get as much money as possible. I’m against it, but I do think people who cannot prepare meals or keep their food on them (homeless for example) should be allowed to. Is it healthy? No, absolutely not. But what are you going to do if you’re in that situation?
 
Posted by: Onica | October 23, 2011, 2:39 pm 2:39 pm
 
Its really sad to see so many ill construed beliefs and ideas contaminate the statistics of welfare. Currently you have to have a job and work at least 20 hours a week, to get and maintain food stamps if your able to work. Those of you who put everyone on food stamps in the same category of being lazy, unwilling to work, and popping out babies have obviously done little to NO research on what you boldly cry about on the internet. All of you make yourselves seem very uneducated, uninformed and have no willingness to learn the truth. I have done a great amount of research on food stamps for many resources. But then again i cant blame you all, since Americans are known for not caring to learn about anything that doesn’t directly affect them.
-An exception to the“American Statistic”
 
Posted by: Brittany | November 14, 2011, 2:24 am 2:24 am
 
I get food stamps to help support my family, but I also work to pay my bills. I feel that this is just a way for businesses to benefit from the people who are too lazy to cook and do anything with themselves to go blow their money on McDonalds etc, to quick feed their children and themselves. A smart plot by the businesses but this I believe will terribly increase obesity in Adults and especially children because most of the families living off of the government to survive don’t know how to raise their children anyways, and will not feed them healthy foods you can get at a grocery store. The Food Stamps I get I try to eat very healthy and feed my daughter healthy foods and I need the food stamp help because right now I just can’t afford all the food and pay all the bills alone. I was raised well and proud of it, and I do not abuse the system, but I am still embarrassed to go to the store with a food stamp card. It is because of people that abuse it and you can almost tell exactly who they are just by how they look and act. I just believe all in all about food stamps is that they should interview their customers a little more closely and do home inspections, follow receipts on where the money is spent (as in make the consumer report every monthly spending amount to where and what items, and pay attention to how they live their lives as if they even try to do things themselves and work their way towards getting out of the system atleast instead off popping out multiple children and infesting like roaches while the government supports their children that wil not even be raised as anything else but more mooches off the government, I believe this will eliminate the problem. The people that deserve the help will be sorted from the losers who choose to be happy with themselves as the lowest of low. Homeless people need the fast food chains to open their doors to them because I agree with the woman above stating this in her comment. Homeless people do not have access to stoves and very few microwaves I’m sure. Homeless shelters may provide one or two microwaves, but still no stoves, so it may be a good idea for the homeless but not for the people who’s job title is“Welfare Mooch.”I believe this leads back to the monitoring I mentioned. Once monitored, these people will either have nothing to hide from because they are not abusing the system, they will change if they want to keep help with food and housing, or they will fail and lose their priviledges. Let this be the way to sort them out. Plus this will open up more jobs as inspectors so it will benefit the employment rate as well. I have seen people work hard for their money and still need help with food stamps. I am one of them. And I believe unless you are completely unable to work, which disabled is B.S. because there are plenty of jobs you can do working on the phone, even from home, then you still need to try while getting help from the government. It’s a helping hand to help you live, show some class and respect.
 
Posted by: Darryl | November 26, 2011, 11:25 am 11:25 am
 
What people need to relize is your tax money weather you like it or not goes to people on welfare it goes to rich people it goes elderly people and everything else so no matter how mucg you complain you cant control what the government takes out your check and puts it towards what ever the governments wants.
 
Posted by: tamara | November 26, 2011, 7:26 pm 7:26 pm
 
I dont think it really matters what people can use there food stamps for because they get x amount a month and when they spend x amount there gone and no mater what they are spending them on they are still paid for by taxes and in all reality food stamp create jobs, there a company that makes the cards, there a company that makes the card readers, hell if more people are able to spend money the the demand for people to take that money goes up like at a fast food place if there are more costumers there will be more staff and if the costumers continue to grow the store will or they will open a new one so by spending food stamps people are creating jobs
 
Posted by: Aaron | December 9, 2011, 3:30 am 3:30 am
 
I am all for this about using food stamps at fast food places or towards hot food especially in Pennsylvania. I am a disabled individual and I find it very dificult to have enough money to even purchase something to drink. People do not realize how had it is for a person to live on $725 a month and be disabled.
 
Posted by: Sarah | January 19, 2012, 4:47 pm 4:47 pm
 
Why idoes it matter so much what type of food people can buy with their ebt cards? Since everyone is complaining about our tax money, let’s not forget the government also used that money (and a lot of it) to bail out big businesses who were in the hole, not to mention fund an expensive war. The food stamp program is just a small percentage of where our money is going. Those of you who have jobs and don’t need foodstamps, count yourselves lucky. Some people actually need the help and the way this economy is going, more and more people are going to need help. I don’t use foodstamps since I’m fortunate enough not to need it but I have no problem with those who actually need it.
 
Posted by: SHEILA | February 2, 2012, 8:36 pm 8:36 pm
 
This is rubbish!!! I cannot believe America is doing this! This is a disgrace! As an American they should NOT be allowed to use foodstamps in a fast food chain!! They should be allowed only in grocery stores for consumption of the basic essentials! Its already bad enough that we have so many that are on foodstamps that don’t even need them. This is only going to make this worse!!!!!
 
Posted by: Suprena | February 4, 2012, 6:15 pm 6:15 pm
 
I am 22, disabled, in school full-time and receive no help from my parents.

I love working, but I can’t where I am in life right now. Instead, I live on $160 a month and $200 in foodstamps. That’s all I get. I don’t by crap and I would NEVER buy Fastfood, even if it were an option in my state. I hard a hard time even coming up with the money for tampons, let alone anything else. Do not make the mistake of assuming everyone who gets aid lives a good, luxury, lazy life.
 
Posted by: Ashley | February 6, 2012, 4:10 pm 4:10 pm
 
For all the idiots out there.Food stamps to use at fast food restraunts was approved for the homeless who do not have kitchens to cook or heat up food.

NOT EVERYONE HAS A KITCHEN
 
Posted by: mylie | February 9, 2012, 1:43 pm 1:43 pm
 
Food Stamps are no longer aimed as assistance of the poor. It is to generate income for corporate farmers and corporations. More corporate welfare than anything else
 
Posted by: Deon | February 28, 2012, 1:16 pm 1:16 pm
 
For all the idiots out there.Food stamps to use at fast food restraunts was approved for the HOMELESS who do not have kitchens to cook or heat up food.

NOT EVERYONE HAS A KITCHEN, i will re post this many time so you guys understand this, the media is notorious for misinformation
 
Posted by: dill-wisconsin | March 23, 2012, 4:44 pm 4:44 pm
 
I am on foodstamps, and yes up until recently I was homeless with 3 children. I can tell you from experience, that getting a hot meal was not easy. Where we were the soup kitchen was there mon- friday. But come sat and sunday you were on your own. So do not tell me if you that claim noone on foodstamps deserves a hot meal.. DO NOT sit there and say if your little ones were crying because they were hungry you would not use it. I do however agree there is a way to make it stretch more. These are you run of the meal“value”menu places. It is not like they are being told they can go to a 5 star sit down. You all that have never had to depend on the help sit there so self righteous. Just remember everyone of you are 1 paycheck away from being in our situation at anytime.
So many of you judge and know nothing about each person’s situation. When your chilld cries because they are hungry, tell me you won’t take advantage. I can agree that it should be restricted to HOT Foods at the grocery store. COme on they taste fresher and they go further.
but you all are just as wrong for judging. I hope none of you are ever in that situation, but if you are I hope noone is as cold and heartless as you all are, because it is hard getting up when you have so many willing to keep you down.
 
Posted by: Tammy | April 8, 2012, 7:47 am 7:47 am
 
what exponent raises $28.5 billion to $64.7 billion? Exaggeration on a website or just a poorly written article?
It seems appropriate to me that if somebody qualifies for food stamps, and doesn’t have a kitchen, that they be able to eat hot food.
Are there problems with food stamps? yes. Is this one of them? no. Although, there could be a requirement added that customers using food stamps are given a cost differential to reduce the rate.
As for some of the other comments on this thread: Bullies!“crack heads”? really?
 
Posted by: Fred | April 13, 2012, 1:27 pm 1:27 pm
 
For the majority of people who commented–did you miss the“homeless”and“disabled”part of the article. If there is no kitchen in which to cook, or the recipients are physically unable to cook, what do you propose as an alternative?
 
Posted by: tgeer | April 20, 2012, 9:14 pm 9:14 pm
 Top 
Leave a Reply

Do you have more information about this topic? If so, please click here to contact the editors of ABC News.

 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 

 
 About Consumer Report 
Tips and advice on how to be a savvy consumer.
 Categories 
 Companies Consumer Report Economy 
 Recent Business Posts 
 Weekend Freebies: Get $146.50 of Food and Fun Brand Name vs. Store Brand:‘GMA’Tastes Breakfast Cereals JC Penney Hit By New Credit Downgrade Chevy Vehicles: Love It or Return It Fla. Man Claims Club Stripped Him of $50K 
 Top Stories from ABC News 
 
 Rock Music History May Have Been Found in Attic 
 
 Baby Boomers Buying Retro Products 
 
 Weekend Freebies: Get $146.50 of Food and Fun 
 
 Brand Name vs. Store Brand:&apos;GMA&apos;Tastes Breakfast Cereals 
 
 JC Penney Hit By New Downgrade 
 
 Subscribe 
 RSS 
 
 Twitter Facebook
	</body>
</document>
