<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001671" url="http://answers.walmart.com/answers/1336/product/8056730/questions.htm?page=3&amp;scrollToTop=true" time="2012-07-12-17:26" support="4" score="0.004488194524879781" bingtitle="Walmart The First Years The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in-1 ..." webtitle="Walmart The First Years The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in-1 Baby Bassinet : Questions, Answers, How To, FAQs, Tips, Advice, Answers, Buying Guide">
			<query id="000544" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="001017" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="000996" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="001363" bing-rank="141"/>
	<description>... for The First Years The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in ... bassinet, bedside sleeper, play seat and changing table ... Yes, but you have to order it directly from Learning ...</description>
	<body>
		Search Product Q&amp;A Search Q&amp;A 
Looking for Answers about The First Years The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in-1 Baby Bassinet?
 Print this page See all Walmart Questions and Answers ACTIVITIES AND GAMES ( Q: 1553 A: 4364) APPLIANCES ( Q: 15762 A: 51786) AUDIO VIDEO ( Q: 9852 A: 22105) BABY AND MATERNITY APPAREL ( Q: 135 A: 611) BABY CARE ( Q: 3589 A: 11960) BABY GEAR ( Q: 7780 A: 19558) BABY NURSERY ( Q: 7944 A: 17916) BABY BEDDING ( Q: 907 A: 2093) BABY DECOR ( Q: 773 A: 1725) CASE PIECES ( Q: 981 A: 2009) CRIBS ( Q: 3511 A: 6682) BASSINETS AND CRADLES ( Q: 361 A: 597) BED RAILS ( Q: 122 A: 101) CRIB AND CHANGERS ( Q: 592 A: 1018) CRIBS ( Q: 1780 A: 3745) MATTRESSES ( Q: 530 A: 1054) PORTABLE CRIBS ( Q: 126 A: 167) ROCKERS ( Q: 655 A: 1295) TODDLER ( Q: 1117 A: 4112) BEAUTY ( Q: 4265 A: 9050) BIKES AND RIDE ONS ( Q: 9794 A: 23393) BOOKS ( Q: 898 A: 1538) BOYS TOYS AND MUSIC ( Q: 2172 A: 3071) CAMERAS AND CAMCORDERS ( Q: 7980 A: 12452) COMPUTER PERIPHERALS AND ACCESSORIES ( Q: 15840 A: 28956) COMPUTERS ( Q: 3411 A: 6194) DOLLS ( Q: 723 A: 2216) DOMESTICS ( Q: 17976 A: 38327) FITNESS ( Q: 4975 A: 13915) FURNITURE ( Q: 28841 A: 70981) GROCERY ( Q: 2047 A: 1276) HEALTH AND WELLNESS ( Q: 7068 A: 10268) HOME IMPROVEMENT ( Q: 8275 A: 14631) HOUSEHOLD ( Q: 1331 A: 1953) JEWELRY AND GIFTS ( Q: 5343 A: 6131) KIDS APPAREL ( Q: 327 A: 908) MENS APPAREL ( Q: 1240 A: 3684) MOVIES ( Q: 3270 A: 6189) MUSIC ( Q: 370 A: 496) NON APPAREL ( Q: 1134 A: 1760) OFFICE SUPPLY AND CRAFTS ( Q: 4011 A: 6143) OUTDOOR LIVING ( Q: 9776 A: 18072) OUTDOOR PLAY ( Q: 5982 A: 13762) OUTDOOR SPORTS ( Q: 9080 A: 18196) PETS ( Q: 3551 A: 8176) PORTABLE ELECTRONICS ( Q: 10526 A: 21728) PRESCHOOL AND LEARNING ( Q: 1739 A: 4861) SEASONAL AND CELEBRATIONS ( Q: 1450 A: 1921) SPORTS EQUIPMENT ( Q: 2576 A: 4661) STORE GIFT CARDS ( Q: 1049 A: 2120) TIRES AND AUTOMOTIVE ( Q: 8893 A: 8458) TV ( Q: 7844 A: 19546) UNASSIGNED DEPT ( Q: 78 A: 13) VIDEO GAMES ( Q: 8562 A: 18921) WIRELESS ( Q: 7107 A: 12303) WOMENS APPAREL ( Q: 1458 A: 6338) Most Recent Questions Recent Question: Does this bassinet come with the mattress? (see more details) Asked on: The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in-1 Baby Bassinet Recent Question: What size sheet fits this mattress? (How many inches is the mattress?) I want to be able to buy some spare sheets online. Thanks! (see more details) Asked on: Contours - Classique 3-in-1 Wood Bassinet, Dark Cherry Recent Question: Is this bassinet a rocking bassinet? (see more details) Asked on: Delta - Sweet Beginnings Satin Lane Bassinet Recent Question: How does the carrier recline back? (see more details) Asked on: The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in-1 Baby Bassinet Recent Question: Looking at the arms reach co sleeper, says it attaches to the bed, how does it attach to the bed? (see more details) Asked on: CO-SLEEPER Brand Mini Bassinet, Natural Questions with Most Recent Answers Question: Does this come with a mattress or anything? And what all comes with this? (see answer) Asked on: Summer Infant - Ladybug Soothing Bassinet, Pink Question: How well does it roll on carpet? (see answer) Asked on: Summer Infant - Ladybug Soothing Bassinet, Pink Question: What size sheet fits this mattress? (How many inches is the mattress?) I want to be able to buy some spare sheets online. Thanks! (see answer) Asked on: Contours - Classique 3-in-1 Wood Bassinet, Dark Cherry Question: How does the carrier recline back? (see answer) Asked on: The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in-1 Baby Bassinet Question: what type of material is the disney princess bassinet made out of? (see answer) Asked on: Disney Princess - Bassinet See all Walmart Questions and Answers &gt; BABY NURSERY Q&amp;A &gt; CRIBS Q&amp;A &gt; BASSINETS AND CRADLES Q&amp;A 
Customer Questions&amp;Answers for
 The First Years The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in-1 Baby Bassinet 
 The First Years bassinet for your baby is a portable sleeper, bassinet, bedside sleeper, play seat and changing table all in one. The First Years 5-in-1 bassinet has a strong handle that lets you carry your sleeping baby from one room to another. With a sturdy base, this baby bassinet can either rock back and forth or lock into place. Customer Questions&amp;Answers: 66 Questions | 120 Answers Ask a New Question Overall Rating: 4.4 out of 5 Read All 296 Reviews 269 Choose a sort order Questions With the Most Helpful Answers Most Recent Questions Oldest Questions Questions With Most Recent Answers Questions With Oldest Answers Questions With Most Answers Can You Answer These Questions? 
Questions&amp;Answers for The First Years The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in-1 Baby Bassinet
 Question 
can u autually rock it back and fourth like a cradle?
 asked 3 years, 5 months ago By an anonymous customer - belen on The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in-1 Baby Bassinet 2 answers Answers answer 1 Yes, it has cradle type legs answered 1 year, 10 months ago By NBey - Philadelphia, PA answer 2 The Bassinet will rock with the wheels retracted or not rock with the wheels down and locked as you wish. Chaging back and forth is a breeze and takes just seconds with no tools necessary. It rocks side to side. You must rock it by hand tho, not automatic. answered 3 years, 5 months ago By GrandmaPenny - Wenatchee, WA Question 
Do the plush charaters that dangle detatch?
 asked 3 years, 4 months ago By an anonymous customer on The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in-1 Baby Bassinet 2 answers Answers answer 1 yes they are attatched by a velcro loop answered 1 year, 8 months ago By jenisangel2007 - seattle, wa answer 2 yes they do, but the string part that they hang on don&apos;t so when you detach them you just have the characters and a small ring at the top where they attach to something. answered 3 years, 4 months ago By eeyorelover05 - Missouri Question 
Can you purchase and replace bedding?
 asked 3 years, 1 month ago By kferris209 on The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in-1 Baby Bassinet 2 answers Answers answer 1 Yes, but you have to order it directly from Learning Center website. For $4.99 plus shipping and handling. You get a replacement sheet and mattress pad. answered 2 years, 2 months ago By hchawley - Idaho answer 2 yes you can you can buy just regular bassinet bedding. you wont be able to put the buckle in it for a play seat but if you want different bedding to have just in case of spit up in the middle of the night regular bassinet bedding will work answered 3 years ago By babylove1215 - jamestown,ca Question 
what type of batteries does it require
 asked 2 years, 11 months ago By 1030 on The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in-1 Baby Bassinet 2 answers Answers answer 1 AA answered 1 year, 10 months ago By NBey - Philadelphia, PA answer 2 It requires AA batteries. answered 2 years, 11 months ago By Texmom01 - Texas Question 
I am expecting twin Grandbabies; a boy and a girl. Does product come in any other colors but beige?
 asked 2 years, 9 months ago By lazyway - Indialantic, FL on The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in-1 Baby Bassinet 2 answers Answers answer 1 No only beige, 
 Top 1000 Contributor 
 answered 1 year, 6 months ago By MrsC2012 - Spokane WA answer 2 Not that I saw. The l ight and music is
a plus answered 2 years, 7 months ago By NewGrandmother1007 - Lincoln MI Question 
How much weigh does it hold?
 asked 2 years, 4 months ago By valerie8464 on The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in-1 Baby Bassinet 2 answers Answers answer 1 in the manual it says to stop using when baby is 17.5lbs. answered 1 year, 8 months ago By jenisangel2007 - seattle, wa answer 2 it says on the product that you can put your baby in it until he or she can push themselves up on their bellies unassisted or up to 17.5 pounds whichever comes first. answered 2 years, 2 months ago By sassygrl06 Question 
Does this bassinet have wheels?
 asked 2 years, 2 months ago By an anonymous customer on The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in-1 Baby Bassinet 2 answers Answers answer 1 yes answered 1 year, 10 months ago By NBey - Philadelphia, PA answer 2 Yes, with a braking button so it can&apos;t move when stationary. answered 2 years, 2 months ago By hchawley - Idaho Question 
Is the height adjustable?
 asked 2 years ago By khollow on The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in-1 Baby Bassinet 2 answers Answers answer 1 Yes, the bassinet is adjustable. It has several settings to choose from. answered 1 year, 8 months ago By Becca419 - PA answer 2 Yes it is and it will lock into different height positions. answered 2 years ago By OttumwaMomOfThree - Ottumwa, Iowa Question 
What kind of batteries does this take? I read that rechargeables do not work.
 asked 1 year, 11 months ago By an anonymous customer on The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in-1 Baby Bassinet 2 answers Answers answer 1 If I am remembering correct, AA answered 1 year, 10 months ago By NBey - Philadelphia, PA answer 2 4 AA batteries answered 1 year, 10 months ago By Havreitte - Havre, MT Question 
I have lost it&apos;s user manual, and I cannot assemble the Vinyl covered changing table part of the bassinet.
 I have lost it&apos;s user manual, and I cannot assemble the Vinyl covered changing table part of the bassinet. I searched for the user manual online but unable to find one. Can I please get the manual or information on how to assemble the changing table part of the bassinet? asked 1 year, 9 months ago By an anonymous customer on The First Years - Carry-Me-Near 5-in-1 Baby Bassinet 2 answers Answers answer 1 Contact The First Years customer service, and I&apos;m sure they can help you. answered 1 year, 4 months ago By meand8 - Madison Heights, VA answer 2 I can email the instructions to if you cannot read them. The last part of the instrucs are as follows since I can only post two pics..
5. Squeeze rod supports into place make sure they are firmly inserted into holes in stand.
6. Snap brackets over fabric supports. Align holes and push short screw into place secure with nut using pliers
7. Wrap velcro fasteners around fabric support tubes and foam pad doing center one last, repeat for other side.
8. Pull fabric over and straighten ruffle. Images for this Answer (click to see full-size image) (Click anywhere inside this popup to close it) Part 1 (Click anywhere inside this popup to close it) Part 2 answered 1 year, 7 months ago By llavigne - Goffstown, NH 3 of 7 total pages Previous Next ©2010 Wal-Mart Stores, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
