<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001163" url="http://abcnews.go.com/Sports/" time="2012-07-12-16:36" support="15" score="0.007449958353679195" bingtitle="Sports News | Wide World of Sports - ABC News" webtitle="Sports News | Wide World of Sports - ABC News">
			<query id="000806" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="001157" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="001434" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="001139" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000963" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="001148" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="001182" bing-rank="242"/>
			<query id="001309" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000812" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="000711" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="001283" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="001277" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="000994" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="001144" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="000932" bing-rank="200"/>
	<description>Get the latest sports news from the NFL, NBA, MLB, NHL and more. Get football, baseball, basketball news photos and videos at ABCNews.</description>
	<body>
		Hot Topics: 
 Joe Paterno  Romney NAACP  Kristen Chenoweth 
 
 Home U.S. World Politics Video Investigative Health Entertainment Money Tech Travel 
 Latest Headlines 
 Report: Paterno &apos;Concealed&apos; Sandusky Abuse Avalanche in French Alps Leaves 9 Dead JC Penney Hit By New Downgrade FDA Sued Over Right to Free Sperm Baby Boomers Buying Retro Products 
 WATCH VIDEO: Most Popular » Out-of-Court Settlement for TomKat? Adderall Prescriptions Increased 750... More Headlines 
 Two Fla. Teens Attacked by Gators Team USA Gets Uniforms From China Calif. Man Finds 50,000 Bees in Home Film Exposes Transgender Life in Asia Angry? Be a Fly on the Wall 
 In The News 
 Dick Cheney Penn State Probe Propecia Effects National Anthem 
 
 Watch Live Louis Freeh Holds Press Conference on Penn State Report 
 Slideshows ESPN Sports open slideshow Athletes Plagued By Injury More Slideshows » Wide World of Sports Penn State&apos;s Sandusky Report Will Draw Scrutiny Freeh: Penn St. officials had &apos;total disregard&apos; for safety, welfare of Jerry Sandusky victims Trainer O&apos;Neill Drops Appeal of Suspension Trainer Doug O&apos;Neill drops appeal of suspension, will serve 40-day punishment starting Aug. 19 6 Dead in French Alps Avalanche Mont Blanc summer avalanche leaves 9 climbers dead, 11 injured and 4 others missing AP Source: Saints, Brees Apart on Guaranteed Money Person familiar with negotiations: Brees, Saints more than $10 million apart in the guarantees Heat Get 2 New Shooters; No Deal for Magic Center Heat get 2 new shooters in Allen, Lewis; Magic can&apos;t find a good deal to move their center Magic GM: Howard Talks With Nets &apos;Stationary&apos; Magic GM: Howard trade talks with Nets &apos;stationary,&apos; but remain open with Brooklyn, and others Steve Nash Surprised to Find Himself With Lakers Unlikely adventure: Steve Nash says he&apos;s still surprised he ended up with the LA Lakers Trade Talk Should Heat up in Baseball&apos;s 2nd Half Trade talk, injuries and the Pirates are talk of the town as baseball begins 2nd half   Most Viewed → 
 Nearly Half of Newborns at Tenn. Hospital Drug-Dependent W.Va. Sheriff Says Woman Tortured Baldness Drug&apos;s Sex Effects Possibly Permanent, Study Says Photos: Athletes Bare All in &apos;Body Issue&apos; Photos: Lingerie Model&apos;s Cheeky Pose Photos: Kate Upton Poses Like Pam More Popular News » 
 Follow Us External links are provided for reference purposes. ABC News is not responsible for the content of external Internet sites. Copyright©2012 ABC News Internet Ventures. Yahoo! - ABC News Network Back to top 
Sections

 U.S. World Politics Investigative Health Entertainment Money Technology Travel Recipes News Topics 
 
Shows

 NY Med Good Morning America World News with Diane Sawyer Nightline This Week with George Stephanopoulos 20/20 Primetime What Would You Do? ABC.com 
 
Tools

 iPad App Register Sign In Facebook Twitter Blogs Emails&amp;News Alerts Message Boards RSS Headlines 
 
About

 Contact Us Feedback Advertising Privacy Policy Interest-Based Ads Terms of Use ABC News Store Site Map Site Index Authors List Text Version
	</body>
</document>
