<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001220" url="http://e-classifieds.me/listings/oh/akroncanton/forsale_business/photo-view/" time="2012-07-12-16:40" support="16" score="0.013859561966134417" bingtitle="eclassifieds - Business in Akron / Canton Craigslist and other ..." webtitle="eclassifieds - Business in Akron / Canton Craigslist and other Classified Listings, View by photo or list!">
			<query id="000322" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000072" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000076" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="001105" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000571" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000039" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000089" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="001011" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="000078" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000572" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000081" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000518" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000071" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000082" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="001482" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="000602" bing-rank="170"/>
	<description>Landmark Replacement Lids for trash receptacle (Cuyahoga Falls) $75 Landmark Replacement Lids for trash receptacle (Cuyahoga Falls) $75</description>
	<body>
		Search 
 Create post Log in Sign up 
 
 Ohio &gt; Akron / Canton &gt; Business

 Switch to List View 
 
 07-10 Lot at 10th And Mckinley (Canton ohio)
 Lot at 10th And Mckinley (Canton ohio) A lot on the corner of 11th and mckenley just trying to get rid of it will take any serious offers only text 3302653036 07-10 Cincinnat Silk Screen Tee shirt Dryer (Canton Ohio) $4
 36&apos;&apos; wide belt, 11ft. long conveyor , 6ft. electric heating chamber, insulated with exhaust fan. 240 volt single phase 10.4KW Portable on casters with long power cord. Looks and runs like new. Any Questions Call Gregg 330-575-9982 07-10 Business for Sale (Stark county)
 Business for Sale (Stark county) Profitable Business for sale must sell due to illness $25,000 OBO Please call 330-685-2251 for details 07-10 Lock Box Stand alone mail box (Rt 18 west of I-77) $70
 atLock Box / Mail Box. Large, Heavey metal, lockable box on a stand that can be bolted to cement or any surface. NEVER USED. 330-328-6887 07-10 Singer 120 U ...Industrial..Never used in Factory (Akron / central..interchange) $500
 Very Fast Machine ..self oiling.. used for drapes&amp;Quilts at home... contact here or call leave message 330-434-3157 .. 07-10 chest freezer commercial (massillon) $500
 chest freezer commercial (massillon) $500 this is a nice size freezer for lots of stuff to put in nice and cold we want 500 for but well take offers call or tex 330-949-0828 07-10 Ice Machine $1350
 Crystal Tips ice machine. Makes 800 pounds a day. Serviced and runs great. Call Steve 330 280 3121 or Frank 330 605 2944 07-10 Restaurant/Deli Meat Slicer (Malvern, Ohio) $350
 Used Univex Meat Slicer Model 6509 115 volt 3.9 amp 60 hz. 8 3/4&quot; blade (needs replaced) Working condition 07-10 55 ft electric boom truck (zanesville) $15000
 This an excellent running 2000 ford f 750 with a CAT engine with only 143000 miles.It was a well maintained truck has new hydraulics and all 6 tires are in great shape.new price is around $80,000 to $100,000 bought used in 2007 with 75,000 miles for [...] 07-10 Stack paper cutter (commercial-grade) (Akron) $1200
 We are selling our Dahle 852 Premium Stack Cutter because have not been able to use it after all. It has barely been used and is in fantastic condition. The current lowest internet price is $1500 and we are offering ours for $1200. Here are some fea [...] 07-10 LARGE COCA COLA LIGHT UP MENU BOARD (AKRON,OHIO) $1
 I have a large Coca Cola light up menu board. Power cord was sliced but I have electrical tape on it and this works great. Includes a pull string for turning on/off light. This will need letters and numbers for it which can be found online cheap. Per [...] 07-10 Used Table Bases (Independence) $10
 Used table bases with 22&quot; x 22&quot; base spread. standard dining height. Call Gregg 330-592-2799 07-10 Rolls of Epoxy Tape (Tallmadge) $5
 1 Case of 16 Rolls of Epoxy Tape...Made by Van Roll....Each Roll is 360&apos;....Item #VRI77984C....$5 Per Roll or $50 Per Case..Call 330-606-3161 07-10 STORAGE BIN UNIT W/WHITE RACKS THAT ADJUST (NORTH CANTON) $40
 STORAGE UNIT W/WHITE ADJUSTABLE RACKS. I USED THIS IN A THRIFT STORE I HAD FOR SOCKS, WALLETS, ACCESSORIES. IT IS HEAVY DUTY. THERE ARE 6 WHITE WIRE BASKETS THAT ARE ADJUSTABLE AND REMOVABLE. $40.00. PLS CALL 330-283-2082 VITTIE 07-10 Restaurant Tables PrEtTy Burgundy w/oak wrap, black pedestal, chairs (Mentor) $40
 We have 4 used restaurant tables in very good condition. 30&quot; square size. Asking $40 each. Have chairs that went with them. Real wood, heavy duty, library mahogany finish at $20 each. 440-897-6227 07-10 Caterpillar MC30 Towmotor (Lodi, Ohio) $2500
 Caterpillar MC30 Towmotor (Lodi, Ohio) $2500 Selling a good working CAT MC30 Indoor Towmotor. S/N 41W440. Rated 36V, includes newer electric charger. Inquiries call Three Three 0 6 Three Fivvve 06 Five Nine. 07-10 Vending machines (Ravenna)
 Vending machines (Ravenna) I have 2 machines, one is a soda machine and the other is a multi temp snack machine. Both are in like new condition. Both take and change bills as well as coins, they both have true vend bill changer. These are not cheap machines they are top qualit [...] 07-10 Two new heated portable carpet extractors must go! (Cuyahoga Falls) $1995
 These two Xaact carpet extractors must be moved! They are being sold at cost and are basically being given away. Great machines with warranty. The 200H model comes with a 15&apos; hose, stainless steel wand, 200 PSI, and is $1995. The 500H model comes wit [...] 07-10 Custom Concrete Tables (Canton)
 We specialize in custom made concrete countertops and/or tables. Any designs or colors available. Great for outdoors or indoors. 1 yr warranty on all work. Prices vary on design&amp;colors. Call us today to order your CONCRETE COUNTERTOP or TABLE. [...] 07-10 WESTERN SNOW PLOW 03 DODGE 3500 (ORRVILLE) $2500
 WESTERN SNOW PLOW 03 DODGE 3500 (ORRVILLE) $2500 I HAVE A WESTERN UNIMOUNT SNOW PLOW,IT NEEDS NEW LIGHTS.WORKS VERY WELL ANY QUESTIONS PLEASE CALL 330-234-FOUR 0 ZERO 5 07-09 HEAVY DUTY STEEL FILE CABINET (North Canton) $45
 HEAVY DUTY STEEL FILE CABINET (North Canton) $45 Very heavy duty large industrial steel file cabinet - with 2 full size file drawers&amp;4 narrow drawers. Must sell - open to all offers. Email or Call / Text Mark @ 330-327-8389 07-09 LARGE STEEL INDUSTRIAL DESK (North Canton) $65
 LARGE STEEL INDUSTRIAL DESK (North Canton) $65 Large industrial full size desk with drawers on both sides. Good Condition. Must sell, open to all offers. Email or Call / Text Mark @ 330-327-8389 07-09 Red Bull Vending Pop Pepsi Machine (Ravenna, ohio) $975
 &apos;LIKE NEW&apos;, Red Bull vending machine. Vends all varieties of Red Bull, or any other narrow can. I have been told this machine can also be slightly modified to vend the wider cans like Monster, etc. In excellent working order. The machine comes with [...] 07-09 Refridgerted Toppings Bar (Seville) $500
 APW Wyott RTR8 8 Compartment Refrigerated Topping Rail 120V Perfect for vegetable or fruit ... excellent condition... NSF Commercial. Previously used in a coffee shop. Stainless steel, with hindged lids and spoons...retails at $1469 new Dawn 330-46 [...] 07-09 Sharp FO-DC535 Printer Scanner Fax Machine $200 OBO (Hudson) $200
 Sharp FO-DC535 Fax Machine. Used in and office environmet. Works perfectly. Has Owners Manuel. Purchased 3 years ago for $3000 Asking $200, Or Best Offer. Pick up only. Cash Only I found the following description from a web site: Designed for the gr [...] 07-09 Retirement Sale (corner I70&amp;StRt 83) $900000
 Retirement Sale (corner I70&amp;StRt 83) $900000 17 Plus acres with immediate access to Interstate 70 and Ohio State Route 83. Great Location for truck stop, motel/resturant or large industrial opertion. Only serious inquires please. Trying to retire, need to down size. 07-09 RENTAL FOR SALE (Southeastern Ohio) $650000
 RENTAL FOR SALE (Southeastern Ohio) $650000 13 units on 7 acres ample room for expansion, fully occupied, will transfer security deposits, 2006 totally renovated, 2miles from university easy access to I70. Only serious inquires. 07-09 filing cabinets (medina) $50100
 filing cabinets (medina) $50100 Used filing cabinets. We have 2 - 5 drawer filing cabinets. will text pictures. 07-09 McCall 2 Door cooler (Rootstown) $850
 McCall 2 door reach-in cooler. Model 4-4045gd01c 07-09 Hatco Pizza Warmer (Rootstown) $525
 Used Hatco Flav-R-Savor Pizza Warmer FS-1 display cabinet. Works great. 07-09 Pizza/Sandwich Shop (Massillon Ohio) $50000
 Pizza / Sandwich Shop or make it into any kind of retail store. This building is located at 118 6th St. N.E. Massillon Ohio. Parking on both sides of street. This building is also equipped with Stove, Walk in Cooler, Refrigerator, Dough Mixer and two [...] 07-09 Shelves / Shelving (Green)
 Laminate Shelving - White laminate with red trim Various sizes Largest size $20.00 each Medium size $15.00 each Small size $10.00 each I will update with measurements ASAP 07-09 Credit Card Processing Terminal (Medina) $200
 This credit card reader is a few years old but like new and used very little. call Dan more info at: 216-214-5216 07-09 Convenient strore for sale (cleveland) $199
 convenient store for sale Cleveland with 3 apartments, (2) two bedroom and 1 with three bedrooms. business is well established 50+ years, great investment, many building updates and improvements.entire building, property and business included in 199k [...] 07-09 Whitman Mixer
 Whitman Cement Mixer Model WM 900 $ 1250 obo 07-09 Plastic Film Rolls (Tallmadge) $35
 Brand New Plastic Film Rolls...Unknown Use.....$5 Each or $35 for All.....Call 330-606-3161 07-09 Box of Wire Display Racks (Tallmadge) $9
 Box of Wire Display Racks.....$9...Call 330-606-3161 07-09 Metal Gondola Shelving (Windham, Ohio) $300
 20 Sections of metal gray gondola shelving - most sections have two or three shelves - also one corner section - making a total of 21 sections - all sections are 4&apos; wide but the corner Will sell all for $300 If Interested please call 330-980-1933 n [...] 07-09 2000 NEW Guest Checks (North Canton) $20
 2000 NEW Guest Checks (North Canton) $20 2000 NEW Guest Checks, 3.5&quot; X 6.75&quot; Single Green Med. Cardboard, 50 sheets per book, 40 books. 330-966-4633 07-09 Forklift Scales
 Forklift Scales, 6,000 # lb. Capacity, reads in 2 # lb. increments 20 inch carraige, $ 650 07-09 Quick Connect
 Wayne Roy Quick Connect $ 750 07-09 Twin GM Diesel Generator (Alliance, Ohio) $10000
 Twin GM Diesel Generator (Alliance, Ohio) $10000 Twin GE Diesel generator, 2400 volts with power transfer gear 250 KVA, 3 phase, cabinet -Industrial control serial #53549, Federal Pacific Electric Circuit Breaker Serial # E-75759. Runs good, call Frank at 330-313-1128 07-09 HP Designjet 650c and 750c Large Format Printers Plotters (Canton) $400
 Selling 2 Large format HP printers. Removed from service well over a year ago. Both were in working condition when removed from service but as of now, they are untested. They have been in climate controlled storage so they are not corroded or dama [...] 07-09 GBC CombBind c150 Binder (Canton) $50
 Used GBC Comb Binder. In good working condition. Missing the handle but could be an easy fix. Threaded hole for handle is stripped and or crossthreaded. Entire handle is removable and can be easily replaced. Still cuts through paper with minimal [...] 07-09 POS System - Complete (Akroon) $1299
 I have several All-In-One POS systems for sale. These are NEW, complete hardware units ready for software. Perfect for Restaurants, Fast Food, Pizza, niteclubs, taverns or pubs etc. Comes with built-in card reader, thermal receipt printer w/auto cutt [...] 07-09 Bottle cooler (Akron ohio) $300
 3door under bar cooler True does not work call 330 730 6197 07-09 nail tech/pedicurists (JACKSON TWP.) $75
 nail tech/pedicurists (JACKSON TWP.) $75 nail tech/pedicurist $75.00 A week REAL NICE BEAUTY SALOON THANKS FOR LOOKING,IF INT. CALL 330-479-9058 TO SET UP A APT. 07-09 Ford LTS 8000 Vacuum Septic Tanker Pumper (Akron) $28000
 LTS; L= Louisville, T= Tandem S= Set Back Front Axle I was restoring for myself but will be retiring. Formally a Summit County Department of Enviormental Services truck. 3208 210hp. (636 cu. in. or 10.4 Liter) Caterpiller engine was replaced by the [...] 07-09 Established Thrift Store (Business Only) (Jewett) $40000
 Thrift Store for sale $40,000 with 16 ft box truck or $30,000 without truck or best offer. Utica Shale area. Building is rented but if you would be interested in buying inventory and not renting building you can make offer on complete inventory of ap [...] 07-08 Paper Cutter, 3Hole Puncher, 12&quot; Stapler (Akron) $100
 Paper Cutter, 3Hole Puncher, 12&apos; Stapler (Akron) $100 Office Supplies LIKE NEW ACCO 3 hole puncher Stanley Bostitch 12 inch stapler with plastic guide Boston 2612 Paper Cutter with Grid and Plastic Paper Guide All are gently used and almost new OBO Cash Only Call 843.254.1755 Next 50 Copyright©2012 eclassifieds, Inc. 

 Privacy Policy | Terms of Service
	</body>
</document>
