<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001193" url="http://www.typefreediabetes.com/Articles.asp?ID=405" time="2012-07-12-16:38" support="4" score="0.018672315166515036" bingtitle="Diabetes Menu Planner - Diabetic Supplies Online | Diabetes ..." webtitle="The Diabetic Diet Menu PlannerDiabetes Food Guide | TypeFree Diabetes">
			<query id="000369" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="001122" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000846" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="001121" bing-rank="171"/>
	<description>A diabetes menu planner is crucial for people with Type 2 diabetes. Portion control of foods they eat is key to healthy eating. The proportion food you eat has a ...</description>
	<body>
		Home I My Account I Register I Contact Us I Blog I View Cart I Track Your Order 
 1-800-738-5720 $8.95 Shipping, Fast Easy Shipments 
Wholesale Orders
 
Gifts&amp;Specials
 
Shop Clearance Dept
 
Interactive Puzzles
 
Diabetes Facts
 
Monthly Auto - ship Program
 Shop By Brands 
 Panasonic Bronson Omron Sunbeam Oster HoMedics Drew Glucerna Remington SensiFoot 
 Find us on Facebook Join Our Newsletter 
 You are here:  Home &gt; Diabetes&amp;Nutrition &gt; Diabetes Meal Planning &gt; Diabetic Diet Menu Planner 

 
The Diabetic Diet Menu Planner&amp;Diabetes Food Guide
 The Mediterranean Food Pyramid includes more high glycemic index carbs than most food pyramids. 
 Living with diabetes can have significant impact on the foods you eat since everything you eat and drink is broken down into glucose, which can affect your diabetes problem. Lower you risks for heart disease, stroke, and other problems of diabetes with a diabetic diet plan that includes healthy food choices to help you better control your blood sugar level.

Healthy eating&amp;your diabetic diet plan

People with diabetes need to adapt diabetic healthy eating habits. Diabetics are prone to gain weight too easily. So, it is best to plan a diabetic diet menu that can help you lose excess fat and maintain your ideal weight. 
Make healthy food choices with the diabetes food guide

 A diabetic diet menu must be high in nutrients, low in fats and sugar . And so, foods that can quickly spike your blood sugar—processed foods with refined sugars, white rice, white potatoes, white bread—are best avoided in your diabetic menu plan . But you don&apos;t have to feel deprived or restricted. The diabetes food guide will teach you what you can eat (all the nutrients you need), how much you should eat, and how often you can enjoy it (while keeping your blood glucose under control).

Eating well with a diabetic diet menu planner
 
One of the best ways for diabetics to control the quality of their meals is to plan their diabetes menus. Diabetes menu planning means that you create a menu for the day, week, or even month that you stick to. A good diabetes menu plan will include diabetes snack options that will help to control your appetite as well as different diabetic meal options so that you don&apos;t get bored by eating the same foods over and over again.

We at TypeFreeDiabetes.com prefer the Mediterranean food pyramid because it includes more high glycemic index carbs that most food pyramids. Obviously, the larger amounts of food and activities start at the bottom suggesting daily use, and gets smaller as you move up (weekly) toward the top which suggest monthly use.
 
 Diabetes Menu Planning Goals 
The goal of every diabetes menu plan should be to ensure that you have a balanced diet with an appropriate amount of:

 Carbohydrates (45%-65%) - Use more low Glycemic Index carbs than high
 

 Proteins (10%-35%) - Keep it lean
 

 Unsaturated fats (20%-35%) - Monounsaturated and polyunsaturated
 
Diabetes menu planning is an also an excellent way to keep track of calories.


The average person should consume about 2,000 calories per day to ensure that their body functions properly and they have enough energy to be active. It is also recommended that the average person consumers about:
 100 grams of protein (at 4Cal/gram) 
 275 grams of carbohydrates (at 4 Cal/gram) 
 56 grams of fat (at 9 Cal/gram) each day (yes - it is actually important to consume fat - that is monounsaturated fats and polyunsaturated fats from plants and fish). Eat as little saturated fats as possible. Saturated fats mostly come from non-fish animals, like birds, cows and pigs. 


Www.typefreediabetes.com is dedicated to providing you the tools and resources to help you build your diabetes menu plan. A good Diabetes menu plan will not only provide information that is based on careful research 2000-Calorie-Meal-Plan, but we also provide a range of recipes for diabetes (including diabetes snacks, vegetarian recipes, and even diabetes desserts) that are suitable for any healthy diet.

Check out our Nutrition, and Recipes sections for more information about how you can plan your tasty diabetes menus and live a healthy lifestyle by eating well! Remember, the food choices you make will have a major impact on your blood sugar. Bad food choices will raise your blood sugar, that will cause you to use more diabetes drugs, or make you suffer severe diabetes complications. The choices are yours to make. Prevention is much more pleasant that the cure.


 Remember: Eat Healthy With Style!
	</body>
</document>
