<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001589" url="http://news.ninemsn.com.au/national/8418826/melbourne-prankster-returns-with-valentines-day-gag" time="2012-07-12-17:22" support="2" score="0.001265864487376088" bingtitle="Melbourne joker pulls Valentine&apos;s Day prank" webtitle="Melbourne joker pulls Valentine&apos;s Day prank">
			<query id="000613" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="001367" bing-rank="227"/>
	<description>... with starting a craze known as &apos;cone-ing&apos; at fast food restaurant ... drive away looking dejected, leaving his food order ... Police have shot two young indigenous men in a car ...</description>
	<body>
		News Sports Finance Lifestyle Entertainment Video Travel Cars eBay Jobs Dating Property More sites 
 Make ninemsn your Homepage Hot Topics:  Usher Getaway: 54% off Camp Eden Retreat! 
 Mobile Messenger Hotmail 
 01.22 am, Friday July 13 2012 
   Front page     Video     Latest news     National     World     Entertainment     Tech     Health     Weather     Traffic     Finance     Sport   
 
 Local News 
 Sydney Melbourne Queensland 
 More 
 Meet the team 9 Newswatch Contact us Live streaming Lotteries RSS feeds Vote archive 
 
 
   National home     Archives     RSS Feed   
 
Melbourne joker pulls Valentine&apos;s Day prank
 14:30 AEST Wed Feb 15 2012 By Fiona Willan, ninemsn VIEWS: 0 | FLOCKS: 0 | 0 comments so far Also on Pup&apos;s view Guide dog&apos;s trip livestreamed Revenge Boy wants alligator&apos;s head ESCAPE Chimps flee from zoo enclosure BIG STINK Model hurls dog waste into car Channelling Go behind Jess&apos; &apos;Gotcha&apos; video Primped Ricki-Lee&apos;s new beauty secrets 
More national news:
 Labor suspends NSW trio: report Jul 13, 2012 Police close in on Mackay remains: report Jul 13, 2012 Holden Colorado awarded top safety rating Jul 13, 2012 Boy hit by island bus critical Jul 12, 2012 Sydney mall worker charged with assault Jul 12, 2012 One dead in SA highway crash Jul 12, 2012 Facebook tip-off leads to sex act charge Jul 12, 2012 Load not cause of WA plane crash: police Jul 12, 2012 Nurses furious over payroll legislation Jul 12, 2012 Vic prison escapee caught in Melbourne Jul 12, 2012 
 
The Melbourne prankster credited with starting a craze known as &apos;cone-ing&apos; at fast food restaurant drive-throughs has struck again—this time with a Valentine&apos;s Day-themed gag.

Alki Stevens visited a number of drive-throughs across Melbourne yesterday to surprise the employees with a series of ridiculous Valentine&apos;s Day gifts.

The 25-year-old remained stony-faced as he casually handed over extravagant bunches of balloons, teddy bears, hearts cut out of cardboard and even letters spelling out LOVE to whoever happened to be handing over his meal.

 Read more: Melbourne man starts global cone-ing craze 

In most cases, he would drive away looking dejected, leaving his food order in the hand of the baffled employee who rejected his request to &quot;be my Valentine&quot;.

&quot;I thought it went okay but they didn&apos;t really react in the way I expected them to—I thought people would be a bit more thrilled to receive a present,&quot; the comedian told ninemsn.

The stunt is similar to his infamous drive-through cone-ing stunt, in which he would order a soft-serve and then grab hold of the ice cream, rather than the cone, when served.

After the cone-ing video went global last June, Mr Stevens quit his job to become a full-time prankster, making a living from YouTube ads.

While viewers get a laugh out of watching his jokes, Mr Stevens takes his pranking quite seriously.

He said it was easy to keep a straight face while playing a trick, as he was focused on the experience from a purely technical perspective.

&quot;I don&apos;t find it funny because I&apos;m there concentrating on getting a reaction so I have footage to use,&quot; he said.

Since quitting his sales job, Mr Stevens has filmed four or five pranks a week for his YouTube channel , and is also working on a pilot for a TV show.

The Caroline Springs resident has played jokes his whole life but never expected to be able to make a living out of it.

In fact, he got kicked out of school in Year 10 for being a class clown.

&quot;I used school as a way to test out what made people laugh,&quot; he said.

&quot;I once booked a construction worker to come in during class and meet our teacher about extending the classroom.&quot;

Both the teacher and the tradie were baffled by the incident, but Mr Stevens was never sprung.

He ended up being expelled for numerous other incidents of mischief.

While Mr Stevens admits to loving making people feel awkward, his intentions are not all sinister.

He told ninemsn he often received emails from people thanking him for cheering them up as they tackled illness, grief, and other difficult situations.

&quot;I know it looks like I&apos;m just being an idiot, but that&apos;s really why I do it—I like to make people laugh.&quot;
   Flock It! Thanks #nickname#, this article has been Flocked #flock_count# times. &gt; Edit profile 
&gt; Leave The Flock Please wait ... Would you like to become a Mother Flocker? 
By signing up you will be able to leave short comments on all articles. Edit Profile 
Please edit your profile below and click save. Your profile will be used when displaying your Flock comments on the website. Your email: * 
 
 Your email will not be shared with any third parties or published with your Flock. 
Nickname: * 
 
Full name: * 
 
Location: * 
 Write your comment: * 
 
 Maximum characters 70 * Required fields 
 
©ninemsn 2012


 Do you have a photo or video that should be published on ninemsn? Or do you have information that could lead to a news story? Let us know by sending an email to news.feedback@ninemsn.com.au 

 Comment guidelines Avoid using: 
 Personal attacks Irrelevant comments HTML tags Personal information Offensive language Text in ALL CAPITAL LETTERS 
 See full comment guidelines Comment guidelines X Thank you for sharing your opinions with other users of ninemsn. People will
 find your comments more helpful if you include relevant information and avoid some
 common pitfalls. Please note: All reviews and comments submitted are subject to moderation, ninemsn
 reserves the right to alter and / or remove any content that does not comply with
 usage guidelines. What to include in your comment: 
 A title that briefly summarises the opinion expressed in the comment. Additional comments adding more detail. Comparisons to other similar products, if this is relevant. To create a new paragraph, press the Enter key twice. 
 What not to include: 
 Information that will quickly go out of date. Comments on other comments or commenters. Language that other users may find offensive. comments of one sentence or less. Provide information to support your opinion. Personal information like your email address or telephone number. HTML coding. Tags like&lt;b&gt;or&lt;i&gt;will not be recognised. 
 Terms of Service | Privacy Policy Take Control Of The Dark With Cyber-shot from Sony http://www.sony.com.au/cybershot 
Most popular
   UK reveals UFO sighting over Chelsea stadium Britain on Thursday released an archive of &quot;X-Files&quot; detailing government UFO briefings and probes into unexplained sightings, including one above Chelsea football club.   Sydney chef stabbed in altercation: court An exchange of verbal taunts preceded the stabbing murder of a young Sydney chef after a night out with friends, court documents allege.   Motorcyclist films himself rear end van A US motorcyclist recording a video blog has captured the moment he collided into the rear of a delivery van after it stopped abruptly.   Good Wife actress injured on set Actress Kristin Chenoweth had to be taken to a New York hospital after a piece of scaffolding hit her head on the set of the US drama The Good Wife .   Murdered woman in $20k drug deal: court A woman was involved in a $20,000 drug deal the day she disappeared, a Sydney murder trial has heard.   Sydney man pays tribute to stillborn son A Sydney man whose unborn baby died in his wife&apos;s womb is running the City 2 Surf to raise money for the Stillbirth Foundation.   Students abused and bullied, WA probe told An inquiry into sex abuse at WA-run hostels has heard how young boarders were abused, bullied and left to fend for themselves without supervision.   Woman saves children in runaway van A good Samaritan in New Mexico has saved two children who were inside a runaway van after her own abandoned car stopped it rolling towards a busy street.   New Yorkers marvel at &apos;Manhattanhenge&apos; sunset New Yorkers gathered at dusk to witness &quot;Manhattanhenge&quot; -- a rare alignment of the sun with the east-west street grid in which it appears to set between skyscrapers.   &apos;Dead or alive&apos; bounty offered for China piranhas Authorities in southern China have moved to quash a bizarre piranha threat, offering bounties and free bait amid fears the aggressive South American fish has invaded a river, state media said Thursday.   9RAW: Sheep avoid slaughter by suicide   Timberlake grabs Kunis&apos;s breasts   9RAW: Anorexic model campaigner dies   9RAW: Tourist dies after bottom enhancement   What’s next for the royal couple?   Family turn off cop’s life support   Swiss skateboard tourist in jail again   Emotional outpouring for slain police officer   Dale Thomas banned for one match   90-year-old turtle gives birth at zoo   Wild weather   Van explosion   Alec Baldwin   Dan Ewing   Nicola Roxon   Charlie Sheen   Cricket   Manuel Noriega   Harold Hopkins   Nick Sherry Glance: The news in pictures Injured koala returned to the wild
 view all pictures Stolen puppy and owner reunited
 view all pictures Retreat helps teen burn victims
 view all pictures How animals see the world
 view all pictures Ancient Muslim tombs destroyed
 view all pictures Kate Waterhouse weds in Italy
 view all pictures 
 
 Be our fan on Facebook 
 
 Most Recommended 
 
 
 The Flock 
 You need the latest version of Flash Player. Enjoy the most vivid content on the web
Watch video without extra features
Interact with applications on your favourite sites 
 
Nine News

- news.ninemsn.com.au
   
Services and tools
 
 Latest news Headlines National news World news Business news Entertainment news Sport news Technology news Health news News at a Glance 
 
 Weather Photo galleries Video Vote archive Send us your stories Contact us Lotteries   
 RSS Newsletter page complete 
 News Sports Finance Lifestyle Entertainment Video Travel Cars eBay Jobs Dating Property More sites 
 
 About ninemsn Careers at ninemsn Advertise Contact Us Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 Other ninemsn businesses: iSelect RateCity msnNZ Cudo ©1997-2012 ninemsn Pty Ltd - All rights reserved
	</body>
</document>
