<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001098" url="http://www.fastfoodsource.com/fastfoodsource/mcdonalds-europe-part-3-greece" time="2012-07-12-16:31" support="1" score="0.008079147120724037" bingtitle="McDonald&apos;s Europe Part 3: Greece - FastFoodSource - Fast Food at ..." webtitle="McDonald&apos;s Europe Part 3: Greece - FastFoodSource - Fast Food at Fast Food Source:  Your independent guide to fast food restaurants, menus, nutrition, locations, and fast food news!">
			<query id="000252" bing-rank="158"/>
	<description>... feel like ordering one. ... Someone please confirm ... 2000, Fast Food Source has been the premier independent site dedicated to fast food lovers, offering fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to content Skip to main navigation Skip to first column Skip to second column 
   
 Fast Food at Fast Food Source: Your independent guide to fast food restaurants, menus, nutrition, locations, and fast food news! 
 
McDonald&apos;s Europe Part 3: Greece
 Monday, 10 May 2010 21:52 Share 
 

There&apos;s that CBO again!  Yes, it&apos;s the third in a series of stories about McDonald&apos;s fast food restaurants in Europe.  We&apos;ve already visited Spain and France , and our next stop is the island of Corfu in financially-challenged Greece.

The cool thing about touring Europe is the same thing that is currently driving Greece crazy: a common currency.  This allows for comparison of things like a 1 euro menu.

 

Sorry about the cash register blocking part of this menu - it was the only posted chart of 1 euro food items.  But you can see some familiar items as well as the unique &quot;McToast&quot; sandwich.  Um, what is it?  Nobody there spoke English clearly enough for me to find out and I just ate so I didn&apos;t feel like ordering one.

Let&apos;s look at the main board, the McMenu, instead:

 

This menu should make any American feel at home.  In fact, except for the &quot;McFarm&quot; (pork) sandwich, everything is pretty normal.  Even the &quot;Quarter Pounder&quot; is called a &quot;Quarter Pounder&quot;, not a Royal.  Ahh, consistency.

 

In the Happy Greek Children department, the Happy Meal board had a lot that was Greek to me.  But there&apos;s the trusty &quot;McToast&quot; and I am thinking this is a grilled cheese.  Someone please confirm.  And while cherry tomatoes are nowhere to be found, they do have the wedge fries and another American kids menu staple, apple slices.

Join us next time for our next stop - the decidedly non-Euro Croatia.
 Tags:
 europe greece mcdonalds menu opinion review 
 Joomla Templates and Joomla Extensions by ZooTemplate.Com 
 Add New 
 Comments (1) 
 2011-11-26 16:41:22 | From IP:218.48.14.xxx | James  -  McToast The McToast is a small ham and cheese sandwich made using the centre bread slice from the Big Mac. I write a blog on trying McDonalds in every country. http://travellingmcds.blogspot.com/ 
 Write comment Your Contact Details: Name: Email: Comment: Title: Message: Security Please input the anti-spam code that you can read in the image. Joomla components by Compojoom   
 SEO by AceSEF 
 
 
 Find Your Local Restaurants . . . 
 
 Home Search By City List All Restaurants Fast Food Blogs Restaurant Inspections Nutrition Industry Links Mobile Access Awards&amp;Recognition Contact Fast Food Source 
 
What is Fast Food Source?

Since 2000, Fast Food Source has been the premier independent site dedicated to fast food lovers, offering fast food restaurant menus, and nutrition information, as well as fast food blogs, articles, forums, and fast food industry news. We offer fast food location information for over 50 cities and more than 80 fast food chains.
 
Most Popular Tags
 arbys big mac burger burger king carls jr checkers chicken del taco europe fast food fast food source fries hardees jack in the box locations mcdonalds menu news nutrition opinion review taco bell tommys update wendys 
 
 


© 2000-2012 FastFoodSource.com. Use subject to the Terms of Service
	</body>
</document>
