<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001470" url="http://www.stayinbritain.co.uk/search/brochure-display.aspx?clientId=75650" time="2012-07-12-17:14" support="1" score="0.0014925482681274196" bingtitle="Guest House in Peterborough - Self Catering Cottages, Bed and ..." webtitle="Guest House in Peterborough - Arman Lodge House">
			<query id="000698" bing-rank="107"/>
	<description>... request), and for additional comfort a hospitality tray ... By Car: DIRECTIONS FROM THE A1 NORTH: Come off the A1 at ... Cathedral Square ~ Ferry Meadows Country Park ~ Nene ...</description>
	<body>
		Guest House in Peterborough 
 
Save to favourites
 «New search Go to favourites 
Guest House in Peterborough - Arman Lodge House
   Home Accommodation Leisure Extra Info Food&amp;Drink Directions 
 
To enlarge click on a photo
 
 
CONTACT DETAILS
 
Mr B Karavadra

3 Scotney Street
New England
Peterborough

PE1 3NG

fax: 01733 759274
 WEBSITE EMAIL 
RATES INFO

 from£30 -£39 p/room from£50 -£55 p/room from£50 -£55 p/room from£40 -£60 p/room 
 
 Local Restaurants
 Local Attractions
 
 
 
Guest House in Peterborough

Comfortable established guest house situated in the north of the city offering clean and high standard accommodation with en-suite and standard rooms. All bedrooms are individually furnished. Facilities include sky tv with digital freeview channels and for additional comfort tea/coffee in rooms. wi-fi throughout the building. All office use aids are available. Car parking available for mainly cars for commercial vehicles parking is available nearby or on the road. Self-catering with use of microwave,washing machine and fridge freezer available for individual or groups.The continental breakfast consisting Milk juices cereals toasts boiled or fried eggs self serve in dining area including in the prices,cooked breakfast excluding bacon possible by pre arrangement only. Weekend and weekly rates,contractors welcome

We are located one and half miles from the city centre,the railway station and city hospital in New England area off Lincoln road with easy road routes accessible to national highways,Thomas Cook and the Cresset centre,and burley horse trial. Open all year round close to local amenities include big stores Local fast foods and ethnic restaurant places open till late night. Transfers to the Airport and receive from city railway station and bus station arranged. Reasonable Charges apply outside City and long distances.

Peterborough is an ancient cathedral city with an exciting,modern life-style offering great choices of places to visit. In Cathedral Square see the Butter Cross or Guildhall built in 1671,and the local museum is nearby in Priestgate.

The City centre is full of interesting places to visit and things to do. The Key Theatre on the banks of the River Nene and Cresset in Bretton centre provides a year round programme of top rate evening entertainment.

Excellent transport road links make the city a good base to explore other famous locations,like Cambridge,Ely,London,East Coast resorts. Whatever your need whether traveller,day out or on business,Peterborough is ideally best for shopping and nightlife. With so much to see and enjoy,you are certain to visit Peterborough and discover ancient traditional heritage.



 
Directions

The map points to the centre of the postcode for Arman Lodge House and may not indicate the exact position of the property, you can zoom in or out and move the map around to get the best directions for your journey there.
 
 By Car: DIRECTIONS FROM THE A1 NORTH: Come off the A1 at first junction that is signed for Peterborough North-A47 Take the left turn onto the A47 signed to Peterborough or Wisbech,continue and you will be on Soke Parkway. Stay on that lane until you see the sign for city centre,turn left on that junction,continue straight to another island with traffic lights and turn right into Bourgess Boulevard(A15)and Follow the map from here.

DIRECTIONS FROM THE A1 SOUTH: Come off the A1 on to A1139 sign posted for Peterborough and Wisbech A47 continue until third junction turn left into A1260 NeneParkway City Centre follow the road turn left on 2 junction and then right into Long Parkway to City Centre and Thorpe Road A1179 Follow the map from here

DIRECTIONS FROM M6/M1: Pick up A14 and continue for aprox 18 miles. Come off on to A605 Peterborough
 
Accommodation

All bedrooms are individually furnished. Facilities include colour TV,cable TV(on request),and for additional comfort a hospitality tray of tea/coffee,hair dryers,steam irons and ironing boards can be supplied. Weekend and weekly rates. Contractors welcome. Our prices are inclusive of English Breakfast to suit all tastes.
 
Facilities



 Internet facilities Parking 
 
Amenities



 TV in room Coffee&amp;tea in room Cable TV Hair dryers available 
 
Extra Info

Peterborough is an ancient cathedral city with an exciting,modern life-style offering great choices of places to visit. In Cathedral Square see the Butter Cross or Guildhall built in 1671,and the local museum is nearby in Priestgate.

The City centre is full of interesting places to visit and things to do. The Key Theatre on the banks of the River Nene and Cresset in Bretton centre provides a year round programme of top rate evening entertainment.

Excellent transport road links make the city a good base to explore other famous locations,like Cambridge,Ely,London,East Coast resorts. Whatever your need whether traveller,day out or on business,Peterborough is ideally best for shopping and nightlife. With so much to see and enjoy,you are certain to visit Peterborough and discover ancient traditional heritage.
 
Leisure

Places to Visit: ~ Peterborough Cathedral(13th century cathedral)~ Cathedral Square ~ Ferry Meadows Country Park ~ Nene Valley Railway ~ East of England Showground ~ Flag Fen Prehistoric Fenland Centre ~ Peakirk Waterfowl World ~ Elton Hall ~ Queensgate and Rivergate Shopping Centres ~ Burleigh House and Park,Stamford ~ Peterborough Museum and Art Gallery ~ City market ~ Central Park ~ Passport Office

 Golf Walking Bird Watching Cycling Museums Railways Stately Homes Wildlife Countryside Churches National Trust Art galleries Family Attractions 
 
Food&amp;Drink

The continental breakfast consisting Milk,juices,cereals,toast,boiled or fried eggs self serve in dining area including in the prices from 7.00am-10-00am

Cooked breakfast excluding bacon possible by pre-arrangement only.
 
Breakfast



 Continental breakfast (incl) 
 
 Some of the special dining features that we have to offer 



 Home cooking Vegetarian food 
 
Deals&amp;Promotions
 
Reserve It Ltd, cannot confirm or guarantee the description or standard of the properties published on it&apos;s Internet or printed pages and therefore assumes no responsibility for the accuracy or validity of claims and statements made by any property owner within this web site or other locations on the internet. Views expressed within our web sites or other locations are those of the property owner and do not necessarily reflect the views of Reserve It Ltd. We reserve the right to remove from our site, without compensation, any establishment that fails to provide the quality of service claimed in their advertising.
 Home | Meet the team | Links Page | Link to Us | Using the site | Terms&amp;Conditions | Privacy Policy | Terms of use | Gold Customers | Town list | Articles | Counties of Britain | Sitemap 
 Home Search Register Property Amend Property Help About Us Contact Us Our Services Advertising
	</body>
</document>
