<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001023" url="http://www.fundraiserhelp.com/fundraising-cards.htm" time="2012-07-12-16:26" support="1" score="0.0015872721771906545" bingtitle="Fundraising Cards" webtitle="Fundraising Cards">
			<query id="001272" bing-rank="28"/>
	<description>Or, a Burger King may offer free fries with a sandwich selection during a one year ... funds online with a credit card fundraiser - Online fundraiser tips for credit card ...</description>
	<body>
		Fundraising Ideas / Fundraising Cards   

 
Fundraising Cards

Discount Card Fundraisers

Fundraising cards are a great way to raise funds for any group, school club, 
or youth sports team. With discount card fundraisers, you buy the cards in 
advance and sell them at retail prices, so there is a substantial upfront 
expenditure.

However, the large profit margins and incredible popularity of the discount 
cards makes this an easy fundraiser. There are three main types of fundraiser 
cards: pizza, fast food, and gold cards.

Pizza Card Fundraiser

Pizza fundraising cards are extremely popular because they offer a free pizza 
every time you purchase a pizza. Usually, the offer is limited to one year or 
twenty free pizzas.

Pizza Hut, Dominos, and Papa Johns are participating chains and their pizza 
fundraiser cards are always in demand. You don&apos;t buy these from the franchise 
locations. The cards are available from several companies for roughly $2 to $3 
each and retail for $10.

If you&apos;re willing to take a signup form to the local Pizza Hut or Papa Johns 
for the manager to sign, you can lower your cost to $1 each. Considering the 
average pizza card fundraiser sells 500 cards, it&apos;s a very profitable approach.

Click here for more details on a pizza 
card fundraiser .

Fast Food Discount Cards

Fast food chains such as Subway, Quiznos, Blimpies, Burger King, and KFC also 
participate in discount card fundraising programs at the discretion of their 
respective franchise owners. Basically, in this type of card fundraiser, you 
take a merchant agreement to the chain location nearest you and get it signed by 
the manager or franchise owner.

Offers vary, but usually include a free item with each purchase. For example, 
a Subway may offer a free drink with each sandwich for up to 18 visits. Or, a 
Burger King may offer free fries with a sandwich selection during a one year 
period.

Because the parent company does not mandate participation, it&apos;s up to each 
location to set the terms of their offer. Usually, the deals aren&apos;t as good as 
the free pizza offers, but the discount cards sell very well regardless.

Gold Card Fundraiser

Gold card fundraising combines multiple offers from local merchants onto a 
single discount card. Your group contacts up to a dozen stores and features 
their respective offers on the back of a gold card.

These combination offers include something for everyone such as oil change 
discounts, dry cleaning deals, special offers from local restaurants, and free 
movie or bowling passes.

The front of the card is customized with your group&apos;s logo and fundraising 
message while the back of the card lists all the offers. It takes a little more 
effort than some of the other discount cards, but allows you to create a 
community card with broader appeal.

Card Fund Raising Sales Tips

With fundraising cards, it&apos;s all about sales volume. You get the most sales 
by selling to the general public, not just to your supporters.

Set up sales tables outside grocery stores, drug stores, home improvement 
stores, Wal-Mart, local athletic fields, swap meets, etc. Get permission a few 
days ahead of time. Use large signs that clearly state why you&apos;re raising funds 
and what the customer gets for their $10.

The whole idea is to pre-sell people as they walk toward the entrance by 
letting the signs do most of the talking. Make eye contact with those who seem 
interested and tout the customer benefits in your sales pitch.

For example.&quot; Twenty free pizzas for ten bucks! It doesn&apos;t get any better 
than that! &quot;

Fundraising Cards Summary

A fundraising card offers great customer value and high profit margins for 
your group. this win/win scenario makes them a great choice for school 
fundraisers, church youth groups, and youth sports teams.

Choose the type of discount card fundraiser you want to offer, select the 
best supplier, and start making the kind of profit that most fund raisers only 
dream about!
 

Related Pages

 Location, Location, Location - How to find the best fundraiser locations and work them for maximum profits.

 Credit Card Fundraiser - Raise funds online with a credit card fundraiser - Online fundraiser tips for credit card fundraising through signups or affinity cards.

 Fundraising Discount Cards - Sales of $10 discount cards for special merchant offers, pizza, or fast food deals.

 Pizza Hut Fundraiser - Raise funds fast with a Pizza Hut fundraiser - Choose between sales of a $10 pizza discount card with two-for-one pizzas or host a Pizza Night at your local Pizza Hut.

 

 
 Ideas For Fundraisers 

 Animal 
 Art Raffle 
 Auction 
 Bake Sale 
 Band 
 Baseball 
 Bingo 
 Bowling 
 Bracelets 
 Brick 
 Candle 
 Candy 
 Candy Bar 
 Capital Campaign 
 Car Donation 
 Car Raffle 
 Car Wash 
 Cash Calendar 
 Casino Night 
 Cell Phone 
 Chair-ity Event 
 Charity 
 Cheerleading 
 Cheesecake Calendar 
 Chinese Auction 
 Christian 
 Christian Event Ideas 
 Christmas Carols 
 Christmas Trees 
 Church 
 Church Festival 
 Church Fund Raisers 
 College 
 Cookbook 
 Cookie Dough 
 Corporate Grants 
 Cow Chip 
 Credit Card 
 Dance 
 Dance Team 
 Discount Cards 
 Donation Request 
 Donor Recognition 
 Earth Friendly 
 Easy 
 eBay 
 Event Tips 
 Events 
 Events - Part 1 
 Events - Part 2 
 Events - Part 3 
 Flower Bulbs 
 Flowers 
 Food Sales 
 For The Cure 
 Free 
 Fruit 
 Fun 
 Fundraising Sample 
 Gift Wrap 
 Golf Ball Drop Raffle 
 Golf Fundraiser 
 Golf Tournament 
 Grant Requests 
 Halloween 
 Healthy 
 Hockey 
 Home&amp;Garden 
 Holiday Carnival 
 Individual 
 Inkjet Recycling 
 Internet 
 Jamba Juice 
 Jingle Bell Run 
 Jingle Bell Walk 
 Karaoke 
 Kathryn Beich 
 Krispy Kreme 
 Lip Sync 
 Location 
 Lollipop 
 Magazine 
 Mardi Gras 
 Merchant Plan 
 Mini Golf Tournament 
 Non-Profit 
 Pancake Breakfast 
 Photography 
 Pink Flamingo 
 Pizza 
 Pizza Hut 
 Poker 
 Political 
 Popcorn 
 Product Ideas 
 Publicity 
 Raffle 
 Raffle Prizes 
 Raffle Tickets 
 Relay For Life 
 Relay For Life Events 
 Rubber Duck 
 Sales Tips 
 Sample Thank You 
 School 
 Scrapbooking 
 Scratch Card 
 Scrip 
 Seasonal Products 
 Silent Auction Tips 
 Soccer 
 Softball 
 Spaghetti Dinner 
 Spelling Bee 
 Teeter Totter 
 Tips 
 Top Five 
 Tried&amp;True 
 Tupperware 
 Valentines Day 
 Whiskey Tasting 
 Wine Tasting 
 Worlds Finest 
 Youth Group 
 Youth Sports 
 
 
 FundraiserHelp Categories 
 
 Activities 
 Appeal Letter 
 Articles 
 Auction Tips 
 Best 
 Blog 
 Cancer Fund Raiser 
 Candy Sales 
 Charity Event 
 Cheerleading 
 Church 
 Companies 
 Donation Request 
 Donor Fund Raising 
 Elementary School 
 Event Ideas 
 Events 
 Fraternity/Sorority 
 Fundraiser Ideas 
 Fundraising Ideas 
 Fund Raising 
 Grant Writing 
 High School 
 Letters 
 Middle School 
 My Book 
 Newsletter 
 Non-profit 
 Online/Internet 
 Planning 
 Products 
 PTA/PTO 
 Publicity Tips 
 Raffles 
 Ratings 
 Relay For Life 
 Sample Letters 
 School Fundraisers 
 Software 
 Supplier Listings 
 Tips 
 Youth Sports 
 About Us 
 Contact Us 

 
 

 Privacy Policy | Terms Of Use | Disclaimer | Sitemap 
Copyright©1999-2069 - Fundraiser Help
	</body>
</document>
