<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001793" url="http://www.sodahead.com/living/study-says-fast-food-is-middle-class-luxury-how-often-do-you-eat-fast-food/question-2278561/" time="2012-07-12-17:34" support="4" score="0.004681346814262521" bingtitle="Study Says Fast-Food Is Middle-Class Luxury: How Often Do You Eat ..." webtitle="Study Says Fast-Food Is Middle-Class Luxury: How Often Do You Eat Fast Food?">
			<query id="000368" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="000373" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="001126" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="001121" bing-rank="227"/>
	<description>Study Says Fast-Food Is Middle-Class Luxury: How Often Do You Eat Fast Food?</description>
	<body>
		SodaHeadlines Entertainment Living Fun&amp;Humor games sports music fashion News&amp;Politics Leaderboard 
Study Says Fast-Food Is Middle-Class Luxury: How Often Do You Eat Fast Food?
 by SodaHead Living Posted November 12, 2011 18:19:09 Related Topics: Health , School , Los Angeles , Income , State , Research , Past , Lawmakers , McDonalds , Obesity , Fast Food , Restaurants , Time , Eating , Class , Eat 
 +31 Rave 5 Share Widget 
 
 615 votes Read all 417 opinions Lightning Report View Results and Demographics View Demographics 
 
 Never A couple times year Once a month A couple times a month Once a week A couple times a week Every day 
 
 
 
 Loading Demographics... 
Click an icon to see demographic results
 Display unknown and private Never 49 votes 8% A couple times year 125 votes 20% Once a month 96 votes 16% A couple times a month 153 votes 25% Once a week 80 votes 13% A couple times a week 91 votes 15% Every day 21 votes 3% 
 You! Add Photos&amp;Videos According to conventional wisdom, fast-food consumption is behind the skyrocketing obesity rates among America’s poorest individuals. However, a new study by a professor at UC Davis’s medical school discovered that in actuality, fast food is primarily a middle-class luxury.

&quot;There&apos;s a strong correlation been income and obesity,&quot; professor Paul Leigh told the Los Angeles Times. &quot;And so people say, &apos;Oh, well, it&apos;s the fast-food restaurants that are causing obesity among the poor.&apos; But that&apos;s not true. To focus on fast-food restaurants as the sole cause of obesity is incorrect.&quot;

Leigh’s research, which will soon be published in the journal of Population Health Management, found that as a household’s income increased so did visits to fast-food chains like McDonald’s and Burger King. However, as income increased even further, past the $80,000 to $90,000 range, fast-food consumption dropped significantly.

Leigh is not trying to defend fast food. He himself is not fan. However, he hopes to help lawmakers and others in positions of power to focus on the most significant causes of obesity. According to Leigh, when it comes to America’s poorest, the relatively cheap prices of junk food, especially soda, in supermarkets and convenience stores are the worst culprits.

What about you? How often do you eat fast food ? +31 
 Read More: http://latimesblogs.latimes.com/nationnow/2011/11/... 
 
More polls by SodaHead Living

 How Hard Is It to Get Decent Insurance? Do You Understand Your Health Policy? Ever Paid for Accident Out-of-Pocket? Ever Paid a Medical Bill Out-of-Pocket? 
 Add a comment above 
Top Opinion

 Anonymouse ~bibbityboo~ November 13, 2011 02:08:11 Once a month +6 We eat take-aways more often, but we mainly eat home cooked meals. &gt;&gt;See Replies 
 
 Sort By 
 Most Raves Least Raves Oldest Newest 
 text size Opinions
 
 mg&apos;s haven~POTL~PWCM~JLA November 19, 2011 07:24:01 A couple times a month Who did this study and where did they crawl out of. I see more less than middle class people in those places than middle class will ever go there. reply Roxas November 17, 2011 23:29:44 A couple times a month When we can afford it or we dont have time we love to eat out. I love to eat out as unhealthy as that is haha xD reply Johann November 15, 2011 21:26:17 A couple times year I mostly eat at home, I have more control over what I am eating. There are times when I get off college and I do not feel like cooking, that I would head to the local fast food chain or restaurant. I too have read the book, &quot;The Omnivore&apos;s Dilemma&quot; and seen &quot;Supersize Me&quot;. So I am more educated on what and where I should eat when out and about. Being a starving college student, I save more on shopping than if I were to eat out. reply luigi1- in god we trust November 15, 2011 19:38:22 Once a week I brown bag it. Fast food is a once a week luxury when your broke. reply william keegan November 15, 2011 18:11:43 Never Some years ago I would frequent fast food outlets, but in addition to the plastic tasting food, the sullen attitudes of the &quot;servers&quot; there totally turned me off. I presently absolutly refuse to patronize any fast food establishment. reply I Wish I Were A Skywalker..... November 15, 2011 17:03:54 A couple times year +1 When I do go, I completely stuff my face and basically don&apos;t move for the rest of the day. But I give that to myself as a treat about every three months, because I have self control. Fast food isn&apos;t the cost of obesity, people who lack discipline, self restraint and self respect are the issue. reply fuzzy Ken&quot;In G-d We Trust&quot; November 15, 2011 16:57:48 A couple times a month BY fast food I mean take-out Chinese, Thai, Tex-Mex or lamb from a Halal cart.
I do not go to fast food chains.*

* OK, I&apos;ll admit to hitting a White Castle a few times a year, but that&apos;s it. LOL reply janet November 15, 2011 15:49:41 A couple times year I am not big on fast foods but I do buy lots of deli food in the supermarket or in the forzen foods area. I do also buy lots of fresh veggie and fruit but I truly live off the deli section in my supermarket. The food is cooked warm and good. reply Paula Clarke November 15, 2011 15:23:42 A couple times year +1 I only eat fastfood when necessary, like when stuck in a small airport or something reply Yoru Azenia November 15, 2011 14:55:16 Once a week We usually order Dominos Pizza once a week though sometimes we eat at McDonalds or something reply FantasyAuthor November 15, 2011 14:41:55 A couple times a week +2 When my parents and I go out to eat, I try to find the most healthest thing on the menu for 1)I am recovering from my eating disorder 2)I am trying to stay healthy, 3)I am trying to stay healthy and 4)I am trying to make good choices. reply thegaln... to Fantasy... November 15, 2011 17:37:09 hang in there and keep it up.... good for you! reply Fantasy... to thegaln... November 15, 2011 18:21:16 I will. I promise. Thank you. reply RID November 15, 2011 12:42:07 Never +1 never only started a year ago ... but watching Food Inc. and reading Fast Food Nation (and Omnivore&apos;s Dilemma too!) will pretty quickly control that longing for a big mac ... the whole process is pretty nasty frankly reply bettynewberry November 15, 2011 12:38:04 A couple times a month I drive through town all the time looking at the fast food places and I love me a good thick and juicy cheese burger......................but 9 times out of 10 I eat at home. You cannot control the calorie content nor how clean the food is prepared...................plus it is cheaper in the long run to eat at home. I imagine if I stopped and got fast food every time I saw some place that looked good...........I would be over 300 pounds. reply Wizard November 15, 2011 08:00:15 Once a week +4 My autistic sister whom I have custody of after mom died early in summer this year, likes Fast Food. She is used to being taken out around once a week...so I indulge her, even though we have more than enough food at home. She likes McFlurries or other sweets. McDonalds is much cheaper for ice-cream that some of the ice-cream shops. To save on costs, I usually get the bargain burger or whatever is on a coupon or on sale. reply MAMMY51... to Wizard November 15, 2011 10:06:59 +3 It is good she has someone like you to care for her.

 reply fuzzy K... to Wizard November 15, 2011 16:53:52 You are a great brother.
Your sister is truly blessed. reply thegaln... to Wizard November 15, 2011 17:38:18 Bless you for taking care of your sister. reply Wizard to thegaln... November 19, 2011 04:16:10 (edited) Thanks. If I had my choice, I&apos;d choose a triple meat pizza or specialty size with hand tossed crust. My autistic sister will eat pizza...but is nearly 100% vegetarian...so if I get pepperoni, she may or may not pull the little circles of meat off the pizza...and eat the sauce and cheese...leaving the crust and much of the dough behind.

I do have to protest that pizza could be counted as a vegetable. They barely give you enough onions or green peppers - and counting the tomato sauce as a vegetable reminds me of the Ronald Reagan era.

 reply thegaln... to Wizard November 19, 2011 09:15:43 LOL I hear you but you haven&apos;t seen MY Home Made pizza -- a thin tortilla crust, tomato sauce, a WHOLE 3-4inch diameter onion, garlic, two or three cut up tomatoes, black olives, green olives, an 8 oz can of mushrooms, and many other vegetables. You have to eat it with a fork.... it&apos;s all about the toppings and please leave the meat off if you&apos;re going to put cheese on it. reply Wizard to thegaln... November 19, 2011 18:56:28 (edited) Pizza! Pizza! I&apos;d probably get lost in your pizza! At one time...I would of glady eaten pizza everyday. Hot-n-Ready is a favorite. They do have all cheese, but even my sister, who is a pt vegetarian, thinks the pepperoni stays on. I guess it is for looks.

I went with a vegetarian for a year in the 1990&apos;s, we broke up one evening when I came home with McDonald&apos;s on my breath. Hey, I only said I&apos;d meet her 1/2 way, not convert. reply thegaln... to Wizard November 20, 2011 06:14:16 hey, I even designated one pan in my kitchen as a pork pan for my husband. He had his own pork drawer as well in the frig. reply Latika November 15, 2011 06:31:07 Once a month well if pizza counts as fast food - then once a month.
if not - then i hardly ever eat fastfood. i don&apos;t like it except for ff with ice-cream. reply Bill November 15, 2011 05:15:03 Once a week +1 I love fast food. I would eat it everyday, if I wasn&apos;t on a diet most of the time. reply carlton999 November 15, 2011 04:39:48 Once a month hardly ever but I love it. reply Greetings Chap November 15, 2011 04:39:04 Once a week I eat it when it&apos;s convenient and I don&apos;t have time for much else. That is the purpose of fast food. reply Rakohammas November 15, 2011 04:28:03 A couple times year My parents were all crazy about me having a good health lol they still do, if I wanted some fast food was behind their back :s reply Edie November 15, 2011 03:05:31 Never I was not allowed to eat fast food as a child therefore it is not something I crave. reply beck November 15, 2011 02:49:57 Once a week its sooo much easier!! reply SK November 15, 2011 02:44:05 Once a month Burger King french fries = treat. reply MyPaperBleedsInk November 15, 2011 02:08:43 Once a month Whenever my parents come to visit at college we usually go fast food... or a restaurant, but even then I&apos;ll get some fast food on the way back to my dorm to eat the next day. reply MAMMY51♥POTL~PWCM~JLA♥ November 15, 2011 01:39:03 Once a month +1 Does a subway salad count? reply thegaln... to MAMMY51... November 15, 2011 05:15:18 +2 it does for me... the time it takes to make a good salad, going to subway is fast food but healthy.... reply MAMMY51... to thegaln... November 15, 2011 09:59:35 +1 I do eat and enjoy meat. However if salad is on the menu, I nearly always choose the salad. reply I Wish ... to MAMMY51... November 15, 2011 17:08:43 +1 You should be careful, the ingredients in salads (like lettuce and raw vegetables) can slow your metabolism and your digestion, therefore making you gain weight. Plus, they don&apos;t have enough nutrients to keep you going for a long time, making your blood sugar become low, and you become more likely to snack. reply thegaln... to I Wish ... November 15, 2011 17:42:36 +1 granted -- I take a natural vitamin and a high nutrition shake..... reply MAMMY51... to I Wish ... November 15, 2011 18:09:41 Thanks, I didn&apos;t know that. reply I Wish ... to MAMMY51... November 15, 2011 18:44:10 +1 Yeah, my doctor told me and I was so shocked. I always thought salads were what skinny girls ate... reply thegaln... to I Wish ... November 16, 2011 05:36:31 the dressings are especially fattening... try pineapple juice instead or mandarin oranges and the juice. reply 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 ... 11 Next» Last» 
See Votes by State
 The map above displays the winning answer by region. Loading map... 
 Living

 July 12, 2012 15:34:48 

 
 Hot Questions on SodaHead 

 Town Designates Easy Parking Spots for Women: Is It Sexist or Sweet? 78% voted Sexist Do you agree? Lifestyle Do Your Political Beliefs Influence the Social Media Sites You Use? 68% voted No Do you agree? Public Opinion Study Links Spanking to Later Mental Disorders: Is Spanking Ever OK? 73% voted Yes Do you agree? Lifestyle What Is the Most Important Thing You Insure? 35% voted My health Do you agree? Public Opinion A Reality Series About Moms Who Breastfeed Older Kids Is in the Works: Great Idea, or Worst Show Ever? 81% voted Worst sho... Do you agree? tv &apos;Serial Hugger&apos;Tricks Women Into Giving Him Birthday Hugs: Criminal or Just Creepy? 52% voted Creepy Do you agree? Public Opinion Is It Perpetuating Gender Stereotypes to Throw Little Girls Princess Parties? 46% voted It is per... Do you agree? Public Opinion PUBLIC OPINION&gt;15 Is Old Enough to Wax Vote Recap 


 More Community More Originals 
 
 
Slideshow
 Who&apos;s Your Fave Hollywood Rock&apos;Star&apos;? 
Slideshow
 Ugliest Celeb Mother-Daughter Battle? 
Slideshow
 Who Should Replace J-Lo on&apos;Idol&apos;? View more slideshows» 
 
 Login Register 

 Ask 
 Ask a Question Create a Poll Widget 
 Answer 
 Hot Questions Recent Questions 
 Discover 
 Find People Groups Slideshows 
 
 Hot Topics Lifestyle Fashion Food Pets more… Topics: Lifestyle Fashion Food Pets Facebook more… Site Links 
 Ask a Question Create a Poll Widget Hot Questions Slideshows Topics 

 News&amp;Politics Opinions Entertainment Opinions Living Opinions Fun&amp;Humor Sitemap 
 Help 
 FAQs Help Find Friends Contact Us 

 Report Abuse Terms of Use Privacy Code of Conduct 
 About SodaHead 
 About Us Advertise with us Poll Widget Samples 

 Polling Solutions @SodaHead on Twitter Like us on Facebook 
 © 2012
 SodaHead.com All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
