<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001211" url="http://www.tripadvisor.com/ShowUserReviews-g55557-d508898-r29020511-Fastaco-Burleson_Texas.html" time="2012-07-12-16:40" support="3" score="0.014168222396104563" bingtitle="I&apos;ve been eating here FOREVER. They do mess up orders occasionally ..." webtitle="Ive been eating here FOREVER. They do mess up orders occasionally, but what fast food restaurant doesnt? They serve... - Review of Fastaco, Burleson, TX - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="000893" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="001364" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="001348" bing-rank="218"/>
	<description>Fastaco: I&apos;ve been eating here FOREVER. They do mess up orders occasionally, but what fast food restaurant doesn&apos;t? They serve... - See traveler reviews ...</description>
	<body>
		Fastaco reviews
 
 Home Burleson 
 Burleson Tourism Burleson Hotels Burleson Vacation Rentals Flights to Burleson Burleson Restaurants Things to Do in Burleson Burleson Travel Forum Burleson Photos Burleson Travel Guide 
 Hotels Flights Vacation Rentals Restaurants Things to Do Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
 Home 
 &gt; United States &gt; Texas (TX) &gt; Burleson &gt; Burleson Restaurants &gt; Fastaco 
 
 Back to Fastaco 
Fastaco: Restaurant Reviews
 555 SW Wilshire Blvd , Burleson , TX 76028-5331 817-295-7475 Got a photo? 
 Add it. Ranked #18 of 28 restaurants in Burleson 6 Reviews Cuisines: Mexican Restaurant details Update restaurant details Write a Review 
6 reviews from our community
 50% Recommend 
 Excellent 3 Very good 0 Average 1 Poor 0 Terrible 2 
 Rating summary 
 Food Service Value Atmosphere 
 6 reviews sorted by Date Rating A TripAdvisor reviewer on Facebook “I&apos;ve been eating here FOREVER. They do mess up orders occasionally, but what fast food restaurant doesn&apos;t? They serve...” Reviewed April 23, 2009 
I&apos;ve been eating here FOREVER. They do mess up orders occasionally, but what fast food restaurant doesn&apos;t? They serve big portions and it tastes more like real mexican food than Taco Bell. We Love Fastaco!
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? This review is the subjective opinion of an individual contributor and not of TripAdvisor LLC. txfoodknowitall txfoodknowitall 1 review “I will drive for MILES for FASTACO” Reviewed October 26, 2008 
The flagship taco, the FASTACO is so delicious and unique. Instead of your everyday corn taco shell, you get flour. It adds a whole new dimension to the taco world. Also, their salsa is amazing.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Ask txfoodknowitall about Fastaco This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. dissatisfiedTexas dissatisfiedTexas 1 review “Worst place” Reviewed July 1, 2008 
The food is good, but they short you on your food and they will refuse business to anyone!!! Some of the staff are rude.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Ask dissatisfiedTexas about Fastaco This review is the subjective opinion of a TripAdvisor member and not of TripAdvisor LLC. 4-6 of 6 reviews « 1 2 » 
Travelers who viewed Fastaco also viewed
 Babe&apos;s Chicken Dinner House 72 Reviews Burleson, TX On The Border Mexican Grill&amp;Cantina 6 Reviews Burleson, TX   Villa Dianna 6 Reviews Burleson, TX
	</body>
</document>
