<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001849" url="http://azstarnet.com/business/local/lucky-wishbone-founder-a-fast-food-pioneer-dies/article_a1d5d66a-d464-5a5c-a463-8377719a3b92.html" time="2012-07-12-17:38" support="3" score="0.00486974311218534" bingtitle="Lucky Wishbone founder, a fast-food pioneer, dies" webtitle="Lucky Wishbone founder, a fast-food pioneer, dies">
			<query id="000175" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000455" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000424" bing-rank="172"/>
	<description>... the company&apos;s website says was Tucson&apos;s first fast-food ... Credit care: Your credit card payment can be rejected if ... Sign up to receive the Star&apos;s midmorning business news ...</description>
	<body>
		Mobile Advertise Subscriber Services eDelivery Contact Us 99¢ Home Delivery 
 81° Clear 
 Weekly Forecast 
 Friday 102° 81° Saturday 97° 78° Sunday 97° 77° Monday 95° 76° 
 
 sponsored by Advanced Search | Privacy | About Our Ads 
 News 
 News Web 
 
 Search Web Search powered by YAHOO! SEARCH 
 Home News 
 All Headlines Blogs Border Business Crime Education Elections Environment La Estrella de Tucsón Local Multimedia National Real Estate Science State and Region Weather news World 
 Sports 
 UA Sports Blogs Golf Greg Hansen High Schools NBA MLB NHL NFL Olympics Soccer 
 Opinion 
 Caption Contest Editorials Fitz Archive Fitz Blog Fitz Store Letters to the Editor 
 Entertainment 
 Arts/Theater Blog Books Movies Music Outdoors Photos Puzzles Restaurants/Bars TV Articles TV Listings 
 Life 
 Bridal Calendar Celebrations Contests Food Home+Life Pets Travel Photography Readers&apos; Gallery Retirement 
 Obituaries 
 Make a donation Place an obituary Send flowers Storied lives, extraordinary stories Today&apos;s obituaries &amp; guest books 
 Get It! 
 Business Directory Coupons Daily Star Ads Featured Businesses Get It Today - Deals Place a Display Ad 
 Classifieds 
 Cars Jobs Obituaries Pets Place a Classified Ad Public Notices/Legals Real Estate Rentals Stuff Yard Sales 
 Real Estate 
 Agents, Advertise Your Listings Classified Listings Find an Agent Land and Other Luxury New Listings Resale Listings Sell Your Home Sell Your Manufactured Home 
 Rentals 
 Find a Home Find a Rental Renter Insurance, Utilities, Finance Rent Your Home 
 Cars 
 Cycles, Boats, RV&apos;s &amp; More Financing and Loan Calculator Find a Dealer Find a New or Used Car Sell a Car Research &amp; Blue Book Values 
 Jobs 
 Find a Job Job Fairs &amp; Events Post Resume Post a Job Virtual Career Fairs 
 
 
 Mobile apps Android iPhone iPad Kindle Fire E-edition for iPad Wildcat Extra for Android Wildcat Extra for iPhone All 
 
 Home / Business / Local 
 
Lucky Wishbone founder, a fast-food pioneer, dies
 Print Email 2011-10-20T00:00:00Z Lucky Wishbone founder, a fast-food pioneer, dies Kimberly Matas Arizona Daily Star Arizona Daily Star October 20, 2011 12:00 am  •  Kimberly Matas Arizona Daily Star Comments 
Derald Fulton&apos;s recipe for success was simple: Figure out what
Tucsonans want and give it to them.

It was a business plan that served him well for more than 50
years. Fulton was the founder of the Lucky Wishbone restaurants,
where diners are hard-pressed to find anything on the menu that
isn&apos;t deep fried. And that&apos;s how generations of loyal customers
like it.

Lucky Wishbone continued to serve up the same tasty, inexpensive
fare after Fulton retired a dozen years ago. He and his wife of 70
years, Daisy, moved to Phoenix six years ago, and that is where
Fulton died Oct. 5, a month shy of his 97th birthday.

Fulton and his wife moved to Arizona in 1947. After years of
coaching high school basketball and teaching history in the
Midwest, Fulton, a Southern Illinois University graduate, wanted a
new challenge, said his son Gary. Fulton went into business with a
friend in Phoenix and opened the Polar Bar, a restaurant popular
with teens, where food was served by carhops.

After a few years, the Fultons moved to Tucson and in July 1953,
opened the first Lucky Wishbone on South Sixth Avenue. Despite the
sweltering summer temperature, hundreds of people waited in line to
pick up boxes of fried chicken at what the company&apos;s website says
was Tucson&apos;s first fast-food restaurant.

Realizing he had a hit on his plate, Fulton quickly opened more
Lucky Wishbones with the help of three men who would become his
managing partners: Clyde &quot;Buzz&quot; Buzzard, John Kinder and Donald
Morris. Buzzard is the last surviving partner.

&quot;He really experimented,&quot; Gary Fulton said of his father. &quot;He
wanted something different. He wanted something that wasn&apos;t much
trouble, that was simple, that there wasn&apos;t a bunch of
seating.&quot;

The answer: takeout food. Stand in line, place an order, walk
out with a meal in a box.

&quot;That was totally unique back then. Everybody either cooked or
ate at a restaurant,&quot; Gary Fulton said. &quot;It just exploded. They
used to open up a new place and maybe 500 people would be in
line.&quot;

Today, there are seven locations in Tucson, and a Sierra Vista
restaurant is expected to open at the end of the year.

The son of Illinois grangers, Fulton &quot;had that Midwest farmer&apos;s
mentality. He was very, very honest; a lot of integrity. Worked
hard. Treated people right,&quot; his son said.

Fulton is survived by his wife, two sons, Gary and Scott, five
grandchildren, six great-grandchildren and a stepbrother, John. He
was predeceased by his daughter, Jane Block. At Fulton&apos;s request,
there is no public memorial service.

 Contact reporter Kimberly Matas at kmatas@azstarnet.com or
573-4191. 
 Join Discussion 
More Local stories
 
 
 Job fair for veterans, military spouses is today in Tucson 
 
 Home prices hold steady; average number of days on market keeps slipping 
 
 Business briefs 
 
 Phoenix to pour up to $50M into local banks 
 
 
Recommendations
 
Sponsored Links
 
 Copyright 2012 Arizona Daily Star. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 
Most popular
 
 Articles Comments Facebook 
 

 
 Featured businesses 
 View more... 
 DC Auto Sales 
 
 Katrina&apos;s Bridal and Tuxedo 
 
 Small Miracle Craft Mall 
 
 Amoré Assisted Living 
 
Find a local business
 I&apos;m looking for: Located near: 
 Hint: Enter a keyword that you are looking for like tires, pizza or doctors or browse the full business directory , powered by Local.com 
 
 Deals, offers&amp;events 
 View more... 
 Lawns: 

Blend Tank’s Green Stuff Compost with existing soil. Blend 3 t…
 
 Drive As Long As Posiible! 

If you want to keep driving for as long as possible. Here are…
 
 Our Vision 

Our vision of helping the local communities become more sustai…
 
 Stop in and get your Acai fix today! 

A good source of fiber with 3.5 grams of dietary fiber per ser…
 
Event Calendar

 Most viewed: 

 • Today&apos;s events 
 • Add an event 
 • Business 
 • Fund-raisers 
 • Theater 
 • Movie times 
 Local advertising by PaperG 
StarNet newsletters

Sign up for StarNet e-mail newsletters
 Contests Get It Today Daily headlines Top deals Food&amp;Wine Wildcat Sports Report Business Entertainment Tucson Festival of Books First name: Last name: Zip code: Email: 
Services

 Advertise on our site Contact us Databases E-edition Events calendar Mobile StarNet Newsletters Find businesses Photo reprints Public notices Readers&apos; photo gallery Register RSS feeds Scanners StarNet shop Subscriber services / EZ Access 

StarNet partners

 Amazon Arizona Daily Star store Arizona Daily Wildcat KVOI.com La Estrella de Tucson Yahoo! Tucson Festival of Books 
 ©Copyright 2012, Arizona Daily Star , 4850 S. Park Ave. Tucson, AZ | Terms of Service and Privacy Policy × 
Join the conversation
 
 Login Signup 
 
Use your existing azstarnet.com account or a previously connected Facebook account.
 
Login with azstarnet.com account:
 
Email&amp;Password Required!
 Email: Password: Remember me on this computer Forgot Password Please Wait… Login
	</body>
</document>
