<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001784" url="http://www.gazette.com/articles/carson-106191-fort-robbery.html" time="2012-07-12-17:34" support="3" score="0.004326392662290466" bingtitle="One shot in Fort Carson robbery | carson, fort, robbery - Top ..." webtitle="One shot in Fort Carson robbery | carson, fort, robbery - Top Stories - Colorado Springs Gazette, CO">
			<query id="001305" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="000687" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000123" bing-rank="122"/>
	<description>Pay Your Bill Online; Vacation Stop; EZpay Program; Purchase Back Issues; Sales Locations; Green Edition FAQ; Coupons; Matress Img; Jobs; Auto; Real Estate</description>
	<body>
		Gazette 
 Get Email&amp;Mobile Alerts | Classifieds | Green Edition | Subscribe to Paper 
 
 76° 
 Sunny 5-Day Forecast 
 Home Local 
 News Crime&amp;Justice Government Photos Military&gt; 
 SpringsMilitaryLife.com 
 Education&gt; 
 PikesPeakParent.com Graduation 
 Infocenter&gt; 
 Databases Community Links Special News Reports 
 Side Streets Barry Noreen 2012 Vote Nonprofits Traffic Homicide Map Leave a News Tip CSFreshInk.com Around Town Did You Ever Wonder? School Closings 
 Obits 
 Obituaries, Guest Books Submit a Death Notice Place a Paid Obituary 
 Entertainment 
 ColoradoSprings.com Best of the Springs Event Calendar Dining Guide Cinema Guide Around Town TV Listings Travel Books Pets Games Comics Puzzles Horoscopes 
 Life 
 Travel Gardening 
 Sports 
 News David Ramsey Air Force Academy Colorado College Hockey gazettepreps.com&gt; 
 Peak Performers 
 OutThereColorado.com Broncos Olympics Rockies/Sky Sox Where Are They Now? Area Golf Course Guide 
 Business 
 News Local Stocks Local Gas Watch Pikes Peak Shopping Local Home Values Economic Indicators 
 Opinion 
 Views&amp;Letters Guest Columnists Submit a Letter Contact Elected Officials Freedom Politics The Broadside Blog 
 Customer Service 
 Contact Customer Service Subscribe Pay Your Bill Online Vacation Stop EZpay Program Purchase Back Issues Sales Locations Green Edition FAQ Coupons 
 Matress Img Jobs Auto Real Estate 
 
 Don&apos;t Miss: HOW TO DONATE | FIRE COVERAGE | Aerial fire pics | FIRE PHOTOS | FIRE VIDEO | VOTERS GUIDE | LIVE TRAFFIC 
 
 Public Safety 
  &gt;  
 News 
 Font Size 

 

 
Person shot in Fort Carson robbery
 

 October 11, 2010 9:01 PM | Print Story | E-Mail Story CARLYN RAY MITCHELL THE GAZETTE 
One person was shot Monday night in an armed robbery at the Burger King on Fort Carson.

The robbery took place around 8:15 p.m. Fort Carson police questioned and released one person, said Fort Carson spokesman Devin Fischer.

The person shot was taken to the hospital with non-life threatening injuries.

Gates surrounding the post were temporarily closed as a precaution, Fischer said.

No arrests had been made late Monday and no other details were released.
 
 

 See archived &apos;Public Safety&apos; stories» 
  
 
 Day Lily Salon&amp;Spa 70% OFF - ONLY $30 for a Cut, Partial Highlights and Style at Day Lily Salon&amp;Spa ADVERTISEMENT  Most Viewed 
 SIDE STREETS: Flying W owner ponders future (with video) Peyton Manning buys Denver area mansion for $4.5M Velasquez makes explosive new allegations in lawsuit Body&apos;s condition makes identity difficult to discern WALDO CANYON FIRE: More than 30 homes burglarized in evacuated areas 
 Things to do in the Pikes Peak region 
 
 Events Dining Venues Movies 
 
 Featured Events Event Listings 
 Click for More Events Add Your Events   
 Find an Event 
 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT  Latest Obits 
 Anderson, Anthony R. &quot;Tony&quot; Favela, Patricia Kendall, Dorothy Lee Kostelc, Carolyn A. Floryancic Sipe, Debbie 
 Click here for more Local Business Websites 
 Name: City: SELECT AN AREA ALL Air Force Academy Black Forest/Gleneagle Briargate North Broadmoor/Cheyenne Mountain Colorado Springs Downtown Falcon/Peyton/Calhan/Eastern Plains Fountain/Security/Widefield/Fort Carson Manitou Springs Old Colorado City Other Teller County/Lake George Peterson AFB/COS Airport Powers Corridor Rockrimmon Tri-Lakes Ute Pass Woodland Park 
 Featured Categories 
 Arts&amp;Entertainment Autos Beauty&amp;Wellness Financial Health Care Home Improvement 

 Hotels&amp;Lodging Legal Real Estate Restaurant Shopping View All» 
 Poll National Top Videos 
 » U.S. news 
» Entertainment 
» Business 
» Lifestyle 
» Sports 
» Health 
 powered by
          Search: Web   Site 
 Advertising Info Place An Ad Today&apos;s Ads Place an Announcement Interactive   

 About Us Contact Us Facebook Comments FAQ Contact the Newsroom Advertise Gazette Speakers&apos; Bureau Work For Us Copyright and Reprint Information 

 Subscriber Services Subscriber Services Manage Print Subscription Pay Your Bill Online Vacation Stop Archives Newspaper Ads Buy Our Photos Single Copy Locations 

 Online News Environment The Street Green Edition E-Newsletters/ Alerts RSS Feeds Mobile Article Map AP Terms&amp;Conditions 

 Related Sites Dreamcity2020.org Coloradosprings.com Gazettepreps.com PikesPeakParent.com Best of the Springs FreedomPolitics.com CSFreshink.com OutThereColorado.com SpringsMilitaryLife.com 
 


 Privacy Policy | User Agreement | Site Map 

 Autos | Homes&amp;Real Estate | Jobs | Classifieds | ColoradoSprings.com 

 Local Business Directory | Webmaster 
 
 Freedom Communications, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
