<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001807" url="http://boards.straightdope.com/sdmb/archive/index.php/t-329749.html" time="2012-07-12-17:35" support="63" score="0.13227248142540965" bingtitle="The Ten Commandments of Drive-Thru Etiquette [Archive] - Straight ..." webtitle="The Ten Commandments of Drive-Thru Etiquette [Archive]  - Straight Dope Message Board">
			<query id="000260" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000410" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000320" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000498" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000469" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000493" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="000190" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="000567" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="001417" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000484" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000499" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000569" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000973" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="000533" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="001426" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000479" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000986" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="000473" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000487" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000693" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="001412" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="000694" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000069" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="001009" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000161" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001161" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000497" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000488" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000266" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000546" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="001038" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000257" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000194" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="000978" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000482" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000470" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000193" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000690" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000067" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000474" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="000064" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="000485" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="000195" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000475" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000600" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="000661" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000078" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="001164" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000726" bing-rank="249"/>
			<query id="000695" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000253" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000478" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000258" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="001321" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="001415" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="000270" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="000318" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="000494" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000505" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000256" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000755" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000476" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000595" bing-rank="228"/>
	<description>... because the clerk isn&apos;t ready to take your order the ... can&apos;t remember the last time I&apos;ve been to a fast-food restaurant ... large, flat, opaque object (such as a food tray) to ...</description>
	<body>
		Straight Dope Message Board &gt; Main &gt; The BBQ Pit &gt;The Ten Commandments of Drive-Thru Etiquette PDA 
View Full Version : The Ten Commandments of Drive-Thru Etiquette 
 Smapti 08-11-2005, 11:51 AM Having worked far too long in the food service industry, i&apos;ve seen my share of people who seem to have absolutely no idea how drive-thru restaurants work. I&apos;ve suffered no end of heartache and aggravation from people who can&apos;t seem to grasp what should be blatantly obvious, and i&apos;ve finally come to the conclusion that what the world needs is a simple guide to the thou shalts and thou shalt nots of the process. So here it is - a guide to the uninformed and a pitting of the clueless.

1) An there beith a preview board, thou shalt use it. Many drive-thrus now have two separate menu boards - one with the attached speaker, and a second menu one car-length behind the speaker. This is known as a&quot;preview board&quot;because the customer can look it over before advancing to the speaker and starting the restaurant&apos;s speed-of-service timer. If you don&apos;t know what you want, USE this board. Don&apos;t drive past it straight to the speaker, ask the clerk to&quot;gimme a second&quot;, and then spend two or three minutes staring at it while the speed-of-service time gets higher and higher.

2)Thou shalt not shout&quot;Hello?&quot;or honk thy horn if there is a delay at the speaker. Just because the clerk isn&apos;t ready to take your order the second you pull up doesn&apos;t mean they&apos;ve taken off their headset, clocked out, and gone home. Shouting&quot;Hello?&quot;or honking your horn will not make whatever the clerk is working on go away and it WON&apos;T get your order taken any faster - it only aggravates the clerk and potentially deafen them when they get a 110-decibal blast in the speaker strapped directly onto their ear.

3) Thou shalt not ask the clerk questions that could be answered by reading the menu. How much does the chicken sandwich cost? What comes on the TripleMax Superburger Deluxe? This is what the menu is FOR. It&apos;s the big thing right in front of you with all the words and numbers on it, not to mention the great big pictures where each item has been carefully posed to display each of its ingredients in larger-than-life detail. Use it.

4) Thou shalt NOT add to thy order at the window. Doing this requires the clerk to go back in and change your order (which at many restaurants requires a manager&apos;s approval to void part or all of the order), delays us getting your order out while we make whatever you decided you just couldn&apos;t live without during the lengthy 20&apos; drive from the speaker to the window, and delays everyone behind you getting what they want as well. Just don&apos;t do it.

5) If there is a line at the window, thou shalt start counting thy money before reaching it. We tell you what your total is at the speaker. Most restaurants also have video screens that show your total in big numbers. There is no reason for you to not know your total before you leave the speaker. If there&apos;s a car ahead of you at the window, there is no reason for you not to start counting out your money before you get there. Reaching the window after a three-minute wait and THEN deciding to start counting out the $37 in nickels you intend to pay me with is just lazy.

6) Thou shalt use actual numbers when ordering a quantity greater than one. I don&apos;t know how many&quot;a couple&quot;,&quot;a bunch&quot;,&quot;a lot&quot;, or&quot;a shitload&quot;of hamburgers is. I never learned those numbers in kindergarten. If you ask me for such a quantity, I will ask you to be more specific. The same goes for sauces. Our default is to give you one package of sauce for each item that requires it. If you ask me for a specific larger number I will give you that many, but if you ask me for&quot;a bunch&quot;or&quot;a lot&quot;I will give you two packages for each item. If you ask me for&quot;a shitload&quot;I may ask you not to come back to my store.

7) Thou shalt NOT use curse words into the drive-thru speaker. This one follows from the Sixth Commandment. The speaker you&apos;re talking into is connected to a loudspeaker which is audible to everyone in the kitchen and, often, to everyone in the lobby as well. This is a family business and more often than not there are children dining in our lobby. It is not appropriate for you to pull up to my speaker and start using profanity towards me, let alone my staff and customers. An idle slip of the tongue may be excused, but do it again and you&apos;ll be asked to leave.

8) Thou shalt not order another restaurant&apos;s menu items from us. We don&apos;t sell Big Macs here. We don&apos;t sell Whoppers here. We don&apos;t sell McChickens, Biggie Fries, Frosties, Grillburgers, McFlurries, McNuggets, Chicken Fries, Crossainwiches, McMuffins, McGriddles, or anything else that starts with&quot;Mc&quot;for that matter. You cannot Super-Size, King Size, or Biggie-Size our combos. We carry Coke, not Pepsi. We can&apos;t give you fry sauce, onion ring sauce, or Horsey sauce. Corellary: Thou shalt not order the item we carried for about a month two years ago and act shocked that we can&apos;t make it for you. We don&apos;t even carry the ingredients for that anymore. No, not even if you ask nicely.

9) Thou shalt make sure you have cash or a credit card BEFORE thou order. Think hard for just a second, buddy - have you EVER heard of a drive-thru restaurant taking checks? I didn&apos;t think so. Make sure you have the ability to pay for your order BEFORE you order it. Pulling up to the window and then&quot;discovering&quot;that you forgot your wallet won&apos;t earn you any sympathy from those of us who just busted our asses to make your order and now have to throw it all out. And no, it WON&apos;T get you any free food, either.

10) Thou shalt not, not, NOT, EVER, ask the clerk to&quot;hook you up&quot;. This is a business, not a charity. You want free food? Go to the food bank downtown. We&apos;re in business to make money, not feed your broke ass. I don&apos;t even know you. Why would I risk my job by giving away free food to a complete stranger? No, not if you give me a puff off your peace pipe. No, not if your girlfriend shows me her tits (and what kind of girl flashes a complete stranger for a 99-cent sandwich anyway?) No, not if you&apos;re really good buddies with the manager or the area coach or Sally in Accounting, because right here and right now I AM the manager and i&apos;ve never seen you before in my life.

Unbelievers, repent your sins and be saved. Anybody else got any commandments they&apos;d like to throw in before I break out the chisel? lno 08-11-2005, 11:57 AM 9) Thou shalt make sure you have cash or a credit card BEFORE thou order. Think hard for just a second, buddy - have you EVER heard of a drive-thru restaurant taking checks? I didn&apos;t think so.I am an acolyte of the drive-thru window, having spent two summers doing that many years ago. I wish to offer a mild correction to this above -- in Minneapolis, some drive-thru restaurants still do take checks, and those that ceased, only ceased a few short years ago.Anybody else got any commandments they&apos;d like to throw in before I break out the chisel?I would add:

11) Don&apos;t walk up to the drive-thru window. The sign claims it&apos;s for your safety, but it&apos;s for mine. If you&apos;re in your car, ideally wrapped snugly in a seat belt, you can&apos;t reach through the window to get to the register, food, or me. I like it that way. You stay in your car no matter how important you think you are. This goes double if bars have just closed and you&apos;re stumbling around drunk. Get outta the drive-thru lane. Left Hand of Dorkness 08-11-2005, 12:09 PM 2)Thou shalt not shout&quot;Hello?&quot;or honk thy horn if there is a delay at the speaker. Just because the clerk isn&apos;t ready to take your order the second you pull up doesn&apos;t mean they&apos;ve taken off their headset, clocked out, and gone home. Shouting&quot;Hello?&quot;or honking your horn will not make whatever the clerk is working on go away and it WON&apos;T get your order taken any faster - it only aggravates the clerk and potentially deafen them when they get a 110-decibal blast in the speaker strapped directly onto their ear.
Can&apos;t agree with you there. It&apos;s the restaurant&apos;s job to make sure that the customer is acknowledged right away. If the restaurant wants to make this be via an automated voice, fine; but if I am a customer and I drive up to the speaker and nothing happens, I have no way of knowing whether the speaker is broken, whether the employees are all smoking hash down in the deep freezer, or whether the employee is a split-second away from answering the speaker.

I don&apos;t honk, but I don&apos;t blame those who do. It&apos;s the restaurant&apos;s obligation to reassure the customer, not the customer&apos;s obligation to hope that the technology is working.

3) Thou shalt not ask the clerk questions that could be answered by reading the menu. How much does the chicken sandwich cost? What comes on the TripleMax Superburger Deluxe? This is what the menu is FOR. [/quote]
You know the menu backwards and forwards, right? I, the customer, do not. It&apos;s a more efficient use of my time to ask questions if I&apos;m having trouble finding the answers on the often bizarrely-laid-out menu.

Of course, if your restaurant orders the menu in alphabetical order, then never mind; but I&apos;ve never seen that.

6) Thou shalt use actual numbers when ordering a quantity greater than one. I don&apos;t know how many&quot;a couple&quot;,&quot;a bunch&quot;,&quot;a lot&quot;, or&quot;a shitload&quot;of hamburgers is. I never learned those numbers in kindergarten. If you ask me for such a quantity, I will ask you to be more specific. The same goes for sauces. Our default is to give you one package of sauce for each item that requires it. If you ask me for a specific larger number I will give you that many, but if you ask me for&quot;a bunch&quot;or&quot;a lot&quot;I will give you two packages for each item.
That&apos;s kinda dumb of you, I think. If I ask for a lot of ketchup, you either need to give me far more than I could want (e.g., a dozen packets per order of fries), OR, preferably, you need to say,&quot;Will 6 packets be enough?&quot;Instead of making a deliberately stingy guess as to what I need, you ought to be asking the questions you need to ask so as to get the order right.

Yes, questions and clarifications are allowed via the speaker. See item 3.

8) Thou shalt not order another restaurant&apos;s menu items from us.
Once more, you&apos;re the expert at fast food. I&apos;m an expert at database design. I don&apos;t expect you to know about normalizing data, and you ought not expect me to be an expert on what crappy names your restaurant applies to your crappy food. If I get the name wrong--if I order Pepsi instead of Coke--you need to ask,&quot;Is Coke okay?&quot;If I order a Big Mac instead of a Whopper, you need to ask,&quot;Is a Whopper okay?&quot;It&apos;s your job to be the expert here. That&apos;s why you make the big bucks.

Otherwise, I agree :).

Daniel Smapti 08-11-2005, 12:17 PM Can&apos;t agree with you there. It&apos;s the restaurant&apos;s job to make sure that the customer is acknowledged right away. If the restaurant wants to make this be via an automated voice, fine; but if I am a customer and I drive up to the speaker and nothing happens, I have no way of knowing whether the speaker is broken, whether the employees are all smoking hash down in the deep freezer, or whether the employee is a split-second away from answering the speaker.

Perhaps some clarification is in order on this point. I&apos;m not talking about failing to get a greeting - if you pull up to the speaker and nobody says hello, that&apos;s our fault, not yours. However, the clerk is not always ready to take an order when they greet you - they may be talking to a customer at the window, dropping fryer items because the restaurant is short-staffed that day, or doing something else that prevents them from ringing you up at that immediate second, in which case the standard greeting is&quot;Welcome, I will be with you in just a moment&quot;. What i&apos;m talking about is the people for whom this just isn&apos;t good enough, who feel obligated to start shouting or honking their horn if they don&apos;t hear a human voice every five seconds to assure them that the restaurant hasn&apos;t closed and the staff gone home in the time they were wondering whether a Bacon SuperBurger Deluxe with Cheesy Fries would be OK for their diet as long as they had a Diet Coke for the drink. THAT&apos;S what the Second Commandment is targeted at. Fionn 08-11-2005, 12:17 PM 3) Thou shalt not ask the clerk questions that could be answered by reading the menu. How much does the chicken sandwich cost? What comes on the TripleMax Superburger Deluxe?

I agree with all of your commandments, but I would bet that some people who ask these questions either can&apos;t read or can&apos;t read well. When I worked at a record store, we had a few regular customers who always asked us to read track listings for them. One of my coworkers had an uncle who was a lifelong illiterate, and she noticed some patterns that suggested these customers weren&apos;t really forgetting their glasses. Duck Duck Goose 08-11-2005, 12:19 PM Walgreens driveup mini-rant here:

(12) Don&apos;t continue to talk on the fucking CELL phone while I&apos;m attempting to find out what it is you WANT from us. Tell Betty or Bobby or Biddy to fucking HOLD while you tell me what it is you WANT.

And DON&apos;T keep yakking to them while you&apos;re simultaneously talking to ME, &apos;kay, Brenda? Life would be so much simpler, for Betty and Bobby and Biddy, too, if we didn&apos;t all have to cope with conversations that go,&quot;Hi, can I help you?/Just a minute/No, not you, I&apos;m at the Walgreens driveup/Just a minute/Can I get this refilled?/You don&apos;t have any more refills on this, we&apos;ll have to call the doctor/Just a minute/How can it not have any more refills?/No, not you, I&apos;m still at Walgreens/Just a minute&quot;...

My favorite is the lady who flips open her phone and initiates a conversation while I&apos;m getting her change. You cannot wait even 20 more seconds before you just gotta talk to Betty? And what&apos;s so important to tell her?&quot;Hi!....Well, I&apos;m at the Walgreens driveup...&quot;If you waited another 20 seconds, you could tell her,&quot;Hi!...I&apos;m driving away from the Walgreens driveup...&quot;And if you waited another 20 seconds, you could tell her,&quot;Hi! I&apos;m in front of Panera Bread...&quot;


And as long as I&apos;m here:

(13) Try to understand that Walgreens is not McDonalds. It takes us about 20 minutes to process your prescription, and that&apos;s when we&apos;re not busy--we don&apos;t keep your Prozac or Lipitor made up ahead of time in 30-pill batches like Big Macs. You come inside, it takes 20 minutes, you come through the driveup, it still takes 20 minutes. And no, you can&apos;t just sit there and wait, because there are other PEOPLE behind you--hello? And when I get back on the mike and ask you to pull around, don&apos;t glare at me because you hadda roll your window down and I interrupted your phone conversation with Betty or Bobby or Biddy.

(14) Thou shalt not honk thy horn 10 seconds after thou drivest up. I KNOW you&apos;re there, Fred, I can SEE you through the large industrial-size plate glass window, &apos;kay? You can see me, I can see you, but I&apos;m BUSY, Fred, &apos;kay? I&apos;m busy waiting on OTHER customers (see the way I&apos;m handing them pills and stuff? That&apos;s how you can tell I&apos;m waiting on them), and I&apos;ll be with ya in a minute, trust me. Left Hand of Dorkness 08-11-2005, 12:19 PM What i&apos;m talking about is the people for whom this just isn&apos;t good enough, who feel obligated to start shouting or honking their horn if they don&apos;t hear a human voice every five seconds to assure them that the restaurant hasn&apos;t closed and the staff gone home in the time they were wondering whether a Bacon SuperBurger Deluxe with Cheesy Fries would be OK for their diet as long as they had a Diet Coke for the drink. THAT&apos;S what the Second Commandment is targeted at.
Ah, okay then, the commandment is just and proper. Sorry about that!

Daniel dwc1970 08-11-2005, 12:27 PM #12 Thou shalt always informeth cashier of coupons and other discounts before pulling up to the window.

One of my greatest pet peeves of all from my fast food days was when customers would present coupons or inform me that they are senior citizens and are thus entitled to a 10% discount. In these cases the old ticket had to be voided out and re-entered, driving up speed-of-service times.

This also goes for dine-in customers as it still delays our work and keeps the people in line behind you waiting even longer.

#13. Thou shalt turneth off thy cell phone!

Please, either tell the other person to hold on for a moment if you are already on a call, or just don&apos;t take the call while you give the cashier money and receive your order. It&apos;s very rude and inconsiderate to prattle on while the cashier has to wait for you to finish your conversation. The cashier may need to ask you questions. When I worked in fast food the year was 1994. Cell phones were just starting to become more commonplace, but not nearly as common as they are now, so I can only imagine how much worse the problem is today. Madd Maxx 08-11-2005, 12:32 PM You work at Taco Bell don&apos;t you? I mean, you&apos;re obviously open late because of the remark about the bars closing. And you don&apos;t mention anything about tacos, burritos, or hot sauces. Seriously, you&apos;ve had women flash you to get free drive through? Dudes have offered you drugs in lieu of payment? Got to be Taco Hell. Sampiro 08-11-2005, 12:33 PM I&apos;ve never worked in fast food but I&apos;ve eaten at enough to have the gut to show for it (lawsuit pending), so may I please add

If thou hast an unusual order, one that is far larger than normal (as in for an entire football team), or yea is even just more complicated than normal [cut the burger in half with mustard on the left side and mayonaisse on the right and a pickle on top of the bun] or requires several different payors, PLEASE go inside.

Fast food in general is for people who don&apos;t have time to spend 30 minutes waiting for their food. The Drive Thru is for people who have even less time. It drives me nuts when I get behind some totally unconcerned nimrod who thinks nothing of ordering 30 hamburgers (for thirty-two different payers) and taking 20 minutes at the window while traffic backs up into the next county.

Of course I also don&apos;t understand people who when they can see there are two-dozed queued cars at the drive thru and maybe three cars in the parking lot can&apos;t figure out it&apos;ll be quicker to go inside.


Do people really ask you for free food? Stringer 08-11-2005, 12:35 PM 1) An there beith a preview board, thou shalt use it. Many drive-thrus now have two separate menu boards - one with the attached speaker, and a second menu one car-length behind the speaker. This is known as a&quot;preview board&quot;because the customer can look it over before advancing to the speaker and starting the restaurant&apos;s speed-of-service timer. If you don&apos;t know what you want, USE this board. Don&apos;t drive past it straight to the speaker, ask the clerk to&quot;gimme a second&quot;, and then spend two or three minutes staring at it while the speed-of-service time gets higher and higher.


I don&apos;t like parking at the preview menu so cars get backed up behind me while I decide. I don&apos;t eat fast food often enough to know exactly what I want, and drive-thru menus are usually confusing. Frankly, your speed-of-service time is not my concern. JThunder 08-11-2005, 12:45 PM I don&apos;t like parking at the preview menu so cars get backed up behind me while I decide.
Well then, they&apos;ll get backed up behind you as you&apos;re placing your order. Ignoring the preview window doesn&apos;t save time at all.

I don&apos;t eat fast food often enough to know exactly what I want, and drive-thru menus are usually confusing.
Then go inside if you want to avoid the drive through menu.

Frankly, your speed-of-service time is not my concern.
It should be, especially when other customers are waiting. Ike Witt 08-11-2005, 12:45 PM 2)Thou shalt not shout&quot;Hello?&quot;or honk thy horn if there is a delay at the speaker. Just because the clerk isn&apos;t ready to take your order the second you pull up doesn&apos;t mean they&apos;ve taken off their headset, clocked out, and gone home. Shouting&quot;Hello?&quot;or honking your horn will not make whatever the clerk is working on go away and it WON&apos;T get your order taken any faster - it only aggravates the clerk and potentially deafen them when they get a 110-decibal blast in the speaker strapped directly onto their ear.
Thou shall not expect my business if there are no cars in front of me and no cars parked in the lot and I am told to&quot;wait a minute&quot;by the person on the other end of the speaker. Smapti 08-11-2005, 12:50 PM You work at Taco Bell don&apos;t you? I mean, you&apos;re obviously open late because of the remark about the bars closing. And you don&apos;t mention anything about tacos, burritos, or hot sauces. Seriously, you&apos;ve had women flash you to get free drive through? Dudes have offered you drugs in lieu of payment? Got to be Taco Hell.

No, it&apos;s not Taco Bell, but we are open 24 hours and we do get our fair share of people who stumble into their car after last call and decide that we&apos;ve got just what they need. More often than not they&apos;ve spent everything they had at the bar, which precipitates the kind of&quot;bargaining sessions&quot;you just mentioned. Dante 08-11-2005, 12:53 PM I don&apos;t like parking at the preview menu so cars get backed up behind me while I decide. I don&apos;t eat fast food often enough to know exactly what I want, and drive-thru menus are usually confusing. Frankly, your speed-of-service time is not my concern.So you park at the speaker and let cars back up behind you? Same twit, different pile.

Perhaps the drive-thru is not so much for you, yes? You go inside. Happy Scrappy Hero Pup 08-11-2005, 12:54 PM Once more, you&apos;re the expert at fast food. I&apos;m an expert at database design. I don&apos;t expect you to know about normalizing data, and you ought not expect me to be an expert on what crappy names your restaurant applies to your crappy food. If I get the name wrong--if I order Pepsi instead of Coke--you need to ask,&quot;Is Coke okay?&quot;If I order a Big Mac instead of a Whopper, you need to ask,&quot;Is a Whopper okay?&quot;It&apos;s your job to be the expert here. That&apos;s why you make the big bucks.

You&apos;re... you&apos;re... KIDDING... right?


There&apos;s a two-story-high MENU right there. On this menu are listed the names and costs of the products offered.


How can you be so good at database design when you can&apos;t even read? Stringer 08-11-2005, 12:56 PM So you park at the speaker and let cars back up behind you? Same twit, different pile.

Perhaps the drive-thru is not so much for you, yes? You go inside.

Uh, at least then both of us can read the menus. I&apos;ll gladly read the preview menu if there is a car ahead of me. Uvula Donor 08-11-2005, 01:01 PM I don&apos;t like parking at the preview menu so cars get backed up behind me while I decide. I don&apos;t eat fast food often enough to know exactly what I want, and drive-thru menus are usually confusing. Frankly, your speed-of-service time is not my concern.

Frankly, your inability to understand big color pictures and three-inch letters on an outdoor menu aren&apos;t my concern. Park your fucking car and go inside. Spoons 08-11-2005, 01:07 PM If there is a line at the window, thou shalt start counting thy money before reaching it....Not exactly the same thing (my comment is more for when there is no line of cars), but here it is anyway. If nobody is ahead of me in the drive-thru lane, the order-taker usually tells me to drive up to the window after placing my order at the speaker. There I stop, put the transmission in Park, undo my seat belt, take my feet off the pedals so I can roll my hips around to get my wallet from my back pocket, then pull a bill out to pay for my meal. All the while, it seems, the clerk at the window is rolling her eyes, with her hand out, with the attitude of&quot;I&apos;m waiting, Bozo. Hurry it up, willya?&quot;

Gee, I&apos;m sorry kid. I haven&apos;t yet had the chance to get my money (no line of cars, thus no stop-and-wait and subsequent chance to do this before getting to the window), but I&apos;ll yell you what: next time, I&apos;ll make damn sure that I take care of this before I get to your window. Y&apos;know, like when I&apos;m driving down the freeway. I can certainly see that it would make your life so much easier if I drove my car while squirming around in my seat, taking my eyes off the road, and rooting around in my wallet. :rolleyes:

Note that I am not accusing the OP and his or her co-workers of this attitude, but as long as we&apos;re doing little drive-thru rants here, I thought I&apos;d add it. I think a little patience and understanding on both sides would go a long way. Thankfully, I seem to have complied with most of the OP&apos;s commandments; I&apos;ll be careful in future with the rest.

I also have to ask, though: what&apos;s with the speakers that sound as if they came secondhand from a closed-out drive-in movie? Not all fast-food drive-thrus have these--some places have really good quality speakers, actually--but some are crackly, staticky, and hard to hear. Anybody else find this? Robot Arm 08-11-2005, 01:08 PM I don&apos;t like parking at the preview menu so cars get backed up behind me while I decide. I don&apos;t eat fast food often enough to know exactly what I want, and drive-thru menus are usually confusing. Frankly, your speed-of-service time is not my concern.
Well then, they&apos;ll get backed up behind you as you&apos;re placing your order. If I pull up to the regular menu, then someone behind me can be reading the preview boards and figuring out what they want. I get served at the same time I would have anyway, the person behind me gets out sooner, and if your stats are adversely affected, then the stats are wrong. Dante 08-11-2005, 01:11 PM Uh, at least then both of us can read the menus. I&apos;ll gladly read the preview menu if there is a car ahead of me.
S&apos;good point.

Now I&apos;m torn between your right to use the drive-thru and your inability to order quickly, which is why everyone else is using the drive-thru. Hmmm, it&apos;s a dilemma. Frank 08-11-2005, 01:14 PM There I stop, put the transmission in Park, undo my seat belt, take my feet off the pedals so I can roll my hips around to get my wallet from my back pocket, then pull a bill out to pay for my meal. All the while, it seems, the clerk at the window is rolling her eyes, with her hand out, with the attitude of&quot;I&apos;m waiting, Bozo. Hurry it up, willya?&quot;

Gee, I&apos;m sorry kid. I haven&apos;t yet had the chance to get my money (no line of cars, thus no stop-and-wait and subsequent chance to do this before getting to the window), but I&apos;ll yell you what: next time, I&apos;ll make damn sure that I take care of this before I get to your window. Y&apos;know, like when I&apos;m driving down the freeway. I can certainly see that it would make your life so much easier if I drove my car while squirming around in my seat, taking my eyes off the road, and rooting around in my wallet. :rolleyes:
I found a way to avoid this. When I go to my car knowing I&apos;m going to a drive-in, I take enough money out and put it in my shirt pocket. *shrug* Works for me. Bippy the Beardless 08-11-2005, 01:19 PM How can you be so good at database design when you can&apos;t even read?

Does the menu take SQL requests? select * from menu where patties=&apos;beef&apos; and sauce=&apos;special&apos; and num of patties&gt;= 2 and price&lt;= 2.32 order by price; Indygrrl 08-11-2005, 01:21 PM I don&apos;t spend enough time in drive-throughs to worry about any of this shit. But then, I don&apos;t typically engage in the behavior that the OP has outlined. My thought is, it&apos;s a drive-through, it ain&apos;t that fucking deep. And if you work at one you need to realize this or you&apos;ll probably go crazy. People aren&apos;t doing the stuff to piss you off, they&apos;re doing it without even really thinking about it. It&apos;s not that big of a deal. Dante 08-11-2005, 01:21 PM Then you just Bluetooth it right into the store, and a printout of your food will be available once compiled. askeptic 08-11-2005, 01:27 PM I think the attitude expressed in to OP is what is wrong here. People seem to forget that they are in a CUSTOMER SERVICE industry. The customer is not there to meekly line up and hand you their money. You are there to provide a service for which the customer pays.

For fuck sake I get so tired of grumpy whiney customer service people that can&apos;t be bothered to smile or say hello. They just sullenly hold out there hand for us to meekly place our money in it like they are doing us a favor.

Fine the job sucks, they do not pay you enough, the CUSTOMERs are dumb asses. Thats the incentive to get a better job. But for cryin out loud try to do the one you have well.

Since we are talking about commandments, how about:

Don&apos;t fuck up my order and put in a Whopper when I ordered a Chicken Sandwich (That I will not discover untill I am 5 miles down the road.

or

Don&apos;t put a stale six hour old meal in my bag just because you know that I will be to far away to come back and raise hell with your manager.

For fuck sake it ain&apos;t rocket science. wring 08-11-2005, 01:29 PM &quot;count thy change while waiting&quot;

nope. sorry. Everytime I&apos;ve done that, I&apos;ve ended up spending more of your time &apos;cause I drop it. I drive a stick shift, and can&apos;t hold onto $4.38 while simultaneously driving and shifting. and if I put it on the seat next to me, it alwasy goes in between the seat cushions. I&apos;ve learned the hard way, to wait til I&apos;m at the window with the person waiting for the money before I start counting it out. (unless I&apos;m simply paying with dollar bills). but change? nope.

meanwhile, you&apos;re holding out my drink/straws whatever while I&apos;m still fiddling with the change you just gave me? what the fuck gives with that program? biscuitsandgravy 08-11-2005, 01:32 PM I have to agree that your speed of service times are not my problem. I&apos;ve done my time in fast food. You&apos;re saying, if there are no cars in the line, stop at the preview board, then roll up to the actual window and make my order, right? (Because if someone was ahead of me I would, by default, spend time looking at the preview board, which is what its actual purpose is.) That cuts the time my order is listed on your automated system (since I&apos;m not going,&quot;two burgers, extra cheese, um, gimme a second - anybody want fries? - three large fries&quot;), which makes your manager happy, right? But I don&apos;t care about your manager&apos;s happiness. I don&apos;t intend to stop at the preview board, check it out, have someone pull up behind me wondering what I&apos;m doing sitting there with no one in front of me, pull forward and still have to spend time looking at the menu while your manager leans on you from behind. It will take the same exact amount of time for me to get my food whether I use the preview board or just the menu, which is what I, as a customer, care about.

Also, you know full well that&quot;a lot&quot;of ketchup is more than two packets.

Short version: fast food employment saps the soul. Go get a different job.

(And you know who used to piss me off most? People who pulled up in the rain and didn&apos;t turn off their wipers, flinging dirty water all over me and the window.) Stringer 08-11-2005, 01:35 PM Now I&apos;m torn between your right to use the drive-thru and your inability to order quickly, which is why everyone else is using the drive-thru. Hmmm, it&apos;s a dilemma.

It&apos;s not like I&apos;m sitting there for 10 minutes, I&apos;m talking 30 seconds tops.

Frankly, your inability to understand big color pictures and three-inch letters on an outdoor menu aren&apos;t my concern. Park your fucking car and go inside.
Oh give me a break. I didn&apos;t say I can&apos;t understand it, I&apos;m saying all those big pictures are disorienting at first. What if what I want isn&apos;t on the big pictures? Then I have to cycle through the entire menu looking for what I want. Dante 08-11-2005, 01:35 PM Don&apos;t fuck up my order and put in a Whopper when I ordered a Chicken Sandwich (That I will not discover untill I am 5 miles down the road.Good call. That&apos;s why I always check my order once they hand me the bag. Hey, stare at me all you want drive-thru amonkey-aboy, I&apos;m making sure I got what I ordered. You&apos;d be surprised (oh heck, no you wouldn&apos;t) at how many times I&apos;ve had to knock on the drive-thru window and get an order fixed. VegemiteMoose 08-11-2005, 01:36 PM When thou fuck up my simple order yet again / or don&apos;t have the menu item(s) ready, which requireth me having to pull over into the parking lot, thou shall comp me something. For thou has invalidated the reason for using the drivethru in the first place. Happy Scrappy Hero Pup 08-11-2005, 01:38 PM I think the attitude expressed in to OP is what is wrong here. People seem to forget that they are in a CUSTOMER SERVICE industry. The customer is not there to meekly line up and hand you their money. You are there to provide a service for which the customer pays.

And what happens when the customer asks for something with which the customer-service person cannot provide them?


The sense of entitlement displayed toward the lower end of the food-service chain is difficult to fathom. The people aren&apos;t there to take our grief, it&apos;s certainly not part of their job description, and I don&apos;t think it&apos;s too much to ask of the customer to look up and notice the LACK OF FUCKING ARCHES before attempting to order a Whopper, two orders of McNuggets, and&quot;Biggie&quot;size it- at fucking Sonic.


I&apos;m reasonbly confident that a lot of grief that drive-thru guys take is from people so insecure in their own skins that they have to take the embarassment of not realizing which restaurant the&apos;re at out on somebody.

I run a pension fund, and I&apos;m going to a top-25 law school in July. Among those accomplishments, I also list&quot;knowing what building I just entered.&quot; Happy Scrappy Hero Pup 08-11-2005, 01:39 PM But I don&apos;t even know what month it is, nor can I spell&quot;reasonably.&quot;

So fuck you, drive-thru guy. And gimme a liter of cola. SisterCoyote 08-11-2005, 01:42 PM Thou shall not expect my business if there are no cars in front of me and no cars parked in the lot and I am told to&quot;wait a minute&quot;by the person on the other end of the speaker.

Thou shalt consider that I might be putting out an oil fire at the fry station when I ask thee to wait.

Yeah, that was a fun day. :rolleyes:


I don&apos;t know; the worst for me when I was at the drive-thru was diesel engines. I hated having to ask people to shut their damn cars off because I couldn&apos;t hear over their engines to take their order.

Without the damn, of course. JohnBckWLD 08-11-2005, 01:44 PM 17) Thou shalt not drive thru Taco Bell with an open beer at 2AM, go into a roid-rage when they can&apos;t hand over the Chalupa and get stuck in the window trying to strangle the late night clerk. A.K.A. The Dion Rayford / Jayhawks (http://www.salon.com/people/wire/1999/11/18/chalupa/) Commandment askeptic 08-11-2005, 01:46 PM Happy, I do not suggest that there is any excuse for customers to be rude or give grief to drive thru workers or any customer service workers. Nor should their be any sense of entitlement. I am there to pay for something they are there to provide it. Curtesy and civility are owed by all to all.

I realize that many customers are rude but that is not what the OP was complaining about. The complaint was along the lines of&quot;Don&apos;t fuck up my delivery time quota by not knowing the menu by heart and wasting my time by not having the axact amount of change out when you get to my window&quot;. SmackFu 08-11-2005, 01:46 PM I think these are more like the&quot;Ten Commandments of how to make his job as easy as possible.&quot;Which are fine and all, but I don&apos;t see how they are all wins for the customer. mack 08-11-2005, 01:46 PM 1) An there beith a preview board, thou shalt use it.
The preview menus are pretty useless, IMO. They usually have the popular combos and maybe some specials. Then you get to the main menu and you get that stuff and everything else they have - kid&apos;s meals, whatever configurations and prices of nuggets, desserts, all the different drinks and sizes - and that, plus all the&quot;do you want...&quot;from the clerk and you&apos;ll probably end up changing your &apos;previewed&apos; order anyway.

Now if the preview board is exactly the same as the main board, you may have a point. Bookkeeper 08-11-2005, 01:48 PM 1) An there beith a preview board, thou shalt use it. Many drive-thrus now have two separate menu boards - one with the attached speaker, and a second menu one car-length behind the speaker. This is known as a&quot;preview board&quot;because the customer can look it over before advancing to the speaker and starting the restaurant&apos;s speed-of-service timer. If you don&apos;t know what you want, USE this board. Don&apos;t drive past it straight to the speaker, ask the clerk to&quot;gimme a second&quot;, and then spend two or three minutes staring at it while the speed-of-service time gets higher and higher.
I agree totally with this, as a common courtesy issue. However, I should point out that the customer isn&apos;t responsible for your management&apos;s poor choice of a method for determining valid speed-of-service performance. ElvisL1ves 08-11-2005, 01:52 PM Good call. That&apos;s why I always check my order once they hand me the bag. Hey, stare at me all you want drive-thru amonkey-aboy, I&apos;m making sure I got what I ordered. You&apos;d be surprised (oh heck, no you wouldn&apos;t) at how many times I&apos;ve had to knock on the drive-thru window and get an order fixed.Joe Pesci as Leo Getz in&quot;Lethal Weapon&quot;:(after receiving the wrong order at the drive-thru) They FUCK YOU at the drive-thru, okay? They FUCK YOU at the drive-thru! They know you&apos;re gonna be miles away before you find out you got fucked! They know you&apos;re not gonna turn around and go back, they don&apos;t care. So who gets fucked? Ol&apos; Leo Getz! Okay, sure! I don&apos;t give a fuck! I&apos;m not eating this tuna, okay? Rodd Hill 08-11-2005, 01:53 PM Put. The straw. In. The. Bag.

Without that simple plastic tube, you have rendered fully half the meal useless.

No, worse than useless.

That drink is now a ticking time bomb, a depth-charge of aspartamic liability, which is bound to wind up sloshing around the floorboards of my pre-cupholder era vehicle.

Oh, the oaths and disfigurements I call down on your family, even unto the tenth generation, as I, in a sodium-induced delerium, scrabble in the bag, seeking the Straw of Destiny to release me from this thirst, stray french fries raising hope, then mocking my blind quest, as I keep my eyes on the road. Finally, it dawns on me...you handed me 22 ounces of drink...with no straw. Fiend.

And no-one short of James Bond could remove the plastic top from one of those filled-to-beyond-the-brim drinks in a moving vehicle, drink from it, replace the top, and not wind up soaked. Not driving a standard. No way, Jack. Happy Scrappy Hero Pup 08-11-2005, 01:55 PM askeptic, I&apos;m certainly with you on civility all around, but I cannot in good conscience champion the cause of someone who tries to order Chicken McNuggets or a Big Mac out of one of these (http://www.ac-nantes.fr:8080/peda/disc/lv/anglais/images/streetgb/fret03.jpg).

You can at least cede THAT point, yes? Indygrrl 08-11-2005, 02:11 PM Strangely, this thread is making me crave fast food. :D askeptic 08-11-2005, 02:14 PM You can at least cede THAT point, yes?

Yes. :cool: Revtim 08-11-2005, 02:14 PM askeptic, I&apos;m certainly with you on civility all around, but I cannot in good conscience champion the cause of someone who tries to order Chicken McNuggets or a Big Mac out of one of these (http://www.ac-nantes.fr:8080/peda/disc/lv/anglais/images/streetgb/fret03.jpg).

You can at least cede THAT point, yes?I&apos;m not going to go so far as to&quot;champion the cause&quot;, but IMO confusing two very similar fast food joint&apos;s food isn&apos;t the stupidest mistake a person can make, as long as they accept correction and don&apos;t keep insisting on getting the food they mistakenly asked for. mack 08-11-2005, 02:18 PM I run a pension fund, and I&apos;m going to a top-25 law school in July. Among those accomplishments, I also list&quot;knowing what building I just entered.&quot;
&lt;cut&amp;paste&gt;
I don&apos;t think it&apos;s too much to ask of the customer to look up and notice the LACK OF FUCKING ARCHES before attempting to order a Whopper

:D Zakalwe 08-11-2005, 02:19 PM Does the menu take SQL requests? select * from menu where patties=&apos;beef&apos; and sauce=&apos;special&apos; and num of patties&gt;= 2 and price&lt;= 2.32 order by price;
No Records Found. 5que 08-11-2005, 02:21 PM I am in general agreement with the commandments, with a couple of personal exemptions:

3.a. If your menu is in 8 point type, don&apos;t expect me to be able to immediately find what I am looking for. Particularly when the order seems pretty random. Why exactly is the Gyros and the Gyros Plate two separate entries, separated by about 2 feet of other menu items? And no explanation of what the&quot;plate&quot;gives me, over and above the gyros itself?

8.a. Where I grew up&quot;coke&quot;was a generic term for soda/pop. So don&apos;t get offended that I don&apos;t specifically say&quot;Pepsi.&quot;

And to continue the list:

14.7., subchapter Culvers: When I am placing a large order which includes your frozen custard in a dish, don&apos;t hand me the dish with a spoon in it, then several bags with my rest of my order. I am not eating this in the car. I&apos;m taking it home with the rest of the order. Put a lid on the damn custard and put it in a bag. (Even when I specifically tell them when ordering I need a lid and it in a bag, they do it about 10% of the time.)

32.765. Don&apos;t greet me by trying to sell me whatever you&apos;re pushing today. Just ask for my order. I&apos;m all ready to order, and now the first thing I hear is a commercial for some other item, plus it&apos;s options. NOW if I stop and reconsider my entire order, it&apos;s your fault, not mine. askeptic 08-11-2005, 02:23 PM Damn I was so busy trying to be conciliatory I didn&apos;t think my answer through. I can certainly understand and forgive somebody for ordering the wrong product. Hell I don&apos;t know most of the things most of the fast food chains sell. I have on occasion had to say&quot;You got a regular hamburger&quot;Only to hear&quot;We have the triple decker super duper jack 1 1/2 pound super sandwich special meal&quot;all I can think is WTF?&quot;Give me a burger fries and a coke (or pepsi or sprite or 7-up or sierra mist or ...) Happy Scrappy Hero Pup 08-11-2005, 02:26 PM Mack, I don&apos;t get your point.

Why, exactly, did you bold the words&quot;ARCHES&quot;and&quot;Whopper?&quot;

Read carefully before you reply.

Apologize or say&quot;zing&quot;as you see fit.

:D bordelond 08-11-2005, 02:27 PM The preview menus are pretty useless, IMO. ...
Now if the preview board is exactly the same as the main board, you may have a point.

Hear, hear!

Also: is there really an expectation among most drive-thru customers and employees that any and all will know exactly what they want as soon as they get to the main menu/speaker? I ask because my normal response to&quot;May I take your order?&quot;is&quot;Just one moment, please&quot;.

If so, that expectation is unreasonable, IMHO. 20-30 seconds to hunt for menu items and to decide on what to order is not unreasonable. Most drive-thru menus these days prominently display combo meals, and place the a la carte items in more-difficult-to-read type and locations. Those kind of menus slow things down a lot for folks like me who don&apos;t intend to order a drink and who want to price out items individually. Ferret Herder 08-11-2005, 02:29 PM I think these are more like the&quot;Ten Commandments of how to make his job as easy as possible.&quot;Which are fine and all, but I don&apos;t see how they are all wins for the customer.
They&apos;re wins for the customers in line behind the guy who&apos;s violating all of the commandments. At least inside the store, you can step to a different line if some idiot in front of you is arguing about how he wants a Whopper (at McD&apos;s) and coaxing his darling children to make up their minds on their orders, all the while bitching at someone while on the cell phone. In the drive-thru line, you&apos;re screwed. Uvula Donor 08-11-2005, 02:30 PM What if what I want isn&apos;t on the big pictures? Then I have to cycle through the entire menu looking for what I want.


Park. Your. Fucking. Car. And. Go. Inside.

Want me to put hy-phens be-tween the syl-la-bles? fessie 08-11-2005, 02:32 PM When I worked at KFC, people would occasionally walk all the way in to our restaurant and still manage to order the wrong thing. As in, a pizza.

I was a teenager at the time, and I found such lapses and the kinds of things listed in the above Commandments simply beyond understanding. Most of our customers were really great, we were a neighborhood restaurant with a lot of regulars. But the ones who weren&apos;t with the program drove me batshit. And we didn&apos;t even have a drive-thru.

The thing is, at the time I didn&apos;t have anything else on my plate. Taking care of myself and avoiding my parents - that was about it.

Recently, when my babies were really young, I went through a period of intense distraction. The best I could do for an outing (that&quot;me time&quot;we all need) was a trip to the drive-thru. Fifteen glorious minutes away from the screaming, crying and pooping. Vastly sleep-deprived and completely stressed out, I never knew where I was. And I was always on the phone - that was my only chance to vent about how much I was struggling.

It would be great if everyone could operate at top efficiency at all times, but we can&apos;t. Some of the people who need a little extra time and care may have a great deal more going on in their lives than you do. Liberal 08-11-2005, 02:35 PM If thou art driving a long-bed truck with a four foot trailer hitched to it, thou shalt park and go inside. You&apos;re leaving everyone behind you a half-step out of sync. bordelond 08-11-2005, 02:36 PM Park. Your. Fucking. Car. And. Go. Inside.

Want me to put hy-phens be-tween the syl-la-bles?
Dude ... sorry. You can&apos;t wait 30 seconds? Really?

So only those who know precisely what they want before they go to the drive-thru should use the drive-thru? No menu-reading allowed? In your world, perhaps these menus are unnecessary?

Can&apos;t disagree with you more. No one&apos;s time is that valuable ... and if it is, you probably have better places to be than a drive-thru line. UncleRojelio 08-11-2005, 02:37 PM I don&apos;t eat fast food often enough to know exactly what I want, and drive-thru menus are usually confusing.

Go the hell inside then stay outta my way. I know EXACTLY what I want and I want it in a damn hurry. VegemiteMoose 08-11-2005, 02:38 PM If thou art driving a long-bed truck with a four foot trailer hitched to it, thou shalt park and go inside. You&apos;re leaving everyone behind you a half-step out of sync.
Oh no you don&apos;t! Then they park sideways taking up three to four spaces and then we have a pit rant about that as well as run on sentences! Happy Scrappy Hero Pup 08-11-2005, 02:38 PM So only those who know precisely what they want before they go to the drive-thru should use the drive-thru? No menu-reading allowed? In your world, perhaps these menus are unnecessary?

You can read the menu, but it sure ain&apos;t War and Peace and should not be so treated.

There is a happy medium. bordelond 08-11-2005, 02:39 PM Go the hell inside then stay outta my way. I know EXACTLY what I want and I want it in a damn hurry.
If you see a line at the drive-thru ... maybe you should go inside (weather permitting).

Not at all kidding -- if the drive-thru has around 5 or 6 or more cars, it can often be quicker. askeptic 08-11-2005, 02:40 PM and I don&apos;t think it&apos;s too much to ask of the customer to look up and notice the LACK OF FUCKING ARCHES before attempting to order a Whopper, .&quot;

JSYK

You would not get a Whopper at the place WITH arches either, you need the place with the King on the sign to get a Whopper.

:D

You owe me one irony guage, I should know better than to have it on around here... biscuitsandgravy 08-11-2005, 02:40 PM Park. Your. Fucking. Car. And. Go. Inside.

Late. At. Night. Only. The. Drive. Thru. Is. Open.

Thank you, pull through. bordelond 08-11-2005, 02:42 PM There is a happy medium.
Which differs for everyone.

Even if someone takes marginally more time reading/deciding than you would, so what? I reading some posts here that seem to suggest that even a few seconds spent looking for a specific item is a no-no. What? VegemiteMoose 08-11-2005, 02:45 PM There is a happy medium.
Would you like to super size that? ;) DiosaBellissima 08-11-2005, 02:48 PM The people aren&apos;t there to take our grief, it&apos;s certainly not part of their job description, and I don&apos;t think it&apos;s too much to ask of the customer to look up and notice the LACK OF FUCKING ARCHES before attempting to order a Whopper, two orders of McNuggets, and&quot;Biggie&quot;size it- at fucking Sonic.


Although I agree that there is some level of stupidity (on the customer&apos;s behalf) there, you would know that they meant: a burger, two orders of nuggets/strips, and make everything large.

Maybe I justify this because I am the person that refers to all the little stores attached to gas stations as&quot;AMPMs&quot;. It&apos;s just one of those things...no real justification for it though. Maybe the customer just isn&apos;t thinking (mind is elsewhere, whatever) and blurts out the usual terminology. Happy Scrappy Hero Pup 08-11-2005, 02:52 PM askeptic, your irony meter is in the mail. :smack:

bordelond, while the happy medium might differ for everyone, I don&apos;t think it&apos;s out of line to be slightly annoyed at the dude who leans out the window, moving his lips as he underlines the difficult words with his finger. bordelond 08-11-2005, 03:01 PM bordelond, while the happy medium might differ for everyone, I don&apos;t think it&apos;s out of line to be slightly annoyed at the dude who leans out the window, moving his lips as he underlines the difficult words with his finger.
Who&apos;s talking about that kind of stuff?

I&apos;m talking about customers/employees who are peeved that people are doing perfectly ordinary and acceptable things like spending half a minute reading over a menu/doing a little head math. Put more plainly: the OP&apos;s First Commandment is way off and should be stricken. UncleRojelio 08-11-2005, 03:05 PM Dude ... sorry. You can&apos;t wait 30 seconds? Really?

So only those who know precisely what they want before they go to the drive-thru should use the drive-thru? No menu-reading allowed? In your world, perhaps these menus are unnecessary?

Dude. The answer is yes. Don&apos;t get in line if you don&apos;t know exactly what you want and can roll if off your tongue in one long, well-scripted, breath. After ordering about a million McKids Super-Duper meals with Frosty instead of a Pepsi, I am an expert and I don&apos;t need you pickin&apos; your nose in front of me trying to make up your mind between a Royal w/ Cheese or a Douple Whooper w/ Jalapenos. Go inside! NotWithoutRage 08-11-2005, 03:10 PM Dude. The answer is yes. Don&apos;t get in line if you don&apos;t know exactly what you want and can roll if off your tongue in one long, well-scripted, breath. After ordering about a million McKids Super-Duper meals with Frosty instead of a Pepsi, I am an expert and I don&apos;t need you pickin&apos; your nose in front of me trying to make up your mind between a Royal w/ Cheese or a Douple Whooper w/ Jalapenos. Go inside!

Agreed. If you don&apos;t know what you want, or don&apos;t know how much you can afford, go the fuck inside.

I realize you don&apos;t care about the people behind you, and you certainly don&apos;t care about the cashier, but most drive-thrus have&quot;seconds of service&quot;meters, that monitors how long it takes for your car to get from start to finish. That&apos;s why the cashier will&quot;park&quot;you if the food isn&apos;t ready yet. They don&apos;t want you in the lane. If the number goes way up for your stupidity, you don&apos;t get yelled at or threatened, do you? FatBaldGuy 08-11-2005, 03:10 PM Maybe I justify this because I am the person that refers to all the little stores attached to gas stations as&quot;AMPMs&quot;. OK, I&apos;ll bite. What is an AMPM? Left Hand of Dorkness 08-11-2005, 03:11 PM Frankly, your inability to understand big color pictures and three-inch letters on an outdoor menu aren&apos;t my concern.
Frankly, that throbbing vein in your forehead isn&apos;t my concern. Chill out, turn on the radio, and breathe.

As for how I can design databases yet not expertly navigate a fast-food menu, it&apos;s because I&apos;ve got a good mind for logical relationships and math, but a bad mind for spatial relationships. Fast-food menus with lots of color, items organized in a fashion that seems arbitrary to me, are not so easy for me to read.

In the interests of full disclosure, I eat fast food maybe once a month, and I use a drive-through maybe once a year: I prefer to eat at a table. But when I use one, I&apos;m not there to show off my leet fast-food fu and amazing skills at remembering product jingles. I really couldn&apos;t care less whether I call your nasty pseudo-food by its appropriate brand name, and if you decide to give me attitude over that, I&apos;ll drizzle you with contempt. If, however, you politely correct me (&quot;Is Pepsi okay? We don&apos;t do filet-o-fish, but we do have a WhaleVomit-o-Rama, will that work?&quot;) then I&apos;ll politely apologize and we can both get on with our sad existences.

Just remember that your restaurant has next to no importance in my world. You have importance as a person taht I want to treat with respect, but I don&apos;t care about your different brand names, the sizes in which you offer different nasty products, or the like. I just want sustenance with a minimum of fuss.
Daniel bordelond 08-11-2005, 03:12 PM Agreed. If you don&apos;t know what you want, or don&apos;t know how much you can afford, go the fuck inside.

I realize you don&apos;t care about the people behind you, and you certainly don&apos;t care about the cashier, but most drive-thrus have&quot;seconds of service&quot;meters, that monitors how long it takes for your car to get from start to finish. That&apos;s why the cashier will&quot;park&quot;you if the food isn&apos;t ready yet. They don&apos;t want you in the lane. If the number goes way up for your stupidity, you don&apos;t get yelled at or threatened, do you?
Holy crap.

20-30 seconds to decide on an order is&quot;stupidity&quot;? Fuck impatient people. bordelond 08-11-2005, 03:14 PM OK, I&apos;ll bite. What is an AMPM?
A 24-hour convenience store, AFAIK. Think of it as&quot;a.m./p.m.&quot;. Happy Scrappy Hero Pup 08-11-2005, 03:14 PM bordelond, I refer you again to the actual text of the First Commandment:

1) An there beith a preview board, thou shalt use it. Many drive-thrus now have two separate menu boards - one with the attached speaker, and a second menu one car-length behind the speaker. This is known as a&quot;preview board&quot;because the customer can look it over before advancing to the speaker and starting the restaurant&apos;s speed-of-service timer. If you don&apos;t know what you want, USE this board. Don&apos;t drive past it straight to the speaker, ask the clerk to&quot;gimme a second&quot;, and then spend two or three minutes staring at it while the speed-of-service time gets higher and higher.

He&apos;s asking for a bit of consideration- don&apos;t start his clock when you&apos;ve got a whole separate area for head-scratching and indecision. And I have no problem with that.

Big difference between 30 seconds and three minutes. cowgirl 08-11-2005, 03:16 PM [display of fast-food ignorance]Um, how hard is it to decide what you want at a fast food place? I mean, outside of buying 7-layer burritos at Taco Bell I can&apos;t remember the last time I&apos;ve been to a fast-food restaurant, drive-through or otherwise, and I could probably tell you what&apos;s on most of their menus: burgers (made with&quot;beef,&quot;chicken or fish); small/med/large/humongo fries; small/med/large/humongo soft drinks (coke/diet/sprite/orange/root beer if lucky); breaded chicken in some shape (nuggets/strips/fingers/noses); onion rings; and other items depending on the chain (fried chicken at KFC, various combinations of tortilla, meat, cheese and veg at Taco Bell, etc).

Why does it take so long to decide what you want? By the time you&apos;ve decided to go to the drive-through in the first place, aren&apos;t you thinking something along the lines of&quot;Man, I could really go for a burger and fries right about now.&quot;So order the damn burger and fries. What&apos;s the problem? Do you ever, when faced with a McD&apos;s menu, say to yourself&quot;Wow! I didn&apos;t know they sold THOSE!&quot;?

[/doffi] bordelond 08-11-2005, 03:17 PM If the number goes way up for your stupidity, you don&apos;t get yelled at or threatened, do you?
Right :rolleyes: That&apos;s the typical experience. A customer takes half a minute to decide what they want, and a employee gets yelled at.

Bullshit -- there&apos;s no way that&apos;s the default situation.

I worked fast food myself (admittedly back in the 80s). If a manager is the type to berate, any excuse will do and nothing the customer does can ultimately prevent verbal abuse. bordelond 08-11-2005, 03:20 PM He&apos;s asking for a bit of consideration- don&apos;t start his clock when you&apos;ve got a whole separate area for head-scratching and indecision.
I&apos;ve never seen a place with such a&quot;separate area&quot;, save for at Chick-Fil-A. I&apos;ve seen preview boards with popular combos listed ... but I don&apos;t do combos very often.

Also -- different locations of the same chain often have different items on their budget menus (esp. McDonalds, believe it or not). What is and is not on those $1 menus often influence what I order, and I&apos;ve never seen a place that had this on their preview board. YMMV. Corrvin 08-11-2005, 03:21 PM Thou shall not expect my business if there are no cars in front of me and no cars parked in the lot and I am told to&quot;wait a minute&quot;by the person on the other end of the speaker.

So employees aren&apos;t allowed to visit the restroom AND wash their hands?

Gotta go sometime, and the best time is when there are NO cars in the drivethru and none in the parking lot...

...aw, man, did somebody just pull up? UncleRojelio 08-11-2005, 03:22 PM Do you ever, when faced with a McD&apos;s menu, say to yourself&quot;Wow! I didn&apos;t know they sold THOSE!&quot;?


I&apos;ve never said that at the scottish restaurant, no. But, after 30 years of going to Sonic, I still find stuff on that menu that I swear was never there before. Getting back to the OP, it&apos;s okay to pull into a Sonic and have a lesiurely nose-pick while you peruse the menu. Just don&apos;t hit the button till you have it all lined up in your brain. Happy Scrappy Hero Pup 08-11-2005, 03:23 PM As for how I can design databases yet not expertly navigate a fast-food menu, it&apos;s because I&apos;ve got a good mind for logical relationships and math, but a bad mind for spatial relationships. Fast-food menus with lots of color, items organized in a fashion that seems arbitrary to me, are not so easy for me to read.

Then go inside.

In your posts, you heap derision on these people or their employers.

Have you ever gotten riled about a cilent who didn&apos;t understand how your programming language was structured or asked you for things you couldn&apos;t give them?

While I&apos;m not going to get out of my car, drag you out of yours, and kick your differently-abled ass or anything, you come off (whether you mean to or not) like the princess of the autistic savants. Whether your grandmother was an Astor or whether you&apos;re freaking Rain Man, there is no entitlement.

Fast-food places are patronized by the impatient. The impatient trade quality and nutritional value for nownownow, and to act as though the status quo ought to be modified while you Indigo-Child your way through the board is, while not earth-shatteringly silly, certainly outside the bounds of the fast-food paradigm. VegemiteMoose 08-11-2005, 03:25 PM [display of fast-food ignorance]Um, how hard is it to decide what you want at a fast food place?
&lt;snip&gt;

Why does it take so long to decide what you want? By the time you&apos;ve decided to go to the drive-through in the first place, aren&apos;t you thinking something along the lines of&quot;Man, I could really go for a burger and fries right about now.&quot;So order the damn burger and fries. What&apos;s the problem? Do you ever, when faced with a McD&apos;s menu, say to yourself&quot;Wow! I didn&apos;t know they sold THOSE!&quot;?

[/doffi]
I may have something in mind, but want to check what the daily special is. I may want to see if they have added something new to the menu. The only times fast food drive thru ordering has gone over two or three minutes from start to finish, is when the restaurant has goofed and needs me to pull over.

Question for those in the know. Does the seconds of service counter keep going if for whatever reason, they&quot;park you&quot;? Left Hand of Dorkness 08-11-2005, 03:26 PM When I go through drive-throughs, it&apos;s usually because I&apos;m in the car with other folks, on a road trip. I don&apos;t eat warm-blooded creatures, so I&apos;m going to be feeding in the corners of the menu already (some places have fish sandwiches, some don&apos;t; some have baked potatoes, some don&apos;t; some have biscuits at all hours, some don&apos;t; etc.) Some places give big discounts on combos, while others give small or no discounts (I&apos;ve even seen one that apparently charged MORE for the combo than if you ordered the items separately--go figure!)

So yeah, it can take me a good thirty seconds to figure out what I want. And if it takes someone else thirty seconds, it&apos;s okay: that vein in my forehead won&apos;t begin a drumroll.

Daniel bordelond 08-11-2005, 03:27 PM What&apos;s the problem? Do you ever, when faced with a McD&apos;s menu, say to yourself&quot;Wow! I didn&apos;t know they sold THOSE!&quot;?
Very often -- yes.

A specific example from among many -- some locations of McDonald&apos;s sell Spicy Chicken sandwiches on the $1 menu. Other locations don&apos;t sell them at all. I consider the Spicy Chicken sandwich better than the burgers, so I always take a few seconds to peruse the $1 menu at a McD drive-thru to see if they&apos;ve got them.

For some people, the McRib sandwich is similar -- another item not sold at all locations.

Some more McDonald&apos;s examples -- apple pies and hash browns. Some locations sell them at 2/$1.00 all the time. Other locations sell them for 99 cents most of the time, and 2/$1.00 occasionally as a special. I will check the menu on their price, because I&apos;ll usually bite on the 2-for-a-buck deal. UncleRojelio 08-11-2005, 03:29 PM When I go through drive-throughs, it&apos;s usually because I&apos;m in the car with other folks, on a road trip. I don&apos;t eat warm-blooded creatures, so I&apos;m going to be feeding in the corners of the menu already (some places have fish sandwiches, some don&apos;t; some have baked potatoes, some don&apos;t; some have biscuits at all hours, some don&apos;t; etc.) Some places give big discounts on combos, while others give small or no discounts (I&apos;ve even seen one that apparently charged MORE for the combo than if you ordered the items separately--go figure!)

So yeah, it can take me a good thirty seconds to figure out what I want. And if it takes someone else thirty seconds, it&apos;s okay: that vein in my forehead won&apos;t begin a drumroll.

Daniel

Then, for you, the rule is very simple. Go the hell inside! Left Hand of Dorkness 08-11-2005, 03:29 PM Then go inside.

In your posts, you heap derision on these people or their employers.

No I do not, and no thank you as to your kind offer for me to go inside. If you&apos;d like this change, try petitioning the restaurants to have a time-limit on ordering.

You&apos;ll find that the folks who set up the restaurant are perfectly happy to allow me to take 30 seconds to order, I wager.

Have you ever gotten riled about a cilent who didn&apos;t understand how your programming language was structured or asked you for things you couldn&apos;t give them?
No, I have not.

you come off (whether you mean to or not) like the princess of the autistic savants. Whether your grandmother was an Astor or whether you&apos;re freaking Rain Man, there is no entitlement.
Actually, you come across as a binary-world-seeing fool who thinks a person who takes 30 seconds to read a menu is autistic. Chill the fuck out, dude! Thirty seconds is not a lifetime!
Daniel bordelond 08-11-2005, 03:29 PM Fast-food places are patronized by the impatient. The impatient trade quality and nutritional value for nownownow, and to act as though the status quo ought to be modified while you Indigo-Child your way through the board is, while not earth-shatteringly silly, certainly outside the bounds of the fast-food paradigm.
30 seconds?!?!? C&apos;mon. DiosaBellissima 08-11-2005, 03:31 PM OK, I&apos;ll bite. What is an AMPM?

Yes yes, as already said, it is just the name of a gas station store. The one by our house growing up was called&quot;AM/PM&quot;so I have always called all of them that. Just a habit, really. Left Hand of Dorkness 08-11-2005, 03:31 PM Then, for you, the rule is very simple. Go the hell inside!
You are incorrect; that&quot;rule&quot;exists only in your fevered imagination.

For you, on the other hand, there is a very simple rule: wait your fucking turn! Continued useless whinging entirely optional.

Daniel Random 08-11-2005, 03:32 PM Because you get Whoppers at Burger King, so there&apos;d be no arches to notice. Your comment would make sense if it read:

&quot;I don&apos;t think it&apos;s too much to ask of the customer to look up and notice the LACK OF FUCKING ARCHES before attempting to order a Big Mac.&quot; UncleRojelio 08-11-2005, 03:34 PM 30 seconds?!?!? C&apos;mon.

You C&apos;mon. Thirty seconds is an eternity when you have a car full of screaming brats.

And, as an aside to the fast-food worker who screws up my order, I&apos;m not adverse to parking the car and turning those brats loose inside your establishment. Happy Scrappy Hero Pup 08-11-2005, 03:37 PM You are incorrect; that&quot;rule&quot;exists only in your fevered imagination.

For you, on the other hand, there is a very simple rule: wait your fucking turn! Continued useless whinging entirely optional.


You do realize that your authority over him is just as valid as his over you, right?
I hope so.



As for this---


30 seconds?!?!? C&apos;mon.

Actually, you come across as a binary-world-seeing fool who thinks a person who takes 30 seconds to read a menu is autistic. Chill the fuck out, dude! Thirty seconds is not a lifetime!


The both of you want an hour to read the menu but won&apos;t take a minute to read what I wrote?


If you look back, I&apos;m with the OP on the&quot;three minutes is too long&quot;point.
I backed that up when I re-posted his First Commandment.
Nowhere in any of my posts did I even mention 30 seconds nor did I agree with anyone that did.


I demand retractions from both of you.

You have...


thirty seconds. Happy Scrappy Hero Pup 08-11-2005, 03:39 PM Random-

read posts 61 and 66. bordelond 08-11-2005, 03:40 PM Then, for you, the rule is very simple. Go the hell inside!
What Left Hand said.

And if Left Hand is a vegetarian, s/he will have to peruse the average fast food menu board a bit more closely. And I can&apos;t think of a valid reason s/he shouldn&apos;t be afforded the same convenience to do it from the comfort of her car as anyone else would.

I&apos;ll post it again -- if you really can&apos;t wait for a line of a half-dozen or more cars, don&apos;t harp that everyone in line needs to hurry up. I suggest that you get out of the car and order inside. You usually will get your food faster than if you had waited in that long drive-thru line. Not posting that to be a dick ... just giving a helpful suggestion I&apos;ve implemented myself many times. Left Hand of Dorkness 08-11-2005, 03:40 PM You do realize that your authority over him is just as valid as his over you, right?
Sure, but:
1) If I break his rule and don&apos;t go inside, everything continues hunky-dory.
2) If he breaks my rule and refuses to wait his fucking turn (e.g., tries to break in line in the drive-through), I guaranfuckingtee that pandemonium will break loose.

Like I said, the rule for him is a real rule.

The both of you want an hour to read the menu but won&apos;t take a minute to read what I wrote?


If you look back, I&apos;m with the OP on the&quot;three minutes is too long&quot;point.
Well, nowhere did I disagree that three minutes is too long, so suck it! :)

Daniel Ike Witt 08-11-2005, 03:41 PM It seems that a lot of people here are upset, more than should be reasonable IMO, about reading menus. I&apos;d like to hear each and every one of you complain just as loud about order takers who try to up-sell or push the trendy McItem of the month.

Thanks. UncleRojelio 08-11-2005, 03:41 PM You are incorrect; that&quot;rule&quot;exists only in your fevered imagination.

I&apos;m rubber, you&apos;re glue. Whatever you say bounces off of me and sticks to you! :wally Left Hand of Dorkness 08-11-2005, 03:45 PM Clearly, uncle, any car you&apos;re driving will have a minimum of one screaming brat in it. Are the others screaming to get out?

But I invite you to try breaking the rule I suggest for you; after all, I break your rule whenever I go through a drive-through, and breaking your rule improves my life.

Daniel bordelond 08-11-2005, 03:47 PM I&apos;m rubber, you&apos;re glue. Whatever you say bounces off of me and sticks to you! :wally
Yippee ... you still gotta wait :wally

Uncle, I&apos;ve got a two-year-old myself, and I can feel you to an extent. But someone taking their time ordering at a drive-thru is pretty damn trivial in the grand scheme of things. UncleRojelio 08-11-2005, 03:49 PM I&apos;ll post it again -- if you really can&apos;t wait for a line of a half-dozen or more cars, don&apos;t harp that everyone in line needs to hurry up. I suggest that you get out of the car and order inside. You usually will get your food faster than if you had waited in that long drive-thru line. Not posting that to be a dick ... just giving a helpful suggestion I&apos;ve implemented myself many times.

I agree that this is a valid strategy and I have implemented it many times. The thing that gets my knickers in a twist it the guy that manages to swing in just before I get to the speaker and then proceeds to launch into an extended meandering discourse with the order-taker, repeatedly changing his mind, whipping out the old cellphone to call the old-lady to see what she wants, and arguing with the kids about what to order. If I had a 105mm howitzer on the front of my truck ... UncleRojelio 08-11-2005, 03:50 PM Uncle, I&apos;ve got a two-year-old myself, and I can feel you to an extent. But someone taking their time ordering at a drive-thru is pretty damn trivial in the grand scheme of things.

Yeah, I know. So is arguing about it on a message board. But you gotta do something at work to make the time go faster. ;) bordelond 08-11-2005, 03:52 PM Does anyone else want to pick up the&quot;you&apos;ll get the cashier in trouble!&quot;gambit that NotWithoutRage dropped?

Not even Spamti has picked that one up. Left Hand of Dorkness 08-11-2005, 03:53 PM I agree that this is a valid strategy and I have implemented it many times. The thing that gets my knickers in a twist it the guy that manages to swing in just before I get to the speaker and then proceeds to launch into an extended meandering discourse with the order-taker, repeatedly changing his mind, whipping out the old cellphone to call the old-lady to see what she wants, and arguing with the kids about what to order. If I had a 105mm howitzer on the front of my truck ...
Hey, for that guy, it&apos;s justifiable homicide. As I was saying to Happy, it&apos;s not an either-or thing: it&apos;s a continuum. Life&apos;s too short to worry about someone taking an extra thirty seconds to read a menu, but if someone is really doing all those things you describe, lethal force is the only answer.

Daniel UncleRojelio 08-11-2005, 03:53 PM Clearly, uncle, any car you&apos;re driving will have a minimum of one screaming brat in it.


I will have to concede this point. Did they let you watch the surveillance or have you been talking to my wife? Left Hand of Dorkness 08-11-2005, 03:59 PM I will have to concede this point. Did they let you watch the surveillance or have you been talking to my wife?
Okay, you caught me. I wasn&apos;t reading the menu, I was looking in my rear-view mirror.

Cackling softly.

Daniel UncleRojelio 08-11-2005, 04:02 PM Okay, you caught me. I wasn&apos;t reading the menu, I was looking in my rear-view mirror.

And, since there was no one behind me, when I finally got to the damn speaker, I order a McHaggis just to see what the order-drone would say.

*snicker* ouryL 08-11-2005, 04:03 PM Having worked far too long in the food service industry, i&apos;ve seen my share of people who seem to have absolutely no idea how drive-thru restaurants work. I&apos;ve suffered no end of heartache and aggravation from people who can&apos;t seem to grasp what should be blatantly obvious, and i&apos;ve finally come to the conclusion that what the world needs is a simple guide to the thou shalts and thou shalt nots of the process. So here it is - a guide to the uninformed and a pitting of the clueless.

1) An there beith a preview board, thou shalt use it. Many drive-thrus now have two separate menu boards - one with the attached speaker, and a second menu one car-length behind the speaker. This is known as a&quot;preview board&quot;because the customer can look it over before advancing to the speaker and starting the restaurant&apos;s speed-of-service timer. If you don&apos;t know what you want, USE this board. Don&apos;t drive past it straight to the speaker, ask the clerk to&quot;gimme a second&quot;, and then spend two or three minutes staring at it while the speed-of-service time gets higher and higher.

2)Thou shalt not shout&quot;Hello?&quot;or honk thy horn if there is a delay at the speaker. Just because the clerk isn&apos;t ready to take your order the second you pull up doesn&apos;t mean they&apos;ve taken off their headset, clocked out, and gone home. Shouting&quot;Hello?&quot;or honking your horn will not make whatever the clerk is working on go away and it WON&apos;T get your order taken any faster - it only aggravates the clerk and potentially deafen them when they get a 110-decibal blast in the speaker strapped directly onto their ear.

3) Thou shalt not ask the clerk questions that could be answered by reading the menu. How much does the chicken sandwich cost? What comes on the TripleMax Superburger Deluxe? This is what the menu is FOR. It&apos;s the big thing right in front of you with all the words and numbers on it, not to mention the great big pictures where each item has been carefully posed to display each of its ingredients in larger-than-life detail. Use it.

4) Thou shalt NOT add to thy order at the window. Doing this requires the clerk to go back in and change your order (which at many restaurants requires a manager&apos;s approval to void part or all of the order), delays us getting your order out while we make whatever you decided you just couldn&apos;t live without during the lengthy 20&apos; drive from the speaker to the window, and delays everyone behind you getting what they want as well. Just don&apos;t do it.

5) If there is a line at the window, thou shalt start counting thy money before reaching it. We tell you what your total is at the speaker. Most restaurants also have video screens that show your total in big numbers. There is no reason for you to not know your total before you leave the speaker. If there&apos;s a car ahead of you at the window, there is no reason for you not to start counting out your money before you get there. Reaching the window after a three-minute wait and THEN deciding to start counting out the $37 in nickels you intend to pay me with is just lazy.

6) Thou shalt use actual numbers when ordering a quantity greater than one. I don&apos;t know how many&quot;a couple&quot;,&quot;a bunch&quot;,&quot;a lot&quot;, or&quot;a shitload&quot;of hamburgers is. I never learned those numbers in kindergarten. If you ask me for such a quantity, I will ask you to be more specific. The same goes for sauces. Our default is to give you one package of sauce for each item that requires it. If you ask me for a specific larger number I will give you that many, but if you ask me for&quot;a bunch&quot;or&quot;a lot&quot;I will give you two packages for each item. If you ask me for&quot;a shitload&quot;I may ask you not to come back to my store.

7) Thou shalt NOT use curse words into the drive-thru speaker. This one follows from the Sixth Commandment. The speaker you&apos;re talking into is connected to a loudspeaker which is audible to everyone in the kitchen and, often, to everyone in the lobby as well. This is a family business and more often than not there are children dining in our lobby. It is not appropriate for you to pull up to my speaker and start using profanity towards me, let alone my staff and customers. An idle slip of the tongue may be excused, but do it again and you&apos;ll be asked to leave.

8) Thou shalt not order another restaurant&apos;s menu items from us. We don&apos;t sell Big Macs here. We don&apos;t sell Whoppers here. We don&apos;t sell McChickens, Biggie Fries, Frosties, Grillburgers, McFlurries, McNuggets, Chicken Fries, Crossainwiches, McMuffins, McGriddles, or anything else that starts with&quot;Mc&quot;for that matter. You cannot Super-Size, King Size, or Biggie-Size our combos. We carry Coke, not Pepsi. We can&apos;t give you fry sauce, onion ring sauce, or Horsey sauce. Corellary: Thou shalt not order the item we carried for about a month two years ago and act shocked that we can&apos;t make it for you. We don&apos;t even carry the ingredients for that anymore. No, not even if you ask nicely.

9) Thou shalt make sure you have cash or a credit card BEFORE thou order. Think hard for just a second, buddy - have you EVER heard of a drive-thru restaurant taking checks? I didn&apos;t think so. Make sure you have the ability to pay for your order BEFORE you order it. Pulling up to the window and then&quot;discovering&quot;that you forgot your wallet won&apos;t earn you any sympathy from those of us who just busted our asses to make your order and now have to throw it all out. And no, it WON&apos;T get you any free food, either.

10) Thou shalt not, not, NOT, EVER, ask the clerk to&quot;hook you up&quot;. This is a business, not a charity. You want free food? Go to the food bank downtown. We&apos;re in business to make money, not feed your broke ass. I don&apos;t even know you. Why would I risk my job by giving away free food to a complete stranger? No, not if you give me a puff off your peace pipe. No, not if your girlfriend shows me her tits (and what kind of girl flashes a complete stranger for a 99-cent sandwich anyway?) No, not if you&apos;re really good buddies with the manager or the area coach or Sally in Accounting, because right here and right now I AM the manager and i&apos;ve never seen you before in my life.

Unbelievers, repent your sins and be saved. Anybody else got any commandments they&apos;d like to throw in before I break out the chisel?

How bout
11) Thou shalt not thy naked body expose to us. Thy car is not clothing. Jme102 08-11-2005, 04:03 PM [QUOTE=Duck Duck Goose]Walgreens driveup mini-rant here:

QUOTE]


Amen to all the Walgreens stuff. I would just like to add:

If you haven&apos;t already been to a Walgreens and registered your address/phone#/insurancecard/allergies/dog&apos;s name/etc.. and you have two legs - come inside! It holds up the entire line and sometimes people who have crying babies or old sick parents are waiting for their medicines behind you! matt_mcl 08-11-2005, 04:04 PM A hijack:

And if Left Hand is a vegetarian, s/he will have to peruse the average fast food menu board a bit more closely. And I can&apos;t think of a valid reason s/he shouldn&apos;t be afforded the same convenience to do it from the comfort of her car as anyone else would.


In what universe is screaming into a microphone, fumbling with change, and then doing food origami while careening down a motorway more convenient and comfortable than going into a restaurant, speaking to a human, and eating one&apos;s food at a table? Dag Otto 08-11-2005, 04:06 PM Go the hell inside then stay outta my way. I know EXACTLY what I want and I want it in a damn hurry.


If you were really in a hurry, you would be in front of me. My truck is so old and slow I really have no idea how you could have not beaten me here. But somehow there you are, behind me. :p

It&apos;s crap food anyway. Getting it 30 seconds faster doesn&apos;t make it any less crappy.

To the OP: Don&apos;t ask me if I want a drink with that. I just gave you my order. Did I order a fucking drink? No? Well, there you go. Left Hand of Dorkness 08-11-2005, 04:07 PM In what universe is screaming into a microphone, fumbling with change, and then doing food origami while careening down a motorway more convenient and comfortable than going into a restaurant, speaking to a human, and eating one&apos;s food at a table?
The universe where I&apos;m on a car trip with other people and the other folks would prefer to use the drive-through :). You want to see REAL prima-donna, imagine me insisting that they let me go inside and eat while they use the drive-through.

Daniel ENugent 08-11-2005, 04:09 PM In what universe is screaming into a microphone, fumbling with change, and then doing food origami while careening down a motorway more convenient and comfortable than going into a restaurant, speaking to a human, and eating one&apos;s food at a table?
The universe in which we finally got the baby to sleep by driving the car all over town. kidchameleon 08-11-2005, 04:10 PM &quot;count thy change while waiting&quot;

nope. sorry. Everytime I&apos;ve done that, I&apos;ve ended up spending more of your time &apos;cause I drop it. I drive a stick shift, and can&apos;t hold onto $4.38 while simultaneously driving and shifting.

:eek:

You must go to some awful long drive throughs if you need to shift to get to the window.... DiosaBellissima 08-11-2005, 04:21 PM Not to speak for wring, but I think he (she?) means shifting the car from neutral to first. I usually stick my car in neutral while ordering so I can take my foot of the clutch and all that jazz, then I need to shift. wring 08-11-2005, 04:30 PM Not to speak for wring, but I think he (she?) means shifting the car from neutral to first. I usually stick my car in neutral while ordering so I can take my foot of the clutch and all that jazz, then I need to shift.


yep.

and gender= female. VegemiteMoose 08-11-2005, 04:40 PM (Hmm, maybe if I try it in Super Slow-mo Asshole Mode.) :p

Does. The. Seconds. Of. Service. Counter. Keep. Going. If. You. Get. Parked?

Seriously, can someone please answer this. Uvula Donor 08-11-2005, 04:44 PM Dude ... sorry. You can&apos;t wait 30 seconds? Really?

So only those who know precisely what they want before they go to the drive-thru should use the drive-thru? No menu-reading allowed? In your world, perhaps these menus are unnecessary?


Dude ... read the thread. Harborwolf 08-11-2005, 04:59 PM 6) Thou shalt use actual numbers when ordering a quantity greater than one. I don&apos;t know how many&quot;a couple&quot;,&quot;a bunch&quot;,&quot;a lot&quot;, or&quot;a shitload&quot;of hamburgers is. I never learned those numbers in kindergarten. If you ask me for such a quantity, I will ask you to be more specific. The same goes for sauces. Our default is to give you one package of sauce for each item that requires it. If you ask me for a specific larger number I will give you that many, but if you ask me for&quot;a bunch&quot;or&quot;a lot&quot;I will give you two packages for each item. If you ask me for&quot;a shitload&quot;I may ask you not to come back to my store.
Whoa buddy do I ever agree with this one. I used to work at a grocery store deli, and easily two thirds of the customers thought&quot;some&quot;was an appropriate quantity of meat. When I asked how much they wanted, they usually got annoyed with me because I couldn&apos;t quantify&quot;some&quot;into an actual measurement. SisterCoyote 08-11-2005, 05:06 PM VegemiteMoose -

It didn&apos;t back in the early 80s when I was serving my time as a drive-thru operator; you move out, the switch gets tripped, and it starts counting the next driver. SisterCoyote 08-11-2005, 05:07 PM Oh, and I meant to add -

Wait a second before pulling up in front of the order grille. If you ride up right on the bumper of the guy in front of you, odds are that you won&apos;t trip the sensor that lets the drive-thru operator know you&apos;re there. From the inside, it sounds just like the guy in front hasn&apos;t moved, not that someone new has pulled up. Gangster Octopus 08-11-2005, 05:18 PM Eh, a lot of the complaints in OP seem to be normal customer service things that are part of the job. PunditLisa 08-11-2005, 05:30 PM I&apos;m one of those people who order precisely what I want, in the order that I&apos;ve come to expect it. For instance, I&apos;ll say,&quot;I&apos;d like a Chicken Nugget Kid&apos;s Meal, with honey mustard sauce, and a Frosty.&quot;

I hate when the nimwit behind the microphone interrupts my well-rehearsed speech.

&quot;I&apos;d like a Chicken Nugget Kid&apos;s Meal, with--&quot;

&quot;----What sauce do you want?&quot;

&quot;Honey mustard. And a coke to --&quot;

&quot;---What drink do you want with that?&quot;

ARRGH! VegemiteMoose 08-11-2005, 05:44 PM Thanks Sister Coyote. If someone could verify (or refute) that this is still true, it would be appreciated. Also thanks for the waiting to pull up tip.

But if this (stopping the seconds) is still true:

a) what a huge cheat if it isn&apos;t honestly factored in somehow,

b) sure it&apos;s a minor annoyance, but still, a free fries&quot;comp&quot;vs. customer satisfaction? Seems like a no brainer to me. Yes, I&apos;ve worked retail. In fact I&apos;ve worked complaint desks. Which makes this even more baffling to me. The worst possible outcome of drive thru ordering (other than food poisoning leading to death I suppose) is getting&quot;parked&quot;. Just seems like common sense to me to balance the irritation of the customer with a relatively minor coupon or something. This shows such a lack of foresight and/or customer service that it boggles my mind. (Well, forgetting the straws for drinks too, but I&apos;m usually headed home with the booty and have straws and even glasses there.) Chanteuse 08-11-2005, 06:11 PM A couple rules for drive-thru employees:

1) Thou shalt not, when I present the $5 for my $4.32 order, ask,&quot;Do you have 32 cents?&quot;If I wanted to dig around for it, I&apos;d have already done so. It won&apos;t kill you to count out 68 cents from your register. And it probably takes less time than waiting for me to root around my purse for change.

2) Thou shalt not wait until I get to the window to tell me you have to cook the pies I ordered. If business is so slow that I&apos;m the only one in line, then you have the time to notice that all the pies are gone. If it&apos;s busy, then the person who takes the last pie should know that more will need to be dropped. I don&apos;t mind waiting for the things, but I do object to ordering, then waiting for three or four cars ahead of me, and only then, when I get to the window do I find that you JUST NOW put the pies on to cook. (I knew this was true because I worked at that very restaurant--I was aware of just how long it took pies, fries, etc to cook. By the time I got to the window, they should&apos;ve been in the oil at LEAST two minutes.) Dung Beetle 08-11-2005, 07:07 PM *snip*The worst possible outcome of drive thru ordering (other than food poisoning leading to death I suppose) is getting&quot;parked&quot;. Just seems like common sense to me to balance the irritation of the customer with a relatively minor coupon or something. *snip*Seems to me that this would lead to customers being needlessly persnickety in hopes of getting something free. Fish 08-11-2005, 08:06 PM Thanks Sister Coyote. If someone could verify (or refute) that this is still true, it would be appreciated. Also thanks for the waiting to pull up tip.
Former (and recovering) fast-food manager speaking, Wendy&apos;s division. Left fast food management in 1992 and have not been stressed by any job since.

I worked about about half a dozen stories in a 50-mile radius from home, and all of them worked more or less the same: a photoelectric eye simply read whether there was a car parked immediately outside the window, when it pulled up, and how long it (the car, not the window) stayed.

The photoelectric eye could be cheated easily if a drive-through attendant had long arms, a good grip on something heavy (such as a cash register) and a large, flat, opaque object (such as a food tray) to cover the eye with. Not that I ever did that.

A clock by the window gave average service times for the periods of 11-2, 2-5, 5-8, and 8-11. However, the clock we initially had did not give car counts or Time At Menuboard.

Then new clocks were installed, which were tied to the menuboard, to the order count at the register (to compare to actual number of cars at window), and to the menu speaker (to count how long it took to greet an incoming car, and how long it took to take that car&apos;s order). It was much easier to tell if the car count varied widely from the order count (i.e., the drive-through cashier was cheating the photoelectric eye).

Generally speaking, I as a manager didn&apos;t give a rat&apos;s patootie about how long it took to take a customer&apos;s order, because there was very little anybody could do to speed up that process if the customer wanted time to be slow. Service times were a priority for a few weeks after the district manager inevitably said they weren&apos;t good enough, until it again became clear that customers were deliberately trying to thwart us. Cars stalled while sitting on the timer, driving service times up to 999 seconds and pinning the needle, so to speak; customers talked on the phone, added orders on at the window, bypassed the menu so they could order face-to-face, friends stopped by to chat with the cashier, got out of their car to look under the window for the dimes they dropped, checked their order and handed out the correct kid toys to the correct children, finished their beers, etc.

So... service times are a thing which people in very serious suits in offices far away think about, as if they can measure money in seconds, while people who actually have to work at the damn place realize that customers can never and will never give a shit as long as they get their food a) right b) fast and c) tasty, or as tasty as possible under the circumstances.


At least when I worked as a manager, we were not permitted by The Rules to give the cashiers the autonomy to give out free fries, coupons, drinks, or anything else at will for orders which had to be pulled ahead for any reason. For the most part, based on the average age and experience of the workforce, I agree with the policy. There are simply not enough managers on-shift to personally give compensatory gifts to any and every customer who feels slightly inconvenienced. (Add to this that the food cost of the coupon came out of my store&apos;s P&amp;L statement, even if they redeemed it at the Wendy&apos;s across town, so we were not even budgeted for this kind of largesse.) UncleRojelio 08-11-2005, 08:56 PM 1) Thou shalt not, when I present the $5 for my $4.32 order, ask,&quot;Do you have 32 cents?&quot;If I wanted to dig around for it, I&apos;d have already done so. It won&apos;t kill you to count out 68 cents from your register. And it probably takes less time than waiting for me to root around my purse for change.

Speaking of which, how come nobody knows how to count out change anymore? They just count out the amount that the register tells them. In the old days, we were taught to start at the sale amount and count up to the amount tendered. Chanteuse 08-11-2005, 09:48 PM Speaking of which, how come nobody knows how to count out change anymore? They just count out the amount that the register tells them. In the old days, we were taught to start at the sale amount and count up to the amount tendered.

When I worked at this particular fast food joint, they did NOT allow us to use the&quot;cash tendered&quot;button. They had discovered that any time the registers were inoperable (say a brief power outage or simple malfunction), the cashiers were unable to compute change. So they just made us learn how from the very start. For a while there, I couldn&apos;t see any number under 100 without mentally calculating the remainder. (For example, if I saw or heard the number 37, my mind automatically responded with the number 63.) This is the cashier&apos;s version of an earworm! bmoak 08-11-2005, 10:04 PM I&apos;m not going to go so far as to&quot;champion the cause&quot;, but IMO confusing two very similar fast food joint&apos;s food isn&apos;t the stupidest mistake a person can make.

Ray Kroc is probably turning over in his grave. :) How many billions in advertising has McD&apos;s spent over the decades to associate its menu items with its brand and people still go to the competition thinking they serve Big Macs? VegemiteMoose 08-11-2005, 10:18 PM Okay I know it&apos;s&quot;walk thru&quot;, but really!

I returned from the Liquor Store tonight with an extra $12.75. Well, extra if you consider that my math skills countered what the register&quot;told&quot;the cashier to say. No, my purchase did not total $33.10, it totalled $20.35. Hey LOOK --&gt;on the flat screen register you just entered two single bottles as two 4 packs. Smapti 08-11-2005, 10:36 PM Whew, I post a simple rant and when I come back from work it&apos;s longer than the Battlestar Galactica thread. Anyway:

On speed-of-service and parking cars: Most drive-thrus have a timer that starts the second your car trips the sensor at the speaker box and continues counting until the car leaves the window. These times are averaged up over dayparts (breakfast, lunch, late-night etc). and each shift has a time that their average is supposed to be underneath. (For example, on the shift I usually work our quota is 4:30.) Management uses these numbers for everything from employee performance reviews to determining the size of raises.&quot;Parking&quot;a car does stop the timer, but that&apos;s typically not why it&apos;s done. Where I currently work, our policy is that we park you if your order will take more than 30 seconds to prepare and the order for the car behind you is already ready. For the inconvienience we usually throw in a dessert or a free upsize.

On upselling the special item of the month: I have to agree with the people who said they don&apos;t like it when drive-thru people do this to them. This is something that management makes us do in the hopes of moving more units of that particular item (and it does work).

On preview boards: Yes, I realize that not all restaurant chains have these, and of those that do some only have part of the menu on it. But a great many do, including the one I work at, and it surprises me how so many people don&apos;t even seem to notice it - they drive right into the lane when there&apos;s nobody ahead of or behind them, zoom right past it up to the speaker, and then spend two minutes staring at the board while we all wait for them to speak up so we can start cooking. Ashes, Ashes 08-12-2005, 12:18 AM I detest being asked to pull ahead. What a way to tell your customers that they don&apos;t mean crap to management and/or corporate, they&apos;re just a reason to put the spurs to your harrassed workers. I love being the cause of stress to someone who&apos;s already working hard and just trying to make a living.

I also dislike that policy because it&apos;s now going to take forever for my order to be readied and someone is free to walk it out. The Jack&apos;s that is worst about this has the longest walk in the world from the door to the drive way, as well. Then I&apos;m also forced to make people behind me drive around me in a busy, but tiny parking lot.

A tip for places with drive throughs: Make sure the person working the window speaks enough english to take and confirm orders.


And no-one short of James Bond could remove the plastic top from one of those filled-to-beyond-the-brim drinks in a moving vehicle, drink from it, replace the top, and not wind up soaked. Not driving a standard. No way, Jack.
Bow down to my mighty drinking and driving skills! Okay, that came out wrong. In any case, as I drive, I can not only get the top off and straw placed, but I can add lemon and sweetener to my iced tea without spilling. For extra difficulty points I can do all that while getting back on a busy freeway. Yep, I drive a manual and no cupholder just my lap. Does this mean I&apos;m James Bond? If so, I want to be the Sean Connery James Bond, not the Timothy Dalton one, please. VegemiteMoose 08-12-2005, 12:38 AM Thanks for the response Smapti. But please, let&apos;s call it something other than&quot;speed of service&quot;if it conveniently disregards those whose service is not speedy. Ashes, Ashes 08-12-2005, 12:41 AM A tip for places with drive throughs: Make sure the person working the window speaks enough english to take and confirm orders.
Just to be clear, the employee didn&apos;t speak enough english to understand I wanted a #1 meal. While I was at the window, they were treated rather rudely by the counter cashier, who certainly had no trouble with the english language. I can understand being short staffed, but that just didn&apos;t seem like a very wise re-distribution of the staff. Wolfian 08-12-2005, 01:24 AM 1) Thou shalt not, when I present the $5 for my $4.32 order, ask,&quot;Do you have 32 cents?&quot;If I wanted to dig around for it, I&apos;d have already done so. It won&apos;t kill you to count out 68 cents from your register. And it probably takes less time than waiting for me to root around my purse for change.
As a former cashier I can tell you that 99.999% of the time that happens the register guy is running low on change and doesn&apos;t want to wait for the manager to walk to the safe and come back with a roll of pennies. Trust me, it takes less time for you to root around in your purse. Fish 08-12-2005, 01:43 AM I detest being asked to pull ahead. What a way to tell your customers that they don&apos;t mean crap to management and/or corporate...
The restaurants can&apos;t win. The customer complains if he&apos;s pulled ahead to wait an additional minute while food is made hot and fresh; he complains if he&apos;s given food that isn&apos;t hot and fresh. He complains if he has to wait at the window. He complains that the order is handed to him so fast that he doesn&apos;t have time to put his change back in his wallet.

Some people should just go back to hunting and gathering. sturmhauke 08-12-2005, 04:07 AM On speed-of-service and parking cars: Most drive-thrus have a timer that starts the second your car trips the sensor at the speaker box and continues counting until the car leaves the window. These times are averaged up over dayparts (breakfast, lunch, late-night etc). and each shift has a time that their average is supposed to be underneath. (For example, on the shift I usually work our quota is 4:30.) Management uses these numbers for everything from employee performance reviews to determining the size of raises.
The customers are not there to make your numbers look good, you are there for their convenience. I agree that customers shouldn&apos;t pull up and change their minds 20 times while arguing with their boatload of brats and someone else on a cell phone, but if they&apos;re just looking at the menu your service numbers are your own goddamn problem. If the customer spends the same total time in the drive thru, but your numbers vary depending on whether they looked at the preview board first, then management has their heads up their ass. Duck Duck Goose 08-12-2005, 04:50 AM I&apos;m rubber, you&apos;re glue. Whatever you say bounces off of me and sticks to you
Nitpick.

Just wanna point out that it actually goes:

&quot;I&apos;m rubber, you&apos;re glue,
Bounce off me and sticks to you.&quot;

Which I know isn&apos;t exactly grammatical, as it oughta be,&quot;Bounces off me&quot;, but that&apos;s playground chants for ya.

This version scans better, too.

File for future reference. :D wring 08-12-2005, 06:17 AM but of course, as a comeback from some one chronically over the age of 5 years old, it&apos;s still pretty fucking lame. Chanteuse 08-12-2005, 06:36 AM As a former cashier I can tell you that 99.999% of the time that happens the register guy is running low on change and doesn&apos;t want to wait for the manager to walk to the safe and come back with a roll of pennies. Trust me, it takes less time for you to root around in your purse.

My experience as a cashier was a bit different, I guess. Almost 100% of the time, we had mucho extra rolls of coins. I rarely had to go get change--at least in coin form--and I remember only a couple of times that another register needed me to give them pennies. Primarily, a customer only had to wait on change if he presented a large bill for a small dollar order--dollar bills always seemed to run out quickly. And lowly cashiers were not allowed to change $50&apos;s and $100&apos;s, we had to get management (I hated this SO bad). But I wouldn&apos;t mind it so much if I was told,&quot;I&apos;m out of pennies, do you have any change?&quot;Rarely, if ever, when I couldn&apos;t pony up the coins did I hear this--they just counted the change from the drawer.

There were a couple of times that a cashier opened rolls of coins just before counting time at the end of her shift (a fast food type of short-sheeting a bed, you know) so the manager (or ass&apos;t manager) had piles of coins to count. It&apos;s a good thing some of them had a sense of humor (no, I never had the guts to try it)! :D Left Hand of Dorkness 08-12-2005, 06:52 AM but of course, as a comeback from some one chronically over the age of 5 years old, it&apos;s still pretty fucking lame.
Actually, given that the same poster complains a few posts later about kids these days (In My day, we HAD to compute change in our heads!), I thought it was hilarious.

Daniel Dung Beetle 08-12-2005, 07:25 AM Speaking of which, how come nobody knows how to count out change anymore? They just count out the amount that the register tells them. In the old days, we were taught to start at the sale amount and count up to the amount tendered.
I went to an Applebee&apos;s last night to pick up a take-out order. The pick-up spots were taken so I had to go inside. The girl who rang up my order did something which caused the register to pop open but apparently didn&apos;t tell her how much change to give me. She worked on it mentally for at least five minutes, then handed me the wrong change. I gave it back and told her how much it should be. She then tried to work it out with a pencil and paper and got it wrong again. Finally I put all my stuff down, rooted around in my purse for a calculator, and showed her. UncleRojelio 08-12-2005, 08:13 AM but of course, as a comeback from some one chronically over the age of 5 years old, it&apos;s still pretty fucking lame.

Blow me bordelond 08-12-2005, 08:15 AM Dude ... read the thread.
&lt;yawn&gt; TommyTutone 08-12-2005, 08:39 AM It&apos;s not like I&apos;m sitting there for 10 minutes, I&apos;m talking 30 seconds tops.


Oh give me a break. I didn&apos;t say I can&apos;t understand it, I&apos;m saying all those big pictures are disorienting at first. What if what I want isn&apos;t on the big pictures? Then I have to cycle through the entire menu looking for what I want.

I&apos;m going to guess that you need to lay down when you get a catalog in the mail, lest you be overcome by the vapors? 5que 08-12-2005, 08:46 AM I&apos;d like to hear each and every one of you complain just as loud about order takers who try to up-sell or push the trendy McItem of the month.
See post 48. UncleRojelio 08-12-2005, 08:50 AM &lt;yawn&gt;

If you are too lazy to read the thread and we are boring you, why do you bother to post? ElvisL1ves 08-12-2005, 09:05 AM And, since there was no one behind me, when I finally got to the damn speaker, I order a McHaggis just to see what the order-drone would say.Around here anyway, you have a good chance of hearing&quot;The Dropkick Murphys rock, dude!&quot;

Um, they&apos;re a punk-Irish band with a bagpiper nicknamed Spicy McHaggis. Story is they were on tour in Scotland, saw a Mickey D&apos;s advertising Spicy McChicken, made a bad joke, and it turned into The Spicy McHaggis Jig (http://www.plyrics.com/lyrics/dropkickmurphys/thespicymchaggisjig.html) (lyrics not work-safe).

As if you care. bordelond 08-12-2005, 09:08 AM If you are too lazy to read the thread and we are boring you, why do you bother to post?
No, no ... this thread is fun to follow.

&quot;&lt;yawn&gt;&quot;just means&quot;I am unmoved&quot;. UncleRojelio 08-12-2005, 09:16 AM As if you care.

On the contrary, I was greatly entertained. Thanks for the link. Now I have even more fodder to work with the next time I, and a bunch of other travel-weary punch-drunk nerds on expense accounts, roll into a Scottish establishment after midnight in a strange city. UncleRojelio 08-12-2005, 09:17 AM &quot;&lt;yawn&gt;&quot;just means&quot;I am unmoved&quot;.

Yeah, I know how you feel. I haven&apos;t taken a dump this morning either. Left Hand of Dorkness 08-12-2005, 09:18 AM No shit?
Daniel UncleRojelio 08-12-2005, 09:22 AM No shit?
Daniel

Just a little prairie-dogging. Maybe I&apos;ll be able to drop the kids off at the pool later. zenith 08-12-2005, 09:29 AM I&apos;ve never worked in fast food but I&apos;ve eaten at enough to have the gut to show for it (lawsuit pending), so may I please add

If thou hast an unusual order, one that is far larger than normal (as in for an entire football team), or yea is even just more complicated than normal [cut the burger in half with mustard on the left side and mayonaisse on the right and a pickle on top of the bun] or requires several different payors, PLEASE go inside.


This one is applicable to the drive-up bank window,as well. I get my paychecks direct-deposited to minimize use of the drive-thru, but people occasionally cut me paper checks.

I seem to always get behind: 1) People with tons of coins who can&apos;t read the signs telling them to take large amounts of coins inside. 2)People with 4-th party checks who argue with the teller,make the teller get a supervisor, argue with the supervisor, finally yell&quot;Fuck You&quot;and speed off.3) People who try to get credit card cash advances via drivethru DURING REGULAR BUSINESS HOURS at the walk-in side (I realize that emergencies happen on weekend afternoons or after 5 pm weekdays, so I&apos;ll cut some slack there). Left Hand of Dorkness 08-12-2005, 09:32 AM Just a little prairie-dogging. Maybe I&apos;ll be able to drop the kids off at the pool later.
Probably all that fast food you&apos;re eating.
Daniel Stringer 08-12-2005, 09:35 AM I&apos;m going to guess that you need to lay down when you get a catalog in the mail, lest you be overcome by the vapors?
Psh, like I can read a catalog. UncleRojelio 08-12-2005, 09:45 AM This one is applicable to the drive-up bank window,as well.

Drive-up bank windows merit a thread all by themselves.

My favorites are the asshats who wait until they get up the little vacuum tube kiosk thing to fill out their deposit slip. For crying-out-loud! Fill the mutha fucka out before you leave the house! UncleRojelio 08-12-2005, 09:50 AM Probably all that fast food you&apos;re eating.
Daniel

Naw, I figure it&apos;s caused by having to hold it back while waiting in line behind slow-menu-reading, indecisive, vegans at the fast food place drive-thru window. Left Hand of Dorkness 08-12-2005, 09:51 AM Naw, I figure it&apos;s caused by having to hold it back
One of the benefits of vegetarianism is comfortable bowel control.

Daniel Smapti 08-12-2005, 09:52 AM I agree that customers shouldn&apos;t pull up and change their minds 20 times while arguing with their boatload of brats and someone else on a cell phone, but if they&apos;re just looking at the menu your service numbers are your own goddamn problem. If the customer spends the same total time in the drive thru, but your numbers vary depending on whether they looked at the preview board first, then management has their heads up their ass.

Well, I never said anything about where the heads of our corporate overlords may or may not be located. :) FatBaldGuy 08-12-2005, 09:53 AM I detest being asked to pull ahead. What a way to tell your customers that they don&apos;t mean crap to management and/or corporate, they&apos;re just a reason to put the spurs to your harrassed workers. I love being the cause of stress to someone who&apos;s already working hard and just trying to make a living.

I also dislike that policy because it&apos;s now going to take forever for my order to be readied and someone is free to walk it out. The Jack&apos;s that is worst about this has the longest walk in the world from the door to the drive way, as well. Then I&apos;m also forced to make people behind me drive around me in a busy, but tiny parking lot.I have often been tempted to refuse to pull forward and say&quot;No, thanks. I&apos;ll just wait here until my order is ready.&quot;But I&apos;ve never actually had the guts to do it. Has anyone ever actually done this, and what were the results? UncleRojelio 08-12-2005, 09:54 AM One of the benefits of vegetarianism is comfortable bowel control.l

Just because you can to command your bowels to move while waiting in line at the fast food place doesn&apos;t automatically make you a vegetarian. InkBlot 08-12-2005, 10:01 AM See? I miss all the fun threads. Page one, I&apos;m reading through with my mouse over the reply button, itching to click. Page two, the urge is almost irresistable. Page three, I&apos;ve got most of a post lined up in my mind. And now it&apos;s page four, and the scatalogical jokes are all about.

Damn.

Well, I&apos;m a gonna throw what I got out here anyway, flinging my opinion forth like a monkey with a fistful of...

No, no, I&apos;m better than that.*

Much of the contention in this thread is kind of a customer vs. establishment vibe that, let&apos;s face it, has always been and will always be around. I&apos;d like to be clear up front, I&apos;m not touching that part of the argument. I believe the Customer needs to fight for what they want, or companies claiming to be Customer Focused, or whatever they like to say, won&apos;t know just what their customers want.

No, I wanted to try and explain just what Customer Service means. See, to most Customer Service industries like fast food, the&quot;Customer&quot;the serve is a plural term, not singular. So while,&quot;I don&apos;t care about your time, you&apos;re here to serve me!&quot;might make you feel better, it does nothing for the people in line behind you. And no, I&apos;m not being drawn into the 30 seconds/3 minutes argument. The point is, the quality of service decisions they make are targeted at all their customers, not just one.

So I work for an airline, one of a few that doesn&apos;t assign seats to their passengers. A strange idea that has gotten complaints, which are outweighed by compliments. The decision still boils down to: More customers like it because they board planes faster, pick seats they want (such as, away from the creepy guy or the crying baby), and don&apos;t have to play match the illegible print on their ticket with the tiny, faded plaquard above the seats. It works for us, because we turn our planes faster, fit more flights in a single day, move more passengers places, etc., etc. Sometimes a good customer service move pays off immeditaly, others trickle down. Really good decisions do both.

These drive-through commandments follow the same logic. Fast food is about delivering quality food as fast as possible. The drive-through area even more so. So while their desire to move you through the line at a less than serene pace seems callous, it&apos;s not about you. It&apos;s about the 1.5 billion served.


On a side note, the preview menus are pretty common around here. What&apos;s truly innovative is what I like to call the double-barreled McDonalds. Only one I&apos;ve seen like it, they added on a second drive through lane. One menu, shared by all, then you choose a lane as you pull around. Either you&apos;re next to the window in the building, or a small brick hut. Both have clerks to take your money, and dispense drinks. If you&apos;re in the outer lane, someone from inside runs your food out to you.

Looks like a lot of work for them, but darn, they&apos;re efficient! They don&apos;t even tell you which lane to pick! You just pull around, and they repeat your order....I&apos;ve been through a couple of times, and they&apos;ve never mixed it up yet. They process an extremely high volume of people every day at lunch, and work hard to keep the machinery rolling.

InkBlot
:eek:



*Not really. Left Hand of Dorkness 08-12-2005, 10:05 AM Just because you can to command your bowels to move while waiting in line at the fast food place doesn&apos;t automatically make you a vegetarian.
Oh, you thought I meant control over MY bowels. No, no: it&apos;s better than that.

Daniel UncleRojelio 08-12-2005, 10:09 AM Oh, you thought I meant control over MY bowels. No, no: it&apos;s better than that.

Just when I think that no one could possible dream up yet another idea for a super hero, here you come with,&quot;Super Bowel Control Man&quot;.

That is just plain wrong. Left Hand of Dorkness 08-12-2005, 10:13 AM Just when I think that no one could possible dream up yet another idea for a super hero, here you come with,&quot;Super Bowel Control Man&quot;.

That is just plain wrong.
What can I say? I&apos;m in touch with my inner third-grader.

Daniel bordelond 08-12-2005, 10:17 AM No, I wanted to try and explain just what Customer Service means. See, to most Customer Service industries like fast food, the&quot;Customer&quot;the serve is a plural term, not singular. So while,&quot;I don&apos;t care about your time, you&apos;re here to serve me!&quot;might make you feel better, it does nothing for the people in line behind you. And no, I&apos;m not being drawn into the 30 seconds/3 minutes argument. The point is, the quality of service decisions they make are targeted at all their customers, not just one.
This is all well and good. But when I&apos;m at the menu, I will scan over it if I damn well please. I am totally convinced that it is reasonable to do so, to boot.

I don&apos;t care what the&quot;typical customer&quot;or the&quot;average customer&quot;does -- I am my own person with my own way of doing things. If I&apos;m marginally slower** at the speaker than the guy that has ordered the same damn thing every day for 20 years, then tough shit.

** and it is&quot;marginally&quot;. No cell-phone yapping, no changing minds 20 times, etc. InkBlot 08-12-2005, 10:28 AM This is all well and good. But when I&apos;m at the menu, I will scan over it if I damn well please. I am totally convinced that it is reasonable to do so, to boot.

I don&apos;t care what the&quot;typical customer&quot;or the&quot;average customer&quot;does -- I am my own person with my own way of doing things. If I&apos;m marginally slower** at the speaker than the guy that has ordered the same damn thing every day for 20 years, then tough shit.

** and it is&quot;marginally&quot;. No cell-phone yapping, no changing minds 20 times, etc.

That&apos;s you&apos;re call. So far as I know, only the infamous Soup Nazi would actually eject you for delaying too long. The typical fast food place won&apos;t, but I&apos;m just explaining why they&apos;re not necessarily on your side, either. They&apos;re looking for fast, efficient, drive through operations.

But I do point back to my 30 second/3 minute comment. I&apos;m not going to argue what&apos;s&quot;reasonable.&quot;Scan the menu, make an informed choice. Makes you happy when you get the food you want the first time. Yes, they have little service clocks, but they&apos;re inside. When they start mounting timers next to the menus outside, then I&apos;ll be offended right there with you. :)

InkBlot
:eek: Clothahump 08-12-2005, 10:28 AM How about a Commandment for the business?

&quot;Thou shalt maintain the speakers and microphones in good working condition, and ensure that the person taking the order can speak and understand the freakin&apos; English Language!!&quot;

I don&apos;t know what&apos;s worse, driving up to the order mike and hearing&quot;Wel&amp;#^%#&amp;.I take yo*#^&amp;$^^, please?&quot;or hearing&quot;Waccum Mudunna, I take joo ord?&quot;

In scenario one, the following usually ensues:

CH:&quot;I&apos;d like a #3 combo with a diet Coke, please.&quot;
OrderTaker:&quot;That&apos;s a *&amp;^&amp;$%&amp;^# wupersize&amp;%#$$root beer. 3.94, firs&amp;%#^%^$&quot;.
CH:&quot;No. My order was a #3 combo with a diet Coke, please.&quot;
OT:&quot;$@^^#&amp;*$^%@@@(($&amp;^#@&quot;
CH:&quot;Dammit&quot;, at which point I drive around to the window and place my order there, complete with complaint about the mike/speaker issue.

In scenario two, the following usually ensues:

CH:&quot;I&apos;d like a #3 combo with a diet Coke, please.&quot;
OT:&quot;Wha?&quot;
CH:&quot;I&apos;d like a #3 combo with a diet Coke, please.&quot;
OT:&quot;Das a numer tres. Wha drink?&quot;
CH:&quot;Diet Coke&quot;
OT:&quot;Das a numer tres wis a diet Coke. Joo wan fries wi dat?&quot;
CH: (WTF?)&quot;It&apos;s a combo. It comes with fries.&quot;
OT:&quot;Joo wan beeg fries?&quot;
CH:&quot;Cancel the order.&quot;, at which point I go next door to Burger King, where I run the gauntlet once again.

I don&apos;t use the drive-through windows much any more, for obvious reasons. InkBlot 08-12-2005, 10:36 AM How about a Commandment for the business?

&quot;Thou shalt maintain the speakers and microphones in good working condition, and ensure that the person taking the order can speak and understand the freakin&apos; English Language!!&quot;

Oh, yeah. Remember when the LCD screens started going into the menus? So you could see them entering your order? I&apos;m still undecided if this was a good move. As far as I can tell, one of three things happens these days:

1) The screen is broken or missing.

2) The person doesn&apos;t enter my order while I&apos;m sitting there (often, they seem a person behind).

3) The person hits keys so fast, it looks like I&apos;m feeding a small army before they whittle out the errors down to my simple little combo.

I like what many McD&apos;s in my area are doing. No more speakerphone menus. You get one preview menu, then you pull to the window to order with a live person. I suspect the error rate on orders dropped precipitously with that addition. My only improvement would be a second menu behind the guy at the window. Or at least, a reduced menu...maybe just the combos? Because everytime, I look at menu, find my combo, think&quot;#4...I want a #4...&quot;then at the window, it&apos;s,&quot;I&apos;d like a number...er...the...heck, I want a Double Qtr Pounder combo, please.&quot;

InkBlot
:eek: Wolfian 08-12-2005, 10:37 AM Chicken sandwich? InkBlot 08-12-2005, 10:38 AM One day I want to go through a McDonald&apos;s drive through and order a combo 3.14 and see if they give me an apple pie. Wolfian 08-12-2005, 10:40 AM That was directed at Clothahump. bordelond 08-12-2005, 10:40 AM But I do point back to my 30 second/3 minute comment. I&apos;m not going to argue what&apos;s&quot;reasonable.&quot;Scan the menu, make an informed choice. Makes you happy when you get the food you want the first time. Yes, they have little service clocks, but they&apos;re inside. When they start mounting timers next to the menus outside, then I&apos;ll be offended right there with you. :)
You misunderstand me -- the business is offending me in no way, as they are still serving me just fine.

The (apparent?) attitude of the OP towards people take a tad&quot;too long&quot;(whatever that is) at the menu is somewhat off-putting. But it&apos;s not really a biggie (har!) because when push comes to shove, the employee must simply deal with such trivialities, anyway, as part of their job. It&apos;s not an&quot;above and beyond&quot;thing to wait briefly on a menu-scanning customer.

The attitudes of some of the drive-thru customers expressed here in this thread is also off-putting ... but honestly, not particularly relevant. In real life, I have never been honked at or yelled at in a drive through for my extra 20-30 seconds, so I&apos;m certainly not concerned with what random folks on a message board think. I am convinced that the extremely impatient folk in most daily interactions are in a tiny, insignificant, and unreasonable minority, anyhow. D_Odds 08-12-2005, 10:48 AM Ray Kroc is probably turning over in his grave. :) How many billions in advertising has McD&apos;s spent over the decades to associate its menu items with its brand and people still go to the competition thinking they serve Big Macs?
Let him spin.

I visit one of the two major burger chains about once every other year. I never pay attention to which one because, to me, they are the same (very bad). However, Ray and his successors have done a better job at burning their product names into my subconscious. So when I want little bits of battered, fried chicken, I say McNuggets. I don&apos;t need some yoyo giving me a hard time because I didn&apos;t use his store&apos;s specific name. You know what I meant, just give them to me, take my money and get over it. wring 08-12-2005, 11:00 AM Blow me


oooooooooo. once again we stand in awe of your witty repartee. I mean I really felt the&quot;burn&quot;on that one. Do you give tutorials? UncleRojelio 08-12-2005, 11:13 AM oooooooooo. once again we stand in awe of your witty repartee. I mean I really felt the&quot;burn&quot;on that one. Do you give tutorials?

You want lessons from from me on that which you have already elevated to an art form? No, I think your expertise speaks for itself. Boggette 08-12-2005, 11:21 AM #12 Thou shalt always informeth cashier of coupons and other discounts before pulling up to the window.

One of my greatest pet peeves of all from my fast food days was when customers would present coupons or inform me that they are senior citizens and are thus entitled to a 10% discount. In these cases the old ticket had to be voided out and re-entered, driving up speed-of-service times.

I used to use my College Student Discount. If you mentioned it at the speaker, they NEVER applied it. Got so the only way you could get it was to tell them at the window. This might be site-specific, but it happened every time I went there. cabdude 08-12-2005, 12:05 PM I love this thread. I love the diametrically opposed viewpoints.

Group A#: Yeah, uh, wait a sec, I&apos;m just reading the menu. Uh huh. Uh huh. McDonalds sells fries? Who knew? Oh, wait, this is Burger King. Ok, then just give me a Burrito.

Group B#: *revs engine* MOVE IT ASSWIPE!!!! NO READING!! NO REACHING FOR CURRENCY!!! NO WAITING TO ENGAGE DRIVE!!! Where&apos;s my sniper rifle? UncleRojelio 08-12-2005, 12:32 PM Group B#: *revs engine* MOVE IT ASSWIPE!!!! NO READING!! NO REACHING FOR CURRENCY!!! NO WAITING TO ENGAGE DRIVE!!! Where&apos;s my sniper rifle?

If I had it my way ( no pun intended ), I would submit an order via the web and then, at the drive thru, a scanner would read my license plate, whereby the service droids would hand me my stuff without having to have my wheels come to a full and complete stop; the monetary exchange having taken place electronically. sturmhauke 08-12-2005, 02:45 PM Welcome to Geek Burger, if you haven&apos;t ordered already get the hell out of here. Fuckin n00bs. cabdude 08-12-2005, 02:55 PM I guess ideally what you want is for someone to telepathically determine what you want to order, automagically suck the money out of your bank account then fire your hamburgers at your car with a cannon as you speed by.

Now THAT&apos;S fast food. BMalion 08-12-2005, 03:12 PM I guess ideally what you want is for someone to telepathically determine what you want to order, automagically suck the money out of your bank account then fire your hamburgers at your car with a cannon as you speed by.

Now THAT&apos;S fast food.

I would SO pay for that! Club 33 08-12-2005, 03:41 PM Concerning the whole&quot;please pull forward and we&apos;ll bring your order out to you&quot;thing...

If there are a line of cars behind me, I don&apos;t have a problem and will pull forward. Don&apos;t you dare tell me to pull forward and park when there is nobody behind me though. As someone else said, my job is not to make your numbers look better.

I had an assistant manager at a McDonalds actually throw my food at me one time because I refused to pull forward with nobody behind me. When I explained that I didn&apos;t care if I was being timed, he called me a liar and said that they don&apos;t time the people in the drive thru. I pointed to the machine and calmly asked&quot;So what does that do?&quot;He then said&quot;Here is your food&quot;and threw the bag at me.

After a nice 20 minute conversation with the owner of the establishment, he was fired and I got 3 days of free food.

Also, if you don&apos;t want me asking how much a burger is, don&apos;t only offer the combo on the menu with no ala carte pricing. Not my fault that you left that detail off the menu.

And don&apos;t give me a&quot;deer in the headlights&quot;look just because my order came to $4.37 and I gave you $10.37. Just because you saw the $10 in my hand and punched it into the register before I gave you the money is no excuse to not be able to do 3rd grade math.

Also, if you say you close at Midnight and I get there at 11:40, don&apos;t tell me you are closed so you can clean up and get out precisely at 12. This little gem happened to me last weekend after I had driven for 15 minutes to get to your little shithole of a restaurant.

Finally, stop getting my order wrong. You repeated it correctly and then screwed it up. It&apos;s not rocket science. Look at the fucking screen and check that what you put in the bag is what you were supposed to put in the bag.

Try doing some of the above before dictating to me how I can make your simple job easier. Maxxxie 08-12-2005, 03:59 PM Does the menu take SQL requests? select * from menu where patties=&apos;beef&apos; and sauce=&apos;special&apos; and num of patties&gt;= 2 and price&lt;= 2.32 order by price;

As someone who has spent the last month doing a crash course in SQL Server, this is one of the funniest things I&apos;ve read in a very long time! Thanks, Bippy!


:D
Max bordelond 08-12-2005, 04:02 PM Also, if you don&apos;t want me asking how much a burger is, don&apos;t only offer the combo on the menu with no ala carte pricing. Not my fault that you left that detail off the menu.
Yep.

It&apos;s crappy the way folks have fallen hook, line, and sinker for the&quot;Combo Meal&quot;gambit. Yep ... adding a drink for $.40 looks great -- except that the markup on that drink is still 800+ per cent (approximately $.05 wholesale for ~12 oz.).

I rarely take meals while driving, and I&apos;ve got drinks at home. Just the burger and fries, please. NotWithoutRage 08-12-2005, 04:10 PM :wally

And don&apos;t give me a&quot;deer in the headlights&quot;look just because my order came to $4.37 and I gave you $10.37. Just because you saw the $10 in my hand and punched it into the register before I gave you the money is no excuse to not be able to do 3rd grade math.


Even funnier: give them 11.01 on a bill of 5.51. Hilarity ensues.

&quot;Um, do you have the 50 cents?&quot;
&quot;No, just break that.&quot;
&quot;Yeah, but it&apos;s 5.51&quot;
&quot;Wait, you gave me a single, it&apos;s only 5.51, you can use the ten.&quot; sturmhauke 08-12-2005, 05:28 PM :wally

Even funnier: give them 11.01 on a bill of 5.51. Hilarity ensues.

I think in this situation, Dilbert would give them 11.26, using 2 dimes, a nickel, and a penny, and expect to get back a 5 and 3 quarters. Ashes, Ashes 08-12-2005, 07:08 PM The restaurants can&apos;t win. The customer complains if he&apos;s pulled ahead to wait an additional minute while food is made hot and fresh; he complains if he&apos;s given food that isn&apos;t hot and fresh. He complains if he has to wait at the window. He complains that the order is handed to him so fast that he doesn&apos;t have time to put his change back in his wallet.
Some people should just go back to hunting and gathering.
Perhaps others are unreasonable in the way you describe, but I just want to order, pay, get my food, and leave. I don&apos;t eat out if I have to be somewhere at a certain time, so I&apos;ve got no problem with fast food places that don&apos;t get my food to me at Mach 10 (I also don&apos;t mind waiting a bit at the speaker to order, if someone has to search the menu, or if the line is long, either).

All I ask is that you don&apos;t take my money and pull a fake-out on me by having me pull forward. It&apos;s not just an additional minute, I&apos;ve waited in parking lots so long I eventually parked and went inside. That&apos;s when, if I were the sort to complain about fairly minor crap, I would point out my food had been sitting in it&apos;s bag for so long, waiting to be taken out to my car, that the food was not hot and fresh. If we&apos;d all just waited our turns, and the workers weren&apos;t pulling some fancy kung fu with the timers, my food would not have been rendered even less gourmet than usual.

Compensated for my wait? Not in my universe has that ever happened.

Order, pay, receive food, clean get-away. That&apos;s not an unreasonable request. silenus 08-12-2005, 07:23 PM Welcome to Geek Burger, if you haven&apos;t ordered already get the hell out of here. Fuckin n00bs.

Are franchises available, because I would so invest in that! :D RobuSensei 08-12-2005, 09:01 PM Y&apos;know, if you&apos;re frustrated with drive-thru hassles, you should give NinjaBurger (http://www.ninjaburger.com) a try!

Internet ordering, and delivery in 30 minutes or less, or they commit seppuku!

:D StarvingButStrong 08-12-2005, 11:45 PM About that &apos;pull ahead&apos; stuff -- what I really wish is that they&apos;d give you a chance to change the order.

Because I only eat fast food when thosre are really my only criteria: fast and food. You don&apos;t have a fish burger ready? Gimme a chicken burger. Or a hamburger. What DO you have? I&apos;ll take that. Whatever. It doesn&apos;t matter to me all that much.

I want something hot and slightly nutritious to put in my empty belly, but most of all I want it NOW. VegemiteMoose 08-13-2005, 12:50 AM About that &apos;pull ahead&apos; stuff -- what I really wish is that they&apos;d give you a chance to change the order.

Because I only eat fast food when thosre are really my only criteria: fast and food. You don&apos;t have a fish burger ready? Gimme a chicken burger. Or a hamburger. What DO you have? I&apos;ll take that. Whatever. It doesn&apos;t matter to me all that much.

I want something hot and slightly nutritious to put in my empty belly, but most of all I want it NOW.
No kidding!

Can I have one Double McCrapBurg Meal? No?
Then just give me two single McCrapBurg&apos;s and a fries and a drink that I&apos;ll throw out anyway cause it&apos;s just fountain soda crap and ice anyway.
No?
That&apos;s okay, I&apos;ll just wait over here while you screw up the order further. (and screw it up you will !)

The one thing I&apos;ve gotten from this thread is that I&apos;m not going to wait anymore. Not for my benefit or the others behind me.

So, fast food drive thru window Jedi &apos;s.. what can we do to avoid the dreaded&quot;park it&quot;? Or in other words, what is the simplest way to achieve that goal? Just give me something warm between two buns that isn&apos;t illegal and doesn&apos;t require you to undress.

That&apos;s it. I just wanna choke down some&quot;food&quot;and that&apos;s all. sturmhauke 08-13-2005, 02:12 AM Are franchises available, because I would so invest in that! :D
Feel free to send me some investment capital.
So, fast food drive thru window Jedi &apos;s.. what can we do to avoid the dreaded&quot;park it&quot;? Or in other words, what is the simplest way to achieve that goal?
The main thing is to keep your order simple: no elaborate special orders (hold the mayo, extra pickles, fresh onions instead of dehydrated onions, don&apos;t toast the bun, light on the lettuce, blah blah blah) and no ordering a metric shitload of food (say, for a van full of high school baseball players after a game). Sometimes they will tell you to park anyway for whatever fucking reason though.

- sturmhauke, former McDrone Critical1 08-13-2005, 03:08 AM how about

You always order the #X meal, you have ordered that fucking meal about 20 times this month alone, you know how this goes so how about you pull your head out of your ass and order your meal instead of playing 20 questions with the cashier.

DF (dumbfuck)&quot;hi can i get a number 4&quot;
C (cashier&quot;sure what kind of drink with that?&quot;
DF&quot;oh i&apos;ll take a blah de blah&quot;
C and would you like that biggie/king/gigantomorph sized?&quot;
DF&quot;yeah&quot;
C&quot;anything else?&quot;
DF&quot;can i get some extra ketchup and no mustard on that?&quot;

I dont even work or eat fast food and those people drive me crazy. (well I eat the stuff once in awhile but we are talking a drive through every 6 months or so)

my conversation goes like this.
Me&quot;hi can I get X with X nothing to drink yes thats everthing&quot;
C&quot;your total is X at the first window&quot; Left Hand of Dorkness 08-13-2005, 08:02 AM I dont even work or eat fast food and those people drive me crazy. (well I eat the stuff once in awhile but we are talking a drive through every 6 months or so)
You people and your high blood pressure! Where&apos;s the percentage in being so easily driven crazy?

The Dumbfuck order you described is very often the most intelligent way to order: the employee may well have a specific order in which items must be punched into the keyboard, and the experience that is to you unique and exciting and full of anticipation is an experience that they&apos;ll repeat 100 times that hour. Your food order is fuzzing into all other food orders they&apos;ve taken during their shift: they aren&apos;t going to remember what you said more than two seconds beyond your having said it.

So instead of giving them the entire order at once, allow them to ask the questions that will result in their entering your information correctly into the computer. This isn&apos;t some great act of Gandhian magnanimity on your part: this is an attempt to get your request correctly filled.

At the very least, if someone else takes these precautions to make their own life easier, you may want to dial your stressometer down a notch, so that your head isn&apos;t constantly exploding.

Daniel cabdude 08-13-2005, 08:15 AM A: How you doing? Me, I&apos;m doing great. Yes, I&apos;m ready to order. I&apos;d like some food. Yes. Food. A burger, maybe. No, make that two. And a drink. Hmmm. Maybe a pie. Or two. And a straw. Thanks. Here ya go. You have a great day, two. Bubbye.

B: NO CONVERSATION!!! NO SOCIAL INTERACTION!!!! ORDER IN ONE BREATH, PAY AND COLLECT IN ONE SWIFT MOTION THEN RUN THE FUCK AWAY!!!! OR DON&apos;T BOTHER COMING IN AT ALL!!! DICK!!! HEAD!!!! jsgoddess 08-13-2005, 11:11 PM All I can say to this thread is that obviously you people don&apos;t go to White Castle.

Because at White Castle, if you don&apos;t have to wait 20 minutes in the drive through, it&apos;s because the restaurant got closed for health violations.

One doesn&apos;t go inside at a Castle. One goes through the drive through and one parks and eats in the car. CanvasShoes 08-13-2005, 11:52 PM &quot;.....meanwhile, you&apos;re holding out my drink/straws whatever while I&apos;m still fiddling with the change you just gave me? what the fuck gives with that program?
Ooooh, I HATE when they do this. They hold out the drink and straws with one hand, and then the other they hold out for the money. And I am one who gets my money and change all ready (not having a stick shift, and I figure it saves ME time as well).

The coins slide around on the top of the dollar bills, so the chances of it dropping while you&apos;re trying to get drink and straw inside are pretty good. And that&apos;s another thing, who the HELL came up with the coins on bills thing????

Anyway, my solution to the&quot;two hands out, one for soda, one for money&quot;, is to sweetly smile, say thank you, take the coke and straw, put it securely in my drink holder, and THEN hand them the money.

Otherwise, I agree with most of what the OP is saying, since a lot of the commandment breakers are more messing with our, their fellow customer&apos;s time than they are with the fast food workers (other than the idiotic service timers).

I mean, what&apos;s it really to the window clerk if the customer is an idiot and takes forever? Again, other than the sevice timer? That is the dumbest thing I&apos;ve ever heard of. I feel bad for the poor fast food worker that they have to deal with it. Since, again, the hold ups are generally moron customer related and not necessarily their, the worker&apos;s, fault.

At least whenever I go to the drive thru. I always get stuck behind some complete dolt who moves at the speed of slug and has 5 bazillion questions for the clerk and so on and so forth. soulmurk 08-14-2005, 12:21 AM I only get 30 minutes for lunch. It takes me anywhere from 5 to 8 minutes to get to a fast food joint nearby, depending on which one I decide on. I always know what I want ahead of time and have a black belt in fast food fu. If not for other customers, I could place my order and pay before the cashier even has my drink ready.

Figuring it takes about 2-3 minutes for food preparation under normal circumstances, typically more like 5-7 during the lunch rush, it then takes me another 5-8 to get back to work, leaving me with ~10-15 minutes to actually eat.

What this means is that there is very little leeway for me to get stuck behind some yahoo who wants to do a price comparison at the order box or argue with the cashier about 32 cents at the payment window. And invariably, I do.

Sure I could bring my lunch to work and bypass the whole scenario, but the fact is, sometimes I really just want that Whopper. So why should I be forced to have to rush and swallow my food without chewing just because the schmuck in front of me doesn&apos;t comprehend how to utilize a relatively simple tool like the drive-through?

Yeah, it may just be 30 seconds extra, but that&apos;s you. If I&apos;m the 4th car in line and everyone thinks that way, that&apos;s two minutes. Two minutes of my precious lunch, and life, that I&apos;ll never get back because you&apos;re an idiot. And then it&apos;s another 20 seconds in line at the grocery store, per person ahead of me. And then another 17.26 seconds at the ATM machine...

Point being, yeah it&apos;s just 30 seconds, but that time adds up. Seconds become minutes become hours of wasted time because you were too inconsiderate to actually put the minimal amount of thought required into properly preparing for the, let&apos;s be honest here, simple act of using a drive-through.

Henry Rollins put it best when he said, and I&apos;m paraphrasing here,&quot;You&apos;re murdering me slowly.&quot; ethanwinfield 08-14-2005, 01:10 AM About that &apos;pull ahead&apos; stuff -- what I really wish is that they&apos;d give you a chance to change the order.

Because I only eat fast food when thosre are really my only criteria: fast and food. You don&apos;t have a fish burger ready? Gimme a chicken burger. Or a hamburger. What DO you have? I&apos;ll take that. Whatever. It doesn&apos;t matter to me all that much.

I want something hot and slightly nutritious to put in my empty belly, but most of all I want it NOW.

If they told me at the ordering menu,&quot;It will be a five minute wait for your order,&quot;I would change my order to something they have ready now. Instead, they wait until after I have confirmed my order and paid for it.

When asked to pull forward and park, I politely reply,&quot;No thank you. I&apos;ll just cancel my order.&quot;Without fail, I have been told,&quot;Just a second.&quot;Suddenly my food is ready and I am on my way. I have yet to figure this one out--if my order was going to take 5 minutes, and a refund may have taken the same amount of time (more or less), how is it that my order is suddenly ready?

I pulled forward and waited once. My food never came. After 10 or 15 minutes of waiting, I went inside and asked for my food. I was told they gave it to me at the drive-thru window and I was accused of trying to get a duplicate order for free. Right then and there I decided I would never again,&quot;pull forward and park&quot;while I waited for someone to bring me my food. CanvasShoes 08-14-2005, 02:21 AM Nitpick.

Just wanna point out that it actually goes:

&quot;I&apos;m rubber, you&apos;re glue,
Bounce off me and sticks to you.&quot;

Which I know isn&apos;t exactly grammatical, as it oughta be,&quot;Bounces off me&quot;, but that&apos;s playground chants for ya.

This version scans better, too.

File for future reference. :D
Really? Not to disbelieve you, but I remember saying the&quot;whatever you say bounces of of me&quot;version way back in the coughlate60scoughcough.

I didn&apos;t know there was a composium of historically correct kid comebacks.

:D CanvasShoes 08-14-2005, 02:42 AM I have often been tempted to refuse to pull forward and say&quot;No, thanks. I&apos;ll just wait here until my order is ready.&quot;But I&apos;ve never actually had the guts to do it. Has anyone ever actually done this, and what were the results?
Absolutely I have. If they&apos;re screwing things up I&apos;m not going to allow them the luxury to take even longer to get the stuff together (and I used to meekly pull ahead, where I was repeatedly forgotten or left until all of the&quot;real&quot;customers had been taken care of).

What to I tell them? I very nicely say&quot;No thank you, I&apos;ll wait here, I&apos;ve experienced your &apos;it will be right out&apos; before&quot;. I am nice about it, but firm. What happens? They get their qualuude drenched little brains in gear and get the stuff done as it SHOULD have been done in the first place. Bryan Ekers 08-14-2005, 08:40 AM Group B#: *revs engine* MOVE IT ASSWIPE!!!! NO READING!! NO REACHING FOR CURRENCY!!! NO WAITING TO ENGAGE DRIVE!!! Where&apos;s my sniper rifle?

DON&apos;T WAIT FOR THE TRANSLATION!! Left Hand of Dorkness 08-14-2005, 08:40 AM Sure I could bring my lunch to work and bypass the whole scenario, but the fact is, sometimes I really just want that Whopper. So why should I be forced to have to rush and swallow my food without chewing just because the schmuck in front of me doesn&apos;t comprehend how to utilize a relatively simple tool like the drive-through?
Why should the schmuck in front of you be forced to hurry his order just because the schmuck behind him couldn&apos;t be arsed to bring his lunch from home?

More things on heaven and earth, Horatio.

Thing is, there&apos;s a happy medium here. Folks in a drive-through lane should be spending as much of their attention as they can to making the process go quickly, while still getting the food they want. As long as they&apos;re doing that, you need to recognize that you&apos;re not the only customer, and that the line may not always move as quickly as you want. If you don&apos;t like that, you could always pay some dude ten bucks a day to go pick up your food for you, so that you don&apos;t have to deal with the hoi polloi.

Henry Rollins put it best when he said, and I&apos;m paraphrasing here,&quot;You&apos;re murdering me slowly.&quot;
You could look at the bright side of things: by making fast food less appealing to you, they&apos;re saving your life. Slowly.

Daniel soulmurk 08-14-2005, 12:17 PM Why should the schmuck in front of you be forced to hurry his order just because the schmuck behind him couldn&apos;t be arsed to bring his lunch from home?

More things on heaven and earth, Horatio.

Because there is a little thing that most people seem to have forgotten about called common courtesy. It extends beyond the need to not be personally inconvenienced, which is a high crime to most people, and yet they&apos;re the same hypocrites who have the nerve to roll their eyes when someone is inconvenienced by them.

Thing is, there&apos;s a happy medium here. Folks in a drive-through lane should be spending as much of their attention as they can to making the process go quickly, while still getting the food they want. As long as they&apos;re doing that, you need to recognize that you&apos;re not the only customer, and that the line may not always move as quickly as you want.

Agreed.

If you don&apos;t like that, you could always pay some dude ten bucks a day to go pick up your food for you, so that you don&apos;t have to deal with the hoi polloi.

Disagree. The dope who can&apos;t manage to use the drive-through effectively should have someone else go for them.

Though, if it were an option to send a lackey, I would.


You could look at the bright side of things: by making fast food less appealing to you, they&apos;re saving your life. Slowly.

No, they&apos;re just slightly prolonging the inevitable murder, slowly. Left Hand of Dorkness 08-14-2005, 01:05 PM Because there is a little thing that most people seem to have forgotten about called common courtesy. It extends beyond the need to not be personally inconvenienced, which is a high crime to most people, and yet they&apos;re the same hypocrites who have the nerve to roll their eyes when someone is inconvenienced by them.
It seems to me that applies equally to you as to them.

Disagree. The dope who can&apos;t manage to use the drive-through effectively should have someone else go for them.
But they are using it effectively.

Daniel Duck Duck Goose 08-14-2005, 08:43 PM Really? Not to disbelieve you, but I remember saying the&quot;whatever you say bounces of of me&quot;version way back in the coughlate60scoughcough.
Actually, it&apos;s probably one of those regional things, like the&quot;soda/pop&quot;thing. I learned my version in the 60s, too, but in the Chicago white-bread suburbs. Where did you learn yours? Duck Duck Goose 08-14-2005, 08:46 PM And actually, come to think of it, I learned it in the early 1960s, which makes it the hanging-over-from-the-Eisenhower-Era 1950s version. Duck Duck Goose 08-14-2005, 08:51 PM And actually, come to think of it, I learned it in the early 1960s, which makes it the hanging-over-from-the-Eisenhower-Era 1950s version. Dark Side of the Floyd 08-14-2005, 08:58 PM Yes, but did you learn it for twenty minutes? soulmurk 08-14-2005, 10:55 PM It seems to me that applies equally to you as to them.

Thus the reason I can pull in, order, pay, and be gone in as long as it takes them to process my order and get my food to me. My consideration to others and their lack of the same is exactly what frustrates me and is the entire gist of my statement.

It is not hypocritical to give something and expect it in return, but be upset when it is not. Only if I didn&apos;t offer it in the first place would I not have the right to gripe.

But they are using it effectively.

We have different definitions of effective. Left Hand of Dorkness 08-14-2005, 10:59 PM Thus the reason I can pull in, order, pay, and be gone in as long as it takes them to process my order and get my food to me. My consideration to others and their lack of the same is exactly what frustrates me and is the entire gist of my statement.

It is not hypocritical to give something and expect it in return, but be upset when it is not. Only if I didn&apos;t offer it in the first place would I not have the right to gripe.
Indeed. They&apos;re giving you all the time you need to make your order, not crowding you, not complaining the least bit no matter how long you take. They expect the same courtesy from you.

Why should your habits take precedent over theirs? It seems to me that you go knowingly into a situation where other folks&apos; legitimate behavior is going to frustrate you; I think you either need to recalibrate your frustration, or not go into the situation.

Again, the rule at fast food is that you have to wait for the people in front of you, not that you have to pace your order according to the desire of the people behind you. If you don&apos;t like that rule, it&apos;s upon you to find a way around it -- e.g., hiring someone to pick up your food for you.

We have different definitions of effective.
My definition is that they use the process to achieve the results they&apos;re trying to achieve. If they leave with the food they want, they&apos;ve succeeded. Your irritation at their efficacy is not their concern.

Daniel soulmurk 08-15-2005, 12:36 AM Indeed. They&apos;re giving you all the time you need to make your order, not crowding you, not complaining the least bit no matter how long you take. They expect the same courtesy from you.

Why should your habits take precedent over theirs? It seems to me that you go knowingly into a situation where other folks&apos; legitimate behavior is going to frustrate you; I think you either need to recalibrate your frustration, or not go into the situation.
The name of the game is&quot;fast food&quot;. I need no time, nor do most people. If I do need time to decide, my decision is made by the time the voice comes out of the speaker box asking to take my order. I ensure this habit because I would not deign to be rude enough to steal precious time from the people behind me, or to irritate the hard pressed people inside trying to accomodate a lunch rush.

My habits should take precedence over theirs because I do exactly what is necessary to get my order in and get out of the way as quickly as possible, much to the delight of those behind me and those inside (I&apos;ve actually been complimented and comped by the staff because of my quick and courteous behavior).

I go into these situations because I must. To follow your logic, why should I digress from my routine just because there might be a schmuck in line at the fast food restaurant? Or at the grocery store? Or at the ATM? Or in the movie ticket line?

My frustration stems from my taking the time to be prepared and having to suffer through someone who is not because they couldn&apos;t be bothered to take the 3 seconds to think things through beforehand. Their lack of action shows a disregard and disrespect for everyone around them. Are there worse ways to show it? Sure, but the statement made in line is the same made if they&apos;d deliberately cut me off on the highway.

And, frustration is a perfectly acceptable response. I don&apos;t shout obsenities or honk my horn or flip them off. I don&apos;t drag them out of their car and beat them senseless. I see no wrong with becoming frustrated because some asshole refuses to offer me the same courtesy I offer them.

Again, the rule at fast food is that you have to wait for the people in front of you, not that you have to pace your order according to the desire of the people behind you. If you don&apos;t like that rule, it&apos;s upon you to find a way around it -- e.g., hiring someone to pick up your food for you.
And the rule of common courtesy is that you do unto others as you would have done unto you.

Regardless, it is not a complicated procedure. There is absolutely no reason for a person to take more than the time it takes to speak your order. If they have 86 cents and don&apos;t know what they can get for 86 cents, go inside. If they have a coupon, mention it while ordering, not at the window. If their wallet is difficult to reach, get it out beforehand. They aren&apos;t a whole lot to ask and in the end they save everyone time. But people can&apos;t be bothered with anything outside of their own little self-centered world.

People go through the drive-through because they&apos;re in a hurry, so the near-sighted grandma in the Lincoln who can&apos;t see well enough to fit the car through the narrow lane, nevermind what her options are, need to go the hell inside or subscribe to Meals-on-Wheels.

My definition is that they use the process to achieve the results they&apos;re trying to achieve. If they leave with the food they want, they&apos;ve succeeded. Your irritation at their efficacy is not their concern.
The definition I use is summarized in the dictionary as: 1 a : producing a decided, decisive, or desired effect.

Taking their time is neither decided, decisive, nor desired. The desire is to move the line as quickly as possible.

That it is not their concern is exactly the problem. They have no common courtesy. If they did, they&apos;d give a rat&apos;s ass about the world outside their own personal microcosm and realize that their actions are inconveniencing others. sturmhauke 08-15-2005, 01:08 AM I only get 30 minutes for lunch.
Sucks for you. The length of your lunch break is not really my concern.
So why should I be forced to have to rush and swallow my food without chewing just because the schmuck in front of me doesn&apos;t comprehend how to utilize a relatively simple tool like the drive-through?
Last job I had involved a lot of driving, so I tended to go to a lot of drive thrus. Just because two restaurants are both franchises of the same corporation doesn&apos;t mean they have the same stuff on the menu. The combo meals may be numbered differently, the prices may vary, one restaurant may do combos that aren&apos;t officially listed while another may not, there may be a promotional item that&apos;s not available at all restaurants, etc.
Two minutes of my precious lunch, and life, that I&apos;ll never get back because you&apos;re an idiot. And then it&apos;s another 20 seconds in line at the grocery store, per person ahead of me. And then another 17.26 seconds at the ATM machine...

Henry Rollins put it best when he said, and I&apos;m paraphrasing here,&quot;You&apos;re murdering me slowly.&quot;
You&apos;re gonna give yourself an ulcer. Relax a little, dude. Left Hand of Dorkness 08-15-2005, 08:04 AM The name of the game is&quot;fast food&quot;. I need no time, nor do most people.
If most people don&apos;t need any time, then your scenario--
Yeah, it may just be 30 seconds extra, but that&apos;s you. If I&apos;m the 4th car in line and everyone thinks that way, that&apos;s two minutes.
is vanishingly unlikely to occur, so what&apos;s the problem?

And the rule of common courtesy is that you do unto others as you would have done unto you.
Indeed--so, by giving you all the time you need to make your order, the slowpokes are behaving courteously to you, since that&apos;s what they would do unto themselves. Yes?

People go through the drive-through because they&apos;re in a hurry, so the near-sighted grandma in the Lincoln who can&apos;t see well enough to fit the car through the narrow lane, nevermind what her options are, need to go the hell inside or subscribe to Meals-on-Wheels.
No, she doesn&apos;t. Why is she going through the drive-through, do you think?

The definition I use is summarized in the dictionary as: 1 a : producing a decided, decisive, or desired effect.

Taking their time is neither decided, decisive, nor desired. The desire is to move the line as quickly as possible.
Your desire is irrelevant to whether they&apos;re effective. Only their desire is relevant. If they desire to obtain their food, and they decidedly do obtain their food, then they&apos;ve achieved a decided, desired effect. If the food matches what their decision on the order was, they&apos;ve met the definition perfectly.
That it is not their concern is exactly the problem. They have no common courtesy. If they did, they&apos;d give a rat&apos;s ass about the world outside their own personal microcosm and realize that their actions are inconveniencing others.
Of course they have common courtesy: they&apos;re giving you all the time you need. If they&apos;re not screwing around when their time to order comes (talking on the cell phone, reading, chatting up the speaker), then they&apos;re behaving with perfect courtesy.

If you don&apos;t believe me, I invite you to write to Miss Manners, or the etiquette guru of your choice.

Daniel cosmosdan 08-15-2005, 08:25 AM My habits should take precedence over theirs because I do exactly what is necessary to get my order in and get out of the way as quickly as possible, much to the delight of those behind me and those inside (I&apos;ve actually been complimented and comped by the staff because of my quick and courteous behavior).I&apos;m sure their mechanical timer thinks you&apos;re great

I go into these situations because I must. To follow your logic, why should I digress from my routine just because there might be a schmuck in line at the fast food restaurant? Or at the grocery store? Or at the ATM? Or in the movie ticket line?
You may not have noticed it but there are diverse people in the world and things don&apos;t always go smoothly. Sometimes people are at a new ATM and not familiar with the menu, or they have several transactions. Sometimes at the grocery check out there&apos;s a trainee having a problem with a customer who wants to write a check. Sometimes people are trying a new fast food joint for lunch so they have to take a minute to look at the menu. Or someone is on there way somewhere and buyings snacks for a group so it takes a little longer. It&apos;s called real life and real people. They don&apos;t have to follow a set of rules you made up and they&apos;e not schmucks because they interfered with your routine. We&apos;ve created this hurry up society and the result is bad attitudes like yours.

My frustration stems from my taking the time to be prepared and having to suffer through someone who is not because they couldn&apos;t be bothered to take the 3 seconds to think things through beforehand. Their lack of action shows a disregard and disrespect for everyone around them. Are there worse ways to show it? Sure, but the statement made in line is the same made if they&apos;d deliberately cut me off on the highway.

I agree a car full of people who are undecided about what they want should go inside instead of discuss it at the menu board but I know that happens occasionaly. If I decide to take 30 seconds or more to consider any new items on the menu or to remind myself what they have because I only come through twice a year then I&apos;m not being discourteous to anyone. Expecting everyone to have decided and be ready when they get there is unrealistic.

And, frustration is a perfectly acceptable response. I don&apos;t shout obsenities or honk my horn or flip them off. I don&apos;t drag them out of their car and beat them senseless. I see no wrong with becoming frustrated because some asshole refuses to offer me the same courtesy I offer them.
You definition of courtesy is skewed. Courtesy does not demand that everyone be perfectly prepared every time they do anything that involves other people. Courtesy isn&apos;t about saving time. It&apos;s about dealing with people. Patience can be a part of courtesy. I began to notice how much I was buying in to the&quot;hurry up&quot;culture and I&apos;ve made a change. If someone on front of me has a problem and takes longer I won&apos;t get frustrated. I help if I can and wait patiently if I can&apos;t. If they apologize then I smile and say&quot;No Problem, no need to rush&quot;
If I don&apos;t have time to wait then I just go on my way without blaming anyone. It&apos;s just life and stuff happens.

And the rule of common courtesy is that you do unto others as you would have done unto you. Courtesy usually means two people interacting with each other. Sitting in the car behind someone is not interacting with them. It is considerate to be aware that others are waiting but people gauge how long is too long differently. Your exteme is one end of the spectrum.

Regardless, it is not a complicated procedure. There is absolutely no reason for a person to take more than the time it takes to speak your order. If they have 86 cents and don&apos;t know what they can get for 86 cents, go inside. If they have a coupon, mention it while ordering, not at the window. If their wallet is difficult to reach, get it out beforehand. They aren&apos;t a whole lot to ask and in the end they save everyone time. But people can&apos;t be bothered with anything outside of their own little self-centered world.

Certainly there are many self centered people in the world. I&apos;ve even noticed some folks seem to think being oblivious of others is a form of self esteem or personal pride. The&quot;it&apos;s all about me and what I want&quot;syndrome. However, the statement I bolded is just a ridiculous standard that only serves to keep you frustrated and critical of others.


The definition I use is summarized in the dictionary as: 1 a : producing a decided, decisive, or desired effect.

Taking their time is neither decided, decisive, nor desired. The desire is to move the line as quickly as possible. Again we come to what is a reasonable amount of time? Customers who frequent the place and know exactly what they want take less time than customers who only come once in a great while and have to read the menu or groups.

That it is not their concern is exactly the problem. They have no common courtesy. If they did, they&apos;d give a rat&apos;s ass about the world outside their own personal microcosm and realize that their actions are inconveniencing others. There&apos;s a thing called balance. If the guy behind me only has a half hour for lunch thats not my fault. There&apos;s no rule of courtesy that requires me to hurry and get something I don&apos;t really want because he forgot to bring lunch.
On Sat. when I have a only a half hour for lunch I bring lunch. It&apos;s my responsibility to deal with my own schedule not someone elses. If I find myself cussing under my breath because I&apos;m running a little late and the driver in front of me is going 5 miles an hour under the speed limit, that&apos;s my failure not theirs. cabdude 08-17-2005, 07:02 PM DON&apos;T WAIT FOR THE TRANSLATION!!

It took me a little while until I got it.

&apos;I am not in an American courtroom, sir.&apos; vBulletinv3.7.3, Copyright2000-2012, Jelsoft Enterprises Ltd.
	</body>
</document>
