<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001129" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/63545147/Accounting-21e-1" time="2012-07-12-16:33" support="1" score="0.001324359595448198" bingtitle="Accounting 21e[1] - Scribd" webtitle="Accounting 21e[1]">
			<query id="001209" bing-rank="158"/>
	<description>STATEMENT OF CASH FLOWS A summary of the cash receipts ... Transaction f When you pay your monthly credit card bill ... costs, variations in raw materials, and record keeping ...</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 Comment Go Back 
 Download   The Basics 1. Acco unti ng E quati on: Assets = Liabilities + Owner’s Equity 2. T Ac co un t: Account Title L e f t S i d e R i g h t S i d e d e b i t c r e d i t 3. Rule s of De bit an d Cred it: STATEMENT OF OWNER’S EQUITY A summary of the changes in the owner’s equity of a business en- tity that have occurred during a specific period of time, such as a month or a year. BALANCE SHEET A list of the assets, liabilities, and owner’s equity of a business en- tity as of a specific date, usually at the close of the last day of a month or a year. STATEMENT OF CASH FLOWS A summary of the cash r eceipts and cash pay ments of a business entity for a specific period of time, such as a month or a year. 6. Acco unti ng Cycle : 1. Analyze a nd recor d transactions in journal. 2. Post tran sact ions to ledge r. 3. Prepare trial balance, asse mble adjustment da ta, and complete optional work sheet. 4. Prep are financ ial stateme nts. 5. Journalize and post ad justing e ntries. 6. Journalize and post c losing e ntries. 7. Prepare post-closing trial ba lance. 7. T ypes of Adju stin g Entries : 1. Deferred expense (prepaid expense) 2. Deferred revenue (unearned revenue) 3. Accrued expense (accrued liability) 4. Accrued revenue (accrued asset) 5. Depr eciat ion exp ense Each entry will always affect both a balance sheet and an income state- ment account. 8. Clos ing Entri es: 1. T ransfer revenue a ccount balances to Income Summary . 2. T ransfer expense acc ount balances to Income Summary . 3. T ransfer Incom e Summary ba lance to Cap ital. 4. T ransfer draw ing account balan ce to Capital. 9. Spec ial Journ als: Providing services on account → recorded in  → Revenue (sales) journal Receipt of cash from any source → recorded in  → Cash receipts journal Purchase of items on account → recorded in  → Purchases journal Payments of cash for any purpose      → recorded in  → Cash payments journal 10. Shipping Terms: FO B Sh ip pi ng P oi nt FO B De st in at io n Ownership (title) passes to buyer when m e r c h a n d i s e i s . .. . . . . .. . . . .. . . . . .. d e li v e r e d to d e l iv e r e d t o f r e i g h t c a r r i e r b u y e r Transportation costs a r e p a i d b y. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . b u y e r s e l l e r Balance Sheet Accounts A S S E T S L I A B I L I T I E S A s s e t A c c o u n t s L i a b i l i t y A c c o u n t s D e b i t C r e d i t D e b i t C r e d i t f o r f o r f o r f o r i n c r e a s e s d e c r e a s e s d e c r e a s e s i n c r e a s e s OWNER’S EQUITY Owner’s Equity Accounts D e b i t C r e d i t f o r f o r d e c r e a s e s i n c r e a s e s Income Statement Accounts D e b i t f o r C r e d i t f o r de cr ea se s in ow ne r’s eq ui ty in cr ea se s in ow ne r’s eq ui ty E x p e n s e A c c o u n t s R e v e n u e A c c o u n t s D e b i t C r e d i t D e b i t C r e d i t f o r f o r f o r f o r i n c r e a s e s d e c r e a s e s d e c r e a s e s i n c r e a s e s Normal Balance 4. T o Analyze a T ransa ction : 1. Determine whether an asset, a liability , owner’s equity , revenue, or expense account is affected by the transaction. 2. For each ac count affecte d by the transa ction, determine wheth er the account increases or decreases. 3. Determine whether each increas e or decreas e should be re- corded as a debit or a credit. 5. Fina ncial Statem ents: INCOME STATEMENT A summary of the reve nue and the expenses of a bus iness entity for a specific period of time, such as a month or a year. 66124_endsh eets_front.qx d 11/12/03 9:20 PM Page B   11. Forma t for Ban k Reco ncil iatio n: Ca sh ba la nc e ac co rd in g to ba nk st at em en t .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. $x xx Add : Add itio ns by d epo sit or not on ban k state ment............ ....... ........ ....... ........ ....... ....... .. $xx Ba nk er ro rs... .. ... .. ... .. .. ... .. ... .. ... .. ... .. ... .. ... .. .. ... .. ... .. .. xx xx $xxx Deduct: Deductions by depositor not on bank state ment............ ....... ........ ....... ........ ....... ....... .. $xx Ba nk er ro rs... .. ... .. ... .. .. ... .. ... .. ... .. ... .. ... .. ... .. .. ... .. ... .. .. xx xx Ad ju st ed ba la nc e... .. ... .. ... .. ... .. .. ... .. ... .. ... .. ... .. ... .. ... .. .. ... .. ... .. .. $x xx Ca sh ba la nc e ac co rd in g to de po si to r’s re co rd s .. .. .. .. .. .. .. . $x xx Ad d: Ad di tio ns by ba nk no t r ec or de d by de po si to r.. $x x De po si to r er ro rs .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. . xx xx $xxx Deduct: Deductions by bank not recorde d by depo sitor............ ....... ........ ....... ....... ........ .... $xx De po si to r er ro rs .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. . xx xx Ad ju st ed ba la nc e... .. ... .. ... .. ... .. .. ... .. ... .. ... .. ... .. ... .. ... .. .. ... .. ... .. .. $x xx 12. Inven tory C ostin g Met hods : 1. Firs t-in, Fir st-ou t (fifo) 2. Las t-in, Fir st-ou t (lifo) 3. A vera ge Cost 13. Inter est Comp utati ons: Interest = Face Amount (or Principal) × Rate × Time 14. Metho ds of Determini ng Annua l Deprecia tion : STRAIGHT-LINE: DECLINING-BALAN CE: Rate* × Book Value at Beginning of Period *Rate is commonly twice the straight-line rate (1 ÷ Estimated Life). 15. Cash Pro vided by Op eratio ns on Statem ent of Cash Flows (indirect method): Ne t i nc om e, pe r i nc om e s ta te me nt.. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. $x x Ad d: De pr ec ia tio n o f f ixe d a ss et s .. .. ... .. ... .. ... .. .. ... .. .. $x x Amortization of bond payable discount and int ang ible ass ets... .... .... ... .... .... ... .... .... . xx Decreases in current assets (receivables, inv ent ori es, pre pai d exp ens es).. .... .... ... .... xx Increases in current liabilities (accounts an d no te s pa ya bl e, a cc ru ed lia bil iti es ) ... . xx Losses on disposal of assets and retirement of de bt... .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. . xx xx Ded uct : Amo rtiz ati on of bon d p aya ble pr emi um.. .... $xx Increases in current assets (receivables, inv ent ori es, pre pai d exp ens es).. .... .... ... .... xx Decreases in current liabilities (accounts an d no te s pa ya bl e, a cc ru ed lia bil iti es ) ... . xx Gains on disposal of assets and retirement of de bt... .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. . xx xx Ne t ca sh fl ow fr om op er at in g ac ti vi ti es. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. .. . $x x Cost – Estimated Residual Value Estimated Life 16. Cont ribut ion Margi n Rat io = 17. Break- Even Sales (Uni ts) = 18. Sal es (Un its ) = 19. Mar gin of S afe ty = 20. Ope rat ing Lev era ge = 21 . V ar ia nc es = × = × = × = × = – = – 22. = Alternative ROI Computation: ROI = × 23. Capit al Inves tment An alysi s Method s: 1. Metho ds That Igno re Pres ent V alues : A. A vera ge Rate of Re turn Meth od B. Ca sh Pa yba ck Me tho d 2. Metho ds That Us e Prese nt Va lues: A. Net Pr esen t Va lue Met hod B. Inte rnal R ate o f Retu rn Met hod 24. = 25. Prese nt V alue Inde x = 26. = Amount to Be Invested Equal Annual Net Cash Flows Present Value Factor for an Annuity of $1 Total Present Value of Net Cash Flow Amount to Be Invested Estimated Average Annual Income Average Investment Average Rate of Return Sales Invested Assets Income from Operations Sales Income from Operations Invested Assets Rate of Return on Investment (ROI) Applied Factory Overhead Budgeted Factory Overhead for Amount Produced Fixed Factory Overhead Volume Variance Budgeted Factory Overhead for Amount Produced Actual Factory Overhead Variable Factory Overhead Controllable Variance Standard Rate per Hour Actual Hours Worked – Standard Hours Direct Labor Time Variance Actual Hours Worked Actual Rate per Hour – Standard Rate Direct Labor Rate Variance Standard Price per Unit Actual Quantity Used – Standard Quantity Direct Materials Quantity Variance Actual Quantity Used Actual Price per Unit – Standard Price Direct Materials Price Variance Contribution Margin Income from Operations Sales – Sales at Break-Even Point Sales Fixed Costs + Target Profit Unit Contribution Margin Fixed Costs Unit Contribution Margin Sales – Variable Costs Sales 66124_endsh eets_front.qx d 11/12/03 9:20 PM Page C   CARL S. WARREN Professor Emeritus of Accounting University of Georgia, Athens JAMES M. REEVE Professor of Accounting University of Tennessee, Knoxville PHILIP E. FESS Professor Emeritus of Accounting University of Illinois, Champaign-Urbana ACCOUNTING 21 e 66124_frontmatter.qxd 11/13/03 2:41 PM Page i of 00 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
Accounting 21e[1]
 Download or Print 3,901 Reads Info and Rating 
 Category: Uncategorized. Rating: Upload Date: 08/30/2011 Copyright: Attribution Non-commercial Tags: This document has no tags. 
 Flag document for inapproriate content This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
