<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001606" url="http://www.abc-pinewood-derby.com/site_map.php" time="2012-07-12-17:23" support="1" score="0.0006336036707440454" bingtitle="ABC Pinewood Derby Site Directory" webtitle="ABC Pinewood Derby Site Directory">
			<query id="001462" bing-rank="200"/>
	<description>Track Brake - Safely stop your car at the end of the track. Track Timer - This ... Fast Food Pinewood Derby Car - A fun project at a fast food restaurant. Contact Us - We ...</description>
	<body>
		Jul 12 2012 
Everything you need to design and build a car then win your Pinewood Derby race. It&apos;s as easy as ABC!
 
  view shopping cart product catalog pinewood derby home 
 
 
 
 
 ABC Pinewood Derby Site Directory
 You are here: Home »Site Map 
 Products

 Axle Polish -
 The combination of our two step polishing process and special
 formula takes polish technology to a whole new level. The result
 is superior to any other polish available. Instructions Axle Polishing Kit - Sandpaper
 strips of #400 and the hard-to-find #1200 sandpaper. Pinewood Derby Axles -
 Our axles are machined to be smooth, straight and round. Then
 they are nickel plated for a mirror like finish. Axle Guard - A simple device that
 keeps your axles aligned and securely attached to your car. Axle Installer -
 Install the wheels and axles on your car the right way every
 time.. Axle Puller - Removes
 the wheels from your car. Basic Car Building Instructions - A quick guide for beginners. Board Game - Pinewood Racer is a fun game for the whole family. Instructions Body Jig - Drill axle holes in your pinewood derby car. Body Skins - A custom paint job without the paint. Instructions Derby Pinewood Books -
 Three&quot;How To&quot;books for the beginner to the experienced
 racer.
 Pinewood Derby Speed Secrets -
 (book) For beginners and seasoned racers. All the advice
 and tips you need to build the car the brings home the trophy. Pinewood Derby Designs&amp;Patterns - (book) Step-by-step
 instructions for building several pinewood derby car designs. Includes 24
 car templates. Pinewood
 Derby Speed Secrets -
 (download) All the details of what works, and what doesn&apos;t
 and shows you why. 
 Bottom Weights - Steel weights designed to attach to the bottom of your car. Car Accessories -
 Hood scoops, spoilers, engines and more. All designed just for your Pinewood Derby car. Pinewood Derby Car Blocks -
 Your pinewood car will run straight down the track with our precision drilled axle holes. Four different blocks to choose from. Pinewood Designs - Complete guides for building several different pinewood derby cars. Car Eyes - Glue these eyes to your pinewood derby car. The pupils wiggle. Car Kits - Everything you need to build a car in one package.
 Orange Falcon Instructions Orange Nomad Instructions Blue Raven Instructions Red Avenger Instructions 
 Car Parts - Turn your wedge shaped car into a variety of pinewood derby car designs with our plastic parts. Car Photo Gallery - Get some design ideas with these pinewood cars - M1A1 Tank Car Tune Up Kit - A kit including balance scale to weigh your car, stick on weights, stickers, and a book full of information
 about building your car. Instructions Carrying Case - Now you can safely transport and display your Pinewood Derby Car
in this easy to construct“Mobile Garage”. Assembly Instructions Pinewood Derby Completed Cars - Short on time? Let our experts do the work for you. Pinewood Derby Decals - Make your car stand out from the crowd.  Instructions 
 Flames Blue Flames Police / Emergency Military Creepy Pirate NASCAR For Girls Only 
 Derby Dome - Display your car in the Derby Dome. Derby Stop - Makes it easy to hold and display Pinewood Derby or Awana Grand Prix cars on race day. Digital Scale - Accurately weigh your car. Display Stand - A display stand for your car. Can also be used as a paint stand. Down and Derby - Comedy about the Pinewood Derby on DVD Fenders - Give your car a whole new look with fenders. Rear Fenders - For wedge shaped pinewood cars. Graphite Pads - Reduce friction between the wheels and car body. Pine Car Lubricant - Designed for Pinewood Derby cars, there is nothing better. Mud Stick - Add realistic looking mud to your car. Paint - gloss paints in 17 colors selected for best results. Instructions Painted Cars - Just add wheels and axles and you are ready to race. Paint Stand - Holds your car for easy painting.. Pinewood Derby Track - Test your car on our low cost practice
 track. Available in 2 foot sections that can be put together for any length and multiple lanes. Instructions Track Stand - Secure support for our Practice Track. Track Brake - Safely stop your car at the end of the track. Track Timer - This optical timer is designed to be used with our Practice Track. Single lane
 and two lane models are available. Accurate to 0.001 second. Pre-Cut Cars - The basic shape of the car has been cut. All you need to do is sand and paint. Racing Stripes - Several colors to choose from. Easy to apply. Instructions Car Inspection Box - Fast inspection of car dimensions.  Car
 Inspection Box Instructions Rocket Powered Pinewood Derby Car - Watch what happens when a C5 rocket is mounted on a standard Pinewood Derby car. Pinewood Derby Tools - Made just for Pinewood Derby cars, these tools are designed to make your car faster
 Axle Installer - The easy way to install your axles the right way. Axle Press - Make your axles straight and round. Body Tool - Drill precision axle holes. Hub Shaver - Reduce friction between the wheel and axle head. Wheel Roundness Gage - Round wheels are fast wheels. Use this tool to check your wheels. Wheel Shaver - Trim your wheels to eliminate defects. Wheel Mandrel - Polish your wheels the easy way. Wheel Bore Polisher - Polish the part of the wheel that touches the axle. Wheel Alignment Tool - Check several important aspects of your wheels and axles. Rail Rider - Adjust your pinewood derby car&apos;s wheel alignment. The Rail Riding technique Rasps - Three different wood rasps to choose from. Coping Saw - Just the saw needed to shape your car.  Instructions 
 Video - Build the ultimate Pinewood Derby car. Pinewood Derby Weights - Variety of weights to bring your pine car up to the weight limit including our Tungsten
 squares and Wire Weights . Pinewood Derby Wheels - Official BSA Pinewood Derby car wheels that have been matched and trimmed for maximum performance. Wheels for Outlaws - Very fast wheels for unlimited races. Wheel Decals - Easy to apply decals for your wheels. Product Catalog - You can order all of our products from this page. 

 Information

 Frequently asked Questions - Answers to your questions about our products. Design and Building Tips - Basic techniques for building your first car. Speed Tips - The most important things that you should do to make your car faster. How to Manage a Pinewood Derby Race - A step-by-step guide for organizing your Pinewood Derby race. Track Building Tips - A few suggestions and references for building a Pinewood Derby track. Build a Car Stand - A simple car stand can be built with these easy instructions. How to Raise a Front Wheel - A car with a raised front wheel will go faster. Fix a Raised Wheel on your Pinewood Derby Car - This technique will lower a wheel slightly on slotted cars. Paint Wheel Spokes - Use our silver marker to paint the spokes on your wheels. How to Use a Rasp - What is a rasp for and how do you use it? Find out here. How to Use a Coping Saw - Coping saws are a little tricky to use. We give you helpful hints. Pinewood Derby Rules - A typical set of rules as well as some optional rules that you might want to include What is the Pinewood Derby? - The history of the Pinewood Derby. Fast Food Pinewood Derby Car - A fun project at a fast food restaurant. Contact Us - We will answer your questions and solve your problems. 

 Search this Site for:

 Pinewood Derby Car Designs Pinewood Car Templates Pinewood Derby Tips Pine Car Car Pinewood 

 

 
 
Build a Car

 &quot;How To&quot;Books &quot;How To&quot;Video Car Designs Car Blocks Pre-Cut Cars Car Parts Car Kits Car Fenders Painted Cars Completed Cars Tools 
 
Make it Fast

 Axles Axle Polishing Kit Axle Polish Axle Installer Wheels Awana Wheels&amp;Axles Weights Graphite and Oil Tools 
 
Make it Look Great

 Car Decals Wheel Decals Racing Stripes Body Skins Paint Car Eyes Mud Stick Car Accessories 
 
Extras

 Practice Track Car Carrying Case Car Tune Up Kit Digital Scale Pinewood Racer Down and Derby Car Display and Paint Stands Race Management Product Catalog 
 Can&apos;t find what you are looking for? Search our site. 
 
Information

 Home Site Map What is the Pinewood Derby? Pinewood Derby Rules Questions and Answers Car Photo Gallery Shipping and Returns Privacy Notice Pinewood Links Contact Us 
 
How To

 Design and build your Pinewood Derby Car Build a fast Derby Car Run a Pinewood Race Build a Derby Track Build a Car Stand Paint Chrome Wheels Use a Rasp Use a Coping Saw Use Decals 
 
 ABC Pinewood Car
730 73rd Ave NE
Olympia, WA 98506
(360) 459-3002 Please call between 9 am and 6 pm Pacific time
©copyright 2004-2012 ABC Pinewood Car ALL RIGHTS RESERVED
	</body>
</document>
