<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001866" url="http://www.surveyfeedbacks.com/2011_03_01_archive.html" time="2012-07-12-17:39" support="46" score="0.060343550318561805" bingtitle="March 2011 - Survey Feedback" webtitle="March 2011">
			<query id="000168" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="001391" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000583" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="000668" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000574" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000888" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="001390" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="001369" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="001045" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="001209" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="001210" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000262" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="001454" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000992" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="001398" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000417" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="000241" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="001464" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000982" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="001403" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000678" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="000042" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="001214" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="001108" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="001170" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000231" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001180" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="000542" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000730" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="001516" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000930" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000615" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="001055" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="001387" bing-rank="249"/>
			<query id="001201" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000920" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000303" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="000105" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="001399" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000740" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="001495" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000552" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="001404" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="000294" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="001202" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000272" bing-rank="66"/>
	<description>... the Sears Number (Sears #) and Service Order Number ... how long did it take to receive your food? Did you receive your ... Express Group, is the largest Chinese fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		Monday, March 28, 2011 
 
 www.MacaroniGrill.com/Survey - Macaroni Grill Survey 
 Romano’s Macaroni Grill or more popularly known to you as Macaroni Grill is a casual dining restaurant chain offering sumptuous Italian delicacies. Since its inception in 1988, it had always strive to offer you the very best in food and services through its more than 230 restaurants spread in the United States, Canada and Mexico. This endeavor only had led its corporate office in Dallas, Texas, to invite you to share your dining experience in any of its restaurants.

Www.MacaroniGrill.com/Survey is the site, through which you could have participated in its Guest Satisfaction Survey and tell the company about the things you enjoyed as well as those that did not meet your expectation, while dining in any of its outlets. You could have participated in this survey by entering the 12-character Personal Survey Code and as a customer, your feedback was invaluable to the company that would have gone a long way in helping it to improve.

To appreciate your time and effort, at the end of the survey the company had offered you $7 discount on future purchase of two (2) entrees or main courses from any of its outlets. However, the survey has ended as of writing at this time, but may reopen some time in the future. Meanwhile, other Italian restaurant survey include www.OliveGardenSurvey.com .

Survey Website: www.macaronigrill.com/survey Posted by June at 9:36 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: italian restaurant , restaurant survey 
 Thursday, March 24, 2011 
 
 www.CPKSurvey.com - California Pizza Kitchen CPK Survey 
 California Pizza Kitchen provides a variety of authentic California style food to the people living in different regions of the American continent. California Pizza Kitchen have even started operations in countries such as Mexico, India and China. They provide a variety of food items such as Soups and Sandwiches, Salads, Pizzas, Pastas, Desserts and Beverages. Customers can visit their online web portal and place the order after browsing through the various menu items displayed.

It is probably more fun to visit the restaurants itself and dine there with its California theme settings and pizzas fresh from the oven. It is well known for many of its thin crust pizza including the BBQ Chicken Pizza. You can also see the numerous California Pizza Kitchen pizza boxes that has been painted over with different designs hanging on the wall. If you have recently dine at the restaurant, you may have seen a survey invitation printed on your receipt. To measure customer satisfaction level, California Pizza Kitchen have come out with a customer satisfaction survey at CPKSurvey.com. This is similar to survey by other pizzerias such as Pizza Hut which can be found at www.TellPizzaHut.com .

Customers can provide the feedback by reaching the web portal of California Pizza Kitchen located at www.CPKSurvey.com. In the home page of this web site, the customer has to provide the 5 digit code number provided in the survey invitation form. Customers completing the survey are given an automatic entry to the sweepstakes competition. The winners of the sweepstakes competition will take home a gift check worth $500 with them.

 Website Survey: www.cpksurvey.com Posted by June at 8:58 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: pizza hut , restaurant survey 
 www.TellCaribou.com - Tell Caribou Coffee Survey 
 Founded in 1992, Caribou Coffee has steadily risen the ranks and presently is the second largest specialty coffee and espresso retailer in the United States. Headquartered at Brooklyn Center, Minnesota, it offers you the very best in coffee, tea and bakery goods through its more than 415 coffeehouses. It is one of the many retail coffee chain in the US competing with other chains in the coffee category with Starbucks, Pete&apos;s Coffee, Seattle Best, Dunkin Donut and even McDonalds though each targets a different demographics

Www.TellCaribou.com is the site, through which the company wants to listen about your experience that you recently had in one of its outlets.“Caribou Coffee Customer Satisfaction Survey”is the appropriate medium through which you can give your feedback to the company and help it to improve its already existing excellent service. You can participate in this survey by enter the 14-digit survey code and the time in hh: mm format, located next to the word Total, from your receipt. Caribou Coffee values your feedback, greatly and considers it as a gift that will help it to improve, immensely. As a token of appreciation for your time and effort, it provides you a Validation Code at the end of the survey, which you can redeem to enjoy its products during your future visit to any of its outlets.


Like Caribou, other coffee chains like Starbucks and Dunkin Donuts also offers customer satisfaction survey and offer coupons or sweepstakes as part of the incentive for taking the survey. www.MyStarBucksVisit.com and www.TellDunkin.com are the surveys for Starbucks and Dunkin Donuts respectively.



 Survey Website: www.tellcaribou.com Posted by June at 8:47 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: coffee , restaurant survey 
 wwww.MyStarBucksVisit.com - My Starbucks Visit Survey 
 Founded in 1971, Starbucks Corporation or your very own Starbucks is the largest coffeehouse company in the world. Headquartered at Seattle, Washington of the United States, it serves coffee in various flavors along with other snacks to millions of customers in 50 different countries through its more than 17,000 outlets. The first store is located at Pikes Place Market in Seattle and the store still retains the charm and flavor of the original store and still spot the old original Starbucks logo. Starbucks now spot the greener logo and still retain the mermaid.

Www.MyStarBucksVisit.com is the site, through which it attempts to know your experience during your recent visit in one of its 12,000 outlets in the United States and Canada. Here, you will get the opportunity to participate in its survey aimed to collect customers’feedback and share your experience in English, Spanish or French. By entering the Customer Code that you will find at the bottom of your receipt, you can start the survey and critically analyze its products and service, which will help the company to make your future visits even more pleasant and enjoyable. As a token of appreciation for your effort and time, Starbucks will provide a code at the end of the survey, which you can redeem for your favorite beverage during your next visit in any of its outlets.

In addition, they also have a monthly sweepstakes for participants of My Starbucks Visit Survey. If you are lucky, you can be one of its few selected customers and receive an entry in its monthly sweepstakes, for every completed survey, where you will have the opportunity to be among ten (10) monthly winners and win $1,000 in check.


 Website: www.mystarbucksvisit.com Posted by June at 8:40 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: coffee , restaurant survey 
 Tuesday, March 22, 2011 
 
 www.SearsHomeServices.com/Feedback - Sears Home Services Feedback 
 www.SearsHomeServices.com/Feedback is the survey website for Sears Home Services. Sears, Roebuck and Co. or Sears is an American chain of department stores. Founded in 1886 and headquartered at Hoffman Estates, Illinois, it is the subsidiary of Sears Holdings Corporation and presently is the largest retailer in the United States.

Www.SearsHomeServices.com/Feedback is the site through which Sears aims to understand your satisfaction level about the services provided by its division, Sears Home Services. This division offers spare parts and repair services for most of your home appliances, consumer electronics, accessories for your lawn and garden equipment and many more. Through this site, you can participate in the“Sears Home Services Survey”by entering the Sears Number (Sears #) and Service Order Number (Service Order #) from your service receipt and rate the services of its Blue Crew on a scale of 5; 1 being‘extremely dissatisfied’and 5 being‘extremely satisfied’. Apart form participating in this survey, you can use this site to download and print coupons, which you can utilize to save money on future services from Sears Home Services. For the main Sears survey for its general retail store, it can be found at www.SearsFeedback.com . SearsHomeServices.com/Feedback is specifically designed for customers using Sears Home Services.

 Survey website: www.searshomeservices.com/feedback Posted by June at 10:15 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: retail survey 
 Monday, March 21, 2011 
 
 www.DIY.com/Feedback - DIY Feedback Survey 
 B&amp;Q Plc is a British retailer and is the second largest one in entire Europe for Do it yourself or DIY home improvement tools and supplies. Founded in 1969, it is a subsidiary of Kingfisher Plc and is currently headquartered at East Leigh, East Leigh borough of England.

Www.Diy.com/Feedback is the website through which it wants to gather your feedback with regards toyour recent shopping experience in one of its more than 373 stores. For this purpose, it might send you an invitation to participate in its Customer Satisfaction Survey. To appreciate your effort and time for completing the survey, it will award you an entry, for each completed survey, to its“Customer Satisfaction Survey”sweepstakes, which is running throughout each month until the end of the promotion period. This sweepstakes period is again divided into daily sweepstakes, running between 12:00:01 a.m. to 11:59:59 p.m., where everyday you will have ten (10) opportunities to win $1,000; 1,000GBP; CAD$1,000 or 1,000 Euros, depending on your country of residence and a 4GB iPod Nano. The equivalent of the American survey
 is found at www.homedepot.com/opinion and www.lowes.iwrsurvey.com .

After completely filling up an online Sweepstakes form, you can participate in this survey, either by entering the 6-digit alphanumeric number of your Survey Invitation Card or by entering the Store Number, Date&amp;Time of your visit, Total on Receipt and 10-digit Transaction Code from your receipt. You can even enter this sweepstakes after completing the SMS survey, by sending your answers through text messages to the number provided in the Invitation instruction. However, if you do not want to purchase anything and have nothing to share with the company, but want to participate in this sweepstakes only, you can do so by sending your handwritten details to their mail in address.L5N 2X4.

 Website Survey: www.diy.com/feedback Posted by June at 11:32 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: home depot , retail survey 
 www.TalkToWendys.com - Talk to Wendys Survey 
 Wendys has been one of the long time quality providers of America&apos;s old fashioned Hamburgers and Old fashioned salad combos. Some of the other famous recipes provided by Wendys include Fish Fillet, Chicken Sandwiches, Stuffed Baked Potatoes, Fries, Frosties and Beverages. They give a lot of focus with respect to the quality of customer service provided and also with respect to the quality of the food items provided. In this direction, Wendys have come up with a customer feedback survey, for getting the responses from their customers.

For providing the feedback, the customers have to enter the portal www.TalkToWendys.com. In the home page of this feedback portal, the customer has the option of providing the feedback in English, Spanish and French. After selecting the appropriate language by selecting the &quot;Continue&quot; button, the customers can start entering the personal information and submit the details. To participate, you need your Wendys receipt and enter in the 8 digit store number, the purchase date, the amount purchased and your email address. You need to enter in a valid email address so you can receive the $1 coupon if you choose to sign up with Wendys. One can also sign up in order to use the online ordering services provided by Wendys. Customers will get a $1 coupon after signing up as a member with Wendys

 Website: www.talktowendys.com Posted by June at 11:26 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: american restaurant , restaurant survey 
 www.TellRedRobin.com - Tell Red Robin Survey 
 Headquartered at Greenwood Village, Colorado, Red Robin Gourmet Burger, Inc. or popularly known as Red Robin had been satisfying your taste buds with the choicest of delicacies since its inception in 1969. To innovate and improve further, this casual dining restaurant chain of the United States, wants to know your dining experience in one of its restaurants through a Guest Satisfaction Survey.

Www.TellRedRobin.com is the site where you need to log in to participate in this survey. Either enter the details like Store Telephone Number, Date&amp;Time of Visit and Total Amount from your Receipt or enter the 10-digit Certificate Number from your Invitation Card to participate in this survey. Depending on the mode of invitation, you can enter the details from any one of these two and take the survey, either in English or in Spanish. Your feedback will not only help the company to make your every visit, exceptional, but will also help you to earn an entry in the“Customer Satisfaction Survey”sweepstakes.

Every time you provide a feedback to the company, you secure ten (10) separate entries in this sweepstakes that Red Robin had brought in association with Empathica, Inc. Instead of logging on to this site, if you wish, you can complete this survey over telephone, by calling up 1-866-725-6855 and can even complete an SMS survey by text messaging you answers to the number provided in your Invitation instructions. However, if you do not have anything to share with the company and want to participate in this sweepstakes without making a purchase, you can do so by sending your hand-written details to:

&lt;Month&gt;Mail-In Entry
 c/o Empathica Inc. Customer Satisfaction Survey Sweepstakes
c/o Name of Participating Client
511 Avenue of the Americas, #4
New York, NY 10011.

If you are residing in Canada or United Kingdom, you can visit this site to get the respective address for sending your mails.

No matter whichever method you choose to enter this sweepstakes, please take out some time everyday, since this is a series of sweepstakes and is running throughout the month of March 2011. You can enter everyday between 12:00:01 a.m. and 11:59:59 p.m. and enjoy the opportunity to win $1,000 or equivalent in cash and an 8GB iPod Nano.

 Survey Website: www.tellredrobin.com Posted by June at 11:21 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: american restaurant , restaurant survey 
 Sunday, March 20, 2011 
 
 www.TellGameStop.com - Tell GameStop Survey 
 GameStop is a leading provider of video games to the different types of popular gaming systems available in the market. Game stop has a wide collection of games that are played on Gaming systems such as Sony Play Station, Microsoft Xbox and Nintendo&apos;s 3DS games and Wii games. They provide excellent online services to their customers as well as in their numerous retail location. In order to get the feedback of the customer who have purchased these products, they have tied with an online survey provider.

Customers have to follow the link www.TellGameStop.com for providing the feedback. Customers have to provide the feedback number at the home page of this portal to start giving the feedback. The feedback number can be found at the bottom of the sales receipt. You will also need 2 other information that is found right under the date and time stamp on the receipt. To participate in the Tell Gamestop sweepstakes survey, you must be 18 or older.


Customers who complete the survey are also given a free entry to the sweepstakes competition. The entries for this sweepstakes competition is limited to one household each month, but you can participate monthly. There will be 10 winners announced after the the lucky draw and each and every winner will take a home $500 GameStop gift card. If you are a GameStop fan or a video games enthusiast, a $500 GameStop gift card will buy or rent you a lot of games to play for quite some time.
   
 Survey Website: www.tellgamestop.com Posted by June at 12:20 PM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: retail survey 
 www.SportsAuthorityFeedback.com - Sports Authority Feedback Survey 
 SportsAuthority Inc is a Colorado based leading provider of sports goods to the various states across U.S.A. They have been in this business for more than 100 years providing quality sports goods to the people of the country. They provide the option of ordering the goods online for their customers. Sports Authority Inc has come out with a system to get the customer feedback regarding the quality of services and the quality of products provided by them.

Customers have to reach the online web portal by following the link www.SportsAuthorityFeedback.com. In the landing page of this site, the customer has to provide the survey invite number that is provided in the sales receipt given by them

In the sales receipt , this invite code is available at the top of the receipt. The invite code is rather long and so you should enter it carefully. Customers who complete this survey are eligible for $10 discount coupon on the purchases made above $50. They have to make use of the coupon offer within one week from the time of completing the survey.

There may also be an invitation at the bottom of the receipt for you to go to www.sportsauthority.com/save to subscribe to its mailing lists to get another $10 off coupon.

The Sports Authority Feedback survey is quite similar to other surveys provided by other sports and outdoor equipment retailers such as Cabelas and Dicks Sporting Goods. The survey for these Cabelas and Dicks Sporting Goods can be found at www.cabelas.com/storesurvey and www.dickssportinggoods.com/feedback  
 

 Survey website: www.sportsauthorityfeedback.com Posted by June at 11:07 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: retail survey 
 www.DicksSportingGoods.com/Feedback - Dicks Sporting Goods Feedback 
 Dicks Sporting Goods is one of the quality providers of sports goods and equipments to the American public for more than 100 years. They have their retail stores located at different parts of the country. They give high priority to the quality of service provided to their customers. In order to get the inputs from their customers, they have come up with a feedback system. In this feedback system, customers of Dick Sporting goods have to enter the portal www.DicksSportingGoods.com/Feedback for providing the feedback. A similar type of survey that is more outdoors related and by Cabelas store is found at www.cabelas.com/storesurvey 

In the landing page of this portal, customer has to provide information regarding the Store Number, Register number, Transaction number, Transaction date and Total purchase amount to start the survey. The example receipt image below will show you how to locate the different items required since they are in a stirng of number and may not be evident where the store number and register numbers may be. All these details are available in the sales receipt given by Dick Sporting Goods. Customers participating in the survey can then take home a $10 coupon which can be redeemed when the customer makes a purchase for more than $50 at the sports outlet.



 

 Survey Website: www.dickssportinggoods.com/feedback Posted by June at 10:54 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: retail survey 
 www.PaneraListens.com - Panera Listens Survey 
 Panera Bread is a chain of bakery-café casual restaurants in the United States and Canada that offers you a wide variety in breads, sandwiches, soups, salads and other bakery items through its more than 1,360 outlets. Since its inception in 1981, its primary focus had been on customer satisfaction and to know your recent dining experience, it invites you to participate in its Customer Experience Survey.

Www.PaneraListens.com is the site through which you can participate in this survey by entering the Panera bakery-café number that is located at the top of your receipt. Your feedback will help the company, tremendously, to iron out the rough edges and improve its products and services. As a token of appreciation, for every completed survey, it will award you an entry in the“Panera Bread and Paradise Bakery&amp;Café, Inc. Customer Survey”sweepstakes. If you complete a survey for any of its outlets in Colorado, it will award you an entry in the“Panera Bread and Phoenix Cafes Customer Survey”sweepstakes.

Both these sweepstakes runs from 12:01 a.m. on 1st March 2011 till 11:59 p.m. on 31st March 2011 and every month till the end of the survey promotion period. You can enter this sweepstakes by logging on to this site and completing the survey within 48-hours from the date of your purchase. However, to enter either the Paradise or the Phoenix contest, you can log on to www.paradiselistens.com. You can even enter this sweepstakes by completing this survey, over phone, by calling up 1-800-699-0130 and for Paradise and Phoenix, you can call up 1-877-573-0141. However, if you do not wish to make a purchase and thereby do not want to share your feedback and still want to enter this sweepstakes, you can do so by sending your hand-written details to:

Panera Bread and Paradise Cafes Customer Survey Sweepstakes,
The Sweepstakes Center,
P.O. Box 16349
Rochester, NY 14616.

Or

Panera Bread and Phoenix Cafes Customer Survey Sweepstakes,
The Sweepstakes Center,
P.O. Box 16349
Rochester, NY 14616.

No matter whichever method you choose to enter, you may be the lucky winner to win the Grand Prize of $2,000, which will be decided through the drawing of all eligible sweepstakes entries, on or about the middle of each month.



 Link: www.paneralistens.com Posted by June at 10:45 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: american restaurant , restaurant survey 
 Saturday, March 19, 2011 
 
 www.GeekSquadCares.com - Geek Squad Cares Survey 
 Best Buy is one the top rated electronic goods retailer in U.S and has an excellent online service features. The users can order the electronic goods through the Best Buy online portal and the product will be delivered to the person&apos;s residence. Shipping of the ordered electronic products will be taken care by Best Buy. Geek Squad is a subsidiary of Best Buy and also has many electronic stores across America. Yes, even Geeks care and they care about your experience with their services, help with technical support for your electronics and computers and installation they may have done for you.

As a part of getting feedback from the customer with respect to the quality of services provided by Best Buy and its affiliates at the retail store and also the quality of services provided through online ordering. The users have to reach the feedback of portal of Best Buy by following the portal www.GeekSquadcares.com and in the home page of this portal, they have to select the Language in which the feedback will be provided(English/Spanish). This is separate from another survey for its main stores that Best Buy runs at www.bestbuycares.com .

After providing the feedback, the users also get an opportunity to be a part of the Lucky draw competition announced by Best Buy. There are actually two promotional periods for this Lucky draw contest. The first promotional period runs from February 27th 2011 till May 26th 2011 and the second promotional period runs from May 29th 2011 to August 27th 2011. You an also check for a list of past winners on the site.

 Survey Website: www.geeksquadcares.com Posted by June at 10:41 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: best buy , retail survey 
 www.TellJamba.com - Tell Jamba Juice Survey 
 TellJamba.com is the survey website by Jamba Juice to tell them about your recent customer experience at one of their location. Jamba Juice is a chain of restaurants, which provides you blended, chilled and sweetened beverages in canned cases that contain chocolate. These beverages popularly known as smoothies are prepared from fresh fruits and/or vegetables. Jamba Juice was founded in 1990 and is presently headquartered at Emeryville, California of the United States. They also have offer additional stuff such as immunity boost to these smoothies. If you just need fresh juice like a fresh orange juice, it is available too.

Www.TellJamba.com is the site through which the company aims to reach its customers, like you, and wants to know your dining experience in one of its more than 700 outlets. If you had recently been to any of its outlets to taste the smoothies, you can participate in its Guest Satisfaction Survey by entering the 15-digit survey code, located at the bottom of your receipt. You can participate either in English or in Spanish and tell the company about what you had liked and/or disliked about its products and services.

The company gives utmost importance to your views, since these will help it to improve its standards and as a token of appreciation, at the end of the survey it provides you a discount coupon, which you can utilize during your future visit to any of its outlets.

This is another survey by Service Management Group. A survey which we most recently covered is www.RiteAid.com/PharmacySurvey which is also powered by SMG.


 Survey Website: www.telljamba.com Posted by June at 10:16 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: restaurant survey 
 www.RiteAid.com/PharmacySurvey - RiteAid Pharmacy Survey 
 Founded in 1962, Rite Aid Corporation or more popularly known as Rite Aid Pharmacy is the third-largest drugstore chain in the United States. It is presently headquartered at East Pennsboro Township, Pennsylvania and provides you the shopping convenience of almost all types of drugs and medicines through its more than 4,780 stores.

Www.RiteAid.com/PharmacySurvey is the site through which the company encourages you to participate in its Customer Satisfaction Survey. Through this survey, you can provide an insight to the company about your shopping experience in one of its stores and your expectation from it. You can participate in this survey by filling up the 16-digit code that you will find, printed on the front of your receipt. Your feedback will help the company in its constant endeavor for excellence and aim for providing unmatched pharmacy experience, to you, through wide range of every day products and services.

To appreciate your initiative, it provides you a coupon at the end of the survey. You can utilize this coupon in any of its stores to avail a discount of $15 on its products and services, within 14 days of completing the survey. However, before entering the survey, you should make sure that your computer is attached to a printer to take a printout of this coupon, since you neither can save this coupon nor can e-mail it for printing in future.

This is another survey that is powered by the Service Management Group which also helps several other retail chains conduct surveys with their customers. Other related surveys for pharmacy chains include www.walgreensfeedback.com which takes the form of a sweepstakes survey versus a coupon. We think consumers like a coupon survey since everyone is a winner.

 Website Survey: www.riteaid.com/pharmacysurvey Posted by June at 9:46 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: retail survey 
 Friday, March 18, 2011 
 
 www.DollarTreeFeedback.com - Dollar Tree Feedback 
 Dollar Tree, Inc. or Dollar Tree is a chain of discount variety stores that provides you any item for $1 or less through it over 4,000 outlets. Founded in 1986, it is currently headquartered at Chesapeake, Virginia of the United States.

Www.DollarTreeFeedback.com is the site, through which it aims to understand your satisfaction level during shopping at any of its outlets. You can participate in its Customer Satisfaction Survey by entering the Store Number, Total Amount Spent, Date and Time of Visit from your receipt and give your feedback. The image below will help you to locate the information needed. This will help the company to improve its standard and give you a completely satisfying shopping experience in future.

In appreciation of your time and effort, the company provides you an entry in its“Customer Satisfaction Survey”sweepstakes that it has brought in association with Empathica, Inc. You can enter this sweepstakes by completing a survey through Www.DollarTreeFeedback.com, through Www.DealsFeedback.com or by completing a survey over telephone by calling up 1-866-514-1935 or 1-866-399-6370. You can even complete an SMS survey by sending your answers through text messages to the number provided in your Invitation instruction and earn an entry in this sweepstakes. This is quite similar to www.DollarGeneralSurvey.com which is another retail chain specializing in low priced discounted items.

 This sweepstakes runs each month until the end of promotion and you can enter everyday between 12:00:01 a.m. to 11:59:59 p.m. to have an opportunity to win some fabulous prizes through daily draw of all eligible sweepstakes entries.

However, if you wish to enter this contest only and do not want to either spend money on purchases or participate in the survey, you can do so by sending your hand-written details to:

&lt;Month&gt;Mail-In Entry
c/o Empathica Inc. Customer Satisfaction Survey Sweepstakes
c/o Name of Participating Client
511 Avenue of the Americas, #40
New York, NY10011.

Please remember to replace&lt;Month&gt;with the actual month of the sweepstakes in which you want to participate in. If you happen to reside in Canada or United Kingdom, you can visit this site for the addresses for sending the mails.

Here, you will get the opportunity to win a 4GB iPod Nano and ten (10) chances to win $1,000 or equivalent amount, on everyday basis.

 Survey Website: www.dollartreefeedback.com Posted by June at 1:46 PM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: retail survey 
 www.Cabelas.com/StoreSurvey - Cabelas Store Survey 
 Founded in 1961 and headquartered at Sidney, Nebraska of the United States, Cabela’s Retail, Inc. or Cabela’s is a direct marketer and retailer of specialty items for hunting, fishing, camping and other outdoor recreation activities. If you are one of its few million satisfied customers or one of the few not so satisfied ones, here is your opportunity to express your views.

 Www.Cabelas.com/StoreSurvey is the site for entering its customer satisfaction survey and expressing your likes/dislikes about its products and services. The first page of the survey will ask you the state as to where you had visited one of its stores, each of which resembles a cavern. If you had purchased anything, you can choose the appropriate option, here and then by entering the 17-digit alphanumeric code (located just below the bar code of your receipt and date of purchase) you can participate in this survey. As indicataed on the receipt, do not use the stars when you are entering the receipt number.

If you had been just looking around then, too, you can enter this survey by entering the 11-digit alphanumeric code from the handout or business card that you had received inside the store. If you cannot find the code, you can enter the survey code‘CABELAS’to participate in this survey. If you are thinking whether all this effort is worth it or not, remain rest assured, Cabela’s, like any top organization in the world, gives paramount importance to its customers’feedback and strives to make changes, wherever necessary.

 Survey Website: www.cabelas.com/storesurvey Posted by June at 1:39 PM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: retail survey 
 www.BajaFreshSurvey.com - Baja Fresh Survey 
 If ever you had felt your taste buds quivering at the prospect of tasting fresh chicken, steak, shrimp, etc. prepared in Mexican style, Baja Fresh Mexican Grill is the place for you to be in. Since its inception in 1990, it had been constantly striving to provide you, through its chain of restaurants, the best food quality with high nutritious value in a clean and cheerful environment.

Www.BajaFreshSurvey.com is the site through which Baja Fresh, headquartered at Cypress, California of the United States, aims to gather its customers’feedback to understand their satisfaction level and its standing in their minds. If you had recently enjoyed dining or even otherwise, in one of its more than 256 restaurants, you can participate in its customer satisfaction survey and let the company know about your experience.

Enter the store number that is located either below the web address of the survey or to the right of Baja Fresh location’s name at the top and you are on your way to express your views. The company is so committed in meeting all expectations and maintaining a long lasting impression on its customers’minds that it provides you a redemption code at the end of the survey, in appreciation of your time and effort. You can write this code down on your receipt to avail a discount of $2 on its food items during your future visit in any of its restaurants. Below are samples of questions I had to go through to get my redemption code for the offer on the receipt. The overall survey took about 10 minutes to complete.

When did you dine with us?

Please tell us how you dined with us.

How often do you visit Baja Fresh in the course of a month?

Considering the volume of customers, were you greeted promptly?

What food item did you order for yourself?

From the time you placed your order, about how long did it take to receive your food?

Did you receive your order exactly as specified?

Please rate the overall service you received.

Please rate your overall satisfaction with your most recent experience at Baja Fresh.

Rate the menu knowledge of your server.

Please rate the cleanliness of the restaurant.

Rate the quality of your meal.


 Website Survey: www.bajafreshsurvey.com Posted by June at 1:29 PM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: mexican restaurant , restaurant survey 
 Wednesday, March 16, 2011 
 
 www.BrueggersSurvey.com - Brueggers Survey 
 If you have recently tasted and loved the water-boiled bagels, a specialty item of Bruegger’s, tell the company about it. If your experience had not been that great and refreshing about bagels or sandwiches, salads, wraps, etc., please let the company know about it, too.

Www.BrueggersSurvey.com is the site, where you will find its Guest Satisfaction Survey. Bruegger’s, owned and operated by Bruegger’s Enterprises, Inc. had been providing you quality food and service, since its inception in 1983. Currently headquartered at Burlington, Vermont of the United States, it aims to understand your needs and satisfaction level through this survey.

By entering the 13-digit survey code that you will find at the middle of your survey invitation, you can participate in this survey. Your candid feedback will help the company to understand, what it is doing good and where it needs improvement. To appreciate your effort and time, Bruegger’s will provide you a $2 coupon at the end of the survey. You can use it to avail discount on food and beverages on your future visit to any of its nearly 300 restaurants.

If you have tried the freshly baked bagels at Brueggers, you may also be interested in other food stuff with a whole in the center such as freshly baked Donuts. You can find such survey everywhere and one of the more common survey is the survey by Dunkin Donut which can be found at www.TellDunkin.com .

Brueggers Survey is powered by the Service Management Group. 

 Website Survey: www.brueggerssurvey.com Posted by June at 10:24 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: restaurant survey 
 www.ACMEListens.com - ACME Listens Survey 
 A CME is one the largest retailers of fresh vegetables and fruits. In addition to the vegetables, they also provide catering services, bakery products, deli products and pharmacy products. They provide excellent online services to their customers. Through their web portal, they provide information on the latest discount offers, exclusive email offers and the facility for the customers to order the food products online. Acme has a separate portal for getting the user feedback. The users have to reach the portal www.AcmeListens.com and start providing the feedback. This portal is quite similar to other grocery store survey such as www.tellkroger.com .

In the landing page of the portal, the users have to click the &quot;Enter Survey&quot; button and then enter the confirmation code provided in the receipt.Customers participating in the survey get a direct entry into a sweepstakes competition. There is a lucky draw happening every week and the 3 lucky winner takes home a $100 gift card each. This sweepstakes entry is open till September 12th 2011. Please be sure to complete the survey within 3 days of getting the receipt.


 

 Website Survey: www.acmelistens.com Posted by June at 10:11 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: grocery survey 
 Tuesday, March 15, 2011 
 
 www.CubListens.com - Cub Listens Survey 
 Cub Foods, Inc. or Cub is an American chain of grocery stores that provides you shopping convenience for everyday necessities. Founded in 1968, it is owned and operated by SuperValu, Inc. and is currently headquartered at Stillwater, Minnesota of the United States. If you had recently shopped from one of its 73 outlets, here is your opportunity to let the company know about your shopping experience.

Www.CubListens.com is the site, where you can log on and provide your feedback to the company through its Guest Satisfaction Survey. You can participate in this survey, either in English or in Spanish, by filling up the security Captcha and the 16-digit code from your receipt with an example image shown to the right. You should complete this survey within 3 days of the receipt date and give a very candid feedback about what you liked/disliked, while shopping in one of its stores.

In appreciation of your time and effort for giving your views, Cub Foods will enter you into its weekly draw sweepstakes, where you can win a $100 worth of Cub Foods Gift Card.

 Survey Website: www.cublistens.com Posted by June at 3:01 PM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: grocery survey 
 www.Lowes.IWRSurvey.com - Lowes Survey 
 Lowe’s Companies, Inc. or Lowe’s is a chain of retail stores for home improvement products and appliances. Founded in 1946, it is currently headquartered at Mooresville, North Carolina of the United States and serves over 14 million customers every week, through its more than 1,700 outlets.

Www.Lowes.IwrSurvey.com is the site, through which the company invites you to participate in its Customer Satisfaction Survey and share your shopping experience in any of its outlets. Your candid feedback will help the company to improve the standard of its products and services that will best suit the needs of all its customers. You can participate in this survey by entering the Date and Time of Visit, Total Amount Spent and Receipt ID Number from your receipt. The image on the right will show you where some of this information is located on the receipt. To appreciate your effort, the company will award you an entry in the“Lowe’s Home Improvement Warehouse 2011/2012 Customer Satisfaction Survey”sweepstakes, for every completed survey. A similar survey from another big retail home improvement chain is www.homedepot.com/opinion for Home Depot.

This contest starts at 12:01 a.m. on 1st February 2011 and ends at 11:59 p.m. on 31st January 2012 and has four (4) quarterly entry periods. The Entry Periods for the four (4) quarters are from 1st February 2011 to 30th April 2011, 1st May 2011 to 31st July 2011, 1st August 2011 to 31st October 2011 and 1st November 2011 to 31st January 2012. The drawing of all eligible sweepstakes entries will happen on or about the next day of the completion of Entry Period for the sweepstakes for that particular quarter.

You can enter this contest, once every week, during any particular quarterly Entry Period. You can visit this site, complete the survey within 7-days of the receipt date and enter this contest. However, if you want to opt out of the survey by not going for a purchase, you can do so and can still enter this contest by sending your hand-written details to:

Lowe’s Sweepstakes
P.O. Box 268,
Findlay, Ohio 45839.

Therefore, no matter whichever method of entry you choose, please try to enter this contest the maximum number of times possible, since there are four (4) Grand Prizes, one (1) each for every quarter, to be won. Each Grand Prize consists of $5,000 worth of Lowe’s Gift Card, which you can redeem at all Lowe’s retail stores.

 Website Survey: www.lowes.iwrsurvey.com Posted by June at 2:57 PM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: home depot , retail survey 
 www.BostQ.com - Boston Market Survey 
 Boston Market was founded in 1985 and headquartered at Golden, Colorado, Boston Market Corporation or simply Boston market is an American chain of casual fast food restaurants. Owned by Sun Capital Partners, Boston Market offers you its specialty item, rotisserie chicken along with many varieties of side dishes, through its chain of more than 530 restaurants.

Www.Bostq.com is the site, where you can log on and express your liking and disliking about the quality of Boston Market food and service that you had experienced in one of your recent visits to any of its outlets. You can voice your appreciation or grievance through participation in its Customer Satisfaction Survey. By entering the Store Number, Ticket Number and Date from your receipt, you not only become eligible for participating in this survey but can also enter the“Customer Satisfaction Survey”sweepstakes, which it had brought in association with Empathica, Inc. Similar restaurants that sells chicken includes www.TellPopeyes.com ; (Popeyes Restaurant) and www.OpinionPort.com/YUM (for Kentucky Fried Chicken)

This contest runs throughout the month of March 2011 and has everyday drawings of all eligible sweepstakes entries between 12:00:01 a.m. and 11:59:59 p.m. You can enter this contest by completing the survey formalities either through this site or by calling up the telephone number: 1-888-890-1422. However, you can choose to enter this contest, without making a purchase and/or participating in the survey, by sending your hand-written details to and be sure to change the&lt;Month&gt;tag to the month you are participating in:

&lt;Month&gt;Mail-In Entry
c/o Empathica Inc. Customer Satisfaction Survey Sweepstakes
c/o Name of Participating Client
511 Avenue of the Americas, #40
New York, NY 10011.

If you reside in Canada or United Kingdom, you too, can participate through this process; however, please visit the site for complete address.

Whichever entry method you opt for, you stand a very good chance of winning $1,000 or equivalent in cash and an 8GB iPod Nano. These prizes are there on everyday basis; hence, the more number of times you enter this contest, the brighter you chances become for winning.


 Survey Website: www.bostq.com Posted by June at 10:47 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: american restaurant , restaurant survey 
 Monday, March 14, 2011 
 
 www.AutoZoneCares.com - AutoZone Cares Sweepstakes 
 If you had always remained grateful to Auto Zone, Inc or popularly known as Auto Zone, for the spare parts and accessories for your dream car, here is your opportunity to express so. Not so much delighted with its products and services; you can voice that, too.

Www.AutozoneCares.com is the site through which Auto Zone, which had been retailing and distributing automotive spare parts and accessories since 1979 and is headquartered at Memphis, Tennessee of the United States, wants to have a feel of its customers’satisfaction level. Here, it invites you to share your recent shopping experience in one of its more than 4,000 outlets in America, Puerto Rico or Mexico, either in English or in Spanish.

By entering the 17-digit Reference Number, located at the bottom of your receipt and participating in its customer satisfaction survey, you not only can expect its improved services but also can earn an entry in the“AutoZone Spring 2011 Customer Satisfaction”sweepstakes. If you are interested in other surveys, check out surveys such as www.dollargeneralsurvey.com , www.bestbuycares.com and www.kmartfeedback.com .

This contest runs from 12:00 a.m. on 1st March 2011 till 11:59 p.m. on 31st May 2011 and you can enter, if your receipt contains an invitation for participation in the survey. You can also enter this contest by selecting your state, entering the printed reference number of your receipt, completing the survey and filling up the official entry form with your necessary details. However, if you choose enter this contest by not purchasing anything and skipping participation in the survey, you can do so by sending your hand-written details to:

“AutoZone CS Spring 2011 Sweepstakes”,
90 Rockwood Place, Rochester,
New York 14610.

No matter, whichever entry method you opt for, you should definitely try it, since the lucky winner will receive $10,000 in check as Grand Prize, which will be decided through drawing of all eligible sweepstakes entries, on or about 21st June 2011.



 Survey Website: www.autozonecares.com Posted by June at 10:19 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: car survey 
 www.AlbertsonsListens.com - Albertsons Listens Survey 
 New Albertsons, Inc. or simply Albertsons is a supermarket retailer that provides you various types of necessary goods through its more than 460 grocery stores. Founded in 1939 and headquartered at Boise, Idaho of the United States, it is a subsidiary of SuperValu and aims to offer you the very best in products and services.

Www.AlbertsonsListens.com is the site, where you can log on and let the company know, whether it is living up to its potential or not. On this site, after filling up a security Captcha and entering the 16-digit code of your receipt, you can participate in the company’s customer satisfaction survey and express your views. Please note that you need to take the survey within 3 days for the code to be valid. The company, on its part, encourages you to participate in this survey, either in English or in Spanish and rewards you by providing opportunity to enter its“Survey Sweepstakes”for each completed one. This contest runs from 12:00:01 a.m. on 14th June 2010 till 11:59:59 p.m. on 3rd September 2011 and has weekly drawings of all eligible entries for the particular week.

You can enter this sweepstakes, if you are invited by the company to enter its survey and then enter your basic details, after you make a purchase from one of its participating outlets. You can even enter, if you receive an invitation from the company to fill up the survey and necessary details, without making a purchase. However, if you wish to enter this contest without either purchasing anything and or participating in the survey, you can do so by sending your hand-written details to:

Albertsons“Survey Sweepstakes”,
625 Panorama Trail (Building 2, Suite 100),
Rochester, NY 14625-2437.

Whichever way and week/weeks you choose to enter; you can have a chance of winning one (1) of the nine (9) prizes of that particular week, each consisting of a $100 worth of Albertsons Gift Card.
   
 Grocery Survey Website: www.albertsonslistens.com Posted by June at 9:58 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: grocery survey 
 www.CarrabbasListens.com - Carrabbas Listens Survey 
 Owned and operated by OSI Restaurant Partners, LLC, Carrabbas Italian Grill is a chain of Italian restaurants, which had been mesmerizing you with the finest Italian delicacies since its inception in 1986. Headquartered at Tampa, Florida of the United States, its widely popular dishes like Chicken Bryan that not only satiates the taste buds of millions of customers, like you, but also proves to be healthy and free of gluten. Besides owning Carrabbas Italian Grill, OSI Restaurant Partners also owns other well known brands include Outback ( www.telloutback.com ), BoneFish Grill ( www.bonefishexperience.com ), Flemings and Roy.

 www.Carrabbaslistens.com is the site through which it wants to reach you and know your latest dining experience in one of its more than 200 restaurants. It is on a constant endeavor to improve the ambiance inside each of its restaurants, the service provided to its customers and the quality of its food. By entering the 15-digit code located at the middle of your receipt, you can participate in this survey and express your opinion about whether the company is successful in meeting its goals or not. To appreciate your feedback, the company does not give just a penny for your thought; rather it awards you an entry in the related sweepstakes, where you can have a chance to win $1,000 as prize.

 Website Survey: www.carrabbaslistens.com Posted by June at 9:46 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: italian restaurant , restaurant survey 
 www.BobEvans.com/Feedback - Bob Evans Feedback Survey 
 Www.BobEvans.com/Feedback is the site, where you can log on to participate in the Bob Evans Guest satisfaction survey. The company randomly chooses its customers to provide feedback and if your receipt contains the 9-digit survey code, you are one of the randomly chosen customer to share your experience. Bob Evans gives paramount importance to your views and uses this to evaluate the performance of its management team, bring necessary changes in the food quality and for overall improvement of its services, which will further satisfy you in future. As a token of appreciation for your valuable time, it provides you a validation code at the end of the survey, which you can utilize to get certain benefits on your next visit to one of the Bob Evans Restaurants.

Bob Evans Restaurants incorporated as Bob Evans Farms, Inc. in 1953, is a chain of American restaurants that specializes in food items having the flavor and quality of homemade food. If, all these years, the company has provided you the taste of homemade food, now is your opportunity to express your views and let it know about your experience.

 Website Survey: www.bobevans.com/feedback Posted by June at 9:39 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: american restaurant , restaurant survey 
 www.BestBuyCanadaCares.ca - Best Buy Canada Survey 
 Best Buy Co., Inc. or popularly known as Best Buy to you, is a specialty retailer of consumer electronics in the United States. However, it had spread its wings and has telling presence in other countries too; Canada being one such country. If you reside in Canada and are a frequent visitor to one or more of its stores, you are best equipped to provide judgment regarding its products and services.

Www.BestBuyCanadaCares.ca is the site through which, it had aimed to know your shopping experience, throughout 2008. As a true patron of the company, you must have provided your feedback either in English or in French, by participating in its Customer Satisfaction Survey. Best Buy always values its true patrons and to appreciate your time and effort, it had awarded you an entry to the“Best Buy Canada Customer satisfaction”sweepstakes, for every completed survey.

This contest, which ran from 12:00:01 a.m. on 24th January 2008 till 11:59:59 p.m. on 31st December 2008, had provided you the opportunity of entering once, every month during the contest period. The survey sweepstakes is over for Best Buy Canada, but for residents of US, you can still visit www.BestBuyCares.com On your part, you had to only enter the codes in Groups A, B and C, carefully from your receipt and had to remember that these codes, which were required for participation in the survey, were valid for 30 days from the date of your receipt.

All the eligible entries for a particular month underwent drawings to determine that month’s prizewinner of a $500(CDN) worth of Best Buy Gift Card, on or about 15th of the following month. You even had the opportunity of participating in this sweepstakes, without making a purchase and skipping the survey. For that, you needed to send your hand-written details to:

Best Buy Canada Customer Satisfaction Sweepstakes,

8800 Glenlyon Parkway,
Burnaby, BC, V5J 5K3.



 Link: www.bestbuycanadacares.ca Posted by June at 9:35 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: best buy , retail survey 
 Sunday, March 13, 2011 
 
 www.TellDunkin.com - Tell Dukin Donuts Survey 
 www.TellDunkin.com is the website for Dunkin Donuts survey. Dunkin Donuts is one of the world&apos;s largest coffee and baked goods chain that serves millions of customers daily through its numerous outlets scattered across the US and the world. They operate more than 8,000 outlets with more than 2000 international stores using the franchise model. Many of their customers enjoy fresh donuts, coffee and baked goods every day at Dunkin Donuts.

As a potential customer, do you want to share your feedback with Dunkin Donuts? Then, you must visit the site www.telldunkin.com to provide your feedback. This guest satisfaction survey site supports you to attend survey in English and Espanol as well.

To start the survey, you need to enter a six digit store number that is located at the top of your Dunkin Donuts receipt. Upon entering the survey, you can provide your feedback about your recent experience at their outlet. This survey takes a few minutes of your time. At the end of the survey, you will have a chance to win a $250 Dunkin&apos; Donuts Gift Card by participating in a weekly sweepstakes. However, this survey will have a period in which is it valid.


Other times, you may see an offer printed on your receipt such a free donut when you purchase a medium or large beverage. You typically need to complete the survey within 3 days of your visit and then at the end of the survey, be sure to enter the validation code on the receipt to claim the free offer printed on your receipt.

Dunkin Donuts is one of the stores that had expanded rapidly through the franchise model. Other similar restaurants include Subway which also have its own survey at www.tellsubway.com and also offer incentives for patrons to complete survey.

 Link: www.telldunkin.com Posted by June at 3:02 PM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: coffee , restaurant survey 
 www.HappyHarrysFeedback.com - Happy Harrys Feedback Survey 
 www.HappyHarrysFeedback.com is the survey website for HappyHarry&apos;s, a Walgreen pharmacy.They have a feedback portal located at https://www.loyaltysurvey.com/hh/IntroPage.aspx. In the home page of the portal, the users need to enter the Survey # and the password and press the &quot;Take Survey&quot; button. The survey number and the password are provided in the receipt provided when making the purchase.

Moreover, customers participating in the survey have a chance to participate in the sweepstakes competition. People taking up the survey each sweepstakes period are given an entry to the sweepstakes competition. The lucky winner will receive a check of $3000 and the winner will be announced by the second week of April for the March sweepstakes period for example. For entering into the sweepstakes, the customer should complete the feedback by end of each month.

Happy Harrys was founded in Delaware was merged with Walgreens Pharmacy in 2006 to form one of the largest drug store chain in the US. If you want to leave a feedback for Walgreens regarding your shopping experience at the retail store, visit walgreensfeedback.com .

 Link: www.happyharrysfeedback.com Posted by June at 2:50 PM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: retail survey 
 www.PandaExpress.com/Guest 
 www.PandaExpress.com/Guest is the survey website for Panda Express. Panda Express, a part of Panda Express Group, is the largest Chinese fast food restaurant chain of the United States. Founded in 1983 and headquartered at Rosemead, California, it offers millions of customers, like you, a variety of sumptuous delicacies, like Orange Chicken, Mandarin Chicken, Beijing Beef, Kung Pao Chicken, etc.

www.PandaExpress.com/Guest is the site through which it aims to understand, as to how it is faring vis-à-vis its competitors. It invites you to participate in the Panda Express Survey, which will give it a fair idea about the satisfaction level of its patrons, like you. You can take this survey, either in English or in Spanish, by entering the survey number from your receipt and share your recent dining experience in one of its more than 1,320 restaurants. Please provide a very candid feedback, about your satisfaction/dissatisfaction regarding its food quality and services and share your experience ad feedback with Panda Express

 Website Survey: www.pandaexpress.com/guest Posted by June at 2:44 PM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: chinese restaurant , restaurant survey 
 www.Guest-Feedback.com - Guest Feedback Survey 
 Bravo | Brio Restaurant Group (BBRG) provides Italian delicacies to millions of Americans, like you. If you had enjoyed its hospitality, you had an opportunity to share your dining experience, both pleasant and otherwise, with the company. BBRG ows Cucina Italiana and Brio Tuscan Grill.

www.Guest-Feedback.com is the site through which you can participate in its Guest Feedback Survey and help the company to know its strengths and weaknesses. You could participate here by entering the Survey ID printed on your receipt and to appreciate your effort the company awarded you an entry in the“Bravo | Brio Restaurant Group Contest”, for every completed survey.

The contest has monthly drawings of all eligible entries. With each Survey ID, you could have participated once in the survey and this contest; however, since the contest provided you the opportunity to enter once every month, the more you had dined in its restaurants during this period, the more were your scope to participate. Every month there is a $500 worth of BBRG Gift Card as prize, which was given to the winner after drawing of all eligible entries for a particular month. If you had entered the contest a number of times, you had a great opportunity to win one of these prizes.

 Survey Website: www.guest-feedback.com Posted by June at 1:43 PM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: italian restaurant , restaurant survey 
 Saturday, March 12, 2011 
 
 www.ShopKo.com/CRSurvey - ShopKo Stores Survey 
 Shopko Stores Operating Co., LLC or Shopko is a chain of retail stores that was founded in 1962 and is headquartered at Green Bay, Wisconsin of the United States. if you had recently shopped in any of its more than 135 stores, here is your opportunity to share your experience, either pleasant or other.

Www.shopko.com/crsurvey is the site; where you will find its Customer Survey questionnaire and you can participate in it by enter the 3-digit Store Number and your receipt Number. If you want to convey something to the company regarding its services, this is the ideal vehicle and Shopko gives optimum importance to your views. As a token of appreciation for your time and effort, the company will enter you for the“Register To Win”sweepstakes. You can participate to a maximum of four (4) times in this survey in any month.

Therefore, go ahead and explore this opportunity to the hilt, which will definitely boost up your chances of winning the prize of a Shopko Gift Card, worth $250.00. However, if you are completely satisfied with its services and have nothing to provide as feedback, still you can enter this sweepstakes by calling up the phone number, provided here and without making a purchase. By all means, please check the rules of this contest and enter it, where the winner is declared on the 5th of each month, after drawing of all eligible sweepstakes entries for the month.

 Link: www.shopko.com/crsurvey Posted by June at 1:44 PM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: retail survey 
 Thursday, March 10, 2011 
 
 www.Arbys.com/Survey - Arbys Survey 
 Www.Arbys.com/Survey is the website through which you can participate in Arby’s survey for accessing customer satisfaction at Arbys restaurants. If, all these years, you had been enjoying Arby’s delicacies or even otherwise, this is the right forum through which you can let your views known to the company and help it to improve its customer experience.

You can participate in this Arby’s Promise Check Survey, either in English or in Spanish at Arbys.com/Survey, by entering the 4-digit unit number of one of Arby’s outlets and the date of your visit from your receipt. The company believes in the age-old concept of‘the way to a man’s (or even woman’s) heart is through his stomach’and gives paramount importance to your suggestions to satisfy all your needs and demands. In appreciation of your time and effort, it provides you a code, at the end of the survey. You can write it on your receipt and redeem it in future, for a free Arby’s sandwich, in any of its restaurants. You also need to make sure you fill in the survey and redeem your code within a couple of days as stated in the receipt. Unfortunately, there is no survey phone number in which you can contact to find more information and you will need to call Arbys main number.

Founded in 1964 and owned by Arby’s Restaurant Group, Inc., Arby’s is a fast food restaurant chain of the United States. Headquartered at Sandy Springs, Georgia, it serves delicacies like submarine sandwiches, wraps, appetizers, salads, etc. and is operational in Canada, too.


 Website Survey: www.arbys.com/survey Posted by June at 10:37 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: mexican restaurant , restaurant survey 
 www.BoneFishExperience.com - Bonefish Grill Experience Survey 
 If you have ever enjoyed the hospitality of Bonefish Grill, a seafood restaurant chain of the United States, while partying with your friends or dining out with your loved one, here is your opportunity to let the company know about it.

 Www.BonefishExperience.com is the site through which Bonefish, founded in 2000, owned and operated by OSI Restaurant Partners, LLC, strives to understand the needs and level of satisfaction of its customers. The company, headquartered at Tampa, Florida gives paramount importance to your feedback regarding the dining experience that you had in one of its more than 150 restaurants.

Through this site, you can participate in its Guest Satisfaction Survey by entering the 18-digit code, which you will find at the bottom of your receipt. Your candid feedback, whether positive or otherwise, is well accepted by the company and as a token of appreciation of your time and effort; it will provide you a coupon at the end of the survey. You can utilize this coupon to gets benefits on your future dining, in any of its restaurants.

 Survey Website: www.bonefishexperience.com Posted by June at 10:28 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: american restaurant , restaurant survey 
 www.CPKSurvey.com - California Pizza Kitchen CPK Survey 
 Loved your California-style pizzas of California Pizza Kitchen or did not find those as expected! Whatever be the case, this is your opportunity to voice your satisfaction/dissatisfaction.

Www.CPKSurvey.com is the site through which, California Pizza Kitchen or CPK aims to understand the needs and demands of its customers. Founded in 1985 and headquartered at Los Angeles, California of the United States, CPK is a chain of casual dining restaurants. Through this site, it invites you to participate in its Customer Satisfaction Survey by entering the 15-digit code number of your survey invitation and share your experience regarding the food, service and hospitality in one of its more than 230 restaurants. This is similar to other popular pizza restaurants survey such as www.tellpizzahut.com .

CPK is thankful for your time and as a note of appreciation, awards you an entry in the“California Pizza Kitchen Customer Survey”sweepstakes for every completed survey. However, if you have not dined in any of its restaurants or do not want to provide any feedback, still you can enter this sweepstakes by sending your hand-written details to:
 
California Pizza Kitchen Customer Survey Sweepstakes,
PMI Station, PO Box 3520,
Southbury, CT 06488-3520.

This contest, which has thirteen (13) Entry Periods, runs from 12:01 a.m. on 3rd January 2011 till 11:59 p.m. on 3rd April 2011 and you can enter, once everyday, using either of the above two methods. The survey may also continue beyond that date. All eligible sweepstakes entries of a particular Entry Period will be drawn on or about the 10th day after its closure and you have a great chance of winning one or more of the thirteen (13) Grand Prizes; one (1) for each Entry Period and consisting of $500 in check.

 Survey Website: www.cpksurvey.com Posted by June at 10:22 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: pizza hut , restaurant survey 
 www,MyAppleBeesVisit.com - My AppleBees Visit Survey 
 AppleBee’s Neighborhood Grill and Bar or simply AppleBee’s is an American restaurant chain, which is owned and operated by Applebee’s International, Inc. Headquartered at Lenexa, Kansas, it has spread its chain to over 2,000 restaurants, in more than 16 countries across the globe, since its inception in 1980.

 MyAppleBeesVisit.com is the site through which it aims to understand your recent dining experience in one of its casual dining outlets. If you are a great fan, or even otherwise, of its American delicacies like chicken, shrimp, salad as well as riblets- one of its specialties, here is your opportunity to let your views known. You can select from the list of countries where you dine at and also the language. To get started with the survey, you will need to have the server name, date, total amount and serial number that can be found at your most recent receipt. By participating in the survey, you will also stand a chance to win $1,000 or an iPod.

You can be rest assured that your views will not fall to deaf ears and like any top organization, Applebee’s too, values the criticism, both positive and otherwise, of its patrons the most and will take all the necessary corrective measures. The server field helps AppleBees Neighborhod Grill and Bar to identify some of its best waiter and those who have been giving the patrons excellent services.

 Website Survey: www.myapplebeesvisit.com Posted by June at 10:14 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: american restaurant , restaurant survey 
 www.CosiSurvey.com - Cosi Survey 
 Founded in 1996, Cosi is an American fast food restaurant that serves gourmet sandwiches and salads as its specialty products. If you had enjoyed its servings or even otherwise, in any of its more than 144 outlets for all these years, CosiSurvey.com gives you the opportunity for you to express your views and suggestions, which will help the company to maintain and improve its standards.

Www.CosiSurvey.com is the site for participating in its Guest Satisfaction Survey. Please look at your receipt and enter the Store Number, Date&amp;Time of your visit and the Amount that you had spent, on the opening page of the survey and you are on your way to share your dining experience. The company cares a lot about your views and to appreciate your effort and time, awards you an entry to the“Customer Satisfaction Survey”sweepstakes, for every completed survey. This is quite similar to other restaurant survey such as those found at LongHornSurvey.com and GoldenCorral-Listens.com which also combines the element of surveys and sweepstakes to give participants an incentive to provide feedback.

 
Cosi Restaurant has brought this contest in association with Empathica, Inc. and you can enter this, as many times you dine in one of its outlets and participate in the survey, in each month. The sweepstakes provides you the opportunity to win an instant prize of an 8GB iPod Nano and ten (10) chances to win $1,000 or equivalent in cash. Any day and everyday of the month, you can participate in this survey between 12:00:01 a.m. and 11:59:59 p.m. and after completion, over and above other things, you will be provided with a code, which you can utilize to enjoy $2.00 discount on your future dining visit at Cosi restaurant.

However, if you do not have anything to share and want to participate in the contest only, you can do so. In this case, you do not have to make a purchase, can skip the survey and participate by sending your hand-written details to:

March Mail-In Entry

c/o EMPATHICA INC. Customer Satisfaction Survey Sweepstakes
c/o Name of Participating Client
511 Avenue of the Americas, #40New York, NY 10011.

If you reside in Canada or United Kingdom, you can visit the site for the specified address to send in your entry. Also, please be sure to chance the Mail-In entry title with the right month.

 Link: www.cosisurvey.com Posted by June at 10:06 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: american restaurant , restaurant survey 
 Wednesday, March 9, 2011 
 
 www.DennysListens.com - Dennys Listens Survey 
 Denny’s, a part of Denny’s Corporation, is a family restaurant chain that was founded in 1953 and is headquartered at Spartanburg, South Carolina of the United States. It also acts as a full-service coffee shop and serves you breakfast, lunch, dinner, dessert, etc., 24-hrs a day, 7-days a week.

Www.DennysListens.com is the site, through which it wants to understand your experience and satisfaction level regarding its service. Through this site, you can participate in its Guest Satisfaction Survey, by entering the survey code of your receipt and share your recent dining experience in one of its more than 1,500 restaurants.

You must be visiting other restaurants and food joints, too. The fact is that restaurants survey are quite commonly conducted by large restaurant chains and you can find surveys from well known brands such as www.tellpizzahut.com , www.olivegardensurvey.com and www.redlobstersurvey.com and www.goldencorral-listens.com . Therefore, you can compare its overall service, the treatment you received and the cooperation of its staff members and managers vis-à-vis other restaurants. This feedback will help Denny’s to iron out the rough edges and as a token of appreciation, it provides you a validation code at the end of the survey, which you can use to redeem the offer, printed on your receipt.

Some of the survey questions include:

Were you greeted when you walked into Denny’s?   
      
Did you wait to be seated?   
      
Did the manager interact with you during your visit? If you interacted with an employee, but are uncertain whether or not it was a manager, select N/A.   
      
Did your server suggest additional items for your order?   
      
Did the server follow up after your order arrived to verify everything was prepared as you requested?

Were you offered drink refills during your visit?   
      
Was there a wait at the register for checkout?   
      
Were you thanked for your visit?

 Survey Website: www.dennyslistens.com Posted by June at 10:24 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: american restaurant , pancakes , restaurant survey 
 www.IHOPFeedback.com - IHOP Feedback Survey 
 Do you like pancakes, waffles and something interesting in your breakfast food? If yes, you must have visited IHOP already. IHOP stands for International House of Pancakes and obviously it is well known for its pancakes, IHOP serves varieties of favorites that are especially delectable to you. On the other hand, they value to your opinion that you wish to be better than it is. Keeping this thought in mind, IHOP has come up with a survey website named www.ihopfeedback.com. You as a customer can provide your feedback at the stie to improve the quality of food and you can provide your opinion how to make your favorite pancake more zesty and many more.

To get started, you must have received a survey code on an invitation or receipt for the survey upon your last purchase or dining experience at IHOP. So just go to the website to fill out your survey today. IHOP wants you to &quot;Come Hungry, Leave Happy.&quot; Here is your chance to help them improve, to make sure that they live up to their motto. Fill out your survey today, and make a difference! Only with your feedback, IHOP can be sure that they can improve their customer experience.

 Link: www.ihopfeedback.com Posted by June at 10:17 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: restaurant survey 
 www.TellSubway.com - Tell Subway Survey 
 Have you recently visited Subway for your sub sandwich? Do you know that Subway has also recently surpassed McDonalds in terms of the number of restaurant locations? With this kind of growth, Subway will need to measure their customer satisfaction. www.TellSubway.com is the website where you can participate in a survey and provide your valuable feedback to Subway stores. You as an individual have to enter the Subway Store Id as available in the Subway receipt to enter in this survey. The store ID is necessary as most Subway stores are franchised and are owned by different operators. By having a store ID, the feedback can be more directed at the operator of that franchise location. A survey for a sub restaurant is not new as you can find similar one such as the one for Firehouse Sub at www.firehousesubs-survey.com .

 Depending on your payment mode while purchasing from Subway outlet, the site will direct you to the survey. For example, if you paid by cash or you are at a pilot travel center or you used a credit card or subway card, the pictures will show you how to look for the right choice on the receipt. If you use a credit card or have a Subway Card receipt, you will need the host order ID number and store ID number. If you paid by cash, you will need to enter in the Date&amp;Time, Store ID and Transaction number. If you have a receipt from a Pilot Travel Center, you will need the store id, date&amp;time (found at the bottom) and transaction number.

The survey takes literally only a few minutes. It is a single page survey that asks you about your satisfaction level with cleanliness, quality of service received, freshness of food and little more. As part of their continuous endeavor this site is looking for genuine customer feedback which will essentially help them improving their services as well.

More importantly, be sure to enter in the right email address so they can send you a code via email for your free cookie redemption at a Subway store.

 Link: www.tellsubway.com Posted by June at 10:08 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: restaurant survey , subs 
 www.FirehouseSubs-Survey.com - Firehouse Subs Survey 
 Firehouse Subs is a fast food casual restaurant that was founded in 1994 and is currently headquartered at Jacksonville, Florida of the United States. It is very particular about the quality of its specialty product; submarine sandwich of meat and cheese and aims to attain maximum satisfaction of its customers.

 www.FirehouseSubs-Survey.com is the site, through which it encourages you to share your dining experience in one of its more than 390 restaurants. The great thing about its Customer Satisfaction Survey is that, participation earns you an entry in the related sweepstakes. To make matters easy for you, this sweepstakes, which Firehouse Subs has brought in association with Empathica, Inc., allows you to enter by calling up a phone number at 1-866-399-1108. The difference is that the online entry will give you 10 chances in the sweepstakes whereas participating in the survey through the phone will only give you 1 chance.

To participate, you will need to enter in the store telephone number, date, time and total which you can find from its receipt. The receipt sample on the right is meant to help you locate the information.

However, if you choose to enter the sweepstakes only without filling in the survey, you can do so by sending your hand-written details to the specified address. This is because of the fact that the sweepstakes does not require any purchase or surveys to be completed, for participation in the sweepstakes. Your participation in any method, can prove to be lucky, since here you have ten (10) opportunities to win $1,000 or equivalent in check and an 8GB iPod Nano.


 Link: www.firehousesubs-survey.com Posted by June at 9:57 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: restaurant survey 
 Monday, March 7, 2011 
 
 www.Survey4Gap.com - Gap Customer Survey 
 Gap Inc. provides fine quality clothing and accessories and. Since its foundation in 1969, Gap, headquartered at San Francisco, California of the United States, has been constantly endeavoring to improve its products and services to satisfy your needs. It also owns other well known brands such as Banana Republic and Old Navy, both of which also offer coupons for their surveys at www.survey4br.com (Banana Republic) and www.survey4on.com (Old Navy).

Therefore, if you are satisfied or dissatisfied with its products and services, here is your opportunity to let your views and complaints be known. Www.Survey4gap.com is the site where you can log on to enter its Customer Experience Survey in English, Spanish or French and share your recent shopping experience in one of its more than 3,150 outlets. By answering some basic qualification questions and entering the 5-digit store number, you can start taking this survey. You can find the store number in the red circled area provided in the receipt below.


 There is no right or wrong answers, so please convey your candid and true feelings, which will help Gap to understand the customers’expectations. Gap takes your views very seriously and to appreciate your effort, it will provide you a validation code word at the end of the survey. You can write this code word on your receipt and redeem it to get 20% discount on a future purchase of its regularly priced products, from any of its outlets.

The survey takes approximately 10-15 minutes, but it is definitely worth the time. Also, hold on to your 20% discount (though you might want to check the expiry of this) for a large purchase to get a big absolute amount discount. So, spend that 20% on a $200 purchase vs a $20 purchase for example to get the maximum savings you can get.

 Website: www.survey4gap.om Posted by June at 11:17 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: old navy , retail survey 
 www.Survey4BR.com - Banana Republic Survey 
 Banana Republic, a division of The Gap, Inc. is a clothing brand of the United States. It is headquartered at San Francisco, California and had been satisfying the needs for high quality apparels, of millions of customer, like you, across the globe, since 1978.

If you had been a great admirer of this clothing brand, here is your opportunity to express your satisfaction. www.survey4br.com is the site through which you can convey your views and feelings to Banana Republic. This site provides you the opportunity to participate in the company’s Customer Experience Survey in any language of your choice; be it English, Spanish or French. Answer some basic qualifying questions and enter the 5-digit store number from your receipt and you are on your way to express your views. The image shows you where you can typically get that 5 digit number. It is not necessary that you have to only rate the company good, through this survey. Banana Republic encourages you to provide a very candid review of your recent shopping experience in one of its more than 600 outlets, which will help it to understand the things it is lacking in its products and services.


 Banana Republic Receipt 
To appreciate your time and effort, it provides you a Code Word at the end of the survey. You can enter this Code Word on your receipt and redeem it in any of its outlets, to enjoy a 20% discount on a future purchase of its regularly priced products. This is quite similar to the offer from filling up the survey at www.survey4on.com for Old Navy or for Gap at www.survey4gap.com .

This is a huge deal especially if you plan to shop a lot at Banana Republic in future. Just think about it. If you were to purchase $200 worth of apparel, 10-15 minutes of your time filling up the survey will give you a 20% discount on that which is $40. $40 for 10-15 minutes of work is really not a bad use of time. So, be sure to put that receipt to good use at Survey4BR.com.

 Survey Website: www.survey4br.com Posted by June at 11:09 AM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: old navy , retail survey 
 Sunday, March 6, 2011 
 
 www.MyChickFilaVisit.com - My ChickFila Visit Survey 
 Chick-fil-A was started in the year 1946 in Georgia providing plate full of tasty boneless breast of chicken sandwich. Since then it has grown to become the one of the largest selling chicken restaurant in the whole of U.S.A. They have different types of restaurants including mall restaurants, stand alone restaurants and drive through only restaurants. They provide some of the best available nutritious chicken food such as Chicken salads, Chicken Nuggets, Chicken Sandwich, Chicken wraps and Tortilla strips. They provide excellent value for the money spent by the customer. They are a customer focused company and have been getting regular feedback from the customers in terms of on line surveys and feedback forms.

Customer have to visit the feedback portal located at www.MyChickFilaVisit.com and use the serial number printed on the receipt to start the feed back process. If you complete the survey, you can get a validation coupon code for a free chicken sandwich.

MyChickFila Visit Survey is quite similar to other survey offered by restaurants such as Kentucky Fried Chicken which has its survey found at www.opinionport.com/yum .

 Website: www.mychickfilavisit.com Posted by June at 2:30 PM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: restaurant survey 
 www.HallmarkFeedback.com - Hallmark Feedback Survey 
 www.HallmarkFeedback.com is Hallmark feedback website which captures the customer satisfaction of shoppers who visited the Hallmark Gold Crown store. The survey invites you to fill it in English or Espanol. To get started, you need to enter in a few information which can be found on your receipt from your recent purchase. They are the account number, the time of visit, date of visit and the total amount. For taking the time to provide the feedback, HallMark will provide a validation code that allows you to get $2 off in your next purchase at Hallmark stores. If you want to provide your survey by phone, you can also call the number 1-877-661-2448. When you complete the survey and obtain the validation code, please write it down on the line provided at the bottom of the receipt and present that receipt in the next purchase. Please note that you need to redeem the validation code within 30 days for it to be valid.

 Hallmark is one of the popular brands for greeting cards that has been around for more than hundred years. If you visit the stores of many major retailers or a Hallmark Gold Crown stores, you will find Hallmark cards. In the United States, this privately held company has a successful business of more than four billion dollar revenue. Hallmark Gold Crown store is part of this successful business and provide a good collection of greeting cards, gifts wrap, decorative products and many more gift items to their customer. When it comes to birthdays, wedding anniversaries, Mother Days and other special occasions, shoppers always remember to visit a Hallmark store to buy cards. To improve their product and to know the customer need and thought about their product, Hallmark HallmarkFeedback.com site. Please note that HallmarkFeedback.com is different from the site Hallmark.Feedback.com which independently collects customer satisfaction survey comments.

 Website: www.hallmarkfeedback.com Posted by June at 1:46 PM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: hallmark , retail survey 
 Saturday, March 5, 2011 
 
 www.TellOutback.com - Tell Outback Steakhouse Survey 
 Outback Steakhouse, owned and operated by OSI Restaurant Partners in the United States, is a casual dining restaurant chain serving great steak with a Down Under flavor. Founded in 1988 and headquartered at Tampa, Florida, Outback Steakhouse is operational in more than 1,200 locations in 22 countries and provides millions, like you, the very best in steaks.

Www.TellOutback.com is the site, through which the company aims to collect your views regarding your dining experience in one of its restaurants that will help it enormously in its constant endeavor for excellence. The survey is powered by Service Management Group (SMG) and is quite similar to a survey of another steakhouse chain known as LongHorn restaurant (survey review can be found at www.longhornsurvey.com ). Here, you can participate in the Customer Indulgence Survey, either in English or in Spanish, by entering the 18-digit code that you will find in the middle of your receipt at TellOutback.com. Outback Steakhouse encourages both positive and negative feedback and like any top organization, gives paramount importance to your views.
 
Jeff S. Smith, its President, appreciates your time and effort in taking the survey and the company provides you a code, after its completion. This is your incentive and you can use to enjoy a free Bloomin Onion in any of its restaurants. However, please note that this coupon is not redeemable at Outback locations in the Orlando airport. For customers of Outback Steakhouse who love their Bloomin Onion, it will be worthwhile to spend 10-15 minutes to complete the survey.

 Survey Website: www.telloutback.com Posted by June at 3:43 PM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: restaurant survey , steakhouse 
 www.TellRadioShack.com - Tell Radio Shack Survey 
 RadioShack is an American-based chain of electronics retail stores with locations in North America, Europe and Africa. Most retail stores sell parts (such as adapters), audio devices (such as MP3), cameras, computers and accessories. In order to better serve customers, RadioShack is currently hosting a customer satisfaction survey at www.tellradioshack.com .

Those who complete it will receive a coupon worth $10 off of their next purchase of $40 or more and will be entered to win a monthly draw of $1000. To be eligible to win, you must be at least 18 and be a resident of one of the 50 U.S states to enter the survey. You may enter until December 31, 2011. It is possible that Radio Shack will continue to conduct this survey after 2011 and into 2012 and beyond. You will need to print the $10 off coupon at the end of the survey. For that reason, RadioShack advices participants to complete it on a computer rather than on a mobile device, such as a smartphone. The survey takes less than five minutes to complete. Be sure to print out the coupon to present to the store for your next purchase in order to get your discount.

 Website: www.tellradioshack.com Posted by June at 2:35 PM 0
comments Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: retail survey Newer Posts Older Posts Home Subscribe to: Posts (Atom) 

 
Popular Retail Survey
 
 Best Buy Cares Survey Dollar General Survey Gap Survey Home Depot Opinion JCPenney Survey Kmart Feedback Kohls Survey Old Navy Survey Sears Feedback Target Survey Tell Radio Shack Survey Walgreens Feedback Survey 
 
Popular Restaurant Survey
 
 Golden Corral Listens LongHorn Survey Olive Garden Survey Popeyes Survey Red Lobster Survey Tell Outback Tell Pizza Hut YUM Opinion Port 
 
Popular Grocery Survey
 
 Tell Kroger Survey 
 
Tags
 restaurant survey retail survey american restaurant pizza hut best buy coffee grocery survey home depot italian restaurant old navy mexican restaurant sears walgreens car survey chinese restaurant hallmark kfc kmart pancakes pharmacy survey red lobster steakhouse subs survey4on sweepstakes target 
Popular Posts
 
 www,MyAppleBeesVisit.com - My AppleBees Visit Survey www.BestBuyCares.com - Best Buy Cares Survey www.HallmarkFeedback.com - Hallmark Feedback Survey www.TellPopeyes.com - Popeyes Customer Survey www.SearsFeedback.com - Sears Feedback Survey Website 
 
Blog Archive
 
 April (3) March (61) February (7) 
 
Followers
	</body>
</document>
