<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001279" url="http://www.food.com/menu/fast-food-at-home-mcdonalds-deluxe-breakfast-2270" time="2012-07-12-16:43" support="1" score="0.0031100579717132683" bingtitle="Fast Food At Home: McDonalds Deluxe Breakfast Menu By Redneck ..." webtitle="Fast Food At Home: McDonalds Deluxe Breakfast Menu By Redneck Epicurean - Food.com - 2270">
			<query id="000028" bing-rank="69"/>
	<description>Menu #2270 | 47 min to 2 hours | Serves Unknown ... If your kids want to hit a fast food restaurant, serve them this ... Condiments</description>
	<body>
		Food.com: The most complete collection of free recipes on the Internet, trusted by home chefs throughout the world. Search I&apos;m looking for: Recipes Ingredients Members Grilling Central 
 Join Food.com for Free 
 Take the Tour | SIGN IN 
 
 User at Food.com 

 Inbox (0) 
 
 
 
 My Profile My Settings My Cookbooks My Menus My Shopping List My Favorites Sign Out 
 
 Season&apos;s Best: Zucchini Recipes 

Whether you&apos;re craving something sweet, savory, hearty or light, versatile zucchini fits the bill.
 
More Summer Favorites:

 Juicy Strawberry Desserts , Fresh Corn Recipes , Tomato Sides 
 
 
Browse by Ingredient

 Beef Recipes Chicken Recipes Chocolate Recipes Fruit Recipes Pasta Recipes Pork Recipes Seafood Recipes Rice Recipes Tofu Recipes Vegetable Recipes 
 
Explore 400,000+ Recipes

 Newest Recipes Newest Photos Our Most Popular Recipes Easy Recipes Healthy Recipes 
 
 
Join the Food.com community to rate and review recipes and save and share your own—all for free!
 Join Food.com 
 
My Recipes

 My Public Recipes 99 My Private Recipes 99 My Reviews 99 My Private Notes 99 My Photos 99 My Shopping List 99 I Want To… Submit a Recipe 
 
 Season&apos;s Best: Zucchini Recipes 

Whether you&apos;re craving something sweet, savory, hearty or light, versatile zucchini fits the bill.
 
More Summer Favorites:

 Juicy Strawberry Desserts , Fresh Corn Recipes , Tomato Sides 
 
Browse by Ingredient

 Beef Recipes Chicken Recipes Chocolate Recipes Fruit Recipes Pasta Recipes 
 
Explore 400,000+ Recipes

 Newest Recipes Newest Photos Our Most Popular Recipes Easy Recipes 
 
 
 Copycat Recipes 

Why go out to eat? Find a new favorite for tonight from this collection of 300+ copycat restaurant recipes and more.
 
Similar Cookbooks:

 Clones&amp;Copycats , Grocery Store Food Copies 
 
 
Popular Member Cookbooks

 Restaurant Copycats Dessert Cookbooks Chicken Dishes 400-Calorie Meals Vegetarian Cookbooks Cookies Cookbooks Mexican Cookbook Low-Fat Cookbooks Rice Cooker Recipes Appetizer Cookbooks 
 
Explore More Cookbooks

 Newest Cookbooks All Cookbooks Healthy Cookbooks Cookbooks Forum Cookbooks FAQs 
 
 
Our free online cookbooks are like a recipe box, but better. Create as many as you want to help save, sort and share your recipes.
 Join Food.com 
 
My Cookbooks

 My Main Cookbook 

 All of My Cookbooks 99 
 
 Copycat Recipes 

Why go out to eat? Find a new favorite for tonight from this collection of 300+ copycat restaurant recipes and more.
 
Similar Cookbooks:

 Clones&amp;Copycats , Grocery Store Food Copies 
 
Popular Member Cookbooks

 Restaurant Copycats Dessert Cookbooks Chicken Dishes 400-Calorie Meals Vegetarian Cookbooks 
 
Explore More Cookbooks

 Newest Cookbooks All Cookbooks Healthy Cookbooks Cookbooks Forum 
 
 
 Summer Picnic 

Wow a big group of your friends with these 20+ creative backyard party picks.
 
Similar Menus

 Summer Dinner Party , Summer Lunch Al Fresco 
 
 
Popular Member Menus

 Chicken Dinners Seafood Meals Gluten-Free Menus Dinner Party Easy Menus Brunch Menus Vegetarian Menus Mexican Menus Italian Menus Winter Meals 
 
Explore More Menus

 Newest Menus All Menus Healthy Menus Menu Planning Forum 
 
 
Organize your weekly meals, parties or holiday events with our easy (and free!) online menu tool.
 Join Food.com 
 
My Menus

 All of My Menus 99 
 
 Summer Picnic 

Wow a big group of your friends with these 20+ creative backyard party picks.
 
Similar Menus

 Summer Dinner Party , Summer Lunch Al Fresco 
 
Popular Member Menus

 Chicken Dinners Seafood Meals Gluten-Free Menus Dinner Party Easy Menus 
 
Explore More Menus

 Newest Menus All Menus Healthy Menus Menu Planning Forum 
 
 
 Photo Contest: Win a Dream Trip to NYC! 

Give your next party a little French chic with wine, cocktails, cheese or hors d&apos;oeuvres from France. Submit a photo of your French Cocktail Hour and you could win.
 
More on the contest:

 All the Great Prizes , See the Full Rules 
 
 
Popular Forums

 Topic of the Month Contests&amp;Events Cooking Q&amp;A Food Photos Cooking for Kids Vegetarian&amp;Vegan Mexican Cooking Asian Cooking Dieting Breads&amp;Baking 
 
Explore the Community

 Food.com Blog Member of the Month Customer Support All Forums Contact Us 
 
 
Our community forums are the place to hang out, meet other members, trade tips and even play games.
 Join Food.com 
 
My Community

 All Community Forums My Favorite Topics 99 Chefs I Like 99 

More

 My Profile My Settings My Inbox 
 
 Photo Contest: Win a Dream Trip to NYC! 

Give your next party a little French chic with wine, cocktails, cheese or hors d&apos;oeuvres from France. Submit a photo of your French Cocktail Hour and you could win.
 
More on the contest:

 All the Great Prizes , See the Full Rules 
 
Popular Forums

 Topic of the Month Contests&amp;Events Cooking Q&amp;A Food Photos Cooking for Kids 
 
Explore the Community

 Food.com Blog Member of the Month Customer Support All Forums 
 
 
 
Popular Products

 Cookware Bakeware Cutlery Cooking Tools Small Appliances Cookbooks Shop All Categories 
 
Popular Brands

 Calphalon KitchenAid Cuisinart Le Creuset Shop All Brands 
 
 
 
Popular Products

 Cookware Bakeware Cutlery Cooking Tools Small Appliances Cookbooks Shop All Categories 
 
Popular Brands

 Calphalon KitchenAid Cuisinart Le Creuset Shop All Brands 
 
 
 
 Recipes 
 Recipes Navigation 
 Cookbooks 
 Cookbooks Navigation 
 Meal Planning 
 Meal Planning Navigation 
 Community 
 Community Navigation 
 Shop 
 Shopping Navigation Recipe Sifter 
 
 
Start Here

 Course Main Ingredient Cuisine Preparation Occasion Diet Filter by Ingredient Nutrition 
 
 1 
Select ( ) or exclude ( ) categories to narrow your recipe search.
 2 
As you select categories, the number of matching recipes will update.
 
 Make some selections to begin narrowing your results. 
 

 Get   Recipes Calories Amount per serving 
 Total Fat Saturated Fat Polyunsat. Fat Monounsat. Fat Trans Fat 
 Cholesterol Sodium Potassium Total Carbohydrates 
 Dietary Fiber Sugars 
 Protein Vitamin A Vitamin B6 Vitamin B12 Vitamin C Calcium Iron Vitamin E Magnesium Alcohol Caffeine 
Find exactly what you&apos;re looking for with the web&apos;s most powerful recipe filtering tool.
 You are in: Home / Menus / 

 Fast Food at Home: McDonalds Deluxe Breakfast Lost? Site Map 
Photos From This Menu
 
No current photos.
 Share Your Photos! 
Nutrition Facts

 Calculated for 1 serving of each recipe 
 The following items are not included below.
margarine or butter

Sausage Patty

Scrambled Eggs
 
See individual recipes for excluded ingredients Amount Per Serving %DV Calories 1999 Calories from Fat 412 (20%) Total Fat 45.8g 70% Saturated Fat 14.1g 70% Monounsaturated Fat 15.9g Polyunsaturated Fat 13.1g Trans Fat 0.1g Cholesterol 89mg 29% Sodium 1194mg 49% Potassium 1172mg 33% Total Carbohydrate 401.9g 133% Dietary Fiber 4.8g 19% Sugars 262.2g Protein 10.7g 21% 
 How is this calculated? 
 
 
Not Exactly What You&apos;re Looking For?

 Try these similar menus 

Browse Similar Menus By Category

 Weeknight North American Breakfast/Brunch Eggs/Dairy Pork American Southern Easy Kid-Friendly High Calcium Comfort Food Meat Sausage Pasta and Grains Taste/Mood Presentation Served Hot &lt;4 Hours 
 
Fast Food at Home: McDonalds Deluxe Breakfast

Menu #2270 | 47 min to 2 hours | Serves Unknown
 ( Change Servings ) Change servings for each recipe below 
 
 
 
 Rate it! 
 
 Ask me about this menu! 
 
Menu by Redneck Epicurean 
 
Select One

 Contact Me My Page My Recipes My Photos My Reviews My Cookbooks My Menus Add to Favorites 
 
&quot;Woo HOO! What a breakfast! This is really close to a Southern sit-down old-fashioned breakfast, minus the gravy. For fast food, it&apos;s pretty good. I especially adore the hotcakes at Mickey D&apos;s because they are so light and fluffy. The recipe I posted is the closest thing I have ever found to them. The only problem is, McDonalds stops serving breakfast at 10:00 am and I am never up by that time. SO...I drag out my griddle or a good flat skillet and serve them up any time I get a craving. I also love different flavors of syrup, so I can do that here at home, as McDonalds only has their basic hotcakes syrup. If your kids want to hit a fast food restaurant, serve them this and tell them it&apos;s take-out; they&apos;ll never know the difference, except this is much more fresh and tasty!&quot;
 Print Menu Add to Shopping List 
 Want to print the recipes in 1 click too? 
 Sign in or create an account. Go 
It&apos;s 100% FREE&amp;safe. ( Privacy Policy )
 Print Menu List Only 
 Perfect Homemade Hash Browns

 Mcdonalds Hotcakes (Copycat)

 KFC Buttermilk Biscuits

 Basic Pancake Syrup
 Add to My List 
Recipes in this Menu
 
 
 Breakfast 
 
 Perfect Homemade Hash Browns Handle 
Select One

 Add to Cookbook Add to Menu Add to Shopping List Send to Mobile Phone 
 servings 
 
 
 11 Reviews  | By EdsGirlAngie 
Select One

 Contact Me My Page My Recipes My Photos My Reviews My Cookbooks My Menus Add to Favorites 
 
 Mcdonalds Hotcakes (Copycat) Handle 
Select One

 Add to Cookbook Add to Menu Add to Shopping List Send to Mobile Phone 
 pancakes 
 
 
 17 Reviews  | By CeeDee 
Select One

 Contact Me My Page My Recipes My Photos My Reviews My Cookbooks My Menus Add to Favorites 
 
 Scrambled Eggs The eggs at the restaurant are very basic. Use your favorite recipe. 
 
 Sausage Patty Just your basic, buy it in a roll sausage. 
 

 
 Breads 
 
 KFC Buttermilk Biscuits Handle 
Select One

 Add to Cookbook Add to Menu Add to Shopping List Send to Mobile Phone 
 Biscuits The extras freeze so well. 
 
 
 19 Reviews  | By JustaQT 
Select One

 Contact Me My Page My Recipes My Photos My Reviews My Cookbooks My Menus Add to Favorites 
 

 
 Condiments 
 
 Basic Pancake Syrup Handle 
Select One

 Add to Cookbook Add to Menu Add to Shopping List Send to Mobile Phone 
 cups This stuff is MUCH better than store-bought. 
 
 
 67 Reviews  | By Aroostook 
Select One

 Contact Me My Page My Recipes My Photos My Reviews My Cookbooks My Menus Add to Favorites 
 
 margarine or butter 
 
 Advertisement 
What&apos;s Popular Now
 
 Fried Fresh Corn With Bacon Grease 
 By Papa D 
 
 6 Reviews 
 Candied Pecans 
 By JustaQT 
 
 14 Reviews Advertisement 
Over 400,000 Recipes

 All Recipes All Collections Get a Random Recipe Kitchen Dictionary Measurement Converter Request a Recipe 
 
Food.com Network of Sites

 Baking Recipes Blue Recipes Breakfast Recipes Cheese Recipes Chinese Recipes Christmas Recipes Dessert Recipes Healthy Recipes Indian Recipes Italian Recipes Mexican Recipes Quick&amp;Easy Recipes Red Recipes Restaurant Recipes Southern Recipes Thai Recipes Thanksgiving Recipes Unique Recipes Soul Recipes Dairy-Free Recipes Greek Recipes Deep-Fried Recipes Australian Recipes Low-Cholesterol Recipes MyRecipeBox.Food.com 
 
Ideas from Food.com

 How-To Videos Get Our Newsletter Carb-Free Cloud Bread Lemon-Baked Cod Creamy Cajun Chicken Pasta Microwave Caramels Banana Bread Recipe Crock-Pot Macaroni and Cheese Old-Fashioned Banana Cream Pie Whole Chicken Crock Pot Recipe 
More from Food.com

 Chef Directory Cooking Contests Cooking Q&amp;A RSS Site Tour The Food.com Blog 
 
Food.com Family
 
 
 
 Food Network 
 
 Catch Star this Week to Decide Who You Will Vote For 
 
 Cooking Channel 

 Healthy Summer Recipes Top Summer Side Dishes Best Burger Recipes 
 
 HGTV 

 Stunning Kitchen Ideas Join Us on Pinterest Design Star, Tuesdays 9/8c 
 
 Travel Channel 

 Best Sandwich in America 50 States, 50 Landmarks Best of the Road 
 
 
 Food.com: The most complete collection of free recipes on the Internet, trusted by home chefs throughout the world. 
 Recipes Cookbooks Menus Community Shop 
 Search I&apos;m looking for: Recipes Ingredients Members   See All of Scripps Networks Digital 
 Food Network Cooking Channel CityEats.com HGTV DIY Network FrontDoor.com HGTVRemodels.com Travel Channel GAC 
 
©2012 Scripps Networks , LLC. All Rights Reserved

 Sitemap | Terms of Use | Privacy Policy | Ad Choices | Infringements | About us | Help | Contact us
	</body>
</document>
