<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001207" url="http://www.drinkstuff.com/products/product.asp?ID=4545" time="2012-07-12-16:39" support="12" score="0.009676962857539554" bingtitle="DIY Straws | Drinking Straws Unique Straws Crazy Straws - Buy at ..." webtitle="DIY Straws | Drinking Straws Unique Straws Crazy Straws - Buy at Drinkstuff">
			<query id="000235" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000337" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="000233" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000243" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="001043" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="000523" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000526" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000328" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000339" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000246" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="000336" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000229" bing-rank="67"/>
	<description>... of those boring straight-sided things you might have in your drink if you&apos;re in a fast food restaurant. ... Cinema Seats; Exhibition Tables &amp; Stools; Eco-Friendly Products; Catering ...</description>
	<body>
		Drinkstuff.com - Keeping You Entertained

Accessibility Navigation

 Skip to Main Content Skip to Main Navigation 
 Standard UK Delivery£3.99 - FREE over£50* | Next Day£6.99 Login Sign Up Help | Contact Currency Choose: £ Pounds € Euros $ Dollars 
 
 Home Bar Cocktail Wine Glassware Catering Bar Stools Party Games Room Gifts Home&amp;Garden Bundles New to Bar | Bar Accessories | Bar Measures | Spirit Measures | Bottle Openers | Corkscrews | Home Bars | Bar Stools | Glasses | Drip Trays &amp; Bar Mats | Pourers | Bar Caddies | Drinking Straws | Drink Pails | Ice Buckets | Mini Fridges | Bar Towels &amp; Bar Runners | Drinking Gadgets | Beer Bongs | Beer Coolers | Ice Makers | Ice Cube Trays | Drink Coolers | Bar Books | Bar Mirrors | Trays | Bottle Skips | Ashtrays &amp; Cigarette Bins | Wall Signs &amp; Plaques | SodaStream | Bar Accessories Sale 
 Home Bar Drinking Straws DIY Straws 
 See more: Drinking Straws CLICK IMAGE TO ENLARGE 
DIY Straws
 Code: 4545 In stock Qty £4.99
 inc vat DIY Straws Was£5.99
 | Save 17% 1 Reviews Write a review   Email a friend 
 
 
 
 
 
 Description Further Info Video Delivery Returns 
 If, for some odd reason, you ever get asked what your thoughts of straws are, chances are you will struggle to even form half an opinion! Sure, you might be able to remember those silly straw glasses you got in your Christmas stocking one year, or perhaps one of those bendy, curly straws that made an appearance some years ago.

But, of course, 9 times out of 10 a straw is just one of those boring straight-sided things you might have in your drink if you&apos;re in a fast food restaurant. Nothing special to particularly grab your attention.

DIY Straws have risen out of this bleak drinking accessory landscape and dared to be different! Consisting of 21 pieces, these straws are the first DIY drinking aid which adds a new dimension to your drinking habits.

The supplied translucent straws are specifically designed to be used with DIY Straws, they are designed to be more durable than standard straws and are therefore reusable.

Simply use your imagination and relive your childhood as you recreate those many hours spent building Lego and Meccano models, only this time you get a nice refreshing drink at the end of it as a reward for your crazy inventions!

You can even think up some new drinking games using DIY Straws. How about building a multi-ended straw and mixing up your own cocktails as they travel up the pipes? You could get a hold of a a few sets and start building a straw empire in your home! Have competitions with your friends to see who can build the most imaginative construction! 
There is no further information for this product.
 This item can be delivered to the following zones: 
 Showroom Collection FREE Standard Delivery £3.99 Next Day Express £6.99 Scottish Highlands £7.99 Scottish Islands £7.99 Northern Ireland £7.99 Isle of Wight, Isle of Man&amp;Offshore UK £7.99 Channel Islands £7.99 Austria £22.99 Belgium £13.99 Bulgaria £43.99 Czech Republic £25.99 Denmark £22.99 Estonia £57.99 Finland £43.99 France £20.99 Germany £13.99 Greece £43.99 Hungary £42.99 Ireland / Eire (Republic) £12.99 Italy £23.99 Latvia £48.99 Lithuania £49.99 Luxembourg £16.99 The Netherlands £13.99 Poland £25.99 Portugal £28.99 Romania £43.99 Slovakia £35.99 Slovenia £42.99 Spain £28.99 Sweden £23.99 Canada USA 
 
 Drinkstuff Returns Policy: 

 30 Day Money Back Guarantee Faults/Damages must be reported within 3 working days 

For full terms, see our Returns Policy .

 Please note: 
Some products have individual returns policies. Details of these are stated on the relevant products pages. 
 There is no media for this product. Details 
 Product Features: 
Build your own multi-directional straw
21 parts
Get as creative as possible
Share your drinks
Non toxic
Hand wash only
Make up some new drinking games!

 
 Pack Contains: 
2 x T-Shape Connectors
5 x Corner Connectors
3 x Straight Connectors
5 x Short Straw Pieces
6 x Long Straw Pieces


 Weight: 
100g


 Dimensions: 
T-Shape Connectors: H 30mm L 43mm Ø 15mm
Corner Connectors: H 30mm W 30mm Ø 15mm
Straight Connectors: L 30mm Ø 15mm
Short Straw Pieces: L 60mm Ø 10mm
Long Straw Pieces: L 122mm Ø 10mm
Box: L 240mm W 155mm D 30mm
 You may also like... 
 Super Jumbo Straws Clear More info From£2.49 On Sale Flexi Straws Fluorescent More info From£1.50 On Sale Flexi Straws Striped More info From£1.59 On Sale Acrylic Straw Dispenser More info £34.99 Crazy Straw Glasses More info £2.99 On Sale Paper Fruit Straws More info From£0.99 Del Sol Parasol Straws More info From£0.99 Colour Changing Drinking Straws More info £1.99 Tiki Island Flower Straws More info £1.20 On Sale Giant Straws Neon 20inch More info From£13.99 On Sale Giant Straws Black 20inch More info From£13.99 On Sale Mega Jumbo Neon Straws More info £34.99 On Sale Drinking Straws Cocktail Set More info £3.99 On Sale 
 Back to the Top Customer Reviews Average Rating (1 Reviews) Write a review 5 stars &quot;The straws were posted at 4:50 in the evening and were received the next day. Unbelieveably quick. The kids loved them and have now combined both packs for one incredible straw!&quot; Paul Lazarus - Essex, England, 6th April &apos;09 Back to the Top Customer Photos 0 Photos Submit a photo Back to the Top Buy Now DIY Straws Code: 4545 In stock Qty £4.99
 inc vat DIY Straws Was£5.99
 | Save 17% 
 Customers who bought DIY Straws also bought... 
 
 Professional Boston Cocktail Shaker 
 from 2.99 
 Crazy Straw Glasses 
 2.99 
 Colour Changing Drinking Straws 
 1.99 
 Stainless Steel Freeflow Pourer 
 from 1.20 
 White Plastic Ice Crusher 
 7.99 
 
 My Basket 0 Items £0.00 Total: Browse New Arrivals Olympics London 2012 Party Best Selling Bar Bar Accessories Bar Measures Spirit Measures Bottle Openers Corkscrews Home Bars Bar Stools Glasses Drip Trays&amp;Bar Mats Pourers Bar Caddies Drinking Straws Drink Pails Ice Buckets Mini Fridges Bar Towels&amp;Bar Runners Drinking Gadgets Beer Bongs Beer Coolers Ice Makers Ice Cube Trays Drink Coolers Bar Books Bar Mirrors Trays Bottle Skips Ashtrays&amp;Cigarette Bins Wall Signs&amp;Plaques SodaStream Bar Accessories Sale Cocktail Wine Glassware Plastic Glasses Catering Bar Stools Party Games Room Gifts Home&amp;Garden Inflatable Hot Tubs Coming Soon Sale Clearance Sale Bundles Shop by Brand What&apos;s New 
 Sliced Cold Glasses 
 £26.99 Thermo-Electric Mini Fridge 
 £59.99 Brocade Wine Goblets 
 from£23.99 Mostkanne Birne Beer Tankard 
 from£3.99 Ultimate Half Pint Glass CE 
 £38.99 
 Top Brands 
 Guinness 
 Jack Daniels 
 LSA Glassware 
 Duralex Glassware 
 Lay Z Spa 
 Royal Genware 
 Waterford Crystal 
 Artis Glassware 
 Churchill China 
 
 Featured Items 
 CE Mark Glassware 
 Lay Z Spa 
 Bar Stools 
 Wine Racks 
 Home Cinema Seating 
 Cocktail Starter Pack 
 Caldura Mini Bars 
 Tableware 
 
 What&apos;s Hot 
 Red Party Cups 
 Jack Daniel&apos;s Gifts 
 Catering Equipment 
 Customised Poker Chips 
 Mini Fridges 
 Cocktail Sets 
 Gamko Bottle Coolers 
 
 
 
 Featured 
 Kitchen Stools Cinema Seats Exhibition Tables&amp;Stools Eco-Friendly Products Catering Equipment Drinking Games Barbecues Shatterproof Pint Glasses Glass Cocktail Fish Bowls 
 Seasonal 
 Christmas Gifts Secret Santa Valentine&apos;s Day Gifts Halloween Party Mother&apos;s Day Gifts Father&apos;s Day Gifts St Patrick&apos;s Day New Year&apos;s Eve Party Stag Do Party | Hen Do Party 
 Services 
 Gift Wrapping Competitions Newsletter Catalogues Twitter Facebook Google+ | YouTube Drinkstuff Blog UK Bar Supplies 
 Information 
 Price Match Customer Feedback Voucher Codes Affiliates Trade | Hospitality Home Cinema Services Press Office Jobs Site Map 
 Customer Services 
 Help Desk Contact Us Delivery Returns | WEEE Directive FAQ | About us Accessibility Environment Privacy, Cookies&amp;Security Terms&amp;Conditions 
 
 Payment types: 
 
 Orderline: 0845 3133352 
 ©Copyright drinkstuff.com 1998-2012 |&quot;drinkstuff&quot;®is a Registered Trade Mark
Barmans Ltd. Saxon Way, Melbourn, Hertfordshire, SG8 6DN

Partners: Home Cinema Seating | Lay Z Spa UK | The Cocktail Store | Skill Imports Searches: Popular Searches | Popular Products | Categories
	</body>
</document>
