<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001554" url="http://www.dedmangray.co.uk/business-sales/?type=Retail&amp;q=1" time="2012-07-12-17:19" support="1" score="0.00034657522962013774" bingtitle="Buying a business in Southend on Sea &amp; Essex" webtitle="Business sales specialist, business transfer agents, Essex, Southend,">
			<query id="000734" bing-rank="145"/>
	<description>A long established and well regarded Fast Food Restaurant/Cafe ... A Fish &amp; Chips Restaurant (24 seats) &amp; Take Away, with ... on Hamlet Court Road and is suitable for a number ...</description>
	<body>
		Commercial Property Consultants
 01702 311111 News Contact us 
 Home Residential Commercial Business Sales Land Auction 
 
 Business Sectors Catering Convenience Stores Hair&amp;Beauty Hotel&amp;Leisure Licensed Premises Motor&amp;Transport Professional » Retail Services Wholesale&amp;Distribution Other businessses 

 Other info Finance Start ups Checklist Contact us 
 
Search results
 Your search returned 21 results. 
 Basildon essex 100 cover fast food restaurant 

Catering, Catering A3 use, Catering Restaurant - Leasehold

A long established and well regarded Fast Food Restaurant/Cafe in approx 1,300 sq.ft. Seating for nearly 100! Occupying an important Town Centre location and in the same hands for 20 years! Operating ...
 read more» 

 Price: £120,000.00
 
 Close southend essex outstanding patisserie in very busy location 

Catering, Retail - Leasehold

Established by our Client in about 1991, and comprising an outstanding Continental Patisserie. Traditional artisan techniques are in place to produce a varied range of pastries, tarts, breads and besp...
 read more» 

 Price: £22,500.00
 
 Close southend essex. well established pizza, chicken&amp;kebab take away 

Catering, Catering A3 use, Catering Take away - Leasehold

Established in 1980, the business specialises in Authentic Italian Pizza, as well as a variety of other Fast Food including Steaks, Grills, Pasta, Kebabs, Chicken and Hamburgers. The property occupies...
 read more» 

 Price: £70,000.00
 
 Romford essex ladies fashion, baby wear&amp;school uniform retailer 

**RETAIL**, Clothes - Leasehold

Established by the current owner over 30 years ago. The business retails school uniforms, a comprehensive range of ladies fashion garments and a wide selection of baby wear. Situated in a prominent po...
 read more» 

 Price: £20,000.00
 
 South essex (close stanford le hope) long established cafe sandwich bar bakery 

**CATERING**, Bakery, Catering, Catering A3 use, Catering Cafe, Catering Restaurant, Catering Sandwi - Leasehold

The business was established by our Client almost 20 years ago. Serving all day Breakfasts, Lunches, Fast Foods as well as the typically English Jacket Potatoes&amp;Fish&amp;Chips. The property is situate...
 read more» 

 Price: £150,000.00
 
 Rayleigh essex. a well established pet shop in a busy location close to the high street 

Pet Shop - Leasehold

Established in excess of 17 years ago by the current vendor the property is located just off the main High Street of this South East Essex town centre. The property is directly opposite 1 side of the...
 read more» 

 Price: £20,000.00
 
 Loughton essex outstanding&amp;well established ladies designer fashion retailer 

**RETAIL**, Clothes, Jewellery, Retail - Leasehold

Established in excess of 36 years and run by the current vendor for nearly 20 years now, this exceptionally well presented womens designer fashion retailer occupies a prime position on this extremely...
 read more» 

 Price: £47,500.00
 
 Clacton on sea essex a well established floristry business in super trading location 

Florist - Leasehold

Established nearly 40 years ago, and under the current ownership for the last 8 years. A well presented Floristry business close to the nearby High Street. Benefiting from a high footfall, and ideally...
 read more» 

 Price: £47,500.00
 
 Waltham abbey essex 2 acre site with long established retail/wholesale garden centre 

**RETAIL**, Garden Centre - Freehold

Very conveniently located only 2 minutes drive from the M25 London Orbital and the M11. The business has been in the same hands for 13 years and has established itself as one of the most respected bus...
 read more» 

 Price: £1,400,000.00
 
 Chelmsford essex well established gift shop in busy location 

Gift Shop -to be advised

Owned by our Client since 1992, and comprising a well established Gift Shop &quot;with something for everyone&quot;! A business with lots of expansion potential. The location is suitable for a wide variety of o...
 read more» 

 Price: £95,000.00
 
 Southend essex 650 sq.ft. premises (with a3 use) in important location only yards from the world famous pier&amp;adventure island 

Catering, Retail - Leasehold

An exciting opportunity to acquire premises (WITH A3 USE) close to Southend Pier&amp;Adventure Island. The premises form part of the multi million pound Pier Hill (Southend) Regeneration Scheme, and are...
 read more» 

 Price: £55,000.00
 
 Southend essex retail kiosk development in important location only yards from the world famous pier&amp;adventure island 

Retail - Leasehold

An exciting opportunity to build a detached Retail Kiosk of approx 325 sq.ft. close to Southend Pier&amp;Adventure Island. The premises form part of the multi million pound Pier Hill (Southend) Regenera...
 read more» 

 Price: £40,000.00
 
 Freehold fish&amp;chips restaurant&amp;take away with self contained 2/3 bedroom flat 

Catering A3 use, Catering Fish&amp;Chips, Catering Take away - Freehold

A Fish&amp;Chips Restaurant (24 seats)&amp;Take Away, with outside seating for another 20, occupying a very visible corner location. The business has been owned by our Client since 2006, and is run almost...
 read more» 

 Price: £259,500.00
 
 Basildon essex pizza&amp;fast food take away delivery&amp;licenced restaurant 

**CATERING**, Catering, Catering A3 use, Catering Restaurant, Catering Take away, Licenced Bar - Leasehold

Pizza Fast Food Take Away&amp;Delivery business with unused Restaurant/Bar in approx 1,800 sq.ft. A spacious property having been the subject of a thorough development programme a few years ago. At pres...
 read more» 

 Price: £79,950.00
 
 Southend essex unique hi tec detached kiosk housing a cafe&amp;hot fast food business 

Catering A3 use, Catering Cafe, Catering Take away - Leasehold

A unique opportunity to acquire ultra modern Cafe Premises with A3 Use in some 600 sq.ft. Fitted and equipped to the very highest specification. The property is of recent construction with all elevati...
 read more» 

 Price: £57,500.00
 
 Billericay essex in prime high street location a magnificent hamburger restaurant in approx 1,430 sq.ft. overall 

Catering, Catering A3 use, Catering Take away - Leasehold

An ultra modern Hamburger&amp;Fast Food Restaurant trading under the world famous Wimpy brand name. The Wimpy brand was created in the 1950s and inspired by the character of J. Wellington Wimpy from the...
 read more» 

 Price: £145,000.00
 
 Westcliff essex retail premises to let on busy boulevard style location 

Clothes, Retail - Leasehold

Ground floor retail premises in approx 1,150 sq.ft. 1st floor in approx 875 sq.ft. plus ancillary. The property occupies a busy location on Hamlet Court Road and is suitable for a number of uses. Loca...
 read more» 

 Price: £24,000.00
 
 To let, sudbury suffolk new restaurant retail or a2 premises 

Catering Restaurant, **LICENSED PREMISES**, **RETAIL**, Retail - Leasehold

The property comprises the ground floor of this substantial new building which, when completed, will provide commercial accommodation on the ground and part of the first floor, although the final conf...
 read more» 

 Price: £30,000.00
 
 Rochford essex freehold retail greengrocers for sale 

Green Grocer, **RETAIL**, Retail - Freehold

A well established family operated Greengrocery business occupying a bustling market type location. Suitable for a variety of uses. Ground floor approx 700 sq.ft. together with a self contained first ...
 read more» 

 Price: £210,000.00
 
 Basildon essex childrens activity centre 

Childrens Nursery - Leasehold

A well established Childrens Activity Centre within substantial premises extending to approx 8,000 sq.ft. with 45 car parking spaces. Magnificently fitted with several age dedicated play areas, 3 par...
 read more» 

 Price: £175,000.00
 
 Rayleigh essex well regarded farm shop for sale 

Convenience store, Green Grocer, **OTHER BUSINESS**, **RETAIL**, Retail - Leasehold

An established Farm Shop Deli&amp;Tea Rooms within a sprawling and well used mixed retail&amp;light industrial estate. The business has been in our Clients hands for the last 3 years, and during that time...
 read more» 

 Price: £97,500.00
 Winners of the most active Local Agent in Essex award 2009 
Dedman Gray Property Consultants Ltd
Registered Office: 9-13 Nelson Street, Southend on Sea, Essex SS1 1EH - Company reg. 06723624
©2012 Dedman Gray Property Consultants Ltd - Web design by Silkstream
	</body>
</document>
