<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001802" url="http://queenofheartsxxx.xanga.com/" time="2012-07-12-17:35" support="1" score="0.0017936694964471615" bingtitle="queenofheartsxxx on Xanga" webtitle="queenofheartsxxx on Xanga">
			<query id="001231" bing-rank="152"/>
	<description>[ ] I throw things when I get mad. [ ] An adult has ... ( ) Stolen a tray from a fast food restaurant ( ) Paid more than $50 for food ... (x) Eaten frosting out of the original container</description>
	<body>
		Weblog 
 
 Tuesday, 10 August 2010 

 
i havent been on xanga in forever ! =x
 
 11:21 AM 43 Views add eprops add comments email 
 
 
 Friday, 11 September 2009 

 
 ·          Are you like Bryanna? Bolding. 
 [made @ xanga.com/surveys_for_nimrods] 

 Appearance. 
 1. I have brown eyes. 
 2. I have naturally brown hair. 
3. My hair is currently dyed red.
4. My hair currently has a blonde streak.
 5. I&apos;m short. 
 6. I&apos;m skinny. 
 7. I&apos;m pale. 
8. I&apos;m an A cup.
9. People say I have a perfect body.
10. I have shorter hair. 

 Opinions. 
 11. I&apos;m pro-choice. 
 12. I&apos;m pro-gay rights. 
13. I think marijuana should be legal.
14. I think prostitution should be legal.
15. I&apos;m an environmentalist.
 16. I&apos;m a feminist. 
17. I&apos;m for the death penalty.
18. I&apos;m against animal testing for cosmetics, but not for medicine.
19. I&apos;m a liberal.
20. I&apos;m a Democrat. 

 Sex&amp;Relationships.
 21. I&apos;ve had a friend with benefits.
22. I&apos;m not a virgin. 
23. I don&apos;t think sex is a big deal.
 24. I don&apos;t need to love someone to have sex with them. 
 25. I prefer long-term relationships to short-term ones. 
26. I believe in open relationships.
27. I&apos;d be somewhat open to the idea of a polyamorous marriage.
 28. I haven&apos;t had many boyfriends/girlfriends. 
 29. I haven&apos;t kissed many people, either. 
30. The &quot;thrill of getting caught&quot; is actually a turn off for me. 

 Interests. 
 31. I love writing. 
32. I like cemeteries.
 33. I listen to music sung in different languages. 
34. I enjoy making icons.
35. I love posting in forums.
 36. I can draw, but not super good. 
37. I like taking walks on nice days.
38. I like debating.
 39. I love doing people&apos;s hair and makeup. 
 40. I like shopping. 

 Pet Peeves. 
 41. Humidity. 
 42. Conceited people. 
 43. People calling girls &quot;sluts&quot; just because they enjoy casual sex or gave their boyfriend a blowjob. 
 44. People who judge solely on appearance. 
45. Overpriced clothing.
 46. When people rage about how unique and original they are. 
 47. Over the top scene hair. 
 48. Crappy surveys. 
 49. People who depend too heavily on their boyfriend/girlfriend. 
 50. People who believe in love at first sight. 

 Style.
 51. I mostly wear black.
52. I love combat boots.
53. I&apos;m not very trendy.
54. I prefer shopping online to shopping in stores.
 55. I have somewhat of an unique style. 
56. Fishnets are love.
 57. I only go out in pajama pants if I&apos;m sick or on my period or something. 
 58. I rarely wear pants. I prefer skirts.
 59. There&apos;s nothing like Converse shoes with a plaid skirt. 
60 . I get labeled punk , goth, emo, etc. a lot. 

 Attitude. 
 61. I don&apos;t usually care what people think of me. 
 62. I have a high self-esteem.
63. I&apos;m content with my appearance when I&apos;m not wearing makeup.
 64. I wouldn&apos;t do something just because a guy told me to. 
 65. I love my boobs! 
 66. I always treat people with respect unless they treat me bad. 
 67. I don&apos;t judge based on appearance. 
68. I think anything that doesn&apos;t hurt other people should be legal.
69. I listen to my parents unless they ask for something beyond reason.
 70. I&apos;m friendly and talk to almost anyone. 

 Personality flaws. 
 71. I&apos;m really sensitive. 
 72. I cry over silly things. 
 73. I have a bad temper. 
 74. Sometimes I get lazy and just want to sleep for days. 
 75. Sometimes I&apos;m afraid of love and commitment. 
76. I&apos;m easily distracted.
 77. Sometimes I talk too much. 
 78. I&apos;m sometimes brutally honest. 
 79. I lie a lot. 
 80. I ignore people when I don&apos;t want to talk. 

 Things I love. 
 81. Sex. 
 82. Pizza. 
83. Leopard print.
 84. Tripp capris. 
85. Combat boots.
86. Forums.
 87. Starfish. 
88. Betta fish.
 89. Sleeeeeeeeep. 
 90. Boyyyys! 

 Things I do that most other people do but no one admits it. 
 91. Masturbate! 
92. Pick my nose!
 93. Pick wedgies in public! 
 94. Not shave my legs in the winter! 
 95. Pick my scabs!
 96. Itch mosquito bites until they bleed! 
 97. Pee with the door open when no one&apos;s home! 
98. Snoop around people&apos;s bathrooms!
99. Sometimes leave mean comments in people&apos;s honesty boxes!
 100. Look at myself naked in the mirror before a shower! 

 [made @ xanga.com/surveys_for_nimrods] 
 
 11:45 PM 34 Views add eprops add comments email 
 
 ·          Which Degrassi Character Are You Most Like?

 Craig
[ ] I was abused as a child.
 [ ] Both or one of my parents are dead. 
 [x] I love photography. 
 [ ] I’m in a band.
[ ] I’ve tried cocaine.
[ ] I’ve dated more than one person at a time.
[ ] I’ve lost someone in a car wreck.
[ ] I am bipolar.
[ ] I have been pregnant/gotten someone pregnant.
[ ] I play guitar.
 [x] I’ve stolen something. 
[ ] I would leave my friends and family behind if an opportunity for fame arose.
TOTAL: 2

Ashley
[ ] I’ve tried ecstasy.
 [x] I’ve been considered gothic. 
[ ] I play piano.
[ ] One of my parents is gay.
[ ] I have been cheated on.
 [x] I used to be popular. 
[ ] I’ve dated someone handicapped.
[ ] I’ve ruined my reputation while high/drunk.
[ ] My belly button is pierced.
 [x] I write poems. 
 [ ] I am selfish. 
[ ] I like Alanis Morisette.
TOTAL: 3

Ellie
 [x] I’ve been considered punk.
 [x] I’ve cut myself. 
[ ] I love filming.
[ ] I love indie movies.
 [x] I’ve dated /liked someone who ended up being gay. 
[ ] One of my parents is an alcoholic.
 [ ] I know someone fighting inIraq. 
[ ] I’ve dated my supervisor/fellow employee.
[ ] My best friend is gay.
 [x] I have seen a psychologist. 
 [ ] I want to be a journalist or reporter.
TOTAL: 4 

 
Paige
[ ] I have been a cheerleader.
 [x] I have been taken advantage of sexually. 
[ ] A sibling of mine is gay.
[ ] I have liked a teacher.
[ ] I play the guitar.
 [x] I was popular in high school. 
[ ] I’m bisexual.
[ ] I’ve smoked weed.
[ ] I dropped out of college.
 [x] I love fashion. 
[ ] I am a control freak.
[ ] I want to work for a magazine.
TOTAL: 3

Spinner
[ ] I&apos;ve been called a bully.
[ ] I skateboard.
[ ] I play basketball.
 [ ] I have been homophobic. 
 [ ] I get drunk a lot to solve my problems.
[ ] I have spent a lot of time in hospitals.
[ ] I have had cancer.
 [x] I’ve betrayed my friends. 
[ ] I change my hair like it’s underwear.
[ ] I fight to solve my problems.
 [x] I have changed myself for someone I dated.
 [ ] I work at a restaurant.
TOTAL: 2

Jimmy
[ ] I play basketball.
[ ] I’ve had surgery.
[ ] I’m rich.
[ ] I&apos;ve had a really bad breakup.
[ ] I’m in a wheel chair.
[ ] Someone has seriously harmed me, physically.
[ ] I like to draw.
[ ] I’ve started my own business.
 [x] My friends have betrayed me. 
[ ] My bf/gf has betrayed me.
[ ] I like rap music/I rap.
 [x] I have dated out of my race. 
TOTAL: 2

Marco
[ ] I&apos;m gay.
[ ] I have been beaten up.
[ ] I have been class president.
 [x] I‘ve dated someone older than me. 
[ ] I am afraid of bees.
[ ] I’ve had a long distance relationship.
 [ ] I am Italian. 
 [ ] Someone in my family is homophobic.
 [x] I am a good dancer. 
 [ ] My hair is similar to a furry cat.
[ ] I have stolen money from my family.
 [x] I am a really jealous person. 
[ ] I have had invisalign braces.
TOTAL: 3 

 
Emma
[ ] My mom had me when she was a teenager.
 [ ] I don’t see my real dad. 
 [ ] I’m a vegetarian.
[ ] I have been anorexic/bulimic.
[ ] I have gotten a significant other into trouble.
 [x] I know someone who has survived cancer. 
 [x] I’ve lost my best friend. 
[ ] I’ve had an STI/STD.
[ ] My friend has moved in with me.
 [x] I have had a pregnancy scare. 
 [x] I have had an embarrassing experience with my period. 
[ ] I have had pot brownies before.
TOTAL: 4

Sean
[ ] I don’t live with my parents.
 [ ] One or more of my parents is/was an alcoholic. 
 [ ] I&apos;ve been called a bully.
[ ] I’ve really physically hurt someone in a fight.
 [x] I&apos;ve stopped someone from doing drugs. 
 [x] I’ve stolen from my friends. 
[ ] I’ve stolen from the school.
[ ] I have been expelled.
[ ] I have gotten caught with drugs at school.
[ ] I would like to join the army.
[ ] I have been to jail.
 [x] I do not get along with my parents. 
TOTAL: 3

Manny
 [x] I’ve lost my best friend. 
 [x] I&apos;ve been called a slut. 
[ ] I have been a cheerleader.
[ ] I&apos;ve gotten pregnant.
[ ] I&apos;ve gotten an abortion.
 [x] I&apos;ve dated someone who I knew had a girlfriend already. 
 [x] I regularly break the dress code. 
 [x] I would date someone outside of my race. 
 [x] I am Filipina. 
 [x] My parents have plans for me that I don’t want. 
[ ] I have been kicked out of my home.
 [x] I want to be an actress.
 [ ] I went/am going to the same college as my best friend. 
TOTAL: 8

Toby
 [x] I&apos;ve been called a dork. 
 [ ] I love computers.
 [x] My parents have gotten a divorce. 
[ ] I&apos;ve been caught looking at porn by my parents.
 [ ] Someone close to me has died. 
 [x] I have used laxatives. 
[ ] I like anime.
 [x] I have a weblog. 
 [ ] I’ve crashed my car.
 [x] I have kissed my best friend’s ex. 
[ ] One of my close friends has died.
TOTAL: 5

JT
[ ] I&apos;ve been called a class clown.
[ ] I’ve been seriously physically hurt by someone.
 [x] I love little kids. 
 [x] I’m not very self confident. 
 [ ] I’ve been on TV. 
 [x] I like to pull pranks. 
[ ] I have dated someone with a kid.
 [ ] Someone has confessed their love for me, that I didn’t love. 
 [ ] I’ve sold drugs.
 [x] I have attempted/thought about suicide .
[ ] I live with my grandma.
[ ] I know someone who has had a baby and given it up for adoption.
TOTAL: 4

Liberty
 [x] I&apos;ve been called a nerd. 
 [ ] I’m a perfectionist. 
 [x] I have trouble with math. 
[ ] I&apos;m an editor of my school&apos;s newspaper.
 [x] My parents are too over-protective. 
[ ] Nobody liked me in high school.
 [x] I have dated a &quot;bad boy&quot;. 
[ ] I have been pregnant.
[ ] I have been in a car accident.
[x] Someone has thrown me a party.
[x] I have ratted out my friends before.
TOTAL: 4

Darcy
 [ ] I’m Christian. 
 [x] I have posted revealing photos on the internet. 
 [x] I have been taken advantage of sexually. 
 [ ] I have skipped school. 
 [ ] I have had a secret relationship.
 [x] I do not drink or do drugs. 
 [x] I have thought about suicide. 
[ ] I have had an STI/STD.
 [ ] I have confided in a teacher. 
 [x] I have seen a psychologist. 
[ ] A boy has thrown pebbles at my window.
 [ ] I have done missionary work. 
TOTAL: 5

Peter
[ ] I like filming.
 [x] I have ruined someone’s reputation. 
[ ] I have a relative on faculty.
[ ] I am rich.
[ ] I have framed someone.
[ ] I have street raced with someone.
[ ] I have had a secret relationship.
[ ] I snowboard.
[ ] I have no regrets.
[ ] I have had my license suspended.
 [x] I can&apos;t get over &quot;the one that got away&quot;. 
[ ] Someone has kissed me, that I did not want to kiss.
TOTAL: 2

Jay
[ ] I am really attractive.
[ ] I’m homophobic.
 [x] I LOVE candy.
 [ ] I’ve stolen from the school.
[ ] I like to work on cars.
[ ] I drive a Civic.
[ ] I dropped out of high school.
[ ] I have ruined a lot of people’s lives.
[ ] I like to gamble.
 [x] I have dated my best friend’s ex. 
[ ] I have been engaged.
[ ] I have stolen something worth a lot of money.
TOTAL: 2

Holly J
[ ] I always wear my hair in a ponytail.
[ ] I always get what I want.
 [x] I can be a bitch. 
[ ] I am a waitress.
 [x] My family has lost a lot of money. 
 [x] I have screwed things up with my best friend. 
 [x] I like to talk bad about people. 
 [x] I am intimidating. 
 [x] I have had a crush on someone who was taken. 
 [x] I have saved someone&apos;s life.
[ ] I have wanted to drop out of school.
[x] I am pessimistic.
TOTAL: 6

Jane
[ ] I have legally changed my name.
 [x] I was abused in any way when I was a child. 
[ ] My brother is a deadbeat.
[ ] I play football.
[ ] I have a very supportive boyfriend.
 [x] I have proven a teacher wrong. 
[ ] My parents are divorced but still have feelings for each other.
[ ] I have been proposed to.
[ ] I have a nose ring.
[ ] I have been lied to by my significant other.
 [x] I have forgiven someone, though it was hard for me to. 
 [ ] I am very strong, both physically and emotionally. 
TOTAL: 3

Alli
 [x] I had sex before I was ready. 
 [x] The way I dress and look is really important. 
 [ ] My parents are very religious.
 [x] I have given my friend a makeover. 
 [x] I do a lot to impress people. 
[ ] I have dated someone who others find it hard to like.
[ ] My parents try to control every aspect of my life.
 [ ] I am in gifted programs at school. 
[ ] I have a good relationship with my siblings.
[ ] I have done sexual things on school property.
 [ ] I have had a secret admirer. 
 [x] Someone has told me they were embarrassed to be seen with me. 
TOTAL: 5

Conor
[ ] I have an autism spectrum disorder.
 [x] Someone has chosen another person over me. 
 [x] I wear the same outfit a lot. 
[ ] I like robotics and mechanics.
 [x] I do very well in school. 
 [x] I am quite stubborn. 
[ ] I have made two of my friends reconcile after a fight.
 [x] Sometimes I feel like a third wheel. 
[ ] I live in the basement.
 [ ] I throw things when I get mad. 
 [ ] An adult has called me a &quot;weirdo&quot; before.
[ ] I have been suspended.
TOTAL: 5

KC
[ ] I have stolen a car.
[ ] I have had to move because I got kicked out of school.
[ ] I have been in foster care.
 [ ] I have fought over a crush before 
 [x] I am smarter than I look. 
 [x] I don&apos;t like people to know about my past. 
 [x] I have done a lot of things I regret. 
 [x] A friend has told a secret of mine. 
 [ ] I am good at sports.
 [x] I have a temper. 
 [x] I am afraid that people will judge me for who I was and not who I am now. 
 [x] I had my first kiss at school. 
Total: 7

Clare
[ ] My sister is very popular.
[ ] I do not have very much of a sense of style.
[ ] I have been called &quot;plain&quot;.
 [x] I have made a difference at my school. 
 [x] I am an honors student. 
 [x] I have 3 best friends. 
 [x] I have had a makeover. 
 [x] I like to help people. 
 [ ] I have had to choose between two guys.
[ ] I often do things because I feel bad for people.
 [x] I have made the first move and kissed a boy first .
 [x] I have recently become very noticed by the opposite sex 
 Total: 2

Mia
 [ ] I have or I know someone who has had a kid before the age of 15. 
 [ ] I am really busy all the time. 
[ ] I have done modeling.
[ ] I have changed schools in high school.
[ ] I am a very good gymnast.
 [x] A lot of people judge me before they know me. 
 [x] People try to make decisions for me. 
[ ] I would do sexual favors if it meant getting farther in my career.
[ ] I get called a &quot;slut&quot; quite often.
 [x] I have had my heart played with a lot. 
 [x] I have had to grow up fast. 
 [x] I have made a lot of big mistakes in my life. 
Total: 5

Anja
 [x] I am like the sidekick to my best friend. 
 [x] I have been pushed around by my friends. 
[ ] I have dated someone whose parents did not like me.
[ ] I have dated someone, while I was in love with someone else.
 [x] I have been used. 
[ ] I have changed my religion.
[ ] I am very possessive of my boyfriend.
 [x] I look a lot like one of my friends. 
[ ] I have had braces.
 [x] I like to do the right thing. 
 [x] I am a bit underestimated. 
 [x] I am polite. 
Total: 7

Sav
[ ] I have dated someone my parents did not approve of.
[ ] I play the guitar.
 [x] My parents are racist. 
[ ] I have been punched in the face.
[ ] I have had an off and on relationship.
[ ] My sibling and significant other are friends.
 [x] I am protective of my siblings. 
[ ] I am in an experimental rock band.
[ ] My family believes in arranged marriages.
Total: 2 

 
 I am most like: Manny&amp;KC 
 
 11:43 PM 9 Views add eprops add comments email 
 
 
 Thursday, 20 August 2009 

 
 

 

 &apos;X&apos; WHAT YOU HAVE DONE... 

 ( ) Slept all night in a bed with a person of the opposite sex 
 (x) Slept all night in a bed with a person of the same sex 
 (x) Slept for more than 12 hours 
 (x) Missed a week of school or more 
 ( ) Put chapstick on more than 5 times in an hour 
 ( ) Kissed more than one person in a day 
 ( ) Kissed more than two people in a day 
 ( ) Created a myspace/xanga survey 
 ( ) Eaten a worm 
 (x) Jumped on a trampoline 
 ( ) Ridden a unicycle 
 (x) Done something special for someone else 
 ( ) Stolen a tray from a fast food restaurant 
 ( ) Paid more than $50 for food at a fast food restaurant 
 ( ) Got caught for cheating 
 (x) Talked on the phone while going to the bathroom 
 (x) Brushed your teeth while on the phone 
 ( ) Worked in fast food place 
 (x) Written a poem 
 ( ) Randomly called people out of a phone book 
 ( ) Been on a yacht 
 ( ) Put bananas in your cheerios 
 (x) Lied to a friend to make them feel better 
 ( ) Dated someone more than 2 years older than you 
 (x) Eaten frosting out of the original container 
 (x) Had a dream about a myspace/xanga friend 
 (x) Fallen in public 
 (x) Had your pants rip 
 ( ) Recently had a PB&amp;J sandwich 
 ( ) Met your principals parents 
 ( ) Killed an animal 
 (x) Been prescribed to 3 or more medications by a doctor 
 (x) Wished you were an only child 
 ( ) Used your friends razor with out them knowing (razor phone) 
 (x) Been unproud of a decision you made 
 ( ) Worked for a family member 
 (x) Been told you were too young 
 ( ) Made out in a car 
 ( ) Kissed a friend, then their best friend. 
 (x) Been to a concert 
 (x) Gotten away with a lie to your parents 
 ( ) Been dumped the night of a dance and left with out a date 
 ( ) Been cheated on 
 ( ) Gone out with a person one of your parents set you up with 
 (x) Hate to admit you are wrong 
 (x) Ridden on a shopping cart in a grocery store 
 (x) Danced in a grocery store 
 ( ) Went into a mini mart in socks 
 (x) Worn a tiara 
 (x) Been in a play 
 ( ) Gone to church more than 2 times in a week 
 ( ) Copied more than 30 CD&apos;s in a day 
 (x) Made a movie 
 (x) Dressed gothic 
 ( ) Worn 5 or more layers of clothing 
 ( ) Had a stalker 
 ( ) Been to california 
 ( ) Lived on a house boat 
 (x) Swam in clear blue water 
 ( ) Sat in a doctors office with a friend 
 (x) Ran across 6 lanes of traffic 
 (x) Made fish lips 
 ( ) Hit on a waitress 
 (x) Taken pictures with a stranger 
 ( ) Been to Busch Gardens 
 ( ) Stayed in a hotel room with 3 other school mates 
 ( ) Made a public speech 
 ( ) Been on cable television 
 (x) Choreographed a dance 
 (x) Felt used 
 (x) Made a smoothie or milkshake 
 ( ) Had fun at work 
 ( ) Watched Desperate Housewives 
 ( ) Watched a movie so often you could quote every word 
 (x) Listened to an NSYNC or Backstreet Boys CD 
 (x) Kept something from a past relationship (letters, flowers etc..) 
 ( ) Given someone else flowers 
 (x) Taken a foreign language [im taking one this year!] 
 (x) Gotten to school at 6:15 in the morning 
 
 8:45 PM 27 Views add eprops add comments email 
 
 Best, Worst, Last, First, Today, Tomorrow, Favorites, and Currently. 

 b e s t 
 1. Male friend: Brian 
 2. Female friend: Grace 
 3. Vacation:Pennsylvania 
 4. Age: 16 
 5. Memory: idk 

 w o r s t 
 1. Time of day: morning 
 2. Day of the week: monday 
 3. Food: mayo 
 4. Memory: …. 

 l a s t 
 1. Person you saw: my mom 
 2. Talked to on the phone: my mom 
 3. Hugged: idr 
 4 IM: cassie 

 t o d a y 
 1. What are you doing now: sitting around 
 2. Wearing: pajamas 
 3. Better than yesterday: no 

 t o m o r r o w 
 1. Is: friday 
 2. Got any plans: no 
 3. Goal: I don’t have one 
 4. Dislikes about tomorrow: I wont be going to my grandmas 
 5. Do you have homework: no 

 f a v o r i t e 
 1. Number: 5? 
 2. Song: violet by the birthday massacre 
 3. Color: blue 
 4. Season: fall 
 5. State: hawaii 

 c u r r e n t l y 
 1. Missing someone: yes =\ 
 2. Mood: garlicy :s 
 3. Wanting: Soda. 
 
 8:44 PM 21 Views 2 eProps 1 Comment email 
 
 
 browse entries: older » 
 
 Top Tags 
 
 featuredq fq684 fq690 fq693 governmentdestabilizing guywithhammer 

 View all tags 
 
 queenofheartsxxx 
 
 
 Name: queenofheartsxxx Gender: Female Member Since: 7/26/2009 
 

 View full profile 
 
 Connect 
 
 
 Subscribe to queenofheartsxxx 
 
 Get trial subscription 
 
 Add to friends 
 
 Send a message 
 
 Post to chatboard 
 
 
 Archives 
 Don&apos;t worry - your calendar is here…to see it in action just click &quot;Save&quot;
 above and refresh the page. 
 View all weblog archives 
 
 About Me 
 [no info] 
 View full profile 
 
 Subscriptions 
 
 
 axfrayy 
 
 independentbxtch 
 
 glitzygraphic 
 
 fine_fresh_fierce 
 
 likeaportrait_GORGEOUS 
 
 GotThatSwag_quotess 
 
 sunkissedreamers 
 
 xo_vanessaaa 
 
 GRAPHiCS_BBY16 
 
 wOaH_mEe_x3 
 

 Subscribe to queenofheartsxxx Get trial subscription 
 
 Friends (77) 
 
 

 Add to friends 

 View all friends 
 
 Groups 
 
 
 !_-FiLiPiNo PrIdE-_! 
 
 &gt;|| PnOy)::..::|F |L |I |P *sTyLeS::..:(:PnAy ||&lt; 
 
 ~::Thai PryDe KeeP it Alive::~ 
 
 Thai People 
 
 ~`*[[Hawaiian_-_Islander]]*`~ 
 
 FILIPINO/HAWAIIAN 
 
 ~__HaWaIiAn PrYdE__~ If Ya aInT hAwAiIaN gEt OuT~ 
 
 hAwAiiAn_pRiDe 
 
 ~*HawaiiaN_PrIdE*~ 
 
 :::Filipino New Yorkers::: 
 
 DoMiNiCaN ***PrIdE*** 
 
 i have a weird asian name no one can pronounce 
 
 !!!!! Mixed nd Proud !!!!! 
 
 Minorities wanting to be thin 
 
 *~*~CoLoMbIaNs RePrEsEnTiN~*~* 
 

 Browse other Groups 
 
 Pulse 
 queenofheartsxxx has no pulse!... 
 Photostrip 
 
 

 View all photos 
 
 Recommended 
 
 
 weblog entry from Aaliyaan 
 [protected with Footprints Lock] 
 
 Chatboard (5) 
 
 Your welcome and take care of your special eyes, they are deep like an ocean, black like moonless nights ant attractive like a magnet, just let me say good by now are i am caught by the magnetic powers of your eyes, bet me:) 
 Posted 9/10/2009 12:26 AM by PeaceSearcher 
 @PeaceSearcher - Lol, thank you. I like yours too, peace is cool :) 
 Posted 9/9/2009 11:21 PM by queenofheartsxxx 
 Hi Queen of hearts, your user name caught my attention, and so i am here to share:) 
 Posted 9/9/2009 11:20 PM by PeaceSearcher 
 @curious_maya - thanksss =] and i like yours 2 (: hope you have an awesome weekend too xoxo, queenofheartsxxx =) 
 Posted 8/21/2009 10:57 PM by queenofheartsxxx 
 heyy :D &apos;queen of hearts&apos; hmm...pretty cool username (^__^) thanks for adding me, i love your layout.. so pink (*__*) i hope yo uhave an awesome weekend! mya xx 
 Posted 8/21/2009 4:48 PM by curious_maya 
 

 Post to chatboard 

 View full chatboard 
 
 

 
 Main Page Weblog Photos Videos Audio Albums Pulse Profile Chatboard 
 visiting: queenofheartsxxx 
 Subscribe to queenofheartsxxx Add to friends Send a message 
 subscribe 
 Click to see options 
 ratings 
 Click to see options 
 flag 

 join xanga 
 Weblog Add Edit Photos Add Edit Videos Add Edit Audio Add Edit Pulse Add Edit 
 update help sign in 
 
 

 
 &quot;Bumpin` Beat Box&quot; ©AnchorsAwayx started by AnchorsAwayx view all themes! 
 about this theme 

 terms privacy 

 safety parents law enforcement report inappropriate content 

 join xanga help sign in
	</body>
</document>
