<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001712" url="http://blogs.miaminewtimes.com/shortorder/2010/08/maggots_in_the_chicken_at_peop.php" time="2012-07-12-17:29" support="2" score="0.003480486296211145" bingtitle="Maggots in the Chicken at People&apos;s Bar-B-Que? - Miami Restaurants ..." webtitle="Maggots in the Chicken at People&apos;s Bar-B-Que? - Miami Restaurants and Dining - Short Order">
			<query id="000274" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000253" bing-rank="24"/>
	<description>Contacted by Short Order, Lewis claims he was ... Riptide can confirm, from the doctor&apos;s notes, she ... Salty American Fast Food; Restaurant No Shows; Eating House&apos;s New ...</description>
	<body>
		Blogs 
 Entire Site Articles&amp;Blogs Restaurants Places Events Music Images Ads Bars Best Of Movies 
 News Home Riptide Strouse Luke&apos;s Gospel Letters Special Reports Archives Search New Times Flipbook Weekly Newsletter Get Mobile Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads New Times Web Awards Music Home Crossfade Concert Calendar Bars and Clubs Brew at the Zoo Submit an Event Music Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurants Home Short Order Find a Restaurant Menus Iron Fork Happy Hours Dining Deals Dining Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurant Ads Arts Home Cultist Visual Arts Theater Welcome to the Future Skrawberry Jam Artopia Arts Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Film Home Showtimes Cultist Film Film Poll 2011 Film Newsletter Get Mobile Free Stuff Best Of Home 2012 2011 2010 2009 Readers&apos; Poll 2012 Best Of Newsletter Get Mobile Best Of Ads Promotions Home Promotional Events Street Team Free Stuff On Sale Promotions Newsletter Get Mobile Deals Post an Ad Jobs Real Estate Advertiser Index Deals Deals Newsletter Virtual Job Fair 
Top

blog

Stories
 
 
 Miami Spice 

 Gotham Steak Hakkasan, Scarpetta Miami Spice 

By Laine Doss
 
 Holidays 

 Bastille Day at Brand New Fabien&apos;s Bistro 

By Lee Klein
 
 Best of Miami 

 Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants 

By Laine Doss
 
 First Bites 

 Iron Side Cafe: Fresh New Lunch Spot 

By Lee Klein
 
 Gastronomic Gatherings 

 Fairchild Makes Mangoes Exciting This Weekend 

By Laine Doss
 
 Chef on the Small Screen 

 Eat St. to Film Food Trucks in Miami 

By Laine Doss
 
 Food Charity 

 Taste of the Nation Celebrates 25th Anniversary 

By Laine Doss
 
 Neighborhood Joints 

 Shack Shack In Coral Gables Opening Soon 

By Laine Doss
 
 News 

 Zeke&apos;s Reincarnated: Rio Station 

By Hannah Sentenac
 
 Fuming Foodie 

 Teacher Nailed for Horrible Behavior With Food&amp;Kids 

By Ily Goyanes
 
   The Inspector 
Maggots in the Chicken at People&apos;s Bar-B-Que?
 By Gus Garcia-Roberts Mon., Aug. 23 2010 at 10:00 AM Categories: The Inspector 
 Pin It 
 
 
 
 Either a pair of respected Miami-Dade Corrections officers have concocted an outlandish, disgusting hoax for a few thousand dollars, or Miami&apos;s best barbecue joint served maggots with its chicken.

Either way, consider us grievously disillusioned.
 
Last Tuesday, 25-year veteran prison employee Sgt. Rosanna Perry and fellow guard Officer Valerie McKinney went to People&apos;s Bar-B-Que on NW Eighth Street, as they have for decades. Dwyane Wade&apos;s favorite local restaurant was the winner of this publication&apos;s Best Soul Food award in 2009-- plus many other New Times honors over the years -- and is famous for its signature tart sauce.

 
 
​ The sauce apparently comes in handy in concealing maggots. The prison officers claim they got the barbecue chicken to go, chowed down on some of it in their lounge, and then wrapped it tightly in plastic bags and stored it in a fridge.

Feeling peckish a few hours later, Perry popped her chicken in the microwave and sat down to finish it off. Officer Fred Hernandez happened to walk by just as she cut into a piece. He remembers a &quot;really foul smell&quot; that he describes as &quot;like a real bad feet odor, and then you put something rotten on top of it.&quot;

Perry calls it a &quot;smell you had to run out of the room to get away from&quot; -- and then both guards looked down at the chicken. Recalls Hernandez: &quot;All these little worms were just wriggling inside the meat.&quot;

&quot;There were maggots coming out of the meat, out of the bone,&quot; Perry says. &quot;The whole piece of chicken was writhing. I think what might have happened was heating up the chicken activated the maggots. I yelled, &apos;Lord have mercy, Fred -- we done ate half of this damn food already!&apos; &quot;

The ensuing freak-out sounds epic. After the shock of seeing the bugs, Perry says, she began &quot;vomiting like crazy.&quot; Perry and McKinney say they took their food back to People&apos;s, where an apathetic co-owner, George Lewis, tried to give them $10 for the price of the meals.

Contacted by Short Order, Lewis claims he was never confronted about the maggots, even though the guards had his business card. &quot;I don&apos;t see how maggots could be in there,&quot; he protests. &quot;If it&apos;s grilled chicken, we cut it up and throw it on the grill. If it&apos;s fried chicken, we deep-fry it.&quot;

Perry and McKinney went to get checked at an emergency room, where a physician, Dr. Samia Zaki, observed their condition and wrote in a diagnosis: &quot;Probable larvae ingestion as per patient&apos;s history.&quot;

Perry also submitted a stool sample. Riptide can confirm, from the doctor&apos;s notes, she had diarrhea.

In total, five guards claim to have seen maggots in Perry&apos;s chicken. Several of them took pictures with their cell phones, but the photos all came out Sasquatch-esque: blurry and inconclusive.

So what are the guards after? &quot;I want a public apology from the manager,&quot; Perry says. &quot;I want to expose that they&apos;re selling bad chicken, and I want them to actually clean that place up.&quot;

What about reparations for medical expenses? &quot;One thousand dollars,&quot; Perry says. &quot;Actually, put down $5,000.&quot;
 
Location Info
 
Venue



Map
 
 People&apos;s Bar-B-Que 

360 NW 8th St., Miami, FL

Category: Restaurant 
 
 0 user reviews Write A Review Save to foursquare 
0
 
 
Like this Story?
 
Sign up for the Dining Newsletter: The week&apos;s top local food news and events, plus interviews with chefs and restaurant owners, dining tips, and a peek at our print review.
 Privacy Policy Cancel Continue 
Tags:
 Peoples Bar-B-Que Write Comment Email to Friend Print Article 
Related Content
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. 
 
Intelligence is on call here. The whole story doesn&apos;t even make sense. Why did they not see maggots when they ate it the first time. Mind you, they got a take out so if there where maggots, they surely would have been seen by the time they got back to their office to eat. Not only that, the microwave would have KILLED the maggots when the stupid bit@$ warmed up the food the second time. WTF do they mean,&quot;the microwave ACTIVATED the maggots&quot;... what kind of ignorant a$$ BS is that!! Don&apos;t believe the hype!!

I gonna fu%* with every Mother Fuc*** I see on the corner selling oranges and shut their asses down!!
 
Honkeys and Cubans just want to take over and want to see a good reputible black business shut down. When that happens their skank asses will be trying to open up in the same spot selling oranges and shit!! Fuck them, just like dog eat dog...maggots eat maggots!!
 
JUST DROPPING BY TO LET OUR CUSTOMERS KNOW THAT WE ARE OPEN, WE WERE NEVER CLOSED. AND WE HOPE TO SEE ALL OF YOU REAL SOON. ALL IS WELCOME SO COME ON BY, THE CHIMNEY IS SMOKIN.
 
Hey Spanish girl, I agree with you. There full of it. By the way what you look like?
 
HI WE JUST WANT TO LET ALL OF OUR CUSTOMERS KNOW THAT WE ARE OPEN FOR BUSINESS AND WE NEVER CLOSED DOWN SO WE ARE HERE TO SERVE YOU AND WHAT THEY ARE TRYING TO PULL IS JUST SCANDALOUS LIES.
 
Well IDK about all of you, but to me if a maggot can survive reheating in a microwave then it&apos;s time for a new microwave, and how did they survive the initial cook time. What kind of maggots are they? This just sounds like a bunch of BS just like the lady that&quot;found a finger in her Wendy&apos;s Chili&quot;. Whatever get a life, and learn about some natural science.
 
MY Question is how are maggots able to survive after being microwaved ?
 
HEY YA!!I JUST WANT TO LET EVERYONE KNOW DATS A BUNCH OF BS.WE BEEN WORKING AT PEOPLES FOR DA LAST 8YRS N WE ARE DA FIRST ONE TO EAT AND TASTE DA FOOD N FEED OUR KIDS FROM PEOPLES ALL DA TIME. EVERYBODY KNOW DAT EAT AT PEOPLES DATS A DEAM LIE.SO WHATEVER DA HOE IS TRYING TO ACCOMPLISH SHES NOT GONNA GET IT.PEOPLES BBQ IS DA BEST SOUL FOOD EVER!!!!! PS, SPANISH GIRL:)
 
I don&apos;t know what to believe, if the officers say they saw maggots in there food, where is the proof. How we know that food wasn&apos;t in there for days. I really never eat there, but I have heard nothing but good things about them. Except for the ghetto females that work there, but that&apos;s it. You say the pics came out blurry, you must have an wack ass camera phone,(upgrade.)
 
NASTY AS YOU OFFICERS ARE YOU ALL NEED TO BE SERVED MORE THAN MAGGOTS WHAT ABOUT A PLATE OF SHIT AND A CUP OF PISS BECAUSE ALL YOU ALL DO IS TALK SHIT AND PISS PEOPLE OFF.
 
DAMN DONT CO&apos;S MAKE GOOD MONEY?YOU ALL NEED TO LEAVE THAT MOM AND POP&apos;S BUSSINESS ALONE!!!!!!! IT NEVER SEEMS TO AMASE ME HOW FAR PEOPLE WILL GO TO GET MONEY!!!!!!! I HAVE ALWAYS AND WILL KEEP EATING AT PEOPLES!!!!!!! I THINK THE WHOLE STORY IS A LIE IS A LIE
 
IDK what to believe but i have eaten there plenty and put my food away and came back for my left overs AND heated them in the microwave but no maggots i hope the LAW is not trying to ruin these ppl good name for ah few thousand dollars i think its sad BUT my coworker called them cuz we order lunch there all the time and it was said that the lady has been there since this incident WTF? i dont kno who to believe but i hope its not true cause i luv their macaroni&amp;tuna salad!!
 
I know you two whores, you&apos;ll need to be shot in the head for what you are trying to do. You skinks.
 
karma is a motherfucka...they got served prison food...eeh eeh oooohh!!
 
So wen u came n here n flip open da plate it was a police officer orderin a porkchop dinner n ah whole uniform she look at yo ass crazy n looked n da plate n shook ha damn head cuz it wasn&apos;t no damn food n da plate where was da okra n tomatoes n da collard greens n it was straight bones n there but u had maggots n yo plate ah damn fool u r to try to con these ppl out of their money wen u sat n here on da lunch shift n ate damn near da whole plate n if I had maggots n my food I wud of went straight to da er not back to peoples to show da owner da plate so there for it wasn&apos;t shit wrong with u.this is a historic landmark this restaurant has bein serving customers over 40yrs n dis is the first complaint u old bitter whore get a life n stop tryin to ruin others
 
Well this is da 1st i ever heard, But u mean to tell me after eatting half of da dam chicken they just started smelling da chicken or even seeing da dam maggots? I really think this is a bunch of bull shit.
 
Well this is da 1st i ever heard, But u mean to tell me after eatting half of da dam chicken they just started smelling da chicken or even seeing da dam maggots? I really think this is a bunch of bull shit.
 
Well this is da 1st i ever heard, But u mean to tell me after eatting half of da dam chicken they just started smelling da chicken or even seeing da dam maggots? I really think this is a bunch of bull shit.
 
Check out the resturant website 5%off ur meal and take a look at the hours of operations 11:30am to 12:00pm mon-thurs. wow they open 4 30min.
 
&amp;#64;twins maybe the insurance is only $50 but they would love to live to keep paying it not get there stomach pumped.

@ bill when u where in jail did they serve u maggots and rat shit if not ur turn!!!
 
Actually, this may be a case of Karma gone wild. I&apos;m sure the inmates of thr Dade County jail have had maggots and rat shit and everything else served up in their food!
 
I yelled, &apos;Lord have mercy, Fred -- we done ate half of this damn food already!&apos;?&quot;LMAO. Enjoy the maggots screw.
 
Haven&apos;t gone there in years! Never really liked the place. I&apos;m shocked they asked for medical expenses when all they&apos;ll be charged is around $50 bucks thanks to their wonderful insurance plans.
 
This place is just NASTY... No one should eat at Peoples BBQ. I also forwarded this article to my facebook to alert all my friends and family.
 

TotalComments: 24
 
Now Trending


 
Slide shows » 

 Closer Look: Villa Azur Closer Look: Josh&apos;s Delicatessen&amp;Appetizing Rock &apos;n&apos; Roll Beer-B-Que 2012 at Seminole Hard Rock Hotel&amp;Casino More Slideshows&gt;&gt; 
 
 Restaurants 
 
 
Hy Vong Vietnamese Restaurant
 View Ad | View Site 
Tobacco Road
 View Ad | View Site 
Our pizza is simply an honest diversity of all-nat
 View Ad | View Site 
El Bajareque Restaurant
 View Ad | View Site 
 More &gt;&gt; 
Twitter Feed
 
 Follow short_order on Twitter 
 More Twitter &gt;&gt; 
Headlines from our Partners
 

 Summer Gold: Susser Talks Mangoes; London Burger King Installs a Damien Hirst Painting Boulud Hosting &quot;To Live and Dine in Miami&quot;; Balloo&apos;s Summer Additions at Sugarcane &quot;That Glow On The Beach&quot;: The 1950s Restaurants of 22nd Street Whiskey Joe&apos;s Set to Booze on Key Biscayne Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants; Watch an Ad For the Second Cheapest Wine Out There 
 About Us | Work for Miami New Times | Esubscribe | Free Classifieds | Advertising | Privacy Policy | Problem With the Site? | RSS | Site Map 
©2012 Miami New Times, LLC. All rights reserved. Browse Voice Nation Most Popular | Most Recent Newsletters | Mobile Log in Sign up 
 New York Village Voice 
 LA Weekly 
 Phoenix New Times 
 Denver Westword 
 Houston Press 
 Dallas Observer 
 SF Weekly 
 Seattle Weekly 
 St. Louis RFT 
 Miami New Times 
 Minneapolis City Pages 
 OC Weekly 
 Broward/Palm Beach New Times 
 

 
 Voice Places 

Discover restaurants, nightlife, travel, shopping...
 
 VOICE Daily Deals 

Get 50 to 90% off every day on restaurants, movies, massages...
 
 Best Of... 

More than 10,000 of the BEST things to eat, drink, and experience
 
 My Voice Nation 

Join the Village Voice community and get exclusive deals and info
 
 Happy Hour 

Your local Happy Hour guide at your fingertips
 
 or 
 Log in or Sign up 
 Social Connect: 
Use your favorite account to access My Voice Nation.
 
 
Use your My Voice Nation account to log in:
 E-mail 
 
 Password 
 
 Forgot password? Remember me or 
 Sign Up or Log in 
 Social Connect: 
Sign up for My Voice Nation with your preferred network.
 
 
Sign up for a My Voice Nation account:
 E-mail 
 
 Privacy policy 
 Settings Log Out
	</body>
</document>
