<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001355" url="http://www.reviewcentre.com/reviews61231.html" time="2012-07-12-16:51" support="84" score="0.18581872621006187" bingtitle="McDonalds Restaurant Reviews, Find Best Chain &amp; Franchise ..." webtitle="McDonalds Restaurant Reviews, Find Best ChainFranchise Restaurants reviews at Review Centre">
			<query id="000756" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000752" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000908" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000226" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000506" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000883" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000949" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000971" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000978" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="001166" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000915" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000468" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000980" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="000531" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="001161" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001510" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="001190" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000757" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000221" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="001065" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000695" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="000382" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001323" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="001511" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000750" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000353" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000502" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000349" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="001505" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000507" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="000719" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="000725" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="000968" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="000877" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="001168" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000600" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="001159" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000375" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001324" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000973" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="001481" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="000781" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000941" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="000350" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000940" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001322" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000852" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000777" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="001536" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000767" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000847" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="000525" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="001347" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000942" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="001128" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000251" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000442" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="001134" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000125" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000956" bing-rank="242"/>
			<query id="001103" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="001002" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="001318" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000443" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000516" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="000851" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000910" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="000946" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000977" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000062" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="001476" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000530" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000562" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000970" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="000782" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000726" bing-rank="111"/>
			<query id="000406" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000225" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="000688" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="001135" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000625" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000690" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000876" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="001102" bing-rank="213"/>
	<description>The cashier was courteous, in fact the service ... Not the most difficult thing to put some food on a tray is it? ... other than this, Maccy D&apos;s is a good fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		McDonalds Reviews
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★☆☆☆ 2.1 / 5 From 119 reviews 31.1% of users recommend this 
 
Quality of service
 
Quality of food
 
Value For Money
 
 
 Overview Reviews (119) Media Gallery (5) Prices 
 
 Media Gallery for McDonalds 
 
 Latest Reviews 
 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 12/07/2012

 “Quarterpounder craving less than satisfying” 

Driving by my newly remodeled McDonald&apos;s restaurant in Prescott Valley AZ discovered I had a sudden craving for a quarterpounder which I hadn&apos;t had in years. Went through newly designed drive up, paid $5.35 for the burger and a small order of fries. To my dismay the bun was hard, the meat flat and dry; not at all like the quarterpounder I remember, thick and juicy and quite satisfying. Well anyway that took care of my craving; don&apos;t think I will be visiting again. ...
 Read full review Report this review 

 
 dave.2 

 Reviews written: 3 
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★★☆ 
Written on: 01/07/2012

 “I simply adore Mac food. It&apos;s cheap and tasty and...” 

I simply adore Mac food. It&apos;s cheap and tasty and tastes good...
 Read full review Report this review 

 
 Squarehair 

 Reviews written: 4 
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★★☆ 
Written on: 26/06/2012

 “Strangely...I am lovin it!” 

I know I’m in a minority, but I honestly think McDonald’s is great. The food isn’t the best, but then you’re not paying top dollar (A meal costs the same as you might pay for a sandwich somewhere else) so expectations need to be set accordingly. My favourite things about McDonalds are the coffee (which always exceeds expectations. I get one every morning and I save a fortune versus what I’d pay at Costa, Starbucks or the like and the quality is just as good) and the Chicken (It the cheapest...
 Read full review Report this review 
 Comments (1) 
 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 23/06/2012

 “food is terrible and the workers dont give a shirt.” 

I go to mcdonalds and not only is my food wrong but theres hair in my food.Dont u ever try to funk me again mcdonalds!...
 Read full review 
Bobtheeatingmachine&apos;s response to Guest&apos;s Review

Written on: 25/06/2012

For the price its not bad. Why would they give you a shirt? Go to Wal Mart for shirst and etc, McDonalds sells food not clothes.

 Report this review 

 
 BobTheEatingMachine 

 Reviews written: 1 
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★☆☆☆ 
Written on: 20/06/2012

 “Drive through service” 

Why is it that the drive through at many locations get my order wrong 50% of the time. They either give me wrong things, don&apos;t give me stuff I asked for, or things are missing. This an all too common occurance. ...
 Read full review Report this review 

 
 fort40bc 

 Reviews written: 2 
 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 18/06/2012

 “food poisning” 

Went to Mcdonalds on port way Preston got a chicken wrap and food poisning, i know it was that because i ate nothing all day it never again stay away. i complained and the manager had been taught to say you cannot get ill off our chicken what an idiotic thing to say. ...
 Read full review Report this review 

 
keej
 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 12/06/2012

 “ROBBED at fort william mcdonalds!!!!” 

on visiting fort william for 1 night (1st june 2012)my girlfriend and i went to mcdonalds for a burger etc.on arrival at the hotel she noticed her purse was gone.after searching the car etc went back to mcds where the sheepish looking manageress told us nothing had been handed in (girl,early 30s, brown hair)left my name and num to be contacted if it turned up,then went and explained the situation to the police.next morning my girlfriend got a call fromm the bank saying sum1 had tried yo use her...
 Read full review Report this review 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 08/06/2012

 “totally disgusting food” 

i think you are disgusting and you make people fat and you just painted it green to make it look healthy and i think this company should shut down NOW!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!...
 Read full review Report this review 

 
Sudburyboy
 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 06/06/2012

 “I walked in to Walmart McDonald&apos;s at 9:39pm and just...” 

I walked in to Walmart McDonald&apos;s at 9:39pm and just as I was about take my order the manger (nick) said that they were closed. I thought that McDonalds at Walmart closed at 10? I was very disappointed soni had to drive to the regent McDonald&apos;s. ...
 Read full review Report this review 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 31/05/2012

 “poor customer service” 

i bought fries last night. i parked my car at their lot and ran across the street to my job for something, by the time i returned my car was gone (towed) with my laptop, cell phone and even the fries and drink i bought from them, couple of employees including the manager were laughing when i asked them if they knew what happened to my car. ...
 Read full review Report this review See next 10 reviews Showing 1 - 10 of 119 Reviews 

 
barrytrotter
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★★★ 
Written on: 30/05/2012

 “mmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmm” 

YUMMYYYYYYYYY YUMMMMY I MY TUMMY I LOVE COLD FRIES AND HAIR IN MY BURGER IT THE PLACE TO GO #yolo...
 Read full review Report this review 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 23/05/2012

 “chips to salty” 

the chips have to much salt in them i would not go there again...
 Read full review Report this review 
 Comments (1) 
 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 14/05/2012

 “ice cream to cold.” 

at lunch the other day i visted mcdonalds with a friends and brought a mcflurry, it was to cold.never going again, complet;y shocked....
 Read full review 
Guest&apos;s response to Guest&apos;s Review

Written on: 23/06/2012

ice crean is suposed to be cold idite
 Report this review 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 13/05/2012

 “&quot;Did you ask for hair with that burger?” 

&quot;Nasty&quot;To day i went there for lunch The people were nice however there was hair in my burger,my fry&apos;s were cold and hard.This is not the first time i go here to get lunch but after the past few epic fails it will be the last.It seems that hair in your food and cold hard frays happens a lot in this store. if you go here check you double quarter ponder burger before eating it....
 Read full review Report this review 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★★★ 
Written on: 09/05/2012

 “surprising key to great service- patience and...” 

im 15. i started working at mcdonald&apos;s about a month ago. working the till seems like the easiest job out there and frankly i agree but that&apos;s not what i thought starting out. a cranky customer would come in and i would start freaking out, praying that i wouldnt mess up the order. im sure i looked inexperienced and very unprofessional but i couldnt help it. some people are just so intimidating. then there would be those kind souls that encouraged and acknowledged that you were new and still learning,...
 Read full review Report this review 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 08/05/2012

 “Crossroads Shopping centre Apopka-vineland road LBV...” 

After ordering the meal for two (29/04/12)we were told they would not accept payment with a travellers check, tried to explain the difference between personal/travellers cheques but kept saying not allowed to accept any cheque,Staff were unhelpful and abusive.Not once in the two weeeks we stayed in Florida did any one else from flea market booth to national chain refuse to accept travellers cheques ? John&amp;Deb Richardson...
 Read full review Report this review 
 Comments (1) 
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★☆☆☆ 
Written on: 28/04/2012

 “Food is good. Service is bad” 

I love Mcdonalds food. Ive been eating there for years. Until suddenly its like my local Mcdonalds stopped training the order takers. About the past 5 times they have had major trouble getting my order right. Not only that but hey sometimes have a extremely hard time understanding me. I just went there today and i was sitting in my car for 10 minutes telling the order taker my food i wanted. I just said i wanted a grilled chicken snack wrap with no ranch or sauce. She put that on and a grilled chicken...
 Read full review 
Coolboy60044&apos;s response to Guest&apos;s Review

Written on: 28/04/2012

Nice review e g
 Report this review 

 
frrfrgrg
 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 25/04/2012

 “Obesity” 

After I wentI went into mcdonalds with my friend he got morbidlyobese and died of a heart attack...
 Read full review Report this review 

 
 tonyguy5612 

 Reviews written: 1 
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★☆☆☆ 
Written on: 25/04/2012

 “The new Polegate McDonalds, EAST SUSSEX” 

Would not recommend going to this one in a car as you WILL be parked up to wait and there is NOT enough bays to park EVERY customer that goes thru the drive thru! If that wasn&apos;t enough they got our order wrong and when the women came out to give it to me she gave me two other receipts from some other poor customers waiting for their food! I took the receipts back instore and had 2 managers&amp;at least 3 employees stumped at what had gone wrong, I just got what they missed off the order and walked...
 Read full review Report this review 

 
cherryz
 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 11/04/2012

 “COLD FILET-O-FISH MEAL” 

It has been quite a while since i&apos;ve had a yearn for a McDonald&apos;s meal. Suddenly I felt for a Filet-O-Fish meal with a small vanilla shake. The cashier was courteous, in fact the service was excellent. The vanilla shake was good. Sadly, the fries&amp;filet was was cold; not even warm. I was most disappointed. ...
 Read full review Report this review See next 10 reviews Showing 11 - 20 of 119 Reviews 

 
DModest
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★★★ 
Written on: 10/04/2012

 “D Modest Review” 

McDonalds is a place in which almost everybody goes to, and it keeps them satisfied. The food is relatively cheap for parents, and Happy Meal toys keep the kids from complaining. This Also happens to be a reasturant in which i attend so often, because im always out and about, and being an 18 year old male, i seem to always be starving. Out of all the numerous times i have been to the restaurant, my last experience seems to the the best out of all of them. This weekend i was in Atlanta, GA. for...
 Read full review Report this review 

 
 coolgal446 

 Reviews written: 1 
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★★☆ 
Written on: 05/04/2012

 “Mcdonalds is nice” 

mcdonalds is fast and nice food the best hygene you could get could be better quality packaging :)...
 Read full review Report this review 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★★★ 
Written on: 29/03/2012

 “mcdonalds is best restaurant ever !” 

how dare you dis mcdonlads bled i will bang everyone who dises mcdonalds you will bab yourself if you see me yeah too right so anyone say anthing again and i will crap in your mouth....
 Read full review Report this review 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★★★ 
Written on: 29/03/2012

 “best ever” 

mcdonalds is the best restaurant ever nobody better not dis it ...
 Read full review Report this review 

 
 calvin.powell27 

 Reviews written: 2 
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★☆☆ 
Written on: 26/03/2012

 “Terrible Experience” 

Mc Donalds, Bushey is not worth your time and money. They are far from hospitable or courteous. I had a terrible experience. I was kept waiting for a long time. I will never visit them again!...
 Read full review Report this review 

 
bratz405
 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 25/03/2012

 “drive thru” 

the chicken is so thin and most of it are breading and the fries is soak in oil i mean what the hell i pay for it !!!...
 Read full review Report this review 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 25/03/2012

 “hair in my cheeseburger!” 

We went through the McDonalds drive through today, one of the meals we ordered was a cheeseburger happy meal. I got half way through the cheeseburger when i noticed a hair/whisker! I was nearly sick! How discusting!!!!!!!!!!! The rest of the meal was ok, not very hot though and the fries were a bit dark, not burnt but as if the frying oil was old....
 Read full review Report this review 

 
Honeylicious
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★★★ 
Written on: 22/03/2012

 “YEAH BUDDY!” 

Yo, I walked up in this McDizzles in Brampton on Queen Street and that place WAS dope. Key words, dope. I remember the last time I walked up in there was a GameCube... now? Muhh fooneries had taken it out. I wanted to old school mario kart up in there and NOTHING. If that wasn&apos;t bad enuff, I order some McNuggets and this fine azz guido behind the counter was like&quot;Sorry M&apos;am, we don&apos;t gots no honey for your nuggets&quot;. I paused and was like,&quot;SAY WHATTTTTTT&quot;. At the point I was sooooooo raddled up...
 Read full review Report this review 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 20/03/2012

 “mcdonalds near bushey on a41” 

The worst service and the worst food ever. staff did not care and the food was so cold it was a disgrace to serve it at all. There was a manager just sat in the office - you could see him from the front counter. He did not care about the long queues or anything that was happening. Staff were rude and got the order wrong. Not the most difficult thing to put some food on a tray is it? Big Mac had brown lettuce in it and fries were limp and hardly had any salt on. This is the worst mcdonalds I have...
 Read full review Report this review 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 19/03/2012

 “HORIBLE MANAGEMENT” 

LANET AND SHarelle are manegers at this Mcdanolds in Lovejoy 1941 the one next to the carwash I dont recomend. I am sitting here watching a customer sit here yelling for service and the managers are sitting there looking at Him. ...
 Read full review Report this review See next 10 reviews Showing 21 - 30 of 119 Reviews 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★★☆☆☆ 
Written on: 15/03/2012

 “Mugy lettace” 

Frankston North maccas is the worst! From half patties to no lettuce, tides out on the chips, 3/4 of a cup of ice!!!! All in one dinner!!!! To make things even worse the staff are rude and throwing food around. Usually I haven&apos;t had a problem but tonight was a complete joke, and don&apos;t even bother asking for a replacement or refund! You&apos;ll have to wait untill the managers next shift which is more than a week away and don&apos;t bother trying to leave a name either. Not happy...
 Read full review Report this review 
 Comments (1) 
 
Gibbon101
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★★☆ 
Written on: 13/03/2012

 “Its pretty gee” 

Maccy D&apos;s can be quite peak if you order a special item and they give you the cheese you perposely didnt ask for. But other than this, Maccy D&apos;s is a good fast food restaurant. The quality of the food varies with what you order, for example, if you pay 3 pound extra for the chicken selects then you get real chicken as opposed to the &apos;chicken&apos; in the McNuggets! Overall though you do get your food faily fast, and thats what fast food is all about. If you want quality food, then go to Nando&apos;s or some...
 Read full review 
Guest&apos;s response to Gibbon101&apos;s Review

Written on: 15/03/2012

Dude... i Worship you
 Report this review 
 Comments (1) 
 
hellawell2k12
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★★★ 
Written on: 12/03/2012

 “it is the best” 

how dare you dis mcdonalds im gonna bang you bruv mcdonalds is the actaul best 20 chicken nuggets yum ! if i see anyone else dis it ill come to your house and knock you owt....
 Read full review 
Guest&apos;s response to hellawell2k12&apos;s Review

Written on: 24/03/2012

&quot;Hellawell2k12&quot;Firstly you can&apos;t go to someones house and&quot;knock them out&quot;them because its illegal!!! Secondly i&apos;m pretty sure with the people that have complained that it must be pretty bad and so maybe you should keep your mouth shut by eating more burgers fatty!
 Report this review 

 
 dazzym 

 Reviews written: 2 
 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 03/03/2012

 “WONT GO EVER AGAIN” 

I went into McDonalds today with my 2 children,its the worst fast food place going.I asked for a quarter pounder and 2 childrens meals.My little girl wanted a milkshake,the person behind the counter said she cant have a milkshake,the milkshake machines broken(NOT VERY GOOD FOR McDonalds).Then I get my quarter pounder,and it has cheese on(which I dont like).I didn&apos;t ask for a quarter pounder with cheese,or do they put cheese on every burger.So i have to wait for a quarter pounder again,I get my quarter...
 Read full review Report this review 

 
Andrew75
 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 15/02/2012

 “Never Again” 

I am I&apos;n this small town for a couple of sales meetings. I only had about 30 mins. To grab something to eat. I haven&apos;t eaten at McDonalds for about 12 to 15 years because I was tired of the poor quality food, but I thought what the hell I&apos;ll give it another try. Mistake!!! There fries were cold as hell,&amp;the hamburger was too , the cheese wasn&apos;t melted , the meat was dry&amp;strafe color..... I promptly took it back I&apos;n for a refund. I will never eat this food again, I&apos;m done ...
 Read full review Report this review 

 
 stevem001 

 Reviews written: 1 
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★☆☆☆ 
Written on: 10/02/2012

 “horrible coffee from new machines” 

I saw the new machines being introduced and found the Latte taste is not very nice. Really bland and tastes like it has been watered down. The machines have an LCD touchscreen and guess by now have been rolled out to most outlets. I am sure mcDonalds must have trialled these before rollout but honestly to me the taste is far away from the old machines. Not sure if the coffee has changed as well but after having 2 cups a day I will be moving to another brand maybe back to Starbucks or Pret. I have...
 Read full review Report this review 

 
ronron50
 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 03/02/2012

 “North Conway NH McDonalds.. There are two at the...” 

North Conway NH McDonalds.. There are two at the counter in the morning that are filthy... One had crud under her nails.. One tooth and has not taken a shower in days. A manager had taken our breakfast order and then went on to drive up . This filthy person finished the order. We left the counter with our order and threw it out upon leaving....
 Read full review Report this review 
 Comments (2) 
 
 garyth 

 Reviews written: 12 
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★☆☆ 
Written on: 13/01/2012

 “macdonalds stuff language” 

some guys even don&apos;t know to tell you&quot;Hi&quot;I eat there only because of lack of time....
 Read full review 
747Pilot&apos;s response to garyth&apos;s Review

Written on: 29/02/2012

Better check your own language .... McDonald&apos;s is spelt like this not macdonalds. Says it all!
 
Garyth&apos;s response to garyth&apos;s Review

Written on: 23/03/2012

Ok! My fault.
 Report this review 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 13/01/2012

 “Very Poor Customer Service @ Riverside Middlesbrough UK” 

I often go for breakfast at this restaurant firstly it was just for coffee but when I wanted a large cappuccino and got half a cup I gave it a break for a while even there head office did nothing about it. Lately I have been going for breakfast (sausage&amp;egg McMuffin with a large choc milkshake) as our canteen food at work is terrible. The first couple of weeks the breakfast was fine and I got what I ordered without any problems. This week nearly every day there has been a problem and its all staff...
 Read full review Report this review 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★☆☆ 
Written on: 11/01/2012

 “the men&apos;s bathroom” 

absolute disgrace,dirty floor and walls, toilet paper holder broken and half of it missing,no toilet paper,pretty stinky Shame...
 Read full review Report this review See next 10 reviews Showing 31 - 40 of 119 Reviews 

 
malicent
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★★★ 
Written on: 09/01/2012

 “I work at Mcdonalds, and i really like it. The staff...” 

I work at Mcdonalds, and i really like it. The staff are kind and encouraging, and it makes a nice place to work. The food is prepared quickly, and it is good. The only problem i have is the customers. I constantly get yelled at when i&apos;m working for the absolutely dumbest things. I&apos;ve had one customer full out scream at me because he thought the staff should unwrap the customers straw and put it in their drinks for them. I&apos;ve had customers come up to me and say ...
 Read full review Report this review 
 Comments (1) 
 
Sdickson
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★☆☆☆ 
Written on: 26/12/2011

 “Service is abismal!” 

The food is delicious ,and the price is quite decent aswel! However the service is absolutely ridiculous! I go once a week and every other week I have to go back in because they have got something wrong, the people who serve you and work there are complete dimwitted idiots and either don&apos;t listen to a word you say or just choose to ignore you, I always ask for a plain cheeseburger and it&apos;s never plain they always put all the rubbish on it, the people who serve you are stupid, very rude, obnoxious...
 Read full review 
747Pilot&apos;s response to Sdickson&apos;s Review

Written on: 29/02/2012

Sounds like YOU are the stupid, obnoxious, uneducated idiot that McDonalds appeals too with your stinking attitude. I would understand if you were paying for a fine dining experience, but when you are paying on average £3.50 for a meal I find your comments ridiculous.
 Report this review 

 
 mikey4561 

 Reviews written: 2 
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★★★ 
Written on: 03/12/2011

 “Very professional” 

This is a company lots of people could learn from. they do what they say everytime. ...
 Read full review Report this review 
 Comments (2) 
 
chainedprincess7
 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 06/11/2011

 “Mcdonals&apos;s Drunk Driving” 

I stayed at the hotel across the street and ended up having a few drinks. I wanted a late night snack and so I walked across the street to McDonald&apos;s to get some food. The staff would not serve me because I was not in a vehicle. I asked them if I needed to go back across the street to drive me vehicle (drunk) and come back to actually order food and they told me that it was the only way I could order. I would never order food from ANY Mcdonald&apos;s EVER again. What type of company would ever condone...
 Read full review 
Robbiewilliams1994&apos;s response to chainedprincess7&apos;s Review

Written on: 13/01/2012

It is company policy that under no circumstances should any person (be it member of staff or public) be served in a drive through lane due to health and safety issues. The staff members concerned were simply explaining that you need to be in a vehicle to order food. I am a McDonald&apos;s employee and most certainly do not condone driving under the influence of and drugs and I&apos;m sure the staff members that spoke to will hold the same view.
 
747Pilot&apos;s response to chainedprincess7&apos;s Review

Written on: 29/02/2012


I am sure that if every drunken fool like you went to the drive thru window whilst under the influence and tried to order whilst stood in an operating drive thru lane with vehicles present, ever did get run over or injured.... I&apos;m sure then your story would be different and no doubt you would be suing McDonalds. I&apos;m sure they weren&apos;t telling you to get in your car and drive, just informing you what the policy was.
 Report this review 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★☆☆ 
Written on: 29/10/2011

 “Carmel Apple Sundae” 

Why get the Carmel apple sundae for $1.69 when you can get the hot carmel sundae for $1.00. The apples in it were terrible. I can taste the chemical they put on the apples to keep them from turning brown. How about just using something natural like vitamin C excellent for you and not bad tasting. Suggestion: don&apos;t waste the $0.69 just get the carmel apple sundae forget about the nasty apples, cut them up at home and add them. Fuey..I can&apos;t get this taste out of my mouth!...
 Read full review Report this review 

 
 Portia 

 Reviews written: 6 
 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★☆☆ 
Written on: 10/10/2011

 “Chargrilled Egg” 

Ok when i was last visiting family we went to Meadowhall and because of our budget went to McDomalds for breakfast, well this is terrible because the staff where very ignorant some didnt even speak clear english and we ordered egg muffins, when they came out the muffin was burnt and the egg was what can be described as sloppy, would i eat that again? no i didnt even eat it then....
 Read full review Report this review 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★★★ 
Written on: 07/09/2011

 “AWWWW YEA” 

McDonalds is by far the best fast-food restaurant I&apos;ve ever eaten at. I pity the fool that doesn&apos;t eat here. If you don&apos;t eat at McDonalds your probably just sitting at home picking your butt for your supper. It may not be the best quality but it tastes awesome, even better than your mother&apos;s downstairs....
 Read full review Report this review 

 
 kittehs 

 Reviews written: 1 
 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 04/09/2011

 “HORRIBLE” 

the cashiers cheat you out of your money, and the food is badly made. don&apos;t buy a big mac, when you try to eat it, everything will fall out and get all over your hands. i was very disappointed. don&apos;t be decieved by the pictures, in real live the food SUCKS. when i tried to the the cashier about the mistake, he just tried to change the subject. i will never buy from mcdonalds again. the cashiers are rude and annoying, and the food is pathetic :( ...
 Read full review Report this review 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★☆☆☆☆ 
Written on: 31/07/2011

 “No!” 

Dude okay so I&apos;m not gonna say anything cuz people say,&quot;If your not gonna say anything nice then don&apos;t say anything at all.&quot;I rest my case here. GOOD DAY!...
 Read full review Report this review 

 WRITE A REVIEW ★★★☆☆ 
Written on: 27/05/2011

 “Just coffee, please” 

I only order coffee there, because it is a very good roast they have for a very good price. ...
 Read full review Report this review See next 10 reviews Showing 41 - 50 of 119 Reviews Next Review overview 
 Share this page? 
 Business Owner? Claim your free Review Centre Star Rating badge now! 
 Top 5 Chain&amp;Franchise Restaurants   To calculate the top 5&apos;s we take the following factors into account:

•All the star ratings the company/product has received,
•The number of reviews
•How recent the reviews are 
 
As rated by real users

 
 1. Nandos 
 90 reviews read latest review 
 2. Harvester Restaurants 
 263 reviews read latest review 
 3. Subway 
 35 reviews read latest review 
 4. Wagamama 
 20 reviews read latest review 
 5. Brewers Fayre 
 106 reviews read latest review 
 
 Latest Reviews in Chain&amp;Franchise Restaurants 
 
 McDonalds 
&quot;Quarterpounder craving less th...&quot; Read More 
 Perfect Pizza 
&quot;Not satisfied&quot; Read More 
 Nandos 
&quot;Never Again!!!&quot; Read More 
 Frankie&amp;Benny&apos;s 
&quot;The waitress forgot about us -...&quot; Read More 
 Chiquitos 
&quot;Worst food for a very long time&quot; Read More 
 
 
 Latest items in Chain&amp;Franchise Restaurants 
 
 Ask, Victoria Red Hot Buffet - www.redhot-worldbuffet.com Ask Park Street, Bristol Crown Carveries - www.crowncarveries.co.uk Taller De Tapas 
 
 Awaiting Reviews 
 
 Harvey Nichols Restaurants Walkabout Jamies Bars Café Nova Ha Ha Bar and Canteen 
 
 Hot Stuff in Chain&amp;Franchise Restaurants 
 
 Pizza Hut Pizza Express Wagamama Nandos Prezzo 
   
 Privacy Policy Terms and Conditions Contact Help Site Map Review Centre Forums Feedback ©Review Centre 2012 
 
 Home 
 rView Blog Review Centre Twitter Review Centre Surveys Review Centre on Facebook Review Centre Deals 
 
Electronics
 
 Audio Computers In-Car Electronics Mobile Phones Office Equipment Personal Care Photography&amp;Camcorders TV&amp;Home Cinema 
 
Entertainment
 
 Attractions Book Reviews Computer Game and Console Reviews Eating Out Film Reviews Going Out Magazines and Newspapers Music Reviews Musical Instruments&amp;Equipment TV&amp;Radio 
 
Home&amp;Garden
 
 Crafts DIY&amp;Tools Food and Drink Garden Tools Garden and Outdoors Home Improvement Homeware&amp;Furnishings Pets and Animals Utilities and Services 
 
Kitchen&amp;Home Appliances
 
 Cleaning Cooking Drinks Makers Fans and Heaters Food Preparation Fridges and Freezers Laundry and Dishwashers 
 
Life&amp;Style
 
 Beauty Catalogues Clothing&amp;Accessories Education Health High Street Shopping Parenting Weddings&amp;Brides 
 
Money
 
 Business Careers Credit and Debit Cards Currency and Foreign Exchange Debt and Financial Advice Insurance Loans Mortgages Pensions&amp;Investments Property Saving and Banking 
 
Motoring
 
 Buying and Selling Car and Motorbike Accessories Car Reviews Caravans Driving Maintenance and Servicing Motorbikes Motoring Websites Scooters and Mopeds 
 
Sport&amp;Leisure
 
 Bikes, Cycling&amp;Accessories Exercise&amp;Fitness Golf Indoor Sports&amp;Games Outdoor Sports&amp;Activities Shooting&amp;Fishing Skiing&amp;Snowboarding Team Sports Water Sports 
 
Travel
 
 Booking a Holiday Camping&amp;Caravanning Car Hire Cruise Reviews Airline Reviews Getting There Holiday Resorts&amp;Destinations Holiday Essentials Hotels&amp;Accommodation Travel Agents Travel Services Type of Holiday 
 
Websites
 
 Gaming&amp;Gambling Sites Money&amp;Finance Sites News, Reference&amp;Information Sites Online Communities Online Shops 
 
 Register / Login 
 You are here: Review Centre Eating Out Chain&amp;Franchise Restaurants McDonalds Overview
	</body>
</document>
