<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001293" url="http://www.nj.com/news/index.ssf/2011/02/nj_toll_booth_collectors_rally.html" time="2012-07-12-16:44" support="1" score="0.0014264815242117578" bingtitle="N.J. toll booth collectors, N.J. Turnpike Authority accuse each ..." webtitle="N.J. toll booth collectors, N.J. Turnpike Authority accuse each other of misleading info amid privatization proposal | 						NJ.com">
			<query id="000977" bing-rank="231"/>
	<description>... bidders, which is totally out of order and it ... than pumping gas or working at a fast food restaurant. ... What do you expect 12.00 an hour after all those ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign in | Register for free Sign in to NJ.com Username   Password Remember me I forgot my username or password» Don&apos;t have an account?
 Register now for free , or sign in with any of these services:

 

 AIM    Google    OpenID 
 Site Search Search Local Business Listings 
 
 Home News Weather Sports Entertainment Living Interact Jobs Autos Real Estate Rentals Classifieds Find n Save 
 Home &gt; New Jersey Real-Time News &gt; Transportation 
N.J. toll booth collectors, N.J. Turnpike Authority accuse each other of misleading info amid privatization proposal

Published: Wednesday, February 23, 2011, 8:50 PM   Updated: Thursday, February 24, 2011, 5:24 AM 
 By Mike Frassinelli/The Star-Ledger The Star-Ledger 
 Follow 62 Tweet Share close Digg Stumble Upon Fark Reddit Share Email Print John Munson/The Star-Ledger Gregory Junemann, president of the International Federation of Professional and Technical Engineers, talks to member&apos;s of IFPTE Local 194 as they rally against Turnpike Authority&apos;s proposed privatization efforts in the lobby of the Authority&apos;s headquarters while a meeting of commissioners is held inside. 

 WOODBRIDGE —As a deadline nears for bids to privatize toll collection on the state’s two major toll roads, existing toll collectors and the authority that oversees them accused each other of putting out misleading information.

Collectors said the New Jersey Turnpike Authority distorted a Feb. 8 letter from the union president urging members to pack today’s meeting of the authority, which oversees the New Jersey Turnpike and Garden State Parkway.

Franceline Ehret, in the letter, called on members of International Federation of Professional and Technical Engineers Local No. 194 to attend if they were off the clock. Stressing the importance of saving jobs, she encouraged workers to take personal or vacation days to attend.

Authority legal counsel Brian Kronick sent a cease-and-desist notice to Ehret on Friday, saying she was directing members to not report for duty, an action that would impede Turnpike operations.
 John Munson/The Star-Ledger As members of the International Federation of Professional and Technical Engineers (IFPTE) Local 194 rally against Turnpike Authority&apos;s proposed privatization efforts in the lobby of the Authority&apos;s headquarters, Authority chairman James Simpson leads a meeting of commissioners inside. 
&quot;Nowhere does she direct her members not to report to duty on Feb. 23, so that’s just not true,&quot; union official Frank Forst said at the meeting.

After the meeting, state Transportation Commissioner Jim Simpson, who chairs the Turnpike Authority, told reporters he was unhappy with the actions of union members.

&quot;They published a letter that was really untrue that talked about the fact that I wanted to outsource maintenance next—which was a total lie,&quot; Simpson said. &quot;And they have been contacting the prospective bidders, which is totally out of order and it’s not professional.&quot;

Ehret said many toll takers have applied for jobs with the potential bidders in case toll collections are privatized, and she had officially introduced herself to the companies.

The bid deadline is March 7 but the authority could keep existing workers in place.

Ehret said toll collectors have proposed $16 million in cuts—above the $12 million to $14 million in savings the authority requested—but has received no response. Union contracts expire June 30.

Among the union proposals are a 3.5-percent pay cut and elimination of 100 collecting jobs through retirements and transfers. Also, for new hires the top of the pay scale would be $25.53 an hour (about $53,100 a year), down from $31.58 hourly (about $65,700 a year).

Turnpike and Parkway toll collectors are better paid than their counterparts on the George Washington Bridge ($61,000 a year) and Pennsylvania Turnpike ($55,000).
 
Previous coverage: 

• N.J. Turnpike, Garden State Parkway toll collectors are mulling concessions to avoid privatization
 
• N.J. Turnpike toll collectors protest privatization plan 

• Employees protest plans to privatize N.J. Turnpike, Garden State Parkway jobs in Woodbridge
 

 Related topics: garden-state-parkway , nj-turnpike , woodbridge 
 
Sponsored Links
 
 Share this story Print Email Story tools 
 
More stories in New Jersey Real-Time News
 Previous story
 Newark airport program helps autistic children cope with air travel Next story
 Authorities: Stolen human remains from 2 Middlesex cemeteries could be rituals of religious cult Copyright 2012 NJ.com. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 62 
Comments Feed 
 View: 
 
 Oldest first | Newest first   1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 Next comments » lexii3 February 23, 2011 at 9:11PM Follow 

$31.58 to take quarters? HaHa no wonder NJ is broke. A Home Health Aid who is responsible for the care of the elderly makes about $13.00 and hour after 20 years. And in most cases must pay for their own gas to go to each client. Geeze, I wish I told my son to become a toll collector instead of going to college.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new sadpunkin February 23, 2011 at 9:30PM Follow 

Yes, we have warped values in our society.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new smellnj February 23, 2011 at 10:50PM Follow 

You should see what they take home after OVERTIME... Plus, don&apos;t forget the nice Pension......

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new PleaseDontHate February 24, 2011 at 10:25AM Follow 

That&apos;s not a lot of money .especially for that dangerous job their doing. You people sound so jealous ! Stop complaining and get better paying jobs people. Don&apos;t hate on people because they are making more than you. I wish everyone made at least 200,oooo a year like me but they can&apos;t. I. Would never wish bad on anyone. . I just want. To see evryone doing well

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new towaho February 23, 2011 at 10:01PM Follow 

State government unions across the board have done so well that they have now reached the point where they have effectively negotiated many of their members out of their jobs. A job as a toll collector should not be confused with a career. It&apos;s no different than pumping gas or working at a fast food restaurant. How many gas stations or fast food restaurants would stay in business paying $35 an hour?

Granted the job exposes collectors to some toxic fumes but when you pay wages that are out of line with responsibilities you only encourage those people to stay for decades doing it. Market wages will encourage people to move on to better jobs.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new Lemonpie February 23, 2011 at 10:05PM Follow 

Get the facts straight. The state does not pay the collectors. The driving public does. The turnpike has a huge surplus and has a big profit every year. So now no one can make a decent living. I have no problem with someone who is there at that job for over 25 years making 31.00 an hour. What do you expect 12.00 an hour after all those years. So now they will reduce the pay and all those guys will leave and go on unemployment or retire into the system that is not funded. We will pay in the long run. Personally I would keep them all working make changes for new hires. If they stay working they will pay taxes, buy products and support their family. From what I read there was a man their with his kids. He said the one son will be starting college. So now if this guy loses his job or has to take a pay cut to 12.00 an hour. We will pay for his son to get more state financial aid. We pay one way or another. Keep our people working and making decent wages no matter what their job is. Alot of the people that use that rode are from out of state.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new WakeupNJ February 23, 2011 at 10:07PM Follow 

@Lemonpie....everything you say is spot on. The problem is people will attack you for making sense I am sorry to say.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new too 303 February 23, 2011 at 10:11PM Follow 

anyone who is content to make a &quot;career&quot; out of tollbooth collecting doesn&apos;t deserve a 65,000 a year income. besides, why do you think that &quot;years on the job&quot; entitles you to higher pay for the exact same job?

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new Lemonpie February 23, 2011 at 10:21PM Follow 

I has gotten to be nowadays no one can make a decent living. Look I don&apos;t really care if you are the garbage man. If you go to work everyday, pay your taxes, support your family, and do the job good you should be making a living wage. Its easy to say now but some of those people took that job over 25 years ago so now we are just suppose to drop them and everything they have earned. Very selfish attitude to fellow American workers.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new Creasy February 23, 2011 at 10:26PM Follow 

Lemon, this will be the future of NJ. We will have people who point the finger, and say &quot;you make to much money&quot;, well, how are people suppose to live here? Not all of us married into cash.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new too 303 February 23, 2011 at 10:27PM Follow 

@lemon, 65k to make change is slightly more than &quot;making a decent living&quot;
If that&apos;s your conviction, though, then at least have the courage to extend that to every walk of life - from the cashier at wal-mart to the gas station attendant. they all deserve $35 an hour for their effort.... Meanwhile, enjoy paying $10 a gallon for your gas and $8 for a loaf of bread.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new PleaseDontHate February 24, 2011 at 10:03AM Follow 

Cashiers at walmart are not risking there lives everyday. Inhalling fumes , having children born with respiratory problems, working in the cold, and putting there hands in rat feces left in the draws out there. That just doesn&apos;t compare

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new btdw February 25, 2011 at 3:04PM Follow 

one of my friends lost her private jobs and then took a job as a toll collector .Part time and was held up at gun point twice at the Bidwell liberty park toll plaza great job ???? boy she she getting over on the tax payers.
By the way she also payers taxes

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new towaho February 23, 2011 at 10:16PM Follow 

Lemone &quot; I have no problem with someone who is there at that job for over 25 years making 31.00 an hour.&quot;

Why exactly should people doing a job that can be done for $12 an hour make $31? If you ran a business would you pay $31 for a low skill position when you could pay a third that? What viable entity pays hundreds of percent more than needed to fill their positions?

Wakeup, you can also name those entities?

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new lexii3 February 23, 2011 at 10:23PM Follow 

I understand what you are saying, but the blame is on the union. This type of job years ago would be done by a teenager working partime. Just like someone else said it is like working at a gas station, or fast food restaurant. The unions have priced themselves out of the market. How do you think the big three auto companies went bankrupt? $53.00 and hour to screw bolts into an engine? Why do you think so many businesses left our country to go overseas? They could not afford the union pay scales anymore. The unions became their own worst enemy. It is not rocket science to understand this.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new   1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 Next comments » 
 
Post a comment
 (You may use HTML tags for style) 
 

You must accept the terms of service before you can post a comment.
 
Post a comment
 
Sign in to NJ.com
 Username Password 
  Remember me? I forgot my username or password» 
Don&apos;t have an account?

 Register now for free , or sign in with any of these services:
 
 AIM Google OpenID 
 
More New Jersey Real-Time News

 Most Comments Most Recent 
 
 New Jersey Real-Time News stories with the most comments in the last 7 days. 719 Tough talk on the boardwalk: Chris Christie&apos;s heated exchange at Jersey Shore caught on video 286 26,000 N.J. residents will lose extended unemployment benefits this week 183 N.J. teacher who slapped unruly special education student will keep job 144 Memo: N.J. revenue for last fiscal year is $200M short of Christie&apos;s revised projections 142 Second video spurs conflicting views of disabled man&apos;s beating by N.J. State Police 
 
Most Active Users
 What&apos;s this? 
 Users with the most NJ.com comments in the last 7 days 173 tangledhair 147 BrassBand5 94 CountyWatcher2 92 sage1959 86 TMoor 
 

Users We Love
 NJ.com user nl10781 
Posted photos of his Devils collectables More Users We Love 
Connect with NJ.com
 What&apos;s this? 
 
 All Facebook&amp;Twitter accounts » From Our Advertisers 

 
 Advertise With Us» 
Popular Tags
 What&apos;s this? 

 
 Site Search Search Local Business Listings 
 Site Map | Advertise | Contact Make us your home page Home | News | Weather | Sports | Entertainment | Living | Interact | Jobs | Autos | Real Estate | Classifieds | Deals | Place an Ad 
 Your Photos Your Videos Blogs Forums NJ Shore NJ Weddings 
 
 Post a Job Post a Free Classified Ad Sell Your Car Sell/Rent Your Home Apartments&amp;Rentals Claim Your Business
   Listing for Free 
 
 Business High School Sports NJ Lottery New Jersey Politics Obituaries Pets 
 
 Subscribe to our content (RSS) Sign up for news alerts NJ.com Twitter feed Ledger Live vodcast View NJ.com mobile site View mobile product offerings 
 Special home delivery offers! The Star-Ledger | The Times, Trenton | The Jersey Journal | Gloucester Co. Times 
 The News of Cumberland County | Today&apos;s Sunbeam 
 Registration on or use of this site constitutes acceptance of our User Agreement and Privacy Policy (Revised November 1, 2011)

©2012 New Jersey On-Line LLC. All rights reserved ( About Us ).
The material on this site may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, cached or otherwise used, except with the prior written permission of New Jersey On-Line LLC.

 Community Rules apply to all content you upload or otherwise submit to this site. Contact interactivity management .

 Ad Choices
	</body>
</document>
