<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001245" url="http://www.coursehero.com/file/5667525/Chap007/" time="2012-07-12-16:41" support="1" score="0.0009835887053913518" bingtitle="UNL : MNGT 422X : Chap007 - Course Hero | Study Guides, Lecture ..." webtitle="UNL : MNGT 422X : Chap007">
			<query id="000643" bing-rank="246"/>
	<description>Pick five online businesses in the same industry. ... from a large number of companies and pay by credit card ... Any fast food restaurant classifies as this type, while examples ...</description>
	<body>
		Course Hero Sign up Log-in 
 Home Study Documents 
 Find Documents Textbook Help 
 Tutors 
 Ask a Question Browse Questions 
 Courses 
 Find Courses Create a Course Suggest a Course About Courses 
 Flashcards 
 Find Flashcards Create Flashcards About Flashcards 
 Support 
 Contact Us FAQ 
 
 
Why Course Hero?
 7 Million Study Materials From students who&apos;ve taken these classes before 24/7 Access to Tutors Personal attention for all your questions Learn 93% of our members earn better grades 
 Register now to access 7 million high quality study materials. Chap007 Course: MNGT 422X, Spring 2009 
 School: UNL 
 Rating:           
 Related: 
 Document Preview 
 07 Chapter - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
CHAPTER 7: SMALL BUSINESS STRATEGIES: IMITATION WITH A TWIST
Chapter Summary
This chapter introduces a number of tools some of which have been touched on in earlier chapters: industry analysis, value chain analysis, SWOT analysis, industry life cycle, VRIO Analysis, and Porters generic strategies. The strategic planning process is discussed as are... 
 Register Now 
 
MOST POPULAR MNGT MATERIALS
 
 Chap020 
 UNL
MNGT 422X 
 Chap013 
 UNL
MNGT 422X 
 Chap016 
 UNL
MNGT 422X 
MOST POPULAR UNL MATERIALS
 
 [Actuary] ... 
 UNL
ECON 101 
 BSAD 101 E... 
 UNL
BSAD 101 
 ch7 ex3 
 UNL
ECON 211 Ask a Tutor my question   * -- Select a subject -- Accounting Biology Business Chemistry Civil Engineering Computer Science Economics Electrical Engineering English Finance Math Mechanical Engineering Operations Management Other Subjects Physics Statistics and Probability Writing Help * Due Date: Time: Any 12 AM 1 AM 2 AM 3 AM 4 AM 5 AM 6 AM 7 AM 8 AM 9 AM 10 AM 11 AM 12 PM 1 PM 2 PM 3 PM 4 PM 5 PM 6 PM 7 PM 8 PM 9 PM 10 PM 11 PM morning afternoon evening Attachment (optional): Get help Now! Our current time in (CST) is     Unformatted Document Excerpt Coursehero &gt;&gt; Nebraska &gt;&gt; UNL &gt;&gt; MNGT 422X Course Hero has millions of student submitted documents similar to the one
 below including study guides, practice problems, reference materials, practice exams, textbook help and tutor support. 07 Chapter - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
CHAPTER 7: SMALL BUSINESS STRATEGIES: IMITATION WITH A TWIST
Chapter Summary
This chapter introduces a number of tools some of which have been touched on in earlier chapters: industry analysis, value chain analysis, SWOT analysis, industry life cycle, VRIO Analysis, and Porters generic strategies. The strategic planning process is discussed as are the strategic options a firm faces. The types of benefits that win customers are explored and the concept of competitive advantage is introduced.
Learning Objectives
After studying this chapter, the student should be able to: 1. 2. 3. 4. 5. 6. 7. Learn the decisions needed as a foundation for strategic planning. Know the forms for imitative and innovative businesses. Articulate the benefits that win over customers. Use SWOT analysis to identify strategic options. Understand the major strategies of business differentiation, cost and focus. Use value chain analysis to apply strategy throughout the firm. Learn how to sustain competitive advantage through attracting customers and discouraging competition.
Focus on Small Business:
Mindnautilus.com Taking a family idea that had been proposed at the wrong time, Nick Tostenrude and Dennis Moulton formed Mindnautilus, a firm that sold cognitive functioning software via the Internet to people recovering from brain trauma. They have since expanded into related assistive devices and other software for disabled or injured people through their firm Enablemart. The key to their success? Finding the right niche. Instructor information: The Mindnautilus case is a great example of the idea of the corridor principle. While most folks in entrepreneurship think of it as coming from Bob Ronstadt (Ronstadt, R.C. 1988. The corridor principle. Journal of Business Venturing, 3, no. 1: 31-40), the idea was actually a major tenet of career theorist Samuel Osipows open systems model of careers (Theories of career development, 1973). Both authors liken career experience (regular or entrepreneurial) to walking down a corridor full of closed doors. As you walk down the corridor of life as an entrepreneur, you get the chance to open some of the doors. Some of the doors may set you on a new path.
7-1
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
That is what happened to Nick and Dennis. They ended up changing the fundamental strategies of their business from software to retailing, from conventional sales to the fledgling internet sales, and from a focus on their own products to a focus on the products of others. What was comparatively constant in their approach was their focus on their customer segment (those with handicaps who would benefit from assistive devices), and how to best serve this group. The case is a great starting point for students who only have an inkling of what kind of business they think might work, and it serves as a cautionary tale to those who are absolutely certain they know exactly what needs to be done. Nick and Dennis strength from a strategic analysis standpoint is that they let the information they gathered guide their identification and articulation of a business. Their initial passion for the software sustained their hard work learning about the industry, the market and the needs out there, but when the data began to point to other businesses, they let reason come to the front, helping to identify a business that would work. Armed with this insight, they reignited and refocused their passion on making the retailing business work. For all these reasons, Mindnautilus is a great starting point for thinking about the power of strategic analysis, and a good transition from the discussion of entrepreneurial paths, which weve looked at in the prior 2 chapters, to the discussion of specific entrepreneurial actions. Discussion Questions 1. What were the strengths Mindnautilus possessed? What were the weaknesses it faced? Their strengths were that they had an in-depth understanding of the target market people with cognitive disabilities. The market was large. They also had extensive (for the time) knowledge about creating Internet shopping sites using available software. Combining the large market and the Internet, they had a good fit of sales channel (online) and market (diffuse). They had the some support from Dennis father (who created the software), and there were two partners available to work, Nick and Dennis, and they had time to devote to the business. The weaknesses were a lack of suitable sales channels for the product, a lack of customers with the right equipment for using the therapeutic software, and ramping the software up to meet customer expectations in a more sophisticated market. The team lacked the funds to finish the R&amp;D.
7-2
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
2.
What would Mindnautilus do better than its competition? Mindnautilus focused on being a superior marketing organization. Their website offered a variety of assistive products. They marketed their website to major organizations (like Microsoft and Goodwill) gaining credibility and visibility. Building on this, they would become one of the most effective sales outlets for many of their suppliers, strengthening their relationships with suppliers, and decreasing the chance of suppliers competing with Mindnautilus.
3.
What kind of strategy did Nick and Dennis plan for Mindnautilus? The original plan was to create a software company. The final plan was to create an online store (or catalog). Some folks will take Nicks comment at face value Find a niche. Indeed Mindnautilus fills a niche for assitive technologies for the disabled. But is the disabled a niche? It absolutely can be seen as one. However, some folks could make the argument that the disabled are actually a mass market (millions of people scattered all over the country or world), and Mindnautilus followed a differentiation strategy, giving their mass market customers a broader selection, or the convenience of one-stop shopping, or the benefit of the expertise of Mindnautilus. Using this sort of approach, an answer of a mass-market differentiation strategy might be supportable. Not knowing from the case the advertising approach used, a student could reasonably go either way, although the niche market approach is the simpler and more straightforward answer.
4.
Do you think Dennis and Nick could have predicted they would start Enablemart when they started Mindnautilus? Why or why not? It is unlikely that Dennis and Nick could have predicted their becoming a retailer when their intention was to sell software. They might have figured they would have to market their own product, but the idea of become a clearinghouse for other companies products might have seemed at first to be a major distraction from their goal of getting their own software into the marketplace.
7-3
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Extended Chapter Outline
Note: Key terms are in boldface. Teaching tool International application Internet application Group activity
Objective 1: Learn the decisions needed as a foundation for strategic planning. 1.1 Strategy is the idea and actions that explain how the firm will make its profit. 1.1.1 Good strategy leads to greater chances of survival and higher profits 1.1.2 Since most small businesses are imitative rather than innovative, strategy becomes very important. Strategy is based on four major decisions: 1.2.1 The product or service youve chosen (also known as the industry); 1.2.2 The scope of the market you plan to serve, which can range from local to global; 1.2.3 The scale of the market for your product or service, whether it is a mass market or a niche market; and 1.2.4 The decision to go for a firm that imitates existing businesses or one that seeks to be innovative. Strategy is a four step process: Pre-strategy, benefits, strategy and competitive advantage. Pre-Strategy has the goal of deciding on the product or service you intend to offer and the scale and scope of your market. 1.4.1 The first step is to determine the industry that you want to be in. 1.4.1.1 Select an industry that offers good potential for making a profit. 1.4.1.2 Select an industry with a minimum of risk and competition. 1.4.2 Use the industrys code number to seek out information about the industry. 1.4.2.1 Use either the NAICS or SIC code.
1.2
1.3 1.4
Skill Module 7.1: Finding Your Firms Industry This exercise helps students determine their firms NAICS and SIC codes. If the classroom is smart, work through this exercise in class, but for something other than restaurant. Use this industry throughout the lecture to illustrate other techniques as well.
7-4
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
1.4.2.2
Trade and professional organizations as well as the government collect and report data by NAICS or SIC code.
Teaching tool: Have the students work in groups. Give each group several copies of trade magazines for different industries. If available, have them use the Internet to find NAICS or SIC number, and other trade associations that might be affiliated with the industry. Have them visit the Websites of these associations and other trade magazines. From all this information, they should be able to compose a list of helps for starting a business in this industry.
1.4.3
The next step is to look at the market for your product or service and its scale and scope.
Skill Module 7.2: Finding Your Trade of Professional Organization This exercise helps the student find his firms trade or professional association either via the Internet or through trade magazines. Continue with the industry chosen above. 1.4.3.1 Scale has to do with the size of the market. 1.4.3.1.1 A markets scale may cover large portions of the populations a mass market. 1.4.3.1.2 It may also cover a narrowly defined segment of the populations a niche market. 1.4.3.1.3 Most industries have both mass and niche markets 1.4.3.2 Scope looks at the markets geographic spread. 1.4.3.2.1 A markets scope may be local to global; most small businesses tend to be local in scope. 1.4.3.2.2 Scope helps you determine where to focus your sales and advertising efforts. 1.4.3.2.3 Scope also helps you identify the more important competitors.
7-5
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Objective 2: Know the forms for imitative and innovative businesses. 2.1 Businesses have several choices. 2.1.1 Many do more or less what others do in an imitative strategy. 2.1.1.1 Advantages include being able to buy existing technology. 2.1.1.2 Vendors and service suppliers are familiar with what you are doing. 2.1.1.3 Customers already know about your product or service and you dont have to educate them. 2.1.2 An innovative strategy is pursued by those firms doing something very different than whats been done before. 2.1.2.1 The advantage here is making your business precisely fit your own ideas and preferences. 2.1.2.2 The main disadvantage is in the energy needed to market these products. 2.1.3 Most firms operate somewhere on the continuum of purely innovative to cloned, imitative businesses, and varying on degrees of similarity. 2.1.3.1 If your business if basically the same as the competition with a few minor differences, you are following a parallel competition approach. 2.1.3.2 Add a few more significant changes in one or two key areas, and you are following an incremental innovation approach. 2.1.3.3 A brand new product or service is pure innovation.
7-6
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
2.2
2.1.3.4 The main tool to use in this pre-strategy phase is Industry Analysis (IA), which gives the small business owner key information about the industry.
Skill Module 7.3: Short and Sweet Industry Analysis: This exercise helps the student conduct the five steps of an Industry Analysis: 1. SIC/NACIS number 2. Industry size over time 3. Profitability, including gross profit, net profit, and profit before taxes. 4. How profits are made 5. Target market competitor concentration 6. Analysis 7. Sources While doing an IA is an important step in exploring possible industries, the fact that some of this information is for pay only can be discouraging. Many universities allow graduates (and sometimes the general public) permanent access to library resources. Other times, a SCORE office may be affiliated with a university and may be able to help get the information you need. Teaching tool: Check out your universitys library to see what resources are available to assist in doing IAs. If some of these resources are available electronically, show students how to get to them and use them. This may be a good time to have a reference librarian as a guest speaker or to have a session in the library to familiarize students with the resources available. As mentioned under the skill module 7.3, check out your universities policy on access to this information for graduates.
2.2.1 2.2.2 2.2.3
This tool tells you if the industry is likely to meet your income needs. You can determine potential financial growth. It helps you identify your competitive challenges.
7-7
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Objective 3: Articulate the benefits that win over customers.
3.1
The second step in the strategy process is determining what benefits you offer your customer. 3.1.1 The best way to do that is to talk to your potential customers. (More on this in chapter 10.) 3.1.2 Value benefits include quality, style, delivery, service, technology, ease of shopping, personalization, assurance, place, brand or reputation, belonging and altruism. 3.1.3 Cost benefits come from lowering costs, scale or scope economies and greater efficiencies.
The Thoughtful Entrepreneur: Value and Cost Benefits Listed here are definitions of the various cost and value benefits possible. Have students come up with examples of companies large and small that make use of these benefits. 3.1.4
3.1.5
Benefits are how you appeal to your target customer and are reflected throughout your marketing plan, further discussed in chapter 12. Deciding on what benefits you may wish to concentrate is a matter of looking for the right entry wedge from the following list: 3.1.5.1 Supply shortages 3.1.5.2 Unutilized resources 3.1.5.3 Customer contracting. 3.1.5.4 Second sourcing. 3.1.5.5 Market relinquishment. 3.1.5.6 Favored purchasing. 3.1.5.7 Government rules
Small Business Insights: Initiative for a Competitive Inner City Sundra Ryce founded SLR Construction Service Company in Buffalo, New Yorks inner city, using the underutilized resources entry wedge. Have students identify other companies that have made use of these entry wedges.
7-8
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Objective 4: Use SWOT analysis to identify strategic options.
4.1
SWOT Analysis stands for strengths, weaknesses, opportunities and threats and is the tool for the strategy step of the strategy process. 4.1.1 Strengths are characteristics of the business that give it an advantage over others in the industry. 4.1.2 Weaknesses are characteristics that place the firm at a disadvantage relative to others. 4.1.3 Opportunities are chances to make greater sales or profits in the environment. 4.1.4 Threats are elements of the environment that could cause trouble to the business. This well known tool looks at present and future and is an excellent way to help you organize your business strategy. There are a number of ways to gather information for your SWOT analysis. 4.3.1 From yourself; 4.3.2 From others who know your firm or the market or industry; 4.3.3 From customers or potential customers; and 4.3.4 From brainstorming sessions
4.2 4.3
Skill Module 7.4: The Mechanics of a SWOT Analysis This exercise walks the students through SWOT Analysis steps and offers assistance in finding a firms strengths, weaknesses, opportunities and threats. One mistake many people make about SWOT is confusing strengths with opportunities and weaknesses with threats. This distinction probably cannot be emphasized enough. Teaching tool: One firm students know a lot about is their university. Have them do a SWOT Analysis on it. Should the university flaunt, fix, fight or flee?
4.3.5
The Mindnautilus.com opening vignette illustrates several SWOT components.
7-9
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
4.4
Once the SWOT analysis is completed the firms best strategic direction can be determined: flaunt, fix, fight or flee. 4.4.1 Flaunt and focus your efforts if your strengths match opportunities. 4.4.2 Fix weaknesses that get in the way of pursuing opportunities. 4.4.3 Fight threats with your strengths. 4.4.4 Flee when threats are made worse by weaknesses. Finally, match your SWOT Analysis against the benefits sought by your market.
4.5
Objective 5: Understand the major strategies of business differentiation, cost and focus. 5.1
5.2
The next step is to select the actual strategy. The strategies possible are so widely applicable that they are called generic strategies. 5.2.1 Showing how your products or services are different than your competitions products or services is known as differentiation strategy. This strategy is aimed at a mass market 5.2.2 Cost strategy, also aimed at mass markets, shows how your product or service offers cost benefits the competition does not. 5.2.3 Concentrating efforts on a segment of the mass market is known as focus strategy. 5.2.3.1 A focus strategy generally uses aspects of cost or differentiation as well. 5.2.3.2 A small firm (especially service firms) often focuses on a specific geographic area and competes within this area on cost or differentiation. As an extension, there are seven small business supra-strategies that can be pursued: 5.3.1 Craftsmanship 5.3.2 Customization 5.3.3 Super-Support 5.3.4 Serving the Underserved/Interstices 5.3.5 Elite 5.3.6 Single-mindedness 5.3.7 Comprehensiveness
5.3
7-10
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
5.4
In addition, there are several strategies that can be pursued by highly-fragmented industries. They are: 5.4.1 Formula strategies (e.g., franchising); 5.4.2 Bare bones or no-frills provider (e.g., Wal-Mart); 5.4.3 Cutting out the intermediary (e.g., stands); and 5.4.4 Tightly manage decentralization (i.e., opening related firms that capitalize on your expertise). Teaching tool: List a number of businesses with which your students are familiar. For the purposes of this exercise, you may use both small and large businesses. Have students decide which generic strategy then think they follow as well as supra-strategies or highly-fragmented industry strategies as appropriate.
Objective 6: Use value chain analysis to apply strategy throughout the firm.
6.1
Value Chain Analysis is a tool that helps you ascertain that the benefits the customer wants get applied throughout the firm. 6.1.1 The value chain itself is all the activities that support the product or service designing, marketing, delivering, and supporting and includes inbound logistics, operations, outbound logistics, marketing and sales and service. 6.1.2 Support activities such as infrastructure, human resources, technology and procurement are considered as well. 6.1.3 Two outcomes are evaluated for each component: 6.1.3.1 What does/can each of these add to the profit margin? 6.1.3.2 How does each component contribute to the strategy of the firm? 6.1.4 The idea behind value chain is to think through each different part of the business to make sure they are all working together efficiently and effectively towards the common goal.
Objective 7: Learn how to sustain competitive advantage through attracting customers and discouraging competition
7.1
Competitive advantage is the particular way your firm stays ahead of other firms in the industry based on the way you implement the customer benefits you have selected.
7-11
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
7.2
Its harder than it looks to determine this because there are a number of threats a firm faces: 7.2.1 Existing firms are usually obvious. 7.2.2 Consider potential entrants to the industry. 7.2.3 What substitutes are there for your firms product or service? 7.2.4 Suppliers can have a major impact on your business. 7.2.5 Buyers or customers can also aversely affect your business. As a firm you have a variety of resources, both tangible resources and intangible resources. Organizational capabilities abilities, skills and competencies used by the firm are also important. 7.4.1 Transformational competencies happen when a firm can make its product or service better in value or more cost efficient than other firms. 7.4.2 Combinational competencies come from combining tangible and intangible resources in ways superior to the competition.
7.3
7.4
Small Business Insight: Early Years of the Vermont Teddy Bear Company John Sortino started The Vermont Teddy Bear Company in order to make a better teddy bear. His use of organizational capabilities took him from a hobby business to a widely successful company. Have students identify other firms that exhibit transformational or combinational competencies. 7.5 Besides tangible and intangible, there are other ways to describe and value resources: 7.5.1 A resource is valuable if it lets you take advantage of an opportunity or lock out a competitor. 7.5.2 A resource is rare if it is not generally available among your resources. 7.5.3 If a resource is difficult to imitate it helps secure your competitive advantage. Firms shold seek to discourage competitors. There are several ways to do this including: 7.6.1 Locking-in customers by increasing customer loyalty. 7.6.2 Retard or inhibit imitation, often by tradmarks, patents or other government interventions.
7.6
7-12
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
7.7
A tool useful to test your competitive advantage is VRIO Analysis.
Skills Module 7.5: VRIO Analysis This exercise takes the students through the four tests of VRIO Analysis: 1. Value 2. Rareness 3. Imitability 4. Organization This exercise works well if the students have a real resource to analyze. Try newspaper or magazine articles about a start-up company to find examples of these resources. Teaching tool: If the students conducted a SWOT analysis on the university, some of the strengths identified may include resources of the university. Select one of these and do a VRIO Analysis. If there are a number of resources identified, have different groups evaluate different resources and report to the class. 7.7.1
7.7.2
Often tangible resources will fail one of more of the first three tests; most of what survives VRIO are intangible resources. Resources and capabilities that pass VIRO are key components of your firm and help it perform its core competencies.
7.8
The last tool that is useful in determining strategy is to examine the Industry Life Cycle. 7.8.1 Introduction is right after the product has been invented. 7.8.1.1 Niche strategies are likely as the customer segment consists of only pioneers and early adopters. 7.8.1.2 The entrepreneurs strategy is to master the technology to make it a key resource 7.8.1.3 Differentiation strategies make sense to set yourself away from competition. 7.8.1.4 Single mindedness and super-support are good supra-strategies. 7.8.2 In the growth stage, sales go up rapidly. 7.8.2.1 The customer segment moves to the early majority. 7.8.2.2 Their demand creates a mass market. 7.8.2.3 Differentiation and innovation are good approaches. 7.8.2.4 The supra-strategies of craftsmanship, customization and elite fit will here.
7-13
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
7.8.3
7.8.4
7.8.5
In the maturity stage, demand stabilizes. 7.8.3.1 The customer segments is the late majority. 7.8.3.2 Cost strategies become more important. 7.8.3.3 Imitative approaches are common. 7.8.3.4 Single-mindedness and comprehensiveness are the supra-strategies now. The decline stage is where sales and profits fall. 7.8.4.1 The laggards finally become a key segment. 7.8.4.2 Cost cutting strategies and low-cost pricing are key. 7.8.4.3 Imitation but with extreme efficiencies or economies is the strategy. 7.8.4.4 Supra-strategies include serving underserved markets and customization. At this point, the industry dies or enters retrenchment where the industry is revitalized.
7.9
Strategy is the way an entrepreneur plots the path to success. Every business has a strategy and successful businesses have strategies that fit their industry, market and resources.
Key Terms
Benefits: characteristics of a product of service that the target customer would consider worthwhile. Brainstorming: a group discussion where people are asked to give their ideas and thoughts about a topic. Combinational competencies: organizational capabilities which come from combining tangible and intangible resources in ways superior to the competition. Competitive advantage: the particular way a firm implements customer benefits that keeps the firm ahead of other firms in the industry or market. Core competence: the main work of a firm in a particular line of business. Cost strategy: a generic strategy aimed at mass markets in which a firm offers a combination of cost benefits that appeals to the customer. Customer segment: a group or subgroup of potential purchasers that can be approached in a coherent manner. Decline stage: a life cycle stage when sales and profits of the firm begin a falling trend.
7-14
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Degree of similarity: the extent to which a product or service is like another. Differentiation strategy: a type of generic strategy that is aimed at clarifying how one product is unlike another in a mass market. Difficult to imitate: a resource characteristic that enhances value through offering uniqueness to the buyer. Early adopters: a customer adoption segment that purchases after pioneers. Early majority: customer adoption segment that purchases after early adopters, and whose demand creates the mass market. Entry wedge: is an opportunity that makes it possible for a new business to gain a foothold in a market. Focus strategy: a generic strategy that targets a portion of the market called a segment or niche. Generic strategies: three widely applicable classic strategies for businesses of all types differentiation, cost, and focus. Gross profit: funds left over after accounting for the cost of goods sold. Growth stage: an industry life cycle stage where customer purchases increase at a dramatic rate. Highly fragmented industries: collections of similar businesses where virtually all firms have small market shares. Imitative strategy: an overall strategic approach in which the entrepreneur does more or less what others are already doing. Incremental innovation: an overall strategic approach in which a firm patterns itself on other firms, with the exception of one or two key areas. Industry Analysis (IA): a research process that provides the entrepreneur with key information about the industry, its current situation and trends. Industry: the general name for the line of product or service being sold, or the firms in that line of business. Industry life cycle: describes the stages an industry goes through from its birth to its ending. There are five stages: introduction, growth, maturity, decline and death.
7-15
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Innovation strategy: and overall strategic approach in which the firm seeks to do something that is very different from others in the industry. Introduction stage: the life cycle stage when the product or service is being invented and initially developed. Laggard: a customer adoption segment that holds off until prices reach rock bottom, or they are forced to change. Late Majority: a customer adoption segment describing people who wait until the technology has stabilized and the costs have begun to drop. Market: the business term for the population of customers for your product or service. Mass market: a customer group that involves large portions of the population. Maturity stage: the third life cycle stage, marked by a stabilization of demand, with firms in the industry moving to stabilize or improve profits through cost strategies. Net profit: what is left after operating expenses for the business. Niche market: a narrowly defined segment of the population that is likely to share interests or concerns. Organizational capabilities: the abilities, skills and competencies, used by the firm to make profits from tangible and intangible resources. Parallel competition: an imitative business competing locally with others in the same industry. Pioneers: a customer adoption segment characterized by those most willing to be the first to try or have something new. Profit before taxes: what the owner or owners take out of the firm annually. Pure innovation: the process of creating new products or services, which results in a previously unseen product or service. Rare resource: an asset, capability, organizational process, information, or knowledge that is not generally available among competitors. Resource: any asset, capability, organizational process, information, or knowledge that contributes to the firms performance.
7-16
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Retrenchment: an organizational life cycle stage for established firms that involves finding new approaches pursued to improve the business and its chances for survival. Scale: a characteristic of a market, which describes is the size of the market; a mass market or a niche market. Scope: a characteristic of a market, which tells the geographic range covered by the market from local to global. Strategic direction: the conceptualization of how a business might best move in response to the findings of a SWOT analysis: flaunt, fix, fight or flee. Tangible resources: assets of a firm that can be easily and concretely identified. Intangible resources: capabilities, organizational processes, information, or knowledge of a firm that are not clearly evident. Trade association: a group of people who are in the same industry who band together to gather and share information, and present and represent the industry to the public and government (also known as professional association). Trade magazines: publications that target specific industries and professions. Transformational competencies: the capability of a firm to make its product or service in a way that enhances value or efficiency compared to other firms. Valuable resource: an asset, capability, organizational process, information, or knowledge that lets a firm take advantage of opportunities or locks out competitors. Value chain: a collection of processes and activities a small business does to design, produce, market, deliver and support its product or service.
7-17
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Discussion Questions:
NOTE: many questions allow for a number of different answers. Below are some suggestions. 1. What are the four steps of the strategic planning process in small business? The first stage involves the pre-strategy decisions you make which define you firm and your approach to it. Typically, these ideas are shown in a tool called an Industry Analysis. The second stage considers the benefits you want to offer your customers, and this information is tied to a SWOT Analysis. Te third stage is where you select a strategy, which is applied to the firm through Value Chain Analysis. The final state is where you work to assure you firms competitive advantage. 2. How can industry and trade associations help the small business get started and develop its strategy? They (along with government) gather and report industry data, telling you about how others in the industry fared. They can offer advice on how to get into the industry, sources of supply, pitfalls, government and regulatory issues. They can also connect you with others in your industry locally. Armed with such information, a potential entrepreneur can make far better informed decisions about whether a particular industry or trade makes sense, and what is the best way to get into that line of business. 3. What is the difference between a mass market and a niche market? Which is more likely to be something a small business can pursue? The difference is in the scale of the market for which a business crafts its strategy. A mass market is a market that involves large portions of the population all men, all women, all teens, all elderly, all families, all manufacturers, all restaurants. Mass markets are broad, and a mass-market approach targets the entire market. A niche market is a narrowly defined segment of the population that are likely to share interests or concerns 25-34 year old women, families with twins, Boy Scouts, Italian restaurants, manufacturers in your city. Niche markets are specific and narrow, and in a niche market approach, you try and target only customers in the niche. While most industries have both mass and niche markets, niche markets are more likely to fit with the resources and expertise levels of most small businesses, especially start-ups.
7-18
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
4.
What are the differences between innovative and imitative strategies? Which is more likely to be something a small business can pursue? Businesses pursuing imitative strategies do more of less what other businesses in that industry are doing. Businesses pursuing an innovative strategy are trying to do something substantially different from what has been done to date in that industry (or even in extreme cases - start a new industry). They differ in the level of prior knowledge about the product, service or market (imitative reflects higher prior knowledge). They differ in the level of risk perceived with innovation seen as riskier. They differ in the assurance people perceive in cost and profit projections again with innovation seen as riskier. Small businesses are more likely to pursue (and be able to pursue) an imitative strategy. It is more likely because more people do elect imitative approaches (as the PSED shows), and the existence of franchising as a major approach to start-ups reflects an extreme version of imitation. Following an imitative strategy also helps a small business leverage existing technologies, markets and knowledge about your product or service among customers and other stakeholders. This approach increases the initial legitimacy of a small business. Some small business founders elect an innovative strategy. It allows them to do things their own way, and can possibly position them where competition is less. It is riskier insofar as customers, investors or suppliers may be uncertain about the innovation or its likelihood of success, and this makes legitimating the business more problematic.
5.
What are the two general kinds of benefits of each type of strategy? You benefit from being able to buy existing technologies, such as industrial grade washing machines for a Laundromat, Web servers for a hosting service, or calligraphy pens for greeting card publishing. Architects, builders, real estate agents zoning boards, equipment manufacturers, equipment servicing companies and banks, are more likely to understand the industry and what is expected. Because of this, they can give you firm estimates of costs and schedules. With imitative approaches, the possibility also exists to buy existing businesses. Perhaps the key benefit of an imitative strategy comes from your customers. Chances are they already know about the kind of product or service you are offering. This means your marketing efforts can focus on the benefits you offer instead of explaining the product itself.
7-19
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
When you elect an innovative strategy, you have the benefit of making your business precisely fit your own ideas and preferences. Where the innovative business is successful, it is likely to bring a higher price than an imitative business. As an industry leader, a successful innovative business can give its founder heightened visibility. 6. How does the SWOT analysis relate to the selection of a strategic direction of the business? At the end of a SWOT Analysis, you have to make a decision about the strategic direction of the business. The options are generally described as: flaunt, fix, fight or flee. You make the decision based on which pair of relations are the strongest. Where strengths match opportunities, you have the winning combinations you should flaunt and focus your efforts. Where a weakness gets in the way of pursuing an opportunity, you need to fix it to clear the way. Where your firm faces a threat, the best approach is to fight it with your strengths. When you see a threat that is made worse by a weakness in your firm, the best strategy is often to flee, trying to keep the weakness from exacerbating the threat. 7. What are the three generic strategies of business? Give one example of a firm pursuing each type of generic strategy. Differentiation strategies are aimed at mass markets situations where nearly everyone might buy your product or service. With this strategy, you try to show how your firm offers some combination of value benefits that is different and better for the customer than those offered by competitors. Relatively few small businesses use differentiation strategies, because it is hard for small businesses to have the resources to pursue mass markets. Where it does happen most often is where a small business offers a mass market product or service locally. For example, a gas station offers a mass market service, but its sales are naturally limited to a particular location. This business reality sets boundaries for where the firm competes, which helps target advertising and pricing. Cost strategies are also aimed at mass markets. In a cost strategy, you try to show how your firm offers a combination of cost benefits that appeal to the customer. Small businesses in a variety of industries make use of mass market cost strategies. Typically, this comes when the small business can pursue a very low cost operation. For example, one gravel supplier in Memphis, Tennessee was the undisputed low-cost provider. His secret? A farmer by trade, he discovered gravel under one of his farm fields. He sold directly to the users, cutting out intermediaries and their costs.
7-20
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Focus strategies target a portion of the market called a segment or niche. Instead of selling mass market gravel for everyone, a focus strategy might target people seeking decorative gravel. For example, Scott Stone Company in Mebane, North Carolina offers eleven different types of gravel that differ in colors, stone sizes, and durability. By assuring the quality and consistency of the gravel and knowing which types work best in specialized settings, such as oriental gardens or waterscapes, they offer customers products and expertise not readily available elsewhere. The examples students bring up locally are likely to vary dramatically by industry. When in doubt, have the student give the explanation of how the firm fits into the particular generic strategy. It also helps to have some local examples that students will immediately recognize. This can be anything from hamburgers (think of a high-end steak houses $15 burger vs. Fuddruckers or TGI Fridays $8 burger vs. McDonaldss 89 cent burger or the local burger specialist even with fast food burgers, students can quickly tell the different strategies see Experiential Exercise 2 below). One thing to be aware of is the inevitable highest quality/lowest price strategy someone copies from ads. It is usually worthwhile to get students to stop and think through if it is possible to create a service or product that has that mix. A BIC pen is remarkably good quality for the money, but it is no Mount Blanc, nor does it last as long or survive abuse as well. Each has good quality for the price, but neither can claim both quality and price. If there are examples students come up with, ask them to speculate on the business model and its profitability. Often what shows highest quality/lowest price in the real world happens when something is more a labor of love of the entrepreneur than a model for a sustainable or replicable business. 8. What is the competitive advantage of a business, and how does it lead to success? Competitive advantage is the particular way you implement your customer benefits that keeps your firm ahead of other firms in your industry or market. Competitive advantage is your firms edge in meeting and beating the competition. Competitive advantage works by helping customers distinguish your firm from others in the industry or locality. When your advantage matches the customers desires, loyalty is built and sales are strengthened. Having a competitive advantage that is difficult for others to copy can help you sustain the sales and loyalty advantages. It offers protection from competition.
7-21
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
9.
In the life cycle of a young firm, how can you tell when it has left the introductory stage and entered the growth stage? a. In the growth stage, customers begin to notice the product or service and buy significantly more of it (vs. a need for the seller to educate the potential customer about the product in the introductory stage). b. In the Growth Stage there is a burst of new companies providing the product or service, and high variation in the offerings (vs. few companies and some variation in offerings for introductory stage). c. In the Growth Stage, sales boom, suggesting the beginnings of a mass market (vs. niche for introductory stage). d. In the Growth Stage, the major customer segment is the Early Majority (vs. Early Adopter for introductory stage).
Experiential Exercises
1.
Find the trade or professional association for the kind of business you plan to pursue. This is the exercise outlined in Skill Module 7.2. It may help to check oncampus resources (such as whether the library has a copy of Gales Directory of Associations or the Bacon or Burrelle publication directories and perhaps ask permission to borrow it for the class).
2.
Look at local hamburger restaurants. How do they pursue imitative strategies, and where do they offer their innovations on the theme of a hamburger? As noted above in Discussion Question 7, hamburgers offer a great range of strategies (think of a high-end steak houses $15 burger vs. Fuddruckers or TGI Fridays $8 burger vs. McDonaldss 89 cent burger or the local burger specialist even with fast food burgers, students can quickly tell the different strategies). Cost strategies: Ask students for the cheapest burger around White Castle/Krystal are often among the cheapest, although McDonalds often comes close, and there might be a local who wins the low-ball price. Differentiation Strategies here is where gourmet burgers come in. Bison, chicken, tofu, or wildly inventive condiments, seasoning or topper for burgers. Burger King used to say have it your way to differentiate it from McDonalds. What place is the local gourmet burger joint? It is likely not the same as the cheapest burger place.
7-22
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Niche Strategies Hardees aimed for young men with their ads showing hot rods, Paris Hilton, and monster burgers dripping ketchup. A local burger emporium may have a loyal but very narrow following. For example, Dwyers restaurant in Memphis has been cooking burgers in grease (according to local legend, the same grease) for generations. In these cases, the intent is to have an appeal to a very narrow range of the market. Note that all burgers have a lot of similarities shape, basic condiments (either on the burger or immediately available), buns, side orders. If a burger gets too out of the ordinary in terms of these basics of imitation, it can quickly stop being a burger. Think about a hamburger shaped like a hot dog (it happens at Bostons Beantown Dogs, but not many other it places!) just isnt right, and has never caught on. The same is happening with hamburger in wraps. To stay a burger, some degree of imitation is necessary.
3.
Pick five online businesses in the same industry. From their websites, see if you can identify what they think is their competitive advantage. Do you agree with their assessment? Why or why not? You can go about this having students (or student teams) work up their comparisons. Make sure they write down their comparison points (and their basis for making the point otherwise they get lost or forgotten). You can also specify an industry and sites and let students report on their findings a see what you can add approach works well to get new ideas up on the board. To stick with the hamburger example McDonalds keeps trying all sorts of ways to change what folks see as its competitive advantages (ready availability, absolute consistency, low price, relatively low price, relatively fast drive-through, little kids acceptance), to something more upscale and profitable, but the customers dont buy the new approaches. This is a publicly visible example of an intended competitive advantage that does not work out. Jaguar hit the reverse when they introduced their low-priced version. For online businesses, consider picking businesses students are likely to deal with books, music, etc. Or consider going on eBay and having students evaluate the retailers and resellers there. There can be tremendous variation in how the same product gets offered, described, and supported by the seller. Those are the things that can make up competitive advantage.
7-23
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
4.
Think of the life cycles of a business. Give an example of local businesses that are at the different stages, and be ready to defend your classification. Often it is hardest for students to come up with businesses in the introductory stage. One way to make this a motivational exercise is to point up businesses on campus that have been started recently by students refrigerator rentals, dances or performance impresarios, book traders or resellers, delivery services, etc. Growth stage is often the local hero companies that are about to expand to new locations or new markets (exporting or getting big contracts count in this regard). In the maturity stage are the most common companies the older, established small businesses everyone knows about and have dealt with for years. Decline is often the hardest firms to find. It can be hard to distinguish decline firms from mature firms, and often firms in decline try hard to mask the decline. Sometimes students can tell for example a firm that is slowly shedding branches, or is always doing major sales (with a hint of desperation). Sometimes they can see a business get shabbier and less cared-for. These are all indications. If no examples are obvious, ask students about firms that did go out of business in recent memory, and ask what their operations looked like toward the end. You might also consider spending a bit of time on why businesses try to hide decline, and how to get past subterfuges.
7-24
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Student Manual Critical Thinking Exercises
Learning objective 1 1. Evaluate the following businesses and decide if their scale is likely to be local or global, their scope a niche or mass market, and their strategy more innovative or imitative. a. Bobbie is starting a ski-diving center to serve the greater Valparaiso, Indiana area. b. George hand carves bookends from bricks c. Hester is franchising her coffee shop idea. d. Lillian has found a way to make bread from recycled plastics. Scale Niche (geographic and personality) Mass (probably unless his carvings are very specific the coat of arms of one particular university, for example or very expensive) Mass Mass Innovation/ imitative Imitative Imitative (even though each one is likely to be unique, they are still just bookends) Imitative Innovative
Answer: Scope a b Local (greater Valparaiso area) It depends. Hand carving restricts output which hints at local; if he follows the first strategy noted in the scale column, it would also be local. If these are very expensive and he advertises on the Internet, these could be global Global Global
c d 2.
Below are several industries that are typically mass market. Can you identify a niche within each market that might be profitable? a. Makeup b. Baked goods c. Cars d. Hotel rooms e. Shoes Answer:
7-25
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Possible answers are limited only by your creativity, but here are some examples: a. Makeup: clown makeup, makeup for men, makeup for the film industry, makeup that covers severe scars. b. Baked goods: something ethnic or tied to a holiday; a unique flavor that might appeal to only one ethnic group; diabetic baked goods c. Cars: super-expensive cars; race cars; cars adapted for people with disabilities d. Hotel rooms: rooms at airports that rent for partial days for between flights layovers e. Shoes: shoes for special activities; shoes in unique sizes; shoes sold singly (rather than in pairs) for people with different sized feet, one foot or who had lost one shoe Learning objective 2 3. Looking at the ideas in question 1, are these examples likely to be parallel competition, incremental innovation or pure innovation? Parallel competition Incremental innovation (due to the material and the fact that they are hand carved). Parallel competition Pure innovation
Answer: a. b. c. d. 4.
By using the SIC code for plumbers, Leona has found out that the industry is highly fragmented, growing, and relatively profitable. Through her study and interviews, she has found a niche for plumbers willing to work evening and weekend hours when its more convenient to have people to your home. These customers are willing to pay a premium for not having to take time from work. As best you can, evaluate Leonas industry analysis.
7-26
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Answer: According to the text, there are seven parts of an Industry Analysis a. SIC/NAICS number: Leona has the SIC number b. Industry Size Over Time: Leona has found out that it is a growing, but highly fragmented industry c. Profitability: Leona has determined that it is profitable, especially a certain niche she has identified. d. How Profits Are Made: Leona has determined that in one area evening and weekend plumbers it is possible to charge premium process. Whether or not she can charge enough to cover the evening and weekend wages of her plumbers is not given in this example. Leona has some information, but perhaps not everything she needs here. e. Target Market Competitor Concentration: The fact that she has identified a profitable niche MAY imply that she has looked at competition, but there is nothing in this case to prove that she has. f. Analysis: In this case, Leona hasnt done much. She should look at the size of the industry, the trends and its profitability and write this up much better than presented here. g. Sources: Shes indicated interviews and study, but nothing specific.
7-27
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Learning objective 3 5. Using the list of value and cost benefits in your text, see if you can identify which one(s) each of the following entrepreneurs have: a. Alma knows the name of everyone of her customers and uses it immediately when they walk into her accounting office. b. Michaels painting company has established an excellent reputation in the Upland, California area and since he operates from his home, his costs are low. c. Alcos Discount Store purchases products by the truckload so as to pass along savings to its customers and is conveniently located next to the grocery store. d. Ardells Appliances delivers and install each appliance within 24 hours and guarantees them for a full year beyond the manufacturers warranty. e. Now that Don has made several dozen bookcases, he has figured out the most effective and efficient way of building them but yet maintaining the artistry and quality of each piece. f. JoAnns website allows customers to order craft supplies from a large number of companies and pay by credit card on their secure site. g. Purchasing a membership in Elmers Environmentalists not only means you can spend time with other environmentally conscious people, but you know that a portion of your membership dues goes towards cleaning up beaches around the country. Service/personalization Reputation, lower cost Scale, place Delivery, quality/assurance Learning, quality, style Shopping ease, credit Altruism, belonging
Answer: a. b. c. d. e. f. g.
7-28
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
6.
Which wedge? Using the list in the book, which entry wedge does it appear each of the following firms are using? a. Angelina Alvarez uses the fact that her tree and shrub removal service is both woman and minority owned to qualify for set asides b. Gary makes an innovative device that converts your cell phone into a GPS device. Everybody wants one, but there are no competitors yet. c. Pams aunt ran a mail order business. Shed always wanted to have a stamp collection so she saved the stamps off of virtually every piece of mail she received. Pam discovered the cartons of stamps in her aunts attic and persuaded her to let her sell them on eBay. d. The state government gave preferential treatment to Garys construction company when it recently remodeled one of its office building since Garys firm had a record of hiring disabled workers. e. When Dominos decided to no longer delver pizzas out of the city limits, Judys Pizza Palace picked up a lot of the rural business. f. When Orville left his company, he was able to persuade them to sign a contract allowing his new drafting firm to do all their blueprint work. Favored purchasing Supply shortage Unutilized resources Government rules Market relinquishment Customer contracting
Answer: a. b. c. d. e. f.
Learning objective 4 7. Scot wants to open a pet-sitting service. He is currently a pre-vet student at a midwestern university and has already had considerable animal experience on his parents hobby farm. For a paper in one of his classes, he researched the local pet situation and found that it was large and growing. While there are a number of boarding facilities, there are currently no pet sitters. Hes talked to several friends about helping out or even joining him, but so far everyone has other things lined up or no interest. As the business is likely to start out small, Scot figures that he can handle it at first. Eventually hell be able to find help, especially as the major industry in town has just announced it was moving its operations to another state and those employees will be looking for jobs. Do a SWOT analysis for Scot. Which of the four strategic directions does it appear he should follow?
7-29
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Answer: Strengths Scot has experience and his pre-veterinary studies are likely to be helpful Weaknesses Scot is the ONLY employee and hasnt been too successful yet in finding anyone else to join him. What happens to Scots customers if he is ill? - This is an idea that is easy and relatively cheap to duplicate. - How will customers react to the fact that Scot is a student (lack of legitimacy)? Opportunity Currently, there are no pet sitting operations in the area, only boarding centers. - The pet market is large and growing. Threats If the major industry is closing, will there be many people with money to take trips pay for pet sitting? Will many of these people move away? Strategic Direction While it isnt exactly clear-cut, Scot may be facing a fix situation. The weaknesses he has can all be resolved: find several backup employees, come up with something unique and hard to duplicate vet-tobe exams? downplay his student status and take steps to improve his legitimacy in other ways. The impact of the threat isnt really known; even though this is a major employer, are the employees pet owners? Are there enough other jobs to absorb them? Will many of them move? Scot may also be able to advertise pet sitting for those on job hunting trips (or house hunting, if they decide to move with the company.) Learning objective 5 8. Match the company to the generic strategy it practices: a. Cheapseats offers discount airfare to anyone with an Internet connection. b. Altoids breath mint is the only one that is curiously strong. c. Liz travels from nursing home to nursing home cutting and styling only senior citizens hair.
Answer: a. Cost b. Differentiation c. Focus
7-30
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
9.
Match the entrepreneur to the supra-strategy list in your textbook. a. Sonya opened a medical clinic in a ghetto area of her city. b. Tiffanys Truffles feature exceptional candies going for $4 each. c. Moodys pharmacy has not sold out like other drugstores; its a pharmacy, nothing more. d. When Wib builds a custom patio for you, he takes into account the topography of your yard, the style of your house and your lifestyle, giving a one-of-a-kind patio guaranteed to please. e. Emmie makes hand-sewn quilts that she sells at art fairs. f. When Craig sells you a used car, he offers six free oil changes and even stops by your house to see how the car is doing for you. a. b. c. d. e. f. Serving the underserved Elite Single-mindedness Customization Craftsmanship Super-support
Answer:
7-31
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Learning objective 6 10. Tiffanys Truffles mentioned above (9.b.) needs some help making sure everything they do conforms to the elite, exclusive atmosphere they are trying to promote. Use Value Chain to brainstorm ideas for them.
Answer: Answers may vary, but here are some suggestions: Organization wide Physical facilities Store should be very elegant and rich looking, perhaps with gold accents. Very clean. Comfortable chairs for customer to wait while their order is being wrapped People Truffle consultants not salespeople with intensive training in customer service and product features. Technology Customer database includes anniversaries, birthdays and other dates so that reminders can be mailed a week in advance Procurement Concentrate on the most premium ingredients. Product/Service Inbound logistics Climate-controlled storage for ingredients to ensure top quality Operations Only the most perfect truffles are permitted to be sold Outbound logistics Exquisite gift-wrapping; courier service offered Sales&amp;Marketing All prints pieces are on gilt paper in script. Mailers look more like invitations than ads Service Customers should feel like theyve walked into Tiffanys Jewelry Store of Truffles Learning objective 7 11. Leise wants to open a dance school in her hometown. Using Porters five threats, discuss the possible problems she may face.
Answer: Existing firms Any other dance schools that are currently operating are threats Potential entrants Other dance teachers could also open dance schools Substitutes Children may opt for lessons in gymnastics or piano, or to play Little League and any number of after school activities. Suppliers For a business as serviced based as dance lessons, suppliers are probably not a big threat. Buyers Usually parents are budget conscious. Unless they are certain they have a budding Barishnokov, theyll probably seek price and convenience.
7-32
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
12.
Consider Tiffanys Truffles from question 10 above: Tiffany has the opportunity to hire Antoinette who studied the art of truffle making in Paris. A native of France, Antoinette has won several dozen awards for her excellent work making truffles and other candies. Do a VRIO Analysis on this potential resource for Tiffany.
Answer: Value: Hiring Antoinette will certainly not decrease cost, but this resource has the potential to increase sales if she is as good as she seems. Rareness: How many people like Antoinette are there? Not many, so this is a rare resource. Imitability: Could others duplicate this? Possibly, they could hire other French truffle makers, but one who won all these awards? Probably not. Organization: Can Tiffany hire Antoinette? Assuming that Antoinette is not an illegal alien and Tiffany can afford her salary, then the answer here is also yes. 13. Consider the following industries. Where do you think they fall on the Industry Life Cycle? a. Tennis shoes b. High-definition television c. Pharmaceutical companies d. Music downloading industry e. Buggy whip manufacturers f. Cell phone industry g. On-line education
Answer: Specific products in each industry might be located at nearly any point of the Industry Life Cycle. For example, if the topic was computers, certainly a 486 model is in decline (or even death) while other more recent, models are at earlier stages. This judgment is somewhat subjective as the cycle curves are never smooth. Also, in particular regions/countries the industry may be at different stages. Most likely, though, these industries are as follows: a. b. c. d. e. f. g. Tennis shoes: Maturity High-definition television: Introduction to Growth Pharmaceutical companies: Growth, maybe edging into Maturity Music downloading industry: Introduction Buggy whip manufacturers: Decline Cell phone industry: Growth to Maturity On-line education: Introduction or Growth
7-33
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Mini-Case:
Ed Tangier and the Demise of Active Air Active Air was a national airline that began service in Fitchburg. Unfortunately, they left the town. Ed Tangier couldnt have competed with Active Air, but saw his golden opportunity when they left. Mini-Case Questions 1. What is the entry wedge that Ed was going to pursue? Market relinquishment and supply shortage (of airline seats) were obvious wedges, although someone can make a case of the underutlized resource of the airport. Depending on how inventive he is, Ed could ask the local government for a tax incentive to offer the service or even the prepurchase of tickets to help defray initial expenses (TWA got this from the City of St. Louis when it was in financial difficulty). Such efforts might be a form of customer contracting. 2. What kind of benefits do you think would make the most sense for him to offer his customers? The major benefit Ed could offer is place. He would be the only airline offering service in Fitchburg. Some folks might see this advantage as a variant of delivery (as in delivering airline service locally). It might also be possible to argue his airline might offer shopping ease, as an easier way to travel than bus or driving oneself. If Ed advertises his airline as a local hero sort of business, it might be trying to tap into benefits such as belonging or altruism. As his company becomes known, he may also be able to offer Brand/Reputation as a benefit as a consistent carrier. 3. Does he have any resources that would let him charge a premium price? He is the only carrier offering air service so he has the resource of exclusivity of supply. Being small, he might lack the cost advantages of the bigger carriers, letting him charge higher prices. This is a premium based on a lack of resources (e.g. learning or economies of scale).
7-34
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Additional Activities
1.
Educators Corner at Stanford Technology Venture Program (www.edcorner.stanford.edu) has a case by Sei Wei Ong (case # STVP-2002004 on value chain for a entire industry. Pass out annual reports to groups of students. Have them use these reports to glean information about the different strategies they may be using and to do a SWOT analysis. See what information they can gather towards a value chain analysis. If any resources are mentioned, have them try VRIO. With a little coaching, much of this can be found.
2.
End of Book Case
The Computer Guru; a One-Man Show or an Empire? Instructors Executive Summary One major goal of this case is to introduce and work students through the management/decision-making process. This process should begin by correctly identifying the major problem or goal at hand, in this case, the one-man show that wants to grow. Juan feels that he has already maximized sales in his current situation, and needs help in selecting the best and most logical short- and long-term plan. The next step of this process is to brainstorm and list every possible option, such as those presented in the case and others that your students identify. No idea is a bad idea at this point. Each option should then be isolated and analyzed on its own merits. This requires a detailed look from every angle, such as marketing, finance, personnel and so on. The process concludes with the selection, justification and presentation of the best option available relative to the originally stated major problem or goal. This is an industry proven habit for success among managers, executives and others in a decision-making position. There are several possible right answers to this case. You be judge, based on the strength of your students presentations. It is also worthwhile to note that doing nothing is sometimes the best decision in a given situation. Students should get out there and visit computer stores and interview sales associates and others. Students may find it easier to assume that Juans situation is occurring in your local area. This case also provides the opportunity to discuss the strategic and tactical planning process that every business should go through no matter how large or small. This should take place prior to building the original business plan and at selected intervals over time.
7-35
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Actual Results The student team did a great job. After a close look at each option they recommended the establishment of a retail store. The student team found an attractively priced building on the main street of a nearby town that included two upstairs rental units. They recommended the outright purchase of the building considering the anticipated appreciation value of the real estate over time. The students also (correctly) pointed out that owning real estate is a valuable asset to have if and when the business is offered for sale. In addition, the student team located several vendors who would furnish the store with inventory and offer thirty- to sixty-day payment accounts. Many of those vendors had excellent terms and policies regarding inventory buybacks and upgrades. The timing was right, as the economy was in a growth cycle. Good employees were relatively easy to find. Low interest financing was secured which contributed to a low to moderate break-even point. The student team delivered a great presentation to Juan and Conchita. All recommendations were backed up with solid documentation and were very much in keeping with the clients business goals.
MHHE DVD/Video Assignments
Franchising: Just Dogs Summary: This video focuses on how franchising can be a viable option for many entrepreneurs. Diana had always wanted to be her own boss. After carefully looking around, she decided that purchasing a franchise would be the best option for her and her family at the time. She considered the benefit of having a ready-made business to be a huge support. The franchise only cost $300,000 upfront. To obtain the business loan she would need, she decided to mortgage her house. For her money, Diana received everything she needed to start her own business.
7-36
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Rieva Lesonsky, editor of Entrepreneur Magazine, says that if you want it badly enough and you work hard enough, a franchise can be a good option for many entrepreneurs. About 85% of franchisees are in existence after the first five years. That is a huge success rate compared to other types of entrepreneurships. When deciding which franchise to purchase, name recognition matters. The top five franchises of 2005 all have names that are easily recognized, making them safer investments. It is also easier to get funding for a proven product like a well-known franchise. The top five franchises include: UPS store, Jackson Hewitt, Quizno&apos;s, Curves, and Subway. All are well known names and have good reputations. A franchise helps set-up the entrepreneurs business. For instance, Quiznos instructs the entrepreneur on everything from where to put the new store, to what types of ovens to buy, to which food supplier to use. The rate of success drastically increases with a franchise. Discussion Questions: 1. Why is franchising considered an imitation strategy for a small business? 2. Using SWOT analysis, describe the potential strengths and weaknesses of a successful franchise. 3. Give examples of hotel or restaurant franchises that use strategies of differentiation, cost and focus. Discussion Question Answers: 1. Why is franchising considered an imitation strategy for a small business? The imitation strategy is one in which the entrepreneur does basically what others are already doing. A franchise uses the same methods, systems, and protocol for each new business they set up. All franchisees imitate the franchise plan. 2. Using SWOT analysis, describe the potential strengths and weaknesses of a successful franchise. A strength is a characteristic that gives the business an advantage. For a franchise these include name recognition, a proven operation system, and a strong success rate. A weakness is a characteristic that gives the business a disadvantage. For a franchise this may be a cookie cutter look and feel, the inability to adapt easily, or the ability for competitors to readily imitate. 3. Give examples of hotel or restaurant franchises that use strategies of differentiation, cost and focus.
7-37
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
A differentiation strategy clarifies how one product or business is unlike another in a mass market. This is usually not a franchise. Students may have a hard time finding an answer, or may list a regional franchise. Some upscale franchises may use a differentiation strategy with their competitors. A cost strategy is when a business focuses on cost benefits for customers. Any fast food restaurant classifies as this type, while examples in the hotel industry may include Budget Inn, Hampton Inn, Red Roof Inn, etc. A focus strategy allows an organization to focus on a specific segment or niche in the market. A niche the students may think about is family. Any restaurant that has a play land like McDonalds or Burger King is focusing on this niche. Hotels like Howard Johnson and Holiday Inn where kids can stay free is also focusing on this niche.
7-38
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Secondary Video Case
Dippin Dots Summary: Kurt Jones, a microbiologist with a specialty in cryogenics, was in hot pursuit of finding new ways to freeze ice cream, and developed the ice cream of the future. By focusing on a research question for the dairy industry, he was able to creatively apply his talents to make an entirely new product. Jones was attempting to discover ways to freeze ice cream faster, a question whose answer would serve the dairy industry well and perhaps increase the profitability for ice cream makers. A simple business question led to an amazing discovery. Through his research, Jones found that ice cream could actually be frozen into dry, round dots. Because of the ease in freezing, packaging, and serving, Jones pursued this new ice cream business. Through a fun and creative tasting party for the new ice cream dots, the name Dippin Dots was suggested and accepted. The company now is spreading throughout food courts, arenas, and shopping malls. Like regular ice cream, chocolate is the most popular Dippin Dots flavor. Unlike regular ice cream, Dippin Dots are easily scooped, dont melt, and do not run. In addition, the creators of the company state that you cannot get a brain freeze from eating their ice cream. The frosty factory that produces the Dippin Dot ice cream looks like a wild Willy Wonka factory from the past. Through use of a top-secret technique of using CO2, Jones creates this sweet sensation that is a delectable treat across the United States. Discussion Questions: 1. 2. 3. Discuss the scope of the market which Dippin Dots is targeting. How is this different from other ice cream companies? What are several strengths of Dippin Dots based on the evidence presented in the video? What is the strategy being implemented by Dippin Dots? Do you agree with this strategy?
Discussion Question Answers: 1. Discuss the scope of the market which Dippin Dots is targeting. How is this different from other ice cream companies? Dippin Dots has focused their scope on the national market. You can find one of their stores in shopping malls, sports arenas, and shopping malls. Dippin Dots differs from other companies because they have not mass marketed their products through grocery store distribution channels. Eventually, it is likely to see Dippin Dots expand their market internationally.
7-39
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
2.
What are several strengths of Dippin Dots based on the evidence presented in the video? Dippin Dots has several strengths which gives them a competitive advantage in the market. Their product is easily scooped, doesnt melt, cannot run, and cannot create a brain freeze. The unique look and similar taste of regular ice cream is appealing to consumers. In addition, the company has a unique process to develop ice cream that will be the future of ice cream.
3.
What is the strategy being implemented by Dippin Dots? Do you agree with this strategy? Dippin Dots has implemented a differentiation strategy based on their unique product. This is an appropriate strategy for the company based on the differences between their ice cream and their competitors. The company has been successful since their launch because of the distinctive advantages of their product.
Additional Materials
Please see the textbook Website (www.mhhe.com/katzesb) for the latest instructional materials and JFFs (Just for Funs) that can be used with this chapter. Available on Primis Amy&apos;s Bread Sparta Glass Products eClips Videos eClips #1: Clip Title: Brent Gloy Discusses Five Steps of Strategic Management Summary: Brent Gloy explains the five steps of strategic management. Interview/Lecture Intro: Brent Gloy is a professor of agricultural finance and agribusiness management at Cornell University. He teaches an undergraduate course in Agribusiness Strategy and a graduate course in Agricultural Finance. He co-teaches a two-week international field study that allows students to gain exposure to the food and agribusiness systems in foreign countries. In the past three years, groups have traveled to Hungary, Slovakia, Poland, and Australia. He has also participated in farm management study trips to California, Florida, and Georgia and has been actively involved with the Farm Credit Fellows program. In addition to his activities at Cornell, Brent remains involved in the family farming operation located in southwestern Nebraska.
7-40
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Brent Gloy received his B.S. from the University of Nebraska and his M.S. and Ph.D. from Purdue University. Transcript: I like to think about the five steps of strategic management and that&apos;s exactly what we&apos;ve covered in all these sessions that you&apos;ve been viewing. First, we talked about how you form a strategic vision. Second, we talked about setting objectives that are consistent with that vision. Then, your goal is to craft a plan to meet those objectives and that plan ought to be driven by your analysis of the industry and the external economic environment and by your analysis of your business&apos; strengths and weaknesses or the internal economic environment of your firm. Often called the SWOT analysis or strengths and weaknesses, strength and weakness analysis. The opportunities and threats are the OT of the SWAT analysis...tells you what your key opportunities are for your business. So we do that analysis, we have the objectives, and then the idea is to implement and execute that plan. And finally, evaluate your performance and make adjustments. How to organize your business plan? Well, I think you ought to organize your business plan around those issues. However, you need to remember that for one, this plan is for you, it&apos;s not for me. You&apos;re not going to get a grade on it except what the market gives you in terms of performance. It must meet your needs. In...the way I like to think about it is if differentiation is central to your success, the marketing section in your plan ought to be pretty big. For someone who&apos;s cost or production focused, you&apos;re going to want to focus on internal analysis of your business and identifying strategies and operations and finance that can improve your cost of production. Class Questions: 1. How are organizational capabilities important in strategic management? Answer: Organizational capabilities involve the abilities and skills used by the firm to make profits from its resources. Managing a strategy should involve an in-depth study of organizational capabilities to see if profits can be maximized. 2. Why are the opportunities and threats an important part of the SWOT Analysis? Answer: Opportunities and threats are important because they show how the business can be affected from the market at large, which is beyond the basic strengths and weaknesses of the business. Opportunities and threats provide a better understanding of the circumstances by which a business can succeed or not. Other Videos From Same Firm/Entrepreneur used in ESB2 None Other Videos From Same Firm/Entrepreneur on ecips: h Brent Gloy Discusses Goals in Preparing a Business Plan h Brent Gloy Discusses Components of Business Plan h Brent Gloy States Importance of Including Specific Strategies In Business Plan h Brent Gloy Discusses Five Steps of Strategic Management h Brent Gloy Discusses Benefit of Analysis and Planning
7-41
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
eClips #2: Clip Title: Charles McClure Discusses Concept of Being Fast To Fail Summary: Charles McClure explains the fast to fail concept. Interview/Lecture Intro: Charles G.&quot;Chip&quot;McClure is chairman of the Board, chief executive officer and president of ArvinMeritor, Inc. McClure, who has more than 25 years of diverse leadership experience in the motor vehicle industry, most recently served as chief executive officer, president and a member of the Board of Federal-Mogul Corporation, a global supplier of automotive components. Prior to joining Federal-Mogul, McClure served as president, chief executive officer and a member of the Board of Detroit Diesel, a major designer and manufacturer of diesel engines and related products. He joined Detroit Diesel in 1997, after 14 years in a variety of management positions with Johnson Controls, a Milwaukee-based global automotive supplier. In his last role with Johnson Controls, McClure served as president of the company&apos;s Americas region, with management responsibility for a $3 billion group of 50 manufacturing plants. McClure also holds a bachelor&apos;s degree in mechanical engineering from Cornell University and a master&apos;s degree in business administration from the University of Michigan. Transcript: Another concept that we talk about is fast to fail. And as I said before, we are a very capital intensive business. We have got a lot of technology and innovation. And what is absolutely critical is to make sure that you can make decisions quickly as to whether to continue to invest, or to stop. And Dr. Clay Christianson has written a couple books. The first one was called innovators dilemma. Which, if you ever have the chance to read it, it causes a lot of consternation in your stomach because essentially identifies the fact that in this competitive environment that you don&apos;t even know about that are out there. And it gets you kind of concerned you have to be looking over the horizon. Now it very quickly came up afterwards with another book called the competitor solution to try to offer some solutions in that. And one of the concepts he talks about in there is that as you look at innovations, you are going to put it into production. And if you say there is 10 of them, that you are going to invest and recognize, we&apos;re a capital intensive company. So when we make a decision on investment, it is not just a couple hundred thousand dollars. It is millions, or tens of millions of dollars of investment. So you have to be real sure that when you are making that investment it is the right investment. But his view, and I tend to agree with this, is when you look at that even with these 10 that you have gone through probably 1,000 down to 100, down to 10 you are going to invest in, two of them will ultimately fail. Six will become walking wounded. And only two of them will be really successful. So when you start thinking about that type of thing, you&apos;ve really got to make sure you&apos;ve got a very robust process to make the decision early on that you either going to get in or get out of a product. And then get on with it.
7-42
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Class Questions: 1. How does one use innovative strategy to help improve chances of success? Answer: To be innovative, one must develop an idea that is especially unique, and that will be able to find a successful niche in the existing market. This will make or break the initial investment in the product or service. 2. There is always the chance of failure with new business. How can an industry analysis help avoid failure? Answer: An industry analysis is the research inot the current state of the industry, which can show what products and services have done well, and which ones have not. It can also show whether innovative or imitative strategy is more appropriate. Other Videos From Same Firm/Entrepreneur Used in ESB2: None Other Videos From Same Firm/Entreprenuer on eclips: h Charles McClure Shares Personal and Professional Background h Charles McClure Discusses Background of Company, ArvinMeritor h Charles McClure Discusses Importance of Business Principles, Technology and Global Marketplace h Charles McClure Shares Thoughts on Leadership and Technical Background of Those Leaders h Charles McClure Shares Thoughts on Commercialized Innovation h Charles McClure Discusses Influence of Engineering Degree On Method Of Leadership h Charles McClure States Engineering Is An Investment - Not a Cost h Charles McClure Discusses Concept of Being Fast To Fail h Charles McClure Discusses Accountability and Learning From Mistakes h Charles McClure Shares Thoughts On The Global Economy h Charles McClure Discusses Importance In Getting Overseas Professional Experience STVP Videos Don&apos;t Write a Mission Statement, Write a Mantra Overview: The difference between a mission statement and a mantra, and why a mantra is better. Objective: To communicate that a mantra is more effective than a mission statement.
7-43
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Speaker: Guy Kawasaki is a founder and Managing Director of Garage Technology Ventures. Prior to this position, he was an Apple Fellow at Apple Computer, Inc. and sits on the board of BitPass Inc. A noted speaker and the founder of various personal computer companies, Guy was one of the individuals responsible for the success of the Macintosh computer. He is also the author of eight books including Rules for Revolutionaries, How to Drive Your Competition Crazy, Selling the Dream, and The Macintosh Way. Guy holds a B.A. from Stanford University and a M.B.A. from UCLA, as well as an honorary doctorate from Babson College. Class Questions: 1. How can having a mantra instead of a mission statement differentiate a business? Answer: Differentiation is a way for a business to set itself apart from its competition. If a business has a mantra, as Guy suggested, then it could show that the business is more concerned with communicating its message than with creating a lengthy, wordy explanation of their message that most people wont remember anyway. Think Big and Act Small Overview: The importance of having lofty goals for a business, while continuing to take it one step at a time. Objective: To communicate the importance of having big goals. Speaker: Vinod Khosla was a co-founder of Daisy Systems and founding Chief Executive Officer of Sun Microsystems where he pioneered open systems and commercial RISC processors. Vinod serves on the boards of Agami, Centrata, eASIC, Indian School of Business, Infinera, Kovio, Metricstream, QWEST Communications, Spatial Photonics, Xsigo and Zettacore. Vinod holds a Bachelor of Technology in Electrical Engineering from the Indian Institute of Technology in New Delhi, a Master&apos;s in Biomedical Engineering from Carnegie Mellon University and a MBA from the Stanford Graduate School of Business.
7-44
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Class Question: 1. Why is it important to have big goals for a business? Answers: In order for a business to really succeed, they should have plans to make an impact on the market, whether it be a mass market or a niche one. It is still important for a business to take small steps, as success rarely happens overnight. SBTV Videos Aliza Sherman Select a Niche Market Segment Overview: Aliza Sherman explains how to find a niche market. Objective: To explain how a niche market is developed and identified. Speaker: Aliza Sherman is the co-founder of Femina.net. Class Questions: 1. How can having a niche market help an entrepreneur become successful? Answer: A niche market is a very distinct group that one serves. Having a niche market allows a business to work its products and services to meet their needs, which can lead to success. 2. How has Aliza changed her market over time? Answer: Aliza has further changed her niche market. She began designing websites for young women, but tailored her current site for young Hispanic women. This shows her commitment to find increasingly niche markets. Duct Tape Marketing Creating Your Core Message: Differentiation Overview: Seven Steps to Small Business Marketing Success Objective: To show the steps to success in business marketing. Speaker: John Jantsch is a lecturer for Duct Tape Marketing.
7-45
Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation With a Twist
Class Questions: 1. Why is it important to have a unique business idea? A unique business idea brings a different service or product that can lead to marketing success. The less degree of similarity between competition, the more unique a business is. 2. The book mentions incremental innovation. How does Johns advice fit in with that idea? John stresses the importance of being unique. Incremental innovation is an approach in which a firm patterns itself on other firms, except for a few key areas. Uniqueness can be found in even the smallest aspects of a business. Wordpress blog: http://katzesb.wordpress.com/ Commercial - Suburban Auto Group Running with the Squirrels - EDS Trilogy H R Block Ad ANNUAL EDITIONS: Entrepreneurship, Fifth Edition 9. The New Road to Riches, Om Malik, Business 2.0, October 2004 10. One More Time Should Small Companies Attempt Strategic Planning?, William R. Sandberg, Richard Robinson, and John A. Pearce II, The Entrepreneurial Executive, April 2001 11. How Entrepreneurs Craft Strategies That Work, Amar Bhid, Harvard Business Review, March/April 1994 19. Venture Capitalists Assessment of New Venture Survival, Dean A. Shepherd, Management Science, May 1999 30. Are You Built to Grow?, Seth Godin, Fast Company, November 2000 31. Managing Growth, Michael J. Roberts, New Business Venture and the Entrepreneurs, McGrawHill/Irwin 1999 34. Managing Global Expansion: A Conceptual Framework, Anil K. Gupta and Vijay Govindarajan, Business Horizons, March/April 2000 BizInfoLibrary Plotting Strategy? Get Your Hands Dirty Are You Prepared to Succeed in Business?
7-46 Find millions of documents on Course Hero - Study Guides, Lecture Notes, Reference Materials, Practice Exams and more.
 Course Hero has millions of course specific materials providing students with the best way to expand
 their education. 

Below is a small sample set of documents:

 Chap008_1 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 08 - Business Plans: Seeing Audiences and Your Business ClearlyCHAPTER 8: BUSINESS PLANS: SEEING AUDIENCES AND YOUR BUSINESS CLEARLYChapter SummaryThis chapter shows the student how to write different types of business plans and the portions or Chap010 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 10 - Small Business Promotion: Capturing the Eyes of Your MarketCHAPTER 10: SMALL BUSINESS PROMOTION: CAPTURING THE EYES OF YOUR MARKETChapter SummaryThis chapter further discusses what it is that makes you different than your competition and i Chap011 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 11 - Small Business Location: Place and Layout SelectionCHAPTER 11: SMALL BUSINESS LOCATION: PLACE AND LAYOUT SELECTIONChapter SummaryThis chapter concentrates on the place part of the marketing strategy, looking at a number of methods to get t Chap012 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 12 - Marketing Plans: Saying How Youll Get SalesCHAPTER 12: MARKETING PLANS: SAYING HOW YOULL GET SALESChapter SummaryWhile the marketing plan focuses on the strategies of the four Ps, your target market and your competition, this chapter also Chap013 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 13 - Small Business Accounting: Projecting and Evaluating PerformanceCHAPTER 13: SMALL BUSINESS ACCOUNTING: PROJECTING AND EVALUATING PERFORMANCEChapter SummaryThe first chapter of several accounting chapters, this one covers the background of Chap014 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 14 - Cash: Lifeblood of the BusinessCHAPTER 14: CASH: LIFEBLOOD OF THE BUSINESS Chapter SummaryA continuation of Chapter 13, this chapter focuses on cash and cash flow problems and their solutions. Cash flow terminology is explored and students Chap015 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 15 - Small Business Finance: Using Equity, Debts and GiftsCHAPTER 15: SMALL BUSINESS FINANCE: USING EQUITY, DEBTS AND GIFTS Chapter SummaryContinuing with the discussion in the last chapter, this chapter discusses sources and types of capital fi Chap016 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 16 - Assets: Inventory and Operations ManagementCHAPTER 16: ASSETS: INVENTORY AND OPERATIONS MANAGEMENT Chapter SummaryThe chapter covers all assets short-term and long-term other than cash. Determining their value and managing them are covered, Chap017 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 17 - Small Business Protection: Risks Management and InsuranceCHAPTER 17: SMALL BUSINESS PROTECTION: RISKS MANAGEMENT AND INSURANCE Chapter SummaryThe last chapter introduced the student to financial and investment risks, while this chapter cont Chap018 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 18 - Legal Issues: Recognizing Your Small Business NeedsCHAPTER 18: LEGAL ISSUES: RECOGNIZING YOUR SMALL BUSINESS NEEDS Chapter SummaryThis chapter covers several aspects of law including the legal business structures that small businesses assum Chap019 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 19 - Human Resource Management: Small Business ConsiderationsCHAPTER 19: HUMAN RESOURCE MANAGEMENT: SMALL BUSINESS CONSIDERATIONS Chapter SummaryThis chapter touches on a number of human resource issues for the small business. Recruiting, hiring Chap020 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 20 - Achieving Success in the Small BusinessCHAPTER 20: ACHIEVING SUCCESS IN THE SMALL BUSINESS Chapter SummaryJust as industries and products go through life cycles, so does a small business. Small businesses have several growth strategies avai chapter_9_instructors_manual UNL - MNGT - 422X 1CHAPTER 9: SMALL BUSINESS MARKETING: PRODUCT AND PRICING STRATEGIESChapter SummaryThis chapter take the student through two pieces of the marketing plan: product and pricing. The student will learn the different characteristics of a product and servic Chap001 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 01 - Small Business: Its Opportunities and RewardsChapter 01 Small Business: Its Opportunities and RewardsTrue / False Questions1. (p. 4) About half of the adults in the U.S. think about owning their own business, but only one person in 50 who Chap002 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 02 - Small Business Ethics: A Key to Long-Term SuccessChapter 02 Small Business Ethics: A Key to Long-Term SuccessTrue / False Questions1. (p. 26) The Council of Better Business Bureaus reports that most of its consumer complaints from around t Chap003 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 03 - Small Business Entrepreneurs: Characteristics and CompetenciesChapter 03 Small Business Entrepreneurs: Characteristics and CompetenciesTrue / False Questions1. (p. 56) The classic entrepreneur was a loner, often socially isolated, a hard w Chap004 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 04 - Small Business Ideas: Creativity, Opportunity and FeasibilityChapter 04 Small Business Ideas: Creativity, Opportunity and FeasibilityTrue / False Questions1. (p. 79) Search and capture of new ideas that lead to business opportunities is ca Chap005 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 05 - Small Business Entry: Paths to Part-time EntrepreneurshipChapter 05 Small Business Entry: Paths to Part-time EntrepreneurshipTrue / False Questions1. (p. 118) Working for yourself for 40 or fewer hours a week is called part-time selfemploy Chap006 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 06 - Small Business Entry: Paths to Full-Time EntrepreneurshipChapter 06 Small Business Entry: Paths to Full-Time EntrepreneurshipTrue / False Questions1. (p. 142) There are only five ways to get into small business management. TRUEDifficulty: Chap007 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 07 - Small Business Strategies: Imitation with a TwistChapter 07 Small Business Strategies: Imitation with a TwistTrue / False Questions1. (p. 172) Objective is the idea and actions that explain how a firm will make its profits. FALSEDifficult Chap008 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 08 - Business Plans: Seeing Audiences and Your Business ClearlyChapter 08 Business Plans: Seeing Audiences and Your Business ClearlyTrue / False Questions 1. (p. 204) One circumstance under which creating a business plan is absolutely necessary Chap009 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 09 - Small Business Management: Product and Pricing StrategiesChapter 09 Small Business Management: Product and Pricing StrategiesTrue / False Questions 1. (p. 270) Services are tangible, while goods are intangible. FALSEDifficulty: Easy2. (p. Chap010 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 10 - Small Business Promotion: Capturing the Eyes of Your MarketChapter 10 Small Business Promotion: Capturing the Eyes of Your MarketTrue / False Questions 1. (p. 306) Establishing your unique selling points is known as your value proposition. Chap011 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 11 - Small Business Location: Place and Layout SelectionChapter 11 Small Business Location: Place and Layout SelectionTrue / False Questions 1. (p. 340) Usually the first technique an entrepreneur uses to get customers is word-of-mouth. TRUEDif Chap012 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 12 - Marketing Plans: Saying How You&apos;ll Get SalesChapter 12 Marketing Plans: Saying How You&apos;ll Get SalesTrue / False Questions 1. (p. 378) A systematic written plan of all phases of marketing for a business is known as a marketing plan. TRUEDif Chap013 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 13 - Small Business Accounting: Projecting and Evaluating PerformanceChapter 13 Small Business Accounting: Projecting and Evaluating PerformanceTrue / False Questions 1. (p. 406) One reason why accounting is important to a small business is that Chap014 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 14 - Cash: Lifeblood of the BusinessChapter 14 Cash: Lifeblood of the BusinessTrue / False Questions 1. (p. 446) According to a recent poll by NFIB Foundation, less than 20 percent of small businesses experience money problems indicating the imp Chap015 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 15 - Small Business Finance: Using Equity, Debt and GiftsChapter 15 Small Business Finance: Using Equity, Debt and GiftsTrue / False Questions 1. (p. 485) In the U.S., government programs is the number one source of small business financing. FAL Chap016 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 16 - Assets: Inventory and Operations ManagementChapter 16 Assets: Inventory and Operations ManagementTrue / False Questions 1. (p. 518) Given the high interest rate charges, current practice is for small businesses to provide direct credit to c Chap017 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 17 - Small Business Protection: Risk Management and InsuranceChapter 17 Small Business Protection: Risk Management and InsuranceTrue / False Questions 1. (p. 554) Most business owners prefer to avoid risks to the extent possible. TRUEDifficulty Chap018 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 18 - Legal Issues: Recognizing Your Small Business NeedsChapter 18 Legal Issues: Recognizing Your Small Business NeedsTrue / False Questions 1. (p. 586) The United States has the most litigious society in the world. FALSEDifficulty: Medium2. ( Chap019 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 19Human Resource Management: Small Business ConsiderationsTrue/False Questions1.In 2004, more than three-quarters of businesses in the United States had no employees at all, only the owner. Answer: True Difficulty: Medium Page: 6222.Typicall Chap020 UNL - MNGT - 422X Chapter 20 - Achieving Success in the Small BusinessChapter 20 Achieving Success in the Small BusinessTrue / False Questions 1. (p. 656) All models for the life cycle of the small business firm have multiple stages. TRUEDifficulty: Easy2. (p. 656) Man Problem Set 1 UCSB - ANTH - 5 Nicholas Huynh Anthropology 5 Fall 2009 Problem Set # 1 1. The theory of evolution by natural selection is composed of six logical steps of theory. The first is that the ability of a population to expand is infinite. However, the second step notes that th Problem Set 2 UCSB - ANTH - 5 Nicholas Huynh Anthropology 5 Fall 2009 Problem Set # 2 1. A. In Darwins day, biologists believed in the theory of blending inheritance where offspring are the average of their parents. For instance, if one short individual and one tall individual were se Problem Set 4 UCSB - ANTH - 5 Nicholas Huynh Anthropology 005 Introduction to Physical Anthropology Problem Set # 4: Speciation, classification and the comparative method 1. There are millions of reproductively isolated species now in existence yet we believe all organisms are related Problem Set 3 UCSB - ANTH - 5 Nicholas Huynh Anthropology 005 Introduction to Physical Anthropology Problem Set # 3: (Molecular) Genetics&amp;Heritability 1. A. A mutation is the changing of the structure of a gene, resulting in a variant form that may be transmitted to subsequent gener Problem Set 5 UCSB - ANTH - 5 Nicholas Huynh Anthropology 005 Introduction to Physical Anthropology Problem Set # 5: Distinctive and no-so-distinctive traits of humans 1. If its good, it will spread. Is the preceding phrase is an accurate or inaccurate description of evolution by natu Guide For Schneider[1] Duke - NBIO - 93FCS The Neurobiology of MindGuide for the study of the paper by G. Schneider: Two Visual Systems 1. What is the fundamental question addressed by Schneider? 2. How are conditions of partial blindness, anopia, and amblyopia related to this question? 3. What w Current Event Summary DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 Current Event SummaryAnnie Le who was set to be married to her fianc Jonathan Widawsky on Sunday in long island New York was reported missing from the Yale medical research building. Police are working alongside with FBI officials to help investigate thi Current Event Summary 2 DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 Current Event SummaryThis is article is mainly about how this 12 year old Yemeni girl was forced into marriage at only age 12. There is no known cause or reason on why this marriage occurred but she became pregnant with her husband and she later died giv Current_Event_Summary DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 Current Event Summary Seven people have been arrested for killing a Pensacola couple known for adopting special-needs children. However, one more peson is sought for custody says Sheriff Morgan of Escambia County, Florida on Tuesday. The mastermind of the STUDY WORKSHEET FOR PATTERNS OF ORGANIZATION DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 DENNIS GARCIA1.Define the different types of vocabulary context clues and their corresponding signal words. Examples examples are given to relate to the unknown word and you can use them to figure out its meaning. (for example, for instance, including, strategies DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 &lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot;encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;&lt;Error&gt;&lt;Code&gt;InternalError&lt;/Code&gt;&lt;Message&gt;We encountered an internal error. Please try again.&lt;/Message&gt;&lt;RequestId&gt;A66AF7A7FAC534A5&lt;/RequestId&gt;&lt;HostId&gt;f7VlZ03cRgysfBCRbcF9 XQdaxff36Q+9F3xGQHIXokrPfAXekBcCN0YNkHgOfwvP&lt; Advancing03_Supporting_Details DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 TEN STEPS TO ADVANCING COLLEGE READING SKILLSFourth EditionJohnLangan 2008 Townsend PressChapterThree: SupportingDetailsSupportingdetailsarereasons,examples, facts,steps,orotherkindsofevidencethat explainamainidea.WHATARESUPPORTINGDETAILS?A penny s Advancing02_Main_Ideas DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 TEN STEPS TO ADVANCING COLLEGE READING SKILLSFourth EditionJohnLangan 2008 Townsend PressChapterTwo: MainIdeasRecognizingthemainidea,orpoint, isthemostimportantkey togoodcomprehension.WHATISTHEMAINIDEA?Tofindthemainidea,orpoint,inareadingselection, Advancing01Vocabulary_in_Context DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 TEN STEPS TO ADVANCING COLLEGE READING SKILLSFourth EditionJohnLangan 2008 Townsend PressChapterOne: VocabularyinContextDoyouknowthemeaningofthewordubiquitous? Lookatthesentencebelowandseeifthecontextthe wordssurroundingtheunfamiliarwordhelpsyou figu doctors note DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 TaxReturn(2) DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 Electronic Filing Instructions for your 2008 Federal Tax ReturnImportant: Your taxes are not finished until all required steps are completed.Dennis D Garcia 6448 east 6 ave hialeah, FL 33013| | Your federal tax return (Form 1040EZ) shows a refund due t Vanilla Bean Cheesecake DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 Vanilla Bean CheesecakeVanilla graham cracker crust, vanilla bean cheesecake, white chocolate mousse, vanilla bean whipped cream. (try this recipe next time) CRUST: 1 1/2 cups finely crushed graham crackers (Maybe add some flour?) 1/4 cup sugar 1/2 cup b Dennis Garcia resume DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 DennisGarciaHomephone:(305)6871327 Dgarcia1990@gmail.comAddress:6448east6Ave.Hialeah,Fl. CellPhone:(305)4573463 Email: ObjectiveTo obtain an employment position with your company to display my skills and knowledge that were gained throughout my educat pcsetup DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 11/14/2009 1:02:03 PM * 11/14/2009 1:02:03 PM 11/14/2009 1:02:03 PM 11/14/2009 1:01:57 PM install new driver 11/14/2009 1:01:57 PM 11/14/2009 1:01:57 PM 11/14/2009 1:01:57 PM 11/14/2009 1:01:57 PM (United States) 11/14/2009 1:01:57 PM (United States) 11/1 5A_Application_Letter_Dennis_Garcia DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 Music School Records2620 Vine Street Los Angeles, CA 90028 323-555-0028September 12, 2009Mr. William Hawken 123 Eighth Street Harrisville, MI 48740 Dear William: Subject: Your Application to Music School Records Thank you for submitting your applicatio 5A_Application_Letter_Dennis_Garcia 2 DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 MusicSchoolRecords 2620VineStreet LosAngeles,CA90028 3235550028September12,2009Mr.WilliamHawken 123EighthStreet Harrisville,MI48740 DearWilliam: Subject:YourApplicationtoMusicSchoolRecords 5A_Application_Letter_Dennis_Garcia 3 DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 MusicSchoolRecords 2620VineStreet LosAngeles,CA90028 3235550028September12,2009Mr.WilliamHawken 123EighthStreet Harrisville,MI48740 DearWilliam: Subject:YourApplicationtoMusicSchoolRecords Thank you for submitting your Application to Music School Record 5B_Company_Overview_Dennis_Garcia DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 Music School RecordsMusic School Records discovers, launches, and and develops the careers of young artists in classical, jazz, and contemporary music. Our philosophy is to not only shape, distribute, and sell a music product, but to help artists create 6A_Seminar_Dennis_Garcia DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 GHS Law Partners Intellectual Property Seminar for Business Attorneys July 12, 2009 Atlanta, GA Draft Announcement GHS Law Partners will present its fifth annual Intellectual Property Seminar for Business Attorneys in Atlanta, GA, on July 12, 2009. This i 9a DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 Rio Rancho Auto Gallery First Quarter Sales by Vehicle Type Type January February Compacts Sedans SUVs TrucksMarchAprilMay 9A_Auto_Sales_Dennis_Garcia DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 Rio Rancho Auto GalleryFirst Quarter Sales by Vehicle TypeType Compacts Sedans SUVs Trucks Totals January $347,999.12 $330,373.42 $185,835.76 $309,725.48 $1,173,933.78 February $376,984.91 $289,076.30 $161,446.98 $272,558.89 $1,100,067.09 March $377,540 9B_Safety_Products_Dennis_Garcia - chart DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 SafetyShopInventorySuper Flashlight; 12% Premium Auto Safety Kit; 12%Severe Weather Kit; 12%Accident Reporting Camera Kit; 8%Emergency Road Kit; 31%Road Trip Emergency Kit; 8%First Aid Kit; 17%9ce5d59c3fa3d17c744b9f58d1c65da18c61cd42.xlsxRio Ranch 9B_Safety_Products_Dennis_Garcia DeVry Tinley Park - CTS1328 - cts1328 Rio Ranch Auto Gallery 
Flashcards
 
 Marketing 11 Term Definition Branding status appeal social needs Demographic variables aggregate... cohabitation households...     
 
 Business 45 Term Definition Causal Ambiguity Strategic Vision Where are we... Symbiosis means recognizes... SWOT stands for strengths,...     
 
 Strategic Management 4 Term Definition Organizational... managers,... global strategy standardized... Types of resources Tangible and... Types of firm... ...     
 
 Global Strategy Term Definition MNE A firm that... FDI A firms... Triad Three... Emerging Economies A label that...     
 
 UCF Capstone Mid-Term Term Definition 3... Firms and... Under Armour... Started line... Strategic... CEO... Strategic... Process...     
 
 Sitemap Tutors Educational Concepts Textbooks Blog Study Skills 
 Course Hero is not sponsored or endorsed by any college or university.
Copyright©2012. Course Hero, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
