<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001581" url="http://chomposaurus.wordpress.com/2009/09/30/quality-fast-food-original-seafood-restaurant-dennis-port-cape-cod-ma/" time="2012-07-12-17:22" support="1" score="0.0020396229475829974" bingtitle="Quality Fast Food: Original Seafood Restaurant, Dennis Port, Cape ..." webtitle="Quality Fast Food: Original Seafood Restaurant, Dennis Port, Cape Cod, MACHOMPOSAURUS ( the meat blog )">
			<query id="000312" bing-rank="139"/>
	<description>When I walk into a counter-service fast food restaurant and I see the “Lobster Bomb” listed ... Enter your comment here...</description>
	<body>
		CHOMPOSAURUS ( the meat blog ) 
 Your daily dose of protein: the what, where, when, how and why of meat « “[T]he real tyrant is a man who sacrifices a whole nation to his ideal” Just 10,000 More Calories to Heaven » 
Quality Fast Food: Original Seafood Restaurant, Dennis Port, Cape Cod, MA
 
 
When I walk into a counter-service fast food restaurant and I see the “Lobster Bomb” listed on the menu, I know I’ve walked into the right place. The unoriginally named Original Seafood Restaurant offers this explosive 1-pound lobster roll for the completely reasonable sum of $25, as it is more than enough crustacean for two people, especially when it’s accompanied by soft, hot, salty fries.

 
The lobster itself comes in massive red chunks, bathed but not drowned in a coat of mayo. The whole pile tastes so fresh that you could swear it was the fruit of some sort of magical lobster plant, grown and picked in the garden that day. Even if you opt for the more reasonable $13.99 lobster roll and fries, you will get a satisfying heap of tender meat. And of course, since it’s New England, all rolls are served in those controversial “Top Loader” hot dog buns. Perhaps, after years of failing to support my relish-laden Fenway Franks, these rolls have finally found a purpose in hosting light lumps of lobster and lettuce.

 
Unable to try just one thing, we also got a basket of fried clam strips, which were remarkable for their lack of grease. Instead, they were tender inside and out, from the creamy batter to the friendly and forthcoming meat inside.

The only item that received mixed reviews was the chowder, which tasted more like a hearty potato soup with clam chunks in it. But what it lacked in authenticity it made up for in scarfability, especially at $2.99 for a rather generous “small” bowl.

 
So, when you’re in the mid-cape area and can’t defend going to Sundae School for dinner a third night in a row, don’t try and be unique: follow the crowds to the Original Seafood Restaurant. Perhaps you will be bold enough to order the 8-person“Seafood Frenzy”listed ominously at the bottom of their menu…
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
 This entry was posted on September 30, 2009 at 8:24 am and is filed under Original Seafood Restaurant , QUALITY FAST FOOD with tags Cape Cod , fried seafood . You can follow any responses to this entry through the RSS 2.0 feed
 You can leave a response , or trackback from your own site. 
 
2 Responses to“Quality Fast Food: Original Seafood Restaurant, Dennis Port, Cape Cod, MA”

 Steve Says: 
 April 24, 2011 at 6:34 pm 
We spent a week in Cape Cod in Oct 2011. Our Condo was few blocks from Original Seafood. We got in late the first night of our trip and had dinner there just because it was close. We were amazed at the quality and great taste of this seemingly fast food stop. We tried a couple other spots on the cape but ended up coming back to Original Seafood Restuarant almost every day of our trip. Wish we there right now so we could endulge in this great seafood. The Fish And Chips were the best.
 Reply meathouseblog Says: 
 May 24, 2011 at 4:21 pm 
Wow that is a super stuffed lobster roll!
 Reply 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 Blog at WordPress.com . Theme: Black-LetterHead by Ulysses Ronquillo .
 Follow 
 Follow“CHOMPOSAURUS ( the meat blog )” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
