<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001183" url="http://www.city-data.com/va-restaurants/Bojangles-614.html" time="2012-07-12-16:37" support="1" score="0.0015771921434276765" bingtitle="Bojangles #614, 900 Hardy Rd, Vinton, VA - Restaurant inspection ..." webtitle="Bojangles #614, 900 Hardy Rd, Vinton, VA - Restaurant inspection findings and violations, food safety">
			<query id="001106" bing-rank="194"/>
	<description>Observed employee handling ready to eat food items with single-use gloves without the ... Comments: Clean the chicken breading tray more frequently and/or rotate a clean ...</description>
	<body>
		Bojangles #614, 900 Hardy Rd, Vinton, VA - Restaurant inspection findings and violations 

 
 
 
Back to Virginia Restaurants , Virginia , VA smaller cities , VA small cities , All Cities .
 Restaurant: Bojangles #614 
Address: 900 Hardy Rd, Vinton, Virginia 
Phone: (540) 981-1133 
Total inspections: 21 
Last inspection: Oct 8, 2008 
 
 
Violation code
 
Inspection Date
 
Inspection Type
 
Critical violations
 
Non-Critical violations
 
Details / Comments
 
 0080 - Critical Employees or applicants are not aware of the reporting procedures concerning information about their health and activities as they relate to diseases that are transmissible through food, including the date of onset of jaundice or of an illness due to Salmonella Typhi, Shigella spp., Escherichia coli O157:H7 or Hepatitis A virus. 0160 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat Observed several employees fail to wash hands in between single-use glove changes. The Environmental Health Specialist (EHS) advised the employees to wash hands in between glove changes. Employees complied by washing hands before wearing a new pair of single-use gloves. Violation was corrected during inspection. 0220 - Critical Observed food items and uncovered drink cups stored on a metal table along with single-use containers and sandwich buns. 0550 - Corrected During Inspection In-use utensils improperly stored between use. Observed several utensils stored inside a pitcher of room temperature water (66.7 F) with visible food debris in the water. Corrected during inspection. 0610 - Food stored on the floor or food stored less than 6&quot; above the floor. Observed several boxes of single-service items stored on multiple milk crates on the floor. 0700 - Corrected During Inspection Critical The fried chicken was not cooked to a sufficient temperature and time to eliminate pathogenic bacteria. Observed a foodservice employee remove fried chicken from the fryer without checking any internal cooking temperatures. Observed several large chicken breasts at the following temperature (taken immediately after they were removed from the fryer): 148.9 F, 162.4 F. The Environmental Health Specialist (EHS) advised the foodservice employee that the large chicken breasts were not fully cooked and must be placed in the fryer to resume cooking. The large chicken breasts were placed in the fryer for additional cooking. After additional cooking, the foodservice employee removed several chicken breasts from the fryer without verifying any cooking temperatures with a thermometer. EHS observed the following cooking temperature of one large chicken breast: 149.4 F. EHS then spoke with the manager about the undercooked chicken breasts. Manager advised that the chicken breasts fried on this date are substantially larger than the chicken breasts normally received by the restaurant. Manager advised the foodservice employee that the chicken breast cooking temperatures must be verified with a thermometer and that all cooking temperatures must be 180 F or above. Violation corrected during inspection. 0820 A 1 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Grilled Chicken Fillet observed hot holding at improper temperatures. Observed the following food temperature: 119.9 F. Manager discarded the chicken fillets during the inspection. Violation was corrected during inspection. 0820 A 2 - Critical Repeat Several potentially hazardous food items observed cold holding at improper temperatures. Observed the following food temperatures: Sliced Tomatoes (43.6 F, 44.0 F), Eggbeaters stored on Ice (46.1 F), and Half and Half stored in insulated container (53.8 F). Half and Half was discarded during the inspection. 0830 - Corrected During Inspection Critical The prepared ready-to-eat (RTE) BBQ and previously cooled green beans in the refrigeration unit are not properly dated for disposition. The commercially prepared, opened package of sausage links in the Walk In Refrigerator were observed not properly dated for disposition. Violation corrected during inspection. 1570 - Walk In Freezer unit was observed in a condition that prevents necessary maintenance and easy cleaning. Connections at the condensor unit are visibly leaking. The Environmental Health Specialist (EHS) observed large amounts of ice on the floor, preventing routine cleaning. 1770 A - Critical The following utensils were observed soiled to sight and touch: knives, ladels, and scoops. Dirty utensils were observed in a container with other cleaned and sanitized utensils. 1770 C - Observed mold growth on the inside of the ice machine. 2350 ii - Plumbing connections under the three compartment sink are leaking. 
 October 08, 2008 Routine 8 5 Details / Comments 
 0160 - Critical Repeat Employees did not wash hands prior to donning single-use gloves. Observed employees changing out of soiled gloves straight into a new pair of gloves without first washing hands. 0450 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat Observed one foodservice employee handling bread/bakery items with bare hands. Employee was placing bread/bakery items in plastic container with bare hands. Violation was corrected during inspection. 0820 A 1 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Observed cooked pork hot holding at improper temperatures. Temperature was observed at 122.3 F. Cooked pork was discarded during inspection. Violation corrected during inspection. 0820 A 2 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Observed sliced tomatoes in the top of the prep unit cold holding at improper temperatures. Sliced Tomatoes observed cold holding at 56.5 F. Ambient air temperature of this unit was observed at 56 F. Sliced tomatoes were the only potentially hazardous foods stored in this unit during inspection. Liquid pasteurized eggs observed cold holding at improper temperatures at the fryer. Liquid pasteurized eggs were observed stored on ice. The temperature was observed at 58.9 F. 
 March 14, 2008 Routine 4 0 Details / Comments 
 0160 - Corrected During Inspection Critical A food employee failed to wash his or her hands before engaging in food preparation, after touching bare human body parts, after coughing, sneezing, eating, after handling soiled utensils or after engaging in any activity which may have contaminated his/her hands. Observed employee handling cell phone with single-use gloves and then resuming in foodservice activities without washing hands and changing single-use gloves. Observed employees changing single-use gloves but not washing hands in between glove changes. 0450 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Employees observed handling ready-to-eat (RTE) food with their bare hands. Observed employee handling ready to eat food items with single-use gloves without the fingers (fingers were torn off the gloves). 0570 - Wiping cloths improperly stored between use. Sanitizer in the wiping cloth bucket was measured at 400 ppm (Quaternary Ammonium). Sanitizer in the three compartment sink was also measured at 400 ppm. 0700 - Corrected During Inspection Critical The fried chicken breasts were not cooked to a sufficient temperature and time to eliminate pathogenic bacteria. Temperature of fried chicken breasts was taken immediately after the food product was removed from the fryer. Initial cooking temperatures of the chicken breasts were 147 F and 141 F. These pieces of chicken were then put back in the fryer for an additional 2 minutes. The second temperatures taken were 166 F and 189 F. 0820 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Sliced Tomatoes in the top of the prep unit were observed cold holding at improper temperatures (44.0 F, 44.6 F). 
 August 21, 2007 Routine 4 1 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. July 09, 2007 Follow-up 0 0 Details / Comments 2240 - Critical There are not an adequate number of toilets required by law. The only toilet in the men&apos;s room is not operational. June 18, 2007 Complaint 1 0 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. March 30, 2007 Follow-up 0 0 Details / Comments 
 0550 - Corrected During Inspection In-use utensils improperly stored between use. The large metal spoon used to stir the tea was observed stored directly on a dirty cart in between uses. 0570 - Corrected During Inspection Wiping cloths improperly stored between use. The chemical sanitizer in the wiping cloth bucket at the drive through window was measured at less than 100 ppm concentration (quaternary ammonium). 0820 - Critical Sliced tomatoes in the sandwich station prep unit are cold holding at improper temperatures (46.6 F). The thermometer located inside the bottom of the prep unit is reading 46 F. 0850 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Cooked bacon, cooked pork patties, cooked eggs, and cooked sausage patties for which time rather than temperature is being used as a control was not labeled or otherwise marked with a 4 hour cook, serve or discard by time. 1320 - Repeat There was no temperature measuring device located in the reach in cooler immediately behind the fryer, the reach in cooler for buttermilk at the biscuit station, the walk in refrigerator for chicken (digital thermometer outside is broken), and the walk in refrigerator (digital thermometer outside is broken). 1530 - There is no properly working test kit provided in the facility for monitoring the concentration of the chemical sanitizing solutions. 1700 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Quaternary Ammonium sanitizing solution used was not at an acceptable concentration. The automated sanitizer dispensing equipment was observed not operating properly. The sanitizer was measured at less than 100 ppm. 1780 - Critical Surfaces of the ice machine in contact with non-potentially hazardous food items were observed soiled with accumulations of grime and debris (mold). 
 March 22, 2007 Routine 4 4 Details / Comments 
 0830 - Critical The prepared ready-to-eat (RTE) leftover chicken in the refrigeration unit is not properly dated for disposition. 1320 - There was no temperature measuring device located in all refrigeration and freezer units. 1770 C - Observed accumulations of dust, dirt, food residue or other debris on the following nonfood-food contact surfaces: inside equipment. 2330 - The person in charge was unable to produce records of routine maintenance service for the water treatment device located on the filtration system. 2660 - There is no covered refuse container for the disposal of feminine napkins in the ladies room stall. 
 October 30, 2006 Routine 1 4 Details / Comments 
 0550 - Dispensing utensils improperly stored between uses. (ice machine scoop on top of machine) 1800 - The nonfood contact surface of the reach in freezer has accumulations of grime and debris. 1880 - Corrected During Inspection Critical The food-contact surfaces of the following equipment were not observed sanitized: prep and drop pans 3170 - Wall junctures under hand sink is not maintained in good repair 3330 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Working containers of cleaning solutions are not properly labeled. 
 June 29, 2006 Routine 2 3 Details / Comments 
 1320 - Repeat There was no temperature measuring device located in the reach ins. 1770 B - Observed accumulations of encrusted grease deposits or other soil on the following food contact surfaces: biscuit pans 1770 C - Observed accumulations of dust, dirt, food residue or other debris on the following nonfood-food contact surfaces: inside and outside equipment. 2000 - Single service items observed unprotected from contamination. (sausage gravy containers) 2890 - Light bulb over deep fryers not shielded, coated, or otherwise shatter-resistent. 3180 - Repeat Floors in food prep area noted in need of cleaning. 3340 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Containers of cleaning solutions are not properly stored to prevent the contamination of food, equipment, utensils, linens or single service items. 
 February 15, 2006 Routine 1 6 Details / Comments 
 0550 - Corrected During Inspection Dispensing utensils improperly stored between uses. (ice machine scoop) 0820 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Bacon,sausage patties cold holding at improper temperatures.(unit unplugged) 1320 - There was no temperature measuring device located in the reach ins. 1700 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Quaternary Ammonium sanitizing solution used was not at an acceptable concentration. 1800 - The nonfood contact surface of the inside and outside of equipment has accumulations of grime and debris. 3180 - Floors in the food prep area and walk in freezer noted in need of cleaning. 
 October 17, 2005 Routine 2 4 Details / Comments 
 0610 - Food stored on the floor or food stored less than 6&quot; above the floor. (boxes of fries on walk in freezer floor) 0820 - Critical Repeat Sausage patties and fried chicken/front hot holding at improper temperatures. 1450 - Heat lamps for holding fried chicken not adequate for holding at proper temperature for phfs. 1460 - Sanitizer sink stopper on three compartment sink was leaking. 1570 - The door gasket of the small reach in next to drive thru is (missing, damaged). 
 June 13, 2005 Routine 1 4 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. February 22, 2005 Follow-up 0 0 Details / Comments 
 0470 - Critical Unwrapped or uncovered food in the walk in coolers. 0550 - Dispensing utensils improperly stored between uses. (machine ice scoop) 0820 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Fried chicken,sausage gravy hot holding at improper temperatures. 0820 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Phf&apos;s in the small reach in cold holding at improper temperatures. 0830 - Critical Repeat The prepared ready-to-eat left over chicken in the refrigeration unit is not properly dated for disposition. 0850 - Critical Phf&apos;s for which time rather than temperature is being used as a control was not labeled or otherwise marked with a 4 hour cook, serve or discard by time. 1570 - Drain stopper of middle sink was observed in a state of disrepair and damaged. 1640 - Corrected During Inspection The in-use (wash, rinse, sanitize) water in the warewashing sink was observed to be heavily soiled or contaminated.(rinse water) 1800 - Repeat The nonfood contact surface of the inside and outside of equipment has accumulations of grime and debris. 2740 - Corrected During Inspection Trash and litter were observed adjacent to the refuse container outside the facility. 3180 - Repeat Floors in the food prep area noted in need of cleaning. 3330 - Critical Working containers of window cleaner are not properly labeled. 
 February 18, 2005 Routine 5 6 Details / Comments 
 1800 - Repeat The nonfood contact surface of the inside and outside of all equipment had accumulations of grime and debris. 3180 - Repeat Floors in the food prep area noted in need of cleaning. 0550 - Repeat Dispensing utensils improperly stored between uses.flour and food scoops 1700 - Critical Quatenary ammonia sanitizing was not at acceptable level. 
 November 04, 2004 Routine 1 3 Details / Comments 
 0610 - Food stored on the floor or food stored less than 6&quot; above the floor. (bags of flour,walk in) 0820 - Critical Sausage gravy hot holding at improper temperatures. 0820 - Critical Phf&apos;s in the sandwich prep unit cold holding at improper temperatures. 0830 - Critical The prepared ready-to-eat (RTE) fried chicken in the refrigeration unit is not properly dated for disposition. 3180 - Repeat Floors in the walk ins,and food prep area noted in need of cleaning. 3330 - Critical Repeat Working containers of cleaning solutions and window cleaner are not properly labeled. 1570 - The door gasket of the reach in next to the drive thru window is (missing, damaged). 1700 - Critical Chlorine sanitizing solution used was not at an acceptable concentration. 
 July 27, 2004 Routine 4 3 Details / Comments 
 2740 - Trash and litter were observed adjacent to the refuse container outside the facility. 3180 - Repeat Floors in the food prep area noted in need of cleaning. 1560 - Reach in has been installed on a table without sealing to the table or installing legs. This is a cleaning hazard. 1770 A - Critical The following equipment food-contact surfaces were observed soiled to sight and touch: raw chicken containers 3220 - Mops not hung up to air dry. 0550 - Repeat Dispensing utensils improperly stored between uses. 3030 - Repeat No disposable towels were provided a the hand washing lavatory in the back prep area 0820 - Critical Cheeses and tomatoes cold holding at improper temperatures. 0850 - Critical Fried chicken for which time rather than temperature is being used as a control was not labeled or otherwise marked with a 4 hour cook, serve or discard by time. 1800 - The nonfood contact surface of the inside and outside of equipment has accumulations of grime and debris. 3330 - Critical Working containers of sanitized solution are not properly labeled. 
 April 26, 2004 Routine 4 7 Details / Comments 1570 - Reach in was observed in a state of disrepair and damaged. January 27, 2004 Follow-up 0 1 Details / Comments 
 3180 - Repeat Floors in the food prep area noted in need of cleaning. 3030 - No disposable towels were provided a the hand washing lavatory in the back prep area 0820 - Critical Fried chicken hot holding at improper temperatures. 1770 - The nonfood-contact surfaces of the following equipment were observed soiled with an accumulation of dust, dirt, food residue, and/or other debris: all equipment,under grill,chicken containers. 1770 - Observed accumulations of grime and debris on the following food contact surfaces: large can opener 2000 - Single service items observed unprotected from contamination.(drink cup lids) 1320 - There was no temperature measuring device located in the refrigeration units. 0550 - Dispensing utensils improperly stored between. 0830 - Critical The prepared ready-to-eat bbq and chicken wings in the freezer is not properly dated for disposition. 2890 - Repeat Light bulb over the grill and fryers not shielded, coated, or otherwise shatter-resistent. 3080 - Less than 50 foot candles of light was noted in the exhaust hood. 3240 - Handwashing facilities are unclean and not maintained 1530 - There is no test kit located in the facility for monitoring the concentration of the chemical sanitizing solutions. 
 January 20, 2004 Routine 2 10 Details / Comments 
 1570 - Repeat A number of the refrigeration and freezer units door gasgets are split allowing food residue to accumulate. 1800 - Repeat The following nonfood contact surfaces shall be cleaned more frequently due to accumulations of food residue: 1. Tops and sides of equipment attached to the wall, such as, soap and paper towel dispensers. 2. Chrome wire shelving units - flour accumulations. 3. Interior bottoms of refrigeration and freezer units - food spillage 3200 - Repeat The sides of the hood over the biscuit ovens have dust and grease accumulations. Gas pipes also have accumulations. Filter needs to be changed. 
 July 16, 2003 Routine 0 3 Details / Comments 
 0960 2 - The food contact surface of some spatulars have begun to crack and split. 1190 - Some ambient air temperature measuring device (thermometer) are missing in refrigeration and freezer units and others are not in easily readable locations. 1570 - Repeat There are split and damaged door gaskets on the refrigeration and freezer units. 1800 - The following nonfood contact surfaces had accumulations of dust, flour and grease: 1. Top of convection oven and other equipment that has accumulations of dust, grease and flour. 2. Wire storage shelves 3. Insides of reach-in refrigeration and freezer units. 2890 - Light bulbs under the exhaust hoods are not shielded, coated, or otherwise shatter-resistent. 2870 - The following attachments to the walls and doors had accumulations of food residue, dust and grease: Door closures on the walk-in units, shelf brackets, electric cords on the hoods and gas pipes. 3180 - Repeat Floors under and behind equipment and storage shelves have accumulations of flour, grease and dust. In some cases the equipment needs to be moved. 3200 - Exhaust air ducts and hood filters are not being cleaned as ofter to minimize the accumulations of dust and grease. 
 February 10, 2003 Routine 0 8 Details / Comments
	</body>
</document>
