<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001853" url="http://www.moneyreasons.com/2011/10/improve-your-lifestyle-by-creating-a-personal-food-budget/" time="2012-07-12-17:38" support="7" score="0.02656763793183969" bingtitle="Improve Your Lifestyle By Creating a Personal Food Budget | Money ..." webtitle="Improve Your Lifestyle By Creating a Personal Food Budget | Money Reasons">
			<query id="000345" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="001098" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="001115" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000864" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="000690" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000362" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="001035" bing-rank="123"/>
	<description>But I know that’s not true, I will eat at a fast food restaurant again, especially if I ... With this “Budget“, I’ll track my food costs and also my weight readings ...</description>
	<body>
		Money Reasons 
 Smart Reasons to Save, Use and Invest Money Search for: 
 Home About Best Credit Cards Contact Privacy Policy 
 
Improve Your Lifestyle By Creating a Personal Food Budget
 October 14th, 2011 by Money Reasons Leave a reply» 
I have a confession to make, I eat out way too much.  And it’s mostly fast food, which makes the matter even worse.
 
Overweight
 
 

I’ll have short periods of time when I don’t eat out because I’m trying to save money or loss weight, but it typically seems that after a month or two I return back to my old habits and driving to the local drive-thrus, again.

I would like to say that I’m stopping, and this is the end of this trend, and I’ll never eat at a fast food restaurant again…But I know that’s not true, I will eat at a fast food restaurant again, especially if I’m crunched for time.

 So what is a fast food junkie to do? 

Creating a Personal Food Budget!

Synergy is a word that I heard back in college which means that the the combination of the parts is greater than the counting of the parts independently.  You may have seen it defined as 1 + 1 = 3, basically the idea is that elements combined together is stronger or more efficient than if the elements were just grouped separate.  And excellent physical example is the alloy metal“steel”.

So, I’ve decided to create something I’m going to call a Personal Food Budget !

In my Personal Food Budget , I’m going to track what I spent on the food I consume (like any other type of Spot Budget ), but I’m also going to track what I eat as well.  Now the“ Personal ”part of the title is obviously, I’m just doing this budget for me personally!  So I’m not going to track my family spending habits (besides they all look great, I’m the weight offender).

With this“ Budget “, I’ll track my food costs and also my weight readings for some type of repeating time period (probably weekly and monthly).  I’m not going to track calories (too much trouble), and once I reach a certain weight range I may stop recording my weight and just focus on the costs of what I eat, and if I eat out or not.

I decided that I’m not going to record this budget on paper, instead I’m going to do something online.  It may be as simple as a google spreadsheet, or you may see a new feature on my blog that will enable me to create something new.

Why a Personal Budget?

My Personal Budget is definitely to lose weight while keeping costs under control, but also because it would be simpler than going all out with a full budget.  If I make the process accessible from anywhere by keeping the data entry online, I’ll be more apt to record the information instantly.  With paper I might forget the costs of what I ate (who wants to remember those details anyway…it would be a waste of a memory).

Keeping it personal, means I don’t have to badger my wife and kids to determine what they eat.  Plus, as I said above, they look great (athletic really), so a Personal Budget won’t hold as much value for them.

If I find the process is very successful for me, you might find that I open it up for everybody to use.  And expect a few simple recipes that I might discover along the way!

Have a great weekend!

MR

 
 
 Previous Entry: Reader Thoughts–Response to Sacrifices Made On the Road To Become A Millionaire Next Entry: Our Halloween Tradition Watching The Nightmare Before Christmas 
 
Posted in Weight Loss 

Tags: affordable dienting creating a new lifestyle dieting getting in shape improving your lifestyle by eating better and saving money personal food budget saving money saving money on eating saving money with a food budget 

You can follow any responses to this entry through the RSS 2.0 Feed . 

 You can leave a response , or trackback from your own site.
 Advertisement 
25 comments
 Add your comment 
 Everyday Tips says: October 14, 2011 at 2:45 pm 
Definitely let us know how it goes!

I have found that since I have been working in an office, I save so much if I just throw some things together in a lunch box to eat throughout the day. When I work at home, I go out to eat more because I feel more isolated. In an office though, I want to just eat in the office so I can get out of there quicker. Kind of the opposite of what I expected.
 Reply 
 Money Reasons says: October 15, 2011 at 12:20 am 
Interesting turn on lunch!

I escape to the library where I had have free unblocked (and monitored) access to the internet. I should pack, it will enable me to get there more quickly…
 Reply 
 krantcents says: October 14, 2011 at 3:28 pm 
I remember the days when I had to go out to lunch. Either it was with colleagues or friends. It was enjoyable, but I wanted to save the oney. I statrted to bring my lunch once a week and it grew to 5 times a week. Now my choice is (school) cafeteria food or bringing my lunch. I opted for my own lunch because it is better for me and cheaper. Small changes works.
 Reply 
 Money Reasons says: October 15, 2011 at 12:24 am 
Small changes are great! I’m hoping to slowly meander into a more healthy lifestyle too 
 Reply 
 Suba says: October 14, 2011 at 3:30 pm 
I have been doing the tracking for a month and a half now. I am not tracking the cost though. I am just tracking what I eat and the calories, purely for the purpose of weight loss.

We eat out once a week (twice sometimes). We buy gift cards for all the restaurants during the holiday season, so our eating out is almost $0 during the year. If we run out of gift cards, we cut down our eating out too. That sort of keeps our food budget in control.

Let us know how it goes!
 Reply 
 Money Reasons says: October 15, 2011 at 12:26 am 
Very clever! We exchange gift card with my sister, but it never last the entire year or we go someplace different than our gift cards permit.

I like you idea around the gift cards though, it’s like a non-accounting budget!

Awesome technique! I might even try that myself…
 Reply 
 20&apos;s Finances says: October 14, 2011 at 3:30 pm 
Good luck with the“budget.”My wife and I cook 2 meals a week and eat leftovers. It’s quick, easy and saves on the wallet. I was actually planning a post about this. Probably in December as Nov is filling up fast. Who knows…
 Reply 
 Money Reasons says: October 15, 2011 at 12:32 am 
Sounds like a great plan!
 Reply 
 Christa says: October 14, 2011 at 5:24 pm 
I think this is a great idea. One of my friends started to track all of the money she was spending since the beginning of the year, and it inspired her to quit smoking!
 Reply 
 Money Reasons says: October 15, 2011 at 12:39 am 
It’s amazing how expensive smoking is! You pay for a product the reduces your life and make you cough all through life…Go figure.

A few of my family members smoke, and my grandfather died a horrible death from them.
 Reply 
 BeatingTheIndex says: October 14, 2011 at 7:58 pm 
If creating a budget is the key to curbing your appetite for fast food so be it. You’ll hit 2 birds with 1 stone: weight loss and saving on eating out 
 Reply 
 Money Reasons says: October 15, 2011 at 12:37 am 
Yep, I hope that synergy factor comes in to play. Individually, it just isn’t enough, but combining the two (cost and dieting) will push me over the edge (I hope).
 Reply 
 101 Centavos says: October 14, 2011 at 11:23 pm 
Hope you make some good progress, MR. Keeping yourself accountable is a good strategy.

I have a hard time eating healthy (or moderately, for that matter) when a business lunch is called for. Today we took some European colleagues out for some good Oklahoma BBQ. Ribs, slaw, cowboy beans with bacon, and cheese balls. It’s way past dinnertime, and I’m still stuffed. On days like this when I know that a heavy lunch is inevitable, I try to plan to balance it out with no breakfast and only a snack for dinner.
 Reply 
 Money Reasons says: October 15, 2011 at 12:29 am 
Thanks, I have to strike a balance and right quick!

I like the forethought that you came up with to lessen the hit of the very tasty but high caloric lunch!
 Reply 
 Robert @ My Multiple Incomes says: October 15, 2011 at 2:17 pm 
Yes, I’d be interested in hearing your follow-ups!
 Reply 
 Money Reasons says: October 15, 2011 at 8:58 pm 
Thanks, I’m hoping to finally going a grip around my weight and lifestyle
 Reply 
 Hunter @ Financially Consumed says: October 15, 2011 at 4:45 pm 
I look forward to following your progress MR. This is a battle I am confronting right now also. I’m just too heavy and need to smarten up about my food choices. I can’t exercize my way out of it like I did 10 years ago.
 Reply 
 Money Reasons says: October 15, 2011 at 9:01 pm 
I’m going to pull out every trick that I can thinking of to help myself lose weight.
 Reply 
 Roshawn @ Watson Inc says: October 15, 2011 at 11:35 pm 
I have been working hard to stay on track with respect to food for health purposes. It’s something that I constantly watch. Good luck with your journey.
 Reply YFS @ Yourfinancessimplified says: October 16, 2011 at 1:20 pm 
great idea, how much have you lost so far?
 Reply Barb Friedberg says: October 16, 2011 at 10:41 pm 
Good luck with the whole thing. I gotta blame rising food costs a bit. We don’t eat out much and our food costs are HIGH.
 Reply Well Heeled Blog says: October 16, 2011 at 10:53 pm 
I need a personal food budget! Unfortunately, I routinely break my own budget because there are no actual consequences for doing so. I’m going to try to remember that all the money I spend on eating out can be spend on other things…and it won’t hurt to cut back just one or two meals a week.
 Reply Miss T @ Prairie Eco-Thrifter says: October 17, 2011 at 11:49 am 
Good luck with your new system. We have been doing this very thing for a number of months now. We also track whether items were healthy or unhealthy so we can see what percentage of our money is going to junk. It has worked really well in making sure we eat more healthy stuff. It also helps us track and see what we buy most often.
 Reply 
 
Trackbacks /
Pingbacks

 Weekly Favorites, Gratitude, and Giveaways #43 | Budgeting In the Fun Stuff A Taxing Set of Mid-Week Random Links | 101 Centavos 
 
Leave a Reply
 Click here to cancel reply. 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 
 
 

 
 
 

  RSS        Twitter      

 
 Previous Entry Reader Thoughts–Response to Sacrifices Made On the Road To Become A Millionaire Next Entry Our Halloween Tradition Watching The Nightmare Before Christmas 
 Categories Select Category 401k Banking Bargains Beliefs Blogging Book Reviews Budgeting Car Insurance Career Carnival College Costs credit card debt Dividends Economy Employment Entertainment Entrepreneurship Environment Expenses Experiment Family Financial Heroes Free Frugality Funds Giveaway Goal Funds Goals Guests Health Holiday Housing HSA Humor Ideas Inspirational Insurance Investments Kids Lemons to Lemonade lifestyle Milestones Millionaire Mortgages Multitasking Payouts Pet Planning Problems Productivity Real Estate Resolutions Retirement Review RipOff Roth IRA Savings Social Class Stocks Taxes Uncategorized Vacation Wasting Time Wealth Weekly Review Weight Loss Winning 

 

 
 
 

--&gt;
 
 Back to Top 

©2012 Money Reasons·Proudly powered by WordPress &amp; Green Park 2 by Cordobo .

Valid XHTML 1.0 Transitional | Valid CSS 3

 
 
 Disclaimer:

This site is for informational and entertainment purposes only, and the content herein should not be mistaken for professional financial advice. It is highly recommended that you seek advice from a professional for serious financial matters. This site and its author may be compensated for expressing personal opinions regarding featured products and services.
	</body>
</document>
