<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001234" url="http://www.kfyrtv.com/News_Stories.asp?news=45210" time="2012-07-12-16:41" support="1" score="0.00020862020377109404" bingtitle="Natural Weight Loss on KFYR-TV North Dakota&apos;s NBC News Leader" webtitle="Natural Weight Loss on KFYR-TV North Dakota&apos;s NBC News Leader">
			<query id="000861" bing-rank="230"/>
	<description>... person`s seat ... to a fast food restaurant. Because I was hungry and I had a long day, I didn`t eat ... second fast food restaurant. Then sometimes my wife would have a meal ...</description>
	<body>
		Contact Us Search News 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005   
 Natural Weight Loss | Video 
 Juli McDonald | 12/15/2010
 
 Many of the weight loss success stories we hear today are thanks to advances in various surgical procedures. It works great for many candidates, but it`s not the only option.

Two years ago, Dr. Everett Heringer was living large. At 333 pounds, he was sluggish, suffered from chest pain, and struggled to move around.

&quot;One of the biggest embarrassments was when I was flying in a plane. You sit in the seat and the rest of you is just sort of squished over on the other person`s seat, just kind of flowed over. I was always embarrassed sitting in that seat,&quot; he says.

The road to that number on Dr. Heringer`s scale was built on bad habits, like convenient eating.

&quot;I would leave the office, jump to a fast food restaurant. Because I was hungry and I had a long day, I didn`t eat properly and I wasn`t aware of what I was eating. Before I got home, I`d sometimes stop at a second fast food restaurant. Then sometimes my wife would have a meal prepared. It was just a lot of bad eating habits and just eating more food than I should be eating and eating poorly. Not the right kinds of foods,&quot; says Heringer.

Heringer`s doctor told him he was morbidly obese. He knew he had to make a change. Part of the motivation actually came from his own line of work.

&quot;I`ve had the privilege over the years of helping many people through dentistry, find the best version of themselves. It`s been a wonderful privilege and I knew there was a best version of me inside just dying to get out. I just said I`m gonna get it done. I want to find it,&quot; he says.

Heringer knew he had to lose a lot of weight to save his life. While he did consider surgery, ultimately he decided against it, and took on the challenge of changing how he lives everyday.
 COMMENT ON THIS STORY 
 
 BACK TO NEWS | BACK TO REGIONAL STORIES 
Share Story
 
 LATEST NEWS 
 
 Becoming a Legal North Dakota Resident | Video - 11:22 PM Temporary Bypass | Video - 11:19 PM North Hill Shopping Center | Video - 8:19 PM 55th St. NE Bridge Bypass | Video - 8:18 PM Zoo Animals Coming Home | Video - 8:17 PM Minot Man Charged with Killing His Three Daughters | Video - 8:15 PM More Information on Fargo Murder-Suicide | Video - 8:14 PM Update on Missing Ardoch Woman | Video - 8:12 PM Where Are The Women? | Video - 8:10 PM Affordable Housing Needs | Video - 8:07 PM 
 
 FEATURES AND PROMOTIONS News 
 News 
 Webcasts 
 Country Morning Today 
 Meet the News Team 
 Search News Stories 
 NBC News Videos 
 MSNBC 

 Programming 
 NBC On-Demand Weather 
 Weather 
 7 Day Forecast 
 Skytracker Radar 
 Kevin&apos;s Corner 
 Kevin in the Classroom 
 Sky Spy Photos 
 Skywatch Cameras 
 Road Conditions 
 Regional Weather 
 Web Weather 
 Weather Call 
 Sports 
 Sports 
 Sports Spotlight 
 Local Scores 
 Wizards Blog 
 Marauders Weekly 
 NBC Sports 
 MLB Scoreboard Features 
 Community Connection 
 Double Dollar Friday 
 Movie Listings 
 Contests&amp;Promotions 
 Ask an Attorney 
 Off the Beaten Path 
 Mr. Food 
 Best of the Class 
 KFYR-TV Fun Bus 
 Students do the News 
 Find Us 
 Contact Us 
 About Us 
 Advertising&amp;Sales 
 Job Opportunities 
 FCC Reports 
 Privacy Policy 
 Facebook 
 twitter 
 KMOT in Minot 
 KQCD in Dickinson 
 KUMV in Williston 
 ©2012 KFYR-TV
	</body>
</document>
