<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001031" url="http://www.recipelion.com/Restaurant-Recipes/Wendys-Frosty" time="2012-07-12-16:26" support="8" score="0.016736192495612732" bingtitle="Copycat Recipes Wendy&apos;s Frosty | RecipeLion.com" webtitle="Copycat Recipes Wendy&apos;s Frosty | RecipeLion.com">
			<query id="000305" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000279" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="000181" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="000175" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000895" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000293" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000424" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000267" bing-rank="225"/>
	<description>Copycat recipes let you enjoy classic restaurant recipes without ever leaving your home. ... Ingredients. 1 cup milk; 1 / 2 cup Nestle Quik; 4 cups vanilla ice cream, softened</description>
	<body>
		Tweet 
Follow Us on Facebook

Get updates from RecipeLion.com posted directly to your News Feed.
 
 
 My Recipe Box My Newsletters Log In Register Now 
 
 Site Map RSS Bookmark 
 
 Blog Casseroles Cheap Meals Copycat Free eCookbooks Printable Grocery Coupons Reviews&amp;Giveaways 
 
 
Categories

 Restaurant Recipes Appetizers Beans Beef Recipes Bread Breakfast Recipes Budget Friendly Cake Candy Recipes Casserole Recipes Chicken Recipes Cookies&amp;Bars Cooking Tips Dairy Dessert Drink Recipes Dry Mixes Editor&apos;s Picks Ethnic Food Featured Foodies Food Companies Foodie Reviews Fruit Grilling Holidays Meat Recipes Microwave Modified Diet Pasta Pie Recipes Pizza Pork Recipes Preserving Pressure Cooker Rice Salad Sandwiches Sauces Seafood Side Dishes Slow Cooker Snacks Soups, Stews, Chili Substitutions Turkey Vegetables Vegetarian Your Favorite Brands 
 
 Home &gt; Restaurant Recipes &gt; Wendy&apos;s Frosty
 (1) 
 
Wendy&apos;s Frosty
 
You must be logged in to add a private note. Login | Register 
 
My Notes
 
My Notes

ONLY YOU see your private notes.
 
 Notes Print My Recipe Box Add Rate Comment 
 
We are adding the recipe to your Recipe Box.

This was added to your Recipe Box.

 Click here to view your Recipe Box. 

You must be logged in to add a recipe. Login | Register 
 
 
Rate This Article
 Very Poor Poor OK Good Very Good 
Comment On This Article
 
 
We are adding your Comments&amp;Rating. 

Thank you! Your Comment&amp;Rating have been added and will be posted shortly.

You must be logged in to rate or leave a comment. Login | Register 
 
Share this on:

 Twitter Digg Delicious Facebook Google StumbleUpon MySpace Email 
 
Most fast food joints have burgers and fries, but only Wendy&apos;s has the frosty. Make this copycat recipe either as a dessert or a dip for fries. Copycat recipes let you enjoy classic restaurant recipes without ever leaving your home.
 
Ingredients

 1 cup milk 1 / 2 cup Nestle Quik 4 cups vanilla ice cream, softened 
 
Instructions

 Blend milk and Nestle&apos;s Quik for 10 seconds on high speed of blender.
  Pulse in the ice cream until barely mixed. Mixture should be very thick.
  Freeze for at least an hour before serving. 
 
Notes

This recipe was featured in 30 Frozen Desserts to Satisfy your Sweet Tooth . Check out the 29 other awesome frozen desserts featured in the article for some great dessert recipes!
 
Related Recipes
 
 14 Fantastic Easter Dessert Recipes 

 602 Great Recipes for You 

 &quot;14 Restaurant-Style Country Recipes&quot; eCookbook 
 
 Notes Print My Recipe Box Add Rate Comment 
 
Newsletter Signup
 
Free Newsletter!

Subscribe to our free recipe newsletter and we will send you delicious recipes and special offers to your inbox. Sign up today!
 
Please Wait 

Thanks for signing up

Sorry, we could not sign you up.
 
What&apos;s Hot
 
Top Restaurant Recipes

 The 10 Best Copycat Restaurant Recipes &quot;14 Restaurant-Style Country Recipes&quot; eCookbook 27 Secret Restaurant Copycat Recipes eCookbook 9 Must Have Cracker Barrel Restaurant Recipes 11 Irresistible KFC Restaurant Copycat Recipes Shelburne Inn Baked Apple Upside Down French Toast Cheesecake Factory Bruschetta 19 Newly Uncovered Copycat Recipes, Also 3 More Secret Recipes Cracker Barrel Inspired Chicken&amp;Dumplings Wendy&apos;s Frosty 
 My Recipe Box (0) View» 
Something worth saving?

 Register now for FREE to:

 SAVE your favorite recipes ADD personal notes GET fast cooking tips 
 
 Log In 
 
 Join Us Today Forgot Password 
 
 
 
Free eCookbooks
 
 39 Appetizer Recipes and Party Pleasers Must-Have Meatloaf Recipes Simple Mexican Recipes Simple Slow Cooker Suppers Tasty, Easy Breakfast Recipes Top Secret Copycat Restaurant Recipes 
 
Connect with Us

Find us online

 
 
 
 About Us Advertise Contact Us FAQs Keyword Index News Privacy Policy Subscribe Terms of Service Unsubscribe 
 
 
©Copyright 2012 Prime Publishing, LLC. All rights reserved.
 
 
©Copyright 2012 Prime Publishing, LLC. All rights reserved.

www.recipelion.com
 
Log In to Your Account
 
 Register Now! Forgot Password? 
 Email: Password:   Login with Facebook 
Register Now!
 
 Log In Forgot Password? 
 Public/Display Name: Optional: This is the name that will appear alongside any reviews you create on the site. You can use letters, numbers and white space. First Name: Last Name: Email:
	</body>
</document>
