<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001107" url="http://houston.citysearch.com/review/9907304" time="2012-07-12-16:32" support="3" score="0.003288894611297127" bingtitle="Teppay Japanese Restaurant User Reviews - Houston, TX 77057 ..." webtitle="Teppay Japanese Restaurant User Reviews - Houston, TX 77057 - Citysearch">
			<query id="001393" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="001047" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="001396" bing-rank="245"/>
	<description>When the Japanese consul wants to have a reception ... will try your patience if you sit at a table ... too, since I bet Walm**t&apos;s or any fast-food restaurant&apos;s ...</description>
	<body>
		Deals Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Hotels Shopping Best Of Citysearch 

 Mobile Login / Join 
 More More Go! Advertise With Us 
 Citysearch has shed its old skin! In addition to our new look, there&apos;s a boatload of new features. Poke around! Tell us what you think! 
 Houston, TX Metro &gt; Houston &gt; Restaurants &gt; Teppay Japanese Restaurant Teppay Japanese Restaurant (713) 789-4506 
 6516 Westheimer Rd , Houston , TX | Directions  
 77057 29.737801 -95.498901 
 Share Save 
   Own this Business? Recommend this business? Thumbs Up Thumbs Down ? 60 % 100 11 10 Votes Add a Photo Neighborhoods: Great Uptown, Westside Site Feedback 
 Overview Tips (11) Photos (0) 
 Write a Tip for Teppay Japanese Restaurant… 
 Sign in to Write a Tip 
 Write a Tip... optional 
 
 
Tips from Citysearch

 Citysearch ( 10 ) | Around the Web ( 1 ) 
 Sort by:
 Date Rating Popular 
 Recommends mizzv Joined 3 years ago 5.0 May 27, 2011 
 Best sushi I&apos;ve found in Houston. It&apos;s been a while since I&apos;ve been here because I&apos;ve since moved, but this is the freshest sushi I&apos;ve found in Houston. They use real wasabi (ground instead of the powder mix) and shiso leaves instead of the plastic&quot;grass&quot;sheets. I love sitting at the bar since the chef usually gives us freebies off the ends of the rolls or new creations to try.

The food is very traditional, so you will not find exotic rolls that are in the new, hip joints. There are usually many Japanese dining there and the service is friendly, though they can get backed up. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends jldtecmag Joined 4 years ago 5.0 March 11, 2011 
 Best Authentic Japanese Restaurant in Town. When the Japanese consul wants to have a reception at the consulate, he asks Toshiro Sato to prepare dinner for him. When James Baker (former Secretay of State) wants to have Japnese food, he goes there (I met him several times).

I took some Japanese customers there, and they were, at first very sceptical. When they entered the restaurant, one of them said:&quot;It smells like Japan&quot;.

That says it all. I have been to Japan many many times. This is the only original Japanese restaurant in town. Period … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends sushibandit Joined 5 years ago 5.0 March 25, 2009 
 Outstanding. Chef Toshihiro Sato knows what the heck he is doing. Contrary to the previous negative post this place will meet your traditional sushi desires. Of the&quot;Big 4&quot;Japanese owned/operated places in town I like Teppay the best because Chef Sato takes such personal care of his clients, even 1st timers. There are minor issues, the mentioned restroom is not a resort and the waitstaff will try your patience if you sit at a table from time to time, but the quality and diversity of food is truly top drawer. Try the aji sashimi served on the fish carcass, then have the bones fried up kara age style. It&apos;s quite the presentation and adventure, not to mention that it&apos;s highly edible. Last week Chef Sato had tobiwu, flying fish, flown in from Japan. The nigiri from this bad boy was ridiculous. Topped with finely shredded scallion and ginger with a drizzle of the Chef&apos;s own ponzu, it was amazing. Don&apos;t let the ulcerated opinion dissuade you, this place is the real deal. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Doesn&apos;t Recommend melvinhsie Joined 5 years ago 1.0 April 13, 2008 
 Licensed Robber. Even one star is a mercy for Teppay.. If you want to make someone suffer from gastric ulcer, please take him/her to Teppay on Westheimer. The memorable dinning experience I had in Houston began with a strong anchovy smell when stepping into Teppay. Since we were not that hungry, we just ordered Sashimi and Sushi. Nearly half of the sushi menu items were marked with &apos;Market Price&apos;, so that we had to ask one by one for the price in order to make sure they would not rob on any mysterious item, let alone the waitress became a bit not patient. The taste was OK, but I am sure I myself can make better Sushi than the chefs there. The service was incredibly poor, because I had to ask every time to let the waitress refill the tea. The toilet was impressive too, since I bet Walm**t&apos;s or any fast-food restaurant&apos;s toilet can beat this one. Here came the bill for the last moment: a bill for three here can feed an army almost anywhere else, even though we didn&apos;t feel full yet!!!

Not finished yet: The next day I had a hard time at restroom, of course it was because of the wonderul sushi I had in Teppay.

Honestly there are lots of good Japanese restaurants here in Houston. Any of those near Rice University is far better than this one. However, if you want to enhance your dining experience of being fooled, please don&apos;t forget to stop by Teppay. Douzo, jibun de tabe te mi te kudasai. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends superlluclkycat Joined 5 years ago 5.0 October 31, 2007 
 Try Kenny&apos;s Special Sushi Rolls!. My boyfriend and I go here for entertainment, good sushi and sake! The fish is fresh (no dyes in the tuna) and the wasabe is hottt! Japanese food made by a Japanese chef, who has studied in Japan - although he is young - is better than a Mexican behind the sushi bar slicing your sashimi. If you ask the chef to be creative, he has come up with some signature rolls that aren&apos;t on the menu, but if you give him an idea of what ingredients you like, he can come up with something tasty as well as asthetically pleasing. However, if you prefer authentic fare, they offer it as well. We recommend this establishment to sushi beginners, as well as those who are experienced Japanese culinary experts, and we&apos;ve been to all the sushi spots in Houston!! … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Contributor Joined 9 years ago August 19, 2005 
 The sushi at this longstanding Galleria-area restaurant is a favorite of Japanese businessmen and area sushi purists.. In Short 
Among dozens of sushi spots along Westheimer, this restaurant has been serving sushi without the hype for more than a decade. A handful of tables and a busy sushi bar create an intimate atmosphere although it can sometimes be overly smoky. Owner Toshihiro Sato ensures that the authentic Japanese menu offers a variety of flavors. Choose from a number of small plate appetizers, sukiyaki (prepared at the table), noodle dishes or flavorful rolls. Sushi and sashimi are always fresh.
 … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends zptabby Joined 7 years ago 5.0 July 21, 2005 
 YUMMY!. The freshest Sushi I have found in town! The Sushi like butter in your mouth. No chewy Sashimi here! The rolls are excellent as well. My only complaint is they allow smoking and for such a small restaurant, it should certainly be non-smoking! Other than that, the service is great and it is quite cozy inside. Perfect for eating alone or with a very small group. Not great for large parties. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Doesn&apos;t Recommend tony_luk Joined 8 years ago 2.0 February 21, 2004 
 Ex-favorite Jap rest.. Used to be my most favorite Japanese rest---best quality in town after Fuji! Extremely expensive---friends used to call it $80 buffet!(per person of course). But it was still worth it due to the quality. Unfortunately, quality has gone down(even the sea weed for the sushi has changed from crispy to soft(very BAD in a highly-rated, real Japanese rest).

After all, quality still better than most Am-Japanese rest. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends CaptHook Joined 9 years ago 5.0 February 11, 2003 
 Cozy Kitchen. I live around the corner and every time I walk here the staff always takes great care of me and my company. The food is always exceptional and I don&apos;t think I have every heard a complaint from any table while I dine there. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Doesn&apos;t Recommend sushipig Joined 10 years ago 2.5 November 05, 2002 
 Fun, but not the best. Teppay&apos;s new sushi chef is very funny but a little young (21-25 I would guess) to have enough experience to prepare a quality sushi meal. You wont be bored but for the best and most authentic sushi, teppay just isnt there yet. Better than miyako or cafe japon but just not the cream of the crop. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart 
People who viewed this also viewed…
 
 25 % Genji Japanese Restaura… 7964 Westheimer Rd 
 Houston, TX 
0.6 mi away 93 % Sasaki Japanese Restaur… 8979 Westheimer Rd 
 Houston, TX 
1.4 mi away 55 % Uptown Tapas&amp;Sushi Ba… 5706 Richmond Ave 
 Houston, TX 
1.3 mi away 
 
Things to do near Teppay Japanese Restaurant
 
 Restaurants Movie Theaters Banks 

 Bars Shopping&amp;Malls Hotels 
 
 About Apps Careers Privacy Policy Terms of Use Contact Us Blog FAQs 
 
Partner Sites:

 Ask Kids     Bloglines     Expedia     Hotels     Hotwire     Insider Pages     MerchantCircle     Reference     The Daily Beast     Thesaurus     Urbanspoon 
 ©2011. Citysearch is a registered trademark of CityGrid Media. Data provided by Infogroup. All rights reserved. 
 Popular Categories Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Shopping Hotels Deals Sports&amp;Recreation Cafes Movie Theaters Directory&amp;Services 

 Change City New York City Los Angeles Houston Chicago Atlanta Seattle Portland Philadelphia Austin San Francisco More…
	</body>
</document>
