<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001869" url="http://www.statesman.com/blogs/content/shared-gen/blogs/austin/blotter/entries/2011/09/index.html" time="2012-07-12-17:39" support="27" score="0.01803338366783597" bingtitle="Austin news, sports, weather, Longhorns, business | Statesman.com" webtitle="Austin news, sports, weather, Longhorns, business | Statesman.com">
			<query id="000228" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000165" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000291" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000948" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="001011" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="001325" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="001167" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="000414" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000445" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="000328" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="000194" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="000917" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="001420" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="001419" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="000197" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000697" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="001042" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="000979" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000506" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000759" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000791" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000322" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000854" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000259" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="001451" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000509" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="001294" bing-rank="89"/>
	<description>She told the officer she had been drinking whiskey and was still very ... Police have said that Hall was at a fast-food restaurant that morning in the 9500 block of ...</description>
	<body>
		The Adobe Flash Player is required to view this multimedia interactive. Get it here . 
 SUBSCRIBE TODAY PRINT OR E-EDITION 
 
 JOBS HOMES CARS CLASSIFIEDS HOOKEM.COM ENTERTAINMENT NEWS 

 Home NEWS 
 Local News VIRTUAL CAPITOL PolitiFact Texas STATE Commuter Rail Got a news tip? Statesman Investigates Special Reports Education STATESMAN WATCH Elections Database Central WILLIAMSON NATION World Last 7 days Archives Obituaries Corrections Lottery Statesman Crimetracker This is Austin Ethics Policy 
 BUSINESS 
 TECHNOLOGY PERSONAL FINANCE Top Workplaces 
 2012 2011 EMPLOYERS 2010 employers 
 Area Employers Employment REAL ESTATE Markets/AP Business News Business Blog Last 7 days PR Newswire 
 Sports 
 Longhorns Longhorns GameWeek 
 Rice Brigham Young UCLA Iowa State Oklahoma Oklahoma State Kansas Texas Tech Missouri Kansas State Texas A&amp;M; Baylor 
 AGGIES March Madness College Football HIGH SCHOOL 
 Team Pages Volleyball Sports Photo Contest 
 HS Football 
 Photo contest Battle of the Bands 
 Capitol 10,000 Sports Video Express Stars RECRUITING OUTDOORS GOLF Formula 1 Area Pro Teams AP SPORTS NFL 
 Cowboys Texans 
 NBA 
 Spurs Mavericks Rockets 
 MLB 
 Astros Rangers 
 Last 7 days 
 Life 
 Real 
 Shine Domestic Flavor heart Diversions Last 90 days of REAL stories 
 STYLE TRAVEL 
 Hill Country Travel Louisiana Travel 
 GARDENING Season for Caring RAISING AUSTIN 
 Raising Austin Forum Mama Drama 
 BOOKS HEALTH&amp;MEDICAL Camp Guide GREEN Campaign to end breast cancer Dog Show Pets of the Week Weddings Lady Bird&apos;s Legacy Glossy FAITH Entertainment 
 Arts Calendar Food&amp;Drink TV Music Movies Recreation Spas&amp;Salons 
 Last 7 days 
 Opinion 
 Editorials Letters to the Editor Commentary Other Takes Insight&amp;Books 
 Books Forums 
 
 WEATHER 
 Conditions Weather Blog Allergy Report Storm season Storm Tracker 
 Traffic 
 Traffic Cameras 
 MULTIMEDIA 
 Photo Galleries Video Sports video Interactives Collective Vision 
 Blogs 
 News 
 Austin Legal City and County Beat Fort Hood on the Front Lines Focal Point Hill Country Rambler Homeroom Kelso&apos;s Cranky Corner Postcards Salsa Verde Salud Shortcuts Somos Austin The Blotter The Lowdown on Higher Education Weather Watch Willco Wired 
 Business 
 Starting Up Statesman Business Blog Up the Ladder 
 Sports 
 Backspin Bevo Beat Bohl Games Fantasy Island Formula Austin Golden&apos;s Nuggets No Limits The 12th Word at A&amp;M; Tour de France Varsity News 
 Life 
 Anders Meanders Design Austin Keeping It Real Knittin&apos; Kitten Mama Drama The Goods The Reader 
 Opinion 
 Grapeshot The Reader 
 Multimedia 
 Collective Vision 
 
 Customer Service 
 Contact Us Advertise 
 Print Online Classifieds (Print&amp;Online) eTearsheets Newspaper Ads 
 Member Center E-mail Newsletters Subscriber Services Subscribe to the paper Where to buy the Statesman Sign up for the eEdition Buy Photos, Section Fronts Reader Rewards Readers Panel Marketing Careers at The Statesman Internships Community Development Newspapers in Education Sitemap 
 SHOPPING 

 Site Web Archive Web Search by YAHOO! 
 The Blotter 
 
The Blotter
What&apos;s on The Blotter? Police press releases, public safety updates, traffic updates and general breaking news.

What&apos;s on this page?

All the entries posted in September.

RSS feed

If you use an RSS reader, here is feed for The Blotter: XML .
 Learn more about RSS.

Categories

 Airport Animal Cruelty Assault Bank robbery Boil water notice Bomb scare Burglary Chase Child Abuse Collision Comic capers Courts Drowning drugs DWI Election news EMS Escape Fatal accidents Fatal wreck Fire Fort Hood Fraud High speed chase Hit-and-run Home invasion Homicide Illegal gambling Illegal hunting Injury accidents Kidnapping Military casualty Missing Persons News Police Power Protest Rescues Robbery School lockdown Sexual assault Shooting Sports Stabbing Suspicious death SWAT team Theft Traffic Train derailment Vandalism water Weather white collar 
 
Commenting is open from 8 a.m. to 5 p.m. M-F
 
 July 2012 S M T W T F S 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31         More archives... 
 
Statesman Blogs
	</body>
</document>
