<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001521" url="http://wiki.answers.com/Q/Do_Fast_food_places_generally_accept_food_stamps" time="2012-07-12-17:17" support="1" score="0.001927495276412065" bingtitle="Do Fast food places generally accept food stamps" webtitle="Do Fast food places generally accept food stampsDo Fast food places generally accept food stamps">
			<query id="001287" bing-rank="85"/>
	<description>Yes because I use my food stamp debit card there all the time. Who accepts food stamps in ... What is William graham&apos;s contribution to sociology?</description>
	<body>
		Unanswered Questions New Answers Q&amp;A;Categories Coupons Guides 

 Sign In | Sign Up Home Search Settings Top Contributors Help Center English▼ 
 English Français Deutsch Italiano Español Tagalog 
 
 Home Answers.com &gt; Wiki Answers &gt; Categories &gt; History, Politics&amp;Society &gt; Society and Civilization &gt; Welfare &gt; The Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program &gt; Do Fast food places generally accept food stamps? 
Do Fast food places generally accept food stamps?
 In: The Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program [ Edit categories ] 

 Answer: 

No. Food stamps cannot be used to purchase ready-made food. 

 First answer by Kirsten07734 . Last edit by Kirsten07734 . Contributor trust : 281 
 [ recommend contributor recommended ]. Question popularity : 2 [ recommend question ]. [ report abuse ] 
Can you answer these The Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program questions?
 
 Do you still pay child support if you are on food stamps? Answer it! What is the bill number for food stamp ban for drug felons? Answer it! When you move to Ky how long does take to get medicaid and food stamps? Answer it! Can you use Mississippi food stamps in Alabama? Answer it! What restaurant in Nashville take food stamps? Answer it! 
 
Relevant answers:
 
 Where do fast food places keep food ? 
 In the fridge or freezer, then it&apos;s prepared and usually held in some sort of unit heating cabinet or food warmer until being ordered. 
 Why are fast food places garbage? 
 Fast food can cause serious health problems like obesity and heart problems. 
 What is the healthiest fast food place ? 
 it doesn&apos;t exist, sorry 
 What fast food place is the cheapest? 
 MCDONALDS 
 What are the major fast food places ? 
 McDonald&apos;s, Wendy&apos;s, Burger King, Taco Bell, Subway, Pizza Hut, KFC, Jack-In The Box, Del-Taco, Green Burrito, Quizno&apos;s, Carl&apos;s Jr., A&amp;W RootBeer, In-N-Out Burgers, SONIC, Popeye&apos;s, and a lot... 
 
 Sign in using: Answers members: Username Lost password? Password Remember me Sign in 
Home
 
 Recent site activity Browse categories 
 Animal Life Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Vehicles Entertainment&amp;Arts Food&amp;Cooking Health History, Politics&amp;Society Hobbies&amp;Collectibles Home&amp;Garden Humor&amp;Amusement Jobs&amp;Education Law&amp;Legal Issues Literature&amp;Language Relationships Religion&amp;Spirituality Science Shopping Sports Technology Travel&amp;Places WikiAnswers Local 
 Random question Promoted questions Community forum Unanswered questions Advanced search Top contributors Q&amp;A;categories Coupons Guides Settings 
 
 Answer these 
 What is the distance from Sherwood OR to Mt Hood? In: Volcanoes Answer it! Can you put water in your coolant tank if you are out of coolant? In: Antifreeze and Engine Coolant Answer it! Does Tesco have a time portal behind the bakery section? In: Cars&amp;Vehicles Answer it! What time period lasted for more than half the hypothesised history of earth? In: Planet Earth Answer it! » more 
Featured guides
 
 Compare Hospitals In Your Area Suntrust Online Banking Best Pots and Pans How Many Songs Can A 8GB iPod Hold? How to Repair a Scratch 
 » More 
Answers Properties
 
 Answers Wiki Answers Video Answers Guides Coupons 

 Local Answers Online Answers Shop Answers Blog Sitemap 
 
Company
 
 About Terms of Use Privacy Policy IP Issues Disclaimer 
 
Community
 
 Guidelines Reputation Roles Help 
 
Updates
 
 Email Watchlist RSS 
 
 
International sites
 English | Deutsch | Español | Français | Italiano | Tagalog 
 
 Copyright©2012 Answers Corporation facebook twitter youtube blog
	</body>
</document>
