<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001024" url="http://www.naturalpedia.com/Oat_Bran-7.html" time="2012-07-12-16:26" support="1" score="0.000406403574113344" bingtitle="Oat Bran - NaturalNews NaturalPedia" webtitle="Oat Bran">
			<query id="001277" bing-rank="248"/>
	<description>One-half cup of fiber-rich oat bran a day has demonstrated ... the rare occasions when Dr. Anderson finds himself in a fast-food restaurant, he orders a lower-fat selection ...</description>
	<body>
		Home         About NaturalPedia         Contact Us         Sign Up for Free Email Alerts 
 
 
 NaturalPedia &gt; Oat Bran
 Quotes about Oat Bran from the world&apos;s top natural health / natural living authors 
 
 Share Tweet Email to a friend    |   Click here for FREE email alerts 
 
page 7 of 9 | Next -&gt; 
 &quot;Oats: oatmeal, oat bran cereal, oat bran muffins.
 Millet: as side dish, as cereal, or puffed millet.
 Other: quinoa (also available as pasta), amaranth, flours of rice, cornmeal, buckwheat, barley, oats, spelt, and quinoa, to make bread, muffins, cookies, pancakes, crusts, etc. Also consider soy, potato, lentil, or garbanzo flour; chestnut or tapioca flour, kudzu root, and arrowroot (kudzu and arrowroot are commonly used as wheat substitutes for thickening gravies and sauces). Try artichoke or buckwheat pasta (both sometimes also contain wheat), or yam noodles.&quot;
- Ralph Golan, M.D., Optimal Wellness ( Get the book. )

 &quot;The
Food and Drug Administration (FDA) recently approved for oat bran and oatmeal the first food-specific health claim, which reads, &quot;Soluble fiber from oatmeal as part of a low saturated fat, low cholesterol diet may reduce the risk of heart disease.&quot; One-half cup of fiber-rich oat bran a day has demonstrated the ability to lower total cholesterol by an average of 25 mg/dl (milligrams per deciliter) in a variety of populations. Soluble fiber is well known for its ability to prevent the absorption of cholesterol metabolites in the digestive tract.&quot;
- Laurie Deutsch Mozian, M.S., R.D., Foods That Fight Disease: A Simple Guide to Using and Understanding Phytonutrients to Protect and Enhance Your Health ( Get the book. )

 &quot;Wheat germ is a very concentrated source of vitamin E, with a little less than 2 tablespoons providing 5 international units, about 16 percent of the DV. oat bran and whole-wheat breads and cereals also contain vitamin E, although in smaller amounts than the germ.
A Fiber Find
If you remember the oat bran frenzy of a few years ago, you already know that this grain is prized for its high fiber content. But Mr. Ed&apos;s favorite breakfast isn&apos;t the only way to get a lot of fiber in your diet.&quot;
- Prevention Magazine, Prevention&apos;s New Foods for Healing: Capture the Powerful Cures of More Than 100 Common Foods ( Get the book. )

&quot;When you&apos;re trying to eat lean, oat bran is often a better choice than oatmeal. A 1-cup serving of cooked oat bran contains 87 calories, whereas the same amount of oatmeal has 145.
Oatmieal-AprJcot Cookj&apos;es
1
&apos;/4
1/4 11/2 1/2
1 1
1/4 21/2 cup dried apricots, coarsely chopped cup boiling water cup packed light-brown sugar cup unsalted butter, at room temperature cup fat-free egg substitute teaspoons vanilla cup unbleached all-purpose flour teaspoon ground cinnamon teaspoon baking soda teaspoon salt cups quick-cooking rolled oats
Per cookie calories 78 total fat 2.1 g. saturated fat 1.1 g.&quot;

- Prevention Magazine, Prevention&apos;s New Foods for Healing: Capture the Powerful Cures of More Than 100 Common Foods ( Get the book. )

 &quot;Get some wheat or oat bran (not the cereals, the actual bran; you&apos;ll find it in the section of the health food grocery that sells dry bulk items). You can mix the brans together in different proportions and cook it to make your own hot cereal mix, or you can use it as a breading or a filling. I also recommend adding fiber supplements (like psyllium husks or flaxseeds) to your program, but don&apos;t take them at the same time as other medications or supplements, because the fiber can inhibit absorption.
What Are Sugar Alcohols? Do They Count as Sugar?&quot;
- Jonny Bowden, M.A., C.N.S., Living the Low Carb Life: Controlled Carbohydrate Eating for Long-Term Weight Loss ( Get the book. )

&quot;The fiber comes not in the form of grain products like cereals (unless you want to use them as part of your 12- to 15-gram net carb per meal allowance, which will result in awfully small portions), but in the form of actual branwheat bran, oat bran , and, if you can find it, corn bran. Ground flaxseeds are also great. You can also use psyllium husks in cooking as a thickening agent or as a binder for meatballs and meatloaf. And there are actually a couple of very high-fiber commercial cereals that could be eaten as well (All-Bran and Fiber One come to mind).&quot;

- Jonny Bowden, M.A., C.N.S., Living the Low Carb Life: Controlled Carbohydrate Eating for Long-Term Weight Loss ( Get the book. )

 &quot;High-fibre phytomedicines, also used as bulk laxatives such as ispaghula and psyllium husk, lower plasma lipid levels and can be used as adjuncts to a low-fat diet. oat bran (Avena sativa) and guar gum (Cyamopsis tetragonolobus; see also Chapter 18) lower cholesterol levels; these are thought to act by binding to cholesterol.
Garlic, Allium sativum L. H
(Allii sativi bulbi)
The plant and the drug
The garlic bulb (Allium sativum, Liliaceae) is composed of a number of small bulbs or &apos;cloves&apos;, covered with papery, creamy-white bracts.&quot;
- Dr. Michael Heinrich, Joanne Barnes, Simon Gibbons and Elizabeth M. Williamson, Fundamentals of Pharmacognosy and Phytotherapy ( Get the book. )

 &quot;This type of fiber does not dissolve in water and binds cholesterol as it passes through the digestive tract. oat bran is a great example of soluble fiber, and more than twenty studies show that it reduces total and LDL cholesterol when consumed on a daily basis. One bowl of oatmeal can lower cholesterol levels between 8 and 23 percent in just three weeks. Pectin, found in the skin of apples, is also effective, as is ground flaxseeds.
The reduction of fats in the diet, especially the harmful fats described in the sidebar, is important as well.&quot;
- James F. Balch, M.D. and Mark Stengler, N.D., Prescription for Natural Cures: A Self-Care Guide for Treating Health Problems with Natural Remedies Including Diet and Nutrition, Nutritional Supplements, Bodywork, and More ( Get the book. )

 &quot;Other fibers higher in soluble fiber are more effective at increasing butyric acid than oat bran (see below).
Fiber - The roles of fiber (such as cellulose or flax/linseed powder) include the sweeping away of toxins as well as providing the source material from which colonic bacteria make SCFAs to nourish the cells of the colon wall. Fiber also helps to lower the pH of the intestines, thus making it more acidic, which encourages the growth of friendly bacteria and suppresses the growth of unwelcome bacteria such as Clostridium difficile.&quot;
- Antoinette Saville and Antony J. Haynes, Food Intolerance Bible ( Get the book. )

 &quot;You can&apos;t watch television for long without seeing at least one commercial on oats, and supermarkets seem increasingly stocked with oat bran products. This trend has to do mainly with the known cholesterol-lowering effects of oat bran . But the story is even more interesting. Some claim oats have anti-depressant and aphrodisiac properties, and there is evidence that oats can help people kick drug habits.
A decoction of common oats (Avena sativa) has been used in Ayurvedic medicine to successfully treat opium addition.&quot;
- Sheldon Saul Hendler, The Doctor&apos;s Vitamin and Mineral Encyclopedia ( Get the book. )

 &quot;The Quaker oat bran label splits the message into three distinct parts: soluble fiber from oat bran (large type) as part of a low saturated fat, low cholesterol diet (small type) may reduce the risk of heart disease (enclosed in a red heart).
Quaker Oats advertisements promote the research basis of the cholesterol-lowering effects of oat cereals. A full-page color advertisement in the New York Times Magazine of September 2.&quot;
- Marion Nestle, Food Politics ( Get the book. )

&quot;Because the peak of interest in oat bran occurred in 1989 during the hiatus when the FDA was not regulating health claims, the companies were particularly eager to take advantage of this situation; they would not have to prove that their products actually lowered cholesterol or, for that matter, have to put much oat bran into them. According to one review of the studies, up to 35 servings of some products would be needed to achieve a 3% drop in blood cholesterol levels.&quot;

- Marion Nestle, Food Politics ( Get the book. )

&quot;The Quaker oat bran label splits the message into three distinct parts: soluble fiber from oat bran (large type) as part of a low saturated fat, low cholesterol diet (small type) may reduce the risk of heart disease (enclosed in a red heart).
Quaker Oats advertisements promote the research basis of the cholesterol-lowering effects of oat cereals. A full-page color advertisement in the New York Times Magazine of September 2.&quot;

- Marion Nestle, Food Politics ( Get the book. )

 &quot;His studies, along with recent 1987 research at Syracuse University in New York, both show that high-fiber, low-fat diets alone do not reduce cholesterol as much as when oat bran is added to both diets. Oats also raises HDL, thereby preventing heart attacks and hypertension.
Health food stores around the country carry oat bran in a ready-to-eat breakfast cereal marketed by Health Valley of Montebello, California (see Appendix). Or you can do as I&apos;ve done for most of my 40+ yearseat a good helping of cooked Quaker Oats every morning.&quot;
- John Heinerman, Heinerman&apos;s Encyclopedia of Fruits, Vegetables and Herbs ( Get the book. )

 &quot;Then as suddenly as it began, it seemed, our oat bran mania died, a casualty of more headlines. This time, they reported, a study had concluded that oat bran is no better at lowering blood cholesterol than white bread.
End of story? No. Oats do appear to cause a modest reduction in blood cholesterol, and experts say that oats can be a valuable part of a low-fat diet. But when it comes to lowering blood cholesterol, no one food is a magic bullet. Eating a diet low in fatespecially saturated fatis still one of the best ways to lower your blood cholesterol, say experts.&quot;
- The Editors of Prevention Health Books, and William P. Castelli M.D., Cholesterol Cures: More Than 325 Natural Ways to Lower Cholesterol and Live Longer from Almonds and Chocolate to Garlic and Wine ( Get the book. )

 &quot;Linda Van Horn studied the effects of oatmeal and oat bran as part of a low-fat diet versus a low-fat diet alone. She found that both oat bran and oatmeal provided an additional 3 percent reduction over the cholesterol lowering achieved by a low-fat diet alone. That low percentage of cholesterol reduction was due to the fact that the subjects in the study had normal cholesterol levels to begin with. People with elevated cholesterol counts can expect a greater percentage of improvement.&quot;
- Robert E. Kowalski, The 8-Week Cholesterol Cure: How to Lower Your Blood Cholesterol by Up to 40 Percent Without Drugs or Deprivation ( Get the book. )

 &quot;Oat bran adds healthy fiber to any cold or hot cereal.
 Try oat groats as the foundation of your next turkey, chicken, or quail stuffing.
SAFETY
Oats are not commonly an allergenic food. However, they are classified as a member of the &quot;gluten grains.&quot; This grouping of grains has traditionally included wheat, oats, barley, and rye, and it has traditionally been avoided by individuals with wheat-sensitive conditions.&quot;
- Michael Murray, N.D. and Joseph Pizzorno, N.D., The Encyclopedia of Healing Foods ( Get the book. )

 &quot;Oats and oat products have captured increasing amounts of interest because of their beneficial effect on lowering cholesterol. oat bran has the greatest amount of lipid-lowering fiber of the oat products and can be used as a cereal, sprinkled on other cereals, and added to baked goods such as cookies, muffins, and breads. Oat flakes have a little less fiber than oat bran . Rolled oats can be used similarly and in granola mixes.
quinoa This Peruvian Indian staple is like a grain, except, unlike a grain, it is said to contain all of the essential amino acids.&quot;
- Dean Ornish, Dr. Dean Ornish&apos;s Program for Reversing Heart Disease ( Get the book. )

 &quot;Ten subjects were fed 100 grams a day of oat bran (one bowl of hot cereal and five oat bran muffins) in one study, and a 19 percent decrease in cholesterol and a 23 percent decrease in LDL-cholesterol were observed after three weeks. The same authors reported that feeding subjects four ounces of dried beans daily (as cooked pinto and navy beans or as a bean soup) for the same time produced a 23 percent lowering of cholesterol and a 24 percent lowering of LDL.&quot;
- Sheldon Saul Hendler, The Doctor&apos;s Vitamin and Mineral Encyclopedia ( Get the book. )

 &quot;Fiber
There is strong evidence that oat bran and other foods high in soluble fiber can lower blood cholesterol. An analysis of 20 studies concluded that approximately thtee grams of soluble fiber per day from oat products can lower the total cholesterol level five to six mg/dl and that the reduction is greater in those with initially high blood-cholesterol levels.37 oat bran should not be used to replace a low-fat diet but in addition to one.&quot;
- Linda Ojeda, Menopause Without Medicine: The Trusted Women&apos;s Resource with the Latest Information on HRT, Breast Cancer, Heart Disease and Natural Estrogens ( Get the book. )

 &quot;The components of oat bran that lower cholesterol are beta-glucans. But here again, oat bran is not the richest source. Barley contains up to three times more beta-glucans than oats, and beans are also significant sources.
The good news is that often it isn&apos;t necessary to resort to drugs. There are plenty of foods and herbs that can help bring cholesterol levels down.
Green Pharmacy for High Cholesterol
Along with getting adequate fiber from the foods you eat, there are a number of individual foods and herbs that can prove helpful.&quot;
- James A. Duke, Ph.D., The Green Pharmacy: New Discoveries in Herbal Remedies for Common Diseases and Conditions from the World&apos;s Foremost Authority on Healing Herbs ( Get the book. )

 &quot;Many of the studies featured oat preparations containing either oat bran or oatmeal.18 The overwhelming majority of these studies demonstrated that individuals with high cholesterol levels will see significant reductions with frequent oatmeal or oat bran consumption. In contrast, individuals with normal or low cholesterol levels will see little change. In individuals with high cholesterol levels (above 220 mg/dl), the consumption of the equivalent of 3 g of soluble oat fiber typically lowers total cholesterol by 8-23%.&quot;
- Michael T. Murray, ND, Textbook of Natural Medicine 2nd Edition Volume 2 
 ( Get the book. )

 &quot;Anderson often chooses hot oatmeal or oat bran with a banana and skim milk.
 At lunchtime, he frequently opts for raw vegetables, a glass of vegetable juice, fruit and a couple of oat bran muffins.
 For dinner, Dr. Anderson might select pasta, broiled fish or bean (not beeD burritos with a fruit cup for dessert. &quot;If I&apos;m dining out, I might order strawberries sprinkled with brown sugar,&quot; he says.
 On the rare occasions when Dr. Anderson finds himself in a fast-food restaurant, he orders a lower-fat selection, such as a grilled chicken fajita.
 At a Chinese restaurant, Dr.&quot;
- The Editors of Prevention Health Books, and William P. Castelli M.D., Cholesterol Cures: More Than 325 Natural Ways to Lower Cholesterol and Live Longer from Almonds and Chocolate to Garlic and Wine ( Get the book. )

 &quot;Although oatmeal&apos;s fiber content (7%) is less than that of oat bran (15-26%), it has been determined that the polyunsaturated fatty acids contribute as much to the cholesterol-lowering effects of oats as the fiber content. Although oat bran has a higher fiber content, oatmeal is higher in polyunsaturated fatty acids.
In an effort to lower cholesterol with dietary fiber, have patients try to achieve a daily intake of 35 g of fiber from the fiber-rich foods, a full listing of which can be found in Chapter 57.&quot;
- Michael T. Murray, ND, Textbook of Natural Medicine 2nd Edition Volume 2 
 ( Get the book. )

 &quot;In one study, ten people ate 41 grams of oat bran (about three muffins) each day for about six months. The result: Their cholesterol levels dropped 26 percent each.
Oat bran alone will never tame a wild cholesterol level, says Dr. Ornish, but used properly, it can help.
Iron Man Uses Vitamin E
Vitamin E may be making headlines for its cholesterol-busting ability, but that&apos;s nothing compared with John&apos;s seemingly miraculous comeback?due in part to vitamin E.
Seemingly in top condition, John dropped over dead while cutting grass in 1985.&quot;
- Gale Maleskey, Brian Kaufman, Home Remedies: What Works: Thousands of Americans Reveal Their Favorite Home-Tested Cures for Everyday Health Problems ( Get the book. )

 &quot;Researchers at the University of Minnesota in Minneapolis reviewed all the studies examining the power of oats and reached an artery-cleansing conclusion: Add VA cups of oat bran cereal (or three packets of instant oatmeal) to your daily diet, and watch your cholesterol level dip by 2 to 3 percent. If your cholesterol level is already high, you&apos;ll reap even more benefits, with oat bran skimming 6 to 7 percent off the top.
Shape up. You don&apos;t need to compete in a triathlon for the good of your cholesterol. About 20 minutes of exercise, three times a week, should be your goal. &quot;
- Doug Dollemore, Mark Giuliucci and the Editors of Men&apos;s Health Magazine, Age Erasers for Men: Hundreds of Fast and Easy Ways to Beat the Years ( Get the book. )

 &quot;New England Heart Center in Manchester, Connecticut, and author of Optimum Health. oat bran , found in oatmeal and some cereals such as Cheerios and Life,
contains soluble fiber, which is thought to soak up cholesterol and take it out of your system. In various studies, oat bran has shown to lower high cholesterol anywhere from 3 to 20 percent.
Keep the skin on. When you eat a grapefruit, don&apos;t cut it in half and scoop out the fruit. Peel it like an orange and eat it in pieces, Dr. Sinatra recommends. Eating it that way, you eat the white stringy stuff on the outside called pectin.&quot;
- Doug Dollemore, The Doctor&apos;s Book of Home Remedies for Seniors ( Get the book. )

 

page 7 of 9 | Next -&gt; 
 FAIR USE NOTICE: The research quoted here is provided under the protection of Fair Use provisions and published by the 501(c)3 non-profit Consumer Wellness Center for the purposes of public comment and education. Authors / publishers may submit books for consideration of inclusion here .
TERMS OF USE: Read full terms of use . Citations of text from NaturalPedia must include: 1) Full credit to the original author and book title. 2) Secondary credit to the Natural News Naturalpedia as a research resource and a link to www.NaturalPedia.com
This unique compilation of research is copyright (c) 2008, 2009 by the non-profit Consumer Wellness Center.
ABOUT THE CREATOR OF NATURALPEDIA: Mike Adams, the creator of NaturalPedia, is the editor of NaturalNews.com , the internet&apos;s top natural health news site, creator of the Honest Food Guide ( www.HonestFoodGuide.org ), a free downloadable consumer food guide based on natural health principles, author of Grocery Warning , The 7 Laws of Nutrition , Natural Health Solutions , and many other books available at www.TruthPublishing.com , creator of the earth-friendly EcoLEDs company ( www.EcoLEDs.com ) that manufactures energy-efficient LED lighting products, founder of Arial Software ( www.ArialSoftware.com ), a permission e-mail technology company, creator of the CounterThink Cartoon series ( www.NaturalNews.com/index-cartoons.html ) and author of over 1,500 articles, interviews, special reports and reference guides available at www.NaturalNews.com. Adams&apos; personal philosophy and health statistics are available at www.HealthRanger.org . 
 Subscribe to NaturalPedia.com News to receive announcements Enter your email address:
 Email announcements powered by Campaign Enterprise from ArialSoftware.com 

 
Refine your search
with Oat Bran…


...and Macronutrients:
 ...and Fiber (7274)


...and Nutrients:
 ...and Bran (5143)

 
Related Concepts:

 Fiber 
 Bran 
 Oat 
 Diet 
 Foods 
 Wheat 
 Blood 
 Water 
 Oatmeal 
 Beans 
 Eat 
 Soluble Fiber 
 Soluble 
 Food 
 Levels 
 Eating 
 Oil 
 Cereal 
 Vegetables 
 Colon 
 People 
 Whole 
 Blood Cholesterol 
 Flour 
 Health 
 Anderson 
 Body 
 Effect 
 Insoluble 
 Products 
 Cereals 
 Study 
 Fresh 
 Fruits 
 Sugar 
 Lower Cholesterol 
 Protein 
 Barley 
 Cholesterol Levels 
 Juice 
 Source 
 Natural 
 Helps 
 Corn 
 Total 
 Grains 
 Wheat Bran 
 Heart 
 Time 
 Dry 
 Garlic 
 Organic 
 Increase 
 Raw 
 Sources 
 Bread 
 Liver 
 Avoid 
 Risk 
 Studies 
 Disease 
 Drink 
 Grain 
 Regular 
 Fruit 
 Brown Rice 
 Effects 
 Seeds 
 Constipation 
 Soy 
 Supplement 
 Vitamin 
 Apples 
 Seed 
 Intake 
 Muffins 
 Rye 
 Dried 
 Content 
 Minutes 
 Cholesterol-lowering 
 Fibers 
 Diabetes 
 Pectin 
 Fats 
 Whole Grains 
 Plant 
 Little 
 Heart Disease 
 Acid 
 Breakfast 
 University 
 Fish 
 Carrots 
 Dietary Fiber 
 Healthy 
 Diets 
 Calories 
 Blood Sugar 
 Baked 
 
 

 

 
This site is part of the Natural News Network©2012 All Rights Reserved. Privacy | Terms All
content posted on this site is commentary or opinion and is protected under Free
Speech. Truth Publishing International, LTD. is not responsible for content written
by contributing authors. The information on this site is provided for educational
and entertainment purposes only. It is not intended as a substitute for professional
advice of any kind. Truth Publishing assumes no responsibility for the use or
misuse of this material. Your use of this website indicates your agreement to
these terms and those published here . All trademarks,
registered trademarks and servicemarks mentioned on this site are the property
of their respective owners.
	</body>
</document>
