<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001440" url="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/huff-wires/20120411/us-drug-war-newspaper-ads/" time="2012-07-12-17:12" support="2" score="0.002531019098655113" bingtitle="Drug Smugglers Placing Job Ads In Mexican Newspapers" webtitle="Drug Smugglers Placing Job Ads In Mexican Newspapers">
			<query id="000694" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="001291" bing-rank="220"/>
	<description>... and cashiers, telling applicants they must drive company cars to the ... company cars across the border, typically to a fast-food restaurant or ... At Fenway Park</description>
	<body>
		HuffPost&apos;s QuickRead... Loading... HuffPost&apos;s QuickRead... Loading... 
 FBI Caught On Tape News Crime 
 More Log in Create Account 
 Notifications 
 Profile Settings Logout 
 
 July 12, 2012
 
 
 Edition: U.S. 
 CA Canada 
  Québec 
 FR France ES Spain US United States UK United Kingdom 
 
 
 
 FRONT PAGE Politics 
 WATCH: Romney Booed Over Obamacare 41k GOP Votes To Repeal Obamacare Again 21k Chris Christie Makes Fun Of Fat Jokes 1k Ohio Freight Train Derails, Causing Fiery Blast 203 Obama Leading With Single Voters 9k 
 Like 142k   Go to Politics More in Politics 
 Pollster Election 2012 Speculatron HuffPost Hill Fundrace Off The Bus Election Dashboard 
 You might also like 
 World Green Tech 
 Business 
 WATCH: Evidence Ex-Wall Street Trader May Have Taken Cyanide 2k Paul Krugman Slams Times Colleague, CNBC 3k Here Are The 16 Banks Under Investigation Over The Libor Scandal 350 Evander Holyfield&apos;s Unable To Avoid Foreclosure On $14 Million Mansion 674 Missing Banker: I &apos;Hurt The People I Was Trying To Help&apos; 414 
 Like 34k   Go to Business More in Business 
 Small Business Money 
 You might also like 
 World Tech Media Culture Sports Weird News Crime 
 Entertainment 
 Daniel Tosh Apologizes For Rape Joke 5k Singer Apologizes For National Anthem Fail 1k PHOTO: See Sofia&apos;s Engagement Ring! 39 7 Sites You Should Be Wasting Time On Right Now 11 Big News For &apos;Hunger Games&apos; Fans 137 
 Like 72k   Go to Entertainment More in Entertainment 
 Celebrity TV 
 You might also like 
 Comedy Arts Books Culture Style Weird News Moviefone 
 TV 
 &apos;Strange Sex&apos; Features Woman With 102ZZZ Breasts 1k &apos;Melrose Place&apos; Turns 20: Where Are They Now? 36 Kristin Chenoweth Injured On Set Of &apos;The Good Wife&apos; 52 Susan Boyle&apos;s Neighbors File Noise Complaint, Call Singing &apos;Unbearable&apos; 367 Emily Maynard&apos;s Bachelors WIll Tell All About Season 8 11 
 Like 8k   Go to TV More in TV 
 TV Replay TV Recaps TV Spoilers Maureen Ryan Reality-Free Maggie Furlong 
 You might also like 
 Celebrity Media Comedy Entertainment 
 Weird News 
 PHOTOS: In Honor Of National No Bra Day, Here Are Celebs Sans Bras 592 &apos;Strange Sex&apos; Features Woman With 102ZZZ Breasts 1k World&apos;s Heaviest Woman Credits Sex For 98-Pound Weight Loss 2k Porn Star Ron Jeremy Reportedly Recruited To Snare Accused Cannibal Luka Magnotta 322 Can You Believe It&apos;s A Tattoo? 
 Like 26k   Go to Weird News More in Weird News 
 Dumb Crime UFO Hollyweird World Records Animals Anatomical Wonders Weird Photos and Videos 
 You might also like 
 Comedy World Good News 
 Sports 
 Woman Catches Shark! 291 LOOK: Athlete Fashion On ESPY Red Carpet LOOK: Paulina Gretzky Is At It Again 82 PHOTOS: Sneak Peek At ESPN&apos;s &apos;Body Issue&apos; 177 WATCH: Patriots Owner Stars In Bizarre Video With Girlfriend 679 
 Like 22k   Go to Sports More in Sports 
 Wimbledon London 2012 Baseball Sports Crime The Schultz Report 
 You might also like 
 TV Food Entertainment Comedy Detroit 
 Tech 
 10 Free Programs Every Windows User Should Install Immediately 888 The Mildly Fabulous Story Of The First Photo Posted To The Internet 204 Is The U.S. Government Planning To Secret Super-Scanners? 504 11 Things You Should Never Do On OkCupid 242 WATCH: Conservative Group Calls For Boycott Of Google 1k 
 Like 54k   Go to Tech More in Tech 
 Best of TED Social Media 
 You might also like 
 Small Business Green Science New York San Francisco TechCrunch Engadget Joystiq 
 Science 
 PHOTOS: Dinosaur Sex Similar Across Species, Scientists Say 218 Was Famous Physicist Snubbed Over Higgs Find? 635 Ancient &apos;New York City&apos; Of Canada Discovered 751 WATCH: Virgin Galactic Makes Huge Announcement 98 Strange Sounds Of Auroras Explained In New Study 75 
 Like 17k   Go to Science More in Science 
 Space Brain Earth Talk Nerdy To Me Weird Science 
 You might also like 
 Tech Green Arts Religion Weird News 
 World 
 1,000-Year-Old Coins Unearthed At Crusader Battleground 257 Concordia Captain Makes Shocking Revelations 937 Afghans Protest Against Woman&apos;s Execution 697 UK Billionaire Questioned After Wife Found Dead 335 French President Ridiculed For This Photo 127 
 Like 55k   Go to World More in World 
 Foreign Affairs World Elections Arab Uprising Afghanistan War Syria Crisis 
 You might also like 
 Travel Politics Business Tech Religion 
 ALL SECTIONS News 
 Politics World Business Small Business Money Media Sports Education Crime Weird News Good News 
 Entertainment 
 Entertainment Celebrity Culture Comedy Arts Books TV Moviefone 
 Life&amp;Style 
 Healthy Living GPS for the Soul Style Food Kitchen Daily Weddings Travel Parents Divorce Huff/Post 50 Stylelist Stylelist Home 
 Tech&amp;Science 
 Tech Science Green TechCrunch Engadget TUAW Joystiq 
 Voices 
 Women Black Voices Latino Voices Voces (en español) Gay Voices Religion College Teen Impact 
 Local 
 Chicago DC Denver Detroit Miami New York Los Angeles San Francisco Patch.com Mapquest 
 AOL 
 Daily Finance Aol Jobs Aol Autos Autoblog Aol Music Aol Video Games.com Heidi Klum Aol Shopping Real Estate 
 
 Crime 
 Trayvon Martin Luka Magnotta Isabel Celis Sierra Lamar Joran van der Sloot Missing People Mug Shots Death Penalty Bizarre Weapons 
 
 HuffPost Social Reading Some error occurred 
 Login with Facebook to see what your friends are reading Enable Social Reading i 
 
 Settings 
 Read Share Settings Share everything I read Share only things safe for work Dont share what I&apos;m reading 
 
 Read Share History Learn More 
 
 
Drug Smugglers Placing Job Ads In Mexican Newspapers
 
 By ELLIOT SPAGAT 04/11/12 09:30 PM ET 
 reddit stumble Get Crime Alerts: Sign Up React: Amazing
 Inspiring
 Funny
 Scary
 Hot
 Crazy
 Important
 Weird
 Follow:   gangsters ,   Video , Immigration And Customs Enforcement , Drug Smuggler Job Ads , Drug Smugglers , Crime News The U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement is taking out ads in Mexican newspapers warning job-seekers about falling prey to deceitful offers of drug trafficking groups. 
SAN DIEGO—The war on drugs is going to the classified sections of Mexican newspapers.

Smugglers have long advertised work as security guards, housecleaners and cashiers, telling applicants they must drive company cars to the United States. They aren&apos;t told the cars are loaded with drugs.

Starting this week, U.S. Immigration and Customs and Enforcement began buying ad space in Tijuana newspapers to warn jobseekers they might be unwitting pawns.

&quot;Why don&apos;t we do the same thing that (cartels are) doing? It&apos;s successful for them. Why wouldn&apos;t it be successful for us?&quot; Lester Hayes, a group supervisor for ICE in San Diego, recalls his agents telling him.

There have been 39 arrests since February 2011 at San Diego&apos;s two border crossings tied to the ads for seemingly legitimate jobs, according to ICE, which hadn&apos;t seen such significant numbers before.

Those arrests have yielded 3,400 pounds of marijuana, 75 pounds of cocaine and 100 pounds of methamphetamine–a tiny fraction of total seizures but enough to convince U.S. authorities that smugglers are increasingly turning to the recruitment technique.

Drug smugglers always look to exploit weak links along the 1,954-mile border, even if the window of opportunity is brief. In the past several years, they have turned to makeshift boats on the Pacific Ocean and ultralight aircraft in the deserts of California and Arizona. In the San Diego area, there has been a spike in teenagers strapping drugs to their bodies to walk across the border from Tijuana.

Some suddenly popular techniques are limited to particular pockets of the border. ICE has not spotted significant spikes in newspaper ads outside of San Diego.

Ads that authorities connect to drug smugglers appear innocuous. They offer work in the United States–an invitation that only people who can cross the border legally need apply–with a phone number and sometimes a location to apply in person.
 
New hires are told to drive company cars across the border, typically to a fast-food restaurant or shopping center in San Diego, according to ICE. When they arrive, they are often told there will be no work after all that day and must leave the car and walk back to Mexico after being paid a small amount.

The drivers are typically paid $50 to $200 a trip–much less than the $1,500 to $5,000 that seasoned smugglers are typically paid for such trips, Hayes said.

For drug traffickers, the tactic lowers expenses and, they hope, makes drivers appear less nervous when questioned by border inspectors, said Millie Jones, an assistant special agent in charge of investigations for ICE in San Diego.

The drugs are stashed in the usual ways. Fifteen pounds of methamphetamine were found in a pickup truck&apos;s phony exhaust pipe in November. More than 250 pounds of marijuana were discovered in a van&apos;s overhead compartment last April.

More than 200 pounds of marijuana were found in vacuum-sealed plastic bags smothered in grease. Drugs are typically mixed with mustard, ketchup and fabric fresheners to defuse odors and ward off dogs used by authorities.

For years, U.S. authorities have bought newspaper space and broadcast airtime south of the border to deter illegal border crossings. The Border Patrol has a long-running media campaign in Mexico and Central America that includes musical &quot;corridos,&quot; short documentaries and public service announcements.

The ICE ads that began appearing Sunday in classified sections of Tijuana&apos;s Frontera and El Mexicano are nothing fancy. Bold black letters say, &quot;Warning! Drug traffickers are announcing jobs for drivers to go to the United States. Don&apos;t fall victim to this trap.&quot;

Mexican newspapers have faced online competitors but the papers&apos; classified sections are relatively robust compared to U.S. publications.

Victor Clark, director of Tijuana&apos;s Binational Center for Human Rights, doubts the ads will work without specific instructions on how to confirm whether a company is legitimate, such as calling an ICE telephone number.

&quot;It&apos;s very difficult for someone who is unemployed to know whether it&apos;s a trap,&quot; Clark said. &quot;I don&apos;t think many people are inclined to investigate if they are desperate for work.&quot;

The cases can be challenging for prosecutors because drivers may not know they are smuggling drugs.

Debra Hartman, a spokeswoman for the U.S. attorney&apos;s office in San Diego, declined to say how many cases have been prosecuted or cite any examples. Rachel Cano, assistant chief of the San Diego County district attorney&apos;s southern branch, said each case is different.

&quot;Just like any other case, a theft case, we look at all of the facts and if there are sufficient facts that meet the elements of a crime and we can prove it beyond a reasonable doubt, then we file charges,&quot; Cano said.

Guadalupe Valencia, a San Diego defense attorney, said the ads by U.S. authorities might inadvertently help defendants. Attorneys will argue it is an acknowledgement that people are often tricked.

&quot;It has always been my opinion that there are many unknowing couriers,&quot; he said. &quot;The challenge for the prosecution is you always have to prove knowledge.&quot;
 Contribute to this Story: 
 Send us a tip Send us a photo or video Suggest a correction 
 FOLLOW CRIME Like 34k   Get Alerts 
From our partners
 
 Celebrity Trial Quiz: Test Your Knowledge Of These Star-Studded Court Cases - The Huffington Post Jackie Samuels Charges $60 For Cuddling In New York (VIDEO) - www.thefrisky.com Extreme Scalp Tattoos You Won&apos;t Believe Weren&apos;t Photoshopped - www.oddee.com 
 
 
 Video gangsters 
 SAN DIEGO&amp;mdash; The war on drugs is going to the classified sections of Mexican newspapers.

Smugglers have long advertised work as security guards, housecleaners and cashiers, telling applicants th... SAN DIEGO&amp;mdash; The war on drugs is going to the classified sections of Mexican newspapers.

Smugglers have long advertised work as security guards, housecleaners and cashiers, telling applicants th... Around the Web: 

 Drug Traffickers Dupe Job Seekers Into Smuggling | Fronteras Desk 

 US turns to Mexican newspaper ads to counter drug smugglers who target ... 

 Drug Traffickers Dupe Job Seekers Into Smuggling 

 Filed by David Moye  |  
 More in Crime... 

 Sierra Newbold Case: Police Arrest Terry Lee... Nicole Houde, Former Miss New Hampshire USA,... Lynn Jackenheimer Missing: Ohio Mom&apos;s Boyfriend Allegedly... Aaron Schaffhausen Jailed After Girls Thought To...     
 Comments 12 Pending Comments 0 View FAQ 
 Comments are closed for this entry Community Notice:  We&apos;ve made some changes to our badge program, including the addition
of our newest badge: Community Curator. View All Favorites Recency  |  Popularity Ari Sedona 56 Fans 01:02 PM on 04/16/2012 Shouldn&apos;t this be under Latino News? Or might it damage that image the dems so skillfully try to control? Ari_Sedona: Shouldn&apos;t this be under Latino News? Or might it damage http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Ari_Sedona/drug-smuggler-placing-job-ads_n_1418348_148375377.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Sunlogic What Liberal Media!? 292 Fans 09:46 PM on 04/13/2012 $10 Billion,or $45 billion a year. How&apos;s that drug war working out for you all? Not much at all that I can see. Sunlogic: $10 Billion,or $45 billion a year. How&apos;s that drug war http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Sunlogic/drug-smuggler-placing-job-ads_n_1418348_147922077.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER hcwcars Never going back to the old days 211 Fans 11:55 AM on 04/13/2012 You can buy drugs in any prison if you stop that you cant stop it at all ! hcwcars: You can buy drugs in any prison if you stop http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/hcwcars/drug-smuggler-placing-job-ads_n_1418348_147793011.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 skippy42 54 Fans 07:16 AM on 04/13/2012 Smugglers! Smugglers and MORE Smugglers!
When does it end?
 http://www.chron.com/news/article/Boy-15-accused-of-driving-death-van-3478900.php skippy42: Smugglers! Smugglers and MORE Smugglers! When does it end? http://www.chron.com/news/article/Boy-15-accused-of-driving-death-van-3478900.php http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/skippy42/drug-smuggler-placing-job-ads_n_1418348_147744521.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 oldwolf49 Religion is a tool of the evil. 1630 Fans 03:36 AM on 04/13/2012 Where do I sign up?!?! oldwolf49: Where do I sign up?!?! http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/oldwolf49/drug-smuggler-placing-job-ads_n_1418348_147734172.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This user has chosen to opt out of the Badges program ApocalypseAdam 35 Fans 01:33 PM on 04/12/2012 God love free enterprise. ApocalypseAdam: God love free enterprise. http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/ApocalypseAdam/drug-smuggler-placing-job-ads_n_1418348_147571852.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER dbrett480 339 Fans 01:07 PM on 04/12/2012 The defense attorney has a good point. If it cannot be proven that the smugglers knew about the drugs in the vehicle (which isn&apos;t even theirs), getting a conviction will be almost impossible. dbrett480: The defense attorney has a good point. If it cannot http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/dbrett480/drug-smuggler-placing-job-ads_n_1418348_147564279.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER kevin hunt2012 24 Fans 09:45 PM on 04/11/2012 I blame prohibition.. kevin_hunt2012: I blame prohibition.. http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/kevin_hunt2012/drug-smuggler-placing-job-ads_n_1418348_147420360.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Damon G 57 Fans 05:51 PM on 04/11/2012 Hey, at least it&apos;s a job, right? Someone&apos;s got to do it, and you can&apos;t stop all of it. The cartels are like any business, do whatever you can to make money. People and product lost are just the cost of doing business. Legalize and they will move on to other things, sure, but at least it will be harder to recruit people and turn them into the violent criminals we are so familiar with. Everyone begins life as an innocent, but your environment and experiences will transform you. Damon_G: Hey, at least it&apos;s a job, right? Someone&apos;s got to http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Damon_G/drug-smuggler-placing-job-ads_n_1418348_147362674.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This user has chosen to opt out of the Badges program Ilegal 24 Fans 03:55 PM on 04/11/2012 Drug cartels exist in Mexico solely for the purpose of supplying the demand of US consumers. As long as the gringos keep buying drugs, some crooked Mexican is gonna find a way around the law and the border to exchange his drugs for dollars. Period. Ilegal: Drug cartels exist in Mexico solely for the purpose of http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Ilegal/drug-smuggler-placing-job-ads_n_1418348_147328041.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER ramman 112 Fans 03:14 PM on 04/11/2012 Sign up if you want to, the retirement package will certainly put you to rest and please don&apos;t even think about giving a two weeks notice. This truly signing your life away. ramman: Sign up if you want to, the retirement package will http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/ramman/drug-smuggler-placing-job-ads_n_1418348_147315638.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Jon Benedict 7 Fans 02:46 PM on 04/11/2012 I cannot wait until Romney comes out against Obama&apos;s gov&apos;ment going against the &quot;Job Creaters&quot; in Mexico! The rich cannot be hampered in their search for employees to exploit! Hahahahahaha! Not much different then HERE! Jon_Benedict: I cannot wait until Romney comes out against Obama&apos;s gov&apos;ment http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Jon_Benedict/drug-smuggler-placing-job-ads_n_1418348_147307862.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 new comment(s) on this entry—Click to refresh 
 Loading comments…
 FOLLOW US 
 
 Connect with your friends Check out stories you might like,
and see what your friends are sharing! Loading twitter module... Most Popular on HuffPost av%2BoIzr1NlDiMVVHOmqGvq5HJnwj5Ye6c%2Fr6dQ0rfu20RKNI%2FpDTHvq65wDQ3dDwgEVu7AHshVfAte7v1gmxZeuwNUvrPnzu n23g1KxNmTj9RDdZtHnQ8oP7ttCXQ2n5%2B1BaV5NS08yqzi40QJP%2BJez8x5VNUy09rtBvk8T4fPSZgvn7oHgLlCrUV%2FnmyP3F 1 of 2 WATCH: Romney Booed Over Obamacare 
 Like 6k World&apos;s Heaviest Woman Credits Sex For 98-Pound Weight Loss 
 Like 6k Photos Of Kardashian Baby Are A Hard Sell 
 Like 60 Katie Holmes Used Disposable Phones To Orchestrate Divorce 
 Like 424 Daniel Tosh Apologizes For Rape Joke 
 Like 1k &apos;Strange Sex&apos; Features Woman With 102ZZZ Breasts 
 Like 3k PHOTOS: Dinosaur Sex Similar Across Species, Scientists Say 
 Like 1k Kim Kardashian Tweets Yet Another Bikini Pic 
 Like 20 Katie Holmes Returns To Catholic Church 
 Like 2k Don&apos;t Miss HuffPost Bloggers 1 of 5 Dr. Peggy Drexler How to encourage healthy friendships among boys Conrad Black Serious About Getting Sh**-Faced Robin Bronk Nikki Haley’s Short-Sighted Gutting of the Arts Marlo Thomas The&quot;Veepstakes&quot;-- Highlights and Lowlights of a Great American Tradition Sen. Barbara Boxer What Repealing Health Care Reform Would Mean to America’s Families John Cusack The Alchemists: A Conversation with Phil Stutz, Part III Andy Stern Palin Is Right: House Death Panel Vote&quot;Is Downright Evil&quot;-- People Would Die! Rev. Jesse Jackson Put U.S. Jobs Above D.C. Partisanship Drew Westen Let’s Cap the Tax Cut at $253,571.33 Marlo Thomas The Givers: Alan Alda Plays With Fire! An Exclusive Interview   
 
 Advertise | Make HuffPost your Home Page | RSS | Careers | FAQ 

 User Agreement | Privacy | Comment Policy | About Us | About Our Ads | Contact Us 

 Copyright©2012 TheHuffingtonPost.com, Inc. | &quot;The Huffington Post&quot;is a registered trademark of TheHuffingtonPost.com, Inc. All rights reserved. 

 Part of HPMG News 

 HuffPost Lightbox
	</body>
</document>
