<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001929" url="http://chowhound.chow.com/topics/321952" time="2012-07-12-17:50" support="1" score="0.00036317178991180634" bingtitle="What foods can be brought into the US after traveling abroad ..." webtitle="What foods can be brought into the US after traveling abroad? [moved from Spain/Portugal board] - Not About Food - Chowhound">
			<query id="000421" bing-rank="128"/>
	<description>What foods can be brought into the US after traveling ... what was about to happen so me and my neighboring seats ... Did you ever work at a fast food restaurant? [moved from ...</description>
	<body>
		Log in / Sign Up Entire Site 
 Entire Site Chowhound Recipes Stories Video 
 CHOW 
 Follow @CHOW videos 
 All Videos Supertaster CHOW Tips You&apos;re Doing It All Wrong My Go-To Obsessives The Easiest Way 
 recipes 
 All Recipes Quick&amp;Easy Fun DIY Projects Main Dishes Sweets Recipe Slideshows 
 Blogs 
 CHOW Daily Best of Chowhound 
 chowhound discussions 
 All Boards Home Cooking Manhattan San Francisco Bay Area Los Angeles Area Philadelphia Greater Boston Area Southern New England Ontario (including Toronto) B.C. (including Vancouver) 
 
 HOME &gt; Chowhound &gt; Not About Food Save This Board &gt; 
 Email Print 
 
What foods can be brought into the US after traveling abroad? [moved from Spain/Portugal board]
 
Do you know where I can find a copy of an updated&quot;no fly list&quot;?

I know that meat is prohibited but what about packaged cheeses or can goods? I&apos;ve heard that canned olives, for example, are fine and I&apos;ve brought back liters of oil in plain sight several years ago and had no problems. But I always wonder if there are items that are officially prohibited, like oil, olives and canned goods, but are general allowed in small quantities and if there are items like meat that is never allowed.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By mielimato on Aug 30, 2006 03:55 PM 
Updated on Sep 3, 2006

 13 Replies 
 
 
Here is a link to US Customs for prohibited and restricted items. I have found that it is good to carry a copy of the list because sometimes customs will try to confiscate items that are legal. Which they have the right to do even if the item is legal, but it helps.

 http://www.cbp.gov/xp/cgov/travel/vacation/kbyg/prohibited_restricted.xml 

Here is a link to USDA-APHIS Travelers Tips for what you can import. At the bottom of the page are lists of approved items.

 http://permanent.access.gpo.gov/lps30... 
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By JMF on Aug 30, 2006 04:49 PM 
 re: JMF 
Thanks! This is exactly what I was looking for.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By mielimato on Aug 30, 2006 04:54 PM 
 re: mielimato 
Just be prepared that the customs people are not really up to date on everything. They may allow some banned stuff and confiscate some allowable. Frustrating as check in anymore.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Candy on Aug 31, 2006 12:43 AM 

 
 
 
Try the State Dept.&apos;s website. If you can&apos;t find the answer in any of their listed categories, you can e-mail them with your question.

 http://www.state.gov 
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By RGR on Aug 30, 2006 04:52 PM 

 
I have not traveled since the latest security crack down but in the past, I&apos;ve brought back butter, cheese, crackers, cookies, mayonnaise, chocolate, pastries, booze, jelly, paprika, pasta and probably other things too numerous too mention. The only thing that was ever confiscated was a braunschweiger sausage from a German grocery store. Yes, I know it is illegal but gosh darn it, I wanted that sausage for dinner and I was hoping they might be asleep at customs that day. They weren&apos;t...
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Velma on Aug 31, 2006 02:13 AM 
 re: Velma 
I just spoke with a friend who returned last week from Paris and she was stopped from bringing packaged store bought cookies on the airplane.

The security person seriously claimed the cookie filling was a banned&quot;liquid&quot;.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By was_bk on Aug 31, 2006 08:10 PM 

 
 
Ok, so when I fly down to Mexico, I had some some American beef jerky with me as a snack. I had purchased 2 packs of a national brand jerky at the local Giant grocery store in VA.

When I flew out of Mexico, I still had an unopened pack, but customs would not let me bring it into the country, even though I actually bought it in the states.

Did they screw up or was I legally not allowed to bring my jerky back in?
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By rcheng on Aug 31, 2006 03:58 AM 
 re: rcheng 
How would they know where you bought it?
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By PeterL on Aug 31, 2006 10:21 PM 
 re: PeterL 
They wouldn&apos;t know where I had bought it, however the packaging did say that it was packaged in Texas.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By rcheng on Sep 3, 2006 04:48 AM 

 
 
 
Meat is the thing they always catch me with and confiscate. Lately, they&apos;ve
even added a special meat warning to the declaration form you fill out on
the plane, something about how failing to declare your meat will land you
in even more trouble than you will be in if you do declare it. Or something.

I&apos;ve been caught by the dastardly little beagles they occasionally walk past
disembarking passengers. If you&apos;ve got meat and you see a beagle, you&apos;re
screwed.

Last month I completely forgot about the meat thing and a friend in Paris
had just returned from Spain and loaded me up with some awesome chorizo
and ham. An hour before landing, I remembered what was about to happen
so me and my neighboring seats had a little ham fest. Delicious, but not
really the best setting.

On the other hand, I&apos;ve heard stories of friend-of-a-friends who&apos;ve sashayed
through customs with 30 pounds of spanish ham in their backpacks.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Chuckles the Clone on Aug 31, 2006 06:51 AM 
 re: Chuckles the Clone 
I regularly come back from South Africa with biltong in my checked luggage - not a lot, usually 2-3 lbs. So far I haven&apos;t been caught but I get very nervous every time I go through customs.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By cheryl_h on Aug 31, 2006 07:59 PM 

 re: Chuckles the Clone 
I truly did forget that I had canned Haggis in my checked luggage. It had been purchased early in the trip and stashed. I just never gave it another thought and besides it was canned. It wan&apos;t caught and confiscated but the friend I bought it for went the next year and bought hers in the duty free shop, also canned but she declared it and they took it away.
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Candy on Aug 31, 2006 08:40 PM 

 
 
I heard a story about a Portuguese couple who got caught coming into the US with a huge stash of linguiça for their Californian relatives. When they were told that carrying in meat was forbidden, the husband reportedly said,&quot;This isn&apos;t meat! It&apos;s sausage!&quot;

Best policy, I think, is not to say anything to the customs folks unless it&apos;s absolutely necessary. Cautionary tale: I bought an apple in the Kyoto airport coming home from Japan. I didn&apos;t get around to eating it on the plane, so as I entered the SFO customs area (oh, naive me!), I asked an employee where there was a garbage can to toss it, since you can&apos;t legally bring fruit or vegetables into the US. Oh, boy. That set off huge alarms. The customs guy made me&amp;my traveling companion go to a special area to have all of our bags x-rayed and some searched, too. This even though I said quite clearly that the apple was the *only* banned thing we had, and I was looking for a place to throw it away *before* going through customs!!
 
 Permalink | Reply 
 By Kitchen Imp on Sep 1, 2006 04:16 PM 

 
 «Back to the Not About Food Board Back to the Top | Reply to original post 
Discussions You Might Also Like...
 How do you get rid of fruit flies in your kitchen?? (140 replies) 1 Food Scars - Things you will never eat again. (377 replies) 2 Cleaning up after dinner. (103 replies) 3 Can&apos;t find what you&apos;re looking for? Start your own discussion now . 
 Most Recent Discussions 
 
Thursday, July 12, 2012 replies 
 
 92 

 Supertasters Unite! 

about 2 hours ago
 
 211 

 Crazy supermarket check-out... 

about 3 hours ago
 
 17 

 Weird pregnancy cravings? 

about 3 hours ago
 
Wednesday, July 11, 2012
 
 149 

 Glass jars - fess up! 

about 11 hours ago
 
 654 

 Say what?? Cooking comments... 

about 12 hours ago
 
 104 

 So WHY were we forced to sit... 

about 13 hours ago
 
 Videos 
 How to Make an Easy Margarita 
 Recipe Slideshows 

 Meaty, Meaty Beef Recipes! See All 38 Recipes» 
 
 »Videos » How to Make an Easy Margarita » Supertaster Daily: Taco Bell&apos;s Cantina Bell Menu » Supertaster Daily: The Seattle-Style Hot Dog » How to Tell How Much Propane Is Left for Your Gas Grill » NY CHOW Report: Bud Light–Battered Fish Po&apos; Boy at Motorboat&amp;the Big Banana » Supertaster Daily: Whole Grain Beefaroni 
 
 »Recipes » Road Trip Munchies » French-y Picnic Recipes for Bastille Day » Cold Dishes for Hot Weather » Pine Cone Punch » Homemade Chocolate Graham Cracker S&apos;mores » Blue Cheese and Chive Compound Butter 
 
 »Blogs » Should Lamb Have a Strong Taste? » The Diss, Updated: Calling Asian Food&quot;Hipster&quot; » Anyone in the Bay Area Still Making Mandarin Pressed Duck? » Amazing Espresso in Orange County » Boston Lobster Rolls: Chowhound Lists » Yopparai, an Izakaya Speakeasy on the Lower East Side 
 
 »Discussion » Chateau Steakhouse Queens » Where to buy bulk rendered duck or pork fat? » Lamb - should it be gamey or not? » Time for a New Knife? » What is your biggest recipe pet peeve? » Liang’s Kitchen – A Delicious Taiwanese Import from Los Angeles 
 
 About/Contact CHOW | Feedback 
 FOLLOW CHOW 
 facebook twitter google plus pinterest youTube rss 
 CBS Cares | CBS Films | CBS Radio | CBS.com | CBSInteractive | CBSNews.com | CBSSports.com | CHOW | Clicker | CNET | College Network | Find Articles | GameSpot | Help.com | Last.fm | MaxPreps | Metacritic.com | Moneywatch | mySimon | Radio.com | Search.com | Shopper.com | Showtime | SmartPlanet | TechRepublic | The Insider | TV.com | UrbanBaby.com | ZDNet 
CBS Entertainment | About CBS Interactive | Jobs | Advertise 

©2012 CBS Interactive Inc. All rights reserved. | Privacy Policy | Ad Choice | Terms of Use 
 X 
Log In
 USERNAME / EMAIL PASSWORD Remember me Join CHOW | Forgot your password? X 
Sign Up
 USERNAME EMAIL PASSWORD CONFIRM PASSWORD 
Choose Newsletters

 CHOW Announcements CHOW Partner Offers Recipe of the Day CHOW Latest Stories Weekly Recipes 
 THE DIGEST - The best of Chowhound 
 San Francisco Bay Area New York City Los Angeles Area Home Cooking Boston 
 Username is public and once confirmed, is unchangeable. By clicking the SIGN UP button, you agree to CHOW&apos;s terms of use and have read and understand our privacy policy . Share with your friends X 
 TO: FROM: MESSAGE: 
 Share &quot;What foods can be brought into the US after traveling abroad? [moved from Spain/Portugal board]&quot;
	</body>
</document>
