<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001699" url="http://www.sellbuyclassifieds.com/answers/component/content/article/246-chemistry/209615-what-is-the-total-number-of-valence-electrons-in-a-sulfide-ion-in-the-ground-state.html" time="2012-07-12-17:28" support="1" score="0.0007062183111326499" bingtitle="What is the total number of valence electrons in a sulfide ion in ..." webtitle="What is the total number of valence electrons in a sulfide ion in the ground state?">
			<query id="001013" bing-rank="187"/>
	<description>What is the total number of valence ... like what is a sulfide ion? I can&apos;t find it on the periodic table. ... Which is the best fast food restaurant? Will I get sick if ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Contact Or Send Question SellBuyClassifieds.Com 
 Home 
 
What is the total number of valence electrons in a sulfide ion in the ground state?
 
 

 Sunday, 07 November 2010 01:02 
 QUESTION like what is a sulfide ion? I can&apos;t find it on the periodic table. ANSWER Sulfide ion = S -2 [ Sulphur ion which has gained 2 electrons]
S has 6 valence electrons, so sulfide will have 6+2 = 8   Science&amp;Mathematics - Chemistry 
 Latest Answers 
 
 What kind of foods can I bring to Cancun? Where is the best place to eat in Cancun???!?!??!? How to watch IRL races live streaming on the network with good quality ? What is a good way to watch MLB baseball games on the internet live with good quality ? What is a good way to watch NBA palyoffs live streaming on the internet with good quality ? Best Biryani In Chennai? Good and bad things of Mumbai? I would like to sale dinnin table&amp;double bed through ebay? How to celebrate my birthday? What is the significance of french crepes? (Answer only if you know what crepes are)? What to do in a McDonalds interview? Do fastfood locations usually hire people with experience? Poll- Whats your favourite fast food? What are some fast food chains??????? I am doing a discussion infront of my class about fast food, i need help!? When do you know that your step dad is gay? Do you prefer Dunkin Donuts or Starbucks Coffee? Or do you like both or neither? I applied for McDonald&apos;s on Hiring Day, can someone help? Should all fast-food places, like McDonald&apos;s, Taco Bell, Carl&apos;s Jr., etc., be banned except for Subway? How good are Sonic&apos;s Chicago-style hot dogs compared to specialty hot dog restaurants.? Sonic sign meaning 1&lt;=2:13=&gt;0? Which is the best fast food restaurant? Will I get sick if I eat 1 week old chicken tenders from burger king? Who likes Wendys............? Subway vs. Quiznos... Name the better? Is the service at your local McDonald&apos;s bad? How is mc donalds salads fattening? Restaurants in Toronto? Dinner on a boat/cruise? Suggest some cheap restaurants in Victoria? 
 
Copyright©2012 Question And Answer. All Rights Reserved. - Email contact: contact@sellbuyclassifieds.com
	</body>
</document>
