<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001499" url="http://www.happycow.net/europe/greece/athens/" time="2012-07-12-17:16" support="1" score="0.007110594395724957" bingtitle="Health Food, Vegetarian &amp; Vegan Restaurants in Athens (14)" webtitle="Vegan/Vegetarian Restaurants Athens, Healthy, Organic, Greece -HappyCow">
			<query id="001129" bing-rank="199"/>
	<description>Vegan-friendly, Buffet, Fast food, Take-out, Delivery Fast food restaurant. ... yogurt and a frozen section that sometimes carries vegan ice cream cups.</description>
	<body>
		Guide to Athens Vegan Restaurants, Vegetarian Restaurants, Natural Foods,&amp;Health Food Stores. 
 
 ...reviews by vegans&amp;vegetarians you can trust   
 
 
 
 
   
 Home Community» 
 Join My Profile Forum Groups Veggie Blog Members Chat Calendar Newsletter 
 Restaurants&amp;Stores» 
 Search Add Restaurant Add Store&amp;More Update Listing Write Review Priority Upgrade Mobile Version 
 Veg Topics» 
 Veganism Vegetarianism Famous Veg Travel B&amp;Bs/Retreats Health Veg Protein Raw Food Animal Rights Ingredients Environment Humor Wisdom VegIQ Test Links 
 Recipes Blog Shop» 
 T-Shirts HC Stuff Veg Food Veg Goods Books Advertise 
 About» 
 FAQ Flyers Press Link to Us Our Story Advertise Contribute Contact 
 Newsletter Feed the Cow 
 Register / Login   
 
 
Health Food, Vegetarian&amp;Vegan Restaurants in Athens (16) 
 
 
 
 Home | Europe | Greece | Athens 
 100% Vegetarian&amp;Vegan Restaurants Only 
 Show Vegetarian-Friendly Also 

   

   
 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 Please let these businesses know you found them on HappyCow - thanks! Sort By: Alphabetical Highest Rated Price Veg Type Vegan/Vegetarian Restaurants: (6 Listings) 
 ImproV Cafe and Resto     10 Reviews 
 8 Iakhou Street (11854) (at Evmolpidon) 
   +302130240875 
    Vegan, Beer/Wine, Take-out, Greek, American 
 
 All vegan rock cafe/beer, garden/nightclub serving appetizers, salads, sandwiches, entrees, smoothies, desserts and daily specials. At corner ofΙάκχου&amp;Ευμολπιδών. Has outdoor seating. Cash only. Open Tue-Sat 6pm-3am, closed Sun-Mon. 
   Website   Map   Add Photo   Save   Add to Favs   Update   Data Info   Are you the owner? 
 Avocado     23 Reviews 
 Nikis 30 (105 57) (at /Syntagma) 
   30-2103237878 
    Vegan-friendly, Western, International, Juice bar, Beer/Wine, Take-out 
 
 Vegetarian and vegan restaurant opened in March 2011. Serves all natural meals and products with no preservatives or artificial ingredients. Menu includes entrees, sandwiches, smoothies, juices, in-house-made bread and cake. Has outdoor seating. Open Mon-Sat 11am-10pm, Sun 11am-7pm. 
   Website   Map   Add Photo   Save   Add to Favs   Update   Data Info   Are you the owner? 
 Panepistimiou     12 Reviews 
 57 Panepistimiou, El Venezelou 
   013210966 
    Vegan-friendly, Buffet, Fast food, Take-out, Delivery 
 
 Fast food restaurant. Health food market next door. 
   Map   Add Photo   Save   Add to Favs   Update   Data Info   Are you the owner? 
 Lebanese Supermarket and Food Stall     Be first to review! 
 24 Menandrou Street 
   2105202659 
    Vegan-friendly, Mediterranean, Non-veg 
 
 Serves meat, veg options available. A supermarket with a small food stall which offers some vegan options such as falafel and a sandwich with fried eggplant and cauliflower (each costs only 1 euro). Market sells grains, dried fruits and other vegan items. Located close to Omonoia Square. Address:οδόςΜενάνδρουαρ. 24 
   Map   Add Photo   Save   Add to Favs   Update   Data Info   Are you the owner? 
 Meson el Mirador     1 Review 
 Assilaou 88, Kerameikos 
   210-3420007 
    Lacto, Mexican, Beer/Wine, Non-veg 
 
 Serves meat, veg options available. Has approximately 8 items on the vegetarian menu which includes tacos, burritos, and chili with beans and TVP (textured vegetable protein). Many things can be made vegan with the omission of cheese. View of the parthenon from the rooftop seating. Address in Greek:Αγησιλαου88. Nearest cross street is Salaminos. Accepts credit cards. 
   Website   Map   Add Photo   Save   Add to Favs   Update   Data Info   Are you the owner? 
 Mystic Pizza     8 Reviews 
 Emmanouil Mpenaki 76, Exarxia (at Valtetsiou) 
   210-3839500 
    Ovo, Lacto, Italian, Non-veg 
 
 Serves meat, veg options available. Pizza, pasta, salads, sweets. Uses organic cannabis sativa in recipes. Street name may go by Emmanouil Benaki. 
   Website   Map   Add Photo   Save   Add to Favs   Update   Data Info   Are you the owner? 
 Health Food Stores, Vegan Shops, Vegan Bakeries, Vegetarian B&amp;Bs, Veg Catering, Veg*n Organizations: (10 Listings) 
 
 All About Nature   Be first to review! 
 Miltiadou 10-12 (15122) (at Ermou in Marousi region) 
   210-6141083 
 Organic and health foods, vitamins, cosmetics. Located behind Marousi post office. 
   Website   Map   Add Photo   Save   Add to Favs   Update   Data Info   Are you the owner? 
 Artemisia   1 Review 
 3 Parthenonos, Acropolis (11742) 
   2109248840 
 Conveniently located just 300m from the Acropolis, the shop stocks an abundance of vegan products, organic products, food supplements, essential oils, books, CDs, gifts, tofu, drinks, grains and pulses, natural cosmetics, dairy-free and gluten-free products, snacks and more. 
   Map   Add Photo   Save   Add to Favs   Update   Data Info   Are you the owner? 
 Bio Center   1 Review 
 Panepistimiou 58, Attiki (at Aiolou near Omonia Sq) 
   210-3800320321 
 BIOΦΟΣis a small store across from the restaurant and health food store named &quot;Panepistimiou&quot;. Stocks snacks, cosmetics, dry goods, fruits, nuts, cereal. 
   Website   Map   Add Photo   Save   Add to Favs   Update   Data Info   Are you the owner? 
 Four Seasons Bio Shop   3 Reviews 
 30 Nikis (10557) (at near Plaka area and Syntagma Square, between Xenofontos and Navarchou Nikodimou) 
   210-3229078 
 Organic shop stocks local products, quinoa, soymilk, tofu, vegan cheese, wines, herbs, food supplements, herbal cosmetics, and more. 
   Map   Add Photo   Save   Add to Favs   Update   Data Info   Are you the owner? 
 Green Farm - Halandri   Be first to review! 
 Alexandrou Palli 8, Attiki 
   2106141914 
 Part of a chain of health food stores in Athens/Attiki. This particular store has a small section of fresh produce, juice, snacks, crackers, bread, juices, supplements, body care products, soy yogurt, tofu and soya products. Also stocks flour, sugar, oils, cocoa, and baking ingredients. 
   Map   Add Photo   Save   Add to Favs   Update   Data Info   Are you the owner? 
 Green Farm - Kolonaki   Be first to review! 
 Dimokritou 13, Attiki (at Solonos) 
   2103614001 
 Part of a small chain of health food stores. Fresh produce section, dry goods including cereals, whole grains, pastas, baking needs. They also have oils and vinegars. There is a fridge section with tofu and soy yogurt and a frozen section that sometimes carries vegan ice cream cups. They have a small selection of organic wine, cosmetics and beauty products, pet foods, organic shirts and undies. 
   Map   Add Photo   Save   Add to Favs   Update   Data Info   Are you the owner? 
 Iliotropio - Heliotrope   1 Review 
 Laskaratou 1, Ano Patissia (14111) (at Patission) 
   210-2110806 
 A small, varied shop a short walk from the Ano Patissia stop. Sells fresh organic/biologique produce, bulk grains and pulses, soaps and cosmetic products, vitamins, and organic sweets. 
   Map   Add Photo   Save   Add to Favs   Update   Data Info   Are you the owner? 
 Karolina   Be first to review! 
 19 Lampsa&amp;Hantzikonstandi, Abelokipi 
   210-6984526 
 Organic food and products supermarket. 
   Website   Map   Add Photo   Save   Add to Favs   Update   Data Info   Are you the owner? 
 Thisavros Ygeias   Be first to review! 
 Papaflessa 26, Galatsi (at Tralleon) 
   2102220519 
 Biological (organic) food store. Bread, fruit, vegetables, snacks, cosmetics, nuts and seeds. Delivery available. Website is in Greek language. 
   Website   Map   Add Photo   Save   Add to Favs   Update   Data Info   Are you the owner? 
 Troo Food Liberation   Be first to review! 
 Athens 
   +30-210-3317527 
 A food collective based in Athens that provides catering, cooking classes, and online store. Each week they are somewhere in the city cooking vegan food- visit their blog to find the location. See website for details. 
   Website   Map   Add Photo   Save   Add to Favs   Update   Data Info   Are you the owner? 
 
 

 
 
 Still hungry? Try searching HappyCow for areas surrounding Athens .

 Read or add notes, events, travel information for Athens. 


 Please help us improve this Athens vegetarian restaurant guide: 
 - Add health food stores , cafes, or a vegetarian restaurant Athens.
- Report technical difficulty. 

 Phone ahead before you visit any listing in this restaurant directory.
 Please let these businesses know you found them on HappyCow - thank you. 
 
 Spread the word! - Please link to this page from your webpage, blog, facebook, or newsletter. 

 
   
 
 Sign up for our
FREE newsletter: email: name:   
 


 Follow this city
 
 Share: 
        


 Your Ad Here
- info - 


 
 
 

 

 

 Voted&quot;Best Vegetarian Restaurant Guide&quot;on the Internet, 
this is the place to find good vegan restaurants&amp;healthy food! 
HappyCow was created to assist in making healthy vegetarian food available to all wherever possible. These Athens vegetarian and vegan restaurant listings are primarily from you, the users, and some maybe arbitrary, outdated, or incomplete. If you are a local to Athens and know of any places (vegetarian restaurants Athens) that are not included here please add them . 
HappyCow©and its creators claim no responsibility for any information that might be inaccurate in any way. 

 Please support this site: Advertise | Contribute Funds | More ways 

 Symbols&amp;Terms | Full Terms of Use | Privacy Policy | Contact Us 
 
   All Contents Copyright©1999-2012 HappyCow&apos;s Vegetarian Restaurant Guide
	</body>
</document>
