<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001908" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Corbin/Dairy-Queen_498" time="2012-07-12-17:49" support="1" score="0.0005669794057034433" bingtitle="Dairy Queen - Fast Food Restaurant Corbin, KY" webtitle="Dairy Queen - Fast Food Restaurant  Corbin, KY">
			<query id="001031" bing-rank="117"/>
	<description>Dairy Queen is a Fast Food restaurant located at 1020 E Cumberland ... on my drink once, and I had to ask for my bill and ... realizing that I left my phone at the table. So I ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Dairy Queen
 
Average User Rating
 
2
 
Bad

 1 Reviews 
 
Sponsored Link


 
(606) 528-7019

 http://www.dairyqueen.com/ 
 KY &gt; Corbin &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Dairy Queen listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Dairy Queen to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Review Social 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Dairy Queen
 Dairy Queen is a Fast Food restaurant located at 1020 E Cumberland Gap Pky in Corbin, KY . Dairy Queen has been described as an Bad Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 2 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food, American, American Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Dairy Queen
 
 
 
All Reviews for Dairy Queen

 
 Anonymous 
 


March 27, 2009
 
Food
 
2
 
Decor
 
2
 
Service
 
2
 
I went to the Eggroll house tonight and the food was wonderful, but the service was horrible. I was never given a refill on my drink once, and I had to ask for my bill and box for leftovers. Not once did the waitress come out and ask how the food was. I left the restaurant realizing that I left my phone at the table. So I called my phone, and no one answered. So I went back to the restaurant, and all of the workers each said that they did not have it, but when I call my phone again, it was all o
 
Overall Rating
 
2
 
&quot;Bad&quot;
 
 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Dairy Queen:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   1

 
Comments
 
 
Dairy Queen Tips
 Service is slow
 
Andrew A. 
Dairy Queen News
 A Side of Amish Country You&apos;ve Never Seen Queen St., vintage dresses from $20). I scored a handmade, 1950s floral silk dress for $90. I&apos;m sure it would have run $200 or more in a similar shop in New York or Philly ... brown noodles at Stoltzfus Farm Restaurant alone merit a visit to Intercourse ... Starbucks coming to Anderson The development sits between an empty space scheduled to become a Radio Shack and an existing Golden Corral restaurant. The building at 3556 Clemson Blvd. opened as a Dairy Queen in ... has been listed on the New York Stock Exchange since ... China&apos;s Future Deconstructed: Holmes vs. Chang He has made appearances on Fox News and regularly contributes to Business ... allowing commerce to expand across the nation, with restaurants including Dairy Queen and McDonald&apos;s experiencing tremendous growth over the next several decades. Top 7 Quick Serve Trends for 2012 Dairy Queen’s Mini Blizzards, Cinnabon Minis ... Specialty’s Café and Bakery, which has locations in California, Illinois, and New York, offers a number of online ordering options, including in-store pickup, delivery, and even CookieGrams where ... A Look Back at the News of 2011 A group of Jasperites travel to New York and Washington D.C. Community Band Concert is ... A woman steals two vehicles. One from Dairy Queen and one from the Sheriff’s Office after being released from the jail. Drug charges seemed to abound the pages ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing Dairy Queen - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia Dairy Queen, often abbreviated DQ, is a chain of soft serve and fast food restaurants owned by International Dairy Queen, Inc, which also owns Orange Julius and ... Welcome | New York Social Diary PARTY PICTURES The Jewish Museum&apos;s 17th Annual Family Hanukkah Party; Town&amp;Country hosts party for Harry Benson and Hilary Geary&apos;s &quot;New York, New York&quot;; Cheryl ... So Good It&apos;s RiDQulous - Dairy Queen So Good It&apos;s RiDQulous. DQ.com provides a restaurant locator, menus with nutritional information, franchise details, company history and news. Dairy Queen is an ... Blizzard Fan Club - Dairy Queen Dairy Queen’s Blizzard Fan Club is dedicated to everyone who loves DQ Blizzard Treats. Join now to get free Dairy Queen coupons and be the first to hear the latest ... Londoner&apos;s Diary | Evening Standard News, columnists, polls, campaigns, reader rewards and your views from the Evening Standard - London&apos;s quality paper. 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 54° 
Fri
 
 54° - 84° 
Sat
 
 54° - 82° 
Sun
 
 52° - 77° 
 
Address
 
Dairy Queen

1020 E Cumberland Gap Pky

Corbin, KY 
 

 
Telephone
 (606) 528-7019 
Dairy Queen
 
 Rating :  2 out of 10 based on 1 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Dairy Queen Photos
 
 Fast Food American American 
 
 Local Places
 
 Snappy Tomato Pizza Company 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Huddle House 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Pizza&amp;Company 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Dairy Queen 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Sonic Drive-In 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Lees Famous Recipe 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Krystal 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Shoneys of Corbin 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Imperial Gallery 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Access Cash International Incorporated West 
Cuisine: ATMs Access Cash International Incorporated West 
Cuisine: ATMs Access Cash International Incorporated West 
Cuisine: ATMs Aptus Financial 3 
Cuisine: ATMs 
 

See all Corbin Art Museums Galleries 
See all Corbin ATMs 
See all Corbin Bars and Pubs 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Dairy Queen Coupons 

 Dairy Queen Corbin 

 Dairy Queen Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Corbin Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | H | J K | L | M | O | P | R | S | T V | W 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
