<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001382" url="http://www.overseaspinoycooking.net/2009_02_01_archive.html" time="2012-07-12-17:09" support="1" score="0.0005738334606950719" bingtitle="February 2009 ~ Overseas Pinoy Cooking" webtitle="February 2009 ~ Overseas Pinoy Cooking">
			<query id="000336" bing-rank="191"/>
	<description>... popular bakeshop that has ventured into a fast food restaurant. ... Return cut pork leg in the saucepan pour fresh water ... 2 cups coconut milk powder, diluted in 2 cups of ...</description>
	<body>
		skip to main | skip to sidebar 
 Home Recipe Category 
 Beef Chicken Pork Goat | Other Vegetable | Rice Fish | Seafoods Noodles | Pasta Dessert | Salad 
 Other Categories 
 Street Foods Food Find Food Trip Fiesta Recipes Celebration 
 2008 Celebration 2009 Celebration 2010 Celebration 
 Fruit Juice Asian Inspired 
 Chinese Singapore Thailand Indonesia Malay Japanese 
 Book Read Video Round Up 
 Index Glossary 
 Glossary [ A - E ] Glossary [ F - J ] Glossary [ K - O ] Glossary [ P - T ] Glossary [ U - Z ] 
 Foodie Link About Contact Us 
 Use the RECIPE CATEGORY to browse more than 700 recipes with PHOTOS. 
Welcome!
 Pinoy food recipes resource site for OFWs and Overseas Pinoys. 


 Recently Cooked 

 
Search by Category
 
 Beef Chicken Pork Goat and Other Meats Vegetable and Rice Fish and Seafoods Noodles and Pasta Dessert and Salads 
 
Search OPC
 
 Search Overseas Pinoy Cooking
 
 
 Newer Posts Older Posts Home 
 Dinuguan, Goldilocks Pinoydeli 
 
 
 Dinuguan is one of the best sellers of Goldilocks a popular bakeshop that has ventured into a fast food restaurant. I am a fan of Goldilocks ever since, my personal favorite are their laing , pansit malabon , lumpiang ubod and their dinuguan with puto . Of course, those mentioned dishes are not comparable to homemade versions but they are superior on its class as fast food, particularly their dinuguan.

 

Whenever I feel hungry, I would prefer to eat at Goldilocks than those food outlets at mall’s food courts, the usual order of course are those that I have mentioned. For the drinks, I like their sago at gulaman or take a fresh fruit juice drink at a nearby fruit juice kiosk.

 

I am sure a lot of our kababayan overseas have surely missed foods that are offered by Goldilocks, the bakeshop have been around before most burger, fried chicken and spaghetti fast food restaurants become popular. Or have been craving for a dinuguan in particular.

 

Goldilocks have now, in fact have been in the market for a couple of years, a ready to eat version of their popular dinuguan ( bopis , laing and lechon paksiw are also available) in 150g soft pack branded as Pinoydeli . It is very convenient to take back abroad for most overseas Pinoy who are returning from leave or vacation. I myself make it a point to bring back several packets, utilizing my free airline baggage to the maximum. It is always good to have an instant dinuguan whenever you feel the craving. To serve just heat the contents in a small non-stick pan or simply put the whole packet in hot water for a few minutes. I would not recommend heating the dinuguan in a microwave oven, I did once and it all splattered all over the oven. Goldilocks Pinoydeli might also be available on some overseas Asian store.

 
 
 Posted on 2/27/2009 Leave a Comment 8
comments 
 Share this recipe : Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 

 Labels: Dinuguan , Food Find , Kakanin , Pork , Puto 


 
 Chopsuey 
 
 
 Chopsuey is a vegetable stirfry usually made up the cabbage, cauliflower, beans, and bell pepper. Other similar vegetables are also used like sayote, celery, carrots and mushroom. There is no exact measure or combination as long as it is the Baguio type of vegetables , for flavoring, strips of meat and/or seafood is added. Chopsuey is so popular that it is the typical accompaniment vegetables of most meat and seafood dish at fiestas or any other celebrations. It is also as popular in most Pinoy and even Chinese restaurants . Here is a the basic chopsuey recipe

 Ingredients: 

 

1 cup pork, boiled, sliced thinly
1 cup medium size shrimp, shelled
1 cup chicken thigh, boiled cut into pieces
1 can cooked quail egg
12 pcs. young corn, cut diagonally
20 pcs sitsaro , stringed
1 small size cauliflower, cut to pieces
1 medium size carrot, sliced thinly
1 small size cabbage, cut into wedges
1 small red bell pepper, cut into wedges
1 small green bell pepper, cut into wedges
1 stalk celery, separate leaves, stem sliced thinly
1/2 head garlic, chopped
1 medium size onion, chopped
2 tbsp. cornstarch
1 tsp. sugar
salt and pepper
cooking oil

 Cooking procedure: 

 

In a wok sauté garlic and onion, add pork, chicken and shrimp, quickly stir cook for 2-3 minutes or until shrimps are cooked. Add in salt to taste, pepper, sugar, 2 cups of broth or water and bring to a boil and simmer for 2-3 minutes. Add young corn, carrots, celery stalks and stir cook for 2-3 minutes. Add in sitsaro , cabbage, bell pepper, celery leaves and quail eggs, stir cook for 2-3 minutes or until vegetables are cooked but firm. Add in sugar and season with salt and pepper, thicken sauce with cornstarch diluted in 1/4 cup of water cook for another minute or until sauce thickens. Serve immediately.



See other chopseuy recipe:
 Pinoy Buko Chopsuey 
 Oriental Chopsuey 



 
 
 Posted on 2/24/2009 Leave a Comment 9
comments 
 Share this recipe : Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 

 Labels: Chopsuey , Noche Buena , Pinoy , Vegetable 


 
 Braised Pork Leg with Hoisin Sauce 
 
 
 Braised Pork Leg with Hoisin Sauce . Pata or pork leg to most Pinoy is usually cooked as crispy pata , paksiw na pata or nilaga . Should you are looking for an alternative way to cook pork leg other than those mentioned traditional Pinoy method here is my version of braised pork leg with hoisin sauce. The dish has a touch of Chinese due to the addition of star anise and off course the hoisin sauce. I have been using hoisin sauce on some of my recipe, it gives a hint of Chinese to the dish that supposed to taste like one. It is sometimes troublesome to cook authentic Chinese dishes, because it requires ingredients that are not common on the average Pinoy kitchen , however using these ready to use Lee Kum Kee Sauces always do the job. Here is how i cooked it.

 Ingredients: 

 

1 pc. pata , pork leg
1/4 cup soy sauce
2 tbsp. Hoisin sauce
2 tbsp. oyster sauce
1 head garlic, crushed
2-3 pcs. dried chili
1 pc. star anise
1 tbsp. cornstarch
1 tsp. sugar
salt

 Cooking procedure: 

 

Ask the butcher to saw cut the pork leg into large serving pieces. Wash thoroughly and remove all traces of blood. In a saucepan put cut pork leg, pour water to cover, bring to a boil and simmer for a minute. Now drain first boiled water and rinse off all scum. Return cut pork leg in the saucepan pour fresh water to cover, add in garlic, soy sauce, star anise and dried chili. Bring to a boil and simmer at low to medium heat for 1 hour, add more water as necessary. Add sugar, hoisin sauce and oyster sauce simmer for another 25 to 30 minutes or until the meat is tender and the pork skin is soft like gelatin and the liquid is reduced to about half. Thicken sauce with cornstarch diluted in 1/4 cup water. Season with salt to taste if required. Serve hot with a lot of rice. 
 
 Posted on 2/21/2009 Leave a Comment 10
comments 
 Share this recipe : Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 

 Labels: Braised , Chinese , Noche Buena , Pork , Recipe 


 
 Guinataang Lechon Kawali at Baguio Beans 
 
 
 Guinataang Lechon Kawali . This dish is from a leftover lechon kawali that we had the other day. Most Pinoys love any kind of guinataan, dish cook with coconut milk is part of the Pinoy cuisine for the reason of the country’s abundance of the tree of life especially the Bicol Region. On this dish I used coconut milk powder since they are always readily available here compared to freshly extracted coconut milk. Using powdered coconut milk usually results in thicker sauce. Here is the recipe.

 Ingredients: 

1/2 kilo lechon kawali , cut into cubed
1/4 kilo green beans, sliced diagonally
1 small size bell pepper, cut into wedges
1/2 head garlic, chopped
1 medium size onion, chopped
2 cups coconut milk powder, diluted in 2 cups of water
2-3 red chillies, chopped
salt and pepper
cooking oil

 Cooking procedure: 

 

In a sauce pan, sauté garlic and onion. Add 1 cup of coconut milk, let boil, add in lechon kawali and simmer for 5 to 10 minutes. Add in remaining 1 cup of coconut milk and simmer for another about 3 to 5 minutes. Add red chillies and green beans and cook 3 to 5 minutes or until vegetables are just cooked. Add bell pepper and cook for another minute. Season with salt and pepper to taste. Serve hot.

 
 
 Posted on 2/20/2009 Leave a Comment 0
comments 
 Share this recipe : Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 

 Labels: Guinataan , Guinataan Pork , Guinataan Vegetable , Lechon Kawali , Pinoy , Pork , Pulutan , Recipe , Vegetable 


 
 Chicken Macaroni Salad 
 
 
 Chicken Macaroni Salad . Chicken is the usual meat ingredients of this Pinoy style pasta salad. I have already posted a version using ham and bacon. My ham and bacon macaroni salad was suppose to be the special version for the reason that it uses ham and bacon tidbits instead of the usual shredded boiled chicken breast. Chicken macaroni salad is as popular as any other Pinoy pasta salad. It will most likely be serve on Pinoy parties as a dessert. It is simple to prepare and economical as well, this is probably the reason of its popularity. There is always personal version of each individual, there are no exact measures of ingredients from the basic of the average Pinoy to the more elaborate concoction using imported ingredients version of the wealthy. Nevertheless, here is my simple version that anyone can make.

 Ingredients: 

1/2 kilo salad or elbow macaroni, pre-cooked
1 cup mayonnaise
1 cup sandwich spread
1 pc. chicken breast, boiled, shredded
1 cup finely diced onion
1 small size carrot, diced into small pieces
1 cup pineapple chunks, diced into small pieces
1/2 cup raisins

 Method: 

 

Combine and mix thoroughly all the ingredients in a big bowl. Chill in a refrigerator until ready to serve.
 
 
 Posted on 2/16/2009 Leave a Comment 3
comments 
 Share this recipe : Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 

 Labels: Macaroni , Merienda , Noche Buena , Pasta , Pinoy , Recipe , Salad 


 
 Final Destination Northern Ilocos Un-spoilt Beaches 
 
 
 The final destination of our Ilocos adventure is the north most town of Ilocos Norte where some of Ilocandia’s magnificent tourist attractions are located. Today I would be taking a break on my usual post about food and recipe instead I will share to you some of the beautiful places that we have visited.

Northern Ilocos is well known for some of the country’s pristine beaches. Some of the more popular, which are slowly being discovered by local and foreign tourist, are located in Pagudpod the last Town of Ilocos Norte where the Cordillera Mountain Range meet the China Sea.

 

After about 3 hours drive from Vigan we arrived at Laoag City the Capital of Ilocos Norte, being Sunday we passed by at the Church of Laoag for a thanksgiving pray for our safe travel. The church bell tower is famous for as the Sinking Bell Tower of Laoag. The bell tower is located right at the center of the City, a street away from the Church of Laoag.

A visit to the Laoag public market, which is just a block away, is recommended. The vegetable selections are mostly native to the province. It is the best place to buy native delicacies for pasalubong if you are looking for bargain.

Back on the road to Pagudpod. After an hour drive, the Cape Bojeador Lighthouse is now visible on top of the mountain facing the China Sea. This is the landmark that indicates that we are now near on our final destination. Just before the Bangui-Pagugpud boundary were we descend in a zigzag curve at the mountain foot we are greeted with the first sight of the Bangui Windmills. Motorists are stopping-by at an observation deck located at the side of the mountain located halfway before the final decent. On this place is where you could see the panoramic view of the Giant Bangui Windmills.

 

Most Pinoy doesn’t even know that there are windmills this size exists in the country. The Bangui Windmills are electrical generators that are powered by the wind coming from the China Sea. According to figure, forty percent of Ilocos Norte’s electricity supply comes from these wind turbines. The windmills have become a tourist attraction, each tower standing at about 23 stories high. The wind farm is considered the biggest in Southeast Asia.

 

Before proceeding to Saud Beach, we drive straight up to the Northwestern tip of Luzon towards the Cagayan–Ilocos Norte boundary. On the foot of the Cordillera Maintains where it meets the sea is a section of the winding road at the edge of the mountains, is the old Patapat Viaduct. Here you could enjoy the spectacular scenery of the sea against the mountains, sea waves touching the magnificent mountains.

On our way back to Saud we passed-by the un-spoilt paradise, the Blue Lagoon here you could still enjoy a beautiful pristine beach. The beach itself is still undeveloped and most of the shoreline is still inhabited by the local fishermen.

Arrived Saud at about noon we were planning to stay at Saud Beach Resort but it was fully booked. We were lucky that we did get a room at the neighboring Polaris Beach Resort, our noon time arrival did help a lot, it was just in time when other guest are checking out. Polaris is cheaper, however if you plan to stay few days in Pagudpod on a tight budget I would suggest, stay in one of the several house for rent. Some of these Homestay as they are called are also furnished with cooking and dining facility, which is ideal if you prefer to cook your own food. Fresh fish catch and vegetables are peddled by the locals.

 

Pagudpod beach is indeed a place worth spending an unforgettable serene hideaway holiday and vacation. The sunset is spectacular as you watch the falling sun and the skies slowly turning to red orange, you could see the horizon across the Bangui Bay with the Giant Windmills at one end and the blue mountains in the background.

On our way back to Manila we have to take the road to Paoay via the hi-way towards Laoag Airport after the Laoag bridge. Along this route are the Fort Ilocandia Hotel and Resort and the famous Sand Dunes of Suba.

 

The route will also lead motorist to the western coast of Paoay Lake, a freshwater lake, shaped like a horse, with an area of 470 hectares. And the Malacanang of the North, which is located at the northern coast.

 

Paoay Church otherwise known as St. Augustine Church, this majestic church is a must see place when you’re in the Ilocos. The church is one of the several UNESCO heritage site.

Batac is the hometown of the Marcoses. The ancestral house of the Marcoses turned to museum is just in front of the Batac Church across a small creek. The mausoleum where Marcos&apos; body lies in a refrigerated glass coffin is open for public viewing.

 

The main purpose of our Batac stop is to take a taste of the famous Batak empanada. We arrived at the town just in time for an afternoon merienda at the empanadahan. The Batac empanadas are artificially colored with bright orange tint. Compared with the Vigan empanada, which uses annatto that gives a translucent yellowish crust.

That culminates our Ilocos adventure. There are off course more food and places to discover but that is reserved for the next food trip in the future.

See the Second Stop of our Ilocos Adventure
 Royal Bibingka, Empanada and Longganisa. Second Stop Vigan City 

See the first stop of our Ilocos Adventure
 Strawberry Taho, Sundot Kulangot, Baguio City Food Trip 


 
 
 Posted on 2/14/2009 Leave a Comment 3
comments 
 Share this recipe : Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 

 Labels: Empanada , Food Find , Food Trip 


 
 Dinengdeng, Labong, Saluyot at Sigarillas 
 
 
 Here is another version of the Ilocano dinengdeng with labong , saluyot and sigarillas ingredients. Dinengdeng is a dish of boiled vegetables flavored with bagoong na isda and topped with grilled fish. Usually dinengdeng is made up of assorted vegetable that are available at backyard gardens of most Ilocano homes in the countryside. Using labong is considered as s special for dinengdeng. Labong is the young shoot of a bamboo sliced thinly crosswise and pre-boiled. For the Ilocanos labong is best cooked with saluyot, the fibrous texture of labong is compensated by the slimy texture of the leaves of saluyot. If you do not like saluyot, it can be ommitted or substituted with any leafy vegetables.

 Ingredients: 

 

1/4 k. labong , sliced, parboiled
2 bundle saluyot leaves, trimmed, coarsely cut crosswise
2 bundle sigarillas , cut into wedges
2 pcs. grilled alumahan or any other fish
4 tsp. bagoong isda
2 medium size tomato, quartered
1 small size onion, chopped
salt

 Cooking Procedure: 

In a casserole bring to a boil 1 to 2 cups of water. Dilute bagoong na isda in 1 cup of water, strain in a sheave and pour in solution and simmer for 3 to 5 minutes, remove all scams that rises. Add in labong , onion and tomato, simmer for 3 to 5 minutes. Add in saluyot and sigarillas cook for another 3 to 5 minutes or until vegetables are just cooked. Season with salt if required. Top with grilled fish and keep covered for a minute. Serve hot.



See other dinengdeng recipe:
 Dinengdeng 
 Dinengdeng, Green Leafy Version 
 Saluyot at Labong 
 Tabungaw (Upo) nga Buridibud 


See other boiled vegetables recipe:
 Bulanglang Batangas 
 Laswa 
 Utan ug Buwad 
 
 Posted on 2/12/2009 Leave a Comment 1 comments 
 Share this recipe : Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 

 Labels: Dinengdeng , Pinoy , Recipe , Vegetable 


 
 Escabecheng Talakitok 
 
 
 Escabecheng Talakitok . On this post is my version of yellow tinted escabecheng isda. Talakitok can be substituted with any fish but I would suggest white flesh fish. This is mainly for the reason that it will look more vibrant with the yellow sauce. The fish I used for this dish is about a kilo in size and weight. I want it serve as is, one whole fish with all the yellow sweet and sour sauce pour over it. I have to use an oval frying pan for the job. Don’t worry if you don’t have this kind of frying pan. You can always cut the fish in half to for easier frying. Just arrange the fish back together in a big platter before pouring the sauce over, otherwise use sliced fish instead.

 Ingredients: 

 

1 medium size talakitok , or any white flesh fish
1 cup pineapple juice
1/4 cup vinegar
2 thumb size ginger, cut into thin strips
1 medium size carrot, cut into thin strips
1 large size bell pepper, cut into thin strips
1 large size onion, sliced thinly
1 tbsp. cornstarch
1/2 head garlic, chopped
1 stalk celery, sliced thinly
1 tsp. turmeric powder
1/4 c. sugar
salt
cooking oil

 Cooking procedure: 

 

Remove gills and innards of talakitok . Using scissors cut fins and tails. Wash fish thoroughly and slit cut diagonally at two locations across the middle, drain. Season inside and out with salt. Fry fish in a large frying pan until golden brown and skin crispy, Drain on paper towels. Keep aside. I a sauce pan quickly sauté garlic, ginger and onions. Add vinegar and simmer for 2 to 3 minutes, now add in pineapple juice and sugar, stir cook for 2 to 3 minutes or until uniform consistency of sauce is achieved, thicken with cornstarch diluted in 1/2 cup of water. Add in carrot, celery and bell pepper, stir cook for another 1 to 2 minutes or until vegetables are just cooked. Season with salt to taste. In a big platter put fried fish and pour sauce over the fried fish. Serve immediately.



See related sweet and sour fish recipe.
 Escabecheng Tanguige 
 Sweet And Sour Maya Maya 
 
 Posted on 2/11/2009 Leave a Comment 0
comments 
 Share this recipe : Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 

 Labels: Escabeche , Fish , Noche Buena , Pinoy , Recipe , Sweet and Sour 


 
 Royal Bibingka, Empanada and Longganisa. Second Stop Vigan City. 
 
 
 Vigan is the second stop of our Ilocos adventure. After about 4 hours drive from Baguio City ( see the Baguio City food trip post ), we have to stay for a day in Vigan City to visit and say hello to relatives and to my sisters. Our adventure two main objectives are to explore the Ilocos and to rediscover its famous unique foods.

 

First on the menu list is Vigan empanada , we arrive in Vigan at around five-o-clock in the afternoon, just in time for a quick snack of empanada and ukoy . The empanada stalls under the bell tower are packed with tourist we have to wait for sometime to get a table. This time I have to dissect a piece to see the inside. I am hopping to replicate it when I get home in Manila or perhaps in Abu Dhabi. There is no other way to enjoy an authentic empanada , only under the bell tower of Vigan St. Paul Cathedral or at Plaza Burgos where all it has began.

 

Crisologo Street under the dusk, the nostalgia of this UNESCO heritage site is being amplified by the reddish evening skies. This is the first time I have seen the heritage village full of tourist both foreign and local. What caught my attention is the Vigan Max’s Restaurant. The Vigan’s branch specialty is not their famous Max’s fried chicken , what else longganisa , bagnet and dinuydoy (mashed squash with pork and ampalaya ).

 

The Vigan longganisa is famous for its vinegary and garlicky flavors, but personally, I like it because they are leaner compared to other longganisa of other regions. Now the fats are reduced further. An innovative street vendor use turbo oven to roast longganisa skewed in bamboo stick, it did catch the attention of a lot of health conscious tourist.

The next morning it’s time to enjoy a freshly cooked bowl of sinanglao , a stewed beef innards and skin, flavored with kamias (ginger lily fruit) and bile, it is similar to papaitan . They are only available in the morning at street corners of Vigan and they are sold fast.

Well if you do not like this exotic food, try the Vigan miki . They are also freshly cooked in the morning. The miki stalls under the bell tower at Plaza Burgos are again full of customers enjoying a bowl of annatto flavored noodle soup. They are mostly early churchgoers who have come for the early prayer or mass.

A visit at the Vigan public market is part of the journey. Longanisa lined hanging in the meat section is part of the sight along with bagnet. Nevertheless, I was not there for them, should you want longganisa and bagnet to take back home, I would recommend that you order from the reputable manangs who made them homemade style, they usually use better meats cuts of fresh pork. I was there to buy papaitan set, they are sold fresh in complete set with bile and with a block of coagulated blood.

 

A wine derived from sugar cane locally called basi is another must have in Vigan. The equally famous sukang Iloko or cane vinegar share the same process. It is the same vinegar used as a dip for empanada and ukoy .

 

 Tinubong is another unique kakanin of the Ilocanos, They usually come from Magsingal a town up north of Vigan. Tinubong is made up of ground glutinous rice cooked in coconut milk and sugar with strips of young coconut meats sealed in bamboo tubes. In the old days tinubong was supposed to be cooked using the bamboo tubes under charcoals. Today they are commercially cooked in wok and poured inside the bamboo tubes as ready to eat. To eat them the bamboo tubes has to be place under a flame to warm and make the tinubong inside soft before splitting to scoop out the delicacy.

 

The famous Vigan Royal bibingka is the best-recommended food to try if you are in Vigan. Marsha’s Royal bibingka has now become the leader of the several bibingka makers. They have now established their commercial dominance of the delicacy. They have big bakery at the town of Bantay along the main hi-way to Manila from Ilocos Norte where passenger busses and motorist can conveniently stopover. Vigan City is not along this hi-way its about three to five minutes drive to the City center. Marsha’s Delicacy product packaging is way superior from the other bibingka bakers. Their boxes are visually appealing at present they come in lavender colored boxes. They have modern counter complete with illuminated menu signage, a dine-in area and clean rest rooms. Other goodies are also available beside the bibingka .

 

Of course, to mention the other choices are The Sister’s and Tongson’s especially if you have stayed loyal to these two bibingka bakers.

 

There are other food items that I have to mention, they are usually bought as pasalubong . Crispy fried corn kernels ( chichacorn ) they come also in adobo and chili aside from the regular garlic flavor. Balikutsa (pulled sugarcane candy). And the Vigan dried miki should you want to have it cook yourself upon your return home.

Second Stop, Vigan City is part of our Ilocos Adventure during the 2008 Christmas holiday season.


See the first stop of our Ilocos Adventure
 Strawberry Taho, Sundot Kulangot, Baguio City Food Trip 

See the Final Leg of our Ilocos Advanture:
 Final destination Northern Ilocos un-spoilt beaches 


 
 
 Posted on 2/10/2009 Leave a Comment 2
comments 
 Share this recipe : Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 

 Labels: Bibingka , Empanada , Food Find , Food Trip , Longganisa , Tinubong , Vigan 


 
 Puto Special 
 
 
 This Puto post is overdue I should have posted it before my puto pao recipe . But at that time I was trying to post as many celebration recipes as I could and I thought puto pao is one special native food that should be prepared on such special celebration. Of course the ordinary puto is as especial, it is one of the foods that are usually found on the dining table, whenever there is an occasion to celebrate in our household. Today I am posting my puto recipes, special and flavored puto. I love puto especially when they are offered in assorted flavors. Frankly, there is no secret on flavored puto recipe, the most convenient is to use essences, which are also tinted to the color relative to the flavor. Off course if you prefare to extract flavors from natural sources that would require more work and revision of the recipe. But for now we want it simple and convenient after all this is how OPC should be, simple recipes. Please note that the texture of puto defends on how the batter is blended. For coarser texture, the batter should be mix moderately and for finer texture it should be whisk longer. Here are the recipes.

 



 Puto Special 

 

 Ingredients : (To make about 25 puto special.)

2 cup all purpose flour
1 tbsp. baking powder
1/2 cup white sugar
1/2 cup margarine
1 cup water
1/2 cup evaporated milk
2 piece egg, beaten
cheddar cheese, cut into strips for topping
salted egg, cut into strips for topping

 Cooking procedure :

 

In a big bowl, sift all purpose flour, baking powder and sugar. Slowly whisk and blend in water, milk, egg and margarine until fully blended. Fill the cupcake moulds with batter to nearly full. Top with strips of cheese and/or salted egg. Repeat the process for the rest of the cupcake moulds. Arrange filled moulds in a steamer, place cheesecloth in between each tray to avoid water drips. Put enough water and 1 tbsp of vinegar on the steamer and steam for 20-25 minutes. Remove from tray and mould.

 



 Puto Pandan 

 

 Ingredients : (To make about 25 puto pandan .)

4 cup all purpose flour
2 tbsp. baking powder
2 cup white sugar
1 tsp. pandan essence flavor/tint
2 1/2 cups water
1 cup evaporated milk
1 piece egg, beaten
cheddar cheese, cut into strips for topping
salted egg, cut into strips for topping

 Cooking procedure :

 

In a big bowl, sift all purpose flour, baking powder and sugar. Slowly whisk and blend in water, milk, egg and pandan essence until fully blended. Fill the cupcake moulds with batter to nearly full. Top with strips of cheese and/or salted egg. Repeat the process for the rest of the cupcake moulds. Arrange filled moulds in a steamer, place cheesecloth in between each tray to avoid water drips. Put enough water and 1 tbsp of vinegar on the steamer and steam for 20-25 minutes. Remove from tray and mould.



 Puto Ube 

 


 Ingredients : (To make about 25 puto ube .)

4 cup all purpose flour
2 tbsp. baking powder
2 cup white sugar
1 tsp. ube essence flavor/tint
2 1/2 cups water
1 cup evaporated milk
1 piece egg, beaten
cheddar cheese, cut into strips for topping
salted egg, cut into strips for topping

 Cooking procedure :

 

In a big bowl, sift all purpose flour, baking powder and sugar. Slowly whisk and blend in water, milk, egg and ube essence until fully blended. Fill the cupcake moulds with batter to nearly full. Top with strips of cheese and/or salted egg. Repeat the process for the rest of the cupcake moulds. Arrange filled moulds in a steamer, place cheesecloth in between each tray to avoid water drips. Put enough water and 1 tbsp of vinegar on the steamer and steam for 20-25 minutes. Remove from tray and mould.



See other puto recipes.
 Puto Pao 


See related rice cake recipe;
 Royal Bibingka 
 Vigan Royal Bibingka 
 
 Posted on 2/06/2009 Leave a Comment 89
comments 
 Share this recipe : Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 

 Labels: Dessert , Kakanin , Merienda , Noche Buena , Pinoy , Puto , Recipe , Steamed 


 
 Paksiw na Bisugo 
 
 
 Paksiw na Isda is usually topped with ampalaya and eggplant. The vegetables are supposed to be steam during the cooking of the fish. The juices from the vegetables are infused to the paksiw, which enhance the flavor of the fish, specially the bitterness of the ampalaya. I like to drizzle with some cooking oil to the dish to neutralize the sourness. I know many Pinoys are not so keen about paksiw na isda. However, there are more who really love their paksiw, just the though of the dish makes them droll including myself. The dish is usually served with patis and with kalamansi and a couple of cut siling labuyo and of course served with a lot of rice.

 Ingredients: 

1 kilo bisugo 
1 medium size ampalaya , de-seeded, cut into wedges
2 medium size eggplant, cut into wedges
1/2 head garlic, crushed
1 thumb size ginger cut into thin slices
1 medium size onion, quartered
1/4 c. vinegar or 3 tbsp. sampalok sinigang mix
1 tbsp. whole black pepper
3 whole green sili
 cooking oil
salt

 Cooking procedure: 

 

Remove gills and innards of bisugo. Using scissors cut fins and tails and wash fish thoroughly drain. In a casserole put garlic, onion and ginger at the bottom. Arrange fish side by side, add 1 cup of water and vinegar or sampalok sinigang mix. Put on top vegetable, green sili and black pepper. Season with salt and drizzle with cooking oil. Cover and simmer at heat for 8–12 minutes or until fish is cooked.



See other Paksiw na Isda Recipe.
 Paksiw na Asuhos 
 Paksiw sa Gata, Guinataang Tulingan 
 Paksiw na Bangus 

 
 
 Posted on 2/04/2009 Leave a Comment 1 comments 
 Share this recipe : Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 

 Labels: Fish , Paksiw na Isda , Pinoy , Recipe 


 
 Adobong Manok sa Gata, Chicken Adobo in Coconut Milk 
 
 
 Adobong Manok sa Gata, Chicken Adobo in Coconut Milk . For most Pinoy who have the basic experience in the kitchen would not need any recipe for cooking the adobo. Every individual have his or her own way of preparing the dish. Moreover, most of the time it also depends on what are the available ingredients in the kitchen at that moment. There are no exact measurements of ingredients as well. Quantities are most of the time adjusted as the dish is being cook along the way or perhaps if it was not done correctly the first time, it could be adjusted or rectified the next time. Adobo is so common is most Pinoy’s home that the dish has evolved to different versions and addition of other ingredients. These may be versions with lots of soy sauce or chunks of pineapple or perhaps cooked with lemongrass or for my recipe today adobo with coconut milk. Its straightforward nothing special, it is your basic adobo with the addition on coconut milk and extra chilies. Here is how I cooked it.

 Ingredients: 

 

1 kilo chicken, cut into serving pieces, bones intact
1 1/2 cup coconut milk powder
1/2 head garlic, crushed
1 cup vinegar
1 tsp. peppercorns, lightly crushed
2-3 pcs. chilli
3 bay leaf
salt

 Cooking procedure: 

 

Put chicken in a sauce pan, pour in 2-2 cup of water. Add in vinegar, garlic, peppercorns and bay leaf, season with salt to taste bring to a boil and simmer at medium heat for 10-15 minutes add more water if required. Add in chilli and coconut milk powder diluted in 1 cup water, stirring occasionally, continue to simmer for 5-10 minutes or until the liquid has reduce to half and has thicken. Serve with a lot of rice.



See other related adobo recipe.
 Pork and Chicken Adobo, Adobong Puti 
 Adobong Baka 
 Chicken Adobo, Adobong Ilocano 
 Adobong Atay at Balunbalunan ng Manok 
 Humba, Adobong Visaya 
 Adobong Kambing 
 Paksiw na Pata ng Baboy 
 Pork and Chicken Adobo 

 
 
 Posted on 2/01/2009 Leave a Comment 3
comments 
 Share this recipe : Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook 
 

 Labels: Adobo , Chicken , Guinataan , Guinataan Chicken , Pinoy , Recipe 


 Newer Posts Older Posts Home Subscribe to: Posts (Atom) 
Our New Travel Blog
 
Featured Pinoy Recipe
 
 Puto Pao Biko na Pirurutong Cheesy Pinoy Lasagna Pinoy Spaghetti Pancit Malabon Crispy Sisig 
 
Search by Labels
 Show up to max. 10 post per page , Click OlderPost or NewerPost links if required.
 
 Adobo [37] Afritada [4] Alimango [2] Alimasag [9] Arroz Caldo [2] Asado [8] Atchara [1] Australia [1] Avocado [1] Bacon [2] Bagnet [2] Baked [9] Bam-e [1] Banana-Q [1] Bangus [8] Barbecue [6] Batam [1] Batchoy [1] Batso [2] Beef [72] Bibingka [4] Bicol Express [1] Bihon [3] Biko [1] Binagoongan [3] Binakol [1] Bistek [9] Book Read [2] Bopis [3] Bottled [1] Braised [28] Breakfast [21] Bringhe [4] Buko Pie [1] Bulalo [7] Bulanglang [1] Burger [1] Calamares [1] Callos [1] Canton [1] Carbonara [3] Cebu [5] Chicken [76] Chicken Wings [2] Chilli Crab [1] Chinese [39] Chopsuey [6] Coke [1] Corned Beef [4] Crispy Pata [2] Curry [7] Daing [3] Dessert [12] Dinakdakan [1] Dinaldalem [1] Dinengdeng [9] Dinuguan [6] Dried Fish [4] Drinks [1] Egg [10] Embutido [5] Empanada [4] Ensalada [10] Escabeche [4] Estofado [1] Fettucine [2] Fish [105] Food Find [11] Food Photography [1] Food Trip [27] Fresh Fruit Juice [1] Fried [54] Fried Rice [8] Fries [1] Fruit [7] Fruit Salad [5] Giniling [2] Ginisa [43] Glossary [6] Goat [6] Goto [1] Grilled [3] Guinataan [45] Guinataan Chicken [4] Guinataan Fish [10] Guinataan Merienda [1] Guinataan Pork [4] Guinataan Seafood [22] Guinataan Vegetable [17] Halaan [7] Halabos [3] Halang Halang [1] Halo Halo [1] Ham [6] Hardinera [1] Hipon [17] home remedy cure [1] Humba [1] Igado [3] Imbaliktad [1] Inasal [1] Indonesian [7] Inihaw [21] Isarabsab [1] Isaw [1] Italian [1] Jam [1] Japanese [1] Kakanin [6] Kalamansi [1] Kaldereta [12] Kamote-Q [2] Kare Kare [5] Kinamatisan [1] Kinilaw [14] Kinunot [2] Kuhol [1] Laing [4] Lamb [2] Lamb Chop [1] Lasagna [1] Lasang Pinoy [5] Laswa [2] Lato [1] Lauya [1] Leche Flan [2] Lechon [10] Lechon Kawali [2] Lemon Chicken [1] Lenten Season [5] Lobster [1] Lomi [3] Longganisa [4] Lugaw [6] Lumpia [7] Macaroni [4] Malagkit [6] Malay [4] Mami [2] Meatball [1] Meatloaf [3] Mechado [2] Menudo [4] Merienda [76] Miki [4] Miso [2] Misua [5] Mix Seafood [15] Molo [1] Morcon [1] Ngohiong [1] Nilaga [10] Nilasing [1] Noodle [44] Omelet [5] Pad Thai [1] Paella [7] Paklay [2] Paksiw na Baboy [3] Paksiw na Isda [9] Palabok [2] Pandan [1] Pansit [30] Pansit Hab-hab [1] Pansit Malabon [2] Papaitan [4] Pares [1] Pasta [22] Peanuts [1] Penne [1] Pesa [1] Photo Gallery [29] Pichi Pichi [1] Pigar Pigar [1] Pinakbet [2] Pinangat [2] Pininyahan [3] Pinoy [587] Pirurutong [2] Pla-Pla [1] Poached [2] Pochero [3] Poqui Poqui [1] Pork [127] Pork Chop [7] Pork Loin [1] Pork Ribs [1] Pugita [1] Pulutan [75] Pusit [14] Puto [4] Puto Bumbong [1] Quiapo [1] Radish [1] Readers Recipe [2] Recipe [620] Relleno [5] Rice [22] Roast [7] Roll [7] Round Up [5] Salad [18] Salpicao [2] Salsa [2] Sandwich [1] Sarciado [4] Sardinas [10] Scrumbled [1] Seafood [90] Shawarma [1] Sinaing [3] Sinampalukan [2] Sinanglao [1] Sinanglay [2] Singapore [7] Sinigang [17] Siomai [1] Siopao [1] Sisig [6] Sizzling [5] Sopas [5] Sotanghon [2] Soup [66] Soup No. 5 [1] Spaghetti [11] Spanish [1] Starters [3] Steak [6] Steamed [11] Stirfry [52] Street Food [16] Stroganoff [2] Suam [2] Sugpo [4] Suman [1] Sweet and Sour [9] Tahong [5] Talaba [1] Tapa [1] Teriyaki [1] Thailand [5] Tinola [14] Tinowa [6] Tinubong [1] Tocino [3] Tofu [10] Tom Yum [1] Torta [8] Turkey [1] Turon [1] Ukoy [4] Utan [1] Vegetable [126] Video [3] Vigan [24] YouTube [2] 
 
Recent Comments
 

 You need to enable JavaScript to read this. 
Search the Archive
 Search the Archive July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 June 2007   
Subscribe for Free Updates
 
If you like my recipes, submit your email to get free updates delivered to your inbox.

 

Delivered by FeedBurner 

 
 Overseas Pinoy Cooking on Facebook
	</body>
</document>
