<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001048" url="http://chicago.menupages.com/restaurants/sky-chop-suey/" time="2012-07-12-16:27" support="4" score="0.017422444705187966" bingtitle="Sky Chop Suey - Chicago Restaurant - MenuPages Chinese Restaurant ..." webtitle="Sky Chop Suey - Chicago Restaurant - MenuPages Chinese Restaurant Search">
			<query id="000104" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="000667" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000664" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000747" bing-rank="186"/>
	<description>The food is made to order, so they are not a typical fast food restaurant, ie not fast, but if you call ahead ... This place has definitely went down hill. The rice is dry ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to MenuPages - Please Select a city:

 New York City San Francisco Los Angeles Philadelphia Boston Chicago Washington, DC South Florida 
 New Menupages Desintations London   Paris 
 hide 
 
 Home Blog My MenuPages Restaurateurs Submit a Menu Change City Food Delivery Login 
 
 MenuPages 

Now Serving: 4287 Menus for Chicago Restaurants
 
 Search Advanced Find-A-Food 
 
 Areas Neighborhood All Areas Downtown North Side Northwest Side South Side Southwest Side West Side All Neighborhoods Albany Park / North Park Archer Hts / Brighton Pk Bridgeport-McKinley Park Bronzeville / Douglas Chicago Lawn / Ashburn Chinatown / Pilsen Edgewater / Andersonville Far NW Chicago Far SE Chicago Far SW Chicago Gold Coast Hermosa Humboldt-Austin-Garfield Hyde Park / Kenwood Irving Park Lawndale Lincoln Park / DePaul Lincoln Sq / Ravenswood Logan Square / Avondale Loop Midway Montclare / Cragin Near West New City / Chatham Old Town / Goose Island Portage Park / Dunning River North Rogers Park / Devon Ave Roscoe Village / North Ctr South Loop / Near South South Shore / Woodlawn Streeterville Ukranian Village Uptown West Loop / Greektown Wicker Park / Bucktown Wrigleyville / Lakeview Cuisines All Cusines Afghan African American (New) American (Traditional) Argentinean Asian (other) Asian Fusion Australian Austrian Bagels Bakeries Bar Food Barbecue Belgian Bistro Brazilian British (Modern) British (Traditional) Burgers Cafes&amp;Coffeehouses Cajun&amp;Creole Californian Caribbean Central American Central Asian Cheesesteaks Chicago Grill Chicken Chinese Cocktails Crepes Cuban Delis Desserts Dim Sum Diners&amp;Coffee Shops Dutch Eastern European Eclectic&amp;International Ethiopian Filipino Fish&amp;Chips French Gastropub German Greek Haitian Hawaiian Health Food Hot Dogs Indian Indonesian Irish Italian Jamaican Japanese Korean Kosher Latin American Local/Organic Mediterranean Mexican Middle Eastern Moroccan Noodle Shops Nuevo Latino Other Pakistani Persian Peruvian Pizza Polish Puerto Rican/Dominican Russian Salads Sandwiches Scandinavian Seafood Small Plates/Tapas Smoothies/Juice Bar Soups South American Southern&amp;Soul Southwestern Spanish Steakhouses Sushi Teahouses Thai Tibetan Turkish Vegan Vegetarian-Friendly Venezuelan Vietnamese Wild Game Wine Bar Wings Street Zip code Cross street Restaurant name 
 
Hold down Control (PC) or Command (Mac) key + mouseclick to select more than one option
 
 
Sky Chop Suey
 + SHARE 


 $$ 
 Rating Avg. Dinner Entrée $$$$$ Greater than $25 $$$$ $18.01 - $25 $$$ $12.01 - $18 $$ $7.01 - $12 $ Less than $7 
 Chinese 8616 S Kedzie Ave , Chicago   IL 60652 41.7368048 -87.7020682 (Btwn W 85th&amp;W 87th St) Subway Directions 

 
 
 Phone: (773) 778-6970 
 
 Profile&amp;Reviews Menu http://www.menupages.com/restaurants/sky-chop-suey/menu Report Errors Add to
My MenuPages Email 
 Facebook Twitter + MORE 
 
 
User Ratings (Based on 6 reviews) 
 3.74 5 
 Food 4.2 Value 4.1 Service 3.5 Atmosphere 2.5 
 
 Rate and Review this restaurant 
 
Other Restaurant Info
 Phone: work (773) 778-6970 Fax: fax (773) 778-8888 Notes: Visa, MC Hours: Mon-Thu: 11:30am-9:30pm Fri-Sat: 11:30am-11pm Sun: 11:30am-9:30pm Serves: Lunch,
 
 Dinner Features: Delivery,
 
 Accepts Credit Cards,
 
 Lunch Special,
 
 Take Out,
 
 Catering Min Delivery: 10.00 
User Reviews
 
 Sky Chop Suey 
 Posted by A Regular on 02/03/2012 
 
I&apos;m a regular
 
I order food from Sky about once a week. The food is made to order, so they are not a typical fast food restaurant, ie not fast, but if you call ahead like I do, you don&apos;t have to sit around and wait. They also deliver, which I love when I don&apos;t want to leave the house.
 Sky Chop Suey 
 Posted by Chicago Lady21 on 12/06/2011 
 
Downhill
 
This place has definitely went down hill. The rice is dry,service is extremely slow even when your the only one in the restaurant. And the prices have went up. The quality is not worth the amount for the product, that they&apos;re serving now for ten+ years I&apos;ve known and ate at this restaurant, since tastebuds was next door.
 Sky Chop Suey 
 Posted by Alley Oop on 09/15/2011 
 
Simply The Best
 
I pass ten other Chinese take places between my house and trhis place. It is simply the best tasting Chinese food take out on the southwest side of Chicago!
 Sky Chop Suey 
 Posted by N. Cannon on 04/07/2009 
 
The ONLY Chineese Spot for me!
 
I travel from the east side for this food! This is THE BEST as far as fast food spots go. I thoroughly recommend you try it if you are in the mood and in the area.
 Sky Chop Suey 
 Posted by Vada Laylene on 03/30/2009 
 
THIS IS MY SPOT! LOL
 
I&apos;ve been eating at this place for years and, normally, I do delivery. They have pretty good food and the delivery is pretty fast, depending how far you stay. The employees are courteous and do their best to make sure that the customers are satisfied. If you&apos;re around the area and craving Cantonese/Chinese food, then I higly recommend this place.
 Sky Chop Suey 
 Posted by Yolanda on 05/17/2007 
 
If you want good chinese food this is it
 
The food in this establishment is actually very good. The service is good depending on how crowded it is, they are not the fastest but it is worth the wait. The atmosphere is that of a fast food restaurant not bad. Save 10% by faxing your order to them:)
 
 
 1 
 
 Rate and Review this restaurant 
 
Advertising
 
Movies near Sky Chop Suey
 AMC Loews Chicago Ridge 6 
500 Chicago Ridge Mall

Chicago Ridge
 The Amazing Spider-Man 3D  (PG-13) The Amazing Spider-Man  (PG-13) Ted  (R) Tyler Perry&apos;s Madea&apos;s Witness Protection  (PG-13) Brave  (PG) Brave 3D  (PG) More Nearby theaters» 
 Ticketing provided by
 
Hot and Fresh Restaurant News Delivered Weekly
 You are signing up to receive: Weekly updates delivered straight to your inbox covering the latest restaurant news, menus, openings, closings, and food events Menupages Chicago Newsletter You may also be interested in: Hear about special offers from MenuPages or its partners about future events, promotions and features. Offers&amp;Promotions Sign Up 
Thanks for subscribing!

You will soon begin to receive the newsletters you selected.

To enjoy more benefits and personalization available on MenuPages.com, register now! 
 Checkbox is required 
Advertising
 
 About Us Careers Contact Us Advertise With Us Restaurateurs Privacy Policy Legal Notices Copyright Notice 

©2002-2012 Slick City Media, Inc. All Rights Reserved. MenuPages®is a trademark of Slick City Media, Inc. Disclaimer
	</body>
</document>
