<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001855" url="http://www.bloglander.com/cheapeats/category/restaurants/" time="2012-07-12-17:38" support="12" score="0.04428318905749226" bingtitle="Cheap Eats Restaurants : Cheap Eats - Bloglander : A Collection of ..." webtitle="Cheap Eats Restaurants :  Cheap Eats">
			<query id="001073" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000942" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001094" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000690" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="001082" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000438" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="001079" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="001066" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000533" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="001089" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="001085" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="001255" bing-rank="79"/>
	<description>You just walk in and they give you a free order of ... Like nearly every fast food restaurant, they’re under the gun ... Gadgets &amp; Utensils; Groceries; Meat; Prepared Food; Snacks</description>
	<body>
		Your guide to eating cheap including tips, recipes and techniques
 
Archives for Cheap Eats Restaurants

 
3/21/11 | Popeye’s 8 Pieces Chicken 4.99 
 
[ Currently Eating: Hope, that friends in Japan are OK ]
 

Jeebus. Yes, I know–I could’ve picked a better post to stage a comeback on Cheap Eats . You know how it goes, and so on and so on.

This Wednesday March 23, 2011, Popeye’s is offering their Payday Special where you can get 8 pieces of mixed fried chicken for only $4.99.

Am I going down to the closest one to check it out? Absolutely. Am I going to eat all that chicken? I highly doubt it. I’ll probably go pick it up, take it to our pickup hockey game, and then give it all away. Maybe I’ll eat a piece, especially if you hold me down and fart soliloquies in my face. You extra-talented sphincter. And so on.

Muggle buggle, I am done.

 Editor’s Note: I hope that all the food blogger peeps in Japan have made it through OK. I have family in Japan, but they were all in the Tokyo area, so while times are a bit tougher, it’s not as bad. I feel terrible for the people in the north and near the coast–hope the recovery there goes quickly. 
 
 1 Comment» 
 
2/19/09 | Free Hardees Potatoes 
 
[ Currently Eating: Coffee ]
 I’ve occasionally been asked why a lot of the food news and reviews I feature are“West-coast”oriented.

That would be because I live in California–home of the 42 billion dollar debt. Oh, and the Governator.

However. Just to show you I’m willling to give a shout out to companies east of the Rockies, I’d like to tell you about the Free Country Potatoes Day at Hardees tomorrow (Friday February 20, 2009). Yep, no purchase necessary apparently. You just walk in and they give you a free order of country potatoes.

Yes, I know we do have their sister chain Carl’s Junior in my neck of the woods. However, they aren’t serving up the free goods as far as I know. But I would, in fact, be willing to make a road trip to visit Hardees for the free potatoes. I’ve been known to do crageee things like that. (If eating potted meat from the dollar store doesn’t qualify as crageee, I don’t know what does.)

However, it appears that the nearest Hardees is 1063 miles away . In Casper, Wyoming, to be exact. I googlemapped it, and it’s a bit of a far drive even for crageee ol’me. About 16 hours 27 minutes if I drove it straight.

So, I’m going to sit this one out. But I’d like to hear how the free potato event goes if you happen to have a Hardees near you.
 
 4 Comments» 
 
10/15/08 | Togo’s 1.99 Sandwiches 
 
[ Currently Eating: MORE COUGHDROPS ]
 Man. The sandwich shop chain wars continue. Not a millisecond goes by without me being bombarded with ads for Subway or Quizno’s . For what it’s worth, I eat at Subway occasionally. But less often now that their 5 dollar subs are for a limited selection of sandwiches.

I categorically DESPISE Quizno’s, but that is a long, long story for another bright and shiny day when I’m not still feeling the effects of a lingering cold.

But Togo’s –I was actually a huge, huge fan of theirs, especially in college. The sandwiches they made were always slightly better tasting and looking than Subway’s. My friend refused to eat at Subway even if they were closer. He always said“That’s nast…”. I guess he meant short for nasty. We always had to make the trek to Togo’s.

And noooooo, they did not give me the keys to the company lamborghini in order to say that.

But anyhow, the reason for this post is that they are having a special 1970s Flashback Wednesday deal where you can get a featured classic 6″sub for $1.99. The only thing is that it’s good on just one type of their sandwiches per week. This Wednesday, the sandwich is the #24 Turkey and Avocado . I guess I should also mention that Togo’s will be making a donation to the Junior Diabetes Research Foundation for each Flashback 6″sandwich sold. Admirable.

And yessssss, they did spam me and that’s where I got all this information.

I still would like a ride in their company car, however, if the higher-ups would not mind…
 
 2 Comments» 
 
10/7/08 | In-N-Out 25 Cent Hamburgers? 
 
[ Currently Eating: Cough Drops ]
 

Dearest In-N-Out,

I would very much like to know whether or not the keeerazy internet rumor about the In-N-Out 60th Year Anniversary on October 22, 2008 is true or not. According to some many people, on that day you may be selling your hamboyggas for a quarter, your cheeseboyggas for 30 cents, your Freedom Fries for 15 cents and your carbonated sugar water for 10 cents. It is difficult to know what story to believe, and I would very much like to know.

You see, I have been feeling down in the dumps lately–what with the economy sitting in the toilet and people at the Big Lots buying all the Trivial Pursuit Pringles before I can get my hot little hands on them.

Also, I have recently come down with a sore throat and cold so I am bedridden. Thusly, if you are indeed having your 60th bash w/ the low prices–would it be too much trouble to ask if you could please have a courier deliver 10 of your delicious cheeseyburghers and 3 orders of your Freedom Fries to my house? I’ll leave the door open so they can come right in. I believe the total would be $3.45, with tax that comes to $3.73. I’ll put it on the table near the door, next to the life-sized photo of Richard Dean Anderson .

There is an“attack cat”by the door, but he will not attack if you give him 1 cheeseburger and say“YOU CAN HAS CHEEZBURGER LIL FELLOE!”.

Also, if you could please have the courier arrive in a cherry red 1957 Corvette with the In-N-Out logo painted on the side. I would also like the courier to wear a snakeskin hat, Sarah Palin glasses, and a bikini.

Sincerely,
the ill (not illin’) Cheap Eats Editor 

 Editor’s Note : Excuse the above, I’m not feeling myself right now…
 
 4 Comments» 
 
9/18/08 | Free IKEA Breakfast 
 
[ Currently Eating: Just Coffee ]
 Ugh…I’m back a little early. But no worse for wear in general. The painful finger issue seems to have gone away–somewhat of a mystery.

Anyhow, I wasn’t going to post until next week but I felt absolutely compelled to get the word out about the FREE IKEA BREAKFAST that is going to be happening this weekend Sept 19-21, 2008. Seize the day, indeed. O captain, my captain!

I actually like the food in general at IKEA and have been meaning to make a post about it since it’s fairly cheap. But this is for free breakfast, no strings attached. You don’t have to buy anything–but of course, how could you not go to IKEA and NOT buy anything, LOL. That’s what they’re counting on, of course.

There’s more info on the Ikea site (I didn’t link directly to the coupon page because they’ll probably take it down later.) Note, the free breakfast does not apply in several cities (also, I didn’t check whether it applies in other countries), so you should probably check or call before heading down there. I wouldn’t want you to get breakfast-blocked after driving all the way there.

The offer is one per customer and only good until 10:30am. You get a free small breakfast and one cup of coffee–total value is $2. But hey, every little bit counts–have you felt the wobbling crazy insane eeekconomy lately? I have…and speaking of which–I’m still working on that related side project which was part of the reason for the extended break / vacation. I was going to“announce”it next week on the blog. But you can probably find it earlier if you’re interested.
 
 Comments Off 
 
8/12/08 | El Pollo Loco $4 Meal 
 
[ Currently Eating: Bacon ]
 Man, I really apologize for yet another lame post. My sleeping schedule has just been zonked out lately, I feel like a zombie.

If you should decide to forgive me, here is a quickie on El Pollo Loco . Like nearly every fast food restaurant, they’re under the gun to promote some really cheap food to get customers in the door. I never saw so many 99 cent menus in my life. One day, I’m going to have to review them all (yeah, right).

However, EPL also has an under 4 dollar meal which is decent. There are 4 different choices. They are:

 2 Pieces chicken leg/thigh, tortillas, plus 1 side 
 Crunchy Taco, BRC burrito, plus 1 side 
 Classic Chicken Burrito, Taquito, plus 1 side 
 3 Tacos al Carbon, plus 1 side 

Lately on Wednesdays, I’ve been ordering El Pollo Loco to-go after the nightly rollerhockey game. I’ve been somewhat shocked to see the place jumping at 8:30 at night. It took nearly 20 minutes to get my food. It must be because it’s one of the healthier options for fast food. Maybe a lot of folks coming home after a late workday would rather pick that up than KFC. I dunno. I just know that the $3.99 meals are rather nice because you can pick the side. I usually get salad, or mac n cheese.

Their menu says the side is limited to Rice, Pinto Beans, or Mashed Potatoes and Gravy –but ours lets you order whatever you want. Sometimes instead of the 4 dollar meal, I mess around with their dollar menu which we’ve posted about favorably before. Or, I just get the 2 piece chicken / 2 side meal w/out the drink which comes out to about $5. I’ll probably do one or the other tomorrow–if I don’t fall alseep while waiting for the food.

 Read: Four $4 Meals at E.P.L. 
 
 1 Comment» 
 
7/29/08 | Won Ton Time 
 
[ Currently Eating: Earthquake Food ]
 NOTE: Due to rocking and rolling and other earthquakedness, our regular Cheap Eats coverage will be postponed until such a time as the ground stops shaking. For now, please gaze fondly at this older photo of an enormous shrimp dumpling from the now defunct Won Ton Time on Garfield in Monterey Park.

Regular coverage will resume in a few days, or next week depending on schedule and Laziness Quotient ™. Thank you.

 
 
 6 Comments» 
 «Previous Entries Next Page» 
Most Popular
 Making Homemade Gatorade Chicken of the Sea Clams Quesadillas Home Fried Potatoes 
Categories
 Cheap Eats Cities 
 Albuquerque, NM Chico, CA Denver, CO Detroit, MI Eugene, OR Las Vegas, NV Los Angeles, CA 
 Cheap Eats Hall Of Shame Cheap Eats Recipes 
 3 Dollars or Less Appetizers Beverages Bread Breakfast Pasta Rice Sandwiches Seafood Soups 
 Cheap Eats Restaurants 
 Fast Food Sit Down 
 Cheap Eats Shopping 
 Beverages Canned Food Frozen Food Gadgets&amp;Utensils Groceries Meat Prepared Food Snacks 
 Cheap Eats Tips 
 Food Storage 
 Miscellaneous 
 Battles Contests Food Books Food Polls Food Shows Free Food In The News Just Because Leftovers for Lunch 
 
Site Info
 About 
 Contact 
 Privacy Policy/Disclaimer 
 RSS2 
 Copyright 
 Sitemap 
 
 



Archives
 April 2011 
 March 2011 
 January 2011 
 December 2010 
 November 2010 
 October 2010 
 September 2010 
 August 2010 
 July 2010 
 June 2010 
 May 2010 
 April 2010 
 March 2010 
 February 2010 
 January 2010 
 December 2009 
 November 2009 
 October 2009 
 September 2009 
 August 2009 
 July 2009 
 June 2009 
 May 2009 
 April 2009 
 March 2009 
 February 2009 
 January 2009 
 December 2008 
 November 2008 
 October 2008 
 September 2008 
 August 2008 
 July 2008 
 June 2008 
 May 2008 
 April 2008 
 March 2008 
 February 2008 
 January 2008 
 December 2007 
 November 2007 
 October 2007 
 September 2007 
 August 2007 
 July 2007 
 June 2007 
 May 2007 
 April 2007 
 March 2007 
 February 2007 
 January 2007 
 December 2006 
 November 2006 
 October 2006 
 September 2006 
 August 2006 
 July 2006 
 June 2006 
 May 2006 
 April 2006 
 March 2006 
 February 2006 
 January 2006 
 December 2005 
 November 2005 
 October 2005 
 September 2005 
 August 2005 
 July 2005 
 June 2005 
 May 2005 
 April 2005 
 March 2005 
 February 2005 
 January 2005 
 December 2004 
 November 2004 
 
Links
 Candy Blog 
 Cheaplander 
 iateapie . net 
 Phood 
 The Girl Who Ate Everything 
 The Impulsive Buy 
 
Recommended Reads
 
 Desperation Dinners 
 Beverly Mills&amp;Alicia Ross 

 250 appealing and nutritious recipes focusing on &quot;convenience foods&quot; that can be made from start to finish in 20 minutes for those nights when it just seems impossible to cook a home-made meal. 
 Cheap. Fast. Good! 
 Beverly Mills 

 A &quot;get smart&quot; cookbook. 275 delicious recipes that are thrifty, quick to prepare, and intrinsically family-friendly and healthy, too. 
 Miserly Meals 
 Jonni McCoy 

 Family cookbook for frugal moms. A collection of over 200 healthy, tasty recipes under 75 cents per serving. 
 Cheap and Easy 
 Sandra Bark, Vin Ganapathy, Alexis Kanfer 

 Cookbook for girls on the go. Demystifying the kitchen for busy working women who are more apt to order take out than cook meals.   
©2004-2012 Bloglander
	</body>
</document>
