<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001632" url="http://www.bowtrolcleanse.com/" time="2012-07-12-17:24" support="1" score="0.0008184019391876054" bingtitle="Bowtrol ™ Cleanse | Natural Colon Cleanse" webtitle="BowtrolCleanse | Natural Colon Cleanse">
			<query id="001531" bing-rank="189"/>
	<description>Not only that, prescribed drugs, shelved food, and every corner fast food restaurant ... adding extra strain on our colon and other vital organs to rid the waste.</description>
	<body>
		Menu   
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Home Articles 
- Benefits of Cleansing 
- Foods that Cleanse 
- Do You Have a Parasite? 
- Weight Loss&amp;Cleansing 
- Types of a Colon Cleanse 
- Cleansing&amp;Your Skin 
- Is Colon Cleansing Safe? 
- Famous Colon Quotes 
- Keeping Your Colon Clean 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Bowtrol - Natural Colon Cleanse! 

 
Everyday our system is bombarded with toxins, through the air we breathe, the food we eat, 
even the water we drink. This is because of all the pollutants, pesticides, and chemicals that exist
today. Not only that, prescribed drugs, shelved food, and every corner fast food restaurant, adds an extra 
burden to our bodies to cleanse itself and maintain a healthy colon.

With a Bowtrol Colon Cleanse you will experience
 Boost Your Energy Levels Clean Your Entire System Eliminate Unwanted Parasites Relief From Constipation No More Gas or Bloating Lose Excess Weight Clearer Skin and Healthier Hair Better Absorption of Nutrients Strengthens Colon Health Flatter Stomach and Waist Line 30 Day Guarantee 

 
 
   
 
 
 How the Body Detoxifies 

 Detoxification, or what we commonly term as cleansing, occurs everyday through our skin, colon, 
kidneys, and liver. We primarily get rid of the toxins in our body through sweat and using the
bathroom. The Colon is the key component when eliminating toxins from the body. You can think
of it as the final filter that sifts and absorbs all the nutrients and vitamins it can before
eliminating the rest as waste. However, once this filter becomes clogged, it slows down
the natural process of detoxification, adding extra strain on our colon and other vital organs
to rid the waste. 
Too many toxins, and buildup begins to occur in the colon resulting in a variety of symptoms such as:
fatigue, stress, constipation, IBS, bloating, etc...

Even if you eat organic foods, drink pure water, and exercise daily, you cannot
escape the toxins we are exposed to everyday. Your body enters what is known
as &apos;toxic overload&apos;, which make us sick, bloated, constipated, stressed, fatigued, and
many other unwanted symptoms. The bottom line is a clogged colon is detrimental to our 
overall health and well-being.
 
 Bowtrol was formulated just for this specific purpose to clean your colon! Not 
only that, this herbal colon cleanse completely eliminates known parasites that can live sometimes for years 
in your body without you knowing. Check out the article on parasites.
 
   
 SPECIAL OFFER - 2 FREE BOTTLES! 
   
 Try Bowtrol TODAY! 
   
 
 
 
 Home | Articles | Partners | Sitemap | Contact Us 
   

 ©Bowtrol Cleanse.Com
	</body>
</document>
