<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001497" url="http://sm.sbwebman.com/whats-the-difference-btwn-an-ipad-and-a-boss-electronics-2200-7-inch-widescreen-android-2-2-tablet/" time="2012-07-12-17:16" support="3" score="0.003126919619239859" bingtitle="what’s the difference btwn an iPad and a BOSS Electronics 2200 7 ..." webtitle="whats the difference btwn an iPad and a BOSS Electronics 2200 7-inch Widescreen Android 2.2 Tablet - sm.sbwebman.com - Computer and Electronics Informations - sm.sbwebman.com">
			<query id="001399" bing-rank="242"/>
			<query id="001409" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="000930" bing-rank="152"/>
	<description>... I work at a fast food restaurant, so yea I deal with a**holes EVERY day. I&apos;m forced to take it on the chin ... of handing this lady her receipt I ... Can a car just not like ...</description>
	<body>
		sm.sbwebman.com Computer and Electronics Informations 
 Home Electronics Articles Electronics Questions Electronics Video Electronics Products 
 

 
what’s the difference btwn an iPad and a BOSS Electronics 2200 7-inch Widescreen Android 2.2 Tablet
 
Alicia Asked: what’s the difference btwn an iPad and a BOSS Electronics 2200 7-inch Widescreen Android 2.2 Tablet

you can play porn on the ipad while you ca&apos;t on the Android
 
 
 
Answers:
 Beginner Troll Answered: 
Well iPads do half of the things android tablets do and they&apos;re usually double the cost. Answered: 
Why didn&apos;t you immediately report them to the manager? They could be kicked out, or even go to jail. You can&apos;t verbally abuse someone like that for no reason, thats harassment. CatStevens Answered: 
I work at a fast food restaurant, so yea I deal with a**holes EVERY day. I&apos;m forced to take it on the chin because my job depends on it.

One time I was ringing up someones order and instead of handing this lady her receipt I set it on the counter. She took offense to that and YELLED&quot;So now you&apos;re gonna throw sh** at me!?&quot;Nothing was thrown! And we were already at the peak of a bad lunch rush and I had gone hours without water or a trip to the bathroom. I felt like goin postal on her ***, but I just ignored her and got through it.

The only way you could shut them up is by being an even bigger jerk to them, but most people naturally aren&apos;t like that so its hard to beat them at their own game. They are obviously worthless, self-loathing piles of misery, so all you can really do is ignore them…or beat the crap out of them, your call 
Got a better answer? Share it below!

Incoming search terms:

 boss electronics 2200 review boss electronics 2200 tablet Boss Electronics 2200 boss electronics 2200 tablet review Boss Electronics 2200 reviews Boss Electronics 2200 7-Inch Touchscreen Android 2 2 Tablet PC - Black boss 2200a reviews boss tablet 2200 

Related posts:

 Anyone have any ideas for good birthday gifts? Has anyone bought electronics or motorcycle from wu-lili.com? Are they honest? Being an engineer specialized in Electronics, I understand the different panel technologies used in Whats a good electronic i can buy for $500? In simple terms, what is the difference between a resistor, and a capacitor? 
 
 Be the first to comment - What do you think? 
Posted by Syl_wp - August 14, 2011 at 7:00 am

Categories: Electronics Questions   Tags: Alicia Asked , EVERY , Widescreen Android 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 
 

 CAPTCHA Code * 

 Comment 

 

 
 
 
Solar energy
 Solar Energy Facts 
pithching machines
 pitching machines 
Recent Posts

 Why are my electronics turning themselves off and on (please help!!)? What would be the best school for me? how can i make a good conclusion for ultimate electronics recession? :mb_convert_encoding() []: Illegal character encoding specified in on line The Future Light Bulb, its Going to be Full of Electronics! Are EEE students are eligible for job as IT officer in Banks? Question about appearance for a SALES job.? Training Field for Electronics and Communication Engineering? what’s the cause of this pain? What is the meaning of state in Flip-Flops (Digital electronics)? Scary ghost thing that happened to me? which is the most affordable SAP institute in delhi having great placements also? CAN I APPLY FOR AIR FORCE ? 100_1020.MOV Essay revise! Bonus points!!!!? Ipod Car adapter question (10 Points for best answer)? What are the global electronics store? parents with kids over 14 answer this!!! It’s long sorry!!!? Which colour of this ipod case should I get? How to get an internship in public sector companies? Help me I am Bored!!!? When will prices of HDD’s go down? Is My Eyesight Bad When I look at Electronics? How to hack mw2 for ps3? Please help desperate? What is happening ? Tragic? How many electronics are currently on in the room you’re in? www.Electronics-Base.com AVR external interupts–INT0 example I would like to make friend in Malaysia (I’m from Taiwan)? Need help troubleshooting Wii? How can i use a 12volt low amp power source to power a 1.5 to 3 volt motor? what to get a 12 year old boy who loves sports, electronics (not video games)? Any sales 2mrw?? 12/26/2011? Not getting much stuff for christmas? Which of these iHomes is better? There are websites to buy eyeglasses, contact lenses, electronics at very cheap prices. What about f What headohines are better, Dre beats, or MDR-V700 sony Dj style headphones? what headohines are better, Dre beats, or MDR-V700 sony Dj style headphones? When the government just prints whatever money they need,will the cost of the printing exceed the am The 10 Worst Networking and Electronics Stocks of 2010 help me set up my email on new android phone please??? :-D? What are some fun stuff to do when your alone? Advice on producing music? Car electronics–what cable?!? how to make contracts with stores on refurbished electronics? Why does my audio lag my computer? Can a car just not like somebody? planned obsolescence? Why can’t I fall asleep with light? What is a counter in Digital Electronics and why do we need it? Need a very secure way to lock my apt door…? How to get ungrounded? Why does my Frigidaire gas range reset itself? Accounting Help Please :)? Which turntable is better? Pyle vs. Audio Technica? Ok electronics experts, I need help? On a TV question? Ok electronics experts, I need help? What would a massive EMP attack be like? Which of these hdtv/monitors would be best for the price? What can I get my dad for Christmas? Good home theater design book? I need help installing a sound system in a 2006 ford focus zx3? 
 
 
WordPress Theme by HeatMapTheme.com 
 Powered by:
 Wordpress
	</body>
</document>
