<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001144" url="http://blogs.miaminewtimes.com/shortorder/2009/07/big_ice_bold_statement_its_ref.php" time="2012-07-12-16:34" support="1" score="0.0010734503670056415" bingtitle="Cartoon Ice and St. Germain Dreams: It&apos;s Refined Cocktail Time at ..." webtitle="Cartoon Ice and St. Germain Dreams: It&apos;s Refined Cocktail Time at Fratelli Lyon and EOS - Miami Restaurants and Dining - Short Order">
			<query id="000997" bing-rank="69"/>
	<description>We&apos;ve come to expect high quality ingredients and ... Build Ingredients in a mixing glass, add ice, shake ... Fed&apos;s Primal Zin Wine Dinner; Salty American Fast Food; Restaurant No ...</description>
	<body>
		Blogs 
 Entire Site Articles&amp;Blogs Restaurants Places Events Music Images Ads Bars Best Of Movies 
 News Home Riptide Strouse Luke&apos;s Gospel Letters Special Reports Archives Search New Times Flipbook Weekly Newsletter Get Mobile Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads New Times Web Awards Music Home Crossfade Concert Calendar Bars and Clubs Brew at the Zoo Submit an Event Music Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurants Home Short Order Find a Restaurant Menus Iron Fork Happy Hours Dining Deals Dining Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurant Ads Arts Home Cultist Visual Arts Theater Welcome to the Future Skrawberry Jam Artopia Arts Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Film Home Showtimes Cultist Film Film Poll 2011 Film Newsletter Get Mobile Free Stuff Best Of Home 2012 2011 2010 2009 Readers&apos; Poll 2012 Best Of Newsletter Get Mobile Best Of Ads Promotions Home Promotional Events Street Team Free Stuff On Sale Promotions Newsletter Get Mobile Deals Post an Ad Jobs Real Estate Advertiser Index Deals Deals Newsletter Virtual Job Fair 
Top

blog

Stories
 
 
 Miami Spice 

 Gotham Steak Hakkasan, Scarpetta Miami Spice 

By Laine Doss
 
 Holidays 

 Bastille Day at Brand New Fabien&apos;s Bistro 

By Lee Klein
 
 Best of Miami 

 Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants 

By Laine Doss
 
 First Bites 

 Iron Side Cafe: Fresh New Lunch Spot 

By Lee Klein
 
 Gastronomic Gatherings 

 Fairchild Makes Mangoes Exciting This Weekend 

By Laine Doss
 
 Chef on the Small Screen 

 Eat St. to Film Food Trucks in Miami 

By Laine Doss
 
 Food Charity 

 Taste of the Nation Celebrates 25th Anniversary 

By Laine Doss
 
 Neighborhood Joints 

 Shack Shack In Coral Gables Opening Soon 

By Laine Doss
 
 News 

 Zeke&apos;s Reincarnated: Rio Station 

By Hannah Sentenac
 
 Fuming Foodie 

 Teacher Nailed for Horrible Behavior With Food&amp;Kids 

By Ily Goyanes
 
   Booze Hound 
Cartoon Ice and St. Germain Dreams: It&apos;s Refined Cocktail Time at Fratelli Lyon and EOS
 By Jackie Sayet Fri., Jul. 17 2009 at 12:00 PM Categories: Booze Hound 
 Pin It 
 
 Jackie Sayet Even the garnish is a star at EOS 
 We&apos;ve come to expect high quality ingredients and technique in fine dining kitchens around town, so why shouldn&apos;t the same principle be applied behind the bar? It is now thanks to a new focus on natural spirits, supporting mixers and special touches, as well as precision in drink-making. We checked out Fratelli Lyon Driade and EOS, two establishments who are taking this mission to heart.

 Fratelli Lyon Driade&apos;s Retro Ice and New Aperitivo Service 
Back in the 1800s, barmen would take an icepick to blocks of ice, hacking off large chunks to slow melting and thus thwart cocktail dilution. The more perfect the chisel, the better the bartender. Lyon got its liquor license two weeks ago today, and even rapper Ice Cube would be
jealous.  
 Jackie Sayet Ice, ice baby 
 Behind the brother&apos;s bar, Chris and Cricket pile certain drinks high with machine-made frozen beauties, each exactly 1.5 square inches. Almost too perfect for real life. But don&apos;t arrive expecting the sequel to Cocktail . The entertainment at Lyon is its adherence to measurement of each shaken, stirred and layered concoction .  This is a free-pouring and flare-free zone.

Lyon polishes its potions with hand-made single-batch scotches, single-estate vintage tequila and locally made gins. A favorite is one Cricket just dreamed up yesterday, soon to be a specialty drink on the menu: Le Montecarla ($TBD,) featuring Nicolas Lavender Gin from Tampa (via distributor Artisan Brands,) thyme simple syrup, St. Germain Elderflower Liqueur and fresh blueberries. Its prominent feature is a sensuous bouquet of herbs from the lavender spirit and infused simple syrup, matched brilliantly with a subtle sweet tang from blueberry.

 Happy Hour Monday through Friday from 5 - 8pm. Specialty pricing is available for house cocktails, wine and beer. Pricing for cocktails is as follows: $5 from 5-6pm, $6 from 6-7pm and $7 from 7-8pm. Fratelli Lyon Driade, 4141 NE 2nd Avenue, Miami (Design District); (305) 572-2901 

 Bitter is Better at EOS with Grapefruit Superstar
 On a recent visit for dinner, a cocktail made an impressive cameo: the Grapefruit Superstar ($14,) named after its carambola (star fruit) garnish. The
modifying cordial in this drink is again the smittening St. Germain Elderflower
Liqueur, produced in France in batches and numbered with a vintage year, like a fine wine. Herradura Silver, a less
aged tequila, plays an important role in releasing the flavors of this cocktail. It&apos;s a nice departure from the usual candy-in-a-martini glass to which we have unfortunately become accustomed in Miami. Here&apos;s the recipe:

 
 Jackie Sayet Unghetto superstar 
 Ingredients:
1 1/2 oz. Herradura Silver Tequila
3/4 oz. of St. Germain Elderflower Liqueur
1/2 oz. of Freshly Squeezed Lime Juice
2 oz. Freshly Squeezed Grapefruit Juice

Method:
Build Ingredients in a mixing glass, add ice,
shake vigorously, strain in a cocktail glass. Garnish with a star
fruit slice on the rim.

The creator of this drink iss Ryan Magarian and tweaked to perfection by Freddy Diaz, Head Bartender at Club 50 Viceroy.
 
EOS, where you can find the Grapefruit Superstar, does not have a Happy Hour; however Club 50, The Viceroy&apos;s 50th floor lounge, does on Thursdays from 6-8pm, with $10 specials for the sponsored drink plus a free welcome drink. They also have an extensive menu of hand-crafted cocktails that cause a stir, like the Dark&amp;Stormy, Floradora and Mango Bellini (regularly priced at $12.) EOS at The Viceroy , 485 Brickell Ave., 15th Floor, Miami (Brickell); 305-503-4400.

 
 Jackie Sayet From left to right: The Aviator featuring incredible marasca cherries marinated in sugar to a creamy consistency (no electric red fakes here!), Dark&amp;Stormy and Le Montecarla at Fratelli Lyon 
 
 
 Jackie Sayet Aperol spritz with prosecco and orange blossom water at Fratelli Lyon 
 
 Jackie Sayet Cordially invited: Last night Fratelli Lyon celebrated its one-year anniversary of its &quot;Aperitivo in Milano&quot; Happy Hour 
 
 Jackie Sayet Obsession of the moment: St. Germain, here on the bar at EOS 
 
Like this Story?
 
Sign up for the Dining Newsletter: The week&apos;s top local food news and events, plus interviews with chefs and restaurant owners, dining tips, and a peek at our print review.
 Privacy Policy Cancel Continue Write Comment Email to Friend Print Article 
Related Content
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. 
 
Ice Making Machine: Thanks! It was fun to research to say the least. Are you in the ice-making business?

AlchemistGeorge: Thank you so much for pointing this out. I failed to catch this error in the recipe I was given from the restaurant. I just updated the post to reflect the correct missing ingredient, lime. Happy mixing.
 
wow its really a very amazing and colorful posting.............................
 
The grapefruit superstar recipe looks like it has a typo - it lists grapefruit juice twice, I&apos;m guessing the smaller amount is lemon juice.
 

TotalComments: 3
 
Now Trending


 
Slide shows » 

 Closer Look: Villa Azur Closer Look: Josh&apos;s Delicatessen&amp;Appetizing Rock &apos;n&apos; Roll Beer-B-Que 2012 at Seminole Hard Rock Hotel&amp;Casino More Slideshows&gt;&gt; 
 
 Restaurants 
 
 
Little Brazil
 View Ad | View Site 
Grimpa Steakhouse
 View Ad | View Site 
Gordon Biersch
 View Ad | View Site 
Montes de Oca Original Pizza Cubana
 View Ad | View Site 
 More &gt;&gt; 
Twitter Feed
 
 Follow short_order on Twitter 
 More Twitter &gt;&gt; 
Headlines from our Partners
 

 Summer Gold: Susser Talks Mangoes; London Burger King Installs a Damien Hirst Painting Boulud Hosting &quot;To Live and Dine in Miami&quot;; Balloo&apos;s Summer Additions at Sugarcane &quot;That Glow On The Beach&quot;: The 1950s Restaurants of 22nd Street Whiskey Joe&apos;s Set to Booze on Key Biscayne Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants; Watch an Ad For the Second Cheapest Wine Out There 
 About Us | Work for Miami New Times | Esubscribe | Free Classifieds | Advertising | Privacy Policy | Problem With the Site? | RSS | Site Map 
©2012 Miami New Times, LLC. All rights reserved. Browse Voice Nation Most Popular | Most Recent Newsletters | Mobile Log in Sign up 
 New York Village Voice 
 LA Weekly 
 Phoenix New Times 
 Denver Westword 
 Houston Press 
 Dallas Observer 
 SF Weekly 
 Seattle Weekly 
 St. Louis RFT 
 Miami New Times 
 Minneapolis City Pages 
 OC Weekly 
 Broward/Palm Beach New Times 
 

 
 Voice Places 

Discover restaurants, nightlife, travel, shopping...
 
 VOICE Daily Deals 

Get 50 to 90% off every day on restaurants, movies, massages...
 
 Best Of... 

More than 10,000 of the BEST things to eat, drink, and experience
 
 My Voice Nation 

Join the Village Voice community and get exclusive deals and info
 
 Happy Hour 

Your local Happy Hour guide at your fingertips
 
 or 
 Log in or Sign up 
 Social Connect: 
Use your favorite account to access My Voice Nation.
 
 
Use your My Voice Nation account to log in:
 E-mail 
 
 Password 
 
 Forgot password? Remember me or 
 Sign Up or Log in 
 Social Connect: 
Sign up for My Voice Nation with your preferred network.
 
 
Sign up for a My Voice Nation account:
 E-mail 
 
 Privacy policy 
 Settings Log Out
	</body>
</document>
