<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001202" url="http://www.ehow.com/operations-management/" time="2012-07-12-16:39" support="1" score="0.0016713437967452443" bingtitle="Operations Management - How To Information | eHow.com" webtitle="Operations Management - How To Information  | eHow.com">
			<query id="001272" bing-rank="3"/>
	<description>Make quality assurance effective with help from a small business owner and active ... Narrow Your Selection. Purchasing; Management Information Systems; ISO; Inventory</description>
	<body>
		money section 
 Saving&amp;Spending 
 Budgeting Banking Credit Cards Loans 
 Real Estate 
 Buying a Home Home Loans Selling a Home 
 Careers 
 Career Advice Land the Job Work for Yourself 
 Your Business 
 Starting a Business Managing Employees Running a Business 
 Insurance 
 Insurance Basics Auto Insurance Life Insurance 
 Retirement 
 Get Started Plan Ahead Make It Last 
 
 
 More eHow 
 home mom style food tech money health 
 
 Featured: Allergies eHow Now Blog 
 eHow Business Operations Management 
 
Operations Management

 
 RSS Show Newest in Operations Management 
 How to Purchase Business Insurance Online 
Purchasing business insurance online always requires you to keep a few very important things in mind. Purchase business insurance online with help from an insurance professional in this free video clip.
 How Can Project Management Information Systems (PMIS) Give an Organization a Competitive Advantage? 
Whether or not using a project management information system can give you a competitive advantage depends entirely on a few key aspects of your business. Find out if and how using a project management information system can give you a competitive advantage with help from the principal change agent at Vince Rogers&amp;Associates in this free video clip.
 What Is Analytics API? 
If you have ever used an analytics service to track website visits, sales, customer interactions or other information, but found yourself wishing the information was presented in a different way than it was, then you already understand why an analytics API can be helpful. API is an Application Programming Interface that enables or third-party developers to take analytics information from a service and present it in new ways to benefit customers.
 How to Fix ISO Insulation 
ISO (polyisocyanurate) insulation comes in a rigid form that resembles thick sheets. The boards come in different widths, and you can trim the boards to different sizes or shapes. The insulation takes the place of traditional insulation material. Its thick and sturdy construction makes it a good choice for areas where you cannot use blow-in or batting insulation. Fixing tiny cracks or gaps in ISO insulation requires the use of ISO Fix Adhesive.
 Methods of Network Analysis for Production Planning 
Network analysis looks at product manufacturing as a network of tasks that a company has completed. By identifying the key points and paths within the network, analysts calculate the time to complete the project and determine which tasks need the most resources. Employing project-management and network analysis software reduces the work involved.
 ISO 1133 Vs. ASTM D1238 
In the world of plastics, melt flow index measures the output rate -- or flow -- that occurs in natural polymer or masterbatch over the course of 10 minutes when a piston applies a fixed amount of pressure at 190 degrees Celsius. Knowing the MFI helps manufacturers asses the viscosity of a substance to better control its processing. The International Organization for Standardization&apos;s 1133 and the American Society for Testing and Material&apos;s ASTM D1238 both serve as standards for measuring melt flow index.
 Do Graphics Look Bad When Compressed From ISO to CSO? 
Compressing ISO files to CSO format was necessary in the early days of the Sony PlayStation Portable. Memory sticks for this device had a limitation of 1GB, while games were released on Universal Media Discs that were often much larger. To fit these games onto the memory stick, the user compressed them first using third-party software. Memory sticks of today have a much larger capacity, but by using CSO files, users are able to fit more games on one stick. Compressing the files from one format to the other has no impact on the visuals of the game, so the…
 ISO 27001 Vs. Cobit 
Businesses look to the idea of best practices, defined as procedures proven to produce optimal results, to optimize efficiency and profit. Governance frameworks such as ISO 27001 and COBIT serve as highly detailed standards of discipline meant to manage risk, lower loses and reduce negative publicity. Although both ISO 27001 and COBIT cater to governance in the area of information technology -- helping ease IT expenditures and reduce tech-related security risks -- these prominent methodologies differ in focus and details.
 How to Add Macrovision to an ISO 
Macrovision is a video-copy protection method used to prevent unauthorized copying of media on various mediums such as DVDs, VCDs and SVCDs. Although Macromedia protection is applied to the physical media by a replication facility, you can apply it to your ISO file prior to sending it for replication. Currently, the only software that can properly add Macrovision to an ISO and enable you to select the type of protection is DVD Architect Pro.
 How to Use Microsoft Access to Create Steel Inventory Systems 
Keep track of your steel inventory in Microsoft Access. You can catalog forms and types, such as bars, pipes, sheets and rods, as well as other characteristics, including the weights, pieces and locations where your inventory is stored. This relational database software gives you the ability to produce a variety of custom reports to help you track and manage your steel inventory. Access is compatible with other Microsoft Office applications, and best of all, you can download and use a free template to get started right away.
 Absolute Dates Vs. ISO 
Software systems use date and time stamps for everything from recording a file&apos;s revision history to telling a forum&apos;s visitors when a contributor made a post. Depending on the purpose the time stamp will serve on the system, developers have several options how to format date and time data. This includes using specific, or absolute, dates formatted with standards from the International Organization for Standardization (ISO).
 Magic ISO Mode 1 Vs. Mode 2 
When burning a disc in Magic ISO, one of the options is burning in&quot;Mode 1&quot;or&quot;Mode 2.&quot;These options are set up mostly for older disc readers, because any modern computer will have no issue reading any mode. Understanding the different modes will help you learn about the burning process and use for each one.
 What Is the Purpose of the Command Interpreter? 
A command interpreter is a computer program that accepts textual commands interactively, from the keyboard; or reads them from a file, and executes them. The purpose of a command interpreter is therefore to execute commands, such as setting dynamic variables that contain information about the environment of the system, known as“environment variables,”or to load and execute other files.
 How to Make Quality Assurance Effective 
You can make quality assurance effective in a wide variety of different ways. Make quality assurance effective with help from a small business owner and active advocate for the small business community in this free video clip.
 What Is Sap R2? 
SAP R/2 is an enterprise resource-planning software application. SAP AG, a German software developer, originally released this real time data-processing software in 1979 as a follow-up to its materials management product, RM/1. A little more than a decade later in 1992, the company replaced the SAP R/2 application with the updated SAP R/3 application. SAP AG no longer supports the SAP R/2.
 What Is a Soft Appliance? 
Living languages, such as English, evolve as speakers adopt and adapt old words to new uses. Nouns like&quot;priority&quot;and&quot;impact&quot;become the verb“prioritize”or adjective“impactful”and appear in dictionaries within a decade. Compound words, such as“soft appliance,”combine existing words to describe new products or concepts.
 What Is the Siemens HMI? 
A Human Machine Interface simplifies complex processes in manufacturing, warehousing, logistics and other businesses. The Siemens HMI integrates hardware and software in automation systems for different industries and helps to make these systems more efficient. A visualization HMI system gives the user instant access to relevant information, allowing the user to take appropriate action. Each HMI system is customized to meet the demands of a specific business and includes considerations such as size, capacity and output.
 How to Rename Inventory Adjustment Values in QuickBooks POS 
If you made a mistake while performing an inventory adjustment in QuickBooks Point of Sale, you can correct it by assigning the correct value to the adjustment type. Two types of inventory adjustments can be done in QuickBooks POS: cost or quantity adjustments. If you made an error, you can assign the correct adjustment name to an inventory item in QuickBooks POS by following a specific procedure.
 What Is a Profile in SAP? 
SAP is a suite of administrative and financial software from German company SAP AG. SAP is an acronym for Systems, Applications and Products; the suite is divided into individual modules that represent job functions within an organization. Access to each module is controlled by a text file containing configuration settings, otherwise known as a profile.
 Visual Network Analysis 
As network traffic continues to increase, analysts need to better understand network data to service and secure networks. Analysts examine network data using words, numbers and graphs, and new methods for displaying the data make it easier for the analysts to visualize and interpret the data. Additionally, knowledge compression through visualization helps to make the data more accessible and easier to retain, as the brain interprets visual data differently than other types of data.
 What is the Procedure to Get ISO 28000? 
ISO 28000 is a specification by the International Organization for Standardization regarding security management systems. In particular, it lists the requirements for establishing, maintaining, operating and reviewing a Supply Chain Security Management System, or SCSMS. The procedure for obtaining certification is complex and time-consuming.
 Process Mapping Software for a Mac 
Processing mapping software is designed to make planning and project management easier by providing users with access to customized digital flow charts, diagrams and analysis tools. Some process mapping software titles for Macintosh computers are Web-based, while others run off your Mac&apos;s hard drive.
 What Is SCM, ERP and MRP? 
Businesses generate information in their regular operations. This data must be collected, because it can be used in various business processes. For example, when you write an invoice, you need to know what sales were made. The sales invoice needs to tie in with the sales order and deliveries. Rather than keeping important business information on paper or in separate packages, application software aims to tie together the inputs and outputs of business processes. This need created the concepts of SCM, ERP and MRP.
 Can I Track Inventory in Quicken Home&amp;Business? 
Quicken Home and Business is financial software that is aimed at individuals with home businesses who want to track both their personal and business finances. The program provides a number of tools that make it easier to keep track of how your business is doing. However, if you&apos;re looking for business inventory tracking, this is not the program for you.
 RFID Technology Disadvantages and Alternatives 
RFID technology uses radio transmissions for inventory management. When someone scans an RFID tag with a reader, she sends radio signals to the tag to decode the item information stored within the tag&apos;s computer chip. The chip then reflects the signal, returning the item information to the reader. While RFID systems have been widely adopted by major retailers, their drawbacks and vulnerabilities may make alternative inventory management systems more attractive to end users.
 What Is a Dataset in Coding? 
Websites and desktop computing applications model data in varied ways. Databases and XML files are among the most common options for storing data. A dataset is a data collection. Data sources such as databases and XML markup files store datasets. When an application needs to retrieve data from a data source, it queries it for a specific set of data. Once a program or script has a dataset, it can process and display it to the user.
 SOP for Safety 
Many types of organizations, from research institutions to manufacturing companies, safely deal with biological hazards, radioactive materials and powerful machinery because they have good management practices in place. One of these practices involves the use of Standard Operating Procedures, or SOPs. These documents explain in detail how to use a piece of equipment, dispose of hazardous chemicals or handle injuries.
 The Swedish ISO Code 
If you&apos;ve ever sent or received a letter from overseas, sent an international email or even traveled abroad, then you&apos;ve already used an ISO country code. The International Organization for Standardization, abbreviated and standardized itself as ISO, assigns two-letter codes to nations to streamline everything from Internet use to passport assignment.
 About ISO Code CL 
ISO Code CL may on first glance look like a secret code straight out of a spy movie. But you actually use this code -- and hundreds of others like it -- on a regular basis. In fact, if you&apos;ve ever sent a letter overseas, sent an email to a recipient in a different country or used a passport or foreign currency when traveling abroad, then you&apos;ve already use an ISO code without even realizing it.
 How to Reset the ISO Producer Configuration 
ISO Producer is a CD/DVD image utility that lets you make an image file (ISO) from a disc. The program does not come with an installer package; instead, it runs directly out of its own folder, which includes the necessary DLL file. To reset the ISO Producer configuration options you&apos;ll need to delete the program and download it again.
 Salary for a Level III Program Manager 
Level III program managers are senior program managers who work in a variety of industries. They have worked their way up to the senior classification by managing programs, departments or projects for many years with consistent success. Required skills include leadership, scheduling, delegating, organizing and analyzing. Salaries for the position vary widely by industry and experience, though senior program managers can expect to earn salaries similar to that of middle to upper management.
 Is a Physical Count of Inventory Needed With a Perpetual Inventory? 
Perpetual inventory requires a few specific things that you may not be completely used to. Learn whether a physical count of inventory is needed with a perpetual inventory with help from an accomplished consultant, financier, and marketing expert in this free video clip.
 What Is a Redemption Period for a Purchaser? 
When the bank forecloses on a home, it may sell the home for a price beneath its fair market value. However, if you purchase a foreclosed home, it&apos;s important to be aware that its previous owner is typically entitled to a redemption period during which he retains certain rights to the property and may be able to reverse the sale.
 What Is an AVR Microcontroller? 
Many modern devices contain small computers that regulate their activity. These tiny computers, known as microcontrollers, pack all the capabilities of a simple computer into a miniature package. AVR microcontrollers are a proprietary line that is produced by the Atmel Corporation for a wide range of uses.
 What Are the Benefits of Introducing ERP? 
Enterprise Resource Planning, or ERP for short, refers to any software system that integrates and controls all the business processes in an organization. The benefits that ERP brings to an organization are both tangible, such as cost reduction, which directly influences a business&apos;s net profit or loss, and intangible, such as improved customer satisfaction, which is less quantifiable.
 The First Stages of Tendering 
Businesses that make a good first impression increase their chances of winning contract-awards. The tendering process is an important part of many government projects. Government or public projects have a strict set of rules to follow that vary with each region. Competitive tendering requires a full understanding of the project’s rules and guidelines for compliance. Tenders that do not comply may be immediately disqualified. Submissions that initially qualify will be scrutinized against the proposed parameters and may be invited to continue the tendering process.
 Salary of a Junior Achievement Program Manager 
A junior achievement program manager position provides benefits that go beyond salary. Your commitment to helping young people succeed will be rewarding. Salaries for this position fall in line with the mean hourly wages for all positions tracked by the Bureau of Labor Statistics. It offers a comfortable living for people who are motivated and have strong personal skills. A person in this position often plays several roles that make planning and multi-tasking a part of your typical workday.
 How to Keep an Accurate Inventory in a Distribution Center 
The benefits of inventory accuracy include prioritizing purchasing, keeping track of what sells versus what doesn&apos;t, balancing financial books at the end of every business quarter and reducing operating costs by avoiding having to recount unorganized inventory. Certain steps can be taken to keep an accurate inventory in your distribution center.
 How to Make a Multiboot ISO With GRUB 
With the GRUB bootloader for Linux, you can create a multiboot system on a USB Flash drive. To save space on the Flash drive, configure GRUB to boot the operating systems from your LiveCD ISO images. Unlike multiboot hard disks, you will need to use a Flash drive with only one partition.
 How to Sync QuickBooks Database Inventory 
Intuit QuickBooks (version 2009 and up) has a useful feature called“Intuit Sync Manager”that is designed to help you sync your company’s database or inventory file with the Intuit online service. After it has been synced, you will be able to access it from your Intuit account on their Web site. For the QuickBooks database to sync properly however, you need to make sure your version of QuickBooks has the most recent update installed.
 How to Check Your Inventory in ROBLOX 
In the online world-building game ROBLOX, users can customize their own social world by building virtual spaces from the ground up, or by expanding upon core templates with themes such as fantasy and sports. Players can also create avatars with a variety of clothing items and character models. Essential to managing the vast number of places, gear and characters available is My Stuff, a personalized inventory of everything you&apos;ve used and collected.
 How to Improve the Microphone Quality on a Pioneer FH-P8000BT 
You can improve the quality of the microphone input on our Pioneer FH-P8000BT car stereo when using it with the Bluetooth connection on your phone. The FH-P8000BT is designed to function as a hands-free Bluetooth calling option, using the vehicle&apos;s speakers and its integrated microphone. However, the feedback between the speakers and the microphone can cause an echo-effect that adversely affects call quality. The Pioneer settings allow you to enable echo canceling and noise reduction to improve the microphone quality.
 Can WD TV Live Play an ISO? 
Converting a DVD disc of your favorite movie or TV show to an ISO file is one way to view the content without having to insert the disc into a DVD player. After you’ve ripped the ISO file from the original disc to your computer, you can transfer it to your WD TV Live Media Player for viewing on your TV set.
 ISO vs. BIN 
ISO and BIN are two common formats for storing disc images, or virtual copies of optical media such as CD-ROMs and DVDs. Both types of files are useful for backing up CDs and DVDs on your computer in case the physical disc is damaged or lost. The BIN file extension is also used for other types of binary files.
 How to Add an ISO to DevHook 
You can use DevHook on your Playstation Portable gaming device to play backed-up copies of the games you&apos;ve purchased. To protect the discs on which the games are saved, you can create an image of the disc, called an ISO, which can then be played on your PSP. Note that it is illegal to download games that you do not own. DevHook should only be used for playing copies of your own games.
 Network Inventory and Tracking 
When running a business, learning how to track inventory correctly could be the difference between making a profit and struggling to get by. Using the right type of software can track inventory over a potentially large network of warehouses or shipping centers. By tracking inventory more effectively, you can allocate fewer resources to inventory and save more money for other things.
 Which Is Better: ISO or CSO? 
When working with image files, finding the right type of file to work with can make a difference in the quality of the image displayed. The ISO file is a type of image file that is commonly used with pictures and video games. CSO file are often compared with ISO files, although they are not the same.
 How to Revert an ECM to ISO 
The Error Code Modeler, or ECM, format stores disc images by removing redundant code, thereby reducing the file size so the disc images are easier to store and compress. ISO is a very common format for storing disc images, or electronic copies of physical discs. An ECM file created from an ISO disc image will contain&quot;.iso&quot;in the file name before the ECM file extension. You can revert the ECM back to ISO format using unecm.exe.
 What Is an ISO Programmer? 
The ISO -- the International Organization for Standardization -- has developed more than 18,500 standards for various subjects, including for the C programming language. The ISO adopted its standards for C in 1999 and has updated them several times since. An ISO programmer is one who knows and follows ISO standards for C.
 Ping Alternatives 
Ping is a troubleshooting utility for IP networks and is typically used for testing the basic connection from one network device to another. Ping sends a small packet of information and waits for a reply. If the reply does not come back within the allotted time, the ping utility issues a timeout error message. While ping is basic and is included on virtually all computers, there are alternatives to this very useful tool.
 
 
Narrow Your Selection

 Purchasing Management Information Systems ISO Inventory Supply Chain Management Inventory Control Production Planning Standard Operating Procedures Miscellaneous Operations Management Program Management Inventory Systems Process Improvement Business Information Technology ISO 9001 Industrial Relations Quality Management Systems Process Mapping ISO Certification Inventory Accounting Create Flow Charts Business Purchasing Purchasing Agreements Quality Control Tools ISO 9000 Quality Management Information Management ERP Request for Proposals Quality Assurance Process Flow Inventory Management Supply Chain Purchasing Departments Continuous Quality Improvement Procurement Electronic Records Management Systems UPC Bar Codes Due Diligence Reports Statistical Process Control ERP System Operations Management Tools ERP Implementation RFID POS Systems Due Diligence Checklists Measure Quality Process Capability Track Inventory Document Retention Quality Audits Facilities Management SOPs Business Procurement Systems Contract Administration CRM Tools Inventory Turnover Enterprise Resource Planning Quality Assessment Industrial Psychology Quality Metrics ERP Software Visitor Management ERP Training 
 ehow.com 
 About eHow eHow Blog How to by Topic How to Videos Sitemap 
 
Copyright©1999-2012 Demand Media, Inc.
Use of this web site constitutes acceptance of the eHow Terms of Use and Privacy Policy . Ad Choices en-US
	</body>
</document>
