<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001473" url="http://www.chicagonow.com/good-bad-parents/2012/04/mcdonalds-isnt-making-your-kid-fat-but-maybe-you-are/" time="2012-07-12-17:14" support="3" score="0.002048206737829671" bingtitle="McDonald&apos;s isn&apos;t making your kid fat, but maybe you are! | Good ..." webtitle="McDonalds isnt making your kid fat, but maybe you are! | Good and Bad Parents">
			<query id="000851" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="000867" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="001058" bing-rank="220"/>
	<description>... Happy Meal, pulled out your wallet, paid the cashier and you handed your child this meal ... is still cheaper to cook a meal at home than to eat at any fast food restaurant .</description>
	<body>
		Advertisement: 
 Good and Bad Parents 
 
 Home About 
 
McDonald&apos;s isn&apos;t making your kid fat, but maybe you are!
 14 comments Tweet By Tracy A. Stanciel ,
 April 13, 2012 at 7:46 am 
McDonald&apos;s has become the whipping boy for people who are complaining about the childhood obesity epidemic.  They have been sued for making kids fat, misleading nutritional claims and most recently for including toys in their Happy Meals that make kids want to eat unhealthy food.  A California judge threw out the most recent lawsuit several days ago.

When are parents going to accept responsibility for their actions?  Are parents going to sue candy manufacturers because sugar from candy can cause children to get cavities and gain weight?  Parents seem to want to place the blame on everyone else instead of taking a look in the mirror.

Did McDonald&apos;s employees come to your house with guns and hold you at gun point while they force fed your child a Happy Meal?  Hell no!  You took your child to McDonald&apos;s, ordered his/her favorite Happy Meal, pulled out your wallet, paid the cashier and you handed your child this meal that you deem unhealthy.  You may have even watched your child eat the meal.  You, the parent of this child did all of these things on your own with only your child asking and you want to sue McDonald&apos;s!  WTF!  McDonald&apos;s should sue the plaintiffs for their legal fees for such a frivolous lawsuit.

As a parent, you have control over most, if not all of your child&apos;s food intake.  You decide how and when you spend your money.  If parents cave into their child&apos;s every whim for fast food and junk food, then they are responsible for their child being overweight. You can&apos;t blame the companies that make the food that you deem unhealthy if you make the choice to buy it.

Parents are responsible for the food that they purchase for their child.  Every time you are at the grocery store check out and you purchase a candy bar or a bag of chips, think about your responsibility.  When you order pizza instead of cooking a healthy meal, think about your responsibility.  Parents have a choice and they choose not to make it because they don&apos;t want to make their child unhappy.  Part of being a parent is making tough choices when it comes to your child&apos;s well being.  If you can&apos;t tell your child that he/she can&apos;t have an unhealthy meal, what are you going to do when real issues arise?

What would happen if certain businesses or agencies wanted to sue or punish parents for failing to properly parent their children?  Suppose the insurance companies started to pay claims related to weight issues at a lower rate if they knew that the child had an unhealthy diet?  What if our schools made parents sit in detention when their child misbehaved in school?  Suppose parents were given jail time if their child was a juvenile delinquent?  Turn around is fair play.  If parents continue to file frivolous lawsuits against businesses for things that they are responsible for, eventually someone is going to fight back.

Childhood obesity is a serious issue that needs to be addressed.  If you buy your child a Happy Meal, he/she won&apos;t be overweight due to the occasional indulgence.  There is plenty of blame and finger pointing to go around, it just needs to be pointed in the right direction.

Weakness as a parent is not a reason to sue McDonald&apos;s or any other company.
 
Filed under: Parenting 

Tags: Childhood Obesity , Happy Meal Lawsuit , Happy Meal Toys , Happy Meals , McDonald&apos;s , McDonald&apos;s Happy Meal Lawsuit , McDonald&apos;s Happy Meals , Obesity , Parenting 
 Tweet Advertisement: 
Comments
 Leave a comment 
 Aquinas wired said April 13, 2012 at 12:00 am 
Of course, parents ultimately are responsible for the well-being of their children. But you fail to take into account the enormous peer pressures that are exerted on the young via advertizing. When a fast-food company uses the public air waves to hawk its products, it has a public responsibility to offer healthy choices on its menu.
 Reply Sergio Robles said April 13, 2012 at 12:00 am In reply to Aquinas wired : 
your an idiot.
 Reply Hoss said April 14, 2012 at 12:00 am In reply to Sergio Robles : 
Uh, no, YOU&apos;RE the idiot. Not YOUR the idiot.

Remember your apostrophes Sergio? Obviously not.
 Reply teeay said April 13, 2012 at 12:00 am In reply to Aquinas wired : 
(1) Fast food companies, just like other companies, PAY to advertise, they&apos;re not getting free time on PBS.
(2) Fast food companies, just like other companies, have a responsibility to their shareholders or owners. Towards the public? They are responsible for following all current laws.
(3) No. N. O. it&apos;s a very simple word. You don&apos;t want your kid eating fast food? Learn it and use it.
 Reply Tracy A. Stanciel said April 13, 2012 at 12:00 am In reply to teeay : 
You are 100% correct! It seems like such a simple word, yet many parents have a hard time saying it.
 Reply Darryl said April 14, 2012 at 12:00 am In reply to Aquinas wired : 
sergio you beat me to it. Its up to the parent to say no. No matter how many yimes they ask. In that case lets sue the toy companies for all the ads they show on tv as well because kids nag their parents after seeing those commercials as well.
 Reply waggy said April 15, 2012 at 12:00 am In reply to Aquinas wired : 
You started off 100$ correct. It is parents who are responsible for the well-being of their children. that&apos;s it. nobody else&apos;s. Not McDonalds, not the goverment Not the school&apos;s. It&apos;s MY responsibility for the well-being of MY kids.

So when they ask for fast food? i tell them no. they beg they get in trouble. They are healthy and happy. I make sure they eat right and get plenty of exercise.

guess what? it&apos;s easy. Say &quot;NO&quot; and mean it. Back up the punishments if needed and use common sense.
 Reply Tracy A. Stanciel said April 13, 2012 at 12:00 am 
It&apos;s up to the parent to teach their child about peer pressure with regards to advertising as well as other aspects of life. In my opinion, Disney is one of the largest companies that target it&apos;s marketing to kids and I don&apos;t exactly like them either but it&apos;s my choice to buy their products.
 Reply Chef Jody said April 13, 2012 at 12:00 am 
I agree, we can not blame McDonalds for the obesity in this country. Since we are talking about the &apos;golden arches&quot;, may I suggest a little experiment for readers? I taught a Health class for middle school students. One month before the class was to start I purchased a burger, plain. I kept the burger in the bag on the counter, with the date and receipt taped to the bag. On the first day of class, the first question was, &quot;How many of you eat at McDonalds&apos;&quot;, as they all raised their hands. So I reach into my bag which was now 5 weeks old and much to my own suprise, it had not changed shape, no signs of mold, it was perfect. (Cold, but perfect shape and form). The children were very grossed out! I then asked, &quot;if this is what the burger did in a bag, what is it doing to our bodies?&quot;
I think as a parent today we are obligated to control what our children eats. My children ask everyday, can we go to McDonald&apos;s. I say no for the most part, but do allow every couple of months for a &apos;treat&apos;. Now they order chicken wraps. :o)
 Reply Tracy A. Stanciel said April 13, 2012 at 12:00 am In reply to Chef Jody : 
Chef Jody, thanks for sharing your experiment. I will definitely share it with my children. There are lots of unhealthy choices in terms of food that go well beyond McDonald&apos;s but parents need to understand that too much of anything can be bad for your health.
 Reply Expat in Chicago said April 13, 2012 at 12:00 am 
Obviously you&apos;re right that parents are responsible for the health and well-being of their children, but the real crime IMO is the alarmingly low price of junk food compared to healthier options. It should not be more expensive to buy fresh food, but it is. So when you have a family living on the breadline, with both parents (or just one parent) working two jobs and counting every penny, is it any wonder that they buy the biggest meal they can for the lowest amount?
 Reply Tracy A. Stanciel said April 13, 2012 at 12:00 am 
Expat, I agree with you about junk food being cheap. Its really a shame that a salad at McDonald&apos;s is more expensive than a burger. However, eating out is considered a luxury and McDonald&apos;s isn&apos;t so cheap anymore.
 Reply Douglas Burns said April 14, 2012 at 12:00 am 
Everyone seems to be making excuses for the lack of there responsibilities of tailing the time of cooking a heathy meal at home. When my children were young all fast food was considered a treat, or a reward.It is still cheaper to cook a meal at home than to eat at any fast food restaurant . Peer pressure is nothing more than another excuse for taking the easy way rather than accepting he responsibility of you raising your children instead of them raising you or you being in control instead of the children being in control.Parenting is hard ,if done right, and the the children don&apos;t love u any less and respect u a lot more if you do the right thing. So wake up and do the right thing ,if you are going to have children discipline is love if it is done right and the jails and courts would have room for the real criminals instead of the failures of lazy parents ,that aren&apos;t doing there job.
WAKE UP AMERICA AND PUT THE BLAME WHERE IT BELONGS .LOOK IN THE MIRROR FOR THE ANSWER.
 Reply Tracy A. Stanciel said April 14, 2012 at 12:00 am In reply to Douglas Burns : 
Douglas, I agree with you 100%. Too many parents want to take the easy way out when it comes to parenting. Parenting is a hard job and anyone who says that it&apos;s easy is either lying or not doing it correctly.
 Reply 
 
Leave a comment

You must be logged in to post a comment.
 
 
Welcome to the new ChicagoNow .

 Learn about the changes, browse our blogs, or
 join ChicagoNow .
 Sign in Pitch your idea Advertisement: 
 GOOD AND BAD PARENTS ON FACEBOOK 
 
 Subscribe By Email 
 
Enter your email address:

 
 
Delivered by FeedBurner 
 
 Meet The Blogger 
 
Tracy A. Stanciel

I live in Chicago with my husband and two daughters. My passion for parenting and education is what inspired me to start blogging. Parenting is an important responsibility that is not to be taken lightly. Unfortunately, too many people take it lightly so I have lots of things to blog about.
 
Good and Bad Parents Archives

 December 2011 – A Shout Out To The Good Parents December 2011 – Parents Need To Make Education A Priority December 2011 – People Who Should Not Be Parents December 2011 – The Season Of Giving December 2011 – Why do children have a sense of entitlement? January 2012 – Cheers to the divorced parents who put their children first! November 2011 – Halloween and the low class people it attracks November 2011 – Reducing A Twin Pregnancy To One? November 2011 – Should Mother&apos;s Be Held Responsible When Their Boyfriends Harm Their Children November 2011 – The Homework Debate November 2011 – When does parental involvement at school go from good to bad? October 2011–My Education Reform October 2011–Parents need to raise their children October 2011–Should schools change rules when too many kids break the rules? October 2011–What to do when your children don&apos;t get along? September 2011–Should new parents be required to take parenting classes? September 2011–Unruly tweens&amp;teens! How to set them straight September 2011 – Are you micro-parenting your child? 
 
 Monthly Archives 

 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 
 
 Latest on ChicagoNow 

 
 I&apos;ve got no strings to hold me down 
 from The Bad Diabetic by Patrick O&apos;Hara
posted today at 10:00 am 
 Will other rehabbed Red north stations look like Granville? 
 from CTA Tattler by Kevin O&apos;Neil
posted today at 10:00 am 
 Tee Shirt&amp;Koozie Order Cutoff Date: July 31st 
 from DA BEARS BLOG by Jeff Hughes
posted today at 9:54 am 
 American Women Use 30,000 Words Per Day 
 from Taking A Second Look by Jack Spatafora
posted today at 9:20 am 
 White Sox All-Star Break Report Card: Outfielders 
 from Art of the Pale Hose by Art Berke
posted today at 8:29 am 
 
 Related posts 
 From Lifestyle: Parenting » 
 
 The Supreme Court and its Jester » 
 Janet Dahl on Janet Dahl, et. al Posted June 27, 2012 at 8:28 pm 
 Budget Hearing Boos » 
 Alexander Russo on District 299: The Inside Scoop on CPS Posted today at 7:40 am 
 I&apos;ll show you my summer bag if you show me yours » 
 Caitlin Giles on Wee Windy City Posted July 6, 2012 at 9:27 pm 
 New Year’s Resolutions…In July? » 
 Lisa Witek on Ay Mama! Posted today at 1:47 am 
 A Letter to Katie&apos;s Birthmother » 
 Carrie Goldman on Portrait of an Adoption Posted Monday at 9:54 am 
 
 Related blogs 

 
 Janet Dahl, et. al 
 Life in the slow lane. 
 District 299: The Inside Scoop on CPS 
 News&amp;commentary on Chicago schools 
 Wee Windy City 
 Family-friendly activities in Chicago 
 Ay Mama! 
 Chicago mamas share the trials and tribulations of motherhood. 
 Portrait of an Adoption 
 Chicago artist Carrie Goldman paints a family portrait of adoption. 
 More from Lifestyle: Parenting 
 Read these ChicagoNow blogs 

 
 Twins Apart: The Soldier and the College Student 
 Just another ChicagoNow site 
 My goodbye to my soldier 
 
 Public Affairs with Jeff Berkowitz 
 National, state and local political commentary and video interviews. 
 Way better than tonight’s All Star game: Sen. Dan Duffy, who could face Lisa Madigan for Gov., on cable/web 
 
 Tales of Awkward 
 The societal paradigm we live in presents several moments of awkward. Unfortunately, the given rules don&apos;t account for these blunders and we&apos;re forced to fend for ourselves. 
 America’s awkward state of affairs 
 
 
 Featured on ChicagoNow 

 
 Rahm Emanuel: A severe case of ‘voter&apos;s remorse’? » 
 from Pimps, Preachers and Politicians by Kay S
reblogged today at 7:54 am 
 Jabari Parker narrows list, Illini isn&apos;t on it » 
 from Chicago Sideline Report by Brady Stiff
reblogged today at 7:52 am 
 New Year’s resolutions … in July? » 
 from Ay Mama! by Lisa Witek
reblogged today at 7:50 am 
 The lighter side of the Taste » 
 from What Kate Ate by Katy Kusek
reblogged today at 7:49 am 
 The biggest mommy lie:&quot;You CAN have it all!&quot; » 
 from Music Mom by Anne Kiplinger
reblogged today at 7:49 am 
 
 Read these ChicagoNow Bloggers 

 
pintotowncar
 from cinnamon twists : Scramble with Non-Friends 
Denise Williams
 from Uncommon Sense : Religion and Abortion 
Evan Moore
 from Fanning The Flames Since 1978 : If you are an adult and you don’t have an ID to vote you probably shouldn’t be voting 
 
 ChicagoNOW 
 About ChicagoNow • About Chicago Parking • FAQs • Advertise • Recent posts RSS • Privacy policy • Comment policy • Terms of service 
 ©2012 CTMG - A Chicago Tribune website - 
 Crafted by the News Apps team
	</body>
</document>
