<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001433" url="http://www.yumsugar.com/Do-Dont-Bringing-Outside-FoodDrink-Restaurant-2486464" time="2012-07-12-17:11" support="1" score="0.002058858601221137" bingtitle="Do or Don&apos;t: Bringing Outside Food/Drink Into a Restaurant" webtitle="Do or Dont: Bringing Outside Food/Drink Into a Restaurant">
			<query id="000223" bing-rank="3"/>
	<description>Do or Don&apos;t: Bringing Outside Food/Drink Into a Restaurant Do or Don&apos;t: Bringing ... Cooking Basics 17 10 Condiments You Should Stock in Your Pantry ; party planning 18 Direct a ...</description>
	<body>
		Don&apos;t Miss Our First Ever POPSUGAR Must Have Bag! Only 808 left . Join now to receive July&apos;s Summer must-have bag! 
 Front Page Entertainment 
 Celebrity Entertainment Sex&amp;Culture Happy 4th Birthday to Jet-Setting Toddlers Knox and Vivienne Jolie-Pitt 
 Style 
 Fashion Beauty CelebStyle Fashionologie ShopStyle STYL.MX 50 Summer Dresses Under $50 to Wear All Season Long 
 Living 
 Health Home Mom&amp;Kids Food Tech Money Pets Circle of Moms Taste the States: 50 Iconic American Foods From A to Z 
 PopSugar TV 
 Celebrity 01:48 Video: Would Channing Star in Fifty Shades? Yes! Latest on PopSugarTV PopSugar Rush I&apos;m a Huge Fan Specials The Buzz Celebrity Interviews Fashion 01:27 Nicole Richie Talks Summer Essentials — and Latest on FabSugarTV Fashion Week FabSugar Lookbook Currently Trending Fab How To Fab Flash Beauty 02:04 Karlie Kloss Reveals Her Supermodel Inspiration Latest on BellaSugarTV Bella Beauty Book Bella Secret Weapon Bella How To Bella Beauty Review Bella Beauty Beat Food 00:52 Make Tuna Tartare at Home With This Recipe From a Latest on YumSugarTV Get the Dish Yum How To Fitness 02:22 Jackie Warner&apos;s Prescription For a Killer Beach Latest on FitSugarTV Get the Bod Class FitSugar Fit How To Healthy Recipes Branded Content Meet Our Editors and Tell Us How You Stand Out! Latest Branded Content Starbucks Levi&apos;s New Balance Frye 
 Must Have 
 
 Shop 
 
 Sign In 
 To die for. 
 Recipes 
 Original Recipes Fast and Easy Breakfast Appetizers Soup Salads Sandwiches Dinner Vegetarian Baking Dessert Reader Recipes 
 Cooking Basics 
 Yum How-to Cooking Tips 
 Party Planning 
 Cocktails Wine Beer Edible Gifts Menus Party Planning 
 Food News 
 Celebrity Chefs Taste Test Savory Sights 
 Food Video 
 Latest Popular Get the Dish Yum How To 
 Summer 
 Taste the States: 50 Iconic American Foods From A to Z Fast and Easy Summer Dinners A Burger by Any Other Name: Touring McDonald&apos;s International Menu Options Summer Calls For No-Bake Desserts 10 Shore Food Specialties to Enjoy Now 
 More 
 Community Kitchen Goddess Super Special Occasion Savory Sights Celebrity Chefs Cocktails Edible Gifts Fast and Easy Grilling Halloween Holiday St Patrick&apos;s Day Sugar Community Vegetarian 
 
 
Do or Don&apos;t: Bringing Outside Food/Drink Into a Restaurant

Do or Don&apos;t: Bringing Outside Food/Drink Into a Restaurant
 
 Updated Nov 14 2008 - 6:14am · Posted Nov 11 2008 - 12:30pm by YumSugar · 61 comments 
 Poll · restaurants · New york times · dining out · Etiquette · ethics · Do or Don&apos;t · Frank Bruni 
Last week, New York Times critic Frank Bruni broached the question of whether it&apos;s kosher to bring outside food or drink into restaurants . I&apos;ve noticed at some places — most recently at a popular neighborhood coffeehouse — that a growing number of establishments have barred customers from bringing items (such as water) inside. Bruni cited an example of a friend getting turned away from brunch at a New York diner for arriving with a Starbucks coffee in hand, and argued in favor of the establishment. &quot;It strikes me as a measure of disrespect,&quot; he writes.

What are your thoughts on the issue? Is Bruni being too extreme when he calls it disrespectful behavior?
 Do or Don&apos;t: Bringing Outside Food/Drink Into a Restaurant Do. Everyone does it at the movies, so why not? Don&apos;t. I&apos;d never bring food into a restaurant that was from some other establishment. It depends on where you&apos;re going and what you&apos;re bringing. Other — see my comments below. Link Love 
 Ketchup on a hot dog: OK or not OK? — Kitchen Daily How a Damien Hirst painting wound up featured in a UK Burger King — Eater Why these 10 cookbooks still matter — Food52 Nine sexy bathrooms from restaurants across the nation — Zagat Watch Andy Warhol eat a Whopper — Grub Street NY Why cows in France are being fed red wine — Delish How PBS will celebrate Julia Child&apos;s 100th birthday — HuffPost Food 
 Join The Conversation: Sign Up / Log In powered by Please sign in to comment. Featured Partners 
 

 Nikki Reed&amp;Paul McDonald Get Affectionate at Twilight Afterparty » Jessica Biel Goofs Off with Jeremy Lin and Tim Tebow at the ESPYs » New Mom Pink Misses the Whiskey, Not the Cigarettes » Inside Katie Holmes&apos;s Life in New York City » 
 More News at PEOPLE.com 
 

 15 Ways Rice Krispie Treats Just Got Better » 20 Things To Do With Summer Peaches » Obscure Summer Produce You Should Be Eating » Food52: A Tomato Takeover: 8 Summer Tomato Recipes » 
 
 

 Yuji Ramen Closes at Kinfolk Studios, Will Frej Expand? » First Look: Soaked, Now Operating On the Rooftop of the Mondrian SoHo » Random Culinary Inventions: Kookn&apos; Kap » Off-the-Radar Eats: 5 Old-World Food Shops in Queens » 
 More News at Zagat You might also like 10 Shore Food Specialties to Enjoy Now 12 Days of Edible Gifts: Homemade Kahlua Watch George Clooney Show Off His Home Bar and Kitchen Spaghetti Aglio, Olio, e Peperoncino Hunger Games Roundup: Set Pictures, Mockingjay Products, Beauty Secrets, Party Decor, and More! Sponsored Links ShopStyle Headlines Top Brands 
 Topshop Three Dots Rachel Pally Dolce Vita  Lola Cruz SeaVees Velocity Art and Design J Brand Letarte Ecco  Ernest Jones Melissa Joy Manning 
 Top Searches 
 bra yellow handbag cocktail dress cropped jacket trench coats leather skirt purses tube top nail polish wedding shoes chloe dress tank 
 Check out ShopStyle Deals : Skinstore promo codes , ... 
 YumSugarTV 1 Make Tuna Tartare at Home With This Recipe From a Top Chef summer 2 Taste the States: 50 Iconic American Foods From A to Z Editor&apos;s Pick 3 Roasted Beet and Garlic Soup with Chèvre summer 4 A Burger by Any Other Name: Touring McDonald&apos;s International Menu Options Get the Dish 5 Get the Dish: California Pizza Kitchen&apos;s BBQ Chicken Pizza recipes 6 Summer Calls For No-Bake Desserts Cooking Basics 7 The Key to Perfectly Poached Eggs recipes 8 10 Shore Food Specialties to Enjoy Now Aspen Food And Wine 9 What Everyone Should Know About the Food&amp;Wine Classic in Aspen party planning 10 13 Eats That Bring the Ballpark to Your Living Room summer 11 The Secret to Perfect Grilled Vegetables summer 12 Mapping Regional US Cuisine With an American Food Atlas celebrity chefs 13 British Invasion: Our Favorite Chefs From the UK The Amazing Spider-Man 14 Watch The Amazing Spider-Man Premiere LIVE on POPSUGAR! taste test 15 Taste Test: Lay&apos;s Potato Chip Flavors From All Over the World party planning 16 7 Classic Wimbledon Drinks and Dishes to Celebrate the Final Cooking Basics 17 Love It or Leave It? 25 Controversial Foods dinner 18 Fast and Easy Summer Dinners party planning 19 Wedding Desserts to Try in Lieu of a Wedding Cake summer 20 Recipes We Tried (and Loved!) This June community 21 Fire Up the Grill! Your Best Grilling Snaps Yum How To 22 Enjoy Naked, Steamy Kale Cooking Basics 23 Rethink This Ingredient: 5 Mouthwatering Ways to Eat Spam recipes 24 Seasonal Soups to Reheat Throughout the Week 
 Top Stories 
More Sugar 
 
 

 Katie Holmes With Suri at Chelsea Piers Nicole Richie Impulse Collection Party Pictures Magic Mike European Premiere Pictures Jason Segel and Matilda Ledger Pictures 
 
 

 Why Stop Now Movie Trailer The Vampire Diaries Pictures of Ian Somerhalder as Damon Hot Actors in Uniforms The Bachelorette Final Two Contestants 
 
 

 Dwell on Design New Products 2012 Pictures Mad Men Decorating Tips Sofia Coppola Loft Photos Best Outdoor Fabrics by the Yard 
 
 

 Girls Ice Cream Birthday Party Rainy Day Activities For Kids Handprint and Footprint Crafts Outdoor Wooden Playhouses 
 
Sites We Love 
 
 

 WATCH: Nookie Does The Best Impression Of His Fellow 80 Plates Cheftestants » Marion Cunningham, Legendary Cook And Author, Dies At 90 » Your Morning Tweet: Best Humblebrag In The Business » Last Call: Wylie Dufresne Is A Cartoon Mad Scientist » 
 
 

 Nikki Reed&amp;Paul McDonald Get Affectionate at Twilight Afterparty » Jessica Biel Goofs Off with Jeremy Lin and Tim Tebow at the ESPYs » New Mom Pink Misses the Whiskey, Not the Cigarettes » Inside Katie Holmes&apos;s Life in New York City » 
 
 

 Yuji Ramen Closes at Kinfolk Studios, Will Frej Expand? » First Look: Soaked, Now Operating On the Rooftop of the Mondrian SoHo » Random Culinary Inventions: Kookn&apos; Kap » Off-the-Radar Eats: 5 Old-World Food Shops in Queens » 
 
 

 Jay Weston: DineLA Begins July 16th for 12 Days -- A Culinary Bonanza! » LOOK: Check Out This Sexy Bathroom » Andrew Kimbrell: Will Congress Let Monsanto Write Its Own Rules? » Want Fries With That? At Olympics, They Can Only Be From McDonald&apos;s » 
 ©2012 Sugar Inc. · Insanely Addictive™· PopSugar Home&amp;Family About · Advertising · Site Map · Contact · Terms · Privacy · Mobile Site
	</body>
</document>
