<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001463" url="http://www.holyjuan.com/2009/08/top-ten-worst-diets-ever_17.html" time="2012-07-12-17:14" support="2" score="0.0013536556872468346" bingtitle="HolyJuan: Top Ten Worst Diets Ever" webtitle="HolyJuan: Top Ten Worst Diets Ever">
			<query id="000078" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="000089" bing-rank="98"/>
	<description>Just try and open the fridge or drive to the fast food restaurant. ... How to Use the Automatic Soap Dispenser; I Got My Hair ... Soda Jerk; Dear Ray; Family Photo at the Office; For ...</description>
	<body>
		Top Ten Worst Diets Ever
 They say dieting is good, but not if you are on one of the following diets. I&apos;m no doctor, but I can tell you that this list is most definitely the top ten worst diets ever.

 The Cardboard and Butter Diet 
 
This is an extremely high fiber, high saturated fat diet. The butter helps the cardboard to go down. Helpful hint: buy an extra plunger.

 Tapeworm Diet 
With this diet, you ingest one pill which contains a tapeworm. Over time, you lose weight. And energy. When you are at the desired weight, take a second pill which, hopefully, kills the tapeworm.

 Deserted Island Diet 
With this diet, you only eat foods you would find on a deserted diet: sand, shell fish, seaweed and driftwood. It works for the people on Survivor... why not you?

 Salt Diet 
Eat anything and everything you want, as long as it is salt. Try Salt Pancakes or Salt Soup or Crunchy Sea Salt Nuggets with Salt Sauce. In a few days, if you can still see the scale, you&apos;ll notice significant weight loss.
 
U-Z Diet 
In this diet, you only eat foods that begin with the letters U and Z. Watch the weight disappear after eating Ziti glazed with Ugli Fruit and unleavened bread with sliced zucchini every day for a week.

 Sprinting Diet 
With this diet, you can only eat while doing wind sprints. As soon as you stop running, you must stop eating. NOTE: Thanksgiving stinks on this diet and gravy can cause 2nd degree burns.
 
Boxing Glove Diet 
 
This diet is easy: you can eat anything you want as long as you are wearing boxing gloves. Just try and open the fridge or drive to the fast food restaurant. Corn on the cob is really tough. Pudding is not so bad if you have a big vat of it.
 
Burnt Diet 
This is another of the &quot;eat anything you want&quot; diets. All you have to do is burn the food item until it is charred black , though and through. I do this already with most my cooking.
 
Backyard Diet 
Sticks and stones may break my bones, but they also make for a great diet. Eat only what you find in your yard. Gardens do not count, but weeds do. If you live in an apartment, go out to eat at the park. No digging through the trash cans.
 
Overeat Diet 
This diet is akin to catching your child smoking a cigar and locking them in a closet until they smoke a whole box. With the Overeat Diet, you attempt to stuff yourself with fatty and high calorie foods to make yourself sick of eating. Do this for eight or nine weeks straight and weight loss will be inevitable when you can&apos;t move to feed yourself. Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: bad diets , diet , diets , top 10 , Top Ten Lists 
2 comments:
 Anonymous
said... 
Repeting posts?
What, you lost it??
 12:28 PM Doug said... 
Yes. Back in 2005.
 1:00 PM 
 Post a Comment 
 


 
 Newer Post Older Post Home Subscribe to: Post Comments (Atom) 
Feed Me then E-mail Me or Catch me on Twitter
 Automatically be entertained via my RSS feed! 
 E-mail me at holyjuan@gmail.com 
 Do you like t-shirts? 
Follow me on Twitter: @holyjuan 
 
About Me
 HolyJuan Some names have been changed to protect the innocent. Others have been underlined and highlighted.©2006-2011 HolyJuan 
All Rights Reserved View my complete profile 
Followers
 
You have got to read these stories.
 
 How to Use the Automatic Soap Dispenser I Got My Hair Cut at the Black Barbershop Unemployed Stuff to Do List 10 Attributes of Really Lazy People I Can&apos;t Believe This Guy Is Kicking My Ass 
 
I owe these people money
 
 Tour Absurd - My new best friend! AmyD is one cool chick. Lia writes Lost Glove Found Miss Cellania knows funny Kristen beats me at Scrabble Steve Whitt is a lot smarter than me Chris&apos; stuff Bits and Pieces Dustin is funny and usually naked Steph is my West Coast photography connection Contemporary Insanity Look at this... A ton of links to interesting stuff Feed the Girl You&apos;ve Got Smail 
 
Blog Archive
 
 ►  2012 (30) 
 ►  July (2) 
 Sick of Political Ads? New device can block comme... Not for Individual Sale 
 

 ►  June (6) 
 The Real Back to the Future, Future Date Turn down the refrigerator temperature, HAL. How The Frack do I do the Turing Google Doodle? No Touch Flush A Third Scenario Clancy&apos;s 
 

 ►  May (5) 
 The Friend Tiers Don&apos;t ever... Neighborhood Sign Feud The Rich Man and the Eye of the Needle The Bird Cage 
 

 ►  April (8) 
 A Question of Odds The Mountain The Mountain (Coming Soon) Jesus exits the tomb Rabid Egg Churches Running Out of Clever Sign Slogans Bent Pipe is Sad The Problem with Living on Kitty Drive 
 

 ►  March (3) 
 College Pranks The Lumberjack Local Man Discouraged his Ron Paul 2012 Sign Still... 
 

 ►  February (3) 
 The Somewhat Reverse Gift of the Magi Things I Have Learned as a Husband Lake Erie to be renamed Lake Ohio 
 

 ►  January (3) 
 It begins with a lie and ends with a lie Removing MyWebSearch from Firefox Where did you lose your virginity? 
 
 

 ►  2011 (77) 
 ►  December (7) 
 Soda Jerk Dear Ray Family Photo at the Office For the Motorcycle Enthusiast Feed the Pets Velveeta’s Mix 08/2002 The REAL 13 Things Your Pizza Guy Won’t Tell You 
 

 ►  November (4) 
 Save Money on Nasal Rinse! Thanks, Ray. Fake Dispatch Is Killing HolyJuan Hairs Did 
 

 ►  October (3) 
 The One Ring You go ahead. I don&apos;t have to pee anymore. Jesus as a Child 
 

 ►  September (5) 
 Boots The Rock and Roll Hall of Fame has Competition Hotel Electricity No carry on Bathroom Sign 
 

 ►  August (3) 
 Star Wars Fan? 
 

 ►  July (2) 

 ►  June (8) 

 ►  May (5) 

 ►  April (11) 

 ►  March (11) 

 ►  February (8) 

 ►  January (10) 
 

 ►  2010 (240) 
 ►  December (19) 

 ►  November (13) 

 ►  October (22) 

 ►  September (23) 

 ►  August (27) 

 ►  July (23) 

 ►  June (15) 

 ►  May (14) 

 ►  April (19) 

 ►  March (20) 

 ►  February (21) 

 ►  January (24) 
 

 ▼  2009 (322) 
 ►  December (35) 

 ►  November (19) 

 ►  October (16) 

 ►  September (16) 

 ▼  August (24) 
 Sarah and Josh&apos;s Reception: The Photo Booth How to cut a sandwich What Twitter is actually good for Like Father, Like Son Editorial Fail The Baconizer HolyJuan Eats: Dirty Franks Does this mean the internet will be down? Top Ten Worst Diets Ever We miss Meshell Top Ten Worst Diets Ever Stick People Sex WOW! really likes its customers (even the ones tha... Why, Thank You and Why Thank You I played chicken with WOW! and something amazing h... What No One Tells You About Moving I had a vasectomy today A good three person card game The Whistler at Work Flotation Device Greg Interviews Ann Douchebag Jackson Pollock Venn Diagram My First Beer Bong 
 

 ►  July (27) 

 ►  June (34) 

 ►  May (17) 

 ►  April (23) 

 ►  March (34) 

 ►  February (38) 

 ►  January (39) 
 

 ►  2008 (395) 
 ►  December (28) 

 ►  November (27) 

 ►  October (25) 

 ►  September (22) 

 ►  August (35) 

 ►  July (23) 

 ►  June (26) 

 ►  May (40) 

 ►  April (30) 

 ►  March (53) 

 ►  February (47) 

 ►  January (39) 
 

 ►  2007 (255) 
 ►  December (24) 

 ►  November (25) 

 ►  October (31) 

 ►  September (21) 

 ►  August (26) 

 ►  July (19) 

 ►  June (27) 

 ►  May (23) 

 ►  April (15) 

 ►  March (14) 

 ►  February (17) 

 ►  January (13) 
 

 ►  2006 (124) 
 ►  December (17) 

 ►  November (14) 

 ►  October (14) 

 ►  September (13) 

 ►  August (16) 

 ►  July (10) 

 ►  June (6) 

 ►  May (6) 

 ►  April (4) 

 ►  March (9) 

 ►  February (9) 

 ►  January (6) 
 
 
Labels
 comic (85) Jesus (59) Greg (47) Ask HolyJuan (38) sarah palin (25) Greg and Dad (22) Ohio University (22) photo (19) Erik Eats (18) t-shirt (16) skreened (15) twitter (14) Ohio (13) Ohio State (13) Skully&apos;s (13) miss sally (12) Margot and the Nuclear So and So’s (10) Star Wars (10) sex (10) relationships (9) tips (9) Chicago (8) work (8) Shorty (7) math (7) reddit (7) scam (7) President Bush (6) WoW (6) scam bait (6) thank you (6) Michigan (5) beer (5) goodbye (5) michelle (5) pic (5) secret (5) top 10 (5) Egotistical Bastard (4) Ketchikan (4) Noah (4) Palmerfest (4) Predictions (4) license plate (4) love (4) movies (4) soccer (4) time travel (4) Stephanie (3) Stuart Hyatt (3) Subway Seat for 3 (3) lazy (3) mom (3) money (3) steve (3) ten things (3) two-sack (3) Jerk It (2) Randy Pausch (2) The Church of Scientology (2) Bed and Breakfast (1) Stephen Whitt (1) 
HolyJuan Disclosure Policy
 http://www.holyjuan.com/2009/10/holyjuan-disclosure-policy.html 
 
 google3ca463ac79492d4a.html 
 
 Simple template. Powered by Blogger .
	</body>
</document>
