<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001066" url="http://www.gizmag.com/statin-drugs-at-fast-food-restaurant/17701/" time="2012-07-12-16:29" support="23" score="0.050151888804949224" bingtitle="Would you like statins with that burger? - Gizmag | New and ..." webtitle="Would you like statins with that burger?">
			<query id="000286" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000573" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="000034" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="001020" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="000576" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="000592" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000849" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000010" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000030" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000362" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="000061" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="000024" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="000223" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="000749" bing-rank="242"/>
			<query id="000586" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="000566" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000723" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000013" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000300" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000374" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="000018" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000563" bing-rank="152"/>
			<query id="001006" bing-rank="139"/>
	<description>&quot;It&apos;s ironic that people are free to take as many unhealthy condiments in fast food ... Just enter your friends and your email address into the form below. For multiple ...</description>
	<body>
		Gizmag&apos;s YouTube Channel Follow Gizmag on Twitter Explore Gizmag Subscribe 
 Write for Gizmag 
 

 Stalker UAS flight time improved by 2,400 percent using laser beams Freeheel Runningpads literally leave you (half) barefoot Sign language-to-speech translating gloves take out Microsoft Imagine Cup 2012 Ultra-efficient 4,000 mph vacuum-tube trains – why aren&apos;t they being built? Rolls-Royce unveils 150,000-part LEGO jet engine 
 MORE TOP STORIES» HEALTH AND WELLBEING 
Would you like statins with that burger?
 
By Dr. Jaroslav Boublik 

 16:57 January 27, 2011 
 
 12 Comments 


 Tweet 
Should cholesterol reducing drugs be served with fast food? (Photo: Suat Eman via freedigitalphotos.net)
 
A study from researchers at Imperial College London seriously suggests that it may be wise for fast food outlets to provide statin drugs free of charge with the condiments, so that customers can neutralize the heart disease dangers of fatty food. Statins are a class of drugs that can reduce the amount of &quot;LDL&quot; cholesterol in the blood. Some data suggests that this reduction is accompanied by a reduced risk of cardiovascular disease including heart attack and stroke.

Dr Darrel Francis and colleagues state in their paper published in the American Journal of Cardiology , that the reduction in cardiovascular risk offered by a statin would be enough to offset the increase in heart attack risk from eating a cheeseburger and a milkshake.

Dr Francis, who is from the National Heart and Lung Institute at Imperial College London, is the senior author of the study.

&quot;Statins don&apos;t cut out all of the unhealthy effects of burgers and fries,&quot; said Dr Francis. &quot;It&apos;s better to avoid fatty food altogether. But we&apos;ve worked out that in terms of your likelihood of having a heart attack, taking a statin can reduce your risk to more or less the same degree as a fast food meal increases it.&quot;

Simvastatin, one of this popular class of drugs, is already available in the UK at low doses (10mg) without a prescription, over the counter at pharmacies. Other statins are, so far, only available by prescription due, in part, because of possible side effects and drug interactions which must be assessed prior to use. However, the cost of these drugs has fallen sharply in recent years from approximately £40 (US$60) per month to around £1.50 (US$2.50) per month in the UK.

&quot;It&apos;s ironic that people are free to take as many unhealthy condiments in fast food outlets as they like, but statins, which are beneficial to heart health, have to be prescribed,&quot; said Dr Francis. “Everybody knows that fast food is bad for you, but people continue to eat it because it tastes good. We&apos;re genetically programmed to prefer high-calorie foods, and sadly fast food chains will continue to sell unhealthy foods because it earns them a living.”

The National Heart and Lung Institute researchers note that studies need to be conducted to assess the potential risks of allowing people to take statins freely, without medical supervision or prescription. They further recommend a warning on packets of the drug emphasizing that no tablet can substitute for a healthy diet, and advising people to consult their doctor for dietary advice.

“Statins have among the best safety profiles of any medication” according to the Imperial College release , but a review of several papers on statins suggest this is not quite true. At the very least the suggestion that statins should be freely available, and so possibly ingested by those who’s blood lipid profiles would not be improved by their use, with the possible and sometimes serious side effects that accompany their use, is pretty questionable public health policy.
 Share Tweet Tags 
 »  Drugs »  Food »  Heart Disease »  Imperial College 
 User Comments (12)   
Please tell me every one knows this is SO WRONG!
 mrhuckfin - January 27, 2011 @ 08:11 pm PST 
That last paragraph needed to be expanded on and emphasized...and at least located in the middle of the article.
 Racqia Dvorak - January 28, 2011 @ 04:57 am PST 
And would you like some chemotherapy with your cigarettes?
 David Alden - January 28, 2011 @ 05:27 am PST 
Our society is SO bizarre. If the option of eating less is off the table (probably because there&apos;s no room on the table, given the increase in portion size), how about adding healthy natural condiment instead of pharmaceuticals? Virtually all nuts, even peanuts, have statin-like properties. How about serving a small handful of nuts with that burger? Maybe even formulating burgers with some ground nuts in the mix?



A nutty idea? Of course!
 Loving It All - January 28, 2011 @ 06:02 am PST 
Get real! This is about the sickest article I&apos;ve ever read on Gizmag. Increase the drugs in your system so that you can continue eating unhealthily? Total madness.



In the US, the number of ads for the drug cartels is increasing dramatically. (I&apos;ve noticed, too, that the time taken on the commercials to list all the contraindications of a drug - up to and including death - has now increased to almost 2/3s of the ad!) Interestingly, so are the ads for attorneys seeking clients who have been seriously damaged or killed by some &quot;safe&quot; drug. Unless in a life threatening situation or continuing pain, the body is heavily damaged by drug use, as is the brain. Humans were not designed for drug use, despite what the medical industry would like to convince us!
 TheRogue1000 - January 28, 2011 @ 06:58 am PST 
That&apos;s just funny. Unless someone takes it seriously.
 Daniel Vulikh - January 28, 2011 @ 08:29 am PST 
Thank goodness for the last paragraph! Otherwise, the proposal itself is an outrage and a totally arrogant big-Pharma insult! These bastards won&apos;t rest until the whole world is popping their poisons.



It is at least heartening (npi) to see the posts.
 Swami Poindexter - January 28, 2011 @ 08:29 am PST 
1. Statins have side effects. Medical policy wonks see more risks than benefits in giving statins to low risk folks. The liver testing alone would be stunningly expensive.



2. The next problem is the predictive validity of saturated fat and various cholesterol subfractions. If you look at the Stanford A-Z Study, folks on the Atkins diet had twice the positive health markers than other diets.



 http://jama.ama-assn.org/content/297/9/969.abstract 



 http://nutrition.stanford.edu/documents/AZ_press.pdf 




 





 




3. There may be other things going on. Fast food places may be injecting substances in burgers to keep them moist while they&apos;re sitting (did you think that burger was magically cooked in 30 seconds from frozen solid?) and high-heat cooking may be creating HCAs, etc.



4. The best counter-measures may be reviewing the entire process to include the buns. Again, the Stanford data says the high carb bun is causing damage. Then look at the heirloom wheat vice todays wheat research. So, maybe a thinner, 100% whole grain bun with vegetables in it might be healthier (more antioxidants, nutrients, fiber, etc.).
 cwolf88 - January 28, 2011 @ 08:31 am PST 
My health care providers put me on statins and they nearly killed me. I only began to feel better when I changed up my diet. Eat healthy, stay healthy!
 YukonJack - January 28, 2011 @ 08:37 am PST 
oh shit!
 Donnakelli Maddencox - January 28, 2011 @ 11:15 am PST 
&quot;Everybody knows fast food is bad&apos;? That would depend on the fast food. Just because it is fast does not mean it is bad. McDonald&apos;s offers salads and yogurt drinks as alternatives. Boston Market has rotesarie chicken and vegetable side dishes.
 BigWarpGuy - January 28, 2011 @ 06:01 pm PST 
&quot;Dr Orli Etingin, vice chair of medicine at New York Presbyterian Hospital, is quoted as saying that atorvastatin, the best-selling drug on the market, &quot;makes women stupid.&quot; Etingin told the Journal that 24 of her female patients taking atorvastatin lost the ability to concentrate or recall words. &quot;




 Adrian Akau - January 29, 2011 @ 02:49 pm PST Post a Comment 
 Login with your gizmag account: 


 Email 

 Password 
 Register here     Forgotten your password? 
Or Login with Facebook: 

 
 Related Articles Cost to treat heart disease in United States could triple by 2030 Credit card-sized device tests for heart disease using less than a drop of blood 4D heart imaging could have far-reaching effects for patients Cell reprogramming breakthrough could mend broken hearts Compostable plastics breakthrough sounds sweet Imagine that: Study shows that thinking about eating can reduce food consumption Email this article to a friend 
 Just enter your friends and your email address into the form below 

 For multiple addresses, separate each with a comma 
 Your Email 
 Friends Email 
 

Privacy is safe with us because we have a strict privacy policy .
 Looking for something? Search our 18,678 articles Sections 
 Aero Gizmo Architecture Around The Home Automotive Baby Gizmo Childsplay Digital Cameras ecoGizmo Electronics Games Good Thinking Health and Wellbeing Holiday Destinations Home Entertainment Inventors and Remarkable People Laptops Military Mobile Technology Motorcycles Music On the Water Outdoors Personal Computing Pet Gizmos Podcasts Research Watch Robotics Science and Education Sports Spy Gear Telecommunications Urban Transport Wearable Electronics 
 Recent popular articles in Health and Wellbeing 
 Focal Locus workstation splits the difference between sitting and standing Chapul to launch world&apos;s first cricket snack bar Israeli company grows medical marijuana which doesn&apos;t get you high Oxygen microcapsules could save lives when patients can&apos;t breathe IBM Research produces bacteria-killing &quot;ninja polymers” Brazilian researchers develop new anti-inflammatory for severe pain Easter Island drug improves learning and memory in mice of all ages Synthetic protein kick-starts the immune system to prevent all strains of the flu Cancer treatment that blocks cellular “protein factories” set to begin clinical trials Portable cooling vests could save cardiac arrest victims from brain damage 
 Most Popular Articles 
 Today Last week All time 
 
 Ultra-efficient 4,000 mph vacuum-tube trains – why aren&apos;t they being built? Garmin&apos;s first outdoor GPS watch includes advanced navigation features Stalker UAS flight time improved by 2,400 percent using laser beams Lockheed Martin and OPT team up on Australian 19 MW wave energy project DARPA crowdsourcing tank design to speed up heavy weapons development Yatoo concept turns your car into a camper with a tent, kitchen and bed Rolls-Royce unveils 150,000-part LEGO jet engine A 100 percent solar-powered boat that cost under $3,000 to build! Freeheel Runningpads literally leave you (half) barefoot Palacio de Sal hotel built entirely of salt 
 

 

 Most Commented Articles 
 Today Last week All time 
 

 
 Ultra-efficient 4,000 mph vacuum-tube trains – why aren&apos;t they being built? (64) Will Microsoft redefine the industry with Windows 8 and the Surface Pro? (21) Stanford scientists give new life to Thomas Edison&apos;s nickel-iron battery (17) Cost-effective solar power module could also serve as an eco-friendly furnace (15) All-limb-drive bicycling with Raxibo (14) 18 year-old electrical engineering student wows with levitating light (13) Israeli company grows medical marijuana which doesn&apos;t get you high (12) Add-on handle makes carrying your bike a snap (11) New system puts the brake on mobile phone use while driving (11) Chapul to launch world&apos;s first cricket snack bar (11) 
 

 Subscribe to Gizmag 
Subscribe to Gizmag&apos;s email newsletter:
 Subscribe Follow Gizmag on 
 Twitter Subscribe to Gizmag&apos;s 
 YouTube channel Subscribe to Gizmag&apos;s 
 RSS feed All content copyright©Gizmag 2003 - 2012 
 Top Home About Contact Privacy Terms&amp;Conditions Advertise
	</body>
</document>
