<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001880" url="http://calorielab.com/news/2008/04/08/mega-size-me-i-ate-nothing-but-mcdonalds-japan-mega-burgers-all-day-and-survived/" time="2012-07-12-17:47" support="1" score="0.007451938468496327" bingtitle="Mega Size Me: I ate nothing but McDonald’s Japan Mega burgers ..." webtitle="Mega Size Me: I ate nothing but McDonalds Japan Mega burgers all day and survived">
			<query id="000853" bing-rank="232"/>
	<description>... participating in a daylong Mega burger three course meal ... When I do happen to go to McD’s I usually order a ... message, I knew many unfortunate kids who had to eat at ...</description>
	<body>
		| 
 
 Health News Diet Blog Diet Reviews Diet Delivery Calorie Counter Calories Burned 
 Get CalorieLab by E-Mail Close 
 
 Most Recent Comment: 

 Sara : Hi! Love your work! How can I see you for a consult? 
 
 Enter your search terms   
 Web calorielab.com 
 Submit search form 
 
 Mississippi is fattest state in 2011 All about the Photoshop Diet Master Cleanse &amp;Stanley Burroughs The big 9 foodborne illnesses State flags as infographics (humor) Diet delivery meal services Slim down with the Photoshop Diet Unhealthy foods that aren&apos;t Healthy foods that aren&apos;t Diet plans from women&apos;s mags Diet tips from ordinary women Diet bento boxes step by step Why Japanese don&apos;t get fat Yikes! Oklahoma&apos;s official state meal Waist measurement and your health Brawndo test drive Actress Koda Madison tells all Japan&apos;s mega fast food trend Dr. Lulu : The original diet guru &quot;I lost 30 pounds eating bentos &quot; Thin high schooler &quot;not anorectic!&quot; Disneyland&apos;s Small World supersized Kimkins Diet&amp;Heidi Diaz exposé Man boobs epidemic studied Vegetarian diet for omnivores Celebrity weight loss secrets archive &quot;I lost 40 pounds as a vegan &quot; Yo-yo dieting folk wisdom disproven Don&apos;t be chicken: Eat the dark meat 8 glasses of water urban legend Eating fat is good for you! Big in Japan: Morning Banana Diet Miracle fruit makes sour sweet Comments from a skinny girl Hydroxycut background information Antidepressants for weight loss Diets from A to almost Z (humor) The bariatric surgery-alcoholism link 99% cocoa bars from Lindt, Meiji Seth Roberts&apos; Shangri-La Diet 
 
 Our Top Page: Most Recent Articles 

 Previously: Nibbles: More on kids and sleep, moms and exercise and overdoing supplements 

 More Recently: Twenty years behind the American obesity nightmare 
 
Mega Size Me: I ate nothing but McDonald’s Japan Mega burgers all day and survived
 
 [CalorieLab contributor Khalilah Aleem has completed what we believe to be the first 1-day Mega burger hat trick in history. Her story follows.] 

The day before: April 7

 10:30 a.m.: Yogurt with cereal 3:40 p.m.: Roast lamb with tons of vegetables 8:00 p.m.: Noodles with veggies 

This is what I ate was the day before participating in a daylong Mega burger three course meal at the McDonald’s here in Fukushima, Japan, and the only thing that prompted me to be a guinea pig was curiosity and curiosity alone.

 

McDonald’s has introduced various supersized“Mega”sandwiches over the past couple of years, but on Friday, for the first time, they began serving a different Mega sandwich for each meal in the day. CalorieLab asked me to try them out and report back.

In all my twenty five years I never had a Big Mac, let alone a MEGA MAC (loud theatrical voice insert), so if I had to try it, then I at least wanted others to know about it. When I do happen to go to McD’s I usually order a cheeseburger and juice. And that is only once every two months.

Yet, I secretly always wanted to know what it would be like to do what that Morgan Spurlock from the movie Super Size Me did. The guy ate only at McDonald’s for an entire month. While what he had done had a message, I knew many unfortunate kids who had to eat at McDonald’s everyday because their mothers were always on the go and could never cook them a decent meal.

 

One of them was my cousin, who I swear to you was taken to McDonald’s at least twice a day because his mom hated to cook. The last time I saw him, he was twelve and so huge that the doctor advised him to use a sleeping aid while he was losing weight because his fat was slowly crushing him. I have no idea how the chap is doing now, but hopefully he got sick of eating at fast food restaurants.

 

Today: April 8

 10:00 a.m.: Mega Muffin, hash browns, and orange juice 

I’m feeling okay if slightly overstuffed and a little tired.

 1:30 p.m.: Mega Mac 

I feel nausea and am constipated, extremely tired, and irritable. And not long after eating I’m hungry yet full—if that makes any sense.

 9:40 p.m.: Mega Teriyaki 

I’m tired, with low energy, irritable, and I have an uncomfortable feeling in my stomach, with a metallic taste in my mouth after eating.

 

Words cannot explain how crappy I feel today. When I ate the first burger—the breakfast Mega Muffin, the first three bites were great. But then I had to take a rest before I finished the sandwich. Surprisingly it was really good, and the fat slab of eggs and the two slices of sausage with bacon on top was not as bad as I had anticipated. I even ate the hash browns and drank the orange soda that went along with it.

As I finished the burger, the ladies working at the McDonald’s restaurant knowingly smiled at me as if it was normal for an American to like hamburgers. Come on people. Can I say stereotype any louder?

Too embarassed to order a second Mega burger

It was 10:40 a.m. when I finished, so to save another long walk to McDonald’s on such a tight schedule for that day, I begged my boyfriend to order the Mega Mac before we left. I could not go to the counter again and order another Mega burger because, first, I was too embarrassed, and, secondly, I did not want the mothers of a few of the kids I taught to think that their teacher was a total pig.

 

As my boyfriend passed me the heavy bag that contained the Mega Mac, I knew that it was going to be a long day, especially when I had to go to work and teach English to at least five groups of hyperactive kids. We took a 30 minute walk and about 3 hours later, I was hungry.

How could I be hungry after eating such a huge hamburger? From taking one look at the Mega Muffin anyone could guess that, for all its 695 calories and over 50 grams of fat in one serving, it was highly nutrient deficient. With a stomach that was heavy yet hungry, I retreated back to my room to eat the second Mega burger but this time it was the MEGA MAC (loud theatrical voice insert).

How in blazes was I to eat a hamburger that had four slices of meat, three slices of bread, a slice of cheese, and limp lettuce and pickles? Guys and girls, the amount of meat piled on the hamburger was phenomenal, and waves of nausea hit me as I finished the last bite.

The nausea was soon over with but then came the sleepiness that hit me right at the core. I had never been so sleepy in the middle of the day, so I took an hour nap, and even after waking up I wanted to go back to sleep. But I had to go to work, so after a few cups of coffee I was at least presentable. Can you guys see a pattern here? Caffeine overload, fast food, and a tired body are some of the symptoms I would guess that most fast food enthusiasts experience.

Would you like an apple pie with your third Mega burger?

After work my boss gave me a lift to McDonald’s, and I got the Mega Teriyaki burger, apple pie, and orange soda. If I was going to go out, then it was going to be big, and yet even after the huge meal I felt no satisfaction at all. Just lazy, guilty, nauseated, and sleepy. While I felt like crap after finishing the mission, I could not imagine doing this for another day, let alone a month.

 

When my meal was finished I decided to check the nutritional values for the McDonald’s Mega sandwiches, and each burger is around 700 to 900 cals and has about 50 to 65 grams of fat. So all in all excluding the extra stuff, the burgers alone accounted for about 2,360 calories and 160 grams of fat.

During this interesting but health detrimental quest, I learned that nothing beats a home cooked meal, that fast food is a definite killer, and that“you are what you eat.”

Today was a mega tired day, a mega nauseous day, and a mega upset stomach day.

However, the Mega Mac is extremely popular in Japan for reasons I cannot understand. Yes the Mega Mac is good from the first bite—especially the teriyaki one—but after a few bites that satisfaction goes away.

If the Mega Mac continues to be as popular and regular in Japan as it is now, then no longer will Japan boast of slim waifs and long lived centurions . They will soon have the same problem than many nations around the world have with their quickly expanding obese and overweight population.

 [Khalilah is resting comfortably and is expected to completely recover. Notes of sympathy and encouragement can be left in the comments.] 

(By Khalilah Aleem for CalorieLab Calorie Counter News)
 Diet-to-Go Meal Delivery: $25 Off 1st Week’s Order with Coupon“calorielab25″ 
 
 
Related posts from the CalorieLab Calorie Counter News archives:

 “Mega size”fast food takes hold in Japan Gigantic food gets a little crazy Nibbles: Overeating diabetics, metabolic syndrome and breastfeeding, and a Mega hat trick Japan’s company diet not the answer to obesity Nibbles: Nutrition facts, healthy snacking and giant burgers 
 
 This entry was posted
 on Tuesday, April 8th, 2008 and is filed under Diet guinea pig , Fast food and restaurants , Foreign stories (non-U.S.) , Japan diet, fitness, food , Offbeat diet news .

 You can skip to the end and leave a response. Pinging is currently not allowed. Permalink. 
 
9 Responses to“Mega Size Me: I ate nothing but McDonald’s Japan Mega burgers all day and survived”
 
 Tom says: May 26, 2010 at 2:44 pm 
Oddly, when I indulge in a big McLunch or BK O.D., I have all kinds of energy at the gym after work. Perhaps these meals may be somewhat vitamin deficient, but a MegaMac would certainly not be protein deficient.
As for the foolish assumption that all Americans like hamburgers,,,,,why that’s as dumb as assuming all Japanese like rice. The truth is only 99% of Americans like burgers. How ever could anyone stereotype based on that? Why those Japanese are so unsophisticated. Based on the profligate consumption of hamburgers, your apparent distaste put you in the minority. And don’t tell me….you think that its OK for government to tax some foods at a higher rate than others to compel people to eat healthier….
 Daniel B. says: May 22, 2010 at 9:20 pm 
Gomenasai.
 Daniel B. says: May 22, 2010 at 9:19 pm 
I am so Sorry Japan.
 grover says: April 6, 2010 at 7:34 am 
that’s why Mcdonalds Japan is #2 in the world
 http://www.japansugoi.com/wordpress/japan-has-most-mcdonalds-after-usa/ 
 Keith says: March 30, 2010 at 2:24 am 
Where are the before and after pictures? We want to see how much you’ve changed.

And yes, all Americans do like hamburgers. The truth shall not be called a stereo-type.

The child in the photo has excellent English!

The Mega Mac has too much meat. Perhaps that’s what Mega means in Japanese,“too much!”Haha.

It’s one way to sell more expensive food. Give you more than you need.
 beatwho says: August 29, 2008 at 2:25 am 
what the hell? you bought the mega mac 3.5 hrs before you ate it? No wonder you got sick.
 Chaz says: April 17, 2008 at 4:34 am 
In my day in Japan (’03), McDonald’s came out with a burger so covered with extra fattening sauces that if you weren’t careful it would squirt out of its bun. Its been too long and i cant remember the name, but it seemed to be a combination of thousand island dressing, ketchup and mayo. Maybe ranch as well. My brother made the mistake of eating one on the shinkansen tracks in Kyoto. The combination of incorrectly applied hand pressure and the suction a passing Nozomi bullet train practically catapulted the burger out of the bun and onto the tracks.

In anycase, nice work and good luck with the recovery.
 patrick says: April 16, 2008 at 8:50 am 
wow, i had no idea mega-macs existed
 Dr. J says: April 8, 2008 at 7:15 pm 
Kobayashi better not look back or he’ll see you gaining on him :-)
 
 
Leave a Reply
 Click here to cancel reply. 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 

 

 
 
 
Monthly Archives

 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 June 2007 May 2007 April 2007 March 2007 February 2007 January 2007 December 2006 November 2006 October 2006 September 2006 August 2006 July 2006 June 2006 May 2006 April 2006 March 2006 February 2006 January 2006 December 2005 November 2005 October 2005 September 2005 August 2005 July 2005 June 2005 May 2005 April 2004 December 2003 
 
Categories

 115 Reasons 2000 Calories at… Bariatric surgery Best of 2010 Beverages Biggest Loser Body Image Body Mass Index Breakfast and Obesity Calorie Restriction and Antiaging Cancer and diet Cancer and Weight Celebrities and politicians Celebrity Diets Celebrity Weight Loss Secrets Childhood obesity Cholesterol Competitive eating Consumer watchdogs Cooking at home Costs of being obese Detox and Fasting Diets Diabetes Die Die Diet–Robert Rosenblum Diet and food industry Diet and food media Diet Blog Diet books and authors Diet Christmas carols Diet Delivery Diet foods Diet guinea pig Diet humor and wit Diet pills, drugs, supplements and devices Diet programs Diet scams and myths Diet Tips Diet TV this week Diets and weight loss programs DietTribe Disney food and obesity news Dr. J will see you now Dr. Slimbozo&apos;s Gizmos and Gadgets Dukan Diet Eating disorders, anorexia&amp;bulimia nervosa Erik Sansom Exercise and fitness Fast food and restaurants Fattest States Fertility and diet food allergies Food dangers Food miscellaneous Food safety Foreign stories (non-U.S.) Freshman 15 Gift Guide Girl Scout cookie nutrition Government obesity actions Guest contributors Heart Disease and Heart Disease Reversal Holidays and seasons Illustrations and infographics Japan diet, fitness, food Karen Collins Kids and families Kimkins Diet and Heidi Diaz Koda Madison Labeling and disclosure Legal and legislative Man Boobs&amp;Pseudo Gynecomastia Marketing and Advertising Medical professionals Metabolic syndrome Milk controversy Monthly Top 10s Motivation and mental Nibbles: diet news shorts Nutrigenomics Nutrition Obese animals Obesity causes Obesity conferences Obesity denialism Obesity discrimination Obesity health dangers Obesity research and studies Obesity statistics Offbeat diet news Omega 3 Pet-assisted weight loss Portion control Portion size Prison nutrition and obesity Pro ana (Proana) Profiles of the obese Public policy Religion and obesity School lunches and junk food Science and Technology Seafood and mercury controversy Seniors and obesity Shangri-La Diet Sleep and Obesity Snacks Sociology and environment Soda pop, HFCS, and beverages Sodium and hypertension Sources Supersizing our surroundings Susan McQuillan Tabloid Diet Posts Takeru Kobayashi Trans fat Uncategorized Vegetarian and vegan diet waist to hip ratio Weight control in the military weight loss competition Weight loss industry Weight maintenance What I&apos;m Eating Now Worst Foods _Administrative posts 
 
RSS Subscription Sign-Up

 RSS | My Yahoo | Other Subscription Services 
 
 
Copyright 2000-2008 CalorieLab, Inc. | About CalorieLab® | By using CalorieLab you accept our User Agreement | Privacy | tips3@calorielab.com | (702) 866-9006
	</body>
</document>
