<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001968" url="http://www.menuism.com/restaurants/house-of-wong-st-paul-226847" time="2012-07-12-17:52" support="5" score="0.014764946929872054" bingtitle="House of Wong - Reviews &amp; Menu - St Paul 55113" webtitle="House of Wong - Reviews&amp;Menu - St Paul 55113">
			<query id="000350" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="001103" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="001511" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000037" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000600" bing-rank="116"/>
	<description>... House of Wong is a Asian, Chinese, and Fast Food restaurant ... judging by the amt of people that eat there ... On my last visit about 4 months ago they mixed up my order.</description>
	<body>
		Menuism - Restaurant and dish reviews 
 Explore Restaurant Reviews&amp;Menus 
 Restaurants Near Me Make Online Reservations Order Delivery&amp;Takeout Restaurant Week Directory Popular Cities Popular Chains What&apos;s Menu ism ? Monthly Review Contest 
 Remember Personal Dining Journal 
 My Favorites My Try List My Photos Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 
 Learn Foodie Education Blog 
 Food Primers Exclusive Interviews 
 
 FIND AROUND GO 
 Write a Review Upload Menu&amp;Food Photos 

 Not a member? To save, rate, and share reviews, sign up! Already a member? Log in (OpenID) Connect with Facebook 
 
 larger map / directions 

 House of Wong Locations 
 
 - Actions - Write a Review Add to Try List Add to Favorites Suggest Corrections Upload Pics 

 - Pages - The Restaurant Map/Directions 
 St Paul Restaurants » Asian » House of Wong Share | 
House of Wong
 
 4.15 star rating           
  4.2 rating over 4 reviews 
 (651) 488-6687 

 1163 Larpenteur Ave W ( ) 

 St Paul , MN 55113-6382 

 View Nearby Businesses» 
 Send to Phone Email Listing Print Listing View Hours 
 Read Reviews (4) View Map/Directions 
 
 Information From the Restaurant Offers 
 
 Description:  House of Wong is a Asian , Chinese , and Fast Food restaurant where most Menuism users came for fun with friends , paid between $10 and $25 , and tipped between 15% to 18% . Tags: Asian, Chinese, Fast Food, Good For Kids, Takeout, and Good for groups 
 
Nothing yet.
 
 Do you own House of Wong? Contact us to connect with your diners. 
 
 Suggest Corrections/Menu 
 
Reviews for House of Wong
 Write a review 
 4 reviews First reviewed by Laureate651 
 
 0 helpful votes over 1 review 
 ruthanne 
 1 Restaurant Review 0 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 House of Wong ruthanne 
 September 21, 2011 
 5.0 
 5.0 star rating           
 0 0 0 0 Votes   
great food
 
I grew up eating at House of Wong and taking out food…………..never had a bad outing. Took my best friend there last May and she fell in love with the food……………their food is great…………..service was friendly and fast.
Will always go there…………..not like some restaurants where all the food is the same color…………..
The quantities are huge……………….so its always like eating there for two days…………..
judging by the amt of people that eat there…………they must be doing something right.
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply 
&quot;If it looks good eat it! (and if it doesn&apos;t eat it anyway)&quot;

 3 helpful votes over 9 reviews 
 Laureate651 
 9 Restaurant Reviews +3 
 
 Add as friend Send Msg 
 House of Wong Laureate651 
 December 29, 2009 
 2.0 
 2.0 star rating           
 0 0 0 0 Votes   
Poor service, average food
 
I used to get House of Wong to go fairly often when I worked in the Roseville area. The food is average in terms of quality. The pot stickers are tasty but everything else seems bland. It is also a lot more expensive than many other places. You can find better food and cheaper prices up the street at Chin’s Kitchen. I have also had a couple very poor experiences with the customer service. On my last visit about 4 months ago they mixed up my order. When I told them that I had not gotten the sesame chicken I ordered they insisted I didn’t order it and would not help me in any way. They dismissed me and refused to acknowledge me. I have not been back since.
 Link To Review 
 

 Copy 
 
 Add a Comment 
 
Comments
 
 What do you think? Reply or write your own review .
 Reply: Login or join with Facebook to reply to this restaurant review. Login to Reply Cerissa L 
 from Insider Pages 
 
August 6, 2010
 
 4 star rating           
 
House of Wong
 
I only been here once and had their chick fried rice and egg rolls. The food was okay, but then again I didn&apos;t try anything fancy. The service was fast and super friendly. The restaurant though could use some renovations.

 read full review» 
 Karin L 
 from Insider Pages 
 
March 30, 2010
 
 3 star rating           
 
Good Food Here
 
When I lived in St. Paul my family would go here quite often. Food is good and reasonably priced. Surprisingly one of my family&apos;s favorite things on the menu is the cheeseburger basket - it&apos;s really good.

 read full review» 
 Read 18 reviews on Citysearch» 
Best Dishes at House of Wong
 
Thinking about visiting House of Wong? Check out the full House of Wong menu to decide if the menu items&amp;prices meet your expectations. When available, we&apos;ll provide pictures, dish ratings, and descriptions of each item. House of Wong prices and menu items may fluctuate by location or over time, so use the following menu information as a reasonable guideline as to what is currently being served at the restaurant.
 
 Sort: Top Rated Most Popular 

No menu items or dish reviews have been added for this restaurant.
Be the first food lover to add a dish.
 
Menuism intends to provide as accurate information as possible. House of Wong prices and menu items are known to fluctuate. The information above has been provided by Menuism users or 3rd party data sources. If you represent House of Wong you are invited to feed us with more accurate information by contacting us.
 
 Embroidme of Roseville Arthur&apos;s Jewelers 
 145 reviews 5.0 stars JOHN&apos;S TAILORS Tobacco Tree, Inc. Tobacco Tree Inc Walgreens The UPS Store Falcon Plumbing, LLC 
 0 reviews 5.0 stars Computer Joe Pro Team Painting Plus 
 House of Wong is located near the cities of Saint Paul, West Saint Paul, West St Paul, Lilydale, and South St Paul. People found this by searching for: House Of Wong Roseville Mn Menu, House Of Wongs Restaurant Roseville, House Of Wong Roseville Menu, House Of Wong Menu Roseville, House Of Wong Menu Mn, House Of Wong Menu, House Of Wong Roseville, House Of Wong Mn, and House Of Wong, St Paul. 
Featured in St Paul
 
 4.36364 star rating           
 Ho Ho Gourmet 
 4.33333 star rating           
 Carbone&apos;s - Seventh Street 
 3.75 star rating           
 Pad-Thai Restaurant 
 2.75 star rating           
 Buca di Beppo 
 5.0 star rating           
 India House 
 5.0 star rating           
 Ray J&apos;s 
 4.0 star rating           
 Little Venetian 
 4.0 star rating           
 Downtowner Woodfire Grill 
 4.0 star rating           
 Rocco&apos;s Pizza 
 1.0 star rating           
 Panino Brothers 
 Upload Pics Photos
 
Nearby Restaurants
 Mc Glynn&apos;s Bakery Roseville Bakery Caribou Coffee Papa John&apos;s Pizza 
Link to House of Wong
 
Copy the link below and paste onto your website or blog to display badge.

 Copy 
 
 Follow Menuism around the web Find us on Facebook Follow us on Twitter Find us on Google+ 
 
 Learn More
 Advertise About
Advertise
FAQ
Privacy
Terms of Use 
 Take Action
 Link to Menuism / Badges and Widgets 
 Browse
 Restaurant Week Restaurant Locations Popular Cities Sitemap 
 
 ©2006 - 2012 Delta Beans, LLC
 Contact Menuism 

Some Images and Data provided by Citysearch .
	</body>
</document>
