<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001154" url="http://www.webmd.com/food-recipes/features/best-worst-smoothies" time="2012-07-12-16:35" support="1" score="0.005908128435216101" bingtitle="Best and Worst Smoothies - WebMD - Better information. Better health." webtitle="Best and Worst Smoothies">
			<query id="000220" bing-rank="184"/>
	<description>What you can end up with is a drink that has upwards of 600 calories, enough ... Browse our collection of healthy, delicious recipes, from WebMD and Eating Well ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to content 
 Home&amp;News 
 WebMD Home WebMD News Home Free Health Newsletters 
 Health A-Z 
 ADD/ADHD Allergies Alzheimer&apos;s Anxiety Disorders Arthritis Asthma Back Pain Bipolar Disorder Breast Cancer Cancer Carpal Tunnel Syndrome Cholesterol Cold, Flu,&amp;Cough Colorectal Cancer COPD 
 
 Depression Diabetes Erectile Dysfunction Eye Health Fibromyalgia Heart Disease Heartburn/GERD Herpes HPV/Genital Warts Hypertension IBS Incontinence/OAB Inflammatory Bowel Lupus 

 
 Melanoma/Skin Cancer Menopause Mental Health Migraine Multiple Sclerosis Osteoporosis Pain Management Rheumatoid Arthritis Sexual Conditions Shingles Skin Problems Sleep Disorders Stroke See All Topics 

 
 Tools&amp;Video First Aid Games Mobile Apps Slideshows Symptom Checker Vaccine Tracker Tests&amp;Tools Videos Community Experts&amp;Blogs WebMD Community 
 Drugs&amp;Medications Center 
 Find or Review a Drug Vitamins or Supplements Pill Identifier Drug News Mobile Drug Information 
 Healthy Living 
 Women&apos;s Health Men&apos;s Health 50+: Live Better, Longer Emotional Health Healthy Beauty Sex&amp;Relationships Oral Health See All Topics 
 Healthy Eating&amp;Diet 
 Weight Loss&amp;Diet Plans BMI Plus Calculator Food&amp;Fitness Planner Food-o-Meter Personal Diet Evaluator Portion Size Helper All Diet Tools Food&amp;Recipes Fitness&amp;Exercise Fit-o-Meter 
 Parenting&amp;Pregnancy 
 Pregnancy Newborn&amp;Baby Children&apos;s Health Children&apos;s Vaccines Parenting Raising Fit Kids Mom&apos;s Guide to Summer Family Health WebMD for Kids 
 Teen Health 
 Teen Girls Teen Boys WebMD FIT Teen Food Move Recharge Mood 
 Pet Health 
 Healthy Dogs Healthy Cats 
 
   Enter Search Keywords: 

 Other search tools: Symptoms Doctors Medical Dictionary 
Find us on:

 
 WebMD Home Food&amp;Recipes Center Food&amp;Recipes Feature Stories Email a Friend Print Article 
 Food&amp;Recipes 
 
Foodie 411

 Best Foods for Energy Can Foods Cause Bedwetting? Smarter Grocery Store Choices Least Healthy Restaurant Meals Probiotics for Digestive Woes? Getting Kids to Eat Healthy 
 Font Size A A A 
Best and Worst Smoothies
 The real skinny on smoothies, plus 3 healthy smoothie recipes. By Elaine Magee, MPH, RD 
WebMD Expert Review 


They’re refreshingly cool, come in fun, fruity flavors, and are served with
a straw. What’s not to like about smoothies? They’re so popular that you can
now find them at fast food restaurants, grocery stores -- even coffee shops.
But while smoothies may sound like a healthy treat, sometimes they’re anything
but.

Smoothies are usually made with healthy ingredients like soy milk, fresh or
frozen fruit, skim milk, or yogurt. But some also feature plenty of high-fat
and/or high-sugar items like ice cream, peanut butter, sweetened syrups, or
chocolate. What you can end up with is a drink that has upwards of 600
calories, enough saturated fat to rival a double cheeseburger, and carbohydrate
grams in the triple digits -- and that’s just for the small size.

Consider: A 20-ounce serving of Smoothie King’s The Hulk-Strawberry has more
calories than a Burger King Double Cheeseburger with a medium order of French
fries (it totals 990 calories, 52 grams total fat, 19 grams saturated fat).
Dairy Queen’s Tropical Blizzard (with 1,122 calories, 62 grams fat, and 25
grams saturated fat) has more total fat and saturated fat than the same
fast-food meal.

If you’re looking for a healthy smoothie, your best bet is usually to keep
it simple. The label on Emerald City’s Fruity Supreme Smoothie, for example,
shows just four ingredients: banana, strawberry, nonfat milk, and protein. Any
smoothie that includes nonfat milk, soy milk, or yogurt will likely contribute
a nice dose of protein, along with other goodies like vitamin D, B-12, and/or
calcium.

If you’re having a smoothie in place of a meal, look for a smoothie with at
least 5 grams of protein and a similar amount of fiber, so it will be more
likely to hold off hunger for more than a couple of hours.  If your
smoothie is a between-meal snack, you’re better off choosing the smallest size
possible and keeping the calories below 300.

The Best and Worst Smoothies

And now for my list of the best and worst smoothies, from a nutritional
standpoint. To be considered for the list, the item had to be called a
“smoothie” or something very similar. The serving sizes range from 10 ounces to
24 ounces, so I ranked them by calories per ounce.

All of the smoothies in the “best” list are free of saturated fat, contain
no more than 61 grams of carbohydrate and at least 4 grams of fiber, and have
17 calories or less per ounce.

10 Best Smoothies

(Listed from lowest to highest calories per ounce)



 

 
 Calories 
 
 Fat 
 
 Sat. Fat 
 
 Carbs 
 
 Fiber 
 
 Protein 
 
 Calories per oz 
 
Jamba Juice LightStrawberry Nirvana, 16 oz
 
150
 
0g
 
0g
 
31g
 
3g
 
5g
 
9
 
Jamba Juice Light Berry Fulfilling, 16 oz
 
150
 
0.5
 
0
 
32
 
4
 
6
 
9
 
Jamba Juice Light Mango Mantra, 16 oz
 
150
 
0.5
 
0
 
31
 
2
 
6
 
9
 
Emerald City Smoothie Island Breeze, 24 oz
 
220
 
0
 
0
 
55
 
6
 
2
 
9
 
Dannon Light ‘n Fit 0% Plus Mixed Berry&amp;Pomegranate, 14 oz
 
140
 
0
 
0
 
28
 
0
 
8
 
10
 
Emerald City Smoothie Pacific Splash, 24 oz
 
240
 
0
 
0
 
58
 
6
 
2
 
10
 
Orange Julius Light Smoothie Berry-Pom Twilight, 20 oz
 
230
 
0
 
0
 
55
 
5
 
3
 
12
 
Emerald City Smoothie Fruity Supreme, 24 oz
 
280
 
0.5
 
0
 
59
 
6
 
12
 
12
 
Smoothie King “Make it skinny” Slim-n-Trim Strawberry, 20 oz
 
275
 
1
 
0
 
61
 
5
 
8
 
14
 
Starbuck’s Vivanno Smoothies(Made with skim milk)Strawberry Banana, 16
oz
 
270
 
0.5
 
0
 
56
 
7
 
16
 
17
 


 1 | 2 | 3 Next Page &gt; 
Top Picks

 Is Corn a Grain or a Vegetable? Healthy Snack Ideas Should You Worry About Artificial Sweeteners? 6 Unhealthy Habits, Including Kitchen Blunders Healthy Menu Plan for Diabetes 8 High-Fiber Foods Your Kids Will Love 
 
Further Reading:

 Slideshow: Skinny Sipping -- The Best&amp;Worst Beverages for Weight Loss Are Beverages to Blame for Your Weight Gain? Good Food, Bad Food Best Ice Cream Treats for 150 Calories or Less Junk-Food Facts Best-Tasting Light Mayonnaise Frozen Dinners: How to Choose Healthy Ones See All Nutrition for Kids Topics 
 
 Food&amp;Recipes 

 Nutrition Cooking Tips Recipes Special Diets Food Resources 
 
 Weight Loss&amp;Diet Plans 

 Weight Loss Basics Popular Diet Plans Weight Loss Strategies Tools and Calculators Diet Support 
 
 Fitness&amp;Exercise 

 Fact vs. Fiction Tips for Success Get Lean Get Strong Fuel Your Body Expert Advice 
 
Healthy Eating Guides

 High Protein Gluten Free Low Sodium Foods for Energy 
 
Related To Food

 Cholesterol Diabetes FDA Center on WebMD Food Poisoning Healthy Recipes Heart Disease Pantry Staples Recipes for Kids More Related Topics 
 
Today in Food&amp;Recipes
 Recipes Satisfying Smoothies Recipes Breakfast Ideas to Try   Recipes Carb-Conscious Recipes Tool Track Calories and Shed Pounds   
WebMD Recipe Finder

Browse our collection of healthy, delicious 
 recipes, from WebMD and Eating Well magazine.
 Recipes Bake Your Own Breads Recipes Warming, Hearty Soups   Recipes Chicken-Centric Meals Recipes Beans, Beans, and More Beans   Recipes Savory Sandwiches Recipes Vegan Meals for Everyone   fit Article 5 Grab-and-Go Breakfast Recipes Slideshow Leading Super Foods for Men   
Subscribe

to WebMD Newsletters
 

 WebMD Daily Women&apos;s Health Men&apos;s Health Weight Loss Wisdom Submit Sign up for more topics! 
WebMD Special Sections
 
 Track the Calories You Consume 
 
Health Solutions From Our Sponsors 
 
 Aching Back Center Alzheimer’s Progression 

 Birth Control for Moms Diagnosed With Low T? 

 Options for Depression Advanced Prostate Cancer? 

 Osteoarthritis Center RA Patient Stories 

 Injectable RA Treatment Understand Fibromyalgia 
 
In-depth coverage:
 Is Your Psoriasis Treatment on Target? | Your Guide to a Healthy Mouth | Rheumatoid Arthritis Health Check | Teen Girls and Puberty | Diabetes and Your Body 
Find us on:

 
 URAC: Accredited Health Web Site HonCode: Health on the Net Foundation AdChoices
	</body>
</document>
