<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001635" url="http://blogs.miaminewtimes.com/shortorder/2009/06/going_to_key_west_here_are_the.php" time="2012-07-12-17:24" support="1" score="0.008081537524680745" bingtitle="Along the Way to Key West: Here Are the Best Places to Eat - Miami ..." webtitle="Along the Way to Key West: Here Are the Best Places to Eat - Miami Restaurants and Dining - Short Order">
			<query id="000098" bing-rank="114"/>
	<description>Here&apos;s a list of places to eat on the drive down ... The array of salsas and condiments at a bar near the ... Salty American Fast Food; Restaurant No Shows; Eating House&apos;s New ...</description>
	<body>
		Blogs 
 Entire Site Articles&amp;Blogs Restaurants Places Events Music Images Ads Bars Best Of Movies 
 News Home Riptide Strouse Luke&apos;s Gospel Letters Special Reports Archives Search New Times Flipbook Weekly Newsletter Get Mobile Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads New Times Web Awards Music Home Crossfade Concert Calendar Bars and Clubs Brew at the Zoo Submit an Event Music Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurants Home Short Order Find a Restaurant Menus Iron Fork Happy Hours Dining Deals Dining Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurant Ads Arts Home Cultist Visual Arts Theater Welcome to the Future Skrawberry Jam Artopia Arts Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Film Home Showtimes Cultist Film Film Poll 2011 Film Newsletter Get Mobile Free Stuff Best Of Home 2012 2011 2010 2009 Readers&apos; Poll 2012 Best Of Newsletter Get Mobile Best Of Ads Promotions Home Promotional Events Street Team Free Stuff On Sale Promotions Newsletter Get Mobile Deals Post an Ad Jobs Real Estate Advertiser Index Deals Deals Newsletter Virtual Job Fair 
Top

blog

Stories
 
 
 Miami Spice 

 Gotham Steak Hakkasan, Scarpetta Miami Spice 

By Laine Doss
 
 Holidays 

 Bastille Day at Brand New Fabien&apos;s Bistro 

By Lee Klein
 
 Best of Miami 

 Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants 

By Laine Doss
 
 First Bites 

 Iron Side Cafe: Fresh New Lunch Spot 

By Lee Klein
 
 Gastronomic Gatherings 

 Fairchild Makes Mangoes Exciting This Weekend 

By Laine Doss
 
 Chef on the Small Screen 

 Eat St. to Film Food Trucks in Miami 

By Laine Doss
 
 Food Charity 

 Taste of the Nation Celebrates 25th Anniversary 

By Laine Doss
 
 Neighborhood Joints 

 Shack Shack In Coral Gables Opening Soon 

By Laine Doss
 
 News 

 Zeke&apos;s Reincarnated: Rio Station 

By Hannah Sentenac
 
 Fuming Foodie 

 Teacher Nailed for Horrible Behavior With Food&amp;Kids 

By Ily Goyanes
 
   Travel Hog 
Along the Way to Key West: Here Are the Best Places to Eat
 By Miami New Times Staff Thu., Jun. 11 2009 at 9:50 AM Categories: Travel Hog 
 Pin It 
 Summer is the time to drive down to Key West. It&apos;s empty now, the streets and beaches quiet. Here&apos;s a list of places to eat on the drive down (or back up).

 Robert Is Here Fruit Stand 
Summer is perhaps the best time to hit up what should be a mainstay of any drive south of Miami: Robert is Here  In these hottest months, this fruit market and shake shop fills up with local varieties of mangoes like Haydens and Kents, several local varieties of lychees, and the curiously-named puzzle of a fruit known as monstera deliciosa (let it ripen until the scales fall off and then scoop out the flesh, which tastes something like Froot Loops). The papaya-key lime shake is worth a stop by itself.
Address: 19200 SW 344th St., Homestead
Phone: (305) 246-1592
 
 Taqueria Morelia 
You&apos;ll find this friendly, impeccably-clean
sit-down taqueria attached to the Raceway gas station at the corner of
Palm Drive and Redland Road in Florida City (just a few blocks west of
Robert Is Here). Especially good are the tacos de suadero, fresh corn
tortillas topped with succulent, near-shredded chunks of beef short
rib. Also worth trying are the tortas--crusty Mexican sandwiches made
with any of the available taco meats--and the ceviche tostadas (when
available). The array of salsas and condiments at a bar near the
register borders on overwhelming.
Address: 961 W Palm Dr., Homestead
Phone: (305) 247-7552

 Lazy Days 
Yes,
the Atlantic Ocean is beautiful, especially when seen from any of the
bridges on the drive down the Keys. However, instead of hanging your
Palmcorder out of your sunroof or taking your eyes off the road for
dangerous amounts of time, why not actually stop? The upstairs patio at Lazy Days in Islamorada
features an amazing view of the Atlantic as well as a fine fried fish
sandwich. Take in the resort atmosphere before spending the night in
your car in Key West.
Address: 79867 Overseas Hwy, Islamorada
Phone: (305) 664-5256

 5 Brothers Grocery and Sandwich Shop 2 
Many
people may not realize that Key West&apos;s best Cuban coffee and sandwich
shop has another location, tucked back just off US1 in Ramrod Key.
Perhaps the best part about this second 5 Brothers location
is that they still make molletes on a regular basis. For those
unfamiliar, a mollete is a sandwich-length piece of Cuban bread that&apos;s
been hollowed out, stuffed with picadillo, sealed up, and then
deep-fried. Eat that behind the wheel!
Address: 27023 Overseas Hwy, Ramrod Key
Phone: (305) 872-0702

 Hogfish Bar and Grill 
Oddly enough, a place that feels like &quot;old Key West&quot; is located just outside of Key West itself. The Hogfish Bar and Grill sits on the docks in Stock Island, just across the Cow Key Channel
Bridge. You&apos;ll find the eponymous hogfish there in sandwich form, as
well as peel and eat Key West pinks, a pool table, and the occasional
cat prowling in from the docks.
Address: 6810 Front St., Stock Island
Phone: 305-293-4041

 -- Nick Vagnoni 
Like this Story?
 
Sign up for the Dining Newsletter: The week&apos;s top local food news and events, plus interviews with chefs and restaurant owners, dining tips, and a peek at our print review.
 Privacy Policy Cancel Continue Write Comment Email to Friend Print Article 
Related Content
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. 
 
after re-reading the headline of the article I realize I misunderstood. Then again, Stock Island IS Key West so the Hogfish entry really technically shouldn&apos;t be on here. But I would submit the 7 Mile Grill, Boondocks, and Mangrove Mamas right off the top of my head. There are a couple of excellent seafood places in Islamorada, but it&apos;s been so long since I&apos;ve been thru there I forget the names LOL.
 
This isn&apos;t a&quot;list of great KW eateries,&quot;but a list of places to eat on the drive to Key West. None of these places are actually in KW, and that&apos;s why El Siboney isn&apos;t on there. The in-KW list would certainly be different. 

Where do you two like to eat along the way?
 
agree w/ Don... this list is really pretty pathetic. First of all, any list of great KW eateries that doesn&apos;t include El Siboney is automatically rejected. There are much better places to eat here than what is included here.
 
fyi
 
These are really the best places you could come up with? Really? You need to get out more.
 

TotalComments: 5
 
Now Trending


 
Slide shows » 

 Closer Look: Villa Azur Closer Look: Josh&apos;s Delicatessen&amp;Appetizing Rock &apos;n&apos; Roll Beer-B-Que 2012 at Seminole Hard Rock Hotel&amp;Casino More Slideshows&gt;&gt; 
 
 Restaurants 
 
 
Hy Vong Vietnamese Restaurant
 View Ad | View Site 
Tobacco Road
 View Ad | View Site 
Our pizza is simply an honest diversity of all-nat
 View Ad | View Site 
El Bajareque Restaurant
 View Ad | View Site 
 More &gt;&gt; 
Twitter Feed
 
 Follow short_order on Twitter 
 More Twitter &gt;&gt; 
Headlines from our Partners
 

 Summer Gold: Susser Talks Mangoes; London Burger King Installs a Damien Hirst Painting Boulud Hosting &quot;To Live and Dine in Miami&quot;; Balloo&apos;s Summer Additions at Sugarcane &quot;That Glow On The Beach&quot;: The 1950s Restaurants of 22nd Street Whiskey Joe&apos;s Set to Booze on Key Biscayne Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants; Watch an Ad For the Second Cheapest Wine Out There 
 About Us | Work for Miami New Times | Esubscribe | Free Classifieds | Advertising | Privacy Policy | Problem With the Site? | RSS | Site Map 
©2012 Miami New Times, LLC. All rights reserved. Browse Voice Nation Most Popular | Most Recent Newsletters | Mobile Log in Sign up 
 New York Village Voice 
 LA Weekly 
 Phoenix New Times 
 Denver Westword 
 Houston Press 
 Dallas Observer 
 SF Weekly 
 Seattle Weekly 
 St. Louis RFT 
 Miami New Times 
 Minneapolis City Pages 
 OC Weekly 
 Broward/Palm Beach New Times 
 

 
 Voice Places 

Discover restaurants, nightlife, travel, shopping...
 
 VOICE Daily Deals 

Get 50 to 90% off every day on restaurants, movies, massages...
 
 Best Of... 

More than 10,000 of the BEST things to eat, drink, and experience
 
 My Voice Nation 

Join the Village Voice community and get exclusive deals and info
 
 Happy Hour 

Your local Happy Hour guide at your fingertips
 
 or 
 Log in or Sign up 
 Social Connect: 
Use your favorite account to access My Voice Nation.
 
 
Use your My Voice Nation account to log in:
 E-mail 
 
 Password 
 
 Forgot password? Remember me or 
 Sign Up or Log in 
 Social Connect: 
Sign up for My Voice Nation with your preferred network.
 
 
Sign up for a My Voice Nation account:
 E-mail 
 
 Privacy policy 
 Settings Log Out
	</body>
</document>
