<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001537" url="http://www.talusweb.com/tag/survey" time="2012-07-12-17:18" support="1" score="0.000123411470948806" bingtitle="Tag - survey" webtitle="Tag - survey">
			<query id="000933" bing-rank="167"/>
	<description>Sonic Drive-In is a fast food restaurant chain in the United States. Every day it ... Love the frappacinos, mochas, music and the store? You can now leave a feedback for ...</description>
	<body>
		Trusted Reviews 
 

Tag - survey

 
 
 www.tellkroger.com - Tell Kroger Customer Satisfaction Survey 
Kroger Customer Satisfaction survey site is found at www.tellkroger.com. To get started , you need your receipt. You should be able to find a date, time, store number, terminal number, transaction number, operator number and the survey entry code. By providing your feedback, you will get a chance to win. For this current sweepstake, a total of 359... read more... 
 
 www.DennysListens.com - Dennys Restaurant Survey 
www.DennysListens.com is a website owned by Denny’s chain of restaurants having various franchisee and headquartered in South Carolina, United States. Customers to the restaurant are required to complete the Guest Satisfaction Survey by entering the survey code in the text box provided, the code printed on the receipt provided while... read more... 
 
 www.RiteAid.com/Feedback - Rite Aid Pharmacy Survey 
www.riteaid.com/feedback Rite Aid is the type of pharmacy which takes its customer service seriously as they try to ensure each customer receives that personal assistance which will keep them coming back for more. As a part of their mission to serve the pharmacy engages their customers by encouraging them to participate in a semi-annual cash prize... read more... 
 
 www.TalkToSonic.com - Sonic Survey Coupon 
Sonic Drive-In is a fast food restaurant chain in the United States. Every day it offers over 3 million customers, like you, the facility to drive in their automobiles in any of its more than 3,500 restaurants and enjoy dining. It was established in 1953 and is currently operational in forty-four states of America.Www.TalkToSonic.com is the site... read more... 
 
 www.TellPayless.com - Payless Shoe Survey 
www.TellPayless.com is the survey website for Payless Shoe store which is shoe retail chain that sells shoes at great low prices. If you have purchased your shoes at Payless store recently, you can now go to the website to complete the survey by answering some questions regarding your shopping experience. To do so you need to visit the site... read more... 
 
 www.WhatABurgerSurvey.com - What A Burger Survey Free Hamburger 
Www.Whataburgersurvey.com is the site through which the management of the WhataBurger Restaurants LP strives to gather your views about the quality of its food items and services in any of its outlets. For this reason, it encourages you to participate in its customer survey and share your most recent dining experience in one of its restaurants. You... read more... 
 
 www.Lowes.IWRSurvey.com - Lowes IWR Survey 
Lowe&apos;s is the largest home improvement warehouse available in the country and is located across the country from coast to coast. Any person thinking of a home modification activity will head directly to the Lowe&apos;s web site and search for the required information. Lowe&apos;s also provide excellent customer service at their retail outlets and also... read more... 
 
 www.myBKExperience.com - Burger King Experience Survey 
www.myBKExperience.com is a survey feedback website for Burger King customers who has recently dined in a Burger King location before. Upon entering the website, it prompts the visitor to enter a restaurant number which you can find on the store receipt. You can also complete the website in Spanish for non-english speaking guests who were invited... read more... 
 
 www.CubListens.com - Cub Food Survey 
www.CubListens.com is the survey website for Cub Foods. Cub Foods is a chain of grocery stores that was started in 1968 and operates about 73 stores in Wisconsin, Illinois, Iowa, Minnesota and the Minneapolis/St. Paul area. Cub Foods also operate 8 fuel express stations and Cub Liquor stores.At www.CubListens.com, you can leave a feedback for Cub... read more... 
 
 www.PapaSurvey.com - Papa Murphy Survey 
www.PapaSurvey.com is a survey website for the famous pizza store“Papa Murphy’s”. The chain of take and bake pizzerias was started during 1981. Papa Murphy’s had also been voted as one of the best pizza chain in America. They are the 5 largest pizza chain in United states having over 1,100 stores. They are also having their... read more... 
 Page: 1    2     3     4     5     6     



©2010 TalusWeb      Home      About Us      Terms      Privacy      Contact Us
	</body>
</document>
