<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001094" url="http://roadtips.typepad.com/a_salesguys_guide_to_the_/kansas-city/" time="2012-07-12-16:31" support="19" score="0.019858773219004606" bingtitle="Road Tips: Kansas City" webtitle="Road Tips: Kansas City">
			<query id="001221" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000640" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="000195" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="000015" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000593" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="001442" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000507" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000971" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="001383" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="000566" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="000814" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000282" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="001159" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000631" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000006" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="000750" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000646" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000643" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="001410" bing-rank="96"/>
	<description>It helps keep the moisture in and it&apos;s easy to ... It was a fast food restaurant with 10 letters in its name and ... Boy is on a series of boards above the front counter.</description>
	<body>
		Road Tips 

A Sales Guy&apos;s Guide to Travel, Food and Music in the Midwest and Beyond - and Much More!
 
The Best of Roadtips
 
 2011 Consumer Electronics Show 
 A Return to Canteen Lunch - Ottumwa, IA 
 A Tribute to a Tough Old Marine 
 A Trip to Lambeau Field - Green Bay, WI 
 Behind the Scenes at River Roots Live - 2010 
 Behind the Scenes at the Indianapolis Motor Speedway 
 Best Burger List 
 Floppy 
 Fonda Dicks 
 Meeting Charles M. Schulz 
 Meeting the King 
 My First Brisket 
 One Night in Paris 
 The Blizzard of 2011 
 The Cable Guy of Carver Hawkeye Arena 
 The Most Food I&apos;ve Ever Eaten in One Sitting 
 The Plane Crash 
 The Shocking Truth About Hotels 
 The Speeding Ticket 
 The Time Stephen Stills Threw Up Next to Me 
 The Tsunami of 2010 
 
 
Recent Posts
 
 Oddfellows Burger Kitchen - Ames, IA Barrio - Minneapolis The Standard - Elmhurst, IL East Side Bakery - Davenport, IA Lucky&apos;s 13 Pub - Bloomington, MN Francie&apos;s - Des Moines Westport Flea Market - Kansas City, MO Sonny&apos;s Pizza Bistro - Des Moines King Kong - Omaha Crabby&apos;s Bar and Grill - Coal Valley, IL 
 
 Categories 
 
 Amana Colonies Ames, IA Ann Arbor, MI Appleton, WI Atlanta Audio/Video Info Austin, MN Balltown, IA Bands and Music Bar and Grill Barbecue Battle Lake, MN Beer Beer Bars Beer, Wine and Liquor Stores Bismarck, ND Bloomington, IL Boulder, CO Bowling Green, KY Breakfast Brew Pubs Brookings, SD Brushes With Greatness Burger Joints Butcher and Meat Shops Cajun Cape Girardeau, MO Cedar Rapids, IA Champaign/Urbana, IL Chicago Chicago Suburbs Chinese Chippewa Falls, WI Cincinnati Clayton, IA Clear Lake, IA Clinton, IA Columbia, MO Columbus, OH Comfort Food Condiments Cool Drives Covington, IN Dayton, OH Daytona Beach, FL De Witt, IA Decorah, IA Denver Des Moines, IA Destinations Detroit Lakes, MN Dexter, IA Dickinson, ND Dogs - Chili and Hot! Door County East Dubuque, IL Edgewood, IA Elkader, IA Eureka Springs, AR Events Fargo, ND Fort Wayne, IN France Galena, IL German Gibson City, IL Grand Forks, ND Greek Green Bay, WI Gridley, IL Grinnell, IA Grocery Stores and Markets Guilty Pleasures Gunder, IA Hawaii - Big Island Hilton Head, SC Hotels Huntington, WV Indian Indianapolis Iowa City, IA Irish Pub Italian Kansas City Kellogg, IA Kenosha, WI La Crosse, WI Lafayette, IN Las Vegas LeMars, IA Lincoln, NE Louisville Lyon, France Madison, IN Madison, WI Manhattan, KS Marshalltown, IA Maui Memphis Mexican Milwaukee, WI Mineral Point, WI Minneapolis Minot, ND Monmouth, IL Monroe, WI Montreal Munster, IN Muscatine, IA Nashville, IN Nashville, TN New Castle, IN New York City Newton, IA Observations and Rants Omaha, NE Ottumwa, IA Owatonna, MN Paris Peoria, IL Phoenix Pizza Platteville, WI Pork Tenderloin Portage, WI Potosi, WI Prairie du Chien, WI Quad Cities, IA-IL Racine, WI Rapid City, SD Recipes Rest In Peace Restaurants River Falls, WI Rocheport, MO Rochester, MN Rockford, IL Rolla, MO Saint-Etienne, France Salina, KS San Francisco Sandwich Places and Deli&apos;s Santa Barbara, CA Savannah, GA Seafood Seattle Sioux City, IA Sioux Falls, SD South Bend, IN Sports Bars Springdale, AR Springfield, IL Springfield, MO St. Cloud, MN St. Louis St. Paul St. Peters, MO Steak Houses Sushi Tales of Jane Thai Food This &apos;n&apos; That 2005 This &apos;n&apos; That 2006 This &apos;n&apos; That 2007 This &apos;n&apos; That 2008 This &apos;n&apos; That 2009 This &apos;n&apos; That 2010 This &apos;n&apos; That 2011 This &apos;n&apos; That 2012 Topeka, KS Utica, IL Washington, IA Wausau, WI Why I Won&apos;t Go In There Wichita, KS Williamsburg, IA Wine Wisconsin Dells, WI York, NE 
 
 Archives 
 
 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 

 More... 
 Subscribe to this blog&apos;s feed 
Kansas City
 
 Westport Flea Market - Kansas City, MO 
 
 
I want to give a shout out to Tricia T. who sent me a note telling me that she thought Westport Flea Market in the Westport Entertainment and Shopping area of Kansas City, MO had the best burgers in that area. I wasn&apos;t familiar with Westport Flea Market, so on a recent trip to K.C. I decided to have lunch there one day. I had trouble finding it, driving by it once. But when I figured out where it was, I was almost embarrassed that I didn&apos;t know about this place before. 

 From the street, the Westport Flea Market is pretty non-descript. For the uninitiated - like me - it sort of does look like a building that houses a decrepit flea market. And that&apos;s probably what I thought as I know I&apos;ve driven past the place on Westport Road ( see map ) many times in the past. In fact, there&apos;s a Sonic Drive-In just across the street that I&apos;ve eaten at a couple times in the past. Had I known a good burger joint was just across the street, I would have gladly ditched the Sonic burger in favor of a good ol&apos;bar and grill burger.  

 Actually, the Westport Flea Market and Bar and Grill - in its present state - has been around since 1981. It truly is a flea market/bar and grill. There are a handful of booths run by vendors (hours vary). Looking into some of the fenced in spaces, it looked like an eclectic mix of kitsch and nostalgia.  

 

The background story of Westport Flea Market goes back even further than their opening in 1981. Prior to World War II, the building housed the Calhoun Mantle and Tile Company - a business that made mantles for fire places and sold ceramic tiles for floors. Due to a downturn in home building during World War II, the company went out of business and the building sat vacant for a handful of years. In 1950, the building was bought by the old Kitty Clover potato chip company out of Omaha and served as their Kansas City-area factory until 1963.  

 The building was transformed into a restaurant in the mid-60&apos;s called The Place in Westport. It was primarily a bar and grill that sold burgers and beer - similar to the present day Westport Flea Market. It was sort of a bohemian type of place that featured dancing and also sold artwork from local artists. It was in business for just a few years before closing around 1973.   

 In the mid-70&apos;s, the building was transformed into a retail market space called Things Unlimited, the precursor to what became the Westport Flea Market. With the downturn in the economy in the late 70&apos;s, the flea market went into bankruptcy. A Kansas City area investor, Mel Kleb, bought the Westport Flea Market and reopened it as a bar/grill/flea market.  

 The Westport Flea Market thrived for years, very much known for their big juicy burgers and their variety of beers they had on tap. But in 2005, Hooters came calling, wanting to put in a Hooters restaurant in the Westport area of Kansas City. Kleb, being the consummate businessman, took their offer and began the process of selling the business.  

 Then two things happened. The first involved a young entrepreneur by the name of Joe Zwillenberg who found out that Kleb was selling the business. Long a fan of the Westport Flea Market, Joe contacted Kleb and wanted to buy the Westport Flea Market from him. Kleb told him that the deal was already consummated with Hooters. Undeterred, Zwillenberg, who ran a burger joint styled after the Westport Flea Market, finally sat down with Kleb and offered him a downpayment of $25,000 and showed him a line of credit from his bank to finance the remaining part of the purchase. Kleb still resisted, saying the deal with Hooters was done. However, Kleb told the young Zwillenberg that if the deal fell through, it was his to have. Zwillenberg was determined to have the Hooters deal fall through.  

 The second thing that happened was when the Westport Neighborhood Association found out that the Hooters corporation was going to demolish the existing building to put up a new restaurant, they put up a fight to stop the demolition. While the fight was going on to stop Hooters from building a new restaurant, Kleb was getting checks from Hooters on a monthly basis to purchase the building and business. However, due to an accounting oversight Kleb didn&apos;t receive a check one month. Kleb immediately called it a breach of contract and told Hooters that the deal was over. He sold the business to Joe Zwillenberg. 

 Two months later on March 1, 2006, Kleb and Zwillenberg consummated their deal with the&quot;passing of the burger&quot;- a five-pound ceremonial burger that was made for the occasion. (Picture at right courtesy KC Confidential.com ) Zwillenberg brought his&quot;Joe&apos;s Burgers&quot;concept over to the Westport Flea Market and the rest, as they say, is history.  

 Zwillenberg is no stranger to the food service industry. He has a long history of working in various capacities in a number of restaurants in the Kansas City area. He was a singing waiter at the age of 17, he was a bartender at an upscale bar/restaurant at the age of 20 - both jobs he got by lying about his age.  

 After graduating with a degree in hotel and restaurant management from the University of Missouri , Zwillenberg started to work for the Gilbert/Robinson restaurant corporation, owners of the Houlihan&apos;s restaurant chain and J. Gilbert&apos;s Wood Fired Steaks in suburban Overland Park. He managed a couple Houlihan&apos;s in the Kansas City area before he decided he wanted to get into business for himself in the mid-90&apos;s.  

 After a short experience as a partner in a restaurant that soured him on ever having a partner again, Zwillenberg started Joe Joe&apos;s Italian Eatery, an Italian-style bistro in Kansas City&apos;s mid city area. Joe Joe&apos;s is said to be the first place to serve panini sandwiches in the Kansas City area.  

 There was a Hardee&apos;s just across the street from Joe Joe&apos;s and it closed up a couple years after Zwillenberg opened his Italian bistro. Zwillenberg had been looking at wanting to do a catering company and he ended up buying the old Hardee&apos;s and opening his catering business - Joe Joe&apos;s Catering . It continues to be one of the top catering businesses in Kansas City today. 

 Having a large love for the Westport Flea Market concept, Zwillenberg lifted a menu from the business on one visit and used it for his blue print for his own burger joint, Joe&apos;s Burgers. It wasn&apos;t long after he opened his burger joint that he found out that the Westport Flea Market was up for sale. It was then he contacted Mel Kleb and that&apos;s the beginning of their relationship which eventually led to Zwillenberg taking over the Westport Flea Market, saving the building and sparing the Westport area from the mediocre food served at a Hooters.   

 
It was around 1:30 when I got into the Westport Flea Market. I took a quick look around and decided to have a seat at the L-shaped bar. I looked behind the bar and saw their very impressive line up of draft beers that they have on tap. I wasn&apos;t certain I wanted a beer, but looking at all those tappers sort of made me thirsty.  

 I took a menu and began to look through it to see what they had to offer at Westport Flea Market. Actually, there&apos;s a lot more than just burgers on the menu at Westport Flea Market. They have a number of sandwiches, including Joe Zwillenberg&apos;s famous grilled chicken panini that he brought over from his days running his Italian bistro. The menu features a large array of appetizers, a handful of salads, daily specials and a special kids menu. In fact, their burger menu is only three items long - the Flea Market burger, the smaller Mini Market burger, and a patty melt that features the Mini Market burger on a toasted rye bread with grilled onions and Swiss cheese.  

 The burgers have been named&quot;Best in Kansas City&quot;by a number of polls consistently over the past 20+ years. Westport Flea Market gets their beef from McGonigle&apos;s Meat Market , a famous Kansas City butcher shop that is nationally known for their steaks and other cuts of meat. It&apos;s been awhile since I&apos;ve done an entry on a butcher shop. The next time I go to Kansas City, I need to take a large cooler with me and get some beef from McGonigle&apos;s and do a Road Tips entry on the place. 

 A waitress/bartender came over and greeted me after a bit. She asked if I wanted something to drink and I asked back,&quot;Do you have Boulevard Pale Ale on tap?&quot; Actually, that was a pretty stupid question - any beer bar worth their salt in Kansas City has Boulevard Pale Ale on tap. She said that they did and wondered if I was ready to order some food. I had noticed in the short time that I was there that a guy was calling out people&apos;s names over an in-house P.A. system and they would go to a window and pick up their food orders. I said,&quot;Do I order food from you?&quot; 

 She said,&quot;Yep! We&apos;ll call out your name and you pick up your food at the window over there.&quot; She pointed at a small dining area just beside the bar area. &quot;There&apos;s a small condiment bar down there and you dress your food with lettuce, tomatoes, pickles, whatever.&quot; 

 I said,&quot;Well, I understand your burgers are pretty good.&quot; 

 &quot;The best in town,&quot;she quickly shot back.  

 I ordered up a burger, medium. She asked,&quot;You want cheese on it? Cheddar, Swiss, pepperjack...&quot; I stopped her at pepperjack.  

 She then asked,&quot;You want any grilled mushrooms, bacon ?&quot; I said mushrooms sounded great. And I got a choice of sides with the burger, as well. Curly fries, cole slaw or cottage cheese were my choices, but for an upcharge I could get onion rings. I wasn&apos;t certain I wanted fries, but cottage cheese sure sounded good to me.  

 After about 15 minutes, I heard my name called over the P.A. and I went over to the pick up window to get my burger. The condiment bar featured onions, pickles, lettuce, tomatoes and some other things. I got some onions, pickles and the tomato slices, though small, looked very fresh for the time of year.  

 
Sitting down with the burger, well... You ever have food sat down in front of you and the smell of it is so good that you KNOW that it will be good? That&apos;s what the Flea Market burger smelled like. There were a gob of fresh grilled mushrooms on and around the burger that was covered with a thick blanket of pepperjack cheese. 

 My first bite - it was ecstasy. Oh, my God! I immediately said,&quot;Ummmmm....&quot;as I chewed my first bite. The burger was juicy and overly flavorful. It had that old time flat grill seasoned taste to it. The juices just flowed out of the burger. The sesame-seeded lightly toasted bun was thick, but still pretty light to chew. It went well with the burger meat. About the only quibble I had with the burger was that it was probably more medium-rare than medium. I know that if my wife would have ordered a burger medium and it came out like this she would have sent it back. But I was fine with it. I&apos;ll just have to remember to order it medium-well the next time.  

 With the great tasting grilled mushrooms, the fresh and forward tasting onions and the tangy pickles, this burger was a winner. I immediately realized had to put it in the Top Ten of my Best Burger List . I&apos;ll have to figure out where I&apos;ll put it when I finally do my updated Best Burger List 2012 sometime in the coming weeks. I could easily see why it&apos;s been named the best burger in Kansas City for so many years. And I was also a little embarrassed that I hadn&apos;t had one of these burgers before this visit. As many times that I&apos;ve been in Kansas City in the past, I should have known about Westport Flea Market before this. 

 As I got finished, my waitress/bartender came over and asked how the burger was. &quot;Killer,&quot;I replied enthusiastically. And it was.  

 She handed me my bill and I got out my credit card to hand to her. She said,&quot;Uh, normally we don&apos;t take credit cards...&quot; 

 I said,&quot;Oh! OK! No problem!&quot; I got a $20 bill out of my pocket and handed it to her. She gave me $4.65 in change and I left $3 bucks for her tip. OK, so rookie mistake and something to remember for next time - Westport Flea Market only takes cash. They have an ATM in their billiards area for those who are caught short on cash for their food. 

 Before I left, I took a look around the place. Toward the street side of Westport Flea Market there&apos;s a dining room with a number of vintage beer cans that line the walls on shelves. This room was actually closed off for diners at this time, but they have two other dining areas - the one pictured above near where the pick-up window is located, and a dining area up near the bar.   

 
So, thanks to Tricia for turning me onto Westport Flea Market for a great burger. I was overly impressed with the place, the food, the service and and the history behind the business. Once again, I&apos;m somewhat embarrassed by the fact that I had no idea that a great burger place like this existed in a city that I&apos;ve been traveling to for over 25 years. I highly recommend going to Westport Flea Market if you&apos;re in K.C. and want to go to a fun and interesting place with a world-class burger.    

 
 
 June 21, 2012 in Bar and Grill , Beer Bars , Burger Joints , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (4) 

 | | | 
 
 Town Topic - Kansas City 
 
 Since 1937, Town Topic in Kansas City has been churning out burgers for the masses, 24 hours a day, 365 days a year. What started out as a White Castle , Town Topic uses a flat grill and smashes onions into the top of the burger patty during the cooking process. When they&apos;re done, the patties are flat and crispy on the outer fringes with caramelized onions embedded into the meat. I&apos;ve been wanting to try a Town Topic burger for quite sometime and I had the chance during a recent trip to Kansas City. ( Photo courtesy of Serious Eats.com )  

 There are three Town Topic locations in the greater Kansas City area - the one on Broadway just north of Southwest Blvd. that I went to ( see map ), another one literally around the corner and three short blocks away on Baltimore ( see map ), and a third location in what was the old Valentine Diner in suburban Shawnee Mission, KS ( see map ). Only the Broadway location is open 24 hours, the other two close around 7 p.m.  

 The original Town Topic opened in 1937 as a White Castle just down the street from the current Broadway location. Owner Claude Sparks opened to little fanfare and rang up $21.00 in sales on his opening day. A few years later, Sparks said good-bye to White Castle and opened his first Town Topic diner four blocks north on Broadway in the Crossroads section just south of downtown Kansas City. The Baltimore Ave. location opened a few years later, and in the late 80&apos;s the Shawnee Mission Town Topic location opened. Today, Town Topic is still owned by the Sparks family with Scott Sparks running all three locations.  

 There&apos;s a somewhat large parking lot next to the Town Topic on Broadway. Actually, I think there are more parking spaces than seats in the little restaurant (I counted - it seats 13 with a stand-up counter along one window on which to eat). I was a little worried I&apos;d be able to get into Town Topic as it was just before 1 p.m. and I knew that it was a pretty popular place during the day. But I was able to get in with no problems. I found a stool at the end of the counter and took a look at the menu on the wall behind the counter.  

 
While burgers are the main item on the menu, Town Topic is also known for their breakfasts, homemade chili and thick milkshakes. I&apos;ve been told that many a late night partier has downed Town Topic&apos;s&quot;Truckstop Omelet&quot;- a four-egg omelet stuffed with hashbrowns, cheese and your choice of sausage, bacon or ham. It sounds somewhat similar to a&quot;Magic Mountain&quot;that has satisfied the late night hunger cravings of drunks for years at Ross&apos;Restaurant in Bettendorf, IA.   

 The burgers at Town Topic aren&apos;t very thick, so I ordered up a double cheeseburger with everything from one of the three waitresses working behind the counter that day. And because they aren&apos;t very thick, it doesn&apos;t take long for a burger to show up in front of you.  

 
The crusty outer shell of the meat patty sealed in the juices and flavor of the burger. I&apos;m guessing the flat griddle that the burgers are cooked on is probably close to 70 years old and it makes for some great flavoring to the burgers. The burger, itself, was pretty good sized (I&apos;d read where they were the size of White Castle&quot;sliders&quot;- they were much bigger than that.) and they easily covered the somewhat average bun. While I still have a slight aversion to&quot;smashed&quot;burgers, I&apos;m quickly warming up to the concept thanks to the taste of the burgers like the one at Town Topic. I&apos;m glad I got a double as a single would have been overwhelmed by the bun. 

 And the burger was good at Town Topic. I can easily see why thousands of people have craved their burgers since 1937. The place is a local institution in Kansas City and full of nostalgia and history. While I&apos;m not overly certain that I&apos;d race back to Town Topic, I&apos;m sure I&apos;ll go back at some point in time. And like it&apos;s been since the 1940&apos;s, the original Town Topic will be exactly the same on my next visit, whether it be later this year or in three years. 

 
 
 April 26, 2012 in Burger Joints , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 KC Smoke Burgers - Kansas City 
 
 On a visit to Kansas City just before the end of 2011, I was in the Westport area of Kansas City looking up the new location for Vinyl Renaissance , a record store/audio dealer in the greater Kansas City area. The owner of Vinyl Renaissance had invited me to stop by his new store on West 39th St. and I made my way there during the middle part of the day. As I was going down W. 39th, just inside the Missouri/Kansas border, I happened to look over and see a place called KC Smoke Burgers . After my visit to Vinyl Renaissance, I decided to back down the street and have lunch at this burger place. ( see map ) 

 KC Smoke Burgers opened in December of 2010 in what was the former Jerusalem Cafe, a Middle Eastern restaurant that was once one of three locations around Kansas City. Owner Farid Azzeh decided that there were too many similar restaurants in the immediate area and came up with a concept of a smoked burger restaurant. After remodeling the restaurant into a burger place, KC Smoke Burgers was born. 

 They grill the burgers first, then they put them in an enclosed pot with wood chips on the bottom, the burger on a little grill and a pot top over the burger. Leaving it in the smoke pot for a short time closing out the cooking process gives the burger a hearty smoked taste. (Photo courtesy of the Arnot family.) 

 It was just after the noon rush and a number of professionals, quite possibly from the Kansas University Medical Center which is just two blocks away across State Line Road, were finishing up their lunch. (KC Smoke Burgers&apos;web site is geographically challenged. They say they are located in Kansas and not Missouri.) A booth in the corner was open and a waitress took me over there. She asked me if I wanted anything to drink.&quot;We have Pepsi products,&quot;she said. 

 I asked if they had Boulevard Beer , which is a pretty stupid question because nearly every bar/restaurant/barbecue joint/burger joint in Kansas City has Boulevard Beer. She said,&quot;We don&apos;t serve alcohol here.&quot; 

 Whaaaaaat? A burger joint with no beer? A red flag popped up in my head. What kind of place was this? I just got a glass of water instead. 

 The inside of KC Smoke Burgers wasn&apos;t all that big. It featured a high ceiling with an arched wood beam across the length of the restaurant. Tables and booths were throughout the place offering seating to about 40 to 50 people at a time. Above the front door was a plaster mural of some of the buildings along the Plaza, one of the municipal icons of Kansas City. There&apos;s an outdoor seating area that was shut down for the winter. 

 
On the concrete brick walls was a bunch of graffiti. Interestingly, it appeared that most of the graffiti was done by people with similar penmanship. Graffiti reached from the floor to the ceiling. It was sort of interesting and strangely weird in a sort of forced way of decorating.  

 The menu at KC Smoke Burgers features a number of basic burgers, as well as a handful of specialty burgers. They have a lamb burger with ground lean lamb meat and topped with a garlic cucumber sauce. They also had a gyro burger that featured a 50/50 mix of ground lamb and beef, mixed with Greek spices and topped with Greek Tzatiki sauce. They also had a Kansas City variation of the Twin Cities&quot;Jucy (Juicy) Lucy&quot;stuffed cheeseburger. 

 Their basic burgers featured a Danger Zone Fire smoke burger topped with jalapenos and chopped habaneros, as well as pepper jack cheese. They also have a Bacon cheese smoke burger, as well as a Challenge burger - something that evidently very spicy. 

 In addition to burgers, KC Smoke Burgers has all beef hot dogs (including Chicago-style hot dogs and chili dogs), Philly cheesesteak sandwiches, grilled chicken sandwiches, a gyros sandwich (old habits from a former Mediterranean restaurant are hard to die), and something called a grilled chicken gyros sandwich. 

 I decided to go with the Bacon cheeseburger and you get your choice of one of six different types of cheese. I took pepper jack cheese and I asked if I could get mushrooms along with the burger. It cost 50 cents more, but I didn&apos;t care. 

 It takes awhile to get a cooked burger at KC Smoke Burger. I&apos;m sure between the grilling, then the smoking process it&apos;s going to take awhile. I was hoping that they didn&apos;t overcook it. When the girl brought out my burger and took it off the smoke pot and placed it on the lower part of the bun, I could tell from the hardness of the meat that it was overcooked. But the the presentation was nice including the branded&quot;KCSB&quot;in the top of the bun. 

 
Even though I wasn&apos;t looking to get fries, they came with the burger. The smoky smell from the smoke pot was still in the air as I doctored up my burger with pickle slices, lettuce, a tomato slice and sliced onions that came with the meal. 

 The bacon was thin and pretty pedestrian when it comes to bacon. The burger was definitely overcooked and not very flavorful. Actually, about the only thing I could taste was the smoke flavor. And I really couldn&apos;t taste the mushrooms - I had to stop once just to pull the toppings off and look to see if they had actually put the mushrooms on the burger. They had, but they were grilled down to almost nothing. 

 I had a few fries and they were cool, limp, mushy and basically lifeless. I ate what I could of the burger and left the fries on the plate. When the waitress came over to take my plate and leave my bill she asked how it was.&quot;Good,&quot;I said, knowingly lying. It wasn&apos;t. 

 I can&apos;t give KC Smoke Burgers any type of glowing recommendation. I can&apos;t give it even a glimmer of a recommendation. The burger was overcooked, it was too much of a smoky taste to it. The fries were bad. It just wasn&apos;t a good dining experience. You may want to try it if you get to Kansas City to see if you like it. But I certainly won&apos;t go back. 

 

 
 
 March 26, 2012 in Burger Joints , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Woodyard BBQ - Kansas City, KS 
 
 Once again, I&apos;m sorry that I don&apos;t have the name of the person who sent me an e-mail last summer telling me that I had to go to Woodyard Barbeque on the Kansas side of Kansas City. I do remember that I was told that it wasn&apos;t much to look at as far as atmosphere is concerned, but to overlook all that because the food was pretty good. On one trip to Kansas City just before the end of the year, I had dinner at Woodyard Barbeque on Merriam Lane in Kansas City, KS. ( see map )  Merriam Lane runs parallel to Interstate 35, just before it meets up with Interstate 635 that takes people from Johnson County in Kansas up to Kansas City International Airport . I used to make that run years and years ago when I worked for a company in southwest suburban Olathe for about five years back in the 80&apos;s when I first started to travel for work. I know I had passed Woodyard Barbeque hundreds of times over the years on trips to Kansas City, but it turns out that it has only been open as a full time barbeque house for about 10 years.  

 It was a cold night when I drove down Merriam Lane past warehouses, industrial businesses and other non-descript commercial buildings. Set back from a street a bit is the old farm house that serves as the nerve center for Woodyard Barbeque. I drove past the place and then doubled back and pulled into the parking lot in front of the place. There was a faint smell of smoky wood in the air and it was coming from the large brick smoker located in front of the house. It was the smoke remnants of the meat that was cooked earlier in the day.  

 There is an outside patio - actually a couple of them that I saw. There&apos;s one that attached to the front of the house and another one across the lane from the house to the west. The patios feature picnic tables and antique-looking metal tables and chairs. It was very rustic in its appearance. Since it was cold, of course, no one was seated outside. But I was told that in the summertime, especially on the weekends, the patios can get packed.  

 
The inside of the main building for Woodyard Barbeque featured a small dining room next to the counter where you order your food. A couple guys were in there enjoying their barbeque at the old farm-style wooden tables. A large picture of Guy Fieri , host of Diners, Drive-ins and Dives on the Food Network . I went up to the counter and a guy greeted me. I said,&quot;Guy&apos;s been here?&quot;  

 He said,&quot;Oh, yeah. He did a piece on us a couple years ago.&quot; I found the video for Woodyard Barbeque from Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives on You Tube:  

 

 Even though there was a big board with all the food they do at Woodyard Barbeque, t he guy at the counter asked if I needed a menu . I did and he pointed out some basic printed menus in a bin on the wall next to the counter. He asked,&quot;First time here?&quot;  

 I told him it was and that I had been told about this place by someone. I said,&quot;This place looks pretty interesting and it smells pretty good, so far.&quot; 
 

 He told me that Woodyard Barbeque had been at this location for over 60 years, and they&apos;d been doing barbeque for about 30 years. And just within the past 10 years that they started to sell barbeque full time.  

 The genesis of Woodyard Barbeque began back in 1913 when Frank Schloegel (pronounced SCHLAY-gul) opened the Southside Coal Company near the Westport area of Kansas City where he and his son, Frank, Jr., sold heating coal to customers around Kansas City. Once fuel oil took over for coal heating, Frank, Jr. moved the business to the current location in the 50&apos;s and changed the name to Southside Patio and Wood. He sold wood for customers that still needed wood for heat, but he also sold patio bricks, lawn ornaments, sand and other things that people would ask for.  

 With the advent of the barbeque craze in Kansas City, Frank, Jr. began to provide other barbecue joints in the area the apple, pecan, cherry, hickory or oak wood they used to cook their barbeque.  During the weekends, Frank, Jr. would fire up his grill and cook free food for his customers over the wood that he supplied to other barbeque vendors.  

 His son, Frank III, took over the business and continued the practice of smoking meats on the weekend. But he took it a step farther as he began to smoke meats for charity fundraisers and church groups. Because his smoked meat was so good, Frank III was pressured into opening a restaurant that served barbeque. Initially, it was only opened on weekends, but about 10 years ago, Frank Schloegel IV - yep, the fourth generation son, decided to open through the week (they&apos;re closed on Sundays).  

 It became a family thing for the Schloegels - Frank IV&apos;s sisters helped lay bricks in the patio out front. His cousin helped with the design of the large brick smoker and his brother-in-law helped him build it. Today, Frank IV&apos;s cousin Mark O&apos;Bryan is the pitmaster, smoking the meats on a nearly daily basis. And former manager Joe Daly is now a co-owner of the place along with Frank Schloegel IV. 

 I&apos;m not certain, but it may have very well been Joe Daly at the counter that particular visit. He was showing me pictures of Frank Schloegel III who still comes in from time to time to talk barbeque with the steady customers they get in the summertime. &quot;Wintertime, we&apos;re a little more slow at night,&quot;he told me. &quot;But we still have a pretty good lunch crowd. And we do a bunch of Christmas-time catering. We can do groups as small as 10 or as large as 10,000.&quot;  

 I looked through the menu, trying to find some sort of a sampler platter. They had the usual ribs, brisket, pulled pork, chicken, turkey, ham, and sausage on the menu. They had a combo that had two ribs, a chicken leg, sausage and brisket. I&apos;m not big on smoked chicken and I would have rather had pulled pork than sausage. Just under that, they had a four meat combo platter. I took the pulled pork, ham and double brisket. &quot;You don&apos;t want any burnt ends,&quot;he asked me.   

 &quot;Naw,&quot;I replied. &quot;I know a lot of people think of burnt ends as a delicacy, but I&apos;ve never warmed up to&apos;em.&quot;  

 He said,&quot;We have a burnt end chili that is to die for.&quot; I told him that I thought I had enough food for that particular visit. But at the last moment, I asked if I could get a couple baby-back rib samples - they sold them for $1.75 each. He asked me what side I wanted and I took their baked beans over cheesy corn, potato salad or cole slaw. I grabbed a couple beers to take to my table while I waited for the food to show up.  

 The guy brought out the meet platter and the ribs about five minutes after I ordered them. Man, this was a lot of food for $13.50! He told me that the barbecue sauce was over by the door. They had two different types of homemade sauces - an original that was a sweet Kansas City style, and a hot that had a sweet and peppery taste. The guy seated at the table near the sauce dispensers said to me,&quot;The hot isn&apos;t all that hot.&quot; He was right - it had a little spiciness to it, but it wasn&apos;t overpowering in heat. 

 
I dug in and grabbed a rib first. Big and thick with succulent pork, the ribs are dry rubbed with a homemade concoction that includes garlic, cayenne, sea salt, lemon pepper and three spices that you don&apos;t normally associate with barbeque - ground cloves, ground cardamom and ground tumeric, three spices you&apos;d usually find in Indian food. The meat was moist, tender and pulled effortlessly off the bone. One thing they don&apos;t do at Woodyard Barbeque is pull the skin off the back of the ribs like other places will. It helps keep the moisture in and it&apos;s easy to peel off during the eating process. (I&apos;m gonna have to try that the next time I do ribs. I have a good friend who taught me to take the skin off. It&apos;s a pain in the ass to do, but he says that&apos;s the way to do it. I may beg to differ after having the ribs at Woodyard Barbeque.) The combination of the faint smoke taste and the rub concoction gave the baby back rib a wonderful taste sensation. It was very good even without any sauce added to it.  I made quick work of the two ribs I had.  

 I dug into the pulled pork next. It may have been some of the best pulled pork that I&apos;d ever had. It was moist, flavorful and had a hint of smoke. With a little bit of the homemade hot sauce, it was fabulous. I immediately wished I would have gotten a double portion of the pulled pork instead of the brisket.  

 The brisket was, eh! Actually, it was a little cold as it wasn&apos;t heated up enough (I&apos;m sure they smoke a lot of their meat and refrigerate it as a number of barbecue houses do these days). It was OK, but it was far from the best brisket I ever had. I was disappointed in the brisket, to say the least.  

 The ham was very good, but not anywhere as good as the pulled pork. The ham was thinly sliced, had a great cured smoke flavor to it. I was sort of craving ham that particular day and I&apos;m glad I got it. 

 The baked beans were good, not outstanding, but good enough. They were good without adding any additional barbeque sauce, as I like to do. But they weren&apos;t anything special, even with the sauce.   

 I got back up to get some more barbecue sauce and by this time another gentleman had joined the guy at the table next to the sauce dispensers. I heard him say,&quot;Man, I love this chili!&quot; I looked over and he had a bowl of Woodyard Barbeque&apos;s famous burnt end chili and it did look very good. It had large chunks of pork burnt ends, and was thick and rich. I thought about taking some to go with me and heating it up in the morning in the microwave. But after I finished what I could of my meal, I decided that I&apos;d come back and get pulled pork and a bowl of chili the next time.  

 So, my scorecard for Woodyard BBQ - Baby back ribs = Excellent. Pulled pork = May have been the best pulled pork I&apos;ve ever had. Ham = Above average. Brisket = Below average. Sauces = Average. Baked Beans = Average. Ambiance = Interesting. History = Overly interesting.  

 Woodyard Barbeque is not a fancy place, even for a regular Kansas City-style barbeque joint. If you can get past the fact that it&apos;s a little rugged and rustic, the food at Woodyard Barbeque was - overall - very good. I even left with a smoky wood smell on my clothes. The ribs and pulled pork more than made up for the short fall in the quality of the brisket. Next time, I&apos;m going for more pulled pork and a bowl of chili.  

 
 
 March 19, 2012 in Barbecue , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Shanghai Boy - Lee&apos;s Summit, MO 
 
 Kevin and Chris used to work at an old dealer that I called on - Accent Sound - in Overland Park, KS. When the owner retired, no one stepped up to buy the business and the employees sort of scattered in the wind, ending up at other audio stores - or in Kevin and Chris&apos; situation - they opened their own place, Soundbytes KC . One day when I was visiting earlier this year, Kevin came in with a cheeseburger. It smelled great. I asked, &quot;Where did you get that, Kev?&quot; 

 He said, &quot;Shanghai Boy.&quot; 

 I said, &quot;Shanghai Boy? That Chinese restaurant about a mile west of here?&quot; 

 Kevin replied, &quot;Yep! You wouldn&apos;t think a Chinese restaurant would make a good cheeseburger, but these guys do.&quot; I made a note to stop at Shanghai Boy at some point. Earlier this fall, I had the opportunity to do so. 

 The story I got from Kevin and Chris about the place was Shanghai Boy is housed in what was an old Dairy Sweet or something like that. It was a fast food restaurant with 10 letters in its name and they sold ice cream, hence the ice cream cone above the Shanghai Boy sign. The new owners bought letters to replace what was on the original sign and came up with the name of Shanghai Boy because, well, it had 10 letters in that name, too. 

 I took off down the street after leaving Soundbytes KC and headed west toward Shanghai Boy ( see map ). Actually, I accidentally passed Shanghai Boy - I passed the first entrance and when I realized I&apos;d done that I tried to get into the second entrance, but that was blocked with a vehicle trying to get out onto busy SW 3rd St. Not wanting to hold up traffic, I went around the block and pulled into the parking lot. 

 The inside of Shanghai Boy is pretty non-descript. It looks like any fast food joint with cramped booths with two or four person tables. With the large windows letting in the sunshine and the fluorescent lighting, you could definitely say it was well lit. 

 
The menu for Shanghai Boy is on a series of boards above the front counter. Interestingly enough, most of the prices of the food are either incomplete or missing on the menu. While most of the menu is Chinese food, there is board off to the side that had their burgers listed. A guy in front of me ordered Chinese, as did a couple directly behind me in line. But I followed Kevin&apos;s suggestion and got a double cheeseburger with everything. Everything is lettuce, tomato, onion, pickles, mustard and ketchup. 

 I got the burger and took it to the car. I found that I didn&apos;t have any water, so I drove down the street to a Quik Trip and got a bottle of water to have with the burger. I sat in the parking lot of the Quik Trip and unwrapped the burger. 

 
It didn&apos;t look any different from most fast food burgers that are out there. It had a sesame seed bun that covered the two cheeseburger patties. The veggies and condiments were on the bottom bun under the patties. The taste of the burger was pretty good. The bun was woefully dry, however, and as I&apos;ve said many times in the past, the mark of a great burger is the bun. You have a dried out or overly chewy bun and it really detracts from the overall taste of the burger. 

 But the smell of that burger is exactly what I remember from the one I smelled when Kevin brought it into his store - it had a that great, flat griddle smell to the burger and the patties were a wonderful taste. There was a little too much lettuce, but overall it was an above average burger. What kept it from being a truly outstanding burger is the bun. Too dry and that was too bad. 

 Shanghai Boy is a pretty good place to get a burger if you&apos;re not willing to patronize any of the fast food chains - like me. I don&apos;t know about their Chinese food, but the burger was better than you&apos;d find at most fast food places. I&apos;d rather give my money to a mom and pop operation than a big corporate chain any day. I just wish the buns at Shanghai Boy weren&apos;t so dry. 
 
 December 14, 2011 in Burger Joints , Chinese , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Blanc Burgers + Bottles - Leawood, KS 
 
 I&apos;ve been wanting to stop at Blanc Burgers + Bottles for quite sometime, ever since I first read about the place in a local Kansas City magazine a couple years ago. They&apos;re known for not only their delectable gourmet burgers, but for their large and eclectic selection of beer and wine. On a recent trip to K.C., I went to the south Kansas City Blanc Burgers location in the Mission Farms shopping area of suburban Leawood ( see map ). 

 Actually, the Blanc Burgers location in Leawood is one of three locations for Blanc Burgers. The original location opened in Westport in 2008 when chef Josh Eans and three investors opened the doors. The road Eans took to becoming a chef was not like other chefs. First of all, he had no experience working in a restaurant growing up. Many chefs either started out working in a restaurant or their family was in the restaurant business. Eans had an academic scholarship to Arizona State University with hopes of becoming a doctor down the line, but dropped out after a year and moved back to Kansas City to re-evaluate his life. It was during this time back in Kansas City when he met his wife-to-be, Abbey-Jo.  

 ( Josh Eans pictured at right )  

 Living in a rental house in suburban Kansas City, Josh and Abbey-Jo talked about what they would like to do with their lives. They talked about owning a restaurant and Abbey-Jo came up with the idea of going to culinary school together. Josh and Abbey-Jo enrolled in the Le Cordon Bleu/Scottsdale Culinary Academy in Arizona. After graduating from there, Josh first worked at the Sea Island Resort in Georgia before getting a job as a line cook apprentice at Seeger&apos;s, a now-closed upscale restaurant in Atlanta. 

 Now married and expecting their first child, Josh and Abbey-Jo decided that back home in Kansas City would be a good place to raise a kid, so they moved back to the area. Josh took a job on the line at the upscale 40 Sardines restaurant (which, too, is now closed).   

 During his time at 40 Sardines, Josh met Ernesto Peralta, Jr. (pictured at left) who was a bartender for the upscale Capital Grille in Kansas City . Peralta and his wife, Jennifer Price, were looking to do their own restaurant/bar and recruited Eans as a consultant in the project. A co-worker with Peralta, Eddie Crane, was also one of the partners of the new restaurant which eventually became The Drop , an acclaimed bistro near the Westport area of Kansas City, MO. Eans became the chef at The Drop as well as their sister restaurant, Martini Corner .  

 As The Drop was developing into a new dining destination for foodies across the Kansas City area, Eans, Peralta and his wife, as well as David McMullin came up with the Blanc Burgers concept, seeing that there was a void in the market place for upscale burgers. The four formed their own restaurant company, The Circle Restaurant Group .   

 Josh Eans moved from The Drop to Blanc Burgers + Bottles to become the executive chef. The first Blanc Burgers opened in the Westport area in March of 2008. It was an immediate hit with people with their burgers made from corn/grain/alfalfa fed beef from California (the group found that customers didn&apos;t care for the grass-fed Kansas beef that was suddenly becoming the rage across the Midwest for natural beef foods). The second location in Leawood opened in 2009 and a third location opened in January of this year up in Omaha. The group opened a more downscale burger joint in Lee&apos;s Summit, MO called B2, but it closed up after about a year in business. It appears the upscale burger is what people want. So much so that the group closed down their original Westport location and moved to a much larger building in the Country Club Plaza area in 2010.  

 In addition to using natural beef in all their burgers, Blanc Burgers uses locally baked brioche buns, as well as locally grown produce and herbs. Plus they make their own ketchup and their own pickles. The one thing that will set Eans off quicker than anything is when a customer asks for store-bought bottled ketchup instead of his homemade condiment.  

 The lunch rush had subsided when I made my first visit to Blanc Burgers. I had my choice of sitting out on their patio as it was a lovely early fall day in Kansas City, or their narrow, but well-lit dining area, or at the bar. The selection of bottles - wine, beer, liquor and pop - behind the bar was intriguing to me, so I opted for a seat there. The very personable and helpful bartender greeted me, gave me a menu and asked if I wanted anything to drink. The chalkboard behind the bar featured a number of beers and natural soda pops that Blanc Burgers rotates in and out on a seasonal basis. One of my favorite Oktoberfest beers is Bob&apos;s 47 from the local Kansas City brewery, Boulevard . They had just gotten them in and I ordered one of those.  

 

 Bright and white is the interior design of the Blanc Burgers. The main walls are white as are the chairs and table tops. Contemporary lighting with white lamp shades hung low from the ceiling. Peralta&apos;s wife, Jenifer, came up with the color concept for Blanc, which, of course, means white in French.  

 Blanc Burgers + Bottles has a very impressive roster of beers to choose from. I was very surprised to see that they featured Capital Brewing Company&apos;s Supper Club beer - a beer you don&apos;t find that far away from their brewery just outside of Madison, WI. It turned out that they were out of it that day or I would have gotten one just to have one. Supper Club is one of my all-time favorite beers.  

 And even though I&apos;m not a pop drinker any longer, I was equally impressed with the list of soda pops Blanc Burgers had to offer. Many of them were eclectic and made from natural ingredients. They had a Thai basil and clove soda pop, as well as sarsaparilla, birch beer pop, and lemon-lime 7 up. They also had bottles of Mexican Coca-Cola , the more sweet - and some say better tasting - Coca-Cola.  

 The burger menu was intriguing. Topping the list was an American Kobe beef burger served with a mustard/mayo aioli sauce, truffle butter and topped with watercress greens on a salt and pepper brioche bun. They have the &quot;Classic&quot; burger that they top with aged white cheddar, lettuce, tomato and a red onion slice along with their homemade pickles, ketchup and mustard and served on a sesame-seed bun. They also had the &quot;Oscar&quot; burger that is basically the same thing as a steak Oscar, only on a bun. The take the American Kobe beef and top it with poached blue crab, asparagus and bernaise aioli, and serve it on a rosemary brioche bun. 

 In addition to the burgers on the menu, Blanc Burgers also features a ground pork burger, a chicken sandwich, a grilled mahi-mahi sandwich and a couple of vegetarian burgers. They also feature a small list of salads and appetizers , as well as a number of handful of sides , such as hand-cut French fries, truffle fries, sweet potato fries and Boulevard beer-battered onion rings.  

 Two burgers that caught my eye were the &quot;Au Poivre&quot; burger - a cracked black pepper encrusted burger, topped with a creamy green peppercorn sauce, grilled onions and watercress, then served on a salt and pepper brioche. The other one - the &quot;Bison&quot; - featured a lean bison burger topped with a fried egg along with peppadew jam, peppadew havarti cheese, red onion, mayo and lettuce on a four seed brioche bun. Oh man - both sounded wonderful.   

 As I said, the bartender was very personable and was eager to answer any questions for me. I told him that I was having trouble figuring out what I wanted and he immediately stopped me. &quot;The Au Poivre burger is, hands down, my favorite on the menu.&quot;  

 I said, &quot;That was easy. The Au Poivre is one that I was looking at.&quot;  

 He asked what the other ones were and I said, &quot;Oh, just the Bison burger.&quot;  

 &quot;The Bison burger is very good, too,&quot; he said. &quot;But I just sort of like that little pepper &apos;pop&apos; in my mouth with the Au Poivre.&quot;  

 He asked if I wanted any sides and the Boulevard onion rings looked intriguing. &quot;But I couldn&apos;t finish a whole order,&quot; I told him. 

 The bartender immediately replied, &quot;I&apos;ll put in a half-order for you. How about that?&quot; 

 Sold!  

 When the burger came out, it looked scrumptious. The burger had an ample amount of cracked peppercorns around it, the green peppercorn sauce wasn&apos;t drenched over the top, but rather subdued under the burger patty. And the salt and pepper brioche was light and spongy. From the first bite, I knew I had a winner. The peppery taste of the burger was just exquisite. The bun turned out to be a little chewy, but still light enough not to be a detriment to the overall taste. I tried some of the homemade ketchup and it was sweet and had a more strong taste than regular ketchup. It was very good.  

 
The onion rings were also very good. The Boulevard beer batter was flavorful and flaky. They were very, very good. It was a tough lunch to beat. 

 After I finished up, my bartender asked, &quot;So, how did you like the burger?&quot; 

 I said, &quot;Awesome!&quot; 

 He said, &quot;Yeah, it is, isn&apos;t it? I just love all that pepper taste in my mouth with every bite I take.&quot;  

 The burger at Blanc Burgers + Bottles was outstanding. The beef was overly flavorful, even without the cracked pepper it in. The natural taste of everything from the toppings to the beef to the bun was simply superb. Josh Eans is looking to expand throughout the Midwest and I&apos;m hoping that at some point he&apos;ll look at expanding into Iowa so Blanc Burgers will be closer to me than Omaha or Kansas City. The burgers are a little more expensive than your regular burger joint, but not by much compared to chain restaurants. And the burger is a helluva lot better. Blanc Burgers is going to get a strong consideration when I do my Best Burgers List in 2012.  

   

 
 
 November 23, 2011 in Burger Joints , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Johnny&apos;s Hickory House Bar-B-Que - Mission, KS 
 
 Thanks to one of my dealers in the Kansas City area who mentioned Johnny&apos;s Hickory House Bar-B-Que in passing during a conversation we had about barbecue caterers in the area, I had the pleasure of trying the place out on a recent visit to the arguable barbecue capital of the world. It&apos;s always great to find new barbecue places in and around Kansas City and I was eager to give Johnny&apos;s a try, considering I&apos;d never heard of the place before. 

 The origins of Johnny&apos;s Bar-B-Que begins in 1977 in the southwest Kansas City suburb of Olathe when a young Johnny White opened his first restaurant. He ran it for five years before selling it. He decided to open a new location in a building on Broadmoor Ave. in Shawnee Mission ( see map ). That location is still going strong today. Johnny&apos;s Bar-B-Que also has a location back out in Olathe ( see map ). 

 It also turns out that Johnny&apos;s Bar-B-Que was featured on the Food Network program, Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives and host Guy Fieri visited the restaurant in early 2010 as part of his show on Kansas City barbecue restaurants. Here&apos;s the segment on Johnny&apos;s from Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives - 

 

 Quite honestly, I didn&apos;t know that Fieri was there until I started doing research on Johnny&apos;s for Road Tips. Evidently, there is a big signed poster of Fieri and a &quot;wall tag&quot; that Fieri painted on the wall at Johnny&apos;s. I completely missed both on my visit there. But, then again, my wife says that I&apos;m not a very observant person. 

 I programmed in my GPS to take me north to Shawnee Mission - which, in itself, it completely confusing to me as I hear people in K.C. refer to Shawnee, Mission or Shawnee Mission. But there is no reference to Shawnee Mission on my GPS which then made me have it search for Johnny&apos;s Bar-B-Que, which it immediately found. It turns out that Shawnee Mission is an area of towns on the Kansas side of the border mainly between Kansas City, KS and Overland Park. Mission is the name of the town that Johnny&apos;s is in. Johnny&apos;s is a little tough to find in that it&apos;s nestled back off Johnson Drive at Metcalf. I have driven by Johnny&apos;s Bar-B-Que for years without knowing it was even there. (Once again, back to what my wife says about being observant.) 

 The parking lot of Johnny&apos;s is behind the building off of Broadmoor. It was just past 7 p.m. when I got there and there weren&apos;t a lot of cars in the lot. Good, it wasn&apos;t packed, so getting a table would be easy. I went into the building and came upon the front counter area where hundreds of bottles of barbecue sauce from around the nation were on display along with some articles on Johnny&apos;s from over the years. The lady who was waiting tables told me I could sit anywhere I like and I took a seat in a booth in the corner just inside the dining room. 

 
The dining area is brightly lit with a handful of televisions around the room. A large number of antique barn stars were on the walls. Booths bordered the dining room at Johnny&apos;s Bar-B-Que with a handful of four and six seater tables in the middle. The waitress gave me a menu and took my order for a beer. 

 The menu at Johnny&apos;s Bar-B-Que is not unlike many others around the Kansas City area. They feature burnt ends - when they&apos;re available. I&apos;m not a big fan of burnt ends, but some people consider them a delicacy. Of course, they have have ribs, barbecued chicken, beef brisket, ham and pulled pork, all smoked in Johnny White&apos;s huge self-designed and homemade in-house smoke room. The sides at Johnny&apos;s include baked beans, mac and cheese wedges (whatever that is), cole slaw, onion rings and french fries - or you can get &quot;frings&quot; which is a half order of fries and a half order of onion rings. 

 I always like to get the combinations when I go to a barbecue joint, especially a new one for me. Johnny&apos;s offered a two-meat dinner where you had your choice between brisket, pulled pork, ham, sausage, turkey or chicken. But it didn&apos;t offer anything like a half or quarter slab of ribs in the combo. I really wanted to try some of the brisket and some of the ribs. Then I looked over and saw that you could &quot;add a rib&quot; to your meal for $2.99. I figured that I&apos;d get the pulled pork and brisket, then get three pork ribs to go along with the meat. I ordered up a side of baked beans and a side of cole slaw. 

 

When the waitress brought the food to the table, I knew I&apos;d made a mistake in regard to the ribs. The pork ribs were huge! Plus the fact that the portions of the brisket and the pulled pork were generous, as well. Then, the sides were in pretty good sized serving cups, plus there were fries AND white bread slices served with the meal. The picture of the pork rib (above right) is after I&apos;d taken a couple bites off the end of it. They were big, meaty, slathered with sauce and very good. 

 The brisket was lean, sliced thin and also very good. The pulled pork was OK - above average - but not as good as the ribs or brisket. The cole slaw, huh uh. I had a bite and it was pretty bland. Same with the fries. Nothing special there. The baked beans were very good, however. And even though they didn&apos;t really need it, I still added some barbecue sauce to them. I guess Johnny&apos;s has a couple three barbecue sauces, but only one was made available to me at the table. But that&apos;s OK - I was more than stuffed by the time I figured I could have asked for different sauces. 

 Overall, I&apos;d have to say Johnny&apos;s Bar-B-Que was very good - a pleasant surprise to say the least. That was a lot of food for about $21 bucks plus a couple three beers. Next time I&apos;ll know not to order three ribs, but maybe only one. Still, there are dozens of barbecue places in the Kansas City area and I know I&apos;ve only scraped the surface of the ones that are around. I found a couple others that were featured in the &quot;Diners, Drive-Ins and Dives&quot; show that I&apos;ll have to try on future visits. Hopefully, they will all be as good as Johnny&apos;s Bar-B-Que is. 
 
 November 14, 2011 in Barbecue , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Kauffman Stadium - Kansas City 
 
 
 With the end of the 2011 Major League Baseball season today, it&apos;s always a melancholy time of the year for me. Summer is over, winter is closing in and, to me, there is nothing more lonely than a baseball field in the dead of winter. Oh, I know the playoffs and World Series are coming up, but for me baseball is over for the season. I may give a cursory glance at a playoff game on TV, but I don&apos;t like to watch the insipid network coverage of Major League Baseball. However, to get one last baseball fix in before it all ended, I had to go to Kansas City for some meetings last week and I was able to take a night out and go to Kauffman Stadium to see the Royals play the American League Central Champions Detroit Tigers . 

 People in Kansas City were optimistic before the season started that the young Royals ballclub was going to make a big splash this year. With one of the best minor league feeder systems in all of baseball, many observers felt that Kansas City could have a surprising year, but the majority of the baseball pundits felt the Royals were possibly a couple three years away from contending once again. Even with a quick start that saw them at and/or near the top of the division standings the first month of the season, the Royals faded quickly after losing at least five games in a row two times in the months of May and June. The Royals will end the season firmly entrenched in fourth place of the AL Central division. 

 With the anticipation of better days ahead for the Royals, Kansas City fans came out and supported the home team this season. Nearly 110,000 more people went through the gates of Kauffman Stadium this past season versus the 2010 season. And with the renovation of the stadium three seasons ago, it&apos;s much more of a fan-friendly environment - definitely on par or even above most major league baseball stadiums. 

 I had not been to the renovated stadium during my recent travels to Kansas City. I think the last time I was there was 2008 when I went to a game with a local dealer. At the time, renovation work was fully underway and was completed in time for the start of the 2009 season. I&apos;d been asked by a handful of Kansas City area people during my travels over the last couple of years if I&apos;d been out to the&quot;new stadium&quot;. I had to chuckle thinking that Kauffman Stadium has been around since 1973 when it was originally known as Royals Stadium. Although it wasn&apos;t really new, people in Kansas City felt it was new to them. 

 Since I knew I was going to be doing a lot of walking around to look at the renovated stadium, I got a standing room only ticket for the game against the Tigers. According to the chart at the ticket window, standing room only tickets run $10 bucks. But the lady at the ticket window said they only had $11 dollar standing room only tickets that evening. I was too dumbstruck to ask,&quot;Hey, what&apos;s the deal?&quot;, until I found out later that depending upon the night and who is in town to play the Royals standing room only tickets can run between $10 and $15 bucks. Actually, $11 bucks to attend a Major League Baseball game isn&apos;t too bad. 

 Upon entering the stadium, the first thing that struck me was how wide the concourses were compared to the pre-renovated Kauffman Stadium. Before the concourse under the grandstand was - maybe - 25 feet wide and when you tried to pack 30,000+ people into the place AND have the concession stands in the concourse, as well, it created bottlenecks and traffic jams of the most ungodly proportion. With the renovation, the concession stands were moved back about 20 feet giving people a wide walk way to and from their seats. 

 
The renovated stadium also offered a 360 degree concourse completely around the stadium - something the&quot;old&quot;stadium didn&apos;t have. They added seats, a sports bar, family amenities and renovated their famous fountains and put in a new scoreboard in center field. This new area also allowed fans to stand just behind the fountains and watch the action from the outfield - something I sort of like to do. The outfield concourse also features a&quot;Walk of Fame&quot;with bronze statues of the three Royals whose numbers have been retired - George Brett , Frank White and Dick Howser - along with a statue of Ewing and Muriel Kauffman who brought baseball back to Kansas City in 1969 and for whom the stadium is named after. 

 

Troubling to me, however, was the family fun area just past the outfield concourse area. It had a carousel, a video game room, playground equipment and a miniature golf course. Call me a traditionalist - or a fun-hater for kids - but I don&apos;t think I&apos;d take my kids to a ballpark to ride a carousel, play video games or have a round of miniature golf. 

 However, one area of in the outfield just beyond the left field concourse was a small baseball field called the&quot;Little K&quot;. It had an artificial surface and allowed for young kids to come onto the field and hit a few balls thrown to them by a worker. I thought this was a better thing for kids to do at a ballpark than ride a carousel or play miniature golf. Actually, this little kid (pictured bottom left), who probably wasn&apos;t much past the age of 3, was hitting the ball really well. He had an amazing swing for as little as he was. I was trying to set up my video camera on my phone to catch him in action, but he was done before I could get a quick video. 

 
Also along the left field concourse at Kauffman Stadium is the new Kansas City Royals Hall of Fame . Not only did it have exhibits and displays from the 42 years the Royals have been in existence, but it also had displays for the Kansas City Monarchs of the old Negro Baseball League , as well as some for the old Kansas City Athletics . 

 There was a theater that had a short video presentation on the history of baseball in Kansas City, a number of kiosks and wall-displays of former Kansas City greats who played for the Monarchs or Royals over the years. It also had historical timelines of baseball history in Kansas City, features on Royals Cy Young and Gold Glove Award winners, and a timeline of Ewing Kauffman&apos;s efforts to not only bring baseball back to Kansas City, but on his efforts to build a new stadium for his Royals. 

 

In a room with a large video display showing highlights of the 1985 World Series is the world championship trophy that the Royals won. I know this is really gonna rankle those of you who are huge St. Louis Cardinals fans because of the horrible call in Game Six that literally stole the World Series away from the Cards. But, to me, who is a fan of baseball, it was pretty neat to see up close. 

 Also in the Royals Hall of Fame was a display of 3,154 baseballs shaped into a huge number 5 for George Brett. The baseballs signified the number of hits Brett had in his 21 year career with the Royals. The bat that Brett used and the ball that he hit for his 3000 Major League hit late in the 1992 season are also on display embedded within the number 5. The Royals Hall of Fame had a guy standing near the display and he kept saying,&quot;Please do not touch the baseballs. They are suspended on metal rods and we don&apos;t want the balls to get dirty.&quot;And almost as soon as he said that, some 30-something rube went over and tried to grab one of the balls. I just stood there, dumbfounded. I sort of looked at the guy who tried to grab one of the balls, then I glanced at the Hall of Fame worker and sort of pointed at the guy. The worker sort of shook his head and said,&quot;I could scream&apos;Do not touch the baseballs&apos;at the top of my lungs and people would still want to touch them.&quot; 

 I said,&quot;Maybe you ought to just say nothing and when someone reaches out to touch a ball, yell&quot;Hey! Get away from the baseballs!&quot;He sort of chuckled over that. 

 One of the growing trends among major league baseball stadiums are in-house sports bars/lounges that serve food. Just beyond the right field wall is Rivals Sports Bar, the Kauffman Stadium sports bar that is open to the public. With a baseball theme and over two dozen televisions turned the Royals game it was actually a pretty cool place to hang out during the game. There was a little patio with waitress service next to it that overlooked the field just behind the fountains in right field. 

 
Above right is the custom made 360 degree circular bar at Rivals. It allowed for people to stand at the bar and easily watch the action through the floor to ceiling windows that looked out onto the field. Even though there was a pretty good crowd there that evening (just shy of 27,000 people came out - about 2/3rds the capacity of Kauffman Stadium), I heard one guy remark that this was the least amount of people he&apos;d ever seen in Rivals. 

 Of course, the game had to be played and I always like to get the first pitch of any Major League ball game that I attend. Here is the first pitch that evening from Kansas City&apos;s Luis Mendoza to the Tigers&apos; Austin Jackson . In the starting line-up that evening for the Royals were five guys (out of ten - including the designated hitter) who started their seasons in Omaha for the Royals AAA team . Three of those guys were playing for the Royals when I was there earlier this season (to see my entry on my visit to Werner Park in Omaha, click here ). As I said, the Royals have one of the best minor league systems - if not THE best minor league systems - in all of Major League Baseball. So there&apos;s cause for optimism among the Royals faithful for years to come. 

 I ventured up to the upper deck of the stadium to take a look around. They have two open areas that are sponsored by Proctor and Gamble that will allow people to stand and watch the game. There are designated standing room only areas along the outfield concourse areas, but I stood in a number of areas during this game and I wasn&apos;t hassled in the least. In fact, I had very helpful ushers ask me if I needed help finding my seat. When I told them I just wanted to stand to watch the game, they left me alone or, better yet, told me to enjoy myself. I found the staff at the renovated Kauffman Stadium to be overly friendly and helpful. 

 And, of course, if you&apos;re a regular reader of Road Tips you know that I have a scoreboard fetish when it comes to Major League ballparks. This is the Royals&apos;CrownVision scoreboard that is a marked improvement over their old scoreboard. The CrownVision scoreboard is 106 feet high by 85 feet wide. It was designed, built and installed by Daktronics , a Brookings, SD-based manufacturer of high-end sports scoreboards and video screens. It has 1800 lines of high definition resolution and features line-ups for both the offense and defense, stats for the batter, inning-by-inning scoring and the count and outs. The scoreboard will then shift to a huge video display to show instant replays in high definition. Although it isn&apos;t the neatest scoreboard I&apos;ve found in the Major Leagues, it was still pretty cool. 

 Beer and hot dogs are a staple for me at any ball game, major league or minor league. I always have to try the hot dogs at any given stadium. I got one of the Royals&apos;hot dogs from a concession stand for $4.75 and a 22 oz. Bud Light for $9.00. The hot dog was overcooked and a little dried out from the warming drawer they kept them in. I would have graded the hot dog a C because the taste wasn&apos;t actually all that bad. But I would have preferred a sizzling hot dog directly off the grill. The beer, however, was very cold. And I like cold beer at a ball game. 

 Walking around later in the game, I happened upon a hot dog stand out along the left field concourse. I sort of went up to the place - called the Dugout Dog House - and took a look at the various styles of hot dogs they had to offer. They had Chicago-style hot dogs with the tomatoes, pickle relish, sport peppers and the works, the Royal Bacon hot dog with bleu cheese and real bacon bits and chopped red onions, the Island Dog with smoked ham, pineapple slices, mandarin orange chunks, with cole slaw and teriyaki sauce, and the El Diablo Dog with chili, pepper cheese, and jalapeno peppers. I was contemplating getting the El Diablo until the guy in front of me turned and said,&quot;Man, the All-Star dog is the best. They put pulled pork on top of a dog, cover it in barbecue sauce, then put on pickles and cole slaw. Damn, is it good!&quot; 

 
The thought of any type of a tomato-based product on a hot dog or a brat almost turns my stomach. About the only tomato-based sauce I like on a brat or hot dog is the Secret Stadium Sauce at Miller Park in Milwaukee. But this guy talked so passionately about the All-Star dog that I had to give it a try. 

 The Dugout Dog House has either regular or foot long flat-grilled all beef hot dogs. The grill cook rolls the hot dogs to give them an even char on the outer casing. Just as I like&apos;em - hot off the grill. I followed the guy&apos;s lead in front of me and ordered a regular All-Star dog. 

 The grill cook pulled a plump all-beef hot dog off the grill, put it in the bun and then proceeded to slather it with copious amounts of pulled barbecue pork, topped with an equally large amount of cole slaw (pictured below left). Then he topped it off with dill pickle slices and a large squirt of barbecue sauce. I got a 16 oz. bottle of Bud Light to go along with it (although they did have a number of very good beers to choose from). The total cost for beer and specialty dog was $14.25. Ouch! 

 
But from the first bite I have to say it was worth the price. The bun was moist and light, the top of which was piled on with the cole slaw, pulled pork and barbecue sauce. Once you got past that, the grilled hot dog was rich and flavorful. It was so much better than the nearly lifeless hot dog I got earlier in the evening. This was just an outstanding combination of taste sensations. In fact, it was one of the all-time top hot dogs I&apos;ve ever had in my life. Remember, I&apos;m not big on a lot of tomato-based product on a hot dog, but having the pulled pork with the barbecue sauce on top was out of this world. 

 And I&apos;m not ashamed to admit that I went back later in the evening to get another one. However, this time it wasn&apos;t as good. They were getting ready to close up for the night after the 7th inning and the bun wasn&apos;t as moist and light as the first one, the hot dog wasn&apos;t quite as crisp as the first one. But the pulled pork and the cole slaw/barbecue sauce toppings were still wonderful. 

 I left soon afterward as the Royals ended up winning the game by a score of 10-2 . The&quot;new&quot;Kauffman Stadium is a great place to watch a ballgame and the amenities - including a truly outstanding hot dog from the Dugout Dog House - are major league worthy. But, it&apos;s going to be another six months before I get fired up to hear the crack of the ball hitting the bat, along with warmer temperatures, sizzling hot dogs and ice cold beer. Winter bums me out, but knowing that baseball isn&apos;t that far off is what keeps me warm. And a trip back to Kauffman Stadium next year is a must for me. Especially for an All-Star dog. 

 
 
 September 28, 2011 in Destinations , Dogs - Chili and Hot! , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (1) 

 | | | 
 
 Jose Pepper&apos;s - Overland Park, KS 
 
 Today, I give a shout out to Ryan Davis and his wife, RaeChelle. I met them earlier this summer during a baseball outing we had here in the Quad Cities.  RaeChelle Davis is the news anchor for WQAD , the local ABC affiliate, and is paired along side with another casual friend of mine, Jason Fechner . The Davis&apos;grew up in Kansas City and went to school at Western Kentucky . We talked about places in and around K.C., how beautiful the campus was at WKU, and, of course, my visit to Mariah&apos;s in Bowling Green, KY. (See the post on Mariah&apos;s  here .) We began to talk about restaurants around the greater Kansas City area and I was telling them about Oklahoma Joe&apos;s   and how much I liked it. RaeChelle asked me,&quot;Have you ever been to Jose Pepper&apos;s in Overland Park?&quot; 

 I told her that it didn&apos;t ring a bell. She said,&quot;Oh, my GOD! They have the best Mexican food in the whole world! When ever we go back home, we always stop at Jose Pepper&apos;s!&quot; She was describing this cheese sauce at the place - escindada con queso - that was simply to die for. As she was describing the taste sensation to me, I thought Ryan was going to cry. Anything that good deserved a visit.  

 I was in Kansas City recently and got into my hotel in Overland Park just after 9 p.m. one evening. I looked up Jose Pepper&apos;s on my GPS and found that it was only 1.3 miles away. I threw my bags in the room and programmed the GPS to take me to Jose Pepper&apos;s. In a long and round-about way (my GPS has a tendency to do that rather than use the real world approach of taking a left turn instead of three right turns) I found Jose Pepper&apos;s ( see map ). 

 I immediately realized that I&apos;d been there before.  

 About six years ago, I had just put on a new dealer in Overland Park. It was after closing time one night and I asked some of the sales crew if they wanted to go out and get something to eat. They suggested this Mexican restaurant that was tucked back in the corner of a strip mall off of Metcalf Ave. I remember the food was outrageously good and the margaritas were some of the best I&apos;d ever had. The problem was that on subsequent trips to Kansas City and hankering for Mexican food I couldn&apos;t remember the name of the place. I had an idea as to where it was and driving up and down Metcalf I couldn&apos;t seem to find it. I figured that it probably went out of business.  

 However, this recent night when I found it, I realized that one of the big reasons why I couldn&apos;t find it was because it was hidden by a big bank at the corner of 103rd and Metcalf. Sure enough, there it was. I couldn&apos;t remember the name of the place (as I usually can&apos;t), but I can sure remember the food and, generally, where it is.  

 Jose Pepper&apos;s is actually a small local chain of Mexican Food restaurants under the J.P.&apos;s Southwestern Cuisine banner. The parent company of J.P.&apos;s Southwestern Cuisine is North Star restaurants which runs 8 Jose Pepper&apos;s throughout Kansas City, one in Topeka and one in Wichita, and the Cactus Grill in suburban Leawood, KS. (click here   to see all the locations.) The original Jose Pepper&apos;s - the one at 103rd and Metcalf - opened in 1988.  

 Jose Pepper&apos;s has been getting some local notoriety lately - and not for the best type of P.R. They just settled a sexual harassment lawsuit that was brought on by an 18-year-old waitress who accused a former assistant manager at the Cactus Grill of inappropriately touching her and making sexual suggestions.  

 And earlier this year, a judge decided that a class action suit  against the chain could go forward after Jose Pepper&apos;s was found in violation of the Fair and Accurate Credit Transaction Act by printing more than five numbers of a customer&apos;s credit card number on their receipt. The lawsuit covers over 45,000 transactions between December of 2006 and December of 2007. The lawsuit could award each person who used their credit card at a Jose Pepper&apos;s or at the Cactus Grill during that period up to $1000. Understandably, Jose Pepper&apos;s lawyers say the lawsuit would be&quot;annihilating&quot;to the chain, but the judge allowed the lawsuit to proceed. 

 Well, I certainly didn&apos;t care about any lawsuits when I got into Jose Pepper&apos;s around 9:15 p.m. There were a few people in the bar area and just a handful of people in the dining room. I contemplated sitting in the bar and having dinner, but I ended up going for a booth along the wall in the dining room. The hostess guided me to the table, dropped off the menu and told me that they had a 2 for 1 special on Patron margaritas - $10 bucks for two 28 oz. margaritas. I immediately signed up for one of those. A young man brought over some fresh corn chips and salsa to get me started. 

 The menu at Jose Pepper&apos;s features a number of authentic Mexican foods including enchiladas, chimichangas, tamales - even seafood tacos featuring grilled mahi or shrimp. Oooo... I remember this place now. They had GREAT mahi tacos! San Diego style with the cabbage. Ummm.... That&apos;s why I kept trying to find the place. 

 The original hostess - also a waitress - brought my first margarita to the table. She said that another waitress would be helping me out. Not long after that, a younger girl - well below 20 years old - with braces on her teeth timidly approached me to see if I was ready to order.  

 I was leaning toward getting the fish tacos, but I&apos;d also been looking over the combination plates. The one that really caught my eye was the number 4 combo - a shredded beef hard shell taco, a pork tamale and a cheese enchilada. Only I asked if I could substitute a beef enchilada instead of the cheese enchilada. The young girl said,&quot;Oh, gee. I don&apos;t really know if we can. I can ask.&quot; I also got an order of the espinaca con queso cheese sauce. 

 I&apos;d downed my first margarita and was ready for the second one. When the young waitress brought out the espinaca, I asked her to bring me the second margarita. She said,&quot;I&apos;ll get someone to get that for you.&quot; It dawned on me that since she was under 21 she couldn&apos;t serve me a drink. The first waitress/hostess brought me my other margarita.  

 I do have to say that the espinaca con queso was absolutely outstanding and sinfully rich. The chunks of peppers they put in the cheese sauce gave it a little kick, but not enough that deterred from the overall taste sensation. While the bowl wasn&apos;t all that big, it was way too much for one person to eat.  But I did take a large chunk of cheese sauce out of the bowl.   

 I never really knew if the substitution I requested would make it to my plate or not. The waitress basically forgot about me and the food took an excruciatingly (it&apos;s a word - I looked it up) long time to get to my table. I was hoping that it was because the food was good and authentic, and not pre-made and micro-waved like you find at some Mexican restaurants. Finally, about 20 minutes after I ordered, my food showed up. The wait was worth it.  

 She was able to make the substitution of the cheese enchilada for the beef enchilada and the seasoning on the beef was outstanding. But the highlights of the meal were the pork tamale and the shredded beef taco, which was placed in its very own holder.  

 The pork tamale was just this side of heaven - flavorful, a nice corn meal outer shell with loads of seasoned sliced pork meat inside. The pork literally melted in my mouth. I&apos;m not big on really doughy tamales, but this one was not that oppressive. It was sensational.  

 For as much as I like grilled fish tacos, I&apos;m about as big a sucker for shredded beef tacos. And the shredded beef taco at Jose Pepper&apos;s was no exception.  The beef was tender and ripe with flavor. The taco shell was nice and crunchy. It was as close to the perfect taco that one could ask for. You&apos;re much more likely to find a shredded beef taco on the menu than one that features ground beef. This one was 4 star taco.  

 I couldn&apos;t finish my meal - I left a good portion of the corn meal dough tamale on the plate, but picked out the pork. I made quick work of the shredded beef taco and finished what I could of the beef enchilada. The meal was exactly what I remembered it to be six years prior - completely outstanding.  

 I will say that the biggest drawback was the service at Jose Pepper&apos;s. It took too long for the food to come and I was almost over-gorged on the chips and espinaca con queso dip by the time it finally showed up. Also, having an underaged girl serving me while I was ordering drinks was a minor hassle. (I ordered a Dos Equis beer when she brought me out my food and the other waitress didn&apos;t get it to me until my meal was nearly finished.) But the food was just outstanding and it was tough to beat the $5 dollar 28 oz. Patron margaritas. Times two.   

 I certainly have to thank Ryan and RaeChelle for mentioning Jose Pepper&apos;s. And I&apos;m overly glad that I was able to find it once again. Now that I know what I&apos;m looking for and where it is, it will be a staple during my trips to K.C. - just like Oklahoma Joe&apos;s has become for me.  I just hope that class action lawsuit doesn&apos;t hurt them in the long run.  

 
 
 November 29, 2010 in Kansas City , Mexican , Restaurants | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Oklahoma Joe&apos;s Barbecue - Olathe 
 
 While in Kansas City recently, I had just gotten back from a long trip out toward West Central Kansas and decided to try and find the newer of the two locations of Oklahoma Joe&apos;s Barbecue - the location on Strang Road in Olathe, KS ( see map ). Oklahoma Joe&apos;s has suddenly risen to the top of my&quot;favorites&quot;list of a long line of great barbecue places in the Kansas City area. (You can read my original post on Oklahoma Joe&apos;s here .)  

 The original Oklahoma Joe&apos;s is located in what is basically an old gas station in Kansas City, KS (below left). It is one of the more unique places I&apos;ve been to for any type of restaurant. The barbecue I had on my first visit was absolutely fabulous - the brisket was out of this world and the ribs were very, very good. Each time I get back to K.C., I have to have at least one meal at Oklahoma Joe&apos;s. 

  
I was staying out at my usual place in Overland Park, KS - the Hilton Garden Inn - and the Olathe Oklahoma Joe&apos;s is much closer to my hotel than the original one in Kansas City. The Oklahoma Joe&apos;s in Olathe (above right - picture courtesy of Kansas Travel.org ) is located in a newer strip mall and has ample parking around the building. Even coming up on 8 p.m., I was having trouble finding a place to park because it was packed with people at that time. The one in Kansas City, Kansas (or KCK, as the locals refer to it) serves its last meal at 8:30 p.m through the week. The Olathe location closes at 9 p.m. for the late eating suburbanite crowd. (The KCK location is open until 9:30 on weekends and the Olathe location closes at 10:00 p.m. on Friday and Saturday. Both locations are closed on Sunday.)   

 

 The inside of Oklahoma Joe&apos;s in Olathe (picture right courtesy of Kansas Travel.org) is vastly larger than the original location, but it doesn&apos;t have any of the rib joint ambiance that the KCK Oklahoma Joe&apos;s possesses. The menu in Olathe is nearly identical to the KCK location and the line to order at the counter was nearly 12 people deep when I walked in. It allowed me ample time to peruse the large blackboard menu on the wall to see what I really wanted to eat that evening. 

 Without getting into the detail that I did with my original post, I&apos;ll just say that I went with the Two Meat Dinner - pulled pork and brisket with a side of baked beans and Texas toast, with a couple bottles of Bud Light to help wash the dust out of my mouth from a long day of driving and to help cut into the zippy chipotle pepper taste of Oklahoma Joe&apos;s&quot;Night of the Living Sauce&quot;barbecue sauce. 

 While the surroundings at the Olathe location was more of a corporate chain restaurant, the food was probably as good as the original Oklahoma Joe&apos;s in KCK.  The brisket was devastatingly delicious, tender and lean with a hint of a smoke taste. The pulled pork was equally tender, but sort of lacked a good smoky base to the meat. But putting a combination of the Oklahoma Joe&apos;s regular&quot;Cowtown&quot;sauce and the more spicy sauce together, the taste sensation with the pulled pork was not lost. And adding some of the&quot;Night of the Living Sauce&quot;to the baked beans helped flare up an already wonderful side dish. 

 Next door to the Oklahoma Joe&apos;s restaurant in Olathe is a barbecue store that sells smokers and grilles, sauces, rubs, wood chips and barbecue accessories. It&apos;s similar to the stuff you&apos;d find at  Smoke&apos;n&apos;Fire in Overland Park, but much smaller in size and in selection than what Smoke&apos;n&apos;Fire offers. 

 I&apos;ve heard that the decor and ambiance of a restaurant can make the food taste better. I sort of like the old rib joint feel to the original Oklahoma Joe&apos;s in KCK compared to the slick, contemporary interior of their Olathe location. While it is comfortable with larger tables and a larger dining area than the original place, I think the KCK Oklahoma Joe&apos;s is just a notch better than the one in Olathe. That&apos;s not to say that I didn&apos;t like my meal at the Olathe Oklahoma Joe&apos;s, it was very, very good - still one of the best, if not THE best barbecue in Kansas City. But even though it&apos;s a little more of a haul from where I stay when I&apos;m in the Kansas City location, I&apos;d go back to the Oklahoma Joe&apos;s in KCK before I&apos;d go to the one in Olathe. 

 
 
 September 17, 2010 in Barbecue , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Bristol Seafood Grill - Leawood, KS 
 
 Trying to impress a potential custom audio/video dealer in the Kansas City area earlier this summer, we agreed on dinner for four of his staff at Bristol Seafood Grill  in suburban Leawood, KS ( see map ). I&apos;d eaten at the Bristol location in St. Louis a number of years ago and I do remember it as being very good. I was sort of surprised to see one in suburban Kansas City and wondered if it were part of the same family as the one in St. Louis.  

 Yep, it sure is. In fact, there are four Bristol Seafood Grill&apos;s these days - the one  in the Creve Coeur area of St. Louis, a location in the far western St. Louis suburb of O&apos;Fallon , one in downtown Kansas City  in the new Power and Light District near the Sprint Center , and the one we went to located in the Town Center Plaza  in Leawood.  The original Bristol Seafood Grill location was in the Country Club Plaza of Kansas City, but that closed up in 1995 (more on that later).  

 The four Bristol locations are owned by the Houlihan&apos;s corporation, the Kansas City-based restaurant chain with 97 locations in 20 states  that had been in and out of financial trouble in the late 90&apos;s and right after the turn of the century. In addition to the Bristol and Houlihan&apos;s restaurants under their corporate umbrella, the restaurant company also owns J. Gilberts, a very good Kansas City-area steakhouse that I wrote about here ; the Devon Seafood Grill with locations in Chicago, Milwaukee, Philadelphia and Hershey, PA; the Braxton Seafood Grill  in the Oak Brook Center in suburban Chicago; and Chequers Seafood Grill in Atlanta.  The Devon, Braxton and Chequers Seafood Grills all have the same concept and theme as the Bristol Seafood restaurants.  

 Like the others, the Bristol Seafood Grill is more of an upscale casual restaurant. The bar area is usually full of people and can get very loud at times, while the dining area is more subdued with sturdy chairs and heavy tables covered with white linen. The executive chef of the Leawood location is Dan Uche, overseeing a staff that makes a number of delectable items to choose from. 

 A couple of the people were late for our 6 p.m. meeting - one was having car trouble, the other - the owner - was still on a job site. I sat down with two of the people who I&apos;d known for years and years from working in the audio/video industry, catching up on old times. The person with car trouble showed up about 6:30 and we were still waiting on the owner. We decided to order a couple appetizers - Bristol&apos;s tuna sushi rolls and a double order of their famous crab cakes. Our waiter, who was a very agreeable fellow, was already getting high marks for his sense of humor and his attentive nature.   

 The center piece of the dining room was this wonderful stained glass dome that was situated right over the top of the room. I was told that the glass dome was in the original Bristol restaurant in the Plaza area of Kansas City, but that restaurant shut down in 1995 because of a dispute with the then landlord of the property. When they decided to build a location in Leawood in 2006, they actually pulled the dome off the old building, crated it up and then helicoptered the crate out to the Leawood location where it was put on top of the existing building.  The light filtering through the stained glass dome gave the main dining area a nice warm glow.    

 It fully appeared the owner was knee-deep in his work, but did tell one of the people that he&apos;d be there as soon as he could, even if it were just to drop by for a bit. And the person with car trouble said that he&apos;d probably only be able to stay for a drink and some appetizers as he needed to attend to his automotive problems. The other two guests and I decided to just to go ahead and order up our food and worry about getting something for the owner a little later on.   

 Our appetizers showed up at the table and the tuna sushi rolls was just excellent. The crab cakes were large and rich - one of my guests said,&quot;I usually order a double order of them for dinner, they&apos;re so good.&quot;  

 And they&apos;re filling! I ate one and I thought there would be no way I could eat a double order of these!   

 The guest with the car trouble excused himself to leave, and one of the others made a quick call to see where the boss was. He was still more than an hour away from leaving and it would have still been a 45 minute drive to the Bristol. He told us to go ahead and order something and he&apos;d worry about getting something when he got there.   

 The menu at Bristol Seafood Grill is very extensive with fresh fish, steaks, pasta and even their rendition of a shrimp enchilada. There were a couple nightly specials, but I was sort of looking at the Big Eye tuna from Hawaii. Usually, the Bristol&apos;s seafood selections are cooked over a mesquite flame, but our waiter had a blackened cajun special that evening. I asked him if I could get the Big Eye tuna rare, but blackened and he said,&quot;We can do anything you like with it, sir!&quot;   

 I said,&quot;Could you take it out back and drag it through the parking lot, then slam it against the building a couple times?&quot; 

 The waiter feigned indignation. &quot;Our seafood is already handled roughly, sir! That&apos;s what makes it so tender!&quot;  He was a great guy. I got mashed sweet potatoes and a vegetable medley for my sides. 

 One of the guests order the seared scallops served with a lemon-asparagus risotto. And the other person ordered the swordfish special along with roasted yellow russet potatoes and asparagus.   

 The Bristol&apos;s wine list is also pretty extensive with a number of very good wines from a number of vineyards from the Pacific Coast, Australia, New Zealand, France and Italy. Since everyone was having seafood, I went with a bottle of the Ferrari Carano Fume Blanc  from 2008, a light and dry wine that I particularly love with seafood. I thought it to be a little over priced at $46 bucks, however. But Bristol was an upscale place and the entrees weren&apos;t all that cheap either.  

 After talking a little shop and going over some things about their business for a little bit, our entrees showed up at the table. My blackened Big Eye tuna had a nice sear around the edges, topped with a generous amount of Cajun seasonings. My knife went easily through the fish and from the first bite I was in heaven. The combination of the spicy seasonings and the freshness of the fish set off a party on my taste buds. It was absolutely fabulous. And very surprising, considering the great seafood dishes I had in Hawaii. The fish I had at Bristol that night easily beat one or two where I had seafood in Hawaii. 

 My one guest said his scallops were very good, as well. &quot;I usually get the double order of crab cakes, but I wanted to try something else tonight. These are great.&quot; 

 My other guest was fully satisfied with her swordfish. &quot;I don&apos;t know how they get the fish so fresh here in Kansas City,&quot; she said. &quot;But I&apos;ve never had a bad meal at Bristol.&quot;   

 Toward the end of dinner, one of my guest&apos;s cellphone rang. It was the boss, he was on his way and would be there in 20 minutes. We ordered up an order of crab cakes and a salad for him so he&apos;d have it as soon as he walked in.   

 He did come in about 25 minutes later, apologizing profusely for missing a good portion of the evening. But I fully understood. He had a big job that he needed to complete for a client and even if that meant skipping out on the dinner meeting, so be it.  But we talked business as he ate his salad and crab cakes. And that continued well into the evening and up to the time that Bristol was getting ready to close at 10 p.m.   

 Although nothing was finalized or agreed upon that evening, I think the meeting went about as well as it could have considering the circumstances. But I will say the meal at Bristol Seafood Grill was just excellent. I remember it being good when I first ate at the one in St. Louis over 20 years ago. My blackened Big Eye tuna was just stellar and the service was outstanding. I gave the waiter a little extra tip as we basically rented a table for six for the night with only three people sitting at it most of the evening.  

 Before we left, the general manager - Phil - came over to see how the evening was. I told him that it was one of the more pleasurable dining experiences in my travels. He told us to come back and see them again.   

 I&apos;m hoping to land this dealer in the Kansas City area because they&apos;re located not far from the Bristol Seafood Grill. And I wouldn&apos;t mind going back there again at some point.      
 
 September 15, 2010 in Kansas City , Restaurants , Seafood | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Hilton Garden Inn - Overland Park, KS 
 
 The Hilton Garden Inn on College Boulevard in Overland Park, KS ( see map ) has become my de facto&quot;home-away-from-home&quot;when I&apos;m in the Kansas City area. Not only is it close to one of my key dealers in the market, it&apos;s not very far from some pretty good restaurants in the area. I recently had an experience at another hotel - literally right next door to the Hilton Garden Inn - that made me appreciate the Overland Park H.G.I. even more. 

 With Cindy and I off to Hawaii recently, I had been really trying to garner as many Hilton Honors points as possible when I was on the road. 95% of my stays last year and early this year were in Hilton properties. I&apos;m also a Marriott Rewards member, but I don&apos;t get points toward stays with Marriott - I get their points applied to my airline points. That&apos;s another reason why Cindy and I were able to fly for free, round-trip to Hawaii, as well. Earlier this year, I got a communication from Marriott saying that they wanted more of my business. (I&apos;m not certain, but I think these hotel rewards factions share information as to who their members are. I&apos;ve been signed up by Ramada , Holiday Inn ,  Choice Hotels and a couple others without ever soliciting their memberships, but after I&apos;ve stayed at a given property.)  The letter said that if I stayed at 10 nights at Marriott properties by March 31, I would maintain Gold Level status - something that Marriott Rewards members attain after, I believe, 30 stays in a year. I thought,&quot;OK, I can stay in 10 Marriott properties by March 31, even if we go to Hawaii for nearly two weeks.&quot;   

 The first Marriott property I booked into to start my trek to 10 nights was the  Courtyard Inn in Overland Park . Although I&apos;d never stayed there before, I was very familiar with the Courtyard Inn as I could see it just across the parking lot from my north side room windows when I&apos;d stay at the Hilton Garden Inn in Overland Park. As is usually the case at the end of a day when I&apos;m on the road, I have a number of e-mails to return, orders to check on and other things that I have to do with the use of my computer. Having a high-speed connection is critical for me as I can hook up directly to our computers to our main office outside of Montreal and get real time information on invoices, inventory and projected dates when product will show up at our warehouse.  This particular day, I had an abnormal amount of work to be done on the computer before I could go out and enjoy some barbecue that evening.  

 I got into my room at the Courtyard and fired up my computer. I found a wireless signal from Ibahn , the company that provides Internet service for Marriott properties. Except I couldn&apos;t get on to the network. After about five futile attempts, I realized that I was probably too far away from the wireless network transmitter and called the front desk to see if I could get another room, lower and more close to the center of the hotel.  

 When I explained my plight to the lady at the front desk, she said,&quot;Oh, well, we don&apos;t have wireless Internet service in our rooms. We do have wireless service in the lobby area. You have to use the cable that is provided in the room to receive your Internet access.&quot;  

 A cable? Seriously? Hooking your computer up to an Ethernet cable for high speed Internet is so... so... so, 1990&apos;s!!! Quite honestly, I can&apos;t tell you the last time I had to hook up my computer to a cable to gain Internet access.  

 An Ethernet cable was on the desk, hooked up to an input on the wall. I plugged it into my computer and waited for the connection to start.  And I waited. And I waited. And I waited. My computer never did see an Internet connection with the Ethernet cable.  

 Well, I&apos;m not going to get into the sordid details of what transpired over the next 90 minutes, but after two calls to Ibahn Support, changing settings on my computer, then a change of Ethernet cables and enough teeth gnashing to grind my molars down to stubs, I finally gave up. It was ninety excruciating minutes of my life that I&apos;ll never get back again. I was getting hungry and tired when I called the front desk and I said,&quot;Look, Internet access is important to me and if I can&apos;t get it here, I&apos;ve got to go somewhere else.&quot;   

 She front desk agent, who was as pleasant as pleasant could be during all of this ordeal, said,&quot;I&apos;m sorry we couldn&apos;t accommodate you, sir. Let me call the Sheraton (across the street, next to the Overland Park Convention Center ) to see what they have for rooms.&quot; 

 I said,&quot;I&apos;d prefer the Hilton next door, if you could.&quot; 

 She called me back in about three minutes and said, &quot;The Hilton next door has rooms, sir. They can accommodate you and they do have wireless Internet.&quot; Well, that I knew as I&apos;d stayed there many times before. 

 I dropped off my keys and apologized to the lady at the front desk for her troubles, but she still stayed very pleasant with me. Hey, it didn&apos;t work out for this particular guest. No use being mean spirited about anything. I drove over to the Hilton - a distance of about 200 feet - and went to check in.   

 Normally, I don&apos;t like to spend more than $129 a night for a room when I&apos;m on the road. Sometimes the Hilton Garden Inn either hits or exceeds that level. But it is one of the better Hilton properties that I stay in, so I usually fudge a bit on my self-imposed rule when it comes to the Hilton Garden Inn in Overland Park. When I went to check in, the guy at the front desk was someone I wasn&apos;t familiar with.  In the past, I&apos;ve dealt with a very likable, but smart-assed lady agent who would always flip me good-natured shit when I would arrive. &quot;Oh, you&apos;re back AGAIN? Don&apos;t you ever stay home?&quot; 

 At other times, I had a guy who recognized me from my Iowa Hawkeye sticker that I have on the side of my suitcase (all the better to be able to see it quickly on baggage carousels at airports) and he would always ask me about Iowa sports. He was from Kansas City, but he was a huge Iowa fan.  At least, that&apos;s what he always said. He may have been doing that to make me feel more welcome, but he did have a pretty good grasp of what was going on with the Iowa Football team during our conversations.    

 The&quot;new&quot;guy at the desk didn&apos;t recognize me as a return guest and he asked if I&apos;d stayed there before. &quot;Oh, God, many times,&quot;I replied.  

 He said,&quot;Oh, great! Then welcome back!&quot; He asked me what my rate was over at the Courtyard and I told him that I couldn&apos;t remember. He said,&quot;Well, I can get you into a room for $129 tonight.&quot;  

 I said that was fair enough and asked if I could get a room on the first floor. He said that was no problem. I gave him my Hilton Diamond level number - a nine-digit number that I have burned into my memory.  He looked up my account and said,&quot;Oh, OK. Yep, there you are!&quot; For my long-time commitment to Hilton properties, the guy gave me a room upgrade to a junior suite on the first floor. 

 (I usually get rooms on the first floor, mainly so I can get easy in and out access to my car when I&apos;m there. I&apos;ve been told that most seasoned hotel guests will want to stay on the top floor of a property - you don&apos;t have the chance that some heavy-footed oaf will be stomping around in the room above you. I learned years and years ago to get a room on the first floor. It just saves time when you come and go. The only time I&apos;ll ask for a high floor is when I&apos;m at a hotel that has more than three floors. I like to get up and look out around the neighborhood. Or when I&apos;m at the Hilton Garden Inn in downtown Chicago , like the recent time I was on the 23rd floor - the top floor - looking out over downtown Chicago, high enough to not hear the street traffic below.) 

 Everything about the Hilton Garden Inn in Overland Park feels like home to me. They always give me a couple bottles of complementary water, at night they have fresh baked cookies, and I get a complementary breakfast with omelets made to order to get my day started. That, right there, is worth $10 to $12 bucks before a tip to the wait staff. Even though it&apos;s a free breakfast and I usually carry my own plate to the table after I get the omelet, I always tip the wait staff at a Hilton Garden Inn a couple three bucks for just being around and asking if I need anything.  

 If Hilton properties are my first choice of places to stay at while I&apos;m on the road, Hilton Garden Inns are the first choice of Hilton properties for me. The one in Overland Park is clean, modern, has a great staff, is easy in-and-out from College Blvd. And, as I said, it&apos;s close to many great restaurants and shopping in the Overland Park area. It&apos;s a little bit of a haul to the attractions around K.C. such as Worlds of Fun , the Truman Sports Complex , Downtown Kansas City and The Plaza , but I think I&apos;d rather stay at the Hilton Garden Inn in Overland Park and make the drive to those places. This recent adventure with the Courtyard next door confirmed my belief that the Hilton Garden Inn in Overland Park is my home-away-from-home when I&apos;m in Kansas City. 

 And, oh, by the way - I guess I lost my Gold status with Marriott as I didn&apos;t stay in even one Marriott property up to March 31. Oh well. I&apos;m going to work on getting more points with Hilton properties for another trip at some point in a year or two where we can stay at a Hilton property in some exotic location for free for a week.  
 
 May 07, 2010 in Hotels , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Smoke &apos;n Fire - Overland Park, KS 
 
 While Smoke&apos;n Fire would be a cool name for a barbecue joint, you can&apos;t eat at the place in Overland Park, KS ( see map ). It&apos;s a superstore for barbecue smokers, grilles, inside and outside fireplaces, and barbecue accessories along with spices, rubs and sauces. I had seen their ad on TV when I was in Kansas City recently and I took the time one day to run out there to check the place out. 

 Jim and Joan Cattey first opened Smoke&apos;n Fire in 1998. How they got into the business is rather interesting. They used to run a farm feed and seed store in Northern Missouri. Through a number of sales contests, they ended up winning some barbecue grills. They had a friend who was selling wood-fired stoves and they sort of partnered up in selling fireplaces, stoves and grilles. The location on 151st St. in Overland Park is the third location Smoke&apos;n Fire has been in - each location more than doubled the size of their previous site.  
 
 Jim Cattey (right) is sort of a local celebrity in that he has a half-hour barbecue show - Xtreme Barbecue Radio - on WHB radio  from May thru October each year, plus he stars in his own commercials that air on TV. Cattey has also authored a book called&quot; Backy ard Grilling &quot;along with his wife and chef  Richard McPeake . In fact, Richard McPeake conducts a number of barbecuing and smoking classes at Smoke&apos;n Fire. When you buy selected smokers or barbecue grilles at Smoke&apos;n Fire, they&apos;ll throw in a basic class for free. 

McPeake also has authored a couple of books on his own on backyard smoking including&quot; Backyard Barbecue - The Art of Smokeology &quot;. He&apos;s a graduate of the Culinary Institute of America and is a certified judge for the Kansas City Barbecue Society . He has conducted over 300 classes for over 9000 people in his association with Smoke&apos;n Fire. He is also the guy behind the great barbecue web site, Rib Stars , where he sells copies of his books and his own barbecue rubs.

I&apos;d finished a morning meeting at a dealer I&apos;ve been chasing off and on in the Overland Park area and it turned out that Fire&apos;n Smoke&apos;s location was not far from the dealer&apos;s store. Being the grilling and smoking nut that I am, I wanted to go over and check out this place. 

As I walked in the door, I was met by two of the new style Weber&quot;Bullet&quot;Smokers . One was the regular 18&apos;size, but they also have a new 22&quot;smoker that&apos;s available for $399. The biggest difference between the Bullet smoker I&apos;ve had for about three years now and the new style is that the new ones have a built in thermometer - my biggest bitch when it came to my smoker. It also appears to be a heavier gauge of metal in the new ones. I immediately wanted one. 

 In addition to the two Weber smokers and a large array of Weber grilles , they also had a wide variety of smokers and grilles including some pretty heavy-duty, industrial style smokers that I wouldn&apos;t mind having. But the prices certainly weren&apos;t cheap at Smoke&apos;n Fire. The quality of the grilles and smokers they had were top-notch. They featured a large selection of grilles and smokers from Lynx , Beef Eater , Primo and Ducane .  They also had one of the famous Big Green Egg ceramic grill and smoker. Those things are not cheap.

The place was just huge. I was walking around in a literal daze just looking at everything they had to offer. It was a barbecue paradise for me. They had everything you needed to make any type of backyard grilling a success. My head was spinning at each turn looking at some of the neat accessories they had to offer. There were little knick-knacks like aprons, mitts, thermometers, grilling tools, cleaning tools and cleaning brushes. They had knife sharpeners, meat marinators and tenderizers, grid lifters (I almost got one of those myself), and something called&quot;Grill Floss&quot;. It cleaned the underside of your grill grate.  That&apos;s a little anal for me. 

 I was back in the corner of the store and I found their area that featured a number of rubs, sauces and spices. I took a quick picture of the area and a lady popped around the corner and she said,&quot;Sir, we don&apos;t allow pictures or videos to be made in the store.&quot;

I was incredulous. &quot;Really,&quot;I asked. &quot;Why&apos;s that?&quot;

She said,&quot;The owner feels that it&apos;s his intellectual property and he doesn&apos;t want someone coming in here to take pictures so they may get ideas for their own place.&quot; 

I said,&quot;Oh, OK. Sorry. I live up in Iowa and I wanted to show some of my friends this place. You&apos;ve got a mecca for grilling and smoking here.&quot; 

 I went back into another corner of the store and I found shelves of wood chips in all sizes of bags - from 100 lbs. down to 10 pound bags. They had all different types of wood from mesquite to hickory to alder to cherry to... Well, if you can think of a type of wood that you can use to smoke with, they had it at Smoke&apos;n Fire. They even had different varieties of flavors within some of the wood chips they sold. I had to get a picture of this, so I snuck one last picture.

I was still wandering around when I heard the lady who initially accosted me about taking pictures with my cell phone say to another guy,&quot;Yeah, that&apos;s him back in the corner. He says he&apos;s just looking around.&quot;

This guy came up to me and asked if he could be of any assistance. As I told the lady before, I told him that I was a big barbecue aficionado and that I saw their ad on television the night before and wanted to check the place out. He asked me where I lived and I told him I lived back in Iowa. He said,&quot;Well, before you leave, give us your name so we can put you on our mailing list.&quot; He said it with sort of an untrusting tone of voice. I mean, I guess I can see why they would be worried about people coming in and taking pictures to get ideas. It was a helluva business for them.

 I did give my name, e-mail and mailing address to the lady at the counter before I left. I&apos;m not certain she actually added it to the list as I&apos;ve not seen anything from them either via e-mail or regular mail, and it&apos;s been awhile since I&apos;ve been in. In the back of my mind, I think they probably wanted to take down my name and address in case they found that I was going to open my own style of Smoke&apos;n Fire store so they could sue me at some point in the future. I&apos;m now probably labeled as an&quot;undesirable&quot;in their system. 

And as I left I did see a sign near the front door that said,&quot;No Photo or Video Cameras&quot;. I may or may not have seen that when I came in...

But Smoke n&apos;Fire is truly a mecca for those of us who are heavily into barbecuing and smoking. I didn&apos;t buy anything this trip, but I&apos;ll be back to Kansas City in a few weeks and I&apos;ll have to block out an hour or so during the day to come in and look for some stuff. The only problem is that they close at 5:30 every day so I can&apos;t spend some time some evening there. But that&apos;s OK - I&apos;d rather be eating good barbecue at that time rather than looking for stuff to buy.
 
  
 
 April 16, 2010 in Barbecue , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (1) 

 | | | 
 
 Oklahoma Joe&apos;s - Kansas City 
 
 
Kansas City has some world-class barbecue. It&apos;s always a treat to get barbecue in K.C. and it&apos;s a double treat when I find a new place to try some barbecue. On a recent trip to town, I was doing a little reading up on a place that I wasn&apos;t familiar with - Oklahoma Joe&apos;s . The article I read on line said that it was in an old gas station in a neighborhood on the Kansas side of Kansas City. I thought I&apos;d give it a shot that evening.  

 Like a number of barbecue joints, Oklahoma Joe&apos;s got its start from a backyard grilling enthusiast - much like myself - who began to enter barbecue competitions around the Midwest in the 1990&apos;s.  Jeff Stehney was inspired by a couple of large Kansas City area barbecue contests to buy a heavy duty Oklahoma Joe&apos;s smoker to enter into competition against some of the best amateur barbecue aficionados in the U.S. Within two years, Stehney and his team,&quot;Slaughterhouse Five&quot;(named after his favorite Kurt Vonnegut novel), won the prestigious Grand Champion awards at both the American Royal Open and the Kansas City Barbecue Society contests.  

 Stehney and his team, the core of which featured his wife, Joy, and good friend, Jim Howell, captured numerous awards   in various competitions throughout Kansas, Oklahoma, Missouri and Arkansas. It was through these competitions he met up with Roger Davidson, the owner of Oklahoma Joe&apos;s smokers. Davidson and Stehney struck up a quick friendship that quickly turned into a business venture together. The first Oklahoma Joe&apos;s Barbecue opened in 1995 in Stillwater, OK - the home of Davidson&apos;s smoker company. The Kansas City location opened in 1996 with Jim Stehney overseeing the operation. Through all of this, Stehney continued to enter barbecue contests - and would usually win awards in multiple categories.  

 In 1997, Davidson sold his smoker company to Char-Broil , the maker of New Braunfels smokers. Char-Broil was eventually bought out by Brinkmann . Davidson moved to Texas and with no one to oversee the Stillwater operation, the Oklahoma Joe&apos;s BBQ closed. Jeff and Joy Stehney bought out Davidson&apos;s interest in the Kansas City location and continue to run it today. Davidson, in the meantime, started a new smoker company - Horizon Barbecue Smokers - based out of Perry, OK.  

 I got the address to Oklahoma Joe&apos;s in Kansas City and punched it into the GPS. As I got closer, I found myself in a residential neighborhood wondering what the place would be like. I came up to the corner of 47th and Mission ( see map ) and there it was on the NE corner of the intersection. The parking lot was packed (it was just after 8 p.m. and they close at 8:30) and I drove around the building to find a parking spot. I found one in front of the gas station. Yes, Oklahoma Joe&apos;s is not in an old gas station - it really is a gas station with a convenience store, gas pumps on two sides and the whole nine yards! I just shook my head in amazement and chuckled as I walked in.  

 Oklahoma Joe&apos;s menu is on a chalk board along the east wall of the establishment. That&apos;s where you order from one of the line cooks and he starts your order. I had a lot of trouble understanding the one line cook from a combination of his southern dialect, the loudness of the dining area and the bustle behind him in the kitchen area. Oklahoma Joe&apos;s menu isn&apos;t extensive like I&apos;ve found at other Kansas City area barbecue places, but it focused on the core foods of real barbecue.  

 I ended up ordering the Rib and Brisket combo - three meaty pork ribs with a stack of thin sliced brisket. I got a choice of a side with that and I didn&apos;t hesitate when I told him I wanted baked beans.  I then went to the cash register and the girl there asked me what I wanted to drink. Thankfully, Oklahoma Joe&apos;s has beer - lots of it to choose from, by the way. I ended up getting a couple bottles of Bud Light to help wash the barbecue down. 

 As I waited for my order to come up, I noticed a number of people coming up and getting orders to go. One couple had called in their order and took their&quot;to-go&quot;sack to a table to eat. The dining area - consisting of a number of two and four chair tables, a few booths and a number of seats along a high bar on the south side of the dining room - was nearly full. After I got my tray with my barbecue and beer, I found a small table near the cash register and sat down to eat. In true barbecue joint style, they had a roll of paper towels on the table along with two different types of sauce - regular and hot.  

 I had one of the ribs first. They had a nice dry rub on them and they were tender to the bite. Meaty and moist, the pork slid effortlessly off the bone. I put a little of Oklahoma Joe&apos;s regular barbecue sauce on a bite of the rib and I have to say it was very good. It had a sweet, smoky taste to the sauce and it was a perfect match with the ribs. I even poured some into my baked beans which were thick and meaty and had a little spicy bite to them. They were very, very good on their own without the barbecue sauce in them. 

 The brisket was next. It was tender and very thin sliced and came with a dollop of their barbecue sauce on top. The brisket sat on a piece of white bread - very Southern as far as barbecue is concerned. From the first bite, I was in heaven. It was so flavorful and tender. Some of the best brisket I&apos;d ever had.  

 They gave me two rib bones and an end piece. While I believe they thought they were doing me a favor with giving me the end piece. While it was tender and flavorful, the end pieces of pork ribs have a lot of little bones in them. I was pausing repeatedly to stop and pull the little bones out of my mouth and put &apos;em on the plate. I didn&apos;t care if anyone was watching. This is barbecue, for God&apos;s sake! 

 I decided to kick it up a notch with Oklahoma Joe&apos;s&quot;Night of the Living Sauce&quot;hot sauce. Well, I didn&apos;t think it was all that hot, but it added more zip to what the regular Oklahoma Joe&apos;s sauce had. I put some of that in my baked beans and stirred it around. It made the beans a little more spicy and helped with the sweet taste, as well.  

 By this time, I&apos;m in barbecue heaven. The ambiance of the place was unique, the barbecue was just outstanding, it was getting close to 8:30 and there were still people coming in to either pick up orders or to eat in the dining area. I was savoring every bite of Oklahoma Joe&apos;s barbecue.  I was slopping up the remnants of the sauce with the piece of Texas Toast that was on my plate. When the sauce was gone from the plate, I&apos;d just pour more on the bread and eat it like that.   As I finished my meal, I thought this might be the best barbecue dinner I&apos;ve ever had.   

 As I was leaving Oklahoma Joe&apos;s, I noticed they had a large section of sauces, spices and rubs on the shelf in the convenience store area of the building. Geez, a gas station/convenience store/rib joint. This was just something else. The gas station/convenience store - Joe&apos;s Corner - had a number of people coming in for stuff other than barbecue. And there were people gassing up outside. As I got in my car and checked my fuel gauge, I decided I needed some gas, too. As I was pumping gas, I thought,&quot;Only at Oklahoma Joe&apos;s can you get gas inside and outside the building.&quot;   

 Oklahoma Joe&apos;s was one of those overly surprising and ultra-pleasant dining experiences that I just love to find when I&apos;m on the road. The barbecue was just outstanding, the beans were delicious, the sauces were wonderful. It&apos;s no wonder that  Anthony Bourdain  named Oklahoma Joe&apos;s as one of his  13 places to eat before you die .   If heaven has barbecue, Oklahoma Joe&apos;s is serving it. 

 Now my stomach is rumbling just thinking of Oklahoma Joe&apos;s. Quite seriously, it may have been the best barbecue that I&apos;ve ever had. If it wasn&apos;t the best, it has to be in the top 3. I can&apos;t wait to get back to K.C. later this spring to have some more. 

 
 
 March 29, 2010 in Barbecue , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Smokehouse Bar-B-Que - Kansas City 
 
 I put on a new dealer in Kansas City recently and we were talking about his favorite barbecue places. I mentioned going to Jack Stack Barbecue , of which one location is just down the street from his store. He said,&quot;You know, a place that I sort of like, but a lot of people shy away from here in Kansas City is Smokehouse Bar-B-Que . The owner is Iranian or Iraqi and that prejudices some people here in town. But I think it&apos;s very good.&quot;  

 Smokehouse Bar-B-Que is a  four location local chain   that was started in 1986 by Darioush Ghasemi. Quite honestly, Smokehouse never registered on my barbecue scanner when it came to looking for good barbecue in K.C. There&apos;s a ton of good to great Kansas City barbecue restaurants, but my new dealer&apos;s recommendation of Smokehouse was rather intriguing. 

 Recently, I found that I would be driving down to Kansas City from Lincoln, NE via Interstate 29. The somewhat-new Zona Rosa shopping center is home to one of the Smokehouse Bar-B-Que locations ( see map ). Since Zona Rosa is right off the Interstate at Barry Road, I decided to stop in for lunch one day.   

 The outside of the Zona Rosa Smokehouse Bar-B-Que is pretty nondescript, but the interior looks like it could be an upscale steakhouse. The first thing you can&apos;t help but notice when you walk in the main dining area is a massive, concave, stained-glass, back-lit window in the ceiling over the middle of the room. It was rather impressive. There is a lounge area off to the left side that features a large square bar with seating on three sides, and four 42&quot;flat screen televisions on the back wall.  

 Since I was a party of one, I opted to sit at the bar. The hostess ushered me to a seat and left a lunch menu  on the bar for me. The bartender was quick to ask what I&apos;d like to drink. A beer sounded good - a beer is always good with barbecue. But since I had a couple meetings in the afternoon and then a product training at my new dealer that evening, I just got water. (No pop - I have only had two Cokes in the last year. Both of those were when I was in the hospital with my hip replacement surgeries. They made me drink them so I&apos;d pee more quickly and I could get released.)   

 Actually, the lunch menu isn&apos;t much different from Smokehouse Bar-B-Que&apos;s dinner menu , as both feature a number of salads, chicken entrees and, of course, ribs and brisket. Both menus feature a number of mouthwatering sandwiches along with combo meat plates. The dinner menu adds steaks and some seafood to the mix. Smokehouse Bar-B-Que&apos;s appetizer include their famous Cajun chicken wings, jalapeno cheese nuggets, and Smokehouse Bar-B-Que&apos;s thick and yummy onion rings.  

 I was looking at the combo plates as I wanted to try both their ribs and their brisket. I got the pork spare ribs and brisket combo. It came with french fries and cole slaw. I probably wasn&apos;t going to eat much of the fries or the slaw, but what the hell.  

 It wasn&apos;t long after I ordered from the bartender that my food came out. The barbecue sauce was pretty mild and served in a small bowl. I asked the bartender if he had any hotter barbecue sauce and he said he&apos;d go get some for me. I should have said,&quot;More spicy&quot;. Instead, he brought out a piping hot bowl of barbecue sauce. The first taste pretty much told me that it was the same barbecue sauce, only warmed up.  

 However, as the sauce in the hot bowl began to cool down, I noticed that the sauce had a little more kick to it than the first bowl he brought out. I figured that the hotness in temperature of the sauce masked the initial spicy bite the sauce had to offer. It wasn&apos;t bad, actually.  

 The pork spare ribs were meaty and flavorful. I got three in total and it was more than enough for lunch. And the brisket was cut thin, was juicy and tender, and also had great flavor to it. I was overly impressed with the barbecue. I had a couple french fries, just to try&apos;em and they were OK. And the cole slaw was average, at best. But the sides aren&apos;t what I came to Smokehouse Bar-B-Cue for. 

 In a city known for world-class barbecue, you have to be pretty good to be in business over 20 years and to have four locations. I was pleasantly surprised by Smokehouse Bar-B-Cue and told my dealer that evening of my experience there. He said,&quot;I told you it was good. It&apos;s just not on the radar of a lot of people around here. The names of other places pop up before they talk about Smokehouse. Places that I, personally, don&apos;t think hold a candle to the food at Smokehouse.&quot;  

 Well, Smokehouse Bar-B-Que is on my radar now. I will definitely seek out another location on a coming trip to K.C. 

 
 
 December 28, 2009 in Barbecue , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Chappell&apos;s Sports Bar - North Kansas City 
 
 

 A little over 4 years ago when I started Road Tips, I was still trying to find my direction and voice as to what I was trying to accomplish with this blog. One of the very first entries I had was on Sports Illustrated&apos;s Top 25 Sports Bars and the ones that I&apos;d visited out of that list. (You can read that entry here .) One place that I&apos;d been into a number of years ago, but hadn&apos;t visited for a long time was Chappel&apos;s Sports Bar in North Kansas City ( see map ). I was in the area not long ago and decided to go have lunch there. 

 Jim Chappell (right) settled in North Kansas City, MO in the early 70&apos;s and ran an insurance agency while dabbling in politics. Chappell was a budding collector of sports memorabilia during that time and he entertained thoughts of opening a restaurant/bar that would house some of his collection, plus be a neighborhood gathering place to discuss local, state and national politics. In the mid-80&apos;s, a building directly across the street from Chappell&apos;s insurance agency became available. In 1986, Chappell opened his sports bar, hoping to run it on a part-time basis. However, it soon became a full-time job for Chappell, who subsequently sold his insurance agency.  
 Chappell has entertained sports figures, politicians and common people at his restaurant which he has literally turned into a sports museum that happens to serve food and drink. The amount of memorabilia that he has in the place is staggering.  They have over 1000 football helmets from college and professional teams, including some vintage helmets from the 50&apos;s and 60&apos;s. He has a large collection of historical Kansas City professional team memorabilia, including old Kansas City Monarchs jerseys and pictures, old Kansas City Athletics memorabilia and a few things from the old Kansas City Kings professional basketball team. Of course, he has a a ton of items featuring the Kansas City Royals and the Kansas City Chiefs .

 The bar features a number of jersey&apos;s from professional and collegiate football, basketball and baseball teams. Chappel has signed baseballs from Babe Ruth , Dizzy Dean and Ty Cobb .  He has the 1974 World Series trophy that was won by the Oakland A&apos;s . It turns out that former A&apos;s owner Charlie Finley  and Chappell were good friends. There are tons of old sports trophies, sports pennants, newspaper clippings, and autographed pictures. Here are the jerseys from two of my all-time favorite baseball players - Stan Musial and Warren Spahn . It had been over 15 years since I was last in Chappell&apos;s and the amount of memorabilia that he has picked up since has grown exponentially.

In addition to a lot of Kansas University , Kansas State University and University of Missouri sports items on display, I was surprised by the amount of Iowa Hawkeye   memorabilia in the place. I certainly didn&apos;t remember seeing much Hawkeye stuff in there before, or I possibly didn&apos;t notice. I didn&apos;t know until I did some research on Chappell&apos;s that he grew up in Keokuk, IA before heading off to Drury College  (now Drury University) in Springfield, MO in the mid-60&apos;s. Turns out that Chappell was a huge Hawkeye fan growing up and still is to this day.

 It was just after 1 p.m. when I took a seat at the bar at Chappell&apos;s. There was just one seat open as I walked in. But it was obvious that it was occupied by someone as there was a half-filled glass of pop and some paperwork. However, an older gentleman next to the empty seat said,&quot;You need a seat? I&apos;m getting ready to leave.&quot; I took his seat and ordered up a beer and a menu . I was looking through the menu and the guy occupying the seat next to me came back to sit down. Turned out it was Jim Chappell himself. He was holding court at the corner of the bar talking with a couple older guys in having coffee or early afternoon drinks. A guy and his teen-aged son came up to Chappell before they left and the guy introduced himself and his son to Jim. Jim said,&quot;Is this your first trip to our place? Well, c&apos;mon, let me show you around.&quot; And just like that he was up and shepherding them around the place. I would have liked to have a guided tour, as well, but I certainly didn&apos;t have the time.

Chappell&apos;s menu is long and diverse. Of course, they have the usual sports bar fare of appetizers, burgers and sandwiches. But they also feature steaks, a large amount of salads and some low carb items, as well. I was torn between the reuben, which was one of Chappell&apos;s featured sandwiches, the blackened chicken sandwich, or the mushroom/provelone cheeseburger. I decided to go with the cheeseburger and I got a side of cole slaw to go along with it.

Jim Chappell came back to his seat after showing the father and son around for about five minutes, finished his pop and said to his friends,&quot;Well, I&apos;m going to work out, fellas. I&apos;ll see you a little later.&quot;  Chappell is in his early 60&apos;s, is tall and lean and looks to be in great shape for his age. I could tell from the short time he was near me that he really dug being Jim Chappell. And I mean that in a good way. This was his place, it was his stuff and he was damn proud of everything.

Chappell&apos;s burgers are 1/2 pound USDA ground beef, cooked to your liking. My burger came out and it was thick and juicy with a good bun to go along with it. While I can&apos;t call it one of the best burgers I&apos;ve ever had, or maybe even put it in the honorable mention category, it was still good. Definitely a very good burger compared to other sports bars that I&apos;ve visited.  The couple of bites of the cole slaw I had were average, at best. It&apos;s obvious the draw to Chappell&apos;s is the memorabilia, but the food is not that bad.

 While there were a lot of televisions throughout Chappell&apos;s, I&apos;m not certain this would be a place that I&apos;d want to go to just to see a game. The decor and memorabilia overpowers Chappell&apos;s televisions. There&apos;s just a lot of very busy stuff on the wall that detracts from watching a game. But if you&apos;re into sports history and memorabilia, and you&apos;re looking for a pretty good meal to go along with it, it&apos;s tough to beat Chappell&apos;s. But plan on spending at least a couple of hours if you really want to look more closely at the things Jim Chappell has in his place. It&apos;s truly a sports museum that happens to have a restaurant in it.
 

 
 
 December 11, 2009 in Kansas City , Sports Bars | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 J. Gilberts Wood Fired Steaks - Overland Park, KS 
 
 It&apos;s been a busy summer for me trying to line up new dealers in Midwest. One of my longtime dealers in Kansas City decided to retire and close his doors earlier this year, so I&apos;ve been scrambling to find a new dealer to take his place in the city. I was able to find two gentlemen - one of whom is an audio/video industry veteran - who were combining their talents to open a new store later this fall and who were interested in carrying some of my products. I suggested we get together for dinner one evening and they suggested J. Gilbert&apos;s , which was not too far from their new store front.  

 Now, I&apos;ve been going to Kansas City since the late 70&apos;s and have been there on a regular basis for a number of years on business. I know I have driven past J. Gilbert&apos;s many times while going down Metcalf Ave. ( see map ), but never knew it was there. It&apos;s sort of set off Metcalf a bit so if you&apos;re not looking for it, it&apos;s tough to see. But it&apos;s been there for quite sometime, so I&apos;m rather mystified that A) I&apos;ve never seen it during my travels to K.C.; B) I&apos;ve never eaten there before; and C) I&apos;ve never even heard of the place. 

 J. Gilbert&apos;s is a traditional old time steak house that hearkens back to how steak houses used to be in the 60&apos;s - rustic interior with dark wood paneling and subdued lighting. Waiters and waitresses are in formal attire and are very attentive to their customer&apos;s needs. J. Gilbert&apos;s boasts some of the finest aged prime center-cut beef, and they grill their meats over an open wood fire.  

 J. Gilbert&apos;s is named after longtime Kansas City restaurateur, Joe Gilbert, who started the Gilbert/Robinson chain of restaurants in the early 60&apos;s. At one point in time, the Gilbert/Robinson chain had over 60 restaurants throughout the Midwest, primarily owning  Houlihan&apos;s   and Darryl&apos;s casual style restaurants. Gilbert/Robinson was bought in 1978 and was subsequently renamed the Houlihan&apos;s Restaurant Group in the mid-90&apos;s. Houlihan&apos;s continues to own the J. Gilbert&apos;s restaurants.    In addition to the Overland Park location , you can find a J. Gilbert&apos;s in such diverse locations as Glatonbury, CT , McLean, VA , and Worthington, OH .    

 I met up with my two dinner guests at J. Gilbert&apos;s just around 7 p.m. and immediately ordered up a bottle of wine - a Franciscan Cabernet - just because it had been a long day for me. We made small talk as we looked over the menu .  I immediately liked J. Gilbert&apos;s for the decor and coziness of the place. I remarked to my guests,&quot;I never knew this was here. I can&apos;t believe how many times I&apos;ve probably passed this place over the years and never even heard of the place.&quot;  

 One of my guests said,&quot;This is a very underrated place here in Kansas City. With all the steak houses this town has, a lot of people don&apos;t appreciate this place like I do.&quot;  

 In addition to steaks, J. Gilbert&apos;s also features seafood, including fresh lobster, salmon, shrimp and scallops. They also have short ribs, chicken and pork chops on the menu. The menu is diverse so that if one isn&apos;t even looking for meat, they can also have salads or a grilled vegetable platter.   

 They had a&quot;fixed price&quot;menu at J. Gilbert&apos;s that evening where you had your pick of four entrees and sides, plus a choice of salad and a dessert for $33 bucks. One of the items on the menu was a 10 oz, KC strip steak with a choice of potato. It was such a good deal, we all three went that route. We each ordered the KC strip. I ordered up J. Gilbert&apos;s signature poblano au gratin potatoes. I also ordered their wedge salad and for dessert I got the creme brulee.   

 The wedge salad was very good - the homemade blue cheese dressing was very flavorful and tangy. The wedge wasn&apos;t overly huge, so there would be room for my steak when it arrived.   

 We talked business up to and into receiving our main entrees. My steak was exactly as I ordered - a wonderful rare that was filled with juices and seasonings. I was very impressed with the steak. It was lean, tender and very flavorful. And I really liked the poblano au gratin potatoes, even though I didn&apos;t come close to finishing them. (I had cut back on potatoes during my diet phase and I don&apos;t miss them all that much.) But it was all so wonderful. I said to my guests,&quot;I just can&apos;t believe that I&apos;ve never heard of this place before!&quot;     

 We continued to talk business up through dessert and well after. The couple bites I had of my creme brulee pretty much told me it was good - not the best I&apos;d ever had, but good. The restaurant closed at 10 p.m. and we were still there talking well past that. I think we finally left around 10:45, but continued to talk in the parking lot for another half-hour. The dinner must have helped - I received their financials and a commitment to two of our lines that evening, with a possibility of more lines going into their store later on.  

 In a city that possibly has more world-class steak houses, per capita, than any other place in the nation, I have to say that J. Gilbert&apos;s acquitted themselves very well. I&apos;ve since been back there one more time and it was just as good as my initial visit. My guest was right - J. Gilbert&apos;s is very underrated when it comes to steak houses in Kansas City. I certainly haven&apos;t been disappointed during my visits.  

   

 
 
 September 04, 2009 in Kansas City , Restaurants , Steak Houses | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Five Guys Burgers - Lee&apos;s Summit, MO 
 
 Five Guys Burgers  is a chain of burger places that began in the mid-80&apos;s in suburban Washington, D.C. Five Guys enjoys the same sort of pop-culture rock-star status with their loyal customers on the east coast that In&apos;n&apos;Out Burger  has on the west coast. A Road Tips reader - and I apologize to whoever it was who e-mailed me about their love for Five Guys Burgers - turned me on to the place. It turned out that they have a couple three franchises in the Kansas City area. While in K.C. recently, I decided to find one to try. 

 Five Guys Burgers was founded in 1986 in Arlington, VA by Jerry Murrell, a local insurance man. At the time, Murrell and his wife had four sons. Jerry wanted to start a burger place where the burgers were hand-formed and cooked to order. Jerry&apos;s sons, all of which were either in grade school to just starting high school, were asked if they wanted to take their college fund and invest it in his eatery. The boys all voted to take their college money and pop it into the new business. Jerry and his sons were the original&quot;five guys&quot;. A couple years after the restaurant opened, Jerry and his wife, Janie, had another son. Those five sons are the Five Guys who are involved in the business today.  

 Five Guys Burgers began to gain a cult following around the D.C. area. The Murrell&apos;s added four more stores in the northern Virginia area before beginning to franchise in 2002. Today, there are over 300 locations in 23 states. They just opened their first two locations in the Chicago area in late 2008.    

 Five Guys is definitely different from most other fast food places. At most other fast food places, the burgers wait for you. With Five Guys, you wait on the burger. This is very similar to the In&apos;n&apos;Out concept. You&apos;re definitely waiting for the burger and it&apos;s hot off the grill when it&apos;s served to you. 

 The bun is specially made for Five Guys at a number of regional bakeries and it is soft, chewy and flavorful. I&apos;ve always said the key to a great burger is the bun. The bun is buttered and toasted before one of their eight different varieties of burgers are placed on the bun. Five Guys also offers 15 different toppings - all of them free - to add to the burger. In addition to your regular ketchup, mustard and pickles, you get your choice of fried or raw onions, jalapenos, sauteed mushrooms, lettuce, tomato and relish - to name a few of the toppings. You can also get hot sauce, A1 sauce, or barbecue sauce topped on the burger.  

 It was around 1:30 when I found the Five Guys Burgers in Lee&apos;s Summit, MO ( see map ). It was located in a strip mall with ample parking in the area. I walked in and was struck at how remarkably shiny it looked. In fact, it sort of reminded me of a Steak n Shake only instead of black and white tile, Five Guys had white and red tile throughout.  

 There wasn&apos;t much of a line, so I really didn&apos;t have a lot of time to look at the menu . Besides, all I wanted was just a basic burger - nothing that would mask the taste of the burger like I&apos;ve run into on some of my first visits to a burger place. I just ordered a basic cheeseburger, topped with raw onions, pickles, mustard, and ketchup. I passed on their french fries and just got a small Coke to help wash it down.   

 The grill is directly behind the counter and there&apos;s a flurry of activity in plain view of the customers waiting for their burgers.  While you wait, you can grab of handful of peanuts in the shell and throw the shells on the floor.  I didn&apos;t do it, but I think they encourage it.  They have these huge bags of peanuts stacked up that they use to pour peanuts into a large bucket that&apos;s sitting opposite the main counter.  

 A number of people that were coming in were picking up called-in orders to go. One guy was getting 20 burgers for the workers back at his office. I heard him say it was a nightmare figuring out the order and making sure that none of the burgers were the wrong combination.   

 After about 10 minutes, my burger came up and I took it to a table to give it a try.  It was wrapped in light aluminum foil and the juices - some people will call it grease - were flowing out of the burger. Everything about the burger was very good.  The meat was very fresh. The bun was a big plus. I was very impressed. It was a great combination. I can see why people have craved Five Guys for years.  

 The next time I try a Five Guys Burger, I&apos;ll dress it up a bit with more of the free condiments they provide. And the way they&apos;re growing, it won&apos;t be that hard to find a Five Guys Burgers in the near future.  

 Update February 2012 - I&apos;ve been to a handful of Five Guys Burger places in the Midwest since my first visit to the one in Lee&apos;s Summit. Each Five Guys has had consistently good burgers. I got an order of fries one time at the Five Guys in Edina, MN and I was surprised to get about a pound and a half at the bottom of my sack. The fries at Five Guys are outstanding, but there&apos;s no way I could have even begun to think of eating them all.  

 Today there are Five Guys in 46 of the 48 continental United States - South Dakota and Wyoming are the only ones missing out . And rather interestingly, my home state of Iowa only has one - out in Sioux City. I don&apos;t know if Iowa&apos;s franchise laws are unfavorable, but there&apos;s not one in any of the larger cities in Central or Eastern Iowa. Hey, maybe that&apos;s the thing I should look into!  

 
 
 February 20, 2009 in Burger Joints , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Thai Place - Shawnee Mission, KS 
 
 As I&apos;ve said a few times before, I don&apos;t eat as much Asian food when I&apos;m on the road as I&apos;d like. Many of the places I&apos;ve eaten in literally soak their food in Mono-sodium Glutamate, and MSG and I don&apos;t get along very well. So, it&apos;s with a little trepidation that I seek out a good Chinese or Thai place while I&apos;m on the road. However, this time in Kansas City I found a very good little Thai restaurant - Thai Place in suburban Shawnee Mission ( see map ).  

 Thai Place is owned by the Liberda family, whose mother, Ann, founded Thai Place in the 1991. Ann came over from Thailand in the mid-70&apos;s and initially worked as a beautician after she came to the U.S.  Ann then ended up working in a restaurant called Bangkok Pavilion in Overland Park. She was a sharp looking, sassy woman who interacted with the customers with ease.   

 Ann left Bangkok Pavilion in 1990 and a year later she opened the original Thai Place restaurant in Overland Park.  Helped by her sons Michael and Ted (who is the head chef for all the Thai Place restaurants), and daughter, Chiara, Ann Liberda&apos;s empire has now risen to five locations across the Kansas City metro area. A lot of the local&apos;s call it the best Thai food in town.  

 The original Thai Place is situated in a strip mall on the south side of Sante Fe Road in Shawnee Mission. It&apos;s set back from the street, so - of course - I drove by it the first time I went there. Once I figured out that I&apos;d gone too far, I called up On-Star for turn-by-turn navigation and the service took me right to the place. Since then, I&apos;ve figured out that I&apos;ve got the turn-by-turn navigation, I may as well use it.  

 The interior of Thai Place is very cozy, white linen table cloths are on the tables, there&apos;s Thai artwork on the walls, the light fixtures are interesting to look at and there&apos;s a small area toward the back of the restaurant. I was seated in a booth and was given a menu  to look through. One of the things Thai Place prides itself on is the eclectic and unusual Thai food they have to offer. After he graduated from culinary school about 10 years ago, Ted Liberda has spent a number of years researching authentic Thai foods to add to the menu.   

 Now, I&apos;m not a very adventurous guy when it comes to Thai food, but some of the things they had on the menu were very interesting. They had four different types of curry dishes that I normally don&apos;t see on menus at other Thai restaurants. They had 16 different types of seafood stir fry, including a squid-jalapeno dish, along with a flash fried Chilean sea bass topped with Thai Place&apos;s famous spicy Sam Rod sauce.   

 They also featured vegetarian dishes, along with regular rice and noodle entrees, salads, soups and appetizers. But I was looking for something like my old stand-by - spicy basil beef. But - oh man - they had some other interesting beef stir-fry dishes, too.  They had a tantalizing jalapeno beef stir fry - beef stir fried with jalapeno chunks and onions. Thai Place also featured a beef mushroom stir fry with three different types of mushrooms and scallions. (I have GOT to quit writing this blog on an empty stomach!) And they had a garlic beef with roasted garlic, scallions, and white pepper all served over chopped cabbage. Oh boy!!! 

 But it got down to choosing between the Ginger Beef (ginger, bell peppers, onions and fresh mushrooms), or the Beef Scallions (scallions, onions and dried chili peppers).   When my waiter came back to take my order, I told him I was torn between the two. He said,&quot;If you wish, we can combine the two.&quot; He suggested getting the Ginger Beef and adding the scallions and dried chili pepper. I asked if he could also have the chef sprinkle some white pepper on the top and he said it would be no problem. He also wanted to know if I wanted fried rice or steamed rice. I went with the fried rice. 

 It wasn&apos;t long - less than 15 minutes - before my food showed up. It was a heaping plate of beef and vegetable stir fry served with a healthy side of fried rice. I eagerly devoured a couple slices of beef and the taste was, well, it was remarkable. The vegetables were perfectly cooked, the dish was a potpourri of taste sensations and although it was a little spicy, it didn&apos;t detract from the overall taste of the food. In a word, the food was outstanding.   

 I don&apos;t know what it is about Thai food, but it&apos;s so good that I usually end up over-eating each time I go. It could be the ginger, it could be the sauce, it could be some mind-numbing drug from Southeast Asia they incorporate into the food. Whatever it is, it&apos;s great. And so addictive. Each time I look at all the food they bring out and I think,&quot;There&apos;s no friggin&apos;way I&apos;m going to eat all of this.&quot; But each time, I do.   

 I didn&apos;t have any alcohol with my meal and it still ended up being $18 bucks before tip. While I thought the prices at Thai Place were a little high, it was still a great meal. In a city where steak and barbecue rule, I&apos;m glad that I was able to find a restaurant like Thai Place. They have so many things to choose from on their menu, I&apos;ll be able to go back time and time again and try any one of the wonderful and interesting food Ted Liberda&apos;s come up with. 

 
 
 January 28, 2009 in Kansas City , Restaurants , Thai Food | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Beer Hunting in Kansas City 
 
 I picked up a number of good Oktoberfest beers this fall once again this year. While I was in Kansas City a few weeks ago, I stopped at a number of liquor stores in the area. These are ones that I&apos;ve been going to for a number of years and I just happened to hit them while I was in town for two or three days earlier this fall. 

 Gomer&apos;s  has been around for over 30 years on the Missouri side of Kansas City. I was first turned on to Gomer&apos;s when I would travel to Kansas City to see an old girlfriend in the late 70&apos;s, then again after I began to work for a company in the KC area in the mid-80&apos;s. Gomer&apos;s was nothing like I&apos;d ever seen before in regard to a liquor store that had such a great variety of beer, wine and liquor.  

 There are four locations of Gomer&apos;s in Kansas City.  I first went to the Midtown location ( see map ) years ago and I went to the south location ( see map ) on my most recent visit. While others in the area have passed Gomer&apos;s by in terms of beer selection, I still like to go in and take a quick look around to see if there&apos;s anything that I can&apos;t live without.  

 Metcalf Discount Liquor in Overland Park ( see map ) is in the same shopping complex as one of my large dealers in the KC area. This location is one of three in the company, which is basically a small family owned business. They have a pretty good selection of eclectic beers and often at a very good price.  

 Metcalf Discount Liquor has a single bottle&quot;mix and match&quot;program with an ever expanding selection of different brands of beer. They had a great price on a case of the Boulevard Brewing Company&apos;s Bob&apos;s 47 Oktoberfest beer . I couldn&apos;t resist the price - about $27 bucks for the case. And I love Bob&apos;s 47 Oktoberfest beer.  

 Lukas Liquor in Shawnee Mission ( see map ) is an 18,000 sq. ft. superstore that features the best selection of beer and wine of any store in the Kansas City area. Founded in 1981, Lukas Liquor moved to its present location in 1995. They also have three other locations , including one in suburban St. Louis that I&apos;ve visited a couple times in the past.  

 I never knew the one on in Shawnee Mission existed until a buddy of mine was telling me about it a couple three years ago. When I found it (it&apos;s actually back off the street a ways in a strip mall), I was astounded at the selection of beers they had in the place. I think I spent well over $50 bucks on my first visit and it&apos;s always a $20 bill or more each time I go into Lukas Liquor. l was able to find a couple six packs of the Paulaner Oktoberfest and the Warsteiner Premium Oktoberfest beers 

 Berbiglia (pronounced Ber-BIL-ya) Wine and Spirits has the Missouri side of Kansas City covered with 11 locations . Berbiglia is arguably the oldest liquor store in the area as it started as a grocery store in 1917. Through the years, it morphed from an upscale grocery store during its day to more of a wine and liquor store that sold eclectic foods, as well.  

 I visited two of the locations while I was in Kansas City - the main location on W. 103rd St. just east of State Line Road ( see map ), and the location at 79th and Wornall ( see map ), just down the street from a dealer I&apos;m trying to land. While the Berbiglia locations I&apos;ve been to seem to cater more toward wine connoisseurs than beer guys. I didn&apos;t really find anything that I absolutely really needed from Berbiglia&apos;s. 

 Royal Liquors  is probably my favorite place to go looking for beer in Kansas City. They rival Lukas Liquor in selection and price, but they seem to have more helpful and knowledgeable people who like to tell you about their favorites. I stopped at the downtown location off of I-35 on Southwest Boulevard when I was in town recently ( see map ). They categorize their beers in two levels - domestic and imports. Actually, all the domestically brewed specialty and craft beers - including Boulevard , which is located just down the street from Royal Liquors - are classified as imports. I have to say that Royal Liquors has the largest variety of EACH beer to choose from. You can buy the different beer by the cases to kegs to 6-packs, 12-packs, singles, whatever. 

 They had a large selection of the Bell&apos;s   Oktoberfest beer - one of my all-time favorite marzen style beers. I had to get a couple sixers of that while I was there. Plus, I was told to try the Ayinger   Oktoberfest beer. Ayinger is a German brewer and their Oktoberfest beer - although a little expensive - was very good. I got a six pack of the beer and it was gone within days of getting it home. I should have gotten another.  

 Any one of the above places is very good to visit when you&apos;re on the hunt for beer in Kansas City. Royal Liquors and Lukas Liquor are probably the best in terms of variety and price. But you don&apos;t want to pass up the other places as you&apos;ll never know what you find.  
 
 December 10, 2008 in Beer, Wine and Liquor Stores , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Arthur Bryant&apos;s - Kansas City 
 
 It had been years since I&apos;d been to Arthur Bryant&apos;s barbecue joint in Kansas City ( see map ) that I wanted to try it again. I still think Jack Stack Barbecue is the best in Kansas City, but something was just calling me the day I stopped in Arthur Bryant&apos;s original location recently.  I had to work a dealer event that evening and wanted to have a big lunch as I knew I probably wouldn&apos;t be eating again that day.  

 Arthur Bryant&apos;s is world renown in that heads of state, celebrities and average&quot;Joe&apos;s&quot;have been eating there since 1930. Arthur Bryant (right) took barbecue out of the dingy back room place in Kansas City and helped transform the town into one of the select cities for barbecue in the world.  

 Henry Perry was known as the&quot;Father of Barbecue&quot;in Kansas City. His barbecue place was one of many that sprang up during the Depression. One of his workers was a guy by the name of Charlie Bryant. Charlie&apos;s brother, Arthur, came to visit him one time and fell in love with Perry&apos;s place. After Henry died, Charlie took over the running of the business with Arthur at his side. When Charlie died, Arthur took over.  Tons of barbecue places have come and gone in Kansas City over the years, but Bryant&apos;s was really the first one that made it available to the masses. 

 Arthur Bryant died in his restaurant in 1982 at the age of 80, doing what he loved doing the most. Bryant&apos;s closed down after that, but was revitalized two months later by two investors - Gary Berbiglia and Bill Rauschelbach. Both continue to run the original one at 18th and Brooklyn, as well as two other locations around Kansas City - all of which hold the same traditions of smoked foods, tangy sauces and large portions that Arthur held so dear.  

 It was around 2 p.m. when I got into Arthur Bryant&apos;s. It had been - oh, God - about 18 years since I was last in the place. And it was exactly the same as it was before.  You have a serving line where you take a tray and order directly with the guy who serves up your food. The menu is posted on a board above the serving area.  

 I remember the beef brisket sandwich being not only very good but very big. I ordered up a brisket sandwich with fries for $9.35. For fun, I decided to try some of their baked beans for an additional $2.25. The guy behind the counter grabbed a handful of succulent, thin shaved beef brisket and formed kind of a ball of meat on top of a piece of white bread. Then he topped it off with another slice of white bread and a shit load of fries.  

 I grabbed a couple of beers and the bill came to about $18.00. Expensive, but what the hell. It was Arthur Bryant&apos;s and it was good barbecue.  

 First of all, there&apos;s no way you can eat a beef brisket sandwich with your hands at Arthur Bryant&apos;s. You pour a little sauce on the top and dig in with a knife and fork. The sauces at Arthur Bryant&apos;s are OK - nothing special. The Original Sauce has a vinegar base to it and it pretty runny. The Rich and Spicy sauce is more thick, but I didn&apos;t think it was all that spicy. Still, I liked it better than the Original. 

 And the amount of food - oh, shit! There&apos;s a good pound of beef brisket and a like amount of fries. The bowl of beans wasn&apos;t all that big, but it was enough. I poured some of the two different sauces in with the beans and tried it that way. They were good, but not outstanding. 

 But the brisket was great. I&apos;m a sucker for a good brisket. It was tender and juicy with the right amount of smoky flavor. Even though I never came close to finishing half the fries and beans, I made damn sure there wasn&apos;t an morsel of beef left on my plate.  

 Actually, I think of Arthur Bryant&apos;s as more of a tourist trap these days than a top notch barbecue joint. The beef brisket sandwich was very good, however. I would go back there in a heartbeat just for that alone. And I&apos;ll probably do just that. Jesus, my stomach is doing back flips as I write this!    

 
 
 April 14, 2008 in Barbecue , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (4) 

 | | | 
 
 Kansas City Barbecue in the Chicago Tribune 
 
 A couple days ago, the Chicago Tribune featured an article on Kansas City Barbecue . The article talked about the history of Kansas City style barbecue and also talked about some of the big names of barbecue in town, including Gates BBQ , Arthur Bryant&apos;s , and my personal favorite, Fiorella&apos;s Jack Stack . It also talks about some of the lesser known and up-and-coming barbecue places in Kansas City. 

 There&apos;s also some recipes included in the article, as well as a series of photographs from some of the Kansas City area barbecue establishments. And click here to see a streaming video interview with Ollie Gates, the son of the founder of Gates BBQ.  

 The only problem I have with the article is that the author is geographically challenged. She states that Kansas City is halfway between Texas and Memphis - two bastions of barbecue. Well, last time I looked on a map, Little Rock, Arkansas, was halfway between Memphis and Texas. Kansas City is directly north of Texas and northwest of Memphis. But that&apos;s neither here nor there when you get into the&quot;meat&quot;of the article. 

 If you&apos;re reading the linked article around lunch time, don&apos;t blame me if your stomach sends out hunger pangs. The pictures and the story made me want to get back to Kansas City as soon as I can.   
 
 August 31, 2007 in Barbecue , Kansas City , Recipes | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Ponak&apos;s Mexican Kitchen - Kansas City, MO 
 
 I love Mexican food and I don&apos;t seem to eat it all that much when I&apos;m on the road. The problem is that most of the great places in a given area are usually only known to the locals. All the touristy places - the chains - are OK, but not what I&apos;m looking for in Mexican food. I want real, authentic Mexican. And they&apos;re usually in places that are tough to find. 

 Fortunately, on my last trip to Kansas City, a couple of the guys from one of my dealers took me to Ponak&apos;s Mexican Kitchen, southwest of the downtown Kansas City area right near the I-35 overpass ( see map ). Ponak&apos;s is owned by John Ponak. I know, you&apos;re thinking - How can a guy with a Croatian name cook great Mexican food? Actually, it was John Ponak&apos;s Mexican grandmother who started the restaurant. He took it over about 20 years ago and continues to run it today (when he&apos;s not at his second home in Florida). 

 One of the guys I was with knew John Ponak from years before and said he liked to drink his beer. I was told,&quot;Just like all of us, I&apos;m sure he&apos;s slowed down.&quot;  

 Well, not me... 

 Ponak&apos;s interior is more reminiscent of a Northwoods lodge with a lot of knotty pine walls and basic tables and chairs.  There&apos;s a bar area as you walk in - that&apos;s the smoking area - and then the main dining room is to the left of the bar area.  

 We sat down at a table in the half-filled dining room. It was around 8:15 in the evening and I understand that Ponak&apos;s can get pretty busy during lunch and dinner. Since it was a Wednesday night, it wasn&apos;t too bad. 

 We were given a basket of homemade chips and some of their spicy and tangy homemade salsa. They were very good. The guys told me their margaritas were very good and I ordered one of those. One of the other guys said,&quot;Why don&apos;t we just get a pitcher?&quot; So we did. 

 There&apos;s a lot of authentic Tex-Mex food on the menu. I was looking at a lot of different things, including their deep fried shredded beef flour tacos, pork enchiladas, and chili rellenos. I couldn&apos;t make up my mind as to what I wanted, so I ordered all of them al a carte.  

 One of the guys got the combo fajitas - shrimp and beef. The other guy ordered a combination platter of a burrito, enchilada and a beef tostada. Refried beans and rice came with the meals.  

 After we polished off the pitcher of margaritas, the waitress came back and asked if we wanted another. I said,&quot;Well, if you guys want another one, that&apos;s fine. But I&apos;m going to have a beer.&quot; 

 I asked the waitress if they had Sol , and she said they did. One of the guys said,&quot;Sol? I&apos;ve never had that before. Is it good?&quot; 

 I said,&quot;I like it better than Corona and it&apos;s more authentic than Corona, I think.&quot; 

 So, he ended up ordering one, as well. And bowing to peer pressure, the other guy said,&quot;Well, sign me up, too.&quot;  

 Almost simultaneously, the food and the beer showed up. Served on huge plates, the portions were large, but manageable. I dug right into my deep fried shredded beef flour taco. I&apos;m a sucker for deep fried flour tacos. The shells puff up and they&apos;re so light and tasty. The shredded beef was seasoned in a machaca -like style with chiles, cumin and garlic. It was wonderful. As was the pork enchilada. It wasn&apos;t all that large, but the pork filling was tender and flavorful. And the chile relleno was very good, as well.  

 Our bill for the three of us with the margaritas and a couple beers each came to just under $50 bucks with tip. A lot of food and good drinks for a little bit of money.  

 There&apos;s a lot of good Mexican restaurants in the area around Ponak&apos;s, but according to one of my guests it&apos;s the best of the best. Not having tried some of the others yet, I&apos;m going to have to take his word for it. Ponak&apos;s Mexican Kitchen was damned good. I highly recommend giving it a try if you&apos;re in the greater Kansas City area. And I&apos;ll be back, you can bet on that.     

 
 
 August 03, 2007 in Kansas City , Mexican , Restaurants | Permalink | Comments (1) 

 | | | 
 
 The Phoenix Piano Bar and Grille - Kansas City 
 
 On a recent trip to Kansas City, Dominic Baker from Focal Loudspeakers and I offered to take one of our dealers in the K.C. area out to lunch. Not far from his place of business is a little jazz club called The Phoenix Piano Bar and Grill . I&apos;d always seen the place and had wanted to try it out. Now was my chance. 

 The Kansas City jazz scene has been a staple of the community for a number of years. There are a number of jazz clubs and bars throughout the Kansas City area - many of them are carrying on the tradition that started in the city in 30&apos;s. 

 The building that houses The Phoenix Piano Bar and Grill in downtown Kansas City ( see map ) sits smack dab in the middle of the historic Garment District. The building, itself, was built in the late 1800&apos;s and was rumored to be a brothel at one time.  

 In 1989, Tim Whitmer (right), a world-class jazz pianist, opened The Phoenix as a place for good food and good jazz. Whitmer brought in a number of great Kansas City jazz musicians to play each night. Whitmer will occasionally play The Phoenix, but he prefers to allow other area musicians show their prowess.  

 As you walk in the door at The Phoenix, there&apos;s a grand piano sitting on a small stage. While the place is not all that large, you get a cozy feeling when you find a seat. Actually, the tables are jammed pretty close together. I&apos;m sure it&apos;s to maximize the minimal seating area they have.  

 The Phoenix draws a pretty good lunch crowd from the downtown offices. Guys in coats and ties were having lunch and talking business all around us. Dominic wasn&apos;t feeling well, having caught a cold in Japan a couple weeks earlier that he couldn&apos;t shake. So we kept the business conversations to a minimum. 

 The Phoenix&apos;s menu offers a number of entrees including a number of pasta dishes. They also have steaks and a couple of seafood items to choose from, as well. Their sandwiches and burgers are pretty basic, but interesting from the description. They also offer appetizers and salads , as well. 

 Even though they feature lunch specials each day during the weekdays, everything that is on the dinner menu can be had at lunch. Dominic was thinking that he really needed to eat some spicy food to help stifle the cold, so he went with the Cajun chicken pasta - chunks of grilled chicken on a bed of fettuccine with a spicy Cajun sauce lopped on top.  

 Our guest got the Smoked Reuben - smoked corned beef brisket piled high on marble rye with sauerkraut and then grilled. It looked great. 

 I went with the Phoenix&apos;s Special - ham and lean roast beef topped with Monterey and cheddar cheese, and piled on sourdough bread and served with a side of Gates BBQ sauce. Even though I&apos;m not a big fan of Gates BBQ sauce, it helped complement the sandwich very well. The sandwich was large and was very good. 

 All three of us were more than full when we were finished. Dominic, who has eaten in fine restaurants all over the world, thought his pasta was delicious. Our guest told us,&quot;They do a pretty fine job here at The Phoenix.&quot; I have to agree. 

 I&apos;m sure the place really packs in the crowd for the jazz music that starts around 9 p.m. each night. But even if it weren&apos;t for the draw of the music, I think The Phoenix would more than hold it&apos;s own as a stand alone restaurant.    

 
 
 April 27, 2007 in Bands and Music , Kansas City , Restaurants | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Bravo! Cucina Italiana - Overland Park, KS 
 
 On a recent visit to Kansas City, I had a meeting with my big dealer there one evening. After the meeting, we went to Bravo! Cucina Italiana for dinner.  

 Bravo! Cucina Italiana - or Bravo! for the regulars - is a small chain of 34 restaurants located mainly in the eastern and midwestern part of the nation. There are two in Kansas City and we went to the Bravo! restaurant located in the upscale Town Center Plaza shopping complex in the Overland Park/Leawood area ( see map ). 

 Bravo! is an Ohio-based corporation headed by CEO Chris Doody. Bravo! is part of the Bravo! Development Group of restaurants that also includes the Tuscany-style offerings of Brio , a 20 plus chain of restaurants across the eastern and middle part of the U.S. 

 Bravo! is more of a&quot;ristorante&quot;style of Italian restaurant complete with linen tablecloths and authentic Italian decor. The&quot;Cucina Italiana&quot;- Italian Kitchen - part of their name signifies the traditional style of Italian cooking that goes on in the restaurant. The kitchen is in full view of the diners, similar to traditional upscale Italian restaurants. 

 According to their web site, Bravo&apos;s interiors are consistent with ancient Italian architecture down to the imported Italian marble floors, the Venetian-plastered walls and other hand-crafted Italian reliefs. I didn&apos;t really pay that much attention to the decor the night we went. It seemed to be nice, but sort of loud in the place. 

 There were five of us who went to dinner that evening. We were seated at a table in the back corner offering us a side view of the goings on in the kitchen. It also afforded us a much quieter surrounding so we could continue to discuss business over dinner. 

 The dinner menu is truly traditional Italian with pasta dishes, pizza, wood-fired steaks and chicken, and seafood. The wine list was a little less than desirable, but we did end up getting a bottle of the Sketchbook Cabernet from California that was recommended by one of my guests. It did the job.  

 Since I&apos;d never been there before (and, subsequently, didn&apos;t realize it was a chain), I looked at a lot of possibilities. Their Pasta Bravo! dish looked interesting - pasta with grilled chicken chunks and mushrooms with a red pepper sauce. They also had a chicken Marsala dish that was grilled above wood, served with a white wine Marsala sauce and served on top of a bed of Tuscan mashed potatoes. They both sounded pretty good to me. 

 However, one my guests absolutely RAVED about the Bolognese Lasagna. He said it was the best lasagna he&apos;d ever had. He talked about how good it was, I had to get try it.  

 One of the other guys got the Lobster and Shrimp ravioli. Another person got the special that night - grilled sea scallops with pasta. And one other person got the sauteed crab cakes.  

 We were also served a generous dinner salad that we ate along with an appetizer of a Spinach and Artichoke dip. Our waiter - a 50&apos;s-ish gentleman - was attentive. But he was almost too attentive and too overbearing for my liking.  

 Our food came and while the portion of lasagna I received was generous, it was no where near the size of the lasagna I&apos;ve gotten from Lunardi&apos;s in Davenport . And I have to say that it was good, but I liked Lunardi&apos;s lasagna much better.  

 The grilled scallops looked great and my guest who ordered them said they were. And the grilled crab cakes were reportedly very fresh and very tasty. But the dish I should have gotten is the Lobster and Shrimp ravioli - chunks of lobster and full shrimp on a bed of mozzarella cheese ravioli with a white wine sauce poured on top. I was offered a bite and I have to say it was very good. 

 But as attentive and hovering our waiter was before the dinner was served, he all but disappeared after our meal was served. A couple of the guys wanted water refills and some fresh cracked pepper. He finally showed back up after we were all nearly finished with our meals.  

 All in all, Bravo! was nice, but there are better Italian restaurants in the south Kansas City area that, I feel, are more authentic and have better food. But as a corporate entity, Bravo! does it well and it doesn&apos;t seem to have the&quot;cookie cutter&quot;feel that one gets from some of the larger Italian chain restaurants. Since most of the Bravo! restaurants are located in or near large shopping complexes, I&apos;d say it&apos;s worth a visit when you&apos;re out shopping.  

 
 
 April 05, 2007 in Italian , Kansas City , Restaurants | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Smokin&apos; Guns BBQ - N. Kansas City, MO 
 
 When I was in Kansas City recently, I traveled one day with an outside sales guy with ADI , a distributor of electronic parts and products. We went to see a dealer in North Kansas City and it turned out that he had an ulterior motive. He wanted to take me to one of the hidden secrets of barbecue in Kansas City, Smokin&apos;Guns BBQ . 

 Smokin&apos;Guns BBQ is located in an industrial area that is populated with a lot of light manufacturing or warehouse firms ( see map ). They&apos;re only open during the day through the week - 10 a.m. to 6 p.m. The dealer we took to lunch told me that the place is packed from 5 p.m. to 6 p.m. with people taking home barbecue. 

 For years, Phil and Linda Hopkins traveled the barbecue contest circuit piling up a number of awards. In 1999, they were the overall winner (scroll down at the link site to see their point total) of the prestigious Jack Daniels World Championship Invitational Barbecue .  Their overall point total&quot;smoked&quot;the competition that year. Here&apos;s a picture of Phil and Linda with their two sons after the competition.
 

 Friends and people they did catering for kept on them to open a restaurant. Phil still wanted to do some weekend barbecue contests and cater parties. When they finally opened up in the North Kansas City location in 2002, he made the decision not to open the restaurant over the weekend. At least, that&apos;s what the dealer we had lunch with told me. And since he&apos;s literally right across the street from Smokin&apos;Guns and eats there all the time, he should probably know. 

 The menu at Smokin&apos;Guns is typical of most Kansas City barbecue places. They&apos;re heavy on the pork ribs and brisket, along with burnt ends, sausage, turkey and ham.  And the ambiance of the place is just like you&apos;d find at any family owned barbecue joint. You go into the place and place your order at the front counter. You pay and then go get your drinks and sit down at these very basic tables. A waitress will find you and bring your food to you.
 

 I wasn&apos;t all that hungry because it was a quarter to 12 and I&apos;d eaten breakfast not knowing if we would have time to eat lunch that day. But the ADI guy knew that we would be ending up around this dealer&apos;s place around noon and he was starving for barbecue. The dealer told me,&quot;It&apos;s best to go early or wait until after 1:30. It gets packed in this place during the lunch hour.&quot; 
 

 I ordered up the large brisket sandwich on regular bread with no sides. One of the dealer&apos;s guys was with us and he said,&quot;Oh, man! They have the best broccoli casserole and potato casserole in the world.&quot; I told him that I&apos;d had breakfast and didn&apos;t know we were going to do lunch. He said,&quot;Well, that was your first mistake this morning. Your second mistake is not getting one of the sides of casserole.&quot; 
 

 The guy from ADI got the burnt ends with the potato casserole. And the other two guys from the dealer were good ol&apos;Catholic boys and were observing Lent. One went with the smoked Salmon and the other guy got the smoked catfish. 

 My sandwich was very good. A lot of meat and the sauce they had with it was rich and sweet. I went up and asked if they had any hot sauce and the waitress, who was well into her 60&apos;s, said,&quot;We sure do!&quot; It was good and spicy, but could have been a little more hot. 
 

 The ADI guy said that he was disappointed in his burnt ends. One of the guys from the dealer said Smokin&apos;Guns burnt ends are&quot;hit and miss&quot;. He just missed&apos;em this time. 
 

 And the guys who had the smoked fish thought they were great. And they kept raving about the potato casserole and the broccoli casserole. OK, I told them. Next time I&apos;ll get one or the other. 
 

 My sandwich was $6.95 and the Burnt Ends were $10.95. The smoked fish were both $8.95 with fries. I didn&apos;t get fries (steak fries are two bucks extra with a sandwich) but that&apos;s OK. A steak fry is a steak fry.
 

 Yes, I&apos;ll go back to Smokin&apos;Guns BBQ. But I didn&apos;t want to pig out with a dress shirt on and in front of guys I hardly knew. I&apos;m looking at getting the three meat platter the next time I go to K.C. 
 

 The only negative I see with Smokin&apos;Guns? They don&apos;t serve beer. Damn... How can you NOT have beer with good barbecue. Oh, well. Smokin&apos;Guns is able to pull it off. 
 

 
 
 March 06, 2007 in Barbecue , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (1) 

 | | | 
 
 Ted&apos;s Montana Grill - Schaumburg, IL 
 
 I recently had to run our daughter into Chicago for her to fly out to England to meet our other daughter who is studying in Spain this year. She said that since she wasn&apos;t going to be eating for awhile while traveling, she wanted a&quot;stick-to-your-ribs&quot;kind of meal before she left. I decided to take her to Ted&apos;s Montana Grill . 

 I&apos;ve written about Ted&apos;s here first as a steakhouse ; then again as a burger joint . They bill themselves as a classic American grill that happens to serve comfort food. I do like their bison steaks and burgers - the best of their kind that I&apos;ve ever had. But they also serve something called bison pot roast and I&apos;ve always wanted to try it. 

 We got in to the Ted&apos;s in suburban Schaumburg just before noon and we were promptly seated in a spacious booth. Our waitress was a red-haired Scottish lady with a big smile, Wilma. Within 90 seconds we found out that Wilma retired from United Airlines after working 30 years as stewardess, she was working part-time at Ted&apos;s because the airlines cut 50% of her pension, she celebrated her 60th birthday in her native Scotland, and the actor Sean Connery kissed her on the cheek on her birthday. She was a real trip and I liked her immediately. 

 She asked if we&apos;d ever been to Ted&apos;s before. Oh, yes. I told her I&apos;d been to different Ted&apos;s Montana Grill&apos;s many times before. She said,&quot;So you&apos;re a veteran, now. You know the story, then.&quot;  

 I said I did, but my daughter didn&apos;t. She talked about the lunch menu and the daily blue plate specials . The special that day was a slow roasted pork loin with cooked carrots, mashed potatoes and gravy.  

 Out of the blue she offered us a sample of their bison pot roast. I hadn&apos;t completely been sold on getting the pot roast as of yet. (I thought about getting a bison burger, only cooked a little longer this time than the last time I had a burger there.) She brought us out two small bowls with shredded bison meat over mashed potatoes with a little gravy. I have to say it was very good. So, I went with the bison pot roast (which is available daily) and my daughter went with the pork loin blue plate special.  

 While we were waiting for our food, the day manager came over, introduced himself, shook my hand and said,&quot;I understand that you&apos;re a veteran of Ted&apos;s Montana Grill.&quot; I told him that I travel a lot and I try to stay away from chains, but I&apos;ve never been steered wrong by eating at a Ted&apos;s. I was hoping he&apos;d give me a gift certificate, but that never materialized. 

 Wilma brought our food out and the pork loin with carrots and mashed potatoes was exactly what my daughter was looking for. And the bison pot roast with mashed potatoes, gravy and a side of green beans was just great for me. The bison meat was tender and the gravy was a excellent complement to the meal.  

 I was intrigued by the gravy so I asked Wilma after I&apos;d finished what was in it. She said,&quot;Oh, you know I should know this, but I&apos;ll check in the kitchen.&quot;  

 She came back out and said the gravy with the pork loin was a combination of chardonnay wine, cream and natural juices, while the beef gravy was also a combination of natural juices from the meat and Kitchen Bouquet . I could have sworn there was some red wine in there with it, but Wilma said,&quot;Nope, Kitchen Bouquet and juices. I know it doesn&apos;t sound glamorous, but it&apos;s good, isn&apos;t it?&quot; 

 It was a spot hitter.  

 I&apos;m always looking for a&quot;stick-to-your-ribs&quot;meal on the road and I&apos;ll be going back to Ted&apos;s Montana Grill for the bison pot roast again.  

 ( Update - Ted&apos;s Montana Grill closed a number of restaurants in the fall of 2010, including the one in Schaumburg. That&apos;s too bad because many of them were in places that I travel to - Wichita, Omaha and Kansas City. I suppose with such strong competition for steakhouses in those markets, Ted&apos;s Montana Grill felt it would be better to focus on markets where they could succeed. Another reason why this particular Ted&apos;s probably shut down was that a  Weber Grill Restaurant    opened just up the road from the old Ted&apos;s location in late 2006. That particular Weber Grill location was always packed. However, I&apos;m not without a Ted&apos;s in my travels. There are still 3 in the greater Chicago region and a couple in Indianapolis.) 
 
 January 12, 2007 in Chicago , Chicago Suburbs , Comfort Food , Kansas City , Rest In Peace | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Kelly&apos;s Westport Inn - Kansas City, MO 
 
 Here&apos;s one of my all-time favorite places to have a beer - Kelly&apos;s Westport Inn in the heart of the Westport district in Kansas City ( see map ). 

 I think the first time I was in Kelly&apos;s was in the mid-70&apos;s and it&apos;s a treat to go back in and have a beer when I get a chance. During our trip to Kansas City this past summer we were walking around the Westport area taking a look at some of the small shops in the area.  

 It was getting to be late morning and we were walking near Kelly&apos;s and I mentioned to Cindy that the place was one of my favorite places to have a beer. She - to my surprise - suggested we go in and have a beer. Wow! Sure, dear!  

 Kelly&apos;s Westport Inn has been around for nearly 60 years. It is truly an institution in Kansas City. The building that houses Kelly&apos;s dates back to the mid-19th century. I&apos;ve heard it&apos;s the oldest building still standing in Kansas City. And I understand it was once a grocery store that was owned and run by Albert Boone , the grandson of Daniel Boone .  

 The grocery store eventually evolved into a high-end grocery store - Wiedenmann&apos;s (left) -by the turn of the 20th century. With the repeal of Prohibition in 1933, the grocery store was turned into a tavern - The Wrestlers Inn. After World War II, Art Brock and two partners bought the bar and renamed it The Westport Inn. Brock eventually bought out his partners to become sole owner. 

 An Irish immigrant by the name of Randal Kelly came to Kansas City and became the head bartender at The Westport Inn (right). Kelly eventually became partners with Brock and took over the operation as sole owner. It soon became Kelly&apos;s Westport Inn. 

 Randal Kelly, who was ultimately associated with the establishment for over 40 years, turned over the reins to his son Randy. Randy eventually moved to the Ozarks and opened up Kelly&apos;s Port , a popular marina on the Lake of the Ozarks . Randy, in turn, handed over the operation to his two younger brothers, Pat and Kyle. They continue to run the bar to this day. 

 The inside of Kelly&apos;s is typical of older restaurants - hard chairs, wooden floors, high ceilings. The bar has a lot of history and the stories people have told about a night at Kelly&apos;s are numerous.  

 Kelly&apos;s doesn&apos;t serve food, per se, but they do have a pizza place in the back - Joe&apos;s Pizza . They serve full pizzas, pizza by the slice and sandwiches. Since we were in there around noon time, we noticed a lot of people grabbing a couple slices of pizza and having a beer with them.   

 Of course, I had to have a Boulevard Pale Ale on our visit there. Cindy ordered up a Smithwick&apos;s . Here&apos;s a picture of Cindy enjoying her cold beer on a warm day in Kansas City. 

 

 
 

 The daytime usually sees more of an older, eclectic crowd at Kelly&apos;s; while at night it gets younger and more crowded.  St. Patrick&apos;s Day at Kelly&apos;s can get a little crazy as evidenced by this picture (right). In fact, at one point, Randall Kelly used to close Kelly&apos;s on St. Patrick&apos;s Day because he was worried the place would get TOO full.   

 Kelly&apos;s is a great place to get a beer. If you like history, beer and a good time - Kelly&apos;s Westport Inn is the place in Kansas City.   
 
 December 15, 2006 in Beer Bars , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (1) 

 | | | 
 
 Hereford House - Kansas City 
 
 I&apos;ve been meaning to write about the world famous Hereford House steakhouses in the Kansas City area for quite some time. I was in Kansas City recently, calling on one of my large dealers out in Overland Park. A scheduling snafu on the dealer&apos;s part ended up with me eating alone that evening. Hey, that&apos;s OK. I&apos;ve got time on my hands. And the Hereford House is right down the road. 

 The Hereford House began in 1957 when Jack Webb (not the actor ) opened the doors of his steakhouse (right) located in downtown Kansas City at the corner of Main and 20th near the famous stockyards ( see map ). 30 years later, a group of investors headed by Rod Anderson bought the Hereford House and began a renovation and expansion of the original property.  

 In 1997, the Anderson Restaurant Group opened a second Hereford House in Leawood, KS ( see map ); followed by a third location in Independence, MO in 2002 ( see map ); and they opened their fourth Hereford House location at the new Zona Rosa shopping area in north Kansas City, MO ( see map ).  

 The Anderson Restaurant Group also runs Pierpont&apos;s at the historic Union Station , as well as the Hollywood Room - a place used for private parties and corporate functions.  

 The Hereford House restaurants serves Sterling Silver meats, a high end meat producer owned by Cargill . Sterling Silver steaks are consistently rated as the highest quality by a number of top chefs across America. The&quot;marbling&quot;of Sterling Silver steaks is a direct result of selecting special cuts that are only available on about 10% of the beef population of North America. 

 The Hereford House in Leawood was characteristically busy that evening. I asked if I can eat at the bar and the hostess said,&quot;Oh, please do!&quot; 

 (As an aside - Each time I&apos;ve eaten at the bar of a fine steak house since my visit to Smoky&apos;s Club in Madison, I&apos;m reminded of what that bitchy hostess said to me when I asked if I could eat at the bar -&quot;We do not serve dinner at the bar. We&apos;re not that kind of place.&quot; Well, a lot more classy and BETTER places serve dinner at the bar and ARE that kind of place. Another reason I&apos;ll probably never go back to Smoky&apos;s.) 

 I got a seat at the bar, right under a light so I could read the paper. They had a basketball game on the TV. They had cold Boulevard Pale Ale on tap - I was set.  

 Looking through the menu , I was tempted to get the prime rib. But I really wanted a grilled steak. And there&apos;s so many to choose from - ribeye, KC strip, filet. But I ordered up the blackened ribeye topped with garlic butter sauce. And I got a side of mashed sweet potatoes and a Caesar salad.  

 I wanted some wine, and I ordered a glass of the Franciscan Oakville Estates merlot. My bartender said that he didn&apos;t have that particular variety that evening. I didn&apos;t see anything else on their&quot;by the glass&quot;list that tripped my trigger. My bartender said that they had half-bottles of some selected wines, so he gave me the wine list. I immediately found a 2003 Duckhorn merlot in a 375 ml bottle for $22 bucks and I ordered that. 

 My steak was brought out and it was cooked a very perfect medium rare. The meat was tender and juicy, and had a great taste to it. Coupled with the mashed sweet potatoes and the wine, it was a killer meal. I was in heaven.  

 With tip, the bill came to just about $70 bucks. The Hereford House isn&apos;t a cheap place, but it&apos;s worth every penny. Believe me.  

 In a city famous for steaks, there&apos;s no place finer than the Hereford House. It&apos;s a must stop if you&apos;re looking for a great steak in Kansas City.  

 
 
 November 30, 2006 in Kansas City , Steak Houses | Permalink | Comments (1) 

 | | | 
 
 Christopher Elbow Chocolates - Kansas City 
 
 One night, Cindy and I were talking with our backyard neighbor, Barb Fensterbusch, and she was telling us about a relative of hers by the name of Christopher Elbow who makes exotic, high-end chocolates in Kansas City. Since we&apos;d just been in Kansas City earlier in the summer, Cindy remarked that she would have loved to have gone there to check his place out.  

 Christopher Elbow (left) graduated from the University of Nebraska in 1996 with a degree is Restaurant and Business Administration. He went home to Kansas City and ran Shiraz restaurant for three years. In 1999, he went to Las Vegas to work for Emeril Lagasse in the new Delmonico Steakhouse in the Venetian . Not long after that, he ended up helping acclaimed chef Jean Joho open the posh Eiffel Tower restaurant in the Paris Hotel and Casino in Las Vegas. 

 Elbow eventually moved back to Kansas City and found himself at the American Restaurant , a world class restaurant in the Crown Center shopping plaza. Elbow was the pastry chef and he soon found that he had a flair for making&quot;artisanal chocolates&quot;, small chocolate treats filled with fruits or liqueurs. In fact, he got so good at it, he struck out on his own and opened Christopher Elbow Artisanal Chocolates a couple years ago. 

 When I was in Kansas City recently, I had just finished meeting with a dealer account of mine in the downtown area. Remembering that Elbow Chocolates were not far from my dealer, I decided to go down and get a box to take back to Barb.  

 Except, I had trouble finding the place. The address showed that it was on Southwest Blvd. ( see map ), but where the business should have been was a Mitchell Gold contemporary furniture store. Finally, I saw a small sign for Christopher Elbow Chocolates above one of the doors of the furniture store.  

 I went into the store and looked around. It didn&apos;t look like a place that would sell chocolates, but then looking toward the back of the store, there was a confectionery case and what appeared to be a kitchen directly behind that. Sure enough, I&apos;d found Christopher Elbow Chocolates. 

 A young girl came out and asked if she could help me. They had an assortment of pre-packed chocolates in the case - the smallest was a nine piece assortment in a nice box with a bow on it. I knew that if I brought a box home for Barb, Cindy would be complaining that I didn&apos;t bring any home for her.  

 I told the girl that I wanted two boxes and she said,&quot;OK, those are $18.00 each.&quot; I about jumped, but thought better of it. They also had a number of single chocolates in the case and I asked,&quot;How much are they individually?&quot; 

 She said,&quot;$2.75 each.&quot; I told her I&apos;d just take the two boxes of nine.  

 As she was ringing me up, I asked her if one of the three workers I could see working in the back was Christopher Elbow. She said,&quot;No, I&apos;m sorry but Christopher&apos;s out of town for a couple days.&quot; Oh well. No biggie.  

 Now, I&apos;m not big on chocolate and I&apos;m not very big on filled chocolates, but the boxes I brought home were rather intriguing. The flavors ranged from a Strawberry Balsamic, to a Pear Cinnamon caramel, to a Venezuelan Spice, to a Passion Fruit. I told Cindy that I wanted to pick three and she could have the rest.  

 She looked at the box of chocolates (which come with a little&quot;road map&quot;to tell what they are) and she said,&quot;Geez, they&apos;re almost too pretty to eat!&quot;  

 The first one that I took was the Grand Marnier filled chocolate. I&apos;m a sucker for Grand Marnier in chocolate. It was very flavorful - probably the best one of that type I&apos;d ever had. 

 The second one I picked was the Rosemary Caramel. I fully expected it to be chewy, but my teeth went right through it to the filling and only after I got past the taste of the chocolate and the hint of rosemary did I get to the chewiness of the caramel.  

 And the last one I picked was the Vietnamese Cinnamon. Vietnam supposedly has some of the most strong and pungent cinnamon in the world and this was no exception. The cinnamon taste didn&apos;t overpower the chocolate, it complemented the chocolate. And the taste lingered for minutes in my mouth. Wow!   

 I took a box up to Barb and she was overly appreciative. It was the least I could do since she lets us swim in her pool each summer.  

 She said that Christopher Elbow&apos;s mother was just there to see her a couple weeks prior and she said that his business is growing so fast that he&apos;s moving to a bigger facility in Kansas City. She said,&quot;His mother told me that he&apos;s on track to make 50,000 pieces of chocolate this year and he&apos;s outgrown that place he&apos;s in now.&quot;  

 Christopher Elbow chocolates are available on his web site, and they&apos;re all available at Hall&apos;s department store in Kansas City, as well as a growing list of high-end confectionery stores across the nation. They may be expensive, but they&apos;re worth it.   
 
 November 27, 2006 in Guilty Pleasures , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Kauffman Stadium - Kansas City, MO 
 
 Baseball season usually ends for me once the regular season is over. It&apos;s maddening for me to watch the baseball play-offs on television, mainly because the commentators dumb down their analysis for the casual baseball fan who tunes in only during the play-offs.  

 With that said, I still love baseball and still love going to games. With freezing temperatures settling in and effectively ending the summertime warmth, I want to remember the trip we took to Kansas City and our visit to Kauffman Stadium , home of the Kansas City Royals . 

 I&apos;ve been to Kauffman Stadium (named after the Royals long time owner Ewing Kauffman ) many times in the past. Built before the 1973 season, the stadium seats a shade over 40,000 people. It&apos;s situated next door to A rrowhead Stadium , the home of the Kansas City Chiefs , and is part of the Truman Sports Complex on the east side of Kansas City ( see map ).  

 It was a warm August evening when Cindy and I went to the see the Royals host the Boston Red Sox . I mean, it was oppressively hot - game time temps were 101 degrees and there wasn&apos;t much of a breeze. 

 Here&apos;s a picture of the opening pitch of the game. Our seats weren&apos;t too bad - they were up a ways behind the first base dugout. There were a lot of Boston fans in the crowd, including about 8 in a row in front of us. I didn&apos;t mind, I wasn&apos;t pulling for one team or the other. I&apos;m there for baseball.  

 Kauffman Stadium is famous for their fountains (keeping in step with the rest of Kansas City) in the outfield. The fountains sort of bubble during the game, then they cut&apos;em loose between innings. 

 Hang on - got to satisfy my scoreboard fetish while we&apos;re at it. Actually, the scoreboard at Kauffman is the tallest in major league baseball. It towers 12 stories high and even though it isn&apos;t as large as others I&apos;ve seen, it&apos;s still pretty impressive. 

 For my friend, Greg Hipskind , here&apos;s a shot of his favorite Red Sox player, Manny Ramirez . 

 The concourses at Kauffman Stadium are somewhat of a problem. Typical of stadiums built in the 1960&apos;s and 1970&apos;s, the concourses are narrow and get crowded in a hurry.  With concession stands and beer stands set up along the way, the congestion can get pretty bad. I understand that they&apos;re looking to do an upgrade to the stadium in the next couple of years that should take care of the narrow walk ways. 

 With the Red Sox in town and less than two years removed from their World Series crown , there was a pretty large crowd at Kauffman that evening. Actually, the sight lines at Kauffman are pretty good so there really isn&apos;t a bad seat in the house.  

 Here&apos;s a great picture of the rising full moon behind the American flag. 

 All in all, Kauffman Stadium is a nice place to see a ball game.  There&apos;s plenty of parking, it&apos;s pretty easy to get in and get out of the parking lot, the stadium has all the amenities for the regular fan. If the Royals would just get a team to put on the field that would be competitive, it would be even more fun to watch a game there.  
 
 October 18, 2006 in Destinations , Events , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (1) 

 | | | 
 
 O&apos;Dowd&apos;s Little Dublin - Kansas City 
 
 During our recent trip to Kansas City, the weather was almost unbearably hot. Walking around the Plaza area one very hot afternoon, we came across a little Irish pub called O&apos;Dowd&apos;s Little Dublin . Cindy suggested that we go in and get a beer. Well, anytime that she suggests to go get a beer, I can&apos;t say no.  

 O&apos;Dowd&apos;s is at the corner of Pennsylvania and Nichols Road in the Plaza ( see map ). Even though the exterior remains true to the Spanish architecture found in the Plaza area, the dark walnut panels on the outside of O&apos;Dowd&apos;s immediately gives it a warm, inviting appeal. 

 O&apos;Dowd&apos;s has been in business since 1996. The interior woodwork, cabinets and many of the signs on their walls came from Ireland. It really has an&quot;old country&quot;feel to the place. 

 Cindy and I both grabbed a beer and headed for one of the window seats looking out into the Plaza. O&apos;Dowd&apos;s has a rooftop beer garden that is one of the more popular places to be most of the time. But with temperatures hovering around 100 degrees, there was no way we were going to go upstairs and outside the air conditioning to have a beer that would turn warm inside 3 minutes.  

 We checked out their menu (it was around 4:30 and we weren&apos;t going to eat there) and it&apos;s typical Irish bar food. But it looked damn good. They have a long list of appetizers and sandwiches, and they also have a number of good Irish entrees including Shepherd&apos;s Pie , Irish Stew and corned beef and cabbage.  

 Their beer selection was wide and varied, but typical of most Irish bars in America. But they did have a large number of Irish Whiskey and Scotch Whisky to choose from. I thought it would be a great place to come back to for a nightcap.  

 Our visit was a little tense, however, as a couple seated near us was having a family argument, and it ended with the guy storming out of the bar. As we watched him stomp across the street, the guy had his cell phone to his ear. I remarked to Cindy,&quot;I think he&apos;s getting a hold of his divorce lawyer.&quot; We felt bad for the lady. She just sat there looking out of the window with tears in her eyes. I almost thought about buying her a drink. But, it was probably best to not get involved. 

 All in all - other than the marital blow-up we witnessed - O&apos;Dowd&apos;s is a neat little place to get a beer and a nice meal. They&apos;ve opened a second location in far north Kansas City at the new Zona Rosa mall, but I&apos;m sure it doesn&apos;t have the warm, comfortable feeling as the original O&apos;Dowd&apos;s in the Plaza.       
 
 September 19, 2006 in Beer Bars , Irish Pub , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Fiorella&apos;s Jack Stack Barbecue - Martin City, MO 
 
 During our trip to Kansas City, I promised to take Cindy to at least three great places to eat. Our first night in Kansas City, the choice of the restaurant was a no-brainer. We drove out to Martin City on the far south side of Kansas City and went to Fiorella&apos;s Jack Stack Barbecue .  

 Now, I&apos;ve talked about the Jack Stack barbecue places before (see my earlier blog post here ), but I just had to tell you all about this one particular meal.  

 We ate there on a hot Monday night, not unlike the first time I ate there 20 years ago this summer when it was called the Smoke Stack before Jack Fiorella renamed it the Jack Stack. We got right in and sat at a booth in the dining room that allowed Cindy to look into the prep area for the kitchen.  

 Jack Stack has an extensive menu and Cindy took her time going through it. That was fine with me, but I knew what I wanted.  

 Cindy and I both got the two meat combos. I got the spare ribs and brisket, Cindy went with the spare ribs and the burnt ends. Burnt ends are the end of the beef brisket cut off into chunks. I don&apos;t care for them myself, but Cindy wanted to give them a try. 

 We also went with a side of their baked beans, a small order of their huge and delicious onion rings, and Cindy got some cole slaw to go with her meal. 

 Like I said, for some particular reason this was the best meal I&apos;d ever had at Jack Stack. The ribs were outstanding - tender and juicy. The brisket was wonderful. Cindy didn&apos;t care for her burnt ends. (I didn&apos;t figure she would, but she had to try&apos;em. Some people go nuts over the burnt ends. I don&apos;t see - or taste - what&apos;s so good about&apos;em.) But she did love the ribs. She stopped at one point when she was knawing on a rib and said,&quot;These are the best ribs I&apos;ve ever had in my life!&quot; 

 About the only thing disappointing with Jack Stack are their sauces. Not that they&apos;re bad - far from it. They just don&apos;t have a lot of&quot;pizzaz&quot;. They only have two different sauces - regular and spicy. The regular is vinegar based and not too sweet (which actually helps bring out the flavor of the meat it&apos;s used on), while the hot isn&apos;t all that hot. I like to add both the regular and hot together and put them in with their baked beans. It makes the beans even better than they are.  

 We got to talking with our waitress and Fiorella&apos;s Jack Stack now offers mail order ribs - ribs and meats that are cooked, then frozen and vacuum packed, and then shipped anywhere in the US. She said that the ribs she&apos;s tried that were mail order actually seemed to be more juicy and tender than the ribs they had at the restaurant.  

 She told us that Fiorella&apos;s had a facility in Kansas City for cooking and processing mail orders, but they quickly outgrew that. They now have a second facility in Denison, IA - of all places - that makes the food and ships it around the country.  

 As it always seems, I could hardly move when I got up to leave, I was so stuffed. The food has always been outstanding at Jack Stack - in my opinion the best barbecue in Kansas City. But for some reason, it was just exceptional this one particular evening. It was probably the best meal I&apos;d ever had there and probably the best barbecue meal I&apos;d ever had in my life.  

 
 
 September 01, 2006 in Barbecue , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (1) 

 | | | 
 
 Mi Cocina - Kansas City, MO 
 
 During our recent trip to Kansas City we came across Mi Cocina , a somewhat upscale, trendy and cosmopolitan Tex-Mexican food restaurant in the Country Club Plaza ( see map ).  

 Mi Cocina is part of the M-Crowd group of restaurants based out of Fort Worth, Texas. The first Mi Cocina was opened in 1991 in Fort Worth by Michael Rodriquez and his wife Carolina. There are now 15 Mi Cocina locations - 14 of them in the Dallas-Fort Worth Metroplex.  

 We stopped in for lunch and it wasn&apos;t too busy as it was after 1 p.m. when we got in there. We took a spacious booth by the window and ordered up a couple of their margaritas. 

 The decor in Mi Cocina is sort of an art-decoish interior, complete with a nice bar area. Actually, it looked more like a martini bar than a Tex-Mex restaurant. 

 There were many things that looked interesting on the menu . A guy next to us got the fajitas, which looked good. They also had a thing called a&quot;Lucy Changa&quot;- a chimichanga with either fajita beef or chicken - that looked pretty good. I almost got that.  

 I went with the Mama Tacos, grilled beef in a crisp corn shell. Cindy went with the beef burrito lunch special. Both were served rather quickly and we dug in. 

 The food was good. I think it was a little over-priced for what we got, but it was good, nonetheless. We had three margaritas between us and a beer and the bill came to $56 bucks including tip. But what the hell - we&apos;re on vacation!  

 If you&apos;re in the Plaza area and looking for good Tex-Mex food, Mi Cocina is worth a stop. However, there are better and a lot cheaper Mexican restaurants in the Kansas City area.   

 ( Update - Mi Cocina lost its lease in 2008 and closed the Plaza location. There are still a number of Mi Cocina locations in Texas and Oklahoma.)  
 
 August 31, 2006 in Kansas City , Mexican , Rest In Peace , Restaurants | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 CC&apos;s City Broiler - Overland Park, KS 
 
 On our recent trip to Kansas City, I promised Cindy that I&apos;d take her to one of the best steakhouses in the area. I was thinking of taking her to the Hereford House (one of my favorite steak houses that still I need to talk about on this blog). But an old rep friend of mine, John Blando, told me not long ago that, hands down, the best steak house now in Kansas City was CC&apos;s City Broiler in Overland Park, KS ( see map ).  

 CC&apos;s City Broiler in Kansas City is the second of two CC&apos;s City Broilers owned by Scott Cleeton. The first location opened in Columbia, MO in the mid-90&apos;s ( see map ), and the Kansas City location was opened in 2003. CC&apos;s City Broiler is named after Cleeton&apos;s younger brother, Casey, who died in a car accident at the age of 19.  

 Cleeton came from a restaurant family. His father owned a butcher shop and the CC Sawyer&apos;s steak house in Moberly, MO and Scott Cleeton learned how to cut his own meat and how to run a restaurant from his father. He was in his late 20&apos;s when he opened CC&apos;s City Broiler in Columbia in the old bus station on a shoestring budget. I was told that Cleeton, now 38, will make the 6 hour round trip between Columbia and Overland Park four or five times a week.  

 The Overland Park location is located in a small mall area near the 151st and Antioch intersection in a fast growing neighborhood. The decor is heavy on the wood paneling, with linen table cloth on each table. The waiters are wearing tuxedos without the jackets and even though it&apos;s decidedly upscale in appearance, we were more than comfortable sitting in the place in shorts and a nice shirt.  

 Our waiter was very accommodating and offered some good recommendations for steaks and side dishes. CC&apos;s is known for their filet mignon cuts and Cindy and I each went with that - Cindy took the 8 oz. petite cut for $22.95 and I went with the 12 ouncer for $29.95.  

 I almost went with two other steaks - the Steak Fromage, a strip steak topped with Maytag Blue Cheese ; and the Steak Au Poivre, a peppered strip steak with a savory cream sauce. But I thought I&apos;d try one of those next time I came (I knew there&apos;d be a next time).  

 CC&apos;s cooks their steaks at 1800 degrees (F) and uses a special blend of spices on their steaks when they cook them. I asked them to pepper my steak with a conconction of black pepper and red pepper flakes they offered.   

 Cindy got a side of hollandaise sauce for her steak, along with a twice baked, jalapeno potato - jalapeno chunks whipped in with the potato topping. I had a side of the sauteed mushrooms.  

 The salads were nothing fancy and the wine list was nice. I asked if he had a reserve wine list and he said,&quot;Why, yes sir, we do!&quot; He brought out a reserve list that seemed to be even bigger than the regular wine list. I ordered a bottle of the Duckhorn Merlot 2003 that ran about $85 bucks, a pretty good price for in a restaurant. Actually, they had a bottle of the Jordan Cabernet 2001 that they had for $105, which is very reasonably priced for a Jordan 2001. But the Duckhorn wine was highly recommended by a co-worker of Cindy&apos;s and I thought we&apos;d give it a go. We weren&apos;t disappointed by any means. 

 Our steaks and sides were served by our waiter and we dug in. The spices and pepper flavoring on my steak, especially when it was cooked at such a high temperature, gave it a distinctive burnt taste that I didn&apos;t find appealing. OK, so I screwed up on getting it peppered. Next time, don&apos;t do that. But cutting past the outer layer of the steak, the inside was moist, tender and flavorful. Cindy&apos;s steak - she offered me a bite with the hollandaise sauce - was wonderful.  

 Everything was wonderful with CC&apos;s City Broiler - the food, the wine, the service. We spent about $225 with a nice tip for our waiter. I really don&apos;t know if it&apos;s the best steak house in Kansas City, but I will say that it definitely gives the Hereford House a run for their money. It was a very fine meal.  

 (Update - Scott Cleeton decided that it was too much to be driving back and forth three hours one way four or five times a week and he closed the Overland Park location in 2007. His Columbia, MO restaurant is still open.) 
 
 August 24, 2006 in Kansas City , Rest In Peace , Steak Houses | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 The Country Club Plaza - Kansas City 
 
 I&apos;ve been going to Kansas City for a number of years. I had a girlfriend who lived down there in the late 70&apos;s who I would visit regularly, then I worked for a company based in the Kansas suburbs from 1986 thru 1991. So I&apos;ve been to Kansas City countless times, but I never really knew much about the core attraction of the city - the Country Club Plaza area, or simply known as the&quot;Plaza&quot;by the locals.   

 Built in the early 1920&apos;s, the Plaza area was designed with Spanish architecture and European art in mind by J.C. Nichols . It was the first&quot;suburban&quot;shopping district in the United States. To learn more about J.C. Nichols and his visionary plans for Country Club Plaza click here . 

 The Plaza area is heavily influenced by the architecture found in Seville, Spain with a number of fountains (Kansas City, in general, has a large number of fountains), murals, statues and tile mosaics. It houses a number of upscale stores and restaurants, and a number of hotels surround the area.  

 Actually, other than the architecture, the fountains and some of the restaurants, the Plaza is not much different than what you&apos;d find at any typical upscale shopping mall across America. Cindy thought the area was neat, but wasn&apos;t impressed with the variety of stores. 

 We were shopping at Halls Plaza , an upscale department store owned by the Hallmark Company , one afternoon and we got to talking to a sales lady about the stores that populate the Plaza area. She told us that of the nearly 90 stores that populate the Plaza area, only three are locally owned - Halls Plaza included. &quot;The developers have charged high rents and have taken the life out of the Plaza,&quot;she said about the national chain stores that have taken over from local merchants over the past few years. 

 (As an aside, it turned out the lady we were talking to at Halls Plaza was named Bette Physioc. I was impressed that she pronounced my last name right when she handed back my credit card after a purchase. She said,&quot;Oh, my last name is Physioc. That gets butchered all the time.&quot; I proceeded to spell it correctly and asked if she was any relation to former ESPN sports anchor and current Los Angeles Angels broadcaster Steve Physioc . It was her son. She was impressed that A) I spelled the name right; and B) that I knew of her son. She was a very nice woman.)  

 On Thanksgiving evening, upwards of a quarter million of people crowd the Plaza area to watch the annual lighting of the Plaza Lights, a tradition since 1925 where each building in the area is outlined with colorful lights for the Christmas season. I have seen the lights during the Christmas season and it does look rather impressive. 

 I&apos;m up for checking an area out and giving it a chance, but I have to say that I, too, was somewhat disappointed with The Plaza area for shopping. Still, we found a lot of things that we couldn&apos;t live without and many things that we could live without (as in&quot;very pricey&quot;). But I could have found the same things in virtually any other medium to large city in the Midwest. 

 The bottom line - it&apos;s a mall with nice architecture.  
 
 August 22, 2006 in Destinations , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Garozzo&apos;s - Kansas City, MO 
 
 S urprisingly, there are a lot of very good Italian restaurants in the greater Kansas City area. One of the better ones - if not the best one - is Garozzo&apos;s . 

 Michael Garozzo (note the emphasis on the long&quot;o&quot;in the logo) was born in St. Louis and lived on the famous Hill there. His father and uncle were long time waiters at many of the great restaurants in that neighborhood. He had a lifelong dream of owning a restaurant, and in 1989 he opened his first restaurant in Kansas City on Harrison St. north of the downtown area ( see map ).  

 He opened his second restaurant a couple years later out in Independence and eventually sold it to his cousin, Sam, who renamed the location Salvatore&apos;s. It&apos;s still in existence today ( see map ).  

 (As an aside - The head chef at Salvatore&apos;s, a Vietnamese immigrant, worked his way up through Garozzo&apos;s kitchen starting out as the salad chef, eventually taking over as head chef at Salvatore&apos;s when Michael Garozzo sold it to his cousin. I&apos;ve heard that many of the menu items that you find at Garozzo&apos;s you can get at Salvatore&apos;s.) 

 In the meantime, Michael Garozzo opened up three other restaurants - one in Overland Park, KS , one in Lee&apos;s Summit, MO , and one in Wichita . The waitress the night we were there told us that he is looking at expanding into other towns, as well. 

 The last time I ate at Garozzo&apos;s was at the Overland Park location about three years ago. The food was outstanding that night and I&apos;ve been wanting to go back. On our trip to Kansas City as part of our vacation, we went to Garozzo&apos;s for a late dinner one evening. Even though we got there around 9:30, the staff was more than accommodating as we apologized throughout the night for getting there so late. 

 The table we sat at was the same table I sat at the first time I ate there in 1990. Unfortunately, it was situated close to a birthday party where a number of younger children - who probably should have been in bed - were fueled by inordinate amounts of sugar and were pretty loud. But we got through it. We found out later that if you go to Garozzo&apos;s for your birthday, you get a free plate of their signature Chicken Spiedini. 

 Garozzo&apos;s is famous for their Chicken Spiedini - chicken breast chunks marinated and breaded, then grilled and served with a house sauce called Amogio. They have variations of the Chicken Spiedini and Cindy went with the Chicken Spiedini Samantha - Chicken Spiedini with an alfredo sauce served over a bed of fettuccine noodles and topped with artichoke hearts.  

 I went with the Tortellini Gina - huge homemade tortellini shells filled with chicken, cheese and prosciutto ham served with a white cream sauce. We each got salads - they were served in big bowls, but the dressing was a little bland for us. And we each got a glass of an Italian Pinot Grigio that I wasn&apos;t familiar with, but it went well with the meal.  

 In short, our meals were outstanding. Cindy thought the Chicken Spiedini over the fettuccine was one of the best meals she&apos;s ever had, and she wasn&apos;t too certain that the chicken was the best she&apos;d ever tasted. My tortellini was equally as good - huge tortellini shells stuffed with a wonderful blend of three different taste sensations.  

 Everything, with the exceptions of their desserts, is made from scratch at Garozzo&apos;s. We did try a piece of their tiramisu and it was average, at best. The waitress explained that a local baker used to do all their desserts, but she retired a few years ago. I think they need to find a new baker.  

 The original Garozzo&apos;s is sort of tough to find - the other locations in the suburbs and in Wichita are on well-traveled streets and easy to get to. But it&apos;s worth the drive to go to the original Garozzo&apos;s for a great Italian meal.  

 
 
 August 18, 2006 in Italian , Kansas City , Restaurants | Permalink | Comments (3) 

 | | | 
 
 Bo Lings - Overland Park, KS 
 
 I don&apos;t eat a lot of Chinese food when I&apos;m on the road. I don&apos;t know why, other than I don&apos;t care for the large amount of monosodium glutamate a lot of Chinese restaurants put in the food as a taste enhancer/preservative. Still, there are a number of good Chinese places that don&apos;t use MSG, but finding them are tough. 

 One of the better places for Chinese food in the Midwest are the Bo Lings restaurants in the Kansas City area. When Cindy and I were down in K.C. for a few days as part of our vacation she wanted Chinese for lunch. I hadn&apos;t been to Bo Lings for a long time (the first time was back in the 80&apos;s).  

 Richard and Therese Ng (pronounced ENG with a long&quot;e&quot;) started the first Bo Lings on Metcalf Ave. in Overland Park in 1981 ( see map ). They now have six locations in the Kansas City area. Each location has a similar menu , with some locations offering more in the way of lunch and dinner entrees.  

 We went to the Bo Lings at 135th and Metcalf in south Overland Park for lunch on a very hot August day. Even though I&apos;ve had their Sichuan Peppercorn beef in the past, I thought it may be too spicy for a hot afternoon. I went with the good ol&apos;beef and broccoli instead. Cindy went with one of the lunch specials, shrimp and scallops with veggies in a sweet and sour sauce.  

 As I said, it had been a number of years since I&apos;d eaten at Bo Lings, but the food was just as good as I remember it. It is the closest thing to&quot;comfort food&quot;one can have without it being comfort food. My lunch was wonderful, so was Cindy&apos;s. A lot of times Chinese restaurants overcook the broccoli, but mine was still crisp, yet tender to the bite. 

 It&apos;s no wonder Bo Lings continues to garner the&quot;Best Chinese Restaurant&quot;award in Kansas City Magazine year after year. The food is great, the service is great, and the restaurants are nice and comfortable. I highly recommend Bo Lings for Chinese in Kansas City. 

 
 
 August 17, 2006 in Chinese , Kansas City , Restaurants | Permalink | Comments (1) 

 | | | 
 
 Hen House Markets - Kansas City 
 
 The Kansas City area boasts 13 eclectic grocery stores called Hen House Markets . They are, simply, some of the finest grocery stores I&apos;ve ever been in.   

 Hen House Markets were first known as Ball&apos;s when the first one opened in the 1920&apos;s by Sidney and Mollie Ball in Kansas City, KS. Ball&apos;s Food Stores, Inc. have grown today to include 15 Ball&apos;s Price Chopper warehouse-style grocery stores throughout Kansas City, and 11 Hen Houses on the Kansas side of Kansas City, with two more on the Missouri side. 

 You&apos;ll find the Hen House Markets in the more upscale shopping areas in suburbs around Kansas City. They have a great meat department, great produce and a wonderful deli. The shopping experience at a Hen House is one of a comfortable nature, mixed in with very pleasant surroundings. 

 But don&apos;t let the eclectic nature of the stores fool you - their everyday grocery items are competitive with the larger chains in the area. They also offer on line specials that change weekly so you don&apos;t have to wait until the Wednesday ads come out in the local paper to see what Hen House has on sale. 

 Recently, Ball&apos;s Price Chopper stores have been feeling pressure from the two big competitors in the area - Hy-Vee and WalMart. But the Hen House Markets all seem to be growing and getting stronger.   

 Hen House Markets have specialty areas for pet food (with food and treats from the famous Three Dog Bakery in Kansas City), organic foods and a nice floral department.   

 I wish we had something like a Hen House around the Quad Cities. It&apos;s a pretty nifty place to shop. 

    
 
 March 16, 2006 in Grocery Stores and Markets , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (2) 

 | | | 
 
 Hampton Inn and Suites - Merriam, KS 
 
 I first stayed at the Hampton Inn and Suites in Merriam, KS about a year and a half ago. Actually, I had been staying at the Hampton Inn or the Hilton Garden Inn in Overland Park until I found out this one was much closer to my dealer. 

 I remember walking in and seeing at how nice the lobby was, thinking this place was brand new. I asked the desk clerk how long they&apos;d been open. She said,&quot;Oh, we&apos;ve been open since 2000.&quot; Nice joint! 

 I&apos;ve stayed there three or four times. The rooms are very nice, the staff is always attentive. They&apos;ve upgraded me to suites a couple of times, which are two rooms - a living room area with a little kitchenette with a bedroom attached. They&apos;ve got a nice breakfast spread in the morning - it&apos;s a great place. 

 But I&apos;ll never stay there again. 

 When I went to check in, they didn&apos;t have my reservation. The desk clerk was very helpful, however, and called over to the one in Overland Park to see if I had a reservation over there.  

 (As much as I travel, I make reservations days in advance and sometimes I forget where I&apos;m staying. I usually print out the reservation confirmations to take with me, usually to help remind me where I&apos;m staying and on what night. For some reason, I didn&apos;t print them out for this particular trip.) 

 It turned out that, yes, I was supposed to be over in Overland Park. I was tired, I&apos;d driven a lot that day, I needed to check e-mail and do some work, then go get something to eat. I didn&apos;t feel like driving over toward Overland Park and going through the process again. I asked if she had rooms - she did - and I asked if she could cancel my reservation over at Overland Park. She did.  

 I sort of wondered why I didn&apos;t make my reservations at this one in Merriam because I knew it was much nicer than the one in Overland Park. (I always try to get into the Hilton Garden Inn in Overland Park first, but because the Overland Park Convention Center is next door, it is usually sold out well in advance.) 

 Let me back up a bit - to get to the Hampton Inn and Suites in Merriam, you get off I-35 at 75th St., then you go west down a hill to the first stop light. Take a right, then take another immediate right, go across some train tracks, then up an hill, around and down a frontage road. It&apos;s kind of a pain in the ass to get to, and if it&apos;s dark and you&apos;ve never been there before, there&apos;s a good chance you&apos;d get lost. Thankfully, the first time I went there, it was daylight and I&apos;m usually pretty good with directions once I&apos;ve been to a place.  

 They put me in the back of the hotel, on the second floor. Nice room. Little fridge in the room, comfy king size bed, it&apos;s a great room. So why won&apos;t I stay there again? 

 Remember what I said about going across some train tracks to get to the hotel?  

 About midnight, I&apos;m trying to fall asleep (I don&apos;t sleep well when I&apos;m away from Cindy) and all of the sudden I hear this train coming down the tracks. Being that I&apos;m in the back of the hotel and closest to the tracks, it sounds like the friggin&apos; train is coming into my room. Then the bastard hits the horn - holy shit!!!  

 I suddenly remembered why I didn&apos;t want to make reservations at this Hampton Inn.  

 Well, it didn&apos;t happen just one time - it happened at least FIVE times in the middle of the night. It turns out those are the Union Pacific tracks to Wichita and points south and west.  

 One time, I think it was around 2:30 in the morning, another one came by and he just laid on the horn like he was saying,&quot;Hey, folks! It&apos;s 2:30 in the morning. If I have to work and not be in bed like you people, I&apos;m going to make you all suffer.&quot; And the horn blast lasted about that long. I&apos;m serious.  

 Now, we have friends - Mike and Gwen Schroeder - who live, literally, 30 yards from train tracks where trains go by their place in the middle of the night at 45 to 60 miles an hour. We&apos;ve stayed there a couple times and the trains have scared the living shit out of us. But Mike and Gwen have lived there long enough that Mike says,&quot;Awww, we don&apos;t even hear &apos;em any more when we&apos;re sleeping.&quot;  

 As many airlines, hotels and car rental companies say,&quot;You have choices.&quot; I choose not to stay here again. Nothing against the staff, the facility or Hampton Inn&apos;s, but with trains going by and slamming on the horn all through the night - and I&apos;m not used to that sound in the middle of the night. I&apos;d rather stay in a more tired hotel than have to be subjected to that.  
 
 March 11, 2006 in Hotels , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 The Longbranch Steakhouse - Overland Park/Lenexa, KS 
 
 Since 1986, the Longbranch Steakhouse has been serving some good steaks at some good prices. One of the original owners was former major league baseball player and manager Lou Pinella. The Longbranch has since gone through a couple of ownership changes and the two Longbranch&apos;s located in suburban Kansas City ( Lenexa map - Overland Park map ) are now owned by Dan Greet.  

 &quot;Sweet&quot;Lou Pinella (left) 

 From the first time I went into a Longbranch, I always had kind of an affinity to the place. The decor is sort of rustic, yet, sort of&quot;frathouse-ish&quot;. There are self-deprecating and rude-to-customers signage and shirts. It&apos;s not quite a steak house, but not quite a beer bar. And it could be categorized as a sports bar, but they prefer to be called a steak house. 

 I will tell you, the burgers at Longbranch are very good - 1/2 pound of fresh ground beef on a toasted bun. I like their Swiss-mushroom burgers the best. Good, lean, yet juicy.  

 And their chili is very good, too. It&apos;s sweet and thick with a little hint of spiciness. I always like to get it topped with onions, jalapenos and cheddar cheese.  

 I had a dinner meeting scheduled one evening in Kansas City, but late in the afternoon the guy who I was supposed to go out to dinner with begged off - he had the flu. I know that he had to have the flu - the steakhouse we were going to is one of his favorites. And since I was paying, I knew that he had to be really sick to not garner a freebie meal from me.  

 I was in the mood for steak all day, but I didn&apos;t want to go to that steakhouse by myself. So, I decided to head over to the Longbranch in Lenexa. Getting there was a major chore as they were working on the 87th St. overpass over I-35 and there were lane closures, detours and one lane roads. I found my way there, but I thought I needed to get a prize for making it.  

 Monday thru Thursday, the Longbranch has steak specials. Stupidly, ridiculously, insanely low-priced steak specials. I took the crew from Accent Sound to the one in Overland Park there one night and they had 16 oz KC Strips with steak fries for $8.99 that night. There was nothing wrong with the steaks, either. No major pieces of gristle, they were cut very lean and cooked perfectly.  

 Tonight, they had an 8 oz. Flatiron steak (to learn more about Flatiron cuts, click here ) and steak fries for $6.99. Wow... OK, sign me up. 

 One thing that I&apos;ve begun to notice at restaurants lately - especially when you&apos;re sitting at the bar alone having diner. The last few places I&apos;ve been to, the bartender will take my drink order and then ask for my name. They introduce themselves with their name, write my name down on my ticket and then they treat me like we&apos;re lifelong friends the rest of the night. I&apos;ll tell you, it adds a couple bucks to their tip when they do it to me.  

 Tonight, the bartender, Mandy, did the same thing. She was very attentive and quick on the spot. I asked her if I could get a cup of chili before the steak and an ice cold Boulevard Irish Ale. She was more than happy to oblige.  

 I hadn&apos;t had the chili for quite sometime, but it was exactly as I remember. Good and thick, sweet and tangy. Add a little Tabasco sauce and it was a spot-hitter.  

 The Flatiron steak was a tad overcooked for a medium-rare, but for $6.99 it was still very good. I only had about four or five of the thick cut steak fries (I really don&apos;t eat french fries that much any longer), but they were good, too.  

 There are definitely better steakhouses in Kansas City, but there may not be any that are more fun than The Longbranch. And it&apos;s tough to beat the weeknight specials. My dinner with the chili, two 22 oz beers and the steak with fries came to just over $22 bucks. With a five dollar tip for Mandy, I was out of there for under $30 bucks.  

 The Longbranch is a good value for a steakhouse, if anything. Give it a shot if you get to K.C.     

 
 
 March 10, 2006 in Kansas City , Steak Houses | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Ted&apos;s Montana Grill 
 
 Ted&apos;s Montana Grill began in 2002 as a joint venture between media mogul Ted Turner and longtime restauranteur George McKerrow (of Longhorn Steakhouse fame).  

 Turner is one of the largest landowners in the nation, owning over 1.5 million acres in 14 states. And he&apos;s also the largest bison rancher in the country. And with that, Ted&apos;s Montana Grill serves bison on their menu, along with beef, chicken and seafood entrees.   

 The first Ted&apos;s Montana Grill opened in Columbus, OH and there are currently nearly 40 restaurants in 17 states. I&apos;ve eaten at three of the Ted&apos;s locations - Omaha , Wichita , and in suburban Chicago . Each one is very, very good. 

 I was told a couple years ago that Ted Turner&apos;s goal was to have 225 restaurants within five years. They aren&apos;t growing quite that fast. I hope they don&apos;t grow that quickly as it will be difficult to keep tabs on quality control. 

 I&apos;ve had bison steak before and I can say that I wasn&apos;t that big of a fan of it. One of the biggest problems with cooking bison meat is that it is so lean a lot of the natural juices cook out of it making the meat tough and flavorless. Ted&apos;s came up with a unique way to keep the juices from escaping during the cooking process.  They cook their bison meat on a flat grill at a high temperature and they put a lid over the top of the meat while it&apos;s cooking to keep the bison steak from drying out. 

 All the Ted&apos;s Montana Grill restaurants hand cut their own beef and bison in house. They offer steak cuts and burgers in both bison and beef. One person can have the KC Strip in beef, while the other can have it in bison.  

 I was kind of skeptical of getting a bison steak at the first Ted&apos;s I ate at in Wichita about two years ago, but the waitress virtually guaranteed that I didn&apos;t have to pay for it if I didn&apos;t like it. So I got the bison filet.  

 She didn&apos;t have to pick up the check that night. The bison filet was juicy and tasty, very much unlike the bison steaks I&apos;ve had in the past. And it&apos;s been that way at the other Ted&apos;s I&apos;ve been to, as well.   

 They also have pot roast and made-from-scratch meatloaf on the menu, although I&apos;ve yet to try either one. Maybe one night when I&apos;m in severe need for comfort food when I&apos;m near a Ted&apos;s I&apos;ll have to give them a try. 

 Ted&apos;s Montana Grill&apos;s decor is designed to make you feel like you&apos;re eating in a western lodge. It&apos;s heavy on the woodwork throughout the restaurant. The place can get a little loud so sitting in a booth is good if you&apos;re there for business or for conversation.  

 There&apos;s a big bar in each Ted&apos;s that handles the overflow and people waiting for tables. One of the best things about Ted&apos;s - all their restaurants are smoke-free.  

 I&apos;ve been told that Ted Turner personally inspects each restaurant and makes it to the individual grand openings across the country. He&apos;s been known to show up unannounced for dinner at various Ted&apos;s, as well. I suppose if the restaurant has your name on it, it&apos;s good to be checking up on them from time to time.  

 Ted&apos;s is a unique place that keeps me coming back. Besides, bison meat is good for you and Ted&apos;s makes the best. It&apos;s definitely worth the visit if you get around one.  
 
 March 01, 2006 in Chicago Suburbs , Kansas City , Steak Houses , Wichita, KS | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | | 
 
 Boulevard Brewery 
 
 One of the better beers brewed in the Midwest is Boulevard Brewing Company out of Kansas City. Started in 1988 by John McDonald, Boulevard delivered their first beer in the fall of 1989 and has been going strong ever since. 

 Boulevard beer is only available in the Midwest and wants to keep it that way. They&apos;re able to have a better handle on production and distribution that way.  

 Boulevard is also a little more expensive than other micro or regional brewed beers. This is due to using more expensive crops for their beer such as two-row malted barley, high grade rice and corn. Their hops are introduced directly from the vine into the brewing process. Finally, Boulevard beers go through a full brewing and fermentation period that allows them to be naturally carbonated. The result is some of the finest tasting beer any where. 

 One of my all-time favorite beers is the Boulevard Pale Ale. Their pale ale is a robust and tasty beer that has a sharp, yet smooth aftertaste. I rate the Boulevard Pale Ale as my most favorite of all the pale ales I&apos;ve tried over the years. 

 Another Boulevard beer that I just discovered last spring is Boulevard&apos;s Irish Ale. A full bodied reddish-brown beer with kind of a smoked or toasted taste to it, Irish Ale is only brewed from January to April in conjunction with St. Patrick&apos;s Day. I discovered it one evening in early May last year when I was out with the guys from Stereo One in Springfield, MO. In fact, we drank the place we were at out of the beer that night, it was so good. I can&apos;t wait to find some on the shelves now that it should be available again.  

 Boulevard got their start making a wheat beer, but I don&apos;t like wheat beers so I can&apos;t say if theirs is good or not. They also make a Bully Porter that&apos;s OK, but a little too heavy for my taste. Same with their stout.  

 I have a friend whose brother works for a local distributor for Boulevard in Kansas City. He keeps telling me to go to the brewery on Southwest Blvd. in Kansas City and check out the tasting room and the gift shop.  On one of my future trips to KC, I&apos;m just gonna have to take the time to do it. 
 
 January 31, 2006 in Beer , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (2) 

 | | | 
 
 Fiorella&apos;s Jack Stack - Kansas City 
 
 There are a lot of great places to eat barbecue in Kansas City. Some are good, some aren&apos;t. Some are overrated and a couple don&apos;t get the recognition they deserve. However, there&apos;s one barbecue place in Kansas City that stands out among the rest. And that&apos;s any of the three locations of Fiorelli&apos;s Jack Stack Barbecue . 

 The orginal Fiorella&apos;s Jack Stack is located in far south Kansas City in a small town known as Martin City . Martin City has been known for years as being the&quot;mecca&quot;for good restaurants in the Kansas City area. The vastly overrated Jess and Jim&apos;s Steakhouse is located in Martin City, as is the vastly underrated Chiarelli&apos;s Pasta House ( see map ). Chiarelli&apos;s is the first place I ever had fettucine alfredo and I haven&apos;t looked back since.  

 Actually, I started going to Jack Stack when it was called&quot;The Smoke Stack&quot;. I don&apos;t quite know when they changed the name to Jack Stack, but the owner of Fiorelli&apos;s is Jack Fiorelli. Jack Fiorelli&apos;s father had a barbecue place since the 1940&apos;s. In the 60&apos;s, Jack and his wife took over the place. With the glut of good barbecue places in Kansas City, Jack&apos;s wife kept saying that in order to succeed, Fiorelli&apos;s needed to take barbecue to a new level and to set themselves apart from the rest. 

 In the mid-70&apos;s, Jack bought the Hickory Wood Cookery in Martin City - a restaurant that cooked their foods in big brick ovens fired by hickory logs. It was an eclectic restaurant, but it wasn&apos;t too successful. After Jack bought the Hickory Wood Cookery, he changed the name to The Smoke Stack. And instead of just doing ribs and brisket, he began to smoke hams, chicken, turkey, and other types of meat that no one else in the Kansas City area was doing.  

 During a trip to Yugoslavia, Jack and his wife found that some of the seaside villages on the Adriatic Sea had restaurants that actually cooked seafood over hickory. They went back to Kansas City and implemented their style of cooking seafood over hickory at The Smoke Stack. Jack also perfected cooking steaks, pork chops and chicken breasts on his hickory fire grills.  

 It&apos;s tough to go wrong with the baby back ribs at Jack Stack. Their brisket is very good, too. However, if you have the time and the money (about $25 bucks), you have to try their Crown Prime Rib short ribs. Oh, man! That is some of the best eatin&apos; I&apos;ve ever had. They&apos;re smoked long and low and the meat is tender and tasty with a hint of hickory in every bite.  

 Jack Stack is famous for their burnt end pieces of pork and beef that I don&apos;t particularly care for, but they&apos;re very popular - both as a meal and as an appetizer. The burned taste is a little too much for me. But like I say, a lot of people like &apos;em. 

 I always get a small pot of Jack Stack baked beans when I go and I throw some of their&quot;spicy&quot;sauce on top of them. And if I go with a group, we always have to get a rack of their great onion rings. They&apos;re big and thick and have a great taste to &apos;em.  

 As I said, Jack Stack has three locations - the one in Martin City, a bigger place in Overland Park at 95th and Metcalf, and a new one just on the southern fringes of downtown Kansas City, MO. I had lunch at the Overland Park location with a buddy when I was in Kansas City earlier this year and I had the Jack Stack sandwich - two meats of your choice on a French bun. I had pork and beef on mine - one on each side of the sandwich. It was very good.  

 The beer is always cold and plentiful at Jack Stack - and you&apos;ll need it. There&apos;s ample parking and they take all credit cards.  

 Jack Stack is reknown for their barbecue throughout the United States. In fact, Zagat&apos;s Travel Guide has named Jack Stack the best barbecue restaurant in America six years in a row! Now, that&apos;s got to be saying something about the place right there.  

 Either Jack Stack location is good, but I&apos;m partial to the original one in Martin City. Kansas City is a nice town. And if you go there, you&apos;ve got to try Jack Stack at least one time.  
 
 December 19, 2005 in Barbecue , Kansas City | Permalink | Comments (0) 

 | | |
	</body>
</document>
