<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001309" url="http://curiousstudents.wordpress.com/2011/05/09/fast-food-is-bad/" time="2012-07-12-16:48" support="3" score="0.001449109177739832" bingtitle="FAST FOOD IS BAD « Curious Students Investigate" webtitle="FAST FOOD IS BADCurious Students Investigate">
			<query id="000293" bing-rank="238"/>
			<query id="000311" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000748" bing-rank="184"/>
	<description>The greater the number of people at a meal in a fast food restaurant, the larger is the bill. ... Enter your comment here...</description>
	<body>
		Home Curious Students 
 
 Curious Students Investigate 
 Learning and teaching internet journalism Stay updated via RSS 
 
Recent Posts

 JACKIE CHAN 28 MAY-REPUBLIC DAY 28 MAY-REPUBLIC DAY Our National Clothes MY HANDWORK FLOWER FESTIVAL Our Rainy Baku INTERESTING FACTS SECRET OF THE PYRAMIDS FAST FOOD IS BAD 
 
 
FAST FOOD IS BAD
 Posted: May 9, 2011 in Uncategorized 
 0 
 BY LEYLA ABBASOVA 

Disadvantages of Fast Food. The greatest disadvantage of fast food is the adverse effect that it has on one’s health. It is a fact that fast food is more unhealthy than home-cooked meals, as they contain higher amounts of salt, fats and calories. Fast food is an important contributor to obesity in the American population. Obesity in children is on the rise and a direct link is being cited between fast food and obesity in children. Given the sedentary lifestyle that we lead today, the excess fats and calories that we take in with fast food is not used up completely.

 

The result is that these accumulate in our body as fat deposits that cause complications like cardiovascular diseases and other related diseases of the heart. With obesity come other problems like high blood pressure and diseases of the joints. It is like a chain reaction set off by fast food and carried forward by our unhealthy lifestyle. In fact, a recent study has shown that people who live within walking distance of a fast food restaurant are at 13% higher risk of suffering from strokes than those who live a considerable distance away. The greater the number of people at a meal in a fast food restaurant, the larger is the bill. Eating at fast food outlets is economical only for a single person.

 Going out to a fast food eating joint with family once in a while won’t matter much. However, frequent visits to such restaurants with one’s family can become quite an expensive affair, besides being unhealthy.
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 MISFORTUNE OF CENTURY SECRET OF THE PYRAMIDS Blog at WordPress.com . | Theme: Greyzed by The Forge Web Creations . Follow 
 Follow“Curious Students Investigate” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
