<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001983" url="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2096662/Evangeline-Lucca-tasered-stun-gun-McDonalds-drive-cutting-line.html" time="2012-07-12-17:53" support="2" score="0.005520289009068419" bingtitle="Evangeline Lucca tasered by stun gun in McDonald&apos;s drive-thru ..." webtitle="Evangeline Lucca tasered by stun gun in McDonald&apos;s drive-thru after cutting line  | Mail Online">
			<query id="001373" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="001184" bing-rank="100"/>
	<description>Authorities in Hope Mills, North Carolina, say Lucca bypassed the order screen and the line at the fast food restaurant, instead pulling directly up to the pick-up ...</description>
	<body>
		Home News U.S. Sport TV&amp;Showbiz; Femail Health Science Money RightMinds Coffee Break Travel Columnists 
 
 News Home Arts Headlines Pictures Most read News Board 

 My Profile Logout Login 
 Find a Job M&amp;S;Wine Our Papers Feedback Thursday, Jul 12 2012 3PM  17°C 6PM 15°C 5-Day Forecast 
She&apos;s not loving it: Woman tasered in McDonald&apos;s drive-thru after cutting line
 
By Daily Mail Reporter 
 UPDATED: 13:41 GMT, 5 February 2012 
 
 Comments ( 55 ) Share 
 
 
 
 Police used a Stun Gun on a woman who had been blocking a McDonald’s drive-thru for more than 20 minutes. 

 Evangeline Lucca, 37, had cut the line and refused to leave before she was served.
 

 Employees, meanwhile, refused to attend to Lucca because she cut the queue. 
 
Have it your way: Evangeline Lucca, 37, was Tasered by police after she refused to move from a McDonald&apos;s queue
 
 Authorities in Hope Mills, North Carolina, say Lucca bypassed the order screen and the line at the fast food restaurant, instead pulling directly up to the pick-up window Friday afternoon. 

 Sheriff’s Office spokeswoman Debbie Tanna told the Fay Observer:‘They told her she had to go around and wait like everybody else did and place her order that way, they weren’t set up at the that window to taker her order.’ 

   
More...

 Dancing boy, 9, told to &apos;Beat It&apos; for imitating notorious Michael Jackson &apos;crotch grab&apos; move during school fundraiser &apos;The vice president of the U.S. is... Bill Clinton!&apos; Shocking video shows high school students are woefully uninformed 
 

 But Ms Tanna added:‘She wasn’t having any of that.’ 

 The woman still refused to move, and police were called after that. 

 Employees told the paper that Lucca often tried to jump the line, but that they finally got sick of it. 
 
Get it to go: Police used a Stun Gun on Lucca after she made threats to the deputies
 
 When the deputies arrived, they said she was‘defiant’to them and was threatening them. 

 Authorities said Lucca was shocked after she blocked the line for 20 minutes. Deputies then performed a‘drive stun’on her, meaning the device was applied directly to her skin, rather than firing the Taser cartridge. 

 Her three-year-old daughter was with her and was taken into protective custody. 

 Lucca was charged with second-degree trespassing. 
 
MOST READ NEWS

 Previous 1 2 3 4 Next 
 
 Billionaire &apos;lived with Eva&apos;s dead body for four days&apos;:... Palace outrage as Australian magazine publishes intimate... Horrific moment three young tigers attack and eat young cub... &apos;The way you brutally manipulated and exploited them is pure... Doing the logo-motion: From McDonald&apos;s without its big... O2 hit by nationwide network failure: &apos;Millions of users&apos;... &apos;The girl with this phone is dead, was smiling&apos;: The... Is that what you call a greenhouse? Ivy-covered house... The human right to claim benefits: Jobless could sue for... The price of financial folly: As airports and luxury flats... McDonald&apos;s force Olympics bosses to ban all other... Renter&apos;s revenge: Pictures which show the squalid aftermath... 
   
Share this article:
 
 Facebook Twitter Google+ Messenger LinkedIn Digg it Newsvine Fark Nowpublic Reddit 

 
 
 Print article Email article 
 
Comments ( 55 )
 
Here&apos;s what other readers have said. Why not debate this issue live on our message boards. 

The comments below have not been moderated.
 
 Newest Oldest Best rated Worst rated 
   View all 
If I would&apos;ve been the manager of that McD I would&apos;ve done the same thing. Calling the cops&amp;have them escort her away was the right thing to do. The fact the cops had to taze her was because she refused to obey a police officer. If tazing wouldn&apos;t have worked, physically pulling her from the car would follow. Her child should be taken from her and put into a foster home, her mom put her in harms way by refusing to obey the cops. Why reward bad behavior? Don, If I was to walk in your front door&amp;grab the keys to your car&amp;said I&apos;m taking your car because I want it, would you let me? Thats exactly what Lucca tried to do .As a culinary art student you have a lot to learn about the real world. It&apos;s one thing to make me a new steak if I claim it was over cooked. It&apos;s something completely different to serve someone who just barges into your resturant, bypasses the 1 hr wait in the lobby and sits down demanding service right now is wrong. I&apos;d call the cops and have them removed

- Shawn Schafer, Burlington, ND USA, 07/2/2012 03:17
 Click to rate     Rating   38 
 Report abuse 
 
Hey Don, you should change careers..Your comments make you sound just like this loser who thinks she is better than everyone else. You missed the point big time.. She is owed nothing..

- Nirad, Tacoma, USA, 06/2/2012 23:56
 Click to rate     Rating   33 
 Report abuse 
 
Obviously not the happy meal.
- jim martin, goldendale usa, 5/2/2012 11:16&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt;nah, she had the zappy meal (sorry...)

- David, Windsor, 06/2/2012 22:00
 Click to rate     Rating   27 
 Report abuse 
 
Wow, who in there right mind acts the way this lady acted? She got what she deserved. Who the hell does she think she is? I&apos;m suprised some of the people that got cut on didn&apos;t do anything to her. At the very least I would have yelled at that B&amp;^%h. Good job local law enforement. bravo!!! Taser again for all I care.

- Mike, Silver Spring USA, 06/2/2012 21:54
 Click to rate     Rating   35 
 Report abuse 
 
Anyone who excuses this woman&apos;s behavior has no sense of right and wrong. They would sooner defend the feral human population&apos;s rotten behavior than consider the benefits of a civilized society to all. And yes, tasering feral humans who are a threat to life and limb is the civilized thing to do. Please, spare us the feigned civility and sophistication.

- Ken, Virginia, 06/2/2012 16:54
 Click to rate     Rating   87 
 Report abuse 
 
I believe that&quot;queuing&quot;is a British invention from a time that&quot;stealing someone else&apos;s time&quot;was considered very bad form. Hence&quot;queuing&quot;is only considered the norm in the UK, US, Australia Canada etc. Try waiting-in-turn in Europe (or London nowadays for that matter!) and you&apos;ll be waiting a very long time. Shame really because good manors costs nothing.

- fed-up-citizen, uk, 06/2/2012 15:58
 Click to rate     Rating   30 
 Report abuse 
 
People like Don Leblanc are what&apos;s wrong with this country...how can you defend her like that? She was way in the wrong and she got puished, it&apos;s simple. Stop making excuses for people to break rules

- Ben, Abilene, USA, 06/2/2012 15:28
 Click to rate     Rating   78 
 Report abuse 
 
Now, if only the police will start tazing people who bring 30 items to the 10 items or less lane, we can finally start having justice in America.

- Lizard, New Albany, USA, 06/2/2012 14:26
 Click to rate     Rating   85 
 Report abuse 
 
Why not tazer the customers, the burgers taste like they have been tazered anyway!

- Philip Harrison, Former Royal Marine and ex pat Brittany France, 06/2/2012 12:43
 Click to rate     Rating   46 
 Report abuse 
 
Sounds like she got her just McDeserts.

- George, Rockville USA, 06/2/2012 11:35
 Click to rate     Rating   80 
 Report abuse 
 
The views expressed in the contents above are those of our users and do not necessarily reflect the views of MailOnline.
 
We are no longer accepting comments on this article.
 Bing Site Web Enter search term: Search     
FEMAIL TODAY

 &apos;This time, Justin messed with the wrong woman&apos;: Triumphant Tulisa settles legal action against ex over sex tape leak &apos;The truth has come out&apos; You&apos;re not fooling anyone! Tulisa spends five hours having her hair dyed blonde... then tries to hide it with a wig Next time put the wig on properly Tulisa! Tom Cruise&apos;s lawyer to sue National Enquirer for &apos;hundreds of millions&apos; over &apos;vicious lies&apos; Branded Tom a &apos;monster&apos; and said he &apos;humiliated his wife&apos; Single lady style statement: Katie Holmes dons tight leather trousers for dinner date Younger, sexier image for Ms Holmes Gorgeous by day: Kelly Brook shows off her shape in sailor bikini as she enjoys amorous day with beau Thom Evans She&apos;s nautical but nice! Playful by night: Kelly Brook narrowly misses popping out of her dress as she dances at the dinner table in Italy Who needs a dance floor? Want a body like Denise? Richards reveals the secret behind her slim frame as she works out in weight loss shorts It&apos;s that simple! The Only Way Is Essex star Gemma Collins in hot water over hair salon tweets Not the only TOWIE star to plug for freebies Gisele Bundchen&apos;s naked ambition is laid bare in daring nude beach shoot for Vogue Paris Stripping back to basics Chris Hemsworth... the human stroller: Thor star carries baby India Rose around on shopping trip - and leaves pram at home Hands on dad! Woman with world&apos;s largest natural breasts claims 102ZZZ-cup assets require security to fend off admirers who &apos;chase her&apos; Annie Hawkins-Turner Big Brother 2012: Psychiatrist rushed in as &apos;depressed&apos; ex Playboy model Shievonne Robinson makes suicide remark Been &apos;crying hysterically&apos; Grimace and bear it: Christine Bleakley looks terrified with Frank Lampard at Universal Studios Not flashing those pearly whites It&apos;s chest OR legs! Sarah Harding reveals her very thin figure in a cropped top AND low-riding shorts Didn&apos;t get the memo Raffaella Fico shows off her growing bump as she steps out after penning open letter to Mario Balotelli Maintains footballer IS the father Aunty Khloe on duty! Kourtney Kardashian&apos;s sister looks after Mason while she spends time with newborn daughter Putting in some practise? Duchess of Cambridge&apos;s extreme makeover: She&apos;s stuck in a beauty rut - now FEMAIL gives Kate a beauty overhaul using new virtual technology A forlorn looking Rihanna goes back to her plaited roots... after returning home for grandmother&apos;s funeral Grieving loss of beloved grandmother Dolly Makes a change from tennis whites! Maria Sharapova reveals killer legs in sheer chiffon dress at ESPY awards Caused quite a racket &apos;One doctor suggested I abort her&apos;: Against all odds one of the world&apos;s smallest surviving babies finally goes home Kenna Claire Moore is a little miracle That&apos;s one pricey push-up! The bra dripping in diamonds and gold selling for $1million Contains 750 grams of gold They&apos;re his mini mes! Liam Gallagher&apos;s sons Lennon and Gene are a chip off the old block Perfected that mean and moody scowl Fifty Shades of Grey author&apos;s saucy tale was inspired by her Latin roots, says her mother Alexandra Mitchell has praised her daughter&apos;s erotic trilogy Making the most of her bikini body: Actress Louisa Lytton shows off her slim frame on holiday Before rehearsing for latest theatre show Lesbian sex scene in ballet thriller Black Swan makes it film with most complaints Some viewers described the scene as &apos;pornographic&apos; What would Marilyn say! Karolina Kurkova flashes a bit too much as she takes centre stage in a sexy photoshoot She took it a lot further! Angelina Jolie shows off simple style as she spends time with half her brood before getting into character in scary costume A woman of many talents Tom Cruise and Katie Holmes&apos;s amicable divorce is &apos;a sham as actor plans to keep Suri in Scientology&apos; He has &apos;planned her indoctrination&apos; &apos;Duct tape over the camera and a $1,000 a night Presidential Suite&apos;: Inside Tom Cruise and Katie Holmes&apos;s last weekend together Efforts to hide tension &apos;Look how broken up we look&apos;: Professor Green denies split from Millie Mackintosh Said he made up lesbian rumours &apos;I just can&apos;t function in the morning&apos;: What Nick Grimshaw told BBC boss moments before being offered top breakfast slot On Chris&apos; show today Pudsey goes Stateside! Talented pooch wins over U.S. audiences with an adorable performance on Jay Leno Entranced by their show Pictured: The moment Glee star Kristin Chenoweth received emergency medical treatment following injury on set Stretchered off set A bit of me time: Jessica Alba quaffs rose wine as she enjoys some bikini time with her mother in Amalfi As the children are away... EXCLUSIVE PICS: We get it, you&apos;re engaged! Katie Waissel can&apos;t keep her hands off model fiance Celebrating poolside in Los Angeles Mr Bigger: Sex And The City heart-throb Chris Noth succumbs to the middle-aged paunch Not the trim suited Mr Big he once was You can leave your hats on! Elle Macpherson&apos;s trendy son copies her jaunty style on holiday A trendsetter in her own family THAT&apos;S how she stays so slim! Lady Gaga reveals Lindsay Lohan snacks on cucumber on big nights out Forget a kebab - its all about salad Why do the children of the rich so often turn into drug addicts? As the Rausings tragedy develops, CATHERINE OSTLER looks at how drugs are classless That will make their friends Greene with envy! Twilight beauty Ashley leads co-stars in greeting determined fans at Comic-Co Mr Bigger: Sex And The City heart-throb Chris Noth succumbs to the middle-aged paunch Not the trim suited Mr Big he once was Proud Eugenie poses in mortar board as she graduates... and she can&apos;t stop smiling Royal looked delighted at Newcastle University It takes a lot of work to look this good! Kim Kardashian heads to the gym after sharing bikini snap from sunrise shoot That&apos;s Barry&apos;s Bootcamp workout Cesc Fabregas&apos; girlfriend Daniella gets snap happy as he shows off his football skills on holiday in Sardinia Who can blame her? When in Rome: Roxanne Pallett goes for a Eastern-inspired dress at Bali spa opening Emmerdale star showed off a lot of flesh DIY Chelsea blow-dry: Can you get Kate&apos;s tumbling curls without professional help? MARIANNE POWER took up the challenge THAT&apos;S how to wind down after Wimbledon! Roger Federer and wife soak up sun on luxury yacht... as Andy Murray battles rain in Britain Miranda Kerr pretends to be demure in long floral dress... but still flashes her cleavage and legs Showed off her runway legs No bingo wings here! Catherine Zeta-Jones shows off her toned arms in a pretty sundress as she hits the shops All that heavy lifting The perfect pairing! Christina Hendricks is the hostess with the most-ess in a plunging black dress You would have to be a mad man not to notice Stephen Dorff&apos;s model girlfriend is nowhere to be seen... as he&apos;s surrounded by bikini-clad babes in Ibiza Katharina Damm MIA Can you fake the perfect cleavage? We put underwear to the test as a new bra promises to boost your assets at the tug of a string She&apos;s a fan of Pink too! Singer steps out with Carey Hart and daughter Willow who is dressed head-to-toe in the girly colour Her number 1 fan How does a man cope when his wife wont stop breast feeding? Vicky&apos;s decision to continue with their three-year-old is inhibiting their closeness, says James I do, I do, I do! Three brides, one dress and 50 years of true love Three generations from one family tell their stories Suri&apos;s smile: Katie and Tom&apos;s daughter has her spirits lifted on zoo outing with mother and grandma Kept her distracted at Central Park in New York Did Katie Holmes make secret calls to Nicole Kidman before blindsiding Tom Cruise with divorce? Claims she sought counsel from his ex 
 
CREDIT CARDS: OUR TOP PICKS

   Best balance transfer credit card rates   Best credit cards for cashback and rewards   Best credit cards for overseas use   Best credit cards for spending
	</body>
</document>
