<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001096" url="http://empowerability.wordpress.com/category/universal-design/bathrooms/" time="2012-07-12-16:31" support="8" score="0.01787618551051634" bingtitle="Bathrooms « EmpowerAbility® , LLC" webtitle="BathroomsEmpowerAbility® , LLC">
			<query id="000420" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="001173" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="000108" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="000265" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000297" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="001488" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000171" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000923" bing-rank="150"/>
	<description>Do you go to your local fast food restaurant, duck into ... were just tired of standing and you needed a place to sit ... your email address to follow this blog and receive ...</description>
	<body>
		EmpowerAbility® , LLC 
 
 Home About 
 
Posts filed under‘Bathrooms’
 
 The importance of customer listening: GreatGrabz® responds with a stylish safety grab bar 

There are many grab bars on the market today, but I wanted to write this blog post about a company that not only offers an innovative product, but was created from the will and determination to make grab bars better. Compelled to create a stylish grab bar product after a client exclaimed, “I would rather fall than have my friends think I have a grab bar!” GreatGrabz® was born.

Abbie Sladick, President of GreatGrabz® , started the company six years ago. After spending many years remodeling bathrooms, this client comment inspired Abbie to design a grab bar that would not only be functional, but aesthetically pleasing. The stylish Wave Bar is GreatGrabz® signature product. The signature line of bars also has the follows features:

• Adjustable wall attachments for flexibility in installation and usage.
• Ability to mix and match finishes on one bar.
• Weight capacity of 500lbs on all bars and the 24″wave is 1100lbs.
• Innovative mounting plate to ensure an easy and precise installation.
• Wave design allows for flexibility in use; many of GreatGrabz® clients feel it is easier to use.
• Abbie says, “There is TLC packed with every bar!!!”

 GreatGrabz® is a reminder of the importance of customer listening.
As an Occupational Therapist/Accessibility specialist and a home owner with grab bars, I am ecstatic about products that are being made for both function and aesthetics. When we built our home, eight years ago, there were not many options on the market that allowed for the creation of a beautiful accessible bathroom. GreatGrabz® gives the choice of beauty and safety, all in one.

Check out the product line and tell me what you think!
 
 
 
 June 9, 2010 at 7:06 am 3 comments 
 
 Aging-in-Place products 

There are quite a few shower systems on the market that boast safety and aging-in-place design. The Seated Safety Shower™ is no exception, stating that it is “the first seated shower built to meet the needs of many people including the elderly and disabled.” The shower system has a contoured built-in seat as well as an area in front for standing. Integrated into the system is a “wrap-around” grab bar.

Like many products that are universally designed, you can argue the points of how the product may not be accessible to certain users. In this case, one point is that the shower enclosure has a 3” threshold which would prohibit its use as a roll-in shower system and can be an issue for those persons who may have trouble stepping into the shower. However, the built-in seat does allow for a person using a mobility device to transfer to the seat from outside the shower, therefore avoiding the threshold altogether, but is this truly an aging-in-place application?

With the many products on the market it is so important to know your clients current functional performance with activities of daily living as well as their projected future abilities to make a sound decision on what product will meet their needs for the long-term. Occupational Therapists look at a person holistically to determine strengths and weaknesses (ex: decreased mobility), which impact the ability to perform a task (ex: bathing, functional transfers), as well as the environment that the task is to be performed (ex: an inaccessible bathroom). The coordination of efforts of all players on a home modifications team is integral to meeting the needs of the client being served.

Have you used this shower system? What do you think of this product?
 
The Seated Safety Shower™ by Safety Tubs
 
 March 13, 2010 at 8:04 am 1 comment 
 
 Universal Design: Public Bathrooms Part II 

It is amazing to me that you can still find a public restroom that does not have adequate signage for the blind and visually impaired. In Dwell’s Universal Design: Public Bathrooms Part II video , the building is very old but could easily be retrofitted with correct signage.  Having the word “men” carved into the cement block that is above the bathroom door is barely enough signage for an able-bodied person, let alone anyone else.  Although it is an old building, it’s main use is for the public as a restroom, but I cannot imagine that the doorway, with the door opening in and to the right partially obstructing the entrance, is wide enough to allow for a person using a mobility device to enter easily.

As for the Automatic Public Toilet in Madison Square Park, I really like the idea that it will be sprayed between each use. Although, if one was not aware of this feature, they might be concerned why the floor was wet.  Perhaps signage within the bathroom denoting this feature might be helpful.  I was unable to determine from the video itself, but my assumption is that the door was at least 36” wide when it opens to allow a wheelchair user enough clearance.  The wall-hung toilet within the bathroom does allow for more clear floor space and there appears to be enough space next to the toilet for transfers.  Also noted are the grab bars around the toilet itself, but what I do not see is where the toilet paper dispenser is located.

Going back to signage, the outside of the toilet facility does appear to have some signage with Braille under the words “Automatic Toilet”, but I did not see any Braille to denote if the bathroom was vacant, occupied, night closure or out of order.  Instead, print and a visual cue are given.  I also could not determine if Braille was available for all of the functions for both the sink and the door within the bathroom itself. Perhaps the use of some other audible alert might be helpful as well.

What are your thoughts on the Automatic Public Toilet?  Would you use it?
 
 March 12, 2010 at 7:11 am 1 comment 
 
 Universal Design versus Accessible Design in a bathroom 

This is a gorgeous example of a contemporary style bathroom that incorporates some Universal Design elements.  The room boasts a large amount of space, a curbless shower with handheld shower head, a wheelchair-friendly sink with lever handle faucet and lots of light.

Keeping in mind that Universal Design attempts to meet the needs of most users, bathroom spaces may need to be customized to meet the needs of specific users.  For instance, in order for a user in a wheelchair to utilize this bathroom, the height of the sink may be a concern.  I also wonder about the space around the toilet and bidet for transfers as well as the potential need for a shower bench/seat versus a roll-in shower chair.  Also, I do not see any grab bars or space for storage and would have some concern for a person with a visual impairment, as this design does not incorporate much contrast.  All of these concerns would need to be configured into the design of the bathroom, depending on the specific current and potential future needs of the client.

What do you think of this bathroom setup?
 
Porcher Epic Collection
 
 March 11, 2010 at 8:34 am Leave a comment 
 
 A look at integrated grab bars 

The Invisia collection, from Health Care Products, is a line of grab bars that was designed with the simple concept that “grab bars should not look like grab bars”.  Health Care Products calls this line “a series of luxurious bathroom accessories that also happen to be grab bars hidden in plain sight.”   The collection is being marketed as Aging-in-Place design.

While these grab bars do not follow guidelines for commercial/facility use, what do you think about their potential popularity for residential applications?  What are your first thoughts on this grab bar collection?  Click on this link for all pictures.

**Please note that any products being placed on this blog, unless otherwise specified, are not being endorsed by EmpowerAbility, LLC.  The blog is solely a means to disseminate information and create discussion regarding current products/trends on the market.
 
Wall toilet roll holder
 
 March 4, 2010 at 7:13 am 3 comments 
 
 Modern Solutions for the ADA Bath 

Seven years ago when we built our home there were few product options on the market that allowed for both accessibility and contemporary aesthetics. The Feb/March issue of SNAP highlights a few bath fixtures, fittings and accessories that take a more modern approach to the ADA bathroom.   From grab bars that incorporate 76% recycled materials, to a cast iron tub with an integrated grip rail….Would you purchase any of these products?  Check them out and let me know your thoughts on these products!
 
 February 19, 2010 at 7:32 am 2 comments 
 
 Universal Design: Public Bathrooms 

If the thought of using a city public bathroom makes you cringe and want to run, you are not alone.   It has happened to all of us before; you are driving or walking around enjoying your day, and you find yourself nowhere near your house, or a friend’s house, and are in need of a bathroom.  Do you go to your local fast food restaurant, duck into a coffee shop, brave a mini-mart or gas station, or rush home hoping that you will make it?

The use of the unfamiliar bathroom requires strategy; a plan to be able to get in, get the job done, get out and not touch a thing.  If only we could create an invisible force field, impenetrable to germs, perhaps the experience would be more positive.  Instead we consciously and methodically complete a hand scrub procedure that is pre-surgery worthy, and then hope to find that elusive paper towel to be the barrier between your newly germ-free hand and the door you have to open to get out.

All of this, and now what if you had a disability?  Used a wheelchair, cane, or walker?  What if your legs were just tired of standing and you needed a place to sit while washing your hands?  Perhaps the bathroom door is too narrow and your wheelchair or walker can’t fit in.  Perhaps the bathroom stall door is not wide enough, and your wheelchair can fit but you can’t close the door behind you.  Perhaps there is only one accessible stall, but it is being used by an able-bodied person.

In this video, Smart Design, a New York-based company, “examines the intersection between Universal Design principles and the limitations of public bathrooms.”  We can all benefit from a universally designed public bathroom in the city.  This is part one of a two-part series.  I look forward to part two.

 
 
 February 10, 2010 at 7:55 am 2 comments 
 
 
 
 

 About 
 
 Categories 

 Accessibility (29)
 Employment (1) Recreation (3) 
 ADA (4) Aging-In-Place design (17)
 Local Chapter (1) NORC (1) 
 Arthritis (2) Assistive Technology (7) Bathroom products (4) Caregiving (6) Home Safety (6) Kitchen products (3) Livable Communities (1) occupational therapy (3) Universal Design (32)
 Bathrooms (7) Hotels (1) Kitchens (3) 
 Wheelchairs (3) 
 
 Search 
 Search for: 
 Follow Blog via Email 
 
Enter your email address to follow this blog and receive notifications of new posts by email.

Join 10 other followers

 

 
 
 Recently Tweeted: 

 The #LivableCommunities Daily is out! Stories by @ APA_Planning @ PPS_Placemaking @ transportdata @ Livability ... fb.me/1UaS3HvaY 1 day ago The #LivableCommunities Daily is out! Stories by @ transportdata @ livability @ StreetsblogNet @ urbandata paper.li/EmpowerAbility… 3 days ago Do you or your parents have #longtermcare insurance? What are your thoughts on this video? goo.gl/Fhscv #aging 5 days ago 
 
 Find posts on highlighted dates: 
 
 July 2012 M T W T F S S «Apr       1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31   
 
   RSS - Posts 
 
Theme: Blix by Sebastian Schmieg . Blog at WordPress.com .
 Follow 
 Follow“EmpowerAbility® , LLC” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
