<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001966" url="http://www.wlbt.com/story/14878263/newton-car-theft-ring-investigation" time="2012-07-12-17:52" support="1" score="0.0004985285558903217" bingtitle="Newton car theft ring investigation - WLBT.com - Jackson, MS" webtitle="Newton car theft ring investigation - WLBT.com - Jackson, MS">
			<query id="001305" bing-rank="241"/>
	<description>Jackson fast food restaurant armed robbery ... &quot;If a $40,000 dollar vehicle and you pay $5,000 and ... the hot vehicles managed to somehow legally get car ...</description>
	<body>
		WLBT.com - Jackson, MSNewton car theft ring investigation
 SITE SEARCH WEB SEARCH BY 
 
 Miss Mississippi Video Landing Page Decision 2012 Jackson Gas Prices Editorials America Now Medical Matters Sign up for Alerts Contact Us 
 
 Decision 2012 Editorials MDOT Traffic Cams Wednesday&apos;s Child Look Around Mississippi Most Wanted Sign up for Alerts 
 
 Alfa Insurance Skycams How to Program a Weather Radio Sign up for Alerts 
 
 Olympic Zone Sign up for Alerts 
 
 MedNOW Medical Matters Sign up for Alerts 
 
 Taking Back Our Neighborhoods 
 
 Main Summer Back to School Entertainment Money Home/Family Health Food Pets Tech Travel Beauty&amp;Style Auto Tax Guide VideoBytes Press Releases 
 
 SkyCopter 3 Community Our Team The Morning Team Midday Mississippi Sign up for Alerts Contact Us Closed Captioning This TV Network 
 
 WLBT Community St. Jude Dream Home SkyCopter 3 Our Team The Morning Team Midday Mississippi Contact Us Fresh from the Flame 
 
 
 Email 
 Share | 
 Print 
 
Newton car theft ring investigation
 Posted: Thursday, June 9, 2011 6:15 PM EST Updated: Thursday, June 9, 2011 8:00 PM EST By Marsha Thompson - bio | email 
 
 Most Popular Stories Most Read More&gt;&gt; 
 
 PD: Father punched man who attempted to meet daughter 

 PD: Father punched man who attempted to meet daughter 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 10:34 PM EDT 2012-07-12 02:34:44 GMT A 42-year-old Monterey man got a bloody nose when he tried to meet a 12-year-old girl that he met on Facebook. More &gt;&gt; A 42-year-old Monterey man got a bloody nose when he tried to meet a 12-year-old girl whom he met on Facebook, according to police. More &gt;&gt; 
 Police identify 3 shooting victims 

 Police identify 3 shooting victims 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 9:44 PM EDT 2012-07-12 01:44:43 GMT Jackson police have identified three people shot while sitting in an SUV at 947 Robinson Street Tuesday night. More &gt;&gt; Jackson police have identified three people shot while sitting in an SUV at 947 Robinson Street Tuesday night. More &gt;&gt; 
 Parents arrested, girl allegedly forced to live in chicken coop 

 Parents arrested, girl allegedly forced to live in chicken coop 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 6:53 PM EDT 2012-07-10 22:53:55 GMT The parents accused of keeping their teen daughter in a chicken coop have been arrested. More &gt;&gt; The parents accused of keeping their teen daughter in a chicken coop have been arrested. More &gt;&gt; 
 Good Samaritan fatal crash results in multiple lawsuits 

 Good Samaritan fatal crash results in multiple lawsuits 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 11:05 PM EDT 2012-07-11 03:05:14 GMT The aftermath of an accident that killed one twin sister and left the other critically injured is headed to federal court. A wrongful death lawsuit was expected in the case, but now there are legal filings More &gt;&gt; The aftermath of an accident that killed one twin sister and left the other critically injured is headed to federal court. A wrongful death lawsuit was expected in the case, but now there are legal filings against lawyers, a Hinds County Constable and the father of the deceased woman&apos;s child. More &gt;&gt; 
 Man takes baby to meet with prostitute 

 Man takes baby to meet with prostitute 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 9:48 AM EDT 2012-07-10 13:48:25 GMT A man in Tuscaloosa may be charged with child endangerment after taking along his nine month old son during a meeting with a prostitute. More &gt;&gt; A man in Tuscaloosa may be charged with child endangerment after taking along his nine month old son during a meeting with a prostitute. More &gt;&gt; 

 
 Sponsored Information More&gt;&gt; 
 
 sponsored information: 

 Personal Injury Attorney 

 Personal Injury Attorney 
 
 
Authorities believe they are onto a high-end vehicle theft ring, operating in Scott and Newton counties. Vehicles were stolen here in the metro, then flipped at unheard of prices.

Officials say the auto theft ring was a smooth operation when it came to stealing and selling. This woman is under arrest for buying a hot car. Newton&apos;s police chief says four vehicles were stolen from individuals in the Jackson area and recovered in Newton.

The trucks and cars were purchased at a fraction of their cost. &quot;If a $40,000 dollar vehicle and you pay $5,000 and it&apos;s only a year old, then it&apos;s some kind of tale-tale sign there. That something maybe is wrong with this vehicle. That&apos;s just too, that&apos;s literally a steal.&quot; A steal and a deal.

Oddly enough, people who bought the hot vehicles managed to somehow legally get car tags in their names with bogus documents. According to Chief Harvey Curry, &quot;The VIN numbers that they used to go and get the license plate through the tax assessor&apos;s office was changed a little, a couple of numbers were moved around and naturally when they run it into their system, it&apos;s not stolen.&quot;

Betty Johnson is charged with buying this one year old Honda Oddessy for $5,000 dollars. The stolen vehicle was valued at 40 grand. The buyer now faces possession of stolen property charges.

Authorities say a joint effort between Newton police and the Mississippi Bureau of Investigations led to the recovery of the stolen vehicles from homes here in Jackson.
 
 
Explore WLBT.com
 Home Local News Decision 2011 Gas Prices America Now Point of View Sound Off News Most Read Local News Skycopter 3 Most Wanted Look Around Mississippi 3 On Your Side Wednesday’s Child Taking Back our Neighborhoods Red Blue Review Medical Matters Weather Local Weather Alfa Insurance Skycams How to Program a Weather Radio Interactive Radar 4-Day Pollen Forecast Sports Sports National Sports Mississippi Sports Friday Nite Lites Video Latest Videos Most Watched Video Center Contact Us Contact Us Sign Up for Email Alerts Our Team Birthday Club All content©Copyright 2000 - 2012 WorldNow and WLBT, a Raycom Media Station .
All Rights Reserved. For more information on this site, please read our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service .
	</body>
</document>
