<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001650" url="http://most-popular.net/beer-america" time="2012-07-12-17:25" support="1" score="0.0005071499779779082" bingtitle="Most Popular Beer in America" webtitle="Most Popular Beer in America">
			<query id="000919" bing-rank="216"/>
	<description>America’s Most Popular Department Store ... Most Popular Fast Food Restaurant in the US; Most Popular Candy Bars ... Cancel reply. Leave a Comment</description>
	<body>
		Home 
 World’s Most Popular Spiritual Leader World’s Most Popular RPGs America’s Most Popular Department Store Most Popular Day to Rob a Bank World’s Most Popular Web Browser 
 
 The Most Popular Journal 
 
Most Popular Beer in America

by tom on December 20, 2006 
 
Can you guess what the worlds most popular beer is? If you guessed Budweiser, you were just partially right. I’ll give you another hint: it was introduced in 1982. Have you figured it out yet? OK, I’ll give you another hint. It is a classic American light lager. Yes you finally got it, Bud Light.

According to Budweiser, it is brewed with two-row and six-row malt, rice, and hops, both American and European varieties. It uses a very different and distinct brewing process to produce a distinctively different, lower calorie beer with a crisp, clean taste.

Even though the micro-brewed beers are more flavorful and are gaining in popularity, the marketing people have help make Bud Light the best selling brand in the US!

 Related 
 Most Expensive Beer 

Similar Posts:

 Most Popular Soda in the US Most Popular Fast Food Restaurant in the US Most Popular Candy Bars Most Popular Ice Cream 


 Share this post: 
 
 
Tagged as: Brands , Drinks , Food , Popular Culture , United States 
 
This website uses IntenseDebate comments , but they are not currently loaded because either your browser doesn&apos;t support JavaScript, or they didn&apos;t load fast enough.
 
 { 55 comments…read them below or add one } 
 
 ←Previous Comments 
 omar August 19, 2010 at 10:21 pm 
In my opion corna is with limon and salt:)

 Reply 
 Ross October 27, 2010 at 11:53 pm 
If you are ever in Australia, try a Crown Lager. Very smooth and tasty.

 Reply 
 
 ←Previous Comments 
 Cancel reply 
Leave a Comment
 
 Name * 

 E-mail * 

 Website 

 

 
 
Previous post: Most Popular Christmas Gift 

Next post: Most Popular Cell Phone Provider 
 
 
Tag Cloud
 Ads Apple Asia Autos Brands Breeds Canada Cats Celebrities Collectibles Colors Countries Culture Dogs Drinks Drugs Education Film Food Games Government Health History Holidays Internet Japan Leisure Music Names People Pets Phones Politics Popular Culture Publishing Social Media Sports Super Bowl Technology Traits Travel United States Video Web World 
 
 
SEARCH
 
 
 
POPULAR POSTS
 
 Sport in the World Car in America Candy Bars Car Color in America Fast Food Restaurant in the US Beer in America Cat Names Dog Breed Web Site Blog / Weblog Dog Names Ice Cream Last Name in the US Christmas Gift Video Game Franchise British Baby Names Korean Last Names Sport in Japan Filipino Baby Names Country 
 
RANDOM POSTS

 Most Popular Sport in the World Most Popular Twitter Account Most Popular YouTube Videos Ever Most Popular Israeli Baby Names
	</body>
</document>
