<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001039" url="http://smallbusiness.chron.com/upselling-techniques-restaurants-20154.html" time="2012-07-12-16:27" support="3" score="0.013557246677858284" bingtitle="Upselling Techniques in Restaurants | Small Business - Chron.com" webtitle="Upselling Techniques in Restaurants | Small Business - Chron.com">
			<query id="000802" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000790" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000812" bing-rank="80"/>
	<description>A fast food restaurant might ask customers if they&apos;d like a super ... Planning the Exit Strategy; Business Plans: Exit ... Cars; Coupons; Classifieds; Place a classified ad; Place a ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to main content. 
 Subscribe Subscriber Services Make a Payment MyChronRewards 
 Chron.com chron.com Web Search by YAHOO! Businesses 
 Home News Sports Business Entertainment Life Travel Blogs Opinion 

 Jobs Homes Cars Classifieds Coupons 

 Index 
 Close [X] Quick links to the best of chron.com | Still can&apos;t find it? see Site Index 
 Don&apos;t miss: Recent Headlines 
 
 Houston&amp;Texas Houston weather Houston traffic Nation&amp;world Politics Health News bizarre Deaths Hurricanes 9/11 anniversary 
 
 Ultimate Astros Rockets Texans Dynamo Colleges High school Golf Outdoors More sports 
 
 FuelFix.com Markets Houston stocks World markets Your portfolio Currency Small business Tech Homes Commercial real estate Press releases 
 
 29-95 Restaurants Alison Cook Music Movies Bars Arts&amp;Theater 
 
 Mom Houston Houston Belief Health Gardening Pets Gloss Food Books Horoscopes Comics&amp;games Weddings&amp;celebrations 
 
 Texas Travel Travel New Orleans Travel Louisiana Flight tracker 
 
 City Brights Newswatch Celebrity Buzz SciGuy Tubular NFL: John McClain Sports Justice TechBlog Texas on the Potomac Mom Houston 
 
 Nick Anderson cartoons Bill King columns Editorials Op-ed columns Letters to the editor 
 
 Advanced search Browse job categories Career Rescue Houston&apos;s Hiring Work&amp;Career Advice 
 
 New Homes Rentals Farms&amp;Ranches Second Homes Research Mortgages Commercial Real Estate 
 
 Research&amp;Reviews Build a New Car Find Dealers 
 Small Business by Demand Media 
 Business Technology&amp;Customer Support | Business Communications&amp;Etiquette | Human Resources | Managing Employees | Setting Up a New Business | Advertising&amp;Marketing | Business&amp;Workplace Regulations | Types of Businesses to Start | More» 
 
 » Business Models&amp;Organizational Structure » Accounting&amp;Bookkeeping » Business Planning&amp;Strategy » Finances&amp;Taxes » Running a Business » Money&amp;Debt 
 
 Small Business » Business Planning&amp;Strategy » Pricing Strategy » Upselling Techniques in Restaurants 
 
Upselling Techniques in Restaurants
 by Elizabeth Smith, Demand Media 

 
Upselling helps boost restaurant sales.

Siri Stafford/Lifesize/Getty Images
 
 Related Articles 

 Different Ways of Upselling in a Restaurant The Keys to Upselling in Restaurants Upselling Techniques for Use in Hotels Keys to Upselling The Internal Process for Upselling Upselling Technique for Shipping 
 
Upselling is a common strategy for restaurants to boost their profits. By training your staff in ways to sell more, you can help their tips and improve business. Upselling is more than sales; it requires perception, knowledge and discretion. At its best, upselling can look less like sales and more like customer service; effective techniques should be subtle enough to avoid annoying the customer or making them feel pestered.
 
Offer More-Expensive Items

A common restaurant upselling technique is to offer more-expensive items than the ones the customer originally ordered. This tactic is most effective when it is not obvious. Servers often use this technique without the customer knowing by offering two choices of liquor without noting that one is more expensive, for example. In order to push up the bill, servers should have knowledge of the profit margins and prices of each item on the menu.
 
Extras

Many restaurants rely on a simple strategy to sell more: offering extra items. A fast food restaurant might ask customers if they&apos;d like a super-sized option or if they would like fries with their meal. A restaurant server will ask a diner if they&apos;d like to start with an appetizer or try a special entree. In some restaurants, the extras are prescribed by management: the chef&apos;s special or a new item they want to push, for example.
 
Offer Specific Items

Instead of asking customers if they would like additional food or drinks, it is often more effective to be specific. Restaurants often employ the strategy of avoiding generalities that are easy for the diners to dismiss. Instead of asking if a customer wants dessert, for example, the server will ask if they want to try the chef&apos;s special dessert and provide a mouthwatering description. This is particularly effective when the server can see that the customers are wavering; the delicious details can convince them to go with their desires.
 
Make Suggestions

When a customer is deliberating on what to order or asks for recommendations, a restaurant server has the opportunity to upsell without seeming pushy or irritating. They might name one of the more-expensive dishes on the menu when asked for a suggestion or recommend that the customer try a beverage that will complement their dish. By making helpful suggestions, the customer feels taken care of rather than like a sales target.
 
Demonstrate Enthusiasm

One of the most effective upselling techniques a server can use is to show enthusiasm about the foods they are pushing. When they can give details about the food and a description of their personal experience and preference, it can be more convincing than simply suggesting an expensive item. For this technique to work, the server should be genuine.
 
References

 Food Service Warehouse: Top 10 Tips for Successful Restaurant Upselling Gator Chef: Upselling Techniques for Restaurant&apos;s Staff 
 
About the Author

Elizabeth Smith has been a scientific and engineering writer since 2004. Her work has appeared in numerous journals, newspapers and corporate publications. A frequent traveler, she also has penned articles as a travel writer. Smith has a Bachelor of Arts in communications and writing from Michigan State University.
 
Photo Credits

 Siri Stafford/Lifesize/Getty Images 
 
More Articles

 
Top Restaurant Sales Techniques
 
Restaurant Selling Techniques
 
Automating HR Functions for Restaurants
 
How to Sell Retail Travel Items at Travel Agencies
 
 
People Also Viewed

 Sales&amp;Selling Tips for Restaurants Fast Food Techniques for Advertising How to Develop a Marketing Strategy for a Restaurant What Is Add-on Selling? How a Restaurant Can Reach a Large Target Market What Is the Difference Between Upselling&amp;Downselling? 
 
Related Topics

 What Is the Importance of Contingency Planning in Strategy Evaluation Results? Planning the Exit Strategy Business Plans: Exit Strategy Examples of a Business Plan Exit Strategy Business-Plan Marketing Strategy 
 
 
The Web&apos;s 6 Most Influential Tech Bloggers
 
America&apos;s 9 Most Tech-Friendly Cities
 
Phone Pas: 9 Places You Should Pocket Your Cell Phone
 
10 Highest Valued Tech Companies
 
9 Gadgets You Can&apos;t Live Without
 
 Small Business Index Powered by Demand Media 
Chron.com

 Home Houston&amp;Texas Nation&amp;World Business Sports Entertainment Life Corrections Blogs Weather 
 
 City Brights Traffic 

Topics

 Small Business MomHouston.com HoustonBelief.com 29-95.com 
 
Neighborhoods

 Aldine Alief Baytown Bellaire Clear Lake Conroe Cy-Fair East End Fort Bend Heights Katy 
 
 Kingwood Lake Houston Magnolia Memorial Montrose Pasadena Pearland Spring Tomball West U The Woodlands 
 
Marketplace

 Jobs Homes Cars Coupons Classifieds Place a classified ad Place a retail ad 

Other Editions

 Home Delivery iPad iPhone Android Mobile RSS Feeds e-Edition 
 
Local Services

 Air Conditioning Contractors in Houston Car Dealerships in Houston Cleaning Services in Houston Family Doctors in Houston Furniture Stores in Houston Injury Attorneys in Houston New Car Dealer in Houston Real Estate Agents in Houston Real Estate Attorneys in Houston Restaurants in Houston 
 
Services

 Help/Contact us Business directory Legal notices Privacy policy Terms&amp;Conditions Employment opportunities Advertise with us Buy a banner ad 
 
©2012 Hearst Communications Inc.
 Hearst Newspapers RSS My Yahoo!
	</body>
</document>
