<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001462" url="http://greenanswers.com/blog/244286/bpa-silent-menace-where-you-can-find-bpa-and-what-you-can-do-about-it" time="2012-07-12-17:14" support="39" score="0.08745679370725815" bingtitle="BPA: The Silent Menace, Where You Can Find BPA and What You Can Do ..." webtitle="BPA: The Silent Menace, Where You Can Find BPA and What You Can Do About It | GreenAnswers">
			<query id="000898" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="001118" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="001218" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="001201" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000662" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000992" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="001209" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000115" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="001385" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="001398" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="001216" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="001207" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="000365" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="001407" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="001495" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="001408" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="001198" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001191" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="001403" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="000586" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="001390" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="001214" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="000568" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000303" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="001405" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="001219" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="001369" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000052" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="001196" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000397" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="001180" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="001387" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="001526" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="000583" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000615" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="001165" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="001396" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="000678" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000740" bing-rank="83"/>
	<description>... like McDonald’s, there is another receipt taped to your bag, outlining your order. ... is common: A person drives through a fast food restaurant, touches money and receipts ...</description>
	<body>
		Log In Join 
 
 Home Ask a Question Answer 
 Unanswered Questions Popular Questions Recently Asked Questions 
 Browse Topics See all... or choose one: 
 Animals&amp;Wildlife Business&amp;Economics Climate Change Education&amp;Activism Energy&amp;Fuels Food&amp;Agriculture Forests, Trees&amp;Plants Health&amp;Wellness Homes&amp;Buildings Ideas&amp;Philosophies Media&amp;Entertainment 

 Nature&amp;Ecosystems Other Policy&amp;Government Pollution&amp;Toxins Products&amp;Shopping Recreation&amp;Activities Recycling&amp;Waste Science&amp;Technology Sustainability&amp;Development Transportation Water, Oceans&amp;Ice 
 Explore 
 Articles Members Widgets FAQ About 
 Articles My Profile 
 
 BPA: The Silent Menace, Where You Can Find BPA and What You Can Do About It 
 By Kirsten Richards on Tue, 06/14/2011 - 12:26pm 
 We recently went through a scare about BPA being used to make water bottles, baby bottles, and food cans. We have seemingly forgotten about the big, bad threat of BPA. However, BPA is also found in other places. And what’s scary is that it is found in something we handle several times per day: cash register receipts.

This information is particularly disconcerting because people sometimes handle the same receipt four or five times. First, the cashier hands you a receipt to sign (if you’ve used a credit card). Then, the cashier hands you your own personal copy of the receipt. If you go somewhere like McDonald’s, there is another receipt taped to your bag, outlining your order. Some people keep their receipts in their wallets and thus handle them when they file them away at home.

Research Results

Just touching the receipts can transfer BPA to a person’s skin. However, when researchers tested human skin, they found that holding a receipt for longer than 10 seconds could transfer a larger amount to the skin. Rubbing the receipt (how many of you fold them?) can transfer almost 15 times as much BPA as holding or touching it alone.

It is slightly reassuring that testers only found BPA on 2 in 5 receipts that were tested by the Environmental Working Group (2010). Tests showed amounts of BPA between 250 and 1,000 times the levels found in a can of food that we were so worried about before. Some of the offending retailers were McDonald’s, CVS, KFC, Walmart, and Safeway. Retailers whose results were virtually BPA-free were Target, Starbucks, and Bank of America.

This is scary enough for the consumers who handle receipts daily, but what about cashiers who are handling hundreds or thousands of receipts daily? These people are much more at risk, and a study by the CDC has shown that they carry much more BPA in their bodies than the rest of the general public.
The same year that the Environmental Working Group did its tests, John C. Warner, the “green chemistry pioneer” did tests of 10 stores’ receipts and found BPA in 8 of them. After issuing his report, several companies said they would abandon the use of BPA coated receipt paper.  

Tests on the harmful effects of BPA have only been done on animals, so the risks to humans can be controversial at times. However, BPA affected animals negatively, so we can assume that there is also a risk to humans. The specific risks of exposure due to BPA exposure or ingestion occur because BPA is a chemical that mirrors the properties of estrogen. The negative effects on animals that have been tested include breast and prostate cancers and altered growth of reproductive organs.

Not Only Receipts

As if worrying about BPA on receipts were not enough, in December of last year, a study done by the joint forces of Safer Chemicals, Healthy Families and the Washington Toxics coalition also found BPA on money. Since people often put receipts in their wallets, they decided to test money for the presence of the toxic substance. Out of 22 bills, 21 of them tested positive for at least some levels of BPA.

A study done on pigs examined how much BPA can penetrate the skin. Luckily, researchers found that most of the BPA stayed on the surface of the skin. However, BPA could still enter the bloodstream if people do not wash their hands before touching their eyes or mouth. The following scenario is common: A person drives through a fast food restaurant, touches money and receipts, and then proceeds to eat the food from the restaurant without washing his or her hands. Not only has the person ingested dirt, bacteria, and other substances we have become somewhat immune to thinking are harmful, but also he or she has now ingested BPA.

BPA is found in many products, namely items with metal coatings, baby bottles, water coolers, food storage containers, medical devices, sunglasses, CDs and DVDs, electronic equipment, automobile parts, and sports equipment. It is used in the production of epoxy resins, and because those are used in the production of plastics, many products that are plastic or have plastic parts contain BPA.

What You Can Do

There are several action steps to take to reduce your contact with products containing BPA. First, tell cashiers that you don’t need a receipt, and select the “no receipt” option from the gas pump. Instead, keep a small notebook with you so you can write down your purchases. Or, you could keep track of them on your debit or credit card statements. Then, investigate further what plastics are present in your home, specifically number 7 plastics, which are known to contain BPA.
Many cities and states have banned some uses of BPA, but investigate your state or city’s practices, and write your senator or congressperson, urging him or her to take up the mantle of banning BPA nation-wide.

There’s no doubt about its presence; we must find a way to protect ourselves.

Sources

Adams, Jill U. “Bisphenol A and its potential health risks.” LA Times 9 August 2010. Retrieved 11 June 2011.
articles.latimes.com/2010/aug/09/health/la-he-closer-look-receipts-20100809/3
Brown, Eryn. “Dirty money: BPA on dollar bills.” LA Times 8 Dec. 2010. Retrieved 11 June 2011.
latimes.com/health/boostershots/la-heb-bpa-on-money-20101208,0,1735042.story
Hunter, Aina. “BPA Receipts Bombshell: Paper Slips Contain High Levels of Bisphenol A.” CBS News. 28 July 2010. Retrieved 11 June 2011.
cbsnews.com/8301-504763_162-20011903-10391704.html
“New Study Confirms BPA in Receipts.” Environmental Working Group. Retrieved 11 June 2011.
ewg.org/new-study-confirms-BPA-exposures-from-receipts
Shapley, Dan. “List of Items Containing Disputed Chemical Bisphenol A.” thedailygreen.com. 7 Aug. 2007. Retrieved 11 June 2011.
thedailygreen.com/environmental-news/latest/4885

Photo credit: scu.edu/sustainability/soap/blog.cfm?c=3652
 
Questions asked about this article on GreenAnswers
 Might the alternatives to BPA be dangerous, as well? 57,401 15 Join GreenAnswers now and we&apos;ll plant a tree on your behalf. After that, we&apos;ll plant another tree for every 5 questions you answer. 
 Most Viewed Most Watched Most Discussed 
 
 how many stages of gang green are there? Ipod Price in India my Carmine Jewel Dwarf Cherry is 3-4 years old now and still no fruit? Plus it seems to be losing leaves. they turn yellow and fall off?? what should I do? When you get all the plastic recycled from a vhs tape. What do you do with the tape? Is global warming harming us? 
 
 what are five main ways in which natural environment of the pacific islands have been degraded or abuse What effect do recreational facilities have on the environment Whats the most recent animal entered on the endangered species list? How can the birds eggs fit inside the bird? Is it better to leave your grass clippings on your lawn or pick them up with the bag attachment? 
 What&apos;s this? 
 Why are the blue fun tuna populations at such a higher risk than the other tuna populations? Why is nuclear nonproliferation so difficult? how many stages of gang green are there? What would happen if we didn&apos;t have a gas tax? How many trees can one acre of land support? 
 GreenAnswers Newsletter Daily Monthly 
Environmental Articles
 
 Greenpeace Urges KFC to Stop Using Illegal Rainforest-Produced Paper Packaging Tech Giants Commit to Renewable Energy in Response to Greenpeace&apos;s Clean Our Cloud Campaign Disney Tightens Their Belt and Cuts Junk Food Advertising Roll Call: Welcoming Four New Species Arctic In Danger Fair Trade: The Damage of Global Trading What’s in This Season? Fruits Edition What’s in This Season? Veggies Edition Fruits and Strategies: Making the Most of the Farmers Market Obesity Epidemic: Whose Fault is it Anyways? 
 More Articles... 
Top 10 Members This Week
 
 
 12tree Karma (last 7 days): 66 
 
 heliosman Karma (last 7 days): 62 
 
 johan Karma (last 7 days): 31 
 
 kiraisthewalrus Karma (last 7 days): 29 
 
 sondarby Karma (last 7 days): 21 
 
 lizbryant88 Karma (last 7 days): 21 
 
 mrblevins Karma (last 7 days): 20 
 
 lovetheearth Karma (last 7 days): 20 
 
 bryguy Karma (last 7 days): 19 
 
 vivian2012 Karma (last 7 days): 19 
 
 More Members... 
Follow Green Answers .com
 
 RSS Twitter Facebook 
 
 Get the LiveOAK Network widget! Not seeing a widget? ( More info ) 
 
Copyright©2012 GreenAnswers.com LLC. All rights reserved.

 About FAQ Contact Terms&amp;Privacy Blog Widgets RSS Feed 
 
Please remember the information provided is from the community and is not intended to provide or substitute for informed professional advice. Please see the Terms of Use for the full disclaimer.
	</body>
</document>
