<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001500" url="http://ezinearticles.com/?Security-Camera-Maintenance-Tips-for-CCTV&amp;id=4914963" time="2012-07-12-17:16" support="1" score="0.001929556423655826" bingtitle="Security Camera Maintenance Tips for CCTV" webtitle="Security Camera Maintenance Tips for CCTV">
			<query id="001259" bing-rank="81"/>
	<description>It never fails, we&apos;ll go into a fast food restaurant for a ... out many of the mistakes businesses make in camera selection ... this camera should be place behind the cashier ...</description>
	<body>
		Search Home » Home Improvement » Security Wm R Thomas 
 Diamond Author |   12 Articles 
 Joined: August 23, 2010 Was this article helpful? 0 0 
Security Camera Maintenance Tips for CCTV

 By Wm R Thomas 
 
It never fails, we&apos;ll go into a fast food restaurant for a quick bite and my tech will start pointing out the cameras that through neglect have just become dust collectors. At one of my favorite places for a quick burrito, we noticed one camera so covered in grease you could hardly see the camera inside its dome. A second camera was disconnected, and another was so out of focus you couldn&apos;t make out even the number of people standing in line. Out of four cameras only one worked well enough that you could even make out an image of people. To make the situation even worse, they had the monitor facing the customers so anyone looking to rob the store could see he was in no danger of being picked up on a security camera.

Surveillance is more than being able to see a crowd of people. If the police can&apos;t identify the person from the recorded image then the cameras are doing you no good at all. The FBI was so frustrated with opportunities lost that they produced a DVD targeted towards businesses to improve the images they&apos;re seeing. In their case they are missing opportunities at potential terrorist, a much more serious situation then a small time thug, unless of course the thug is in your store. The DVD called &quot;Caught on Camera&quot; points out many of the mistakes businesses make in camera selection and placement, but the result is the same as cameras not maintained properly and that is a lot of useless images.

It isn&apos;t any cheaper for the store owner to put off repairing a camera that isn&apos;t working properly, until later, and the truth is when money is tight is precisely the time you can&apos;t afford to be robbed. Maintaining your security cameras can be as simple as buying a can of compressed air and once a month blowing the dust away from the lens. Wiping the lens with a cloth should be avoided, although you could buy a camera lens cloth and use it very carefully to clean a lens. Most cameras will not need to be focused unless someone was tampering with the camera, in which case you may need to call in a professional, but it is usually a relatively inexpensive visit and he can look over all of your cameras at the same time.

Pedestal base cameras can get bumped and some mounts will allow the camera to move fairly easily. Those type bases can usually allow the store owner or manager to move them back into position. Dome type cameras should not permit the problem of the camera being move. The dome can also be cleaned with a soft cloth as it is not as prone to damage as a camera lens, making them a better choice for a greasy environment like a fast food restaurant. Although no camera is going to hold up in a high grease area like over a grill.

The most important camera in any brick and mortar type store or restaurant is the one facing the register. That is the camera most of all you need to make sure is working properly and is properly placed. If possible this camera should be place behind the cashier at eye level. How many times have we seen a picture on the news of the top of a baseball cap? A camera placed at eye level makes it much more difficult for a robber to hide his face and so much less likely to try something. This camera is easier to reach to keep clean, but is susceptible to having items placed in front of it. Part of maintenance is making sure nothing is blocking the view of your cameras. Don&apos;t let a banner or a display rack prevent your camera from identifying a shoplifter.

With just a little time spent each month maintaining your CCTV system, your security cameras will end up paying for themselves in loss prevention.
 
If you have questions on camera maintenance 1st Choice Security Technologies has a camera blog to answer such questions, visit our security camera blog at www.nepasecuritycameras.com 

Wm R Thomas has been in the security industry for over a decade and has designed security systems for well over a thousand homes in Northeastern Pennsylvania. He is the President of 1st Choice Security Technologies who specialize in high quality yet affordable surveillance camera systems. 1st Choice specializes in installing super high resolution cameras into homes and small businesses where just a few years ago the price of these cameras made them unattainable for most home owners.

 http://www.nepasecuritycameras.com 
 
Article Source: http://EzineArticles.com/?expert=Wm_R_Thomas 
 Did you find this article helpful? 0 0 Get Involved 0 comments Suggest a topic Article Tools Print this article E-mail to a friend EzinePublisher Report this article Cite this article Stay Informed Get notified by email when new articles are added to this category or written by this author. 
Subscribe to New Article Alerts:
 
 Home Improvement: Security 
 Wm R Thomas 
 Email Address: Subscribe Security Article Feed Find More Articles Search 
Similar Articles

 CCTV Surveillance Cameras - Ideal For Home Security A Guide to Buying the CCTV Security Systems Security Camera Recording Systems - An Introduction to Current Technology Be Cautious While Choosing a Security System For Your Premise! Video Surveillance Cameras in Schools -- Addressing Student Safety and Security A Short CCTV Guide For Investors Hidden Cameras Versus Obvious In Your Face CCTV Discussed The Benefits Of Having A CCTV At Home Do You Need a CCTV Camera? 10 Tips on Shopping for CCTV Cameras 
 
Recent Articles

 Being Smart About Safety Should You Choose a Manually Operated or Automatic Security Gate? Fences With Automated Gates Home Security Products - An Effective Way To Provide Protection To Your Home Everything You Need To Know About Home Security Products Reflective Address Stickers Safety Precautions - What People Need to Know Home Security: Most Popular Home Security Gadgets - The Top Four Best Wireless Home Security Products - The Top Two Home Security: How To Use Light As An Effective Burglary Prevention Tool - Three Ways 
 
Submitted On August 23, 2010. Viewed 293 times. Word count: 663.
 MLA Style Citation: 
Thomas, Wm R. &quot;Security Camera Maintenance Tips for CCTV.&quot; Security Camera Maintenance Tips for CCTV .
 23 Aug. 2010 EzineArticles.com. 12 Jul. 2012&lt; http://ezinearticles.com/?Security-­Camera-­Maintenance-­Tips-­for-­CCTV&amp;id=4914963 &gt;. APA Style Citation: 
Thomas, W. R. (2010, August 23). Security Camera Maintenance Tips for CCTV .
 Retrieved July 12, 2012, from http://ezinearticles.com/?Security-­Camera-­Maintenance-­Tips-­for-­CCTV&amp;id=4914963 Chicago Style Citation: 
Thomas, Wm R. &quot;Security Camera Maintenance Tips for CCTV.&quot; Security Camera Maintenance Tips for CCTV EzineArticles.com . http://ezinearticles.com/?Security-­Camera-­Maintenance-­Tips-­for-­CCTV&amp;id=4914963 
 EzineArticles.com 

©2012 EzineArticles.com
All Rights Reserved Worldwide
 
 About Us FAQ Contact Us Member Benefits Privacy Policy Shop Site Map 

 Blog Training Video Library Advertising Affiliates Cartoons 
 
Authors
 
 Submit Articles Members Login Premium Membership Expert Authors Endorsements Editorial Guidelines Terms of Service 
 
Publishers

Follow Us
 
 Terms Of Service Ezines / Email Alerts Manage Subscriptions EzineArticles RSS
	</body>
</document>
