<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001924" url="http://www.healthcaremagic.com/healthpage/i-feel-sick-at-my-stomach-after-drink-wine" time="2012-07-12-17:49" support="2" score="0.0014811563397191152" bingtitle="i feel sick at my stomach after drink wine" webtitle="I feel sick at my stomach after drink wine">
			<query id="000246" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="000239" bing-rank="92"/>
	<description>I do not drink alot of wine or alcohol. I have the odd glass once a week perhaps ... stomach problem for a while, if i drink any alcohol and lay down anywhere near 5 ...</description>
	<body>
		Get &quot;Ask a Doctor&quot; App    Are you a Doctor?   |   Sign-In   |   Sign-up    191 Doctors Online! 
 My Dashboard Services Doctors Public Forum 
 Get your Health question answered in 3 easy steps A Doctor will be with you shortly Ask a General&amp;Family Physician Now Change Specialty [x] Please click to select a specialty : Addiction Medicine Specialist Allergist and Immunologist Ayurveda Specialist Cardiac Surgeon Cardiologist Cardiologist, Interventional Cosmetic&amp;Plastic Surgeon Critical Care Specialist Dentist Dentist, Pedodontics Dermatologist Diabetologist Emergency Medicine Specialist Endocrinologist Endocrinologist, Surgical ENT Specialist Gastroenterologist Gastroenterologist, Surgical General&amp;Family Physician General Surgeon Genetics Specialist Geriatics Specialist Hematologist HIV AIDS Specialist Homeopath Infertility Specialist Kidney Transplant Specialist Nephrologist Neurologist Neurologist, Surgical OBGYN OBGYN, Gynecologic Oncology OBGYN, Maternal and Fetal Medicine Oncologist Oncologist, Radiation Ophthalmologist Orthopaedic Surgeon Orthopaedic Surgeon, Hand Surgery Orthopaedic Surgeon, Joint Replacement Pediatrician Pediatrician, Gastroenterology Pediatrician, Pulmonology Proctologist Psychiatrist Psychiatrist, Child Psychologist Pulmonologist Radiologist Radiologist, Nuclear Medicine Rheumatologist Sexologist Sexual Diseases Specialist Spine Surgeon Sports Medicine Specialist Thyroid Specialist Urologist 191 Doctors are Online 
 Online Doctors 
   Dr. Samuel. N. Grief
Family Physician Ask Now»   Dr. Andrew Rynne
Family Physician Ask Now»   Dr. Timothy G Moser
Family Physician Ask Now»   Dr. Matthew Mintz
Family Physician Ask Now»   Dr. Carol Rogala
Emergency Medicine Ask Now»   Dr. Mimi Ghosh
Family Physician Ask Now»   Dr. Kiran Kumar
General Physician Ask Now»   Dr. Ada B. Dickinson
Pediatrician Ask Now»   Dr. Rohit Batra
Dermatologist Ask Now»   Dr. J. Krueger
Oncolgist Ask Now» ...and 3500 more Doctors from across the world A Doctor will be with you shortly Hi, I am Dr. Samuel. N. Grief . I will be looking into your query and will be guiding you through the process. Please write your query below. 
Showing results for : I feel sick at my stomach after drink wine
 
Public Forum Discussions
 61248.jpg   I am a 31 year old male in good health. 
I am a 31 year old male in good health. When I drink wine on an empty stomach, I get a sharp pain in my shoulder, some discomfort in my stomach, and it feels as if my temperatue rises. After about 5 - 10 minutes, the symptoms subsides and I don&apos; View answers (2)» 62764.jpg   Why do I experience bloating and stomach pains after having alcoholic beverages ? 
I have days of bloating and stomach pains&amp;discomfort after drinking a can of soda pop or a glass of wine or alcoholic beverage. Why does this occur? View answer» 61332.jpg   Stomach pain with diarrhea after binge drinking 
do not drink very often at all. I am 21, 225lbs and 6ft tall and no medical history . Iv only been drinking on and off for a period of 6 months. Three nights ago i drank a lot more than i ever have, got sick and threw up then went to sleep. I woke up View answers (2)» null I do not drink alot of wine or alcohol. I 
I do not drink alot of wine or alcohol. I have the odd glass once a week perhaps occasionally as many as two glasses a week. I have been having a sharp distracting pain in my neck located under my right ear possibly in my gland ten minutes into drink null I am a 30 year old female. About six months 

I am a 30 year old female. About six months ago I started noticing a change in the amount of alcohol I was able to drink. Anything beyond two drinks and I was very sick the next day. Horrible headache and terrible stomach problems/nausea (constan 61623.jpg   Why is my stomach tender ? 
i had a gi bleed last friday, i still have stomach pains an little energy why could this be? i was bringing up blood after drinking quit a bit of wine at a family party last friday, i was taken to hospital by ambulance an was put on a drip they allow View answers (2)» What are the disadvantages of drinking wine every day? 
what are the disadvantages of drinking wine every day? View answer» 61220.jpg   Effect of wine on heart 
Is drinking wine really good for your heart? View answers (2)» null Hi , Ive had some stomach problem for a while, 
Hi , Ive had some stomach problem for a while, if i drink any alcohol and lay down anywhere near 5 hours afterwards i feel incredibly ill for the whole of the next day, I barely drink anymore but it would be nice just to have one beer or a glass of w null I m a 25 yr old white female and have 
I&apos;m a 25 yr old white female and have been having very strange reactions to alcohol lately. I almost want to say that I&apos;ve become allergic to it, all kinds, beer, wine, liquor. I&apos;ll go to the bar and have half a glass of wine with dinner Read More Public Forum Questions 
Premium Questions
 60101.jpg   Abdominal pain, feel sick after eating and drinking fizzy pop, taken Spasmonal, Nurofen 
i&apos;ve had pain in my side for about 6weeks now and it moves to my stomach but when i eat i feel sick and if i drink fizzy pop i feel sick my doctor gave me spasmonal to settle my stomach but it doesn&apos;t do anything for me and i got nurofen for the... View answer» 60101.jpg   What could be outcome of taking Xanax after drinking wine and beer ? 
Hello, I am a 27 year old female 5&apos;6&quot; 155lbs. My question is about Xanax. I had three glasses of wine around 5hrs ago and then one beer two hours ago. Without thinking, I took my .25mg Xanax for anxiety. Am I going to be ok?I don&apos;t feel... View answer» 60591.jpg   Gas in the stomach, toothache, white tongue, sore throat. Taking prilosec. Does drinking wine cause these symptoms? 
Hello my name is Cherise .. About two weeks ago I was drinking a lot of wine .. I notice my stomach started to bother me a lot wit a lot of gas.. So I change some eating habits.. Then a week after I Woke up wih a lot of gas and growling in my... View answer» Read More Premium Questions 
Online Doctor Chat
 62110.jpg   Swollen eye with reddening after drinking wine 
Doctor : hi
Doctor : how can i help u?
User : XXXXXXXX i was just wondering if you could give some advice
Doctor : yeah sure
User : my dads ete is really swallon, and red inside he said when he wipes it its blood, he said its worse after... View Transcript» 62403.jpg   Liver function test, Fasting lipid profile 
Doctor : Hi
Doctor : 
How can I help you?
User : 39 years old, heavy drinker in my 20&apos;s. don&apos;t drink much now, but when I do--one beer--I get sick the next day. Would this be allergy or liver problem?
Doctor : 
Like what kind of sickness... View Transcript» 62546.jpg   Feel cool in chest, arm while drinking water 
User : hi
Doctor : Hi
Doctor : How can i help you?
User : when i drink water i feel a cool feeling in my chest and left arm
User : is this normal?
Doctor : it is normal
User : really, no one feels this but me
User : but i will take your... View Transcript» 62110.jpg   Dizziness after riding on a roller coaster 
User : My 12 year old daughter feels dizzy and says she cant fall asleelp when she closes her eyes after riding roller coasters all day. Is this something that requires medical attention?
Doctor : Hi 
Doctor : Let me read what you have... View Transcript» 60591.jpg   Consumption of water while eating 
User : hello doctor
Doctor : hi
Doctor : how can i help you?
Doctor : please proceed with your health query
User : drinking water immediatelty after food...is that right?
User : or wwrong?
User : should we have to drink water before having... View Transcript» Not relevant ? Ask a doctor now» 
Health Articles
 Motion Sickness A feeling of uneasiness to a cold sweat, dizziness and then vomiting during travel. Stomach pain in children It is one of the common symptom of the children. The common causes are infections , poisoning, surgical causes. It is daignosed by blood tests, stool tests. Benefits of drinking milk Drinking milk has many more benefits on body as it contains more nutrients . Milk is one of the most commonly consumed beverages by all section of the people. Reasons to drink more water Water is very essential for our body. 705 of our body is made up of water. It helps in hydration of the body. It is necessary to drink around 8-10 glasses of water. If you do not drink enough of water you get headache , poor concentration, fatigue , constipation and dry skin . Recovery after hysterectomy After hysterectomy the recovery time depends on one patient to other patient. It also depends on the type of hysterectomy done like abdominal or vaginal. Read more Health Articles article:::0.14908991 community:::0.36719474 premiumquestion:::0.26335263 doctorchatlog:::0.30735952 Related searches i feel sick at my stomach after drink wine Services 
 Ask a Doctor Now Ask a Top Specialist Personalized Diet&amp;Fitness plan Health Questions and Answers Health Resources 
 Explore HealthcareMagic 
 About us Contact us In the News Advertise with us FAQs 
   
 Feedback Terms&amp;Conditions Privacy Policy SiteMap Recently Updated Questions 
 All the information, content and live chat provided on the site is intended to be for informational purposes only, and not a substitute for professional or medical advice. You should always speak with your doctor before you follow anything that you read on this website. Any health question asked on this site will be visible to the people who browse this site. Hence, the user assumes the responsibility not to divulge any personally identifiable information in the question. Use of this site is subject to our Terms&amp;Conditions What people are searching on Healthcaremagic Online Doctor Online Medical Advice effects of lupus on the body what to do for infected gums causes of bone loss in mouth pain in left groin area male pain in upper leg near groin what causes dry skin on face skin cancer what to look for dime sized red spots on skin signs of skin cancer on nose how to heal sun damaged skin causes of itchy skin on legs baby s progress week by week inside the womb week by week all the weapons in the world feet and leg cramps at night nerve pain down front of leg causes of leg aches at night top of head painful to touch lower left groin pain in men signs that you have a cavity Hi, whenever I go outside when its hot or when Hi.. I am 24 yrs.. Female.. Married before 7 months. yes doctor ,please i will say u my problem now hello, i have attention deficit disorder and take 50 mg Hi for the past few days i have had a I have a lump thaat has suddenly appeared between my I have a haemangioma in L3 disc it was diagnosed I am 37 weeks pregnant today and I just had Hello, I m 13 years old and i do alot my 18 month old has had tubes for about 2months my father 68 yrs old,5 9 height,58 kg weight,had minor hi sir,my name is ram iam suffering with hydrocele since I am a very healthy 40 year old who is my daughter is 4 years 11 months. She has edinoids hai iam 35 years age on april 23 i got I was recently quite ill with an infection in the Age of boy is of now 18 months. From last hi,my baby is 9months she s got some funy pimple Sometimes when I eat I get really sharp I have been experiencing constant hunger, its like I eat ©2012 - Unified Health Solution | All Rights Reserved   Ask a Doctor Now - Get the answer in 3 simple steps 191 Doctors are Online
	</body>
</document>
