<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001777" url="http://www.weegy.com/home.aspx?ConversationId=1B98799F" time="2012-07-12-17:33" support="1" score="0.0010809582985980047" bingtitle="Which of the following could be considered a modern government ..." webtitle="Which of the following could be considered a modern government responsibility?
 
 A. Governments are responsible for providing equal protection for all people. 
 
 B. Governments are responsible for protecting due process of law. 
 
 C. Governments are responsible for protecting society from unsafe foods. 
 
 D. Governments are responsible for protecting property rights of the public.">
			<query id="000892" bing-rank="245"/>
	<description>Sarah often calls 911 from the drive-through window of a fast food restaurant if they get her order ... Weegy: How many congressional seats are up for reelection every ...</description>
	<body>
		Log In Sign Up MyWeegy Manage Resources Archive Blog About View Conversation Which of the following could be considered a modern government responsibility?
 
 A. Governments are responsible for providing equal protection for all people. 
 
 B. Governments are responsible for protecting due process of law. 
 
 C. Governments are responsible for protecting society from unsafe foods. 
 
 D. Governments are responsible for protecting property rights of the public. 
 Click here to ask Weegy a question. Get an instant answer from an advanced search engine and live experts. Go ahead, give it a try! (It&apos;s free.) 
 
 Call or text Weegy at 707 GoWeegy (707-469-3349). (This is free too.) 
 User: Which of the following could be considered a modern government responsibility?
 
 A. Governments are responsible for providing equal protection for all people. 
 
 B. Governments are responsible for protecting due process of law. 
 
 C. Governments are responsible for protecting society from unsafe foods. 
 
 D. Governments are responsible for protecting property rights of the public.

 Weegy: B.governments are responsible for protecting dues process of law
 Expert answered|concreterose|Points 30| 

 User: Which of the following scenarios describes the free-rider problem?
 
 A. Sam wouldn&apos;t voluntarily pay $2,000 to provide new hoses for local firefighters, but would want those hoses used if his house were burning down. 
 
 B. Sarah often calls 911 from the drive-through window of a fast food restaurant if they get her order wrong. 
 
 C. Just because Charles drives on the highway each morning, it doesn&apos;t mean Lucy can&apos;t drive on the same highway. 
 
 D. The Telly Telephone Company forces all clients to purchase land lines in order to buy a cell phone plan.

 Weegy: B.
 Expert answered|concreterose|Points 30| 

 All Categories|No Subcategories|Expert answered|Rating 0| 6/21/2011 7:36:13 AM View and rate new answers Rating There are no new answers. View comments There are no comments. Add an answer or comment Log in or sign up first. Ask Weegy a question. Search archive. 
 
 CALL or TEXT 707.GoWeegy Who Is Weegy? Recent Conversations Help Call or text Weegy at 707 GoWeegy (707-469-3349) FREE Home | Contact | Terms | Privacy | Social | ©2012 Interlaced Systems Inc. Weegy Ask a question and get an instant answer from an advanced search engine and a team of really smart live experts. It&apos;s free. No kidding! Which of the following could be considered a modern government responsibility?
 
 A. Governments are responsible for providing equal protection for all people. 
 
 B. Governments are responsible for protecting due process of law. 
 
 C. Governments are responsible for protecting society from unsafe foods. 
 
 D. Governments are responsible for protecting property rights of the public. Popular Conversations The LCM of 15 and 30 is _____.
1
15
30
45 Weegy: What is the LCM of 45 30 and 1.5? ... What is the LCM of 15 30 and 45? LCM of 15 30 and 45 is 90. [ The LCM of ... 7/11/2012 7:42:20 AM| 5 Answers What are the age limitations relating to working in your state? Weegy: What are the age limitations relating to working in Kansas? Answer It! In: Kansas [Edit categories] [ ... 7/11/2012 8:05:47 AM| 5 Answers If a person eats salty food, his or her kidneys respond by excreting ... Weegy: If a person eats salty food, his or her kidneys respond by excreting excess salt into the. During a , a patient ... 7/11/2012 1:56:37 PM| 5 Answers should i smack my kid Weegy: Make him wear the pants all day long. Don&apos;t smack him. Let him enjoy his pee pants... ... 7/11/2012 11:14:48 AM| 4 Answers In &quot;Games at Twilight,&quot; Anita Desai describes the furniture in the ... Weegy: I think its B. dead. 7/11/2012 1:37:19 PM| 3 Answers geography Weegy: What&apos;s your question about geography? 7/11/2012 1:17:03 AM| 2 Answers who is theus representative of florida Weegy: Districts
Representative
Party
County(s)
85
Abruzzo, Joseph
Democrat
Part of Palm Beach
12
Adkins, Janet ... 7/11/2012 1:31:10 AM| 2 Answers Orbital motion is a balance between _____ and _____.
 A. force; ... Weegy: ... gravity make up orbital motion ... force that slows a book sliding on a table? A- gravity B- static friction ... 7/11/2012 6:07:29 AM| 2 Answers All of the following statements have the same value except ... Weegy: ... the value of x must lie between four and six ... from zero. Absolute value ... [ the same as those for ... 7/11/2012 6:35:43 AM| 2 Answers How did the Social Security Act help Americans? Note: Has it?

Or has it pilfered from Americans to be &apos;borrowed&apos; for other things and distributed to people who didn&apos;t ... 7/11/2012 7:23:06 AM| 2 Answers Is there any good to being Friends with benifts with someone in stead ... 7/11/2012 7:58:34 AM| 2 Answers Why don&apos;t some people think Shakespeare wrote his plays? Weegy: Who do people think really wrote shakespeares plays? Shakespear Shakespear. [ Why don&apos;t some people think ... 7/11/2012 9:54:16 AM| 2 Answers Top Ranked Experts kaysha S L Points (Month 610 Total 1201 )|Offline debnjerry P S L L L C 1 C M P C C P C 1 P C L P C 1 P C 1 P C P C 1 P C P C C Points (Month 583 Total 33830 )|Offline may100 S 1 Points (Month 448 Total 938 )|Online jeifunk S L 1 P C M Points (Month 443 Total 4331 )|Offline jcr.2008 S Points (Month 298 Total 628 )|Offline andrewpallarca S L P C 1 R P 1 L P C 1 P 1 M P 1 P 1 L P 1 P 1 P 1 P 1 Points (Month 286 Total 13133 )|Online Frankie17851 S M L Points (Month 256 Total 2459 )|Offline rugmaker S P C L P C Points (Month 243 Total 1960 )|Offline patrick_hustla S Points (Month 220 Total 380 )|Online patmarone S L 1 1 L Points (Month 193 Total 5705 )|Online View all experts» Points contest»
	</body>
</document>
