<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001837" url="http://jewelerinraleigh.com/" time="2012-07-12-17:37" support="4" score="0.0032824873365649198" bingtitle="Jeweler In Raleigh - Best fine jewelry store in Raleigh North Carolina" webtitle="Best Place to Sell Gold">
			<query id="000933" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="000930" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="000934" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="000927" bing-rank="107"/>
	<description>... for a diamond and if that is your only focus, it can then leave you ... you shop on a brick and mortar store, you ... no hotels, not even a single fast food restaurant!</description>
	<body>
		/connecting.html&quot;&gt; Earn CASH for referrals&amp;get discount coupons by joining our email list For Email Marketing you can trust 
 If You Want To Sell Gold In Raleigh,
 Do it the smart way. Shop around first, see us last.
 We want you to be able to recognize a strong offer when we present one.

 Why Choose Raleigh Gold Jewelry&amp;Coin? 
 Here are 10 Good Reasons

         








 People Often Ask Us How Our Simple Buying Process Works,
 We keep it simple. Your items will be inspected, separated, weighed and tested in front of you.
Any items with gemstones or diamonds will be discussed.
We then present a generous offer based on the items, their weight, and the spot price of gold.


 We will not be undersold&amp;will beat nearly any legitimate offer.
 
 
 Rated A+&amp;Accredited  
 Click here
 
 
 Interviewed by News14
 Click here .
 
 
 Interviewed by NBC17
 Click here
 
 
 Voted Best Jewelry Buyer
 Click here
 
 
 Interviewed by ABC News
 Click here
 
                                                                                     *Legal Disclaimer:
At Raleigh Gold Jewelry, we offer designer brand name and high quality estate jewelry. We proudly stand behind the authenticity of our
goods. Since we have chosen not to be an authorized dealer, in many instances these goods were not obtained directly from the
designers but rather have been purchased from reputable dealers or from private estates. In this regard, Raleigh Gold Jewelry
expressly disclaims any indication that it is an authorized dealer or agent of any of the designers whose goods are offered in our stores.

All trademarks mentioned in this website are registered trademarks of their original owners who reserve all of their rights and ownership.
The use or mention of any trade name, product name, or trademark in this web site is in no way intended to suggest that the trademark
owner is at all affiliated with or endorses our website or retail estate jewelry stores.
 Privacy Statement
 A bout U s
 
 C ontact U s
 
 
 Terms and Conditions
 
 North Raleigh (919) 872-2600  6301 Falls Of Neuse Road
 Brier Creek (919) 544-5445  10251 Little Brier Creek Lane
 
 
 
 Top Rated Gold Buyer&amp;Estate Jewelry Showroom
 
 1) We are generous, respectful, jewelry&amp;coin professionals. We are not a pawn shop.
2) All of our jewelry buyers are Graduate Gemologists or (GIA) educated.
3) We are a local, family owned jewelry store with a twelve year local history.
4) We make easy to understand offers in a no pressure environment.
5) A+ Rated&amp;Accredited by the Better Business Bureau.  
6) Interviewed by ABC, NBC, News 14&amp;WRAL. We are the most respected buyer in Raleigh.
7) Voted&quot;Best in Jewelry&quot;2009 by Raleigh Citysearch Voters.
8) Awarded Talk of the Town&apos;s Five Star Customer Service Award 2011.
9) We offer a no pressure, private, upscale environment.
10) We offer FREE JEWELRY REPAIR to ALL of our clients.
 
 6301 Falls Of Neuse (919) 872-2600
 
 
 10251 Little Brier Creek Lane (919) 544-5445
	</body>
</document>
