<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001350" url="http://www.yelp.com/biz/cafe-caturra-arlington" time="2012-07-12-16:50" support="3" score="0.0018844315597031027" bingtitle="Cafe Caturra - Arlington, VA" webtitle="Cafe Caturra - Arlington, VA">
			<query id="001390" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="001301" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="001201" bing-rank="149"/>
	<description>... and I was trying to figure out the whole time if I was in a fast food restaurant or a ... You order your food at the counter when you come in, take your receipt and a number ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Search Form Skip to Navigation Skip to Page Content 

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 Log In Sign Up for Yelp Friends&apos; Activity 0 Loading... 
 Yelp is using Facebook to personalize your experience. What is this? Not you?
 Log out of Facebook Don&apos;t want to be connected?
 How to turn this off 
 
 Yelp 
 Real people. Real reviews. ® 
 
 Search for (e.g. taco, cheap dinner, Max&apos;s) 

 Near (Address, City, State or Zip) 
 Search 
 Welcome About Me Write a Review Find Reviews Find Friends Messaging Talk 

 Member Search 
   
Cafe Caturra
 58 reviews Rating Details 
 Category: Restaurants Cafes Cafes   [Edit] 
 2931 S Glebe Rd 
 Arlington , VA 22206 
 (703) 535-5480 http://cafecaturra.com 
 
 Add Photos Price Range: $$ 
 Accepts Credit Cards: Yes
 Parking: Private Lot
 Attire: Casual
 Good for Groups: Yes
 Good for Kids: No
 Takes Reservations: No
 Delivery: No
 Take-out: Yes
 Waiter Service: Yes
 Outdoor Seating: Yes
 Wi-Fi: Free
 Good For: Lunch, Dinner
 Alcohol: Beer&amp;Wine Only
 Noise Level: Average
 Ambience: Trendy, Casual
 Has TV: Yes
 Caters: Yes
 First to Review Anna S. 
 Edit Business Info 
 Send to Friend Bookmark Send to Phone Write a Review 
58 reviews for Cafe Caturra
 Reviews Matching: Search Reviews Sort by: Yelp Sort | Date | Rating | Elites&apos; | Facebook Friends&apos; 
Facebook Friends


 
From Reviewers You&apos;re Following 


 
Reviews from Your Friends


 
58 reviews in English

 
Review from Paul H. 
 
 0 friends 1 review 

 Paul H. 
 
Arlington, VA
 6/11/2012 
I wish Yelp offered 6 stars, because this place is worth all of them!  Great menu, fast, friendly service, awesome wine list, and fantastic ambience.  Everything I&apos;m wanting in a wine bar, and nothing I don&apos;t.  I&apos;m hesitant to post this, because I don&apos;t want the place to get too crowded!

Gets my vote for &quot;best use of a former Blockbuster Video&quot;
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Brian E. 
 
 0 friends 25 reviews 

 Brian E. 
 
Arlington, VA
 7/9/2012 
Not sure that anyone who has given this place more than one or two stars has ever gotten take-out?   I did, and it was absolutely TERRIBLE.  (today is my day to write all of the bad reviews I&apos;ve been saving up)

It all started off fairly well.  Walked in, picked up menu, ordered food, got drink, got number. . . and waited. . . and waited. . . and waited. . . and waited. . . read a magazine. . . the cover on the magazine had a picture of Jackson Hole, but couldn&apos;t really find a story about it and I thought that sucked &quot;those people look like a-hole tourists anyway. . .sigh. . . I miss living in Jackson. . . why did I move back to stupid Arlington&quot;. . . back to waiting for my food, and waiting some more.  Saw the guy behind the counter put the hummus order together. . . saw him redo the hummus order to make it to-go. . .never saw any sort of bag being brought out for this order. . . random food orders going out to everyone else. . . guy behind counter (manager?) notices we&apos;ve been sitting there a hell of a long time, and asks what we ordered.  Inform &quot;manager&quot; that we had hummus, and a chicken sandwich.

(quotes will be used as terms are loosely applicable)

&quot;Manager Guy&quot; tells &quot;Waitress Girl&quot; to go get our order. . .

&quot;Waitress Girl&quot; brings out our order and informs us that&apos;s it.

I notice the bag is a bit light, and take a look.  It&apos;s the hummus. . . where is the chicken sandwich?!?!

Inform &quot;Manager guy&quot; that the bag just contains the hummus, and not the other part of the order.

&quot;Manager guy&quot; finds the chicken sandwich in another bag somewhere behind the counter.

&quot;Manager guy&quot; doesn&apos;t say he&apos;s sorry that it took 1 hour to make a chicken/red pepper sandwich, and scoop some hummus.  Think we got a &quot;thanks for coming in&quot;.

Finally, got our food and took it home to eat. . . even though by that time, I think we forgot we were even hungry.

Get home, and open up the bags to sit down and have &quot;lunch&quot;. . . or is it now dinner time.

The hummus contains 3 little scoops of whatever it contains, an overly lemony hummus (no really, this little scoop must have contained 2 whole lemons), and I guess a pepper type spread, and olive one. . . and a couple of carrots, and celery.  No pita bread for you!

My chicken sandwich. . . so this was like chicken salad on a piece of wonder bread (okay, maybe it was wheat. . .but it wasn&apos;t anything special. . . it could have taken 1 minute to make. . . and maybe I was overly cranky by then, but it was nothing special).  Oh yes, and the potato salad I ordered as a side looked strangely like orzo pasta salad.  @$@@ ME!  1 Hour of waiting for two items, and neither involved actual cooking, and one wasn&apos;t even entirely correct.

I&apos;ll give it props that it looks nice, and if they had their crap together I&apos;d probably go there.  But it irritated me so much, and the fact that &quot;manager guy&quot; didn&apos;t even seem apologetic after knowing we were sitting there for an hour waiting. . . NEXT. . . there are a ton of other restaurants in the area.

Also, I&apos;ll answer the &quot;additional tips&quot; with regard to &quot;Take out&quot; as being &quot;not Sure&quot;. . . because after my experience, I&apos;m not sure that they know what to do with take out.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Heather C. 
 
 2 friends 7 reviews 

 Heather C. 
 
Alexandria, VA
 7/7/2012 
BEWARE!  Salt is a condiment, not a side dish!

I&apos;m sitting at home chugging water because I&apos;m in a salt coma from eating at Cafe Caturra.  Message to the kitchen--lay off the salt!  Every single dish that comes out of this kitchen is dipped in sodium.  Then they add some more for good measure.

Our server Quashawn walked up and greeted out table by saying, &quot;Are you ready to order?&quot;  No hello, no how are you, no do you want to start with something to drink?  We were all impressed by our server memorizing our order until a second person came out to make sure she captured everything.  She ended up missing multiple items from our order.  Our food was delivered, with a side of salt of course, and no one ever came back to see if everything was OK.

A guest at our table said that the food was &quot;clumsy.&quot;  He had the spag and meatballs and felt like the dish was prepared well ahead of time, stuck in the fridge and then re-heated when ordered.  I had a quiche which had a nice custard texture...but, surprise, it was coated in salt!  We were plagued by a collection of plates throughout the meal.  We reasonably had 20 plates sitting on our table by the end of the dinner.  We were about a minute away from clearing the table ourselves.  We finally flagged someone down to and asked for our check.

We even called the restaurant&apos;s main phone number from our table, trying to get someone to pick up the phone so we could get our check delivered since no one was on the floor...but the collection of five servers standing at the hostess stand didn&apos;t pick up the phone after multiple rings.

Our group desperately wanted to like this neighborhood restaurant but it is unlikely we&apos;ll be back.

Final thought--don&apos;t forget to order a side of salt!!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Joe S. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 24 friends 89 reviews 

 Joe S. 
 
Washington, DC
 6/7/2012 1 Check-in Here 
This place is a lot of fun. Not a standard restaurant. You feel free to roam around and do whatever you want. The outside patio is awesome and it looks like they have a gas fire pit!

Food was great. Prices are reasonable. I would recommend it.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from MacRae O. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 588 friends 951 reviews 

 MacRae O. 
 
Alexandria, VA
 4/25/2012 
This is how I feel at Café Caturra&apos;s happy hour: http://www.youtube.com/w… 

I *love* happy hour, and I love a good happy hour deal even *better*.  When a friend asked me to join her at a fundraiser HH at CC, I didn&apos;t have to think about it long.  When she mentioned CC&apos;s HH $3 draughts (anything on tap), $5 glasses of wine (anything on the menu), and a variety of $5 small plates (from pizzas to dip samplers), it only served to clinch my decision.  And since my initial induction to CC, I&apos;ve HH&apos;ed many at time.

There are so many things things to like about CC that bring me back on the regular for HH:

+ The wine list is manageable and impressive.  The Spanish Adegas Gran Vinum Nessa Abariño, crisp and minerally.  A robust and smoky Octavia Cabernet Sauvignon out of California&apos;s central coast.  The surprising, lightly oaked Thomas Henry Chardonnay from Napa.  These would normally run you $30 - 35 a bottle, but CC&apos;s HH lets you have exceptionally generous pours for $5 a glass.

+ The décor is modern and minimal, yet comfortable and inviting.  You can easily lose track of time and end up whiling away a few hours here.

+ A large outdoor patio with plenty of seating, some cushy couches, and heat lamps for cooler weather.

+ The service is so well-intentioned and warm.  Everyone from the hostess and bartenders to the servers and runners.  I have to give a special mention to Adam, CC&apos;s manager, who is so gracious it&apos;s almost suspicious.  Every time we&apos;ve been here he has personally come around to speak with us and thank us profusely for happy hour-ing.  Always happy to oblige, Adam!

+ Even outside the $5 HH menu, CC&apos;s price points are unusually low for the DC area.  $6 mac &apos;n&apos; cheese (fairly average), $10 veggie lasagna (pretty good).  We&apos;ve also nibbled on a five dollar Dip Trio with classic hummus (meh), white bean and tuna (great flavor), and white cheddar pimiento (soooo noms), as well as some roasted tomato, fresh mozz, basil, and balsamic Caprese Crostini (very nice), a margarita pizza (needed salt), and a white pizza (inhaled it).

Annoying things about CC, you ask?  Well...

- That well-intentioned and warm service can be rather slooowwwww sometimes.  I don&apos;t, however, find it to be as confusing or perturbing as other reviewers.  Perhaps HH at CC is more straightforward than regular meal times.

- The affordably priced food won&apos;t blow you away.  There are some menu stand-outs, and then some ho-hums.

So, kids -- one. plus. one.  equals: come to CC early and often for HH.  Forget about dinner, forget about lunch.  Just HH yourself silly at CC.
 
 Listed in: Vegging Out , Milk&apos;s Leap towards… , Where Everybody Knows Your… ,
	</body>
</document>
