<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001159" url="http://www.beyondwhitespa.com/en-us/whiten/procedure.aspx" time="2012-07-12-16:35" support="4" score="0.0030525604270836343" bingtitle="Cosmetic Teeth Whitening from Beyond WhiteSpa" webtitle="Cosmetic Teeth Whitening from Beyond WhiteSpa">
			<query id="000686" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000342" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000666" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="001345" bing-rank="230"/>
	<description>... all items in a cool, dry place. Avoid exposure to direct sunlight. • BEYOND™ WhiteSpa Select Whitening Gel syringes must be stored near 5 ... Simply hold the card over the ...</description>
	<body>
		English Spanish 
  
   
 Treatment Procedure 

 

STEP A - SHADE MATCHING

1. The aesthetician should first assess the needs of the client, creating a teeth whitening plan that best fits each individual client. Ask the client to sign the Client Consent Form and keep a copy for your records. If desired, use the BEYOND™WhiteSpa Select Treatment Checklist (available for download through our website) to determine the best treatment schedule for the client.

2. Before the whitening process, record the color of the teeth. Use the included shade guide to show the client the current color of his or her teeth. The client&apos;s current shade can be marked on the back of this card for reference post-treatment. (FIGURE A)

STEP B - PREPARATION

1. Ask the client to put on the protective eye goggles.

2. Have the client apply a generous layer of lip protection cream to his or her lips using a cotton bud. (FIGURE B)

3. Instruct the client to insert the BEYOND™FlexiBlue Comfort Cheek Retractor into his or her mouth with the tongue guard pointing downwards and resting the lips comfortably along the outside rim. Ask the client to bite down gently on the arms of the retractor and rest his or her tongue against the tongue guard. (FIGURE C) Inform the client that he or she can swallow his or her saliva during the treatment.

4. Have the client stretch the face protection cloth around the outside of the cheek retractor and secure the cloth on either side of the mouth by folding the upper tabs down under the top of the cheek retractor. Insert cotton rolls on either side of the frenum (inside of cheeks against the bottom teeth). (FIGURE D)

5. Additional lip protection cream can be applied to the inner surface of the lower gums. (FIGURE E) NOTE: If the client&apos;s lips are stretched very tight by the cheek retractor such that his or her lips are touching the surface of the teeth, have the client insert a small piece of cotton up under his or her lip to raise it away from the teeth to avoid contact between the gel and the lips.

6. Ask the client to use cotton balls or gauze to dry the surface of his or her teeth to be whitened. DO NOT apply whitening gel to wet teeth as this will inhibit the whitening process. (FIGURE F)

STEP C - APPLY THE WHITENING GEL

1. Ensure all teeth to be whitened are dry and lip protection cream has been applied to the lips and the inner surface of the lower gums.

2. Open the BEYOND™WhiteSpa Select Whitening Gel foil wrap and attach the mixing tip to the dual-barrel syringe of whitening gel before dispensing a single dosage of gel into the preparation tray. (FIGURE G)

3. Instruct the client to use the application brush to apply a 2mm thick layer of whitening gel to the teeth to be whitened. Depending on his or her smile this may include a total of 16 or more of the upper and lower front teeth. (FIGURE H)

STEP D - LIGHT ACTIVATION

1. Ask the client to lean back in the treatment chair. Position the BEYOND™WhiteSpa Select Whitening Accelerator as close as possible to the cheek retractor, ensuring that the light is at a 90-degree angle to the whitening surface. (FIGURE I) NOTE: Positioning the accelerator behind the treatment chair and then lowering the lamp head down over the head of the client allows for the most precise positioning.

2. Press the power on switch found at the bottom of the accelerator base to turn on the device. The LCD control panel will turn on and ENABLE WITH CARD will flash across the top of the blue screen. Hold the 60 minute, System Activation Card over the activation sensor area. A white light above the sensor area will turn on for two seconds and the device will beep twice, signaling that the minutes have been activated. A total of 60 minutes will appear on the left-hand side of the screen, with the larger timer displaying the default setting of 20 minutes appearing in the center of the screen. (FIGURE J)

3. Adjust the treatment cycle timer to the desired treatment time (factory default is 20 minutes) using the SET TIME +/-buttons. Once desired time is selected, press the START button to begin the first treatment cycle. NOTE: Adjusting the treatment cycle time will reset the timer default from factory settings. If the CANCEL button is pressed during the treatment, the timer will reset to the new default treatment interval time. To reset to factory settings, simply adjust the time back to 20 minutes and press START. The next treatment cycle will default back to 20 minutes.

4. You may provide the client with music or video for entertainment during the treatment time, allowing the client to enjoy a relaxing whitening procedure. NOTE: The treatment cycle countdown can be paused or canceled at any time during the treatment. If paused, time will not be reset or lost. When paused, the treatment cycle time can be adjusted using the SET TIME +/-buttons. Pressing the CANCEL button will reset the treatment cycle timer to the default cycle time.

5. After the treatment cycle is completed, the whitening accelerator will beep twice and the light will turn off automatically. Treatment minutes used will be deducted from the total remaining treatment time. If there are treatment minutes remaining, the system will reset to the default treatment cycle timer set at the beginning of the treatment session. If minutes are expired, the system will return to the ENABLE WITH CARD screen.

6. Move the lamp head and have the client use cotton balls or gauze to wipe off the whitening gel from the surface of his or her teeth. DO NOT rinse the teeth with water.

7. Dispense more whitening gel into the mixing lid and Step C: #3 and Steps D: #1-6 twice, for a total of three cycles of 20 minutes; each time removing and reapplying fresh whitening gel to the teeth in between cycles.

STEP E - TREATMENT WRAP-UP

1. After the final cycle, move the lamp head and have the client wipe off the whitening gel from the surface of his or her teeth. (FIGURE K)

2. Ask them to remove the cheek retractor and protective eyewear and to rinse his or her mouth well.

STEP F - POST-TREATMENT

1. Use the included shade guide to show the client the change in his or her tooth color. Mark the client&apos;s post-treatment shade on the card and give to them to take home. (FIGURE L)

2. After the procedure, give the client a Post-Whitening Care Instruction Card and BEYOND™Pearl White Toothpaste. Make sure that the client understands the post-treatment guidelines.
   
IMPORTANT POINTS TO NOTE

•Pregnant or lactating women or persons under the age of 16 are not recommended to undergo the procedure.

•Terminate the whitening procedure if any client reports severe tooth sensitivity and remove all whitening gel. NOTE: Within the 24 hours after the procedure, clients should avoid colored food and drinks. Use of tobacco products should be limited.
   
CONTRAINDICATIONS

•BEYOND™WhiteSpa Select Whitening Gel is contraindicated for clients with known allergy or chemical sensitivity to peroxides or glycols.
   
FOR BEST RESULTS

The recommended initial treatment schedule is three, 20 minute applications of the whitening gel. If additional whitening results are desired (i.e. for more severe stains caused by tetracycline or fluoride), an additional 20 minute session can be performed 24 hours later, or the treatment can be split over two days. (2 x 20 minutes on day one, 2 x 20 minutes on day two) There is enough whitening gel in the BEYOND™WhiteSpa Select Whitening Gel syringe for four, 20 minute applications.
   
SPECIAL NOTES

•Advise the client that it is safe to swallow his or her saliva during the treatment.

•If the whitening paste or gel comes into contact with the client&apos;s gums during the treatment, the pink tissue may turn white during the treatment. This will fade in a few hours following the treatment and is not cause for concern.

•Depending on the client&apos;s diet, oral hygiene, and use of tobacco products, periodic touch¬up treatments may be necessary to maintain his or her new, white smile.
   
STORAGE AND MAINTENANCE

•Store all items in a cool, dry place. Avoid exposure to direct sunlight.

•BEYOND™WhiteSpa Select Whitening Gel syringes must be stored near 5°C. These syringes are packed separately for easy storage in the refrigerator. Do not use if the following conditions are present:

•There is gel leakage evident.

•The gel is no longer viscous and has become liquid or runny.

•Syringe plunger is being pushed out of the syringe body.

It is recommended that any partially used whitening gel be stored in the refrigerator to preserve the effectiveness of the whitening gel formula. Simply remove the mixing tip and replace the syringe cap. Store the remaining gel in the refrigerator until ready to use. Please note that a new mixing tip will need to be used. Extra tips can be purchased from BEYOND™.
   
PRECAUTIONS AND WARNINGS

The BEYOND™WhiteSpa Select Whitening Gel contains 6% hydrogen peroxide. Keep out of reach of children. If accidentally swallowed, get medical help or contact a Poison Control Center right away. If this product comes into contact with skin or eyes, rinse immediately with water and seek medical attention.
   
NOTES CONCERNING SYSTEM ACTIVATION

Each BEYOND™WhiteSpa Select Five Client Treatment Pack comes with five, 60 minute System Activation Cards and one, 5 x 20 minute System Activation Card for Touch-ups. The 60 minute, System Activation Cards are designed to be used for the standard, three x 20 minutes applications treatment schedule. Simply hold the card over the activation sensor to load the minutes into the system and begin the treatment.

•When activated, the entire 60 minutes from the System Activation Card are loaded into the system.

•You cannot load more than 60 minutes into the machine at one time.

•Once added, the minutes must be run through the system. The minutes cannot be re¬added to the card.

•If system is turned off or loses power, leftover minutes will be stored in the machine until used.

The 5 x 20 minute, System Activation Card for Touch-ups contains an additional five, 20 minute treatments that can be added to the accelerator in individual 20 minute segments. This card is designed to be used for touch-up treatments or for those clients with more severe stains who require an additional 20 minutes on top of the standard, 60 minute treatment. Simply hold the card over the activation sensor to load the 20 minutes into the system and begin the treatment. Keep track of the minutes used by marking the back of the card. NOTE: Additional minutes from the 5 x 20 minute System Activation Card for Touch-ups can only be added when there are less than 20 minutes left of the total remaining treatment time.
   
OTHER REMINDERS AND PRECAUTIONS

1. For some clients, especially those with teeth speckled with fluoride, the whitening may not look completely even following the treatment. Under close inspection, there may be small spots on the teeth that are lighter or darker than other parts of the tooth. The whitening gel will continue to penetrate and the teeth will obtain a more even whiteness and shine after 24 hours. This is due to the many layers in the structure of the teeth. Ask the client to be patient and wait for the full effect to appear.

2. If the client has visible cracks in his or her teeth, he or she should not undergo the treatment. If sensitivity is noticed during the treatment, the treatment should be stopped immediately to avoid continued discomfort.

3. Teeth with medium to severe tetracycline stains, other antibiotic stains, or teeth speckled by fluoride may see a slight&quot;rebound&quot;or loss of some of the whitening results (one to two shades) in the 48 hours following the first treatment. The improvement in color will be stable after a second treatment.
  of     
 
 Pearl White Advanced
Formula Whitening
Toothpaste with Fluoride 
-- $15.95
 
 Pearl White Sensitivity
Formula Whitening
Toothpaste with Fluoride 
-- $15.95
 
 e-Bright Tooth
Whitening Accelerator
Home Edition 
-- $125.00
 
 Xspand Dental Floss 
-- $5.95
 
 
 
 Restoring Whitening
Mouthwash 
-- $5.80
 
 Antiseptic Mouthwash 
-- $5.80
 
 Mouthwash for Kids 
-- $5.80
 
 e-Bright Refill 
-- $25.00
 
 become a distributor Copyright © BEYOND Dental&amp;Health Inc. ALL RIGHTS RESERVED.
	</body>
</document>
