<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001986" url="http://72.52.208.92/~gbpprorg/obama/ObamaACORN.html" time="2012-07-12-17:54" support="1" score="0.00025090094087993074" bingtitle="Barack Obama and ACORN" webtitle="Barack Obama and ACORN">
			<query id="001426" bing-rank="243"/>
	<description>... Indianans, and even the name of a fast food restaurant. ... The Census is used to apportion the seats in the U ... So, certainly that’s our goal to count every ...</description>
	<body>
		ACORN
  
 
 
 
 

 &quot;I&apos;ve been 
 fighting alongside ACORN on issues you care about my entire 
 career.&quot;

Barack Hussein Obama
  
 
 
 
 

 click 
 here 
 the bumper sticker 

  
 
  
 
 
 y ear 
 e vent Note: This page is in mixed order -- there&apos;s some 
 chronological stuff and other items are in order of discovery. Obama 
 &apos;s 
 ACORN 

 
 ACORN will shape my agenda  (02:36)
 
The same ACORN that is continually in trouble for voter fraud, the same ACORN 
that has pushed the subprime mortgage crisis that has destabilized our economy, 
is, in the words of Barack Obama, going to shape our national agenda.

Stanley Kurtz asks if Barack Obamas most important radical connection has been hiding in 
plain sight all along? Obama has had an intimate and long-term association 
with the Association of Community Organizations for Reform Now (ACORN), the 
largest radical group in America. If I told you Obama had close ties with 
MoveOn.org or Code Pink, youd know what I was talking about. ACORN is at 
least as radical as these better-known groups, arguably more so. Yet 
because ACORN works locally, in carefully selected urban areas, its national 
profile is lower. ACORN likes it that way. And so, Id wager, does Barack 
Obama. 
 The Association of Community Organizations for Reform Now ( ACORN ), 
 describes itself as a community-based organization that advocates 
 for low and moderate income families by working on neighborhood safety, 
 health care and other social issues.

ACORN has over 350,000 members and more than 850 neighborhood chapters 
 in over 100 cities across the United States, as well as in Argentina, 
 Canada, Mexico, and Peru. ACORN was founded in 1970 by Wade Rathke 
 and Gary Delgado. Maude Hurd has been National President of ACORN 
 since 1990.

ACORN agitates for better housing and wages for the poor, more community 
 development investment from banks and governments, and better public 
 schools. ACORN pursues these goals through intimidation, 
 demonstration, negotiation, legislation, and voter participation. They do the Alinsky.

ACORN is made up of several legally distinct parts including local 
 non-profits, a national lobbying organization and the ACORN Housing 
 Corporation. ACORN lies when it says it is non-partisan, and 
 always aligned with the Democratic Party on policy.

ACORN is again up to its eyeballs if a formal program of voter 
 registration fraud in 
 their registration programs in a dozen battleground states, but in this 
 election cycle, to a degree never before seen. This year, its 
 voter registration efforts that have resulted in criminal investigations 
 in a dozen states. 
 ACORN&apos;s real genius is getting American taxpayers to foot the bill. According to a 2006 report from the Employment Policies Institute (EPI), 
 ACORN has been on the federal take since 1977. For instance, 
 ACORN&apos;s American Institute for Social Justice claimed $240,000 in tax 
 money between fiscal years 2002 and 2003. Its American 
 Environmental Justice Project received 100% of its revenue from 
 government grants in the same years. EPI estimates the ACORN 
 Housing Corporation alone received some $16 million in federal dollars 
 from 1997-2007. Only recently, Democrats tried and failed to stuff 
 an&quot;affordable housing&quot;provision into the $700 billion bank rescue 
 package that would have let politicians give even more to ACORN.

All this money gives ACORN the ability to pursue its other great hobby: 
 electing liberals. ACORN is spending $16 million this year to 
 register new Democrats and is already boasting it has put 1.3 million 
 new voters on the rolls. The big question is how many of these 
 registrations are real. 
 
 ACORNs&quot;Communist Manifesto&quot; 

As a public service here is a copy of ACORNs so-called Peoples Platform , via the Internet Archives Wayback Machine.

As is noted, this version was updated in 1990, which is just two years 
 before Mr. Obama began to work for them via Project Vote and as a 
 trainer for the&quot;power&quot;seminars.
 

 


The Peoples Platform was conceived at ACORNs 1978 Memphis Convention 
 and ratified at the 1979 St. Louis Convention. In 1990, in celebration 
 of ACORNs twentieth anniversary, ACORN members around the country met 
 in order to revise and update the platform. The resulting document was 
 approved by the Executive Committee of the Association board and 
 ratified by acclamation at the 1990 Chicago Convention.

 Peoples Platform Preamble 

We stand for a Peoples Platform, as old as our country, and as young as 
 our dreams. We come before our nation, not to petition with hat in hand, 
 but to rise as one people and demand.

We have waited and watched. We have hoped and helped. We have sweated 
 and suffered. We have often believed. We have frequently followed.

But we have nothing to show for the work of our hand, the tax of our 
 labor. Our patience has been abused; our experience misused. Our silence 
 has been seen as support. Our struggle has been ignored.

Enough is enough. We will wait no longer for the crumbs at Americas 
 door. We will not be meek, but mighty. We will not starve on past 
 promises, but feast on future dreams.

We are an uncommon people. We are the majority, forged from all 
 minorities. We are the masses of many, not the forces of few. We will 
 continue our fight until the American way is just one way, until we have 
 shared the wealth, until we have won our freedom.

This is not a simple vision, but a detailed plan.

Our plan is to build an American reality from the American rhetoric, to 
 deliver a piece of the present and the fruits of the future to every 
 man, to every woman, to every family.

We demand our birthright: the chance to be rich, the right to be free.

Read the rest here . . . . Buycks
Roberson
v
Citibank 
Obama in his own words clearly acknowledged his close 
 association with ACORN, his acceptance of ACORN&apos;s radical methodology 
 and his appreciation for the support of the organization in his run for 
 the presidency.

 

 ACORN also played an instrumental role in urging 
 lenders to extend home mortgages to subprime borrowers, pushing charges 
 against banks in the 1980s that their home lending practices amounted to&quot;red-lining,&quot;in violation of the 1977 Community Reinvestment Act, 
 according to a report published by Stan 
 Liebowitz in the New York Post. 

   

 In 1994, lawyer Obama, a graduate of 
 Harvard Law School then fresh from his Project Vote! experience, represented ACORN in the Buycks-Roberson v. Citibank Federal Savings 
 Bank case, in which ACORN pressed for Citibank to make more loans to 
 marginally qualified African-American applicants&quot;in a race neutral 
 way.&quot; 

   

 After obtaining a settlement in the Citibank litigation , ACORN used its 
 subsidiary organization ACORN Housing , a nationwide 
 organization with offices in more than 30 U.S. cities, to push the 
 group&apos;s radical agenda to get subprime home buyers mortgages under the 
 most favorable terms possible. 

 

The meltdown in subprime home mortgages has been 
 widely regarded as a major contributing cause of the current recession 
 that officially began in December 2008 after two consecutive quarters of 
 negative growth in gross domestic product, or GDP.
 

 During 2008, the Obama presidential campaign attempted 
 to distance the candidate from ACORN voter fraud by arguing that the 
 U.S. Department of Justice was on the same side of the Citibank case as 
 was lawyer Obama, reflecting the Clinton Administration&apos;s determination to expand 
 homeownership among the poor. 

   

 &quot;Barack Obama strongly condemns voter registration 
 fraud or any other breach of election law by any party or group,&quot;Ben 
 LaBolt, an Obama campaign spokesman, said in a statement,. as reported by the New York Times. 

   

 While the Obama administration&apos;s $787 economic 
 stimulus package did not funnel federal funds to ACORN by name, the bill 
 signed by the president included some $2 billion for 
 non-profit&quot;neighborhood stabilization&quot;non-governmental organizations. 
 Some of those funds could be allocated to ACORN to buy abandoned or 
 foreclosed homes in impoverished neighborhoods , with the intent 
 to rehabilitate them for resale or 
 rental. 
 
 
 Votes Pushed to meet daily quotas and bullied by bosses if they didn&apos;t, Ohio ACORN 
 workers faked voter registrations, signed up people more than once, and 
 even paid off registrants to keep from being fired, its canvassers told 
 The Post.

&quot;Every day, there was pressure on us. Every single day,&quot;said 
 Teshika Elder, a Cleveland single mom of three who worked for ACORN this 
 summer.

&quot;We had meetings every morning where they&apos;d go over your quota; they&apos;d 
 yell at you if you were low,&quot;said Elder, 21. &quot;They&apos;d sit us down 
 and say if you didn&apos;t do better, they&apos;d suspend you. They&apos;d say, 
 &apos;Try harder next time,&apos; [and] if you didn&apos;t get it, you&apos;d be fired.&quot;

Desperate canvassers sometimes resorted to trading cigarettes, cash and 
 food in exchange for registrations, according to Elder and two other 
 former ACORN workers, Jaymes Sanford, 18, and Selvin Cunningham, 23.

Some voters were signed up more than once, and said that worried -- or 
 lazy -- canvassers sometimes filled out bogus cards.

The three workers were all fired after they and a dozen other canvassers 
 were identified in a Cuyahoga County Election Board probe as having 
 turned in multiple registrations for the same voters.

The board, which estimates it got more than 8,700 suspect cards -- with 
 multiple registrations, bad addresses or phony information -- from ACORN 
 has turned the matter over to local prosecutors.

&quot;It was just little stuff -- a dollar, a cigarette -- given to people so 
 that they&apos;d register,&quot;said Sanford, a former team leader.

&quot;People are scared of not making their quotas,&quot;he said. &quot;I didn&apos;t 
 do it, but it&apos;s the way it worked.&quot; Obama 
 &apos;s 
 ACORN ACORN voter fraud is so flagrant, that even ABC 
 News has to report what Obama&apos;s old associates are up to, and when Obama denies 
 this relationship, or calls it a distraction, which he will, remember this quote :

&quot;Ive been fighting alongside ACORN on issues you care about my entire 
 career. Even before I was an elected official, when I ran Project 
 Vote voter registration drive in Illinois, ACORN was smack dab in the 
 middle of it, and we appreciate your work.&quot;-- Barack Obama, Speech to 
 ACORN, November 2007


Not only that, but Obama, who has publicly endorsed ACORN, paid them at least $800,000 for its voter registration efforts -- Obama paid for the voter registration fraud. 

Obama&apos;s association with ACORN goes wayyy back. He was ACORN&apos;s attorney in the&quot;Motor Voter&quot;case. He was also deeply 
 involved in organizing&quot;Project VOTE&quot;in 
 1992. All of these activities had a single purpose -- to destroy 
 the integrity of the voting system, and Obama has been at it for years, 
 and years.

Obamas long relationship to ACORN has led many of its members to serve as 
 the volunteer shock troops of Obamas political campaigns. 
 Obama 
 &apos;s 
 ACORN Investors Business Daily asks what Obama knows about the epidemic of voter fraud in ACORN, 
 and its not an unfair question. Not only has he publicly endorsed 
 ACORN, Obama has paid them at least $800,000 for their voter fraud 
 services , an amount that he didnt immediately disclose until 
 pressed.

Obama paid ACORN, which has endorsed him for president, 
 $800,000 to register new voters, payments his campaign failed to 
 accurately report. They were disguised in his FEC disclosure as 
 payments to a front group called Citizen Services Inc. for&quot;advance 
 work.&quot;

The campaign initially told the Federal Election Commission this money 
 was for&quot;staging, sound, lighting.&quot; It later admitted the cash was 
 to get out the vote. ACORN has responded in kind, with their 
 voter-registration efforts that have resulted in criminal investigations 
 in more than a dozen states. Obama,
Ayers and
ACORN 
 
 ACORN 
 &apos;s 
 Obama Audacity of Hypocrisy reports  that w hile 
 Obamas connection with the ACORN has not gone entirely unreported, it 
 has not been fully explained. Most media background pieces simply 
 note Obamas involvement in a 1995 lawsuit on behalf of ACORN. Obamas own website, as well as most major media, fail to reveal the 
 full depth and extent of his relationship with the organization.

Attempts to hide evidence of Obamas involvement with ACORN have 
 included wiping the web clean of potentially damaging articles that had 
 appeared, and were previously publicly accessible. Unfortunately, 
 those behind the attempted cover-up failed to realize that in todays 
 day and age, nothing disappears forever. There also exists another 
 layer of the web, the hidden web, which is full of information included 
 in proprietary scholarly databases where these very same&quot;missing&quot;articles can be easily uncovered.

Obamas campaign website states:

Fact: Barack was never an ACORN trainer and never worked for ACORN in 
 any other capacity.

Is that really a FACT, or just another lie? Lets take a look at a 
 quote from a 2004 article -- Case Study: Chicago -- The Barack Obama 
 Campaign -- written Toni Foulkes, a Chicago ACORN Leader, which was published in 
 the journal Social Policy. Did we mention that Social Policy 
 recently pulled this particular article from their website, while 
 leaving links to all articles up?

&quot;Obama took the case, known as ACORN vs. Edgar (the name of the 
 Republican governor at the time) and we won. Obama then went on to 
 run a voter registration project with Project VOTE in 1992 that made it 
 possible for Carol Moseley Braun to win the Senate that year. Project VOTE delivered 50,000 newly registered voters in that campaign 
 (ACORN delivered about 5,000 of them).

Since then, we have invited Obama to our leadership training sessions to 
 run the session on power every year, and, as a result, many of our newly 
 developing leaders got to know him before he ever ran for office. Thus it was natural for many of us to be active volunteers in his first 
 campaign for State Senate and then his failed bid for U.S. Congress in 
 1996. By the time he ran for U.S. Senate, we were old friends.&quot;

 


Not only does Foulkes boast of Obamas ACORN leadership training, but 
 also makes it clear that Obamas post-law school organizing of&quot;Project 
 VOTE&quot;in 1992 was undertaken in direct partnership with ACORN. The 
 tie between Project VOTE and ACORN is also something that Obama and 
 others have attempted to disprove in recent weeks as ACORN has come 
 under fire for allegations of voter registration fraud.

As recently as March 2008, the Los Angeles Times also made reference to 
 Barack Obamas involvement with ACORN:

&quot;At the time, Talbot worked at the social action group ACORN and 
 initially considered Obama a competitor. But she became so 
 impressed with his work that she invited him to help train her staff.&quot;(LA Times, March 2, 2008)

Here&apos;s another view of Obama conducting leadership training seminars for the ACORN shakedown artists! Project
Vote Obama worked as executive director of ACORNs 
 voter-registration arm, Project Vote, in 1992. Joined by two other 
 community organizers on Chicagos South Side, Obama conducted the 
 voter-registration drive that helped elect Carol Moseley-Braun to the 
 Senate that year.

The next year, 1993, Obama joined the civil-rights law firm Davis Miner 
 Barnhill&amp;Galland, where he sued the state of Illinois on behalf of 
 ACORN to implement the federal&quot;Motor Voter&quot;law, which the GOP governor 
 at the time refused to do. Then-Gov. Jim Edgar argued, 
 presciently, that the Clinton law would invite voter fraud.

Obama downplays his ties to ACORN, and his campaign denies coordinating 
 with ACORN to register voters.

For a man with a short track record, Barack Obama spends a lot of time 
 disassociating himself from political partners. He spent most of 
 the campaign misrepresenting his years-long working relationship with 
 William Ayers, the unrepentant domestic terrorist of the Weather 
 Underground and a man who still wants the overthrow of the capitalist 
 economic system in the US. Now he wants to hide his work over two 
 decades with an organization that should be looking at the business end 
 of a federal RICO prosecution.

ACORN admits Project Vote is part of ACORN and Michelle Malkin outlines the scope of their criminal behavior.

In 1992, Senator Obama served as Illinois Executive Director of PROJECT VOTE!, an effort that added 
 over 100,000 newly registered voters in Illinois. He later 
 received the 1995 Legal Eagle Award from IVI-IPO for his work in 
 bringing Illinois into compliance with the National Voter Registration 
 Act (Motor-Voter).

By 2001, Obama was on the board of several organizations including the 
 Chicago Annenberg Challenge, where he was chairman, the Joyce 
 Foundation, the Woods Fund of Chicago, the Center for Neighborhood 
 Technology, the Chicago Lawyers Committee for Civil Rights Under the 
 Law, and Public Allies. Project
Vote FrontPage magazine&apos;s&quot; Discover 
 the Networks &quot;has the 411 on Project Vote. 

 Project Vote is the 
 voter-mobilization arm of ACORN . It is a 501(c)(3) non-profit organization whose professed 
 purpose is to carry out&quot;non-partisan&quot;voter registration drives; to 
 counsel voters on their rights; and to litigate on behalf of voting 
 rights -- focusing on the rights of the poor and the&quot;disenfranchised.&quot; 

Project Vote&apos;s major program 
 areas include the following:

 Voter Participation Program : &quot;[Since its 
 inception], Project Vote has helped 
 more than 4 million Americans in low-income and minority neighborhoods 
 register to vote, including 1.1 million in 2003-04. In the same period, 
 Project Vote reached more than 2.3 million low-income and minorit y 
 voters to educate them about the importance of voting. Our 
 methodology is based on face-to-face contact between voters and trusted 
 community messengers, generally a representative of a local community 
 organization.&quot;

 Election 
 Administration Program : &quot;[This program] 
 encompasses every aspect of election implementation, from voter 
 registration application design to voting booth placement to vote 
 counting and everything in between. Working in neighborhoods 
 nationwide, Project Vote documents voting problems and works closely 
 with elections officials, secretaries of state, and state legislators to 
 enact proactive, pragmatic solutions. A central component of our 
 work is the inclusion of low-income and minority voters through the 
 involvement of our community partners.&quot;

 NVRA Implementation Project : &quot;[This] 
 partnership between Project Vote, ACORN and Demos aims to improve voter 
 registration services at public assistance agencies. Section 7 of the 
 National Voter Registration Act of 1993 requires states to offer voter 
 registration to public assistance clients upon application, 
 recertification or renewal, and change of addresses. The Project 
 ... offers technical assistance.&quot; The National Voting Rights Institute 
 and the Lawyers Committee 
 for Civil Rights Under Law have recently become co-administrators of 
 this initiative. 

The stated purpose of Project Vote is to work within the system, using 
 conventional voter mobilization drives and litigation to secure the 
 rights of minority and low-income voters under the U.S. Constitution. However, the organization&apos;s actions indicate that its true agenda is to 
 overwhelm, paralyze, and discredit the voting system through fraud, 
 protests, propaganda and vexatious litigation. In this respect, 
 Project Vote is following the so-called&quot;crisis strategy&quot;or Cloward-Piven Strategy pioneered during the Sixties by Columbia University political scientists Richard Cloward and Frances 
 Fox Piven.

As a follow-up to their effort to collapse the welfare system in the 
 1960s, in 1983 Cloward and Piven founded the Human Service Employee 
 Registration, Voting and Education campaign Fund (Human SERVE Fund). Its objective, they said, was to increase voter turnout among the poor. But unlike Project Vote, Human SERVE did not rely on conventional 
 door-to-door canvassing, or even on the more effective method of 
 registering people in food stamp and unemployment lines which Project 
 Vote had pioneered. Rather, Human SERVE lobbied government 
 officials directly to enact laws and regulations directing public 
 employees to offer to register citizens applying for services at 
 government agencies. This effort realized its grandest ambition on 
 May 20, 1993, when President Clinton signed the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 -- 
 commonly called the&quot;Motor-Voter Act.&quot; It ordered every state to 
 provide resources enabling people to register to vote at state agencies, 
 at the same time they applied for drivers&apos; licenses, welfare, Medicaid 
 and disability benefits. In June 2000, Cloward and Piven dissolved 
 Human SERVE, leaving to ACORN and Project Vote the task of making the Motor Voter&quot;crisis strategy&quot;work at the polls. It did, in fact, fuel an explosion of fraudulent voters .

In 1996, Project Vote became involved in Teamstergate -- a 
 criminal conspiracy to embezzle funds from the Teamster treasury, 
 launder them through outside organizations, and then siphon them back 
 into the re-election war chest of Teamsters President Ron Carey in 1996. According to trial testimony, the operation was approved by high-level 
 White House and Democratic Party officials.

A persistent pattern of lawlessness has followed ACORN/Project Vote 
 activists over the years. For example, one Project Vote contractor 
 -- a single mother of three -- forged 400 voter registration cards in 
 1998. &quot;Some of the addresses listed on these applications were 
 traced to vacant lots, boarded-up buildings, abandoned buildings, and 
 nonexistent house numbers,&quot;notes a report by the 
 Employment Policies Institute. Former Miami-Dade field director for 
 ACORN&apos;s 2004 voter mobilization Mac Stuart has testified that fraud is 
 standard procedure for ACORN/Project Vote canvassers -- behavior that is 
 not only tolerated but encouraged by supervisors. &quot;[T]he voter 
 registration project has been operating illegally since it started,&quot;Stuart told investigators.

In the 2004 election cycle, ACORN and Project Vote canvassers fanned out 
 by the thousands across battleground states, turning up repeatedly in 
 press reports and on police blotters in connection with fraudulent 
 petitioning and voter registration. Canvassers were caught or 
 accused of filing registrations in duplicate, filing them for deceased 
 or imaginary people or, in some cases, destroying large numbers of 
 Republican registrations. Obama 
 &apos;s 
 ACORN This video shows Obama at a December 2007 community organizer forum. He says that he will invite ACORN to&quot;shape the agenda&quot;during the 
 transition period and he will allow them to be actively involved during 
 the first 100 days of his administration.

Got that?

The people who helped facilitate the mortgage mess and the people who 
 have been engaging in voter fraud for years will play a direct role in 
 an Obama Administration. Stealing
CT The State Elections Enforcement Commission has opened an investigation into allegations that a community activist 
 organization submitted at least 10 false voter-registration cards in 
 Bridgeport.

One of the phony registrations was for a 7-year-old girl in the Marina 
 Village housing complex, whose age was listed as 27 on the voter card.

Another registration came from a man who later said he couldnt have 
 completed the voter card purported to be his because he was in jail on 
 the date of the document.

Joseph J. Borges, the citys Republican registrar of voters, filed the 
 complaint with state officials after months of local complaints on the 
 tactics that ACORN, the Association of Community Organizations for 
 Reform Now, was regularly filing applications that were ruled 
 ineligible.

In response, a Bridgeport leader of ACORN on Tuesday night called the 
 charges&quot;part of a concerted and coordinated campaign by conservatives 
 and the GOP to attack and discredit ACORN.&quot; Stealing
IA New voter registrations closed Monday in Lake County with possible 
 record-breaking numbers and simmering allegations of fraud and racial discrimination .

Elections board Director Sally LaSota said more than 12,000 voter 
 registration forms are waiting to be processed from recent days before 
 the county knows how many potential voters are ready to cast ballots in 
 the Nov. 4 general election.

&quot;It may be a record,&quot;she said.

Porter County has processed at least 3,500 voter applications since the 
 spring primary in May, officials there said.

However, the large influx has brought new controversies.

LaSota said Monday representatives of ACORN, dropped off 2,000 new voter 
 applications last week in Lake County.

&quot;About 1,100 are no good,&quot;she said.

This is one of those news stories you can hardly believe. In Lake County, Indiana, ACORN 
 turned in 5,000 new registrations. The authorities there started 
 reviewing them, and quit after they found that the first 2,100 were 
 all fraudulent . The mind boggles: ACORN turns in thousands of 
 new registrations, and not a single one represents a legitimate voter. ( video ) Stealing
MI The Michigan Secretary of State told the press in September that ACORN had submitted&quot;a sizeable 
 number of duplicate and fraudulent applications .&quot; Stealing
MO Officials in Missouri, a hard-fought jewel in the presidential race, 
 are sifting through possibly hundreds of questionable or duplicate 
 voter-registration forms submitted by an advocacy group that has been 
 accused of election fraud in other states.

Charlene Davis, co-director of the election board in Jackson County, 
 where Kansas City is, said the fraudulent registration forms came from 
 the Association of Community Organizations for Reform Now, or ACORN. She 
 said they were bogging down work Wednesday, the final day Missourians 
 could register to vote.

&quot;I dont even know the entire scope of it because registrations are 
 coming in so heavy,&quot;Davis said.&quot;We have identified about 100 
 duplicates, and probably 280 addresses that dont exist, people who have 
 drivers license numbers that wont verify or Social Security numbers 
 that wont verify. Some have no address at all.&quot;

The nonpartisan group works to recruit low-income voters, who tend to 
 lean Democratic. Most polls show Republican presidential candidate John 
 McCain with an edge in bellwether Missouri, but Democrat Barack Obama 
 continues to put up a strong fight.

Jess Ordower, Midwest director of ACORN, said his group hasnt done any 
 registrations in Kansas City since late August. He said he was told 
 three weeks ago by election officials that there were only about 135 
 questionable cards 85 of them duplicates.

&quot;They keep telling different people different things,&quot;he said.&quot;They 
 gave us a list of 130, then told someone else it was 1,000.&quot;

FBI spokeswoman Bridget Patton said the agency has been in contact with 
 elections officials about potential voter fraud and plans to 
 investigate. Stealing
NV Earlier this month, Nevada&apos;s Democratic Secretary of State Ross 
 Miller requested a raid on ACORN&apos;s offices, following complaints of false names and fictional addresses (including the 
 starting lineup of the Dallas Cowboys). Nevada&apos;s Clark County Registrar 
 of Voters Larry Lomax said he saw rampant fraud in 2,000 to 3,000 
 applications ACORN submitted weekly. Stealing
OH Teenager Freddie Johnson said he was offered smokes and dollar bills to 
 fill out voter registration cards.

And now the Cuyahoga County Elections Board has 73 
 cards with Johnson&apos;s name on them.

Johnson and another prolific registrant were 
 subpoenaed to testify at a meeting Monday as the 
 Elections Board continued its look at possible fraud 
 by ACORN, a national organization that tries to get 
 low- and moderate-income people to register. ACORN&apos;s methods have drawn interest in a number of 
 states this presidential election year.

Johnson, 19, said he mostly was trying to help ACORN 
 workers who begged him to sign up because they 
 needed to keep their jobs.

&quot;They&apos;d come up with a sob story why they needed the 
 signature,&quot;said Johnson, of Garfield Heights.

An initial review found that about 200,000 newly registered 
 voters reported information that did not match 
 motor-vehicle or Social Security records. Close to one in every three newly registered Ohio 
 voters will end up on court-ordered lists being sent 
 to county election boards because they have some 
 discrepancy in their records, an elections spokesman 
 said Wednesday.

ACORN leaders have acknowledged that workers paid by 
 the hour were given quotas to fill.  Stealing
PA A retired Pennsylvania Supreme Court Justice says that she is&quot;not 
 confident we can get a fair election&quot;in the state come November.

Justice Sandra Newman, accompanied by Dauphin County District Attorney 
 Edward Marsico and Pennsylvania Republican State Chairman Robert 
 Gleason, expressed her concerns at a Harrisburg press conference this 
 morning. A thick document replete with photo copies of phony 
 registrations and aerial shots of vacant lots used as&quot;addresses&quot;for&quot;voters&quot;was handed out to journalists.

Gleason was even more explicit.

&quot;Between March 23rd and October 1st, various groups, including ACORN, 
 submitted over 252,595 registrations to the Philadelphia County Election 
 Board&quot;with 57, 435 rejected for faulty information . &quot;Most of 
 these registrations were submitted by ACORN, and rejected due to fake 
 social security numbers, incorrect dates of birth, clearly fraudulent 
 signatures, addresses that do not exist, and duplicate registrations. In 
 one case, a man was registered to vote more than 15 times since the 
 Primary election.&quot;

According to city officials , close to 8,000 applications turned in by ACORN are 
 problematic, including the 1,500 already sent to the U.S. Attorney, and 
 officials expect the number to climb. Greg Voigt says so far his 
 office is catching them, making sure no bad registrations lead to bad 
 votes, but admits he has limited staff.

ACORN has said it is actually identifying these problematic 
 registrations in advance and trying to notify authorities. In 
 Philadelphia, ACORN said it flagged, I guess, 5,000 applications before 
 the officials found them.

Not according to the city officials, not true. Officials say that 
 ACORN came in with a bundle of 1,100 that they thought were suspect. Actually, it turned out a couple of hundred of them were actually good 
 voter registration cards that they processed and sent voter cards out 
 to. So, there are a lot of disparities between the number that 
 ACORN is getting and what city officials checking the actual records are 
 getting, and that number is only going to grow as they continue to 
 process more of these for this election.

&quot;Voter fraud is no longer just a Philadelphia problem,&quot;Gleason said, 
 with ACORN targeting key counties across the state. Counties 
 specifically cited included:

More here . . . Stealing
WI Milwaukee County prosecutors Tuesday charged a convicted felon with illegally registering himself and 
 others to vote between his conviction and his sentencing.

The complaint accuses Adam Mucklin, 22, of registering to vote in June, 
 after he was convicted of battery in April, and after a judge told him 
 he couldnt vote as a convicted felon. Later in June, Mucklin signed up 
 to work as a paid voter registrar for the Community Voters Project, 
 something else he couldnt do as a convicted felon, the complaint says.

A recent opinion from the staff of the state Government Accountability 
 Board says no one convicted of a felony can ever serve as a registrar, a 
 stricter standard than the previous interpretation that registrars only 
 had to be eligible to vote.

Under Wisconsin law, felons cant vote until after they have completed 
 their sentences and are off probation or parole. For Mucklin, that would 
 not be until Jan. 10, 2012, the complaint notes. 
 Obamas most important radical connection has been hiding in plain sight all 
 along?

Stanley Kurtz provides an in-depth report, showing Obama&apos;s intimate and 
 long-term association with the Association of Community Organizations 
 for Reform Now (ACORN), the largest radical group in America.

If I told you Obama had close ties with MoveOn.org or Code Pink, youd 
 know what I was talking about. ACORN is at least as radical as 
 these better-known groups, arguably more so. Yet because ACORN 
 works locally, in carefully selected urban areas, its national profile 
 is lower. ACORN likes it that way. And so, Id wager, does 
 Barack Obama.

To understand the nature and extent of ACORNs radicalism, an excellent 
 place to begin is Sol Sterns 2003 City Journal article,&quot; ACORNs 
 Nutty Regime for Cities &quot;or for a shorter but helpful piece, try 
 Steven Malangas&quot; ACORN 
 Squash .&quot; Mortgage
Meltdown TO discover the roots of to day&apos;s economic crisis , consider a 
 tale from 1995.

That March, House Speaker Newt Gingrich was scheduled to address a 
 meeting of county commissioners at the Washington Hilton. But, first, 
 some 500 protesters from the Association of Community Organizations for 
 Reform Now (ACORN) poured into the ballroom from both the kitchen and 
 the main entrance.

Hotel staffers who tried to block them were quickly overwhelmed by 
 demonstrators chanting,&quot;Nuke Newt!&quot;and&quot;We want Newt!&quot;Jamming the 
 aisles, carrying bullhorns and taunting the assembled county 
 commissioners, demonstrators swiftly took over the head table and 
 commandeered the microphone, sending two members of Congress scurrying.

The demonstrators&apos; target, Gingrich, hadn&apos;t yet arrived -- and his 
 speech was cancelled. When the cancellation was announced, ACORN&apos;s foot 
 soldiers cheered.

Editorial writers from Little Rock to Buffalo condemned ACORN&apos;s action 
 as an affront to both civility and freedom of speech. Editorialists also 
 pointed out that the&quot;spending cuts&quot;the protesters railed against were 
 imaginary - Gingrich proposed merely to slow the growth in some welfare 
 programs and turn control back to the states.

Yet ACORN had only just begun. Two days later, 50 to 100 of the same 
 protesters hit their main target - a House Banking subcommittee 
 considering changes to the Community Reinvestment Act, a law that allows 
 groups like ACORN to force banks into making high-risk loans to 
 low-credit customers.

The CRA&apos;s ostensible purpose is to prevent banks from discriminating 
 against minorities. But Rep. Marge Roukema (R-NJ), who chaired the 
 subcommittee, was worried that charges of discrimination had become an 
 excuse for lowering credit standards. She warned that new, 
 Democrat-proposed CRA regulations could amount to an illegal quota 
 system.

 More . . . Buycks-
Roberson Sources point to Obama as a possible starting point 
 to the domino affect that lead to the housing crises we are now 
 facing. Check the provided links and judge for yourself.   &quot;In a 1995 case known as Buycks-Roberson v. Citibank , Obama and his fellow attorneys 
 charged that 
 Citibank was making too few loans to black applicants and won the case . As one commentator noted in May 2008, legal &quot;successes&quot; such 
 as this were probably responsible for the sub-prime mortgage crisis 
 of 2007 AND 2008. That is, banks were not loaning to blacks whose 
 credit was poor. When the law forced them to lend money anyway, the 
 inevitable collapse occurred.&quot;

 Buycks-Roberson v. Citibank Fed. Sav. Bank   Obamas Early Legal Career: Heavy on Advocacy for Blacks 
  A trillion here, a trillion there, pretty soon we&apos;re talking about 
 real money   Obama had a part in the lawsuit that started the 
 government on a course of forcing lenders to give more loans to 
 those who had poor credit. Lending companies were forced to 
 come up with imaginative ways of fulfilling the quota that was 
 required. Sub-prime lending was born as a result. The 
 mortgage crises was forecast by many who were able to look beyond 
 the quota. Mortgage
Meltdown Social Engineering or Affirmative Action Lending, whichever, it 
 is/was the shovel that dug the hole we now find our selves in. ( video ) Mortgage
Meltdown The Mortgage Meltdown? Yup, ACORN has had a hand in that, too.

 http://hotair.com/archives/2008/10/11/video-the-obligatory-obama-says-acorn-will-help-set-his-agenda-sort-of-clip/ 
 
From comments:
 

*The CCC had plenty to do with the subprime mortgage mess.
 

Heres an article from the former general counsel of the CCC that 
 you all might find interesting!
 

Why Fannie and Freddie should get into subprime lending
 

The author of this article served as Assistant Secretary of HUD 
 under Andrew Cuomo and wrote the first&quot;affordable housing goals&quot;for Fannie and Freddie that sowed the first seeds of the current 
 disaster. He worked for the CCC before and after he was at HUD.
 

 http://www.nhi.org/online/issues/125/goingsubprime.html 
 

And here is one example from an &apos;ACORN&apos; search of the CCC web 
 site of the overlap of CCC and ACORN:
 

Monday, Mar 10, 2008

Former Womens Union President Assumes New Managing Director 
 Position
 

Washington, DC- The Board and Staff of the Center for Community 
 Change is pleased to announce the appointment of Mary Lassen to the 
 new position of Managing Director of the organization. Ms. Lassen 
 has stepped down as the Board Chair of Center for Community Change 
 and assumed her new role March 10, 2008.
 

Ms. Lassen is an experienced community organizer working at 
 ACORN, where she served as Head Organizer in Missouri and Texas, and 
 at the Committee for Boston Public Housing. She also has significant 
 experience in local and state policy advocacy, partnership building, 
 and communications. For three decades, Ms. Lassen has had extensive 
 experience managing organizations, building teams, and developing 
 staff and leaders. She is the former President of The Womens Union 
 in Boston and served as Senior Fellow at the Boston Foundation where 
 she worked on strategies to improve education and economic 
 opportunities in Massachusetts community colleges.
 

 http://www.communitychange.org/press-room/press-releases/experienced-nonprofit-leader-joins-staff-of-major/?searchterm=None 
 

Check this out:
 

Clinton supporters sharing evidence for RICO case against Obama 
 campaign
 

 http://minx.cc/?post=275362 
 ACORN and Project Vote are being investigated for widespread electoral crimes in Americas closely contended states -- 
 potentially millions of fraudulent voter registrations and the destruction of those of Republican voters. The door is open 
 for fraudulent votes and election theft.
  
 They have driven intimidated citizens into early 
 voting, telling them how to vote.
  

 Obama has funneled $800,000 to ACORN for their 2008 General Election operations and 
 then lied about it.
  

 Obama organized Project Vote activities in Chicago, in 1992 and has trained ACORN operators.
  

 Obamas campaign in its Web site has tried to deny these facts.
  

 Obama as ACORNs lawyer, sued Illinois in 1993, to make voter registration laxer.
  

 Obama as ACORNs lawyer, sued Citibank in 1994 ( Buycks-Roberson case, above ) , 
 to force them into giving subprime loans to home buyers with poor credit 
 ratings, setting the stage for the mortgage meltdown.
  

 Obama promised in 2007 to let ACORN and related groups&quot; help 
 us shape the agenda &quot;of his presidency, by meeting with them after 
 the Nov. 4 election. What is their agenda? &quot;Helping low 
 income people?&quot; In some ways , at 
 least temporarily, but see below.
  

 ACORNs tactical plan is from Rules for Radicals , by the Marxist, Saul Alinsky . Synopsis: the ends justify the means -- 
 ridicule, lie, cheat -- be disruptive, or use stealth to gain power. Hold the virtuous to exaggerated and impossible standards, while not 
 playing by their rules. Sell&quot; change .&quot; And the result of that change is an enforced&quot;egalitarian&quot;( Marxist ) 
 society.
  

 OBAMA has taught these&quot;rules.&quot; He and Michelle Obama use Alinsky rhetoric.
  

 ACORN was started in the 1970s by radicals, George Wiley &amp; Wade Rathke , with input from sociologists, Richard A. Cloward and Frances Fox Piven -- all of neo-Marxist ideology.
  

 ACORN founders strategy has been the Cloward-Piven Strategy -- to overcommit government, growing it past 
 the point of sustainability by causing crises . This, while developing an organized 
 proletariat of dependent classes and applying them to disrupt society and revolt against American freedoms. All, to 
 ring in the new&quot;egalitarian&quot;( neo-Marxist ) 
 state. That would be a big&quot; change .&quot;
  

 Cloward&amp;Piven, plus ACORNs leaders pushed to greatly expand Americas welfare roles. But welfare reform in 
 the 1990&apos;s reversed that trend. Rudy Giuliani cited Cloward-Piven 
 for an&quot; economic 
 sabotage &quot;that lead to the 1975 bankruptcy of New York City.
  

 ACORN was a driving force for the revised Community Reinvestment Act of 1995, 
 pushing subprime mortgages through a very eager Fannie Mae. This allowed ACORN to pressure mortgagors to grant bad loans to bad risk homebuyers in the 
 name of helping the poor. Many of the poor were hurt further, while Fannie Mae prospered. Their personnel gave 
 Obamas campaign $126,349 . By contrast, John McCain attempted reform, but leftist congressmen shouted down reforms -- leftist congressmen now found in a cloud of scandal. 
  

 ACORN is associated with La Raza, pushing for open borders with government assistance.
  

 ACORN is funded in part by wealthy, anti-American radicals such as George Soros -- and by our tax dollars . Their Web site claims a membership of over 
 400,000. From
Little
Acorns The lines of evidence now converge: the founder of 
 ACORN was Wade Rathke, who, like William Ayers, was a member of the 
 Students for a Democratic Society. The Students for a Democratic 
 Society (SDS), the student organization founded in 1960 as part of the 
 New Left, was the gateway drug to the Weather Underground. In the 
 early sixties, many in the SDS reluctantly supported Lyndon Johnson for 
 president in 1964, and grainy black-and-white pictures show clean-cut 
 men and women registering southern blacks to vote. Tom Hayden was 
 amongst this group. But that was then.
  
 By 1969, their Great Society liberalism had been 
 co-opted by Marxists, Maoists, Spartacists, and other assorted 
 revolutionary groups. They were no longer interested in change, 
 but overthrowing the government. It was during this time that Wade 
 Rathke first came into contact with Bill Ayers.
  

 Much has been made of Obamas questionable judgment in 
 befriending and working closely with unrepentant terrorist William 
 Ayers. Regardless of what Obama says, his political career was 
 launched in Ayers home, Ayers served with him on Woods Fund, and 
 promoted him to head the Chicago Annenberg Challenge.
  

 The founder of ACORN, Wade Rathke, like Ayers, is a 
 disciple of Saul Alinsky. Working for ACORN was an important step 
 in Obamas political career.
  

 An article by Professor David Walls directly connects 
 Rathkes ACORN to Alinsky, ACORNs mission of pressuring banks to issue 
 risky mortgages, and the alliance between ACORN and unions:
  

 ACORN began in 1970 as a spin-off from the National 
 Welfare Rights Organization, founded by George Wiley, who enlisted civil 
 rights workers and trained them in an Alinsky-influenced program at 
 Syracuse University. From a base in Arkansas, Wade Rathke and Gary 
 Delgado developed a replicable model of forming membership organizations 
 and developing leaders in low-income neighborhoods -- relying 
 substantially on young middle-class staff working for subsistence wages. ACORN has established local housing corporations to rehabilitate homes, 
 and has successfully pressured banks to provide mortgages and home 
 improvement loans in low-income communities. ACORN has led&quot;living 
 wage&quot;campaigns in many cities, and has forged alliances with labor 
 unions.
  

 But ACORN isnt just Alinsky-inspired. Its a 
 direct off-shoot of his revolutionary agenda: 

 Around 1970 several national networks began to 
 coalesce and develop systematic and distinctive approaches to community 
 organizing. These include the Industrial Areas Foundation (IAF), 
 ACORN, Citizen Action, National Peoples Action, PICO, DART, and the 
 Gamaliel Foundation. Each was indebted, in greater or lesser 
 degree, to Alinsky and his early organizing programs in Chicago through 
 IAF.
  

 Citizen Action, mentioned above, is not&quot;officially&quot;connected to ACORN. But Citizen Action, like Rathkes ACORN and 
 Ayers radical education projects, was founded by another member of the 
 Alinsky-SDS milieu, Heather Booth. But its not just SDS and the 
 City of Chicago that binds this group. As the screen capture below 
 shows, Heather Booths husband was both a member of the SDS and 
 Alinskis [sic] Industrial Areas Foundation.
  

 See more to story check out http://noquarterusa.net/blog/2008/10/17/wade-rathke-acorns-founder-ayers-compatriot/#more-5509 Tom
Brokaw The moderator of the second presidential debate, Tom Brokaw, is involved with a George Soros-Funded Charity that funds ACORN.

Brokaw sits on the board of the Robin Hood Foundation, a charity that, 
 according to its website, targets poverty in New York City by applying&quot;sound investment principles to philanthropy.&quot; The foundation 
 awarded ACORN a $456,000 grant in 2003 and a $365,000 grant in 2004.

The Soros Fund Charitable Foundation, as in George Soros, a major 
 bankroller of the left, gave the Robin Hood Foundation a $9,859,453 
 community development grant in 2000.

The Robin Hood board includes Marian Wright Edelman, president of one of 
 Hillary Clinton&apos;s favorite activist groups, the Children&apos;s Defense Fund. Hollywood movie mogul Harvey Weinstein and actress Gwyneth Paltrow are 
 also members of the board.

As of Dec. 31, 2006, the Robin Hood Foundation had assets of 
 $288,520,098 and income of $159,688,394 (source: guidestar.org). Brokaw has given at least $75,000 to the foundation. (source:&quot;The 
 Emperors of Benevolence,&quot;New York Magazine, November 5, 2007) Tax
Status Georgia State Sen. Jeff Mullis, a Republican from Chickamauga, has 
 filed legislation urging the IRS to revoke the tax exempt status from the 
 Association of Community Organizations for Reform Now, more commonly 
 known as ACORN, after numerous reports that the organization falsified 
 voter records leading up to the 2008 elections.

&quot;An organization 
 that chooses to undermine the integrity of our nations election process 
 should not be entitled to tax exemption benefits,&quot;said Sen. Mullis. &quot;The excessive amount of evidence against ACORN engaging in fraudulent 
 activity demands that the organization to be held accountable for taking 
 advantage of hardworking taxpayers, and I call on the IRS to ensure that 
 justice is executed in this case.&quot; ACORN
To Get
$$$ On January 11th (below), 
 commenting on Obama stimulus plan, I sarcastically wrote,&quot;I can 
 understand 549,00 &apos;temporary programs&apos; jobs. The ACORN people will need 
 work now that they&apos;re not busy corrupting the election process.&quot;Yesterday, I read this :

Looks 
 like the infamous ACORN (Association of 
 Community Organizations for Reform Now) that was caught up in voter 
 fraud in 2008 will be in the running to get some funding (pages 72-73 of 
 the report.) The bill provides for $10 million for the SHOP 
 program. The funding will provide competitively awarded grants to 
 national and regional nonprofit housing organizations to develop or 
 rehabilitate low-income housing.

There is plenty of more funding 
 that will no doubt find its way to ACORN coffers like the $1 billion for 
 Community Development Block Grants or the $4.1 billion for the 
 Neighborhood Stabilization Program.

ACORN is working hard for 
 their money, this&quot;non-partisan&quot;organization is already campaigning for 
 the stimulus:

For three weeks now, ACORN members have been 
 aggressively pursuing a campaign to pass a bold, progressive Economic 
 Recovery package in the new Congress. Working closely with allies 
 like US Action, AFSCME, and the larger Americans United for Change 
 coalition, ACORN members are taking a major role in building the 
 coalition to pass this recovery package, and to create the context for 
 it to be both stronger and more directly responsive to the situation 
 facing working families across this country. ACORN and Obama: Together Again Michelle Malkin reports that Obama&apos;s old friends at the ACORN are launching a new campaign of their own: the&quot;Home Savers&quot;campaign. What a coinky-dinky, huh? As with most of the 
 bully tactics of the radical left-wing group, it ain&apos;t gonna be pretty. They are the shock troops on the streets doing the dirty work while the 
 Community Organizer-in-Chief keeps his delicate hands clean.

Trumpets ACORN:&quot;On Feb. 19, ACORN members will launch a new tactic in 
 fighting foreclosures: civil disobedience. Participants in the 
 ACORN Home Savers campaign nationwide will simply refuse to move out of 
 foreclosed homes, or in some cases, will move back in. ACORN 
 homesteaders intend to squat in their homes until a comprehensive, 
 federal solution for people facing foreclosure is put in place.&quot;

Right now, ACORN offices are training these teams of&quot;Home Savers&quot;-- 
 described as&quot;people ready and willing to mobilize on short notice to 
 defend the homesteaders against attempts to evict them.&quot; Yup, ready, willing and able to mobilize on short notice because they are 
 either unemployed or employed full time as ACORN shakedown artists.

ACORN&apos;s foot soldiers, funded with your tax dollars , 
 will scream, pound their fists, chain themselves to buildings, padlock 
 the doors and engage in illegal behavior until they get what they want. It&apos;s a recipe for anarchy. Threatens Baltimore ACORN&apos;s Louis 
 Beverly, who calls himself a&quot;Foreclosure Fighter&quot;:

&quot;After 
 you&apos;ve used all your legal options, your last resort is civil 
 disobedience. We&apos;re talking about families who have been in their 
 homes 20 or 30 years. People who are assets in the community, who 
 look out for the elderly, who have community associations, and these are 
 the people being kicked out of the community.&quot;

Guess who&apos;s 
 encouraging them to defy the law. Democratic Rep. Marcy Kaptur of Ohio, 
 who told them:&quot;Stay in your homes. If the American people, 
 anybody out there is being foreclosed, don&apos;t leave.&quot; The housing 
 bullies will be assisted by left-wing propaganda documentarians at the 
 Brave New Foundation, headed up by Hollywood lib Robert Greenwald, who 
 will disseminate sob stories to crank up pressure while Obama pushes his 
 housing entitlement plan.

ACORN is targeting the following 
 cities: Tucson, Ariz.; Oakland, Calif.; Los Angeles, Calif.; Contra 
 Costa County, Calif.; Orlando, Fla.; Baltimore, Md.; New York, N.Y.; 
 Houston, Texas; San Mateo County, Calif.; Denver, Colo.; Bridgeport, 
 Conn.; Wilmington, Del.; Broward County, Fla.; Boston, Mass.; Flint, 
 Mich.; Detroit, Mich.; Minneapolis, Minn.; Raleigh, N.C.; Durham, N.C.; 
 Albany, N.Y.; Cincinnati, Ohio; Cleveland, Ohio; Pittsburgh, Pa.; and 
 Dallas, Texas.

ACORN has waited three decades for this moment in 
 the sun. And as Obama promised ACORN members at a forum in 
 December 2007,&quot;We&apos;re going to be calling all of you in to help us shape 
 the agenda. We&apos;re gonna be having meetings all across the country so 
 that you have input into the agenda.&quot; The moment is nigh. Prepare for lawlessness.

 A 
 local TV crew was on hand for openly criminal activity by Obama&apos;s pals 
 at ACORN. ( VIDEO ) More
ACORN and Obama: Together Again &quot;ACORN and Obama: Together Again&quot;was posted on On 2/20/09, 
 below. It described how Obama&apos;s friends and associates in ACORN 
 planned to illegally seize foreclosed properties and contained a video 
 showing ACORN members breaking into a home.

Yesterday, Police in 
 Baltimore arrested an ACORN activist who now faces criminal charges for 
 breaking into a home in southeast Baltimore to protest the foreclosure 
 crisis sweeping the country.

&quot;This is our house now,&quot;ACORN 
 member Louis Beverly reportedly said after cutting a lock on the front 
 door with bolt cutters.

Beverly will be charged with 
 fourth-degree burglary, according to Anthony Guglielmi, a spokesman for 
 the Baltimore Police. Attempts to reach his attorney, Justin 
 Brown, were not immediately successful.

Elsewhere, Pittsburgh 
 Police Spokeswoman Diane Richard said charges would be filed against any 
 individual found living in a foreclosed home, whether that individual 
 had previously lived at the residence or not.

&quot;If someone is 
 court-ordered to vacate and they do not, it would be trespassing at that 
 point,&quot;Richard said.&quot;What exactly would be charged depends on the 
 intensity of the violation. It could go all the way up to burglary, 
 which is a felony.&quot;

 This video shows Obama at a December 2007 community organizer forum. He 
 says that he will invite ACORN to&quot;shape the agenda&quot;during the 
 transition period and he will allow them to be actively involved during 
 the first 100 days of his administration.

Well, ACORN is now 
 involved -- and so are the cops.

And, check out this video -- Stuart Varney -- chews up ACORN and spits it out. Youll recognize Bertha Lewis from her &quot;By Any Means Necessary &quot;article this weekend at the Huffington 
 Post. Obama&apos;s Crowd Michell Malkin comments on ACORNs shakedown artists and thugs who occupied a public 
 school board meeting room to prevent government educators from cutting 
 costs, firing useless teachers, and dealing with financial realities.

This is now the second&quot; civil 
 disobedience &quot;campaign waged by the entitlement-mongers.

Our 
 Community Organizer-in-Chief, who spoke so voluminously yesterday about 
 education reform, was unavailable for comment

A school board 
 meeting turned into a display of civil disobedience Tuesday as about 50 &quot;educators&quot; refused to leave, creating a brief standoff with 
 police, who refused to make any arrests in the presence of media.



 


The members of ACORN and United Teachers Los Angeles (UTLA) -- all 
 wearing bright&quot;red&quot;shirts -- entered the Los Angeles Unified School 
 District Board of Education meeting on Tuesday afternoon, sat down and 
 began chanting. The fist represents union, as&quot;many weak fingers 
 can come together to create a strong fist&quot;, and is also used to express 
 solidarity, generally with oppressed peoples.

Police said the protesters were staging an 
 illegal occupation of a public building. The district said no arrests 
 would occur as long as members of media were in building.

UTLA 
 President A.J. Duffy approached the speakers lectern and told the 
 board,&quot;You know why were here. You know Im not leaving this rostrum. 
 You know Im going to keep talking.&quot;

As he spoke several teachers 
 sat on the floor in front of the board and held up signs saying&quot;Students lose when we lose teachers, No layoffs&quot;as the crowd began 
 chanting.

Board President Monica Garcia repeatedly asked Duffy to 
 sit down, but he kept speaking. The microphone was turned off, but Duffy 
 continued to speak and the chanting continued. Garcia then announced 
 that the&quot;disturbance has interrupted our meeting to the point where the 
 orderly conduct of this meeting is not feasible.&quot; ACORN And The Census The U.S. Census is 
 supposed to be free of politics, but one group with a history of voter 
 fraud, ACORN, is participating in next year&apos;s count, raising concerns 
 about the politicization of the decennial survey.

The Association 
 of Community Organizations for Reform Now (ACORN) signed on as a 
 national partner with the U.S. Census Bureau in February 2009 to assist 
 with the recruitment of the 1.4 million temporary workers needed to go 
 door-to-door to count every person in the United States -- currently 
 believed to be more than 306 million people.

A U.S. Census&quot;sell 
 sheet,&quot;an advertisement used to recruit national partners, says 
 partnerships with groups like ACORN&quot;play an important role in making 
 the 2010 Census successful,&quot;including by&quot;help[ing] recruit census 
 workers.&quot;

The bureau is currently employing help from more than 
 250 national partners, including TARGET and the National Association for 
 the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), to assist in the hiring 
 effort.

But ACORN&apos;s partnership with the 2010 Census is worrisome 
 to lawmakers who say past allegations of fraud should raise concerns 
 about the organization.

And, remember, Rahm Emanuel is now in charge of the Census.

 We are soooooooo screwed! ACORN Is A Bad Seed RottenAcorn reminds us that 
 somethings rotten in the state of New Mexico, and Ohio, and Michigan, 
 and Pennsylvania, and Florida, and

ACORN says it is a community 
 group, but it is really a multi-million-dollar, multinational 
 conglomerate. Its political agenda is driven by a relative handful 
 of anti-corporate activists. ACORN spends millions of dollars to 
 promote economic policies (like raising the minimum wage), but has 
 admitted that it doesn&apos;t always want to abide by them. ACORN 
 advocates for workers&apos; rights and runs two unions, but has in the past 
 fought its own employees&apos; efforts to form a union.

ACORN&apos;s 
 history makes for pretty interesting reading. The Clinton 
 Administration found that ACORN was misspending government grants 
 designed to help counsel the poor. Although it seeks minimum wage 
 increases in cities and states across the country -- ACORN sued the 
 state of California to get out of paying its own employees the state 
 minimum wage.

ACORN&apos;s practices have corrupted our political 
 process as well. It has engaged in questionable election 
 activities for years -- stretching back even to the organization&apos;s 
 founding years in Arkansas. In recent years, as its political 
 power has increased, so have instances of fraud.

In the past few 
 years, it has been investigated for election fraud in at least a dozen 
 states:

AR 1998 A contractor with ACORN-affiliated Project Vote 
 was arrested for falsifying about 400 voter registration cards.

CO 2005 Two ex-ACORN employees were convicted in Denver of perjury for 
 submitting false voter registrations.

2004 An ACORN employee 
 admitted to forging signatures and registering three of her friends to 
 vote 40 times.

CT 2008 The New York Post reported that ACORN 
 submitted a voter registration card for a 7-year-old Bridgeport girl. 
 Another 8,000 cards from the same city will be scrutinized for possible 
 fraud.

FL 2008 Election officials in Brevard County have given 
 prosecutors more than 23 suspect registrations from ACORN. The state&apos;s 
 Division of Elections is also investigating complaints in Orange and 
 Broward Counties.

2004 A Florida Department of Law Enforcement 
 spokesman said ACORN was singled out among suspected voter 
 registration groups for a 2004 wage initiative because it was the 
 common thread in the agencys fraud investigations.

IN 2008 
 Election officials in Indiana have thrown out more than 4,000 
 ACORN-submitted voter registrations after finding they had identical 
 handwriting and included the names of many deceased Indianans, and even 
 the name of a fast food restaurant.

MI 2008 Clerks in Detroit 
 found a&quot;sizeable number of duplicate and fraudulent [voter] 
 applications&quot;from the Michigan branch of ACORN. Those applications have 
 been turned over to the U.S. Attorney&apos;s office for investigation.

2004 The Detroit Free Press reported that overzealous or 
 unscrupulous campaign workers in several Michigan counties are under 
 investigation for voter-registration fraud, suspected of attempting to 
 register nonexistent people or forging applications for 
 already-registered voters. ACORN-affiliate Project Vote was one of two 
 groups suspected of turning in the documents.

MO 2008 Nearly 400 
 ACORN-submitted registrations in Kansas City have been rejected due to 
 duplication or fake information.

2007 Four ACORN employees were 
 indicted in Kansas City for charges including identity theft and filing 
 false registrations during the 2006 election.

2006 Eight ACORN 
 employees in St. Louis were indicted on federal election fraud charges. 
 Each of the eight faces up to five years in prison for forging 
 signatures and submitting false information.

2003 Of 5,379 voter 
 registration cards ACORN submitted in St. Louis, only 2,013 of those 
 appeared to be valid. At least 1,000 are believed to be attempts to 
 register voters illegally.

MN 2004 During a traffic stop, police 
 found more than 300 voter registration cards in the trunk of a former 
 ACORN employee, who had violated a legal requirements that registration 
 cards be submitted to the Secretary of State within 10 days of being 
 filled out and signed.

NC 2008 County elections officials have 
 sent suspicious voter registration applications to the state Board of 
 Elections. Many of the applications had similar or identical names, but 
 with different addresses or dates of birth.

2004 North Carolina 
 officials investigated ACORN for submitting fake voter registration 
 cards.

NM 2008 Prosecutors are investigating more than 1,100 
 ACORN-submitted voter registration cards after a county clerk found them 
 to be fraudulent. Many of the cards included duplicate names and 
 slightly altered personal information.

2005 Four ACORN employees 
 submitted as many as 3,000 potentially fraudulent signatures on the 
 groups Albuquerque ballot initiative. A local sheriff added: Its safe 
 to say the forgery was widespread.

2004 An ACORN employee 
 registered a 13-year-old boy to vote. Citing this and other examples, 
 New Mexico State Representative Joe Thompson stated that ACORN was 
 manufacturing voters throughout New Mexico.

NV 2008 Nevada 
 state authorities raided ACORN&apos;s Las Vegas headquarters as part of a 
 task force investigation of election fraud. Fraudulent registrations 
 included players from the Dallas Cowboys.

OH 2008 ACORN 
 activists gave Ohio residents cash and cigarettes in exchange for 
 filling out voter registration card, according to the New York Post. 
 Some voters claim to have registered dozens of times, and one man says 
 he signed up on 72 cards.

2007 A man in Reynoldsburg was 
 indicted on two felony counts of illegal voting and false registration, 
 after being registered by ACORN to vote in two separate counties. 2004 A 
 grand jury indicted a Columbus ACORN worker for submitting a false 
 signature and false voter registration form. In Franklin County, two 
 ACORN workers submitted what the director of the board of election 
 supervisors called blatantly false forms. In Cuyahoga County, ACORN 
 and its affiliate Project Vote submitted registration cards that had the 
 highest rate of errors for any voter registration group.

PA 2008 
 State election officials have thrown out 57,435 voter registrations, the 
 majority of which were submitted by ACORN. The registrations were thrown 
 out after officials found&quot;clearly fraudulent&quot;signatures, vacant lots 
 listed as addresses, and other signs of fraud.

2008 An ACORN 
 employee in West Reading, PA, was sentenced to up to 23 months in prison 
 for identity theft and tampering with records. A second ACORN worker 
 pleaded not guilty to the same charges and is free on $10,000 bail. 2004 
 Readings Director of Elections received calls from numerous individuals 
 complaining that ACORN employees deliberately put inaccurate information 
 on their voter registration forms. The Berks County director of 
 elections said voter fraud was absolutely out of hand, and added: Not 
 only do we have unintentional duplication of voter registration but we 
 have blatant duplicate voter registrations. The Berks County deputy 
 director of elections added that ACORN was under investigation by the 
 Department of Justice.

TX 2008 In Harris County, nearly 10,000 
 ACORN-submitted registrations were found to be invalid, including many 
 with clearly fraudulent addresses or other personal information. 2008 
 ACORN turned in the voter registration form of David Young, who told 
 reporters The signature is not my signature. Its not even close. His 
 social security number and date of birth were also incorrect.

VA 
 2005 In 2005, the Virginia State Board of Elections admonished Project 
 Vote and ACORN for turning in a significant number of faulty voter 
 registrations. An audit revealed that 83% of sampled registrations that 
 were rejected for carrying false or questionable information were 
 submitted by Project Vote. Many of these registrations carried social 
 security numbers that exist for other people, listed non-existent or 
 commercial addresses, or were for convicted felons in violation of state 
 and federal election law.

In a letter to ACORN, the State Board 
 of Elections reported that 56% of the voter registration applications 
 ACORN turned in were ineligible. Further, a full 35% were not submitted 
 in a timely manner, as required by law. The State Board of Elections 
 also commented on what appeared to be evidence of intentional voter 
 fraud.&quot;Additionally, they wrote, information appears to have been 
 altered on some applications where information given by the applicant in 
 one color ink has been scratched through and re-entered in another color 
 ink. Any alteration of a voter registration application is a Class 5 
 Felony in accordance with 24.2-1009 of the Code of Virginia.&quot;

WA 2007 Three ACORN employees pleaded guilty, and four more were 
 charged, in the worst case of voter registration fraud in Washington 
 state history. More than 2,000 fraudulent voter registration cards were 
 submitted by the group during a voter registration drive.

WI 
 2008 At least 33,000 ACORN-submitted registrations in Milwaukee have 
 been called into question after it was found that the organizations had 
 been using felons as registration workers, in violation of state 
 election rules. Two people involved in the ongoing Wisconsin voter fraud 
 investigation have been charged with felonies.

2004 The district 
 attorneys office investigated seven voter registration applications 
 Project Vote employees filed in the names of people who said the group 
 never contacted them. Former Project Vote employee Robert Marquise 
 Blakely told the Milwaukee Journal Sentinel that he had not met with any 
 of the people whose voter registration applications he signed, an 
 apparent violation of state law, according to the paper. NY Times Spiked Obama-ACORN Story A lawyer 
 involved with legal action against Association of Community 
 Organizations for Reform Now (ACORN) told a House Judiciary subcommittee 
 on March 19 The New York Times had killed a story in October that would 
 have shown a close link between ACORN, Project Vote and the Obama 
 campaign because it would have been a&quot;a game changer.&quot;

Heather 
 Heidelbaugh, who represented the Pennsylvania Republican State Committee 
 in the lawsuit against the group, recounted for the committee what she 
 had been told by a former ACORN worker who had worked in the groups 
 Washington, D.C. office. The former worker, Anita Moncrief, told Ms. 
 Heidelbaugh last October, during the state committees litigation 
 against ACORN, she had been a&quot;confidential informant for several months 
 to The New York Times reporter, Stephanie Strom.&quot;

Ms. Moncrief 
 had been providing Ms. Strom with information about ACORNs election 
 activities. Ms. Strom had written several stories based on information 
 Ms. Moncrief had given her.

During her testimony, Ms. Heidelbaugh 
 said Ms. Moncrief had told her The New York Times articles stopped when 
 she revealed that the Obama presidential campaign had sent its maxed-out 
 donor list to ACORNs Washington, D.C. office.

Ms. Moncrief told 
 Ms. Heidelbaugh the campaign had asked her and her boss to&quot;reach out to 
 the maxed-out donors and solicit donations from them for Get Out the 
 Vote efforts to be run by ACORN.&quot;

Ms. Heidelbaugh then told the 
 congressional panel:

&quot;Upon learning this information and 
 receiving the list of donors from the Obama campaign, Ms. Strom reported 
 to Ms. Moncrief that her editors at The New York Times wanted her to 
 kill the story because, and I quote,&quot;it was a game changer.&quot; 12,000,000 New Democrats The acting director 
 of the U.S. Census Bureau, Thomas Mesenbourg, told CNSNews.com that the 
 bureau intends to work with community organizations to make sure every 
 illegal alien in the United States is counted in the 2010 Census.

The Census is used to apportion the seats in the U.S. House of 
 Representatives. There are 435 House seats that are divided among the 
 states in proportion to their population, which is determined by the 
 decennial census. States with more people get more seats in the U.S. 
 House.

This means that a state harboring more illegal aliens can 
 gain more House seats as long as the Census Bureau finds the illegal 
 aliens and counts them. This also means that the illegal alien 
 population resident in the United States during a census year has the 
 potential to alter the regional and philosophical balance of power in 
 Congress.

When asked whether he intended to maximize the count of 
 illegal aliens in next years census, Mesenburg said:&quot;Our job is to 
 count everyone that resides in the U.S. -- count them once. So, 
 certainly thats our goal to count every individual, every resident 
 whether theyre documented, undocumented, whether they are citizens or 
 non-citizens.&quot;

He said local community organizations will play a 
 key role in making sure all illegal immigrants are counted.

&quot;The 
 local communities are going to have a strong partnership program in each 
 of the local communities, and were going to focus on the hard to count 
 geographic areas. That typically has been areas with high numbers of 
 undocumented workers but its much more diverse than that,&quot;he said.

&quot;So, what well do is well have Census Bureau folks out in those 
 neighborhoods recruiting community organizations, faith-based 
 organizations, and local media to get that message out that its safe, 
 its easy, and its important to file your 2010 Census form,&quot;said Mesenbourg.

Ruben Keoseyan, publisher of the newspaper La Raza , 
 said the organizations at the press conference have partnered with the 
 Census Bureau to help undocumented immigrants&quot;come out and register&quot;for the census.

&quot;This is not just a partnership among the people 
 that you see here,&quot;said Keoseyan. &quot;This is also a partnership 
 with the Census Bureau because we believe that we can aid in helping 
 those people come out and register and participate in the census. Its a much easier form. Its going to be in Spanish.&quot;

 Now you know why Obama moved the 
 Census to the White House and why Rahm Emanuel is in charge. It&apos;s 
 all part of the Progressive&apos;s coup d&apos;tat and consolidation of power.

And, if that isn&apos;t bad enough, check out this email Pamela Geller 
 has at Atlas Shrugs :

 From: Rashad al-Dabbagh
Subject: [ArabCalendar] Fw: Jobs with the Census Bureau
To: 
 naap-oc@yahoogroups.com
Cc: arabcalendar@yahoogroups.com

Dear 
 friends,

Please click on this link for jobs with the US Census 
 Bureau: http://www.census.gov/rolax/www/2010Jobs.html 

Best,

Rashad Al-Dabbagh Corrupting the 2010 Census Earlier this year, 
 Obama announced that he was relieving the U.S. Commerce Department of 
 its responsibility for conducting the census and moving that 
 responsibility into the White House under the control of his Chief of 
 Staff, Rahm Emanuel, one of the most corrupt Chicago machine politicians 
 of all time. However, that decision proved so unpopular that Obama was 
 forced to reconsider. Instead, he has nominated Univ. of Michigan 
 professor Robert Groves as director of the census. Groves is a fervent 
 advocate of statistical sampling, a technique that uses&quot;educated 
 guesses&quot;to determine population instead of actually counting heads. It 
 is a technique that is easily manipulated and which often results in the 
 over-counting of Democratic constituencies.

But, undeterred by 
 suggestions of political manipulation, the Obama Administration and the 
 Democratic Party have pushed ahead with plans to open the 2010 census to 
 massive corruption. For example, news headlines across the country have 
 announced that the Democrats principal vote fraud auxiliary, ACORN, 
 will&quot;partner&quot;with the federal government to conduct the 2010 census.

 Click here to see what sort of shenanigans we find when Democrats team up with the 
 likes of ACORN to assist with voter registration and get-out-the-vote 
 drives? 

ACORN is a 350,000-member Democratic Party 
 auxiliary that the Obama Administration is&quot;partnering&quot;with to count 
 the U.S. population in the 2010 national census. And lest anyone assume 
 that the relationship is either new or coincidental, it should be noted 
 that, during the 2008 campaign, Obama paid ACORN $832,598 to register 
 new voters, payments for&quot;advance work&quot;that the campaign fraudulently 
 reported to the Federal Election Commission as being made to a group 
 called Citizen Services, Inc. The board of directors of ACORN and the 
 board of directors of Citizen Services are one and the same.

During his years in Chicago as a 
 practicing lawyer, ACORN was one of Obamas principal clients. More 
 recently, several ACORN executives in New Orleans were investigated for 
 covering up a $1 million embezzlement. They were represented by lawyers 
 from Michelle Obama&apos;s old Chicago law firm.

Speaking for the 
 Obama Administration, Census Bureau spokesman Scott Levenson has said,&quot;The Census (Bureau) is a non-political agency and were dedicated to an 
 accurate account (sic)... We have a lot of quality controls in 
 place to keep any kind of systemic error or fraudulent behavior to 
 affect (sic) the counts ( wink, wink ).&quot;

During calendar year 2009 the Census 
 Bureau will be preparing for the 2010 census... locating and identifying 
 every residence in every city, town, village, and rural area in the 
 nation... and in 2010, census enumerators will be visiting every 
 household, gathering data from individuals who fail to voluntarily 
 complete and return the census forms that will be mailed to each 
 household.

Given ACORNs record of political corruption in 
 support of the Democratic Party and its candidates, one wonders how many 
 vacant lots, piles of rubbish, and burned-out buildings will appear on 
 Census Bureau data bases as occupied residences, and how many fictitious 
 people will suddenly materialize in Census Bureau tallies as residing in 
 those places. One also wonders how many families will mysteriously grow 
 from three members to six or eight, with the names and ages of the&quot;ghost&quot;members being supplied by the ACORN enumerator.

If some 
 states gain an additional congressional seat, or if some 
 Republican-leaning suburbs are swallowed up by heavily Democratic urban 
 congressional districts in the 2011 congressional redistricting, well 
 know why it happened and well know who is responsible. Well know that 
 Barack Obama and his ACORN&quot;community organizers&quot;have been successful 
 in corrupting the heretofore incorruptible census system.

In an 
 April 7, 2009 report published by the Department of Homeland Security, 
 the Obama Administration has now branded all those who believe in the 
 sanctity of human life, those who believe that marriage should be 
 preserved as the union of one man and one woman, those who have served 
 their country in the armed forces, those who support the 2nd Amendment 
 right to keep and bear arms, those who oppose opening our borders to 
 illegal immigration, and those who oppose government policies that would 
 bury our children and grandchildren under a mountain of debt... as 
 racists and potential domestic terrorists. What we should all be asking 
 ourselves is this:&quot;Would such an administration also take overt steps 
 to bring political benefits to itself and to the Democratic Party by 
 corrupting the 2010 national census? The answer is yes. We cannot assume 
 that any action... legal or illegal, ethical or unethical, moral or 
 immoral, violent or non-violent... is beyond the will and the capacity 
 of Barack Obama, ACORN, and the Democratic Party. ACORN Joins With Union Political activists 
 who masquerade as non-partisan community organizers have joined with 
 organized labor to pressure elected officials into supporting left wing 
 causes, according to a top analyst with the Capital Research Center 
 (CRC).

Matthew Vadum, a senior editor and analyst with CRC has 
 determined that the Association of Community Organizers for Reform Now 
 (ACORN) is best described as a&quot;multi-headed hydra&quot;with over 400,000 
 member families positioned in 110 cities fiercely opposed to the 
 capitalist system.

&quot;ACORN claims to be non-partisan but there are 
 mountains of evidence that show it is flagrantly partisan,&quot;Vadum said. &quot;It celebrates the most left-wing politicians and endorses Democratic 
 Party candidates. Whenever ACORN is called out for activity that might 
 violate their tax status, the standard operating procedure is to deny 
 responsibility and to place the blame on rogue actors. Their network is 
 deliberately set up to avoid scrutiny and to create confusion.&quot;

While the organizations complicated structure makes is difficult to 
 determine how many affiliates and subsidiaries are tied in with ACORNs 
 vast apparatus, its connection with organized labor, especially the 
 Service Employees International Union, is well-established, Vadum 
 observed.

In 2008 SEIU spent over $42 million on independent 
 expenditures and communications, more than any other group aside from 
 the Republican and Democratic National Committees, according to 
 OpenSecrets.org. SEIUs political action committee (PAC) also 
 contributed about $2.3 million to candidates in the 2007-2008 cycle, 
 with 94 percent of its donations going to Democrats.

&quot;ACORN is 
 designed to keep the left in power and to exert pressure on the 
 Democratic party to remain as far left as possible,&quot;Vadum said. &quot;Right 
 now President Obama and the congressional Democrats are getting a lot of 
 grief over card check as it loses support.&quot; Marking Every Front Door In America Well, now 
 we know why ACORN got 5 Billion$ from the Stimulus Bill, and why the 
 White House took control of the US Census Bureau. A perfect excuse to 
 start tagging homes in America for the next Census scheduled for 2010, 
 though it directly violates Sec. 223, Title 13, U.S. Code, Chapter 7, 
 Subtitle 2 which provides the Fed NO authority to GPS paint your front 
 door. It is in direct violation of the Constitution and no one is doing 
 anything to stop it.

ACORN signed on as a national partner with 
 the U.S. Census Bureau in February 2009 to assist with the recruitment 
 of the 1.4 million temporary workers needed to go door-to-door to count 
 every person in the United States -- currently believed to be more than 
 306 million people. But the count doesnt take place until 2010. This is 
 April 2009.

No imagination is required to think up a whole 
 laundry list of evil that could be done with a nationwide GPS grid of 
 coordinates markers painted on every private home across the country. But I was having trouble thinking up one good reason for it, even one 
 legitimate use that would justify what must be a very expensive 
 undertaking.

According to one of the Census workers, who spoke with me on condition of anonymity, they must GPS mark the coordinates&quot;within 40 ft of every front door&quot;in America and they are supposed to 
 complete that mission nation wide, within 90 days, by the end of July 
 2009.

The workers were not told why they were GPS marking every front 
 door. But a supervisor is sent out to follow them door-to-door, to make 
 certain that no door is left unmarked. Every door will be marked by one 
 employee, and then checked by a follow-up supervisor.

So, I had 
 to ask, why?

Why does the Obama administration need or want the 
 latitude and longitude coordinates for every home in America? Why the 
 rush to GPS paint every home in the next 90 days? Why must the marker be 
 within 40 ft of every front door? For what possible purpose does the Fed 
 need GPS coordinates for every home, and under what authority do they 
 have the right? Census workers, whom I asked, had the same holy-crap 
 look on their faces that I had by then.

Best I can tell, the Fed 
 has NO authority whatsoever, to paint the front door of every private 
 residence in America. Still, that is exactly what they are doing. Now, 
 the trillion dollar question is, why?&quot;

Obamas interest in an 
 ACORN controlled 2010 Census, for the purpose of redistricting to the 
 advantage of Democrats before the 2010 mid-term elections, comes as NO 
 shock from a regime known for their heavy handed Rules for Radicals 
 political strategies.

But what does this have to do with GPS marking 
 every home in the country? ACORN Eligible For $8.5 Billion After he reviewed the Obama stimulus bill and the proposed fiscal 2010 budget for 
 the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), Matthew Vadum told the Washington Examiner that ACORN and other left-wing 
 advocacy groups could have a shot at pocketing up to $8.5 billion this 
 year.

Heres how he arrived at the $8.5 billion figure.

The $800 billion-plus stimulus bill, which is now formally known as the 
 American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 or Public Law 111-5, 
 originally set aside $5.2 billion that could flow directly or indirectly 
 into the coffers of ACORN and its liberal friends. It appears the $5.2 
 billion was chopped down to $3 billion in the version of the bill that 
 Obama signed into law on February 17. The $3 billion consists of $2 
 billion in funds set aside for the redevelopment of abandoned and 
 foreclosed homes and$1 billion in Community Development Block Grants 
 (CDBG).

CDBG is good old-fashioned graft. Local politicians of 
 both parties love CDBG because it is flexible. The program gives them 
 wide latitude when spending grant money and allows local leaders to use 
 federal dollars on local projects that they wouldnt dream of spending 
 their own local tax dollars on. ACORN loves CDBG because it is adept at 
 lobbying for CDBG funds.

In addition to the $3 billion available 
 in the stimulus package, the proposed $47.5 billion HUD budget for the 
 fiscal year that begins October 1 provides $1 billion for an affordable 
 housing trust fund and $4.5 billion in CDBG funds that could be funneled 
 to ACORN indirectly.

Of course ACORN wont get it all, and given 
 its history of electoral fraud and racketeering, it shouldnt get a 
 penny of federal money.

According to a Washington Examiner article , ACORN has taken in $53.6 million in federal funding since 1994.

Amazingly, ACORN spokesman Scott Levenson told reporter Kevin Mooney 
 that his group has&quot;received no significant federal funding.&quot;

 This is the same ACORN that is 
 continually in trouble for voter fraud. This is the same ACORN 
 that has pushed the subprime mortgage crisis that has destabilized our 
 economy. This is the same ACORN that, in the words of Barack 
 Obama,&quot;is going to shape our national agenda.&quot;( video ) Follow The Money Wade and Dale Rathke are the 
 founders of Citizens Consulting, Inc . 
 (CCI), and they are incredible 
 organizers. And it was Wade&apos;s vision that allowed ACORN to progress to 
 kind of where it is today. Recently, board members discovered that there 
 is a lot of money missing.

Now, what the board did at that point of time was that, 
 once the full board found out about it, they immediately moved to 
 terminate Wade and Dale, replace them with the two women that were interviewed 
 by Glen Beck -- Karen and Marcel -- in order to 
 try to set the record straight and get to the bottom of what happened to 
 the money.

CCI is the 
 financial nerve center for ACORN and all of its 250+ entities. If 
 you really want to try to follow the money, that&apos;s why we requested a 
 forensic examination and financial audit of CCI.

If you&apos;re in one 
 of these organizations and you apply for federal dollars or any kind of 
 dollars, the money goes there first.

If a a philanthropist wanted 
 to write a grant for a 
 local chapter of ACORN, the local ACORN chapter 
 couldn&apos;t get the grant. The grant would be funneled through its 
 web of organizations to CCI&apos;s New Orleans office -- located in an old 
 funeral home.

Monies are are dispersed from CCI.

CCI says 
 that they pay a small administrative fee, but the problem is, is without 
 an audit, no one knows if CCI gets 1 percent, 50 percent, 90 
 percent -- no one knows. New York Times Spiked Obama ACORN Corruption Story Acknowledging what the blogosphere has known for weeks, the New York 
 Times finally went on record to admit that just before last Election Day 
 it killed a politically sensitive news story involving corruption 
 allegations that might have made the Obama campaign look bad.

But the admission on Sunday, which came seven months after NYT staff 
 reporter Stephanie Strom&apos;s reporting about possibly illegal coordination 
 between the Obama campaign and ACORN last year, took the form of a 
 snarky column from Clark Hoyt, the Old Gray Lady&apos;s&quot;public editor.&quot; Hoyt used the word&quot;nonsense&quot;to describe the allegations of impropriety 
 leveled against ACORN and the Obama campaign.

Details are here . . . ACORN Corruption Probe Disbanded Flopping 
 Aces says that if you are a friend of Obama you need have no 
 fear of a corruption probe! The congressional ACORN corruption probe has 
 been disbanded by the&quot;Powers that Be.&quot;

Heres another in what is 
 fast becoming a series of moves designed to further shield Obama allies 
 from any accountability before the law:

House Judiciary Committee 
 Chairman John Conyers Jr. has backed off his plan to investigate 
 purported wrongdoing by the liberal activist group ACORN, saying&quot;powers 
 that be&quot;put the kibosh on the idea.

Mr. Conyers, Michigan 
 Democrat, earlier bucked his party leaders by calling for hearings on 
 accusations the Association of Community Organization for Reform Now 
 (ACORN) has committed crimes ranging from voter fraud to a mob-style&quot;protection&quot;racket.

&quot;The powers that be decided against it,&quot;Mr. Conyers told The Washington Times as he left the House chambers 
 Wednesday.

The chairman declined to elaborate, shrugging off 
 questions about who told him how to run his committee and give the 
 Democrat-allied group a pass.

 Yawn . . . 
 
 

  Copyright Beckwith 2009
All right reserved
	</body>
</document>
