<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001883" url="http://calorielab.com/restaurants/mcalisters-deli/162" time="2012-07-12-17:47" support="1" score="0.0026609481183195627" bingtitle="McAlister&apos;s Deli Calorie Counter (CalorieLab)" webtitle="McAlisters Deli Calorie Counter (CalorieLab)">
			<query id="000970" bing-rank="91"/>
	<description>McAlister&apos;s Deli Calorie Counter ... The Big Cheese (Your choice of three cheeses, dressed to order) NA: NA: NA: NA</description>
	<body>
		| 
 
 Health News Diet Blog Diet Reviews Diet Delivery Calorie Counter Calories Burned 
 
 How Fat is Your State? 

CalorieLab&apos;s ranking, new for 2011.

 Cheesecake Factory! 

Full nutrition data unveiled.

Beware the Master Cleanse 

Read our expose of the diet.
 
 
 Lab Notes: Anti-Obesity Vaccine May Be a Step Closer; New Trend in Plastic Surgery: Thinner Toes 

Yesterday&apos;s top story: A South Dakota biotech company devoted to finding a vaccine against obesity may have made a major stride toward that goal, with a hormone-inhibiting inoculation that cuts the weight of obese mice by 10% and appears to maintain the weight reduction.
 
 Wheat Belly: Theory with a Dash of Low-Carb 

Cardiologist William Davis, author of The New York Times bestseller Wheat Belly, thinks that all modern wheat (no matter the healthy label on it) is so sinister it can cause your body to practically self-destruct. Is Davis on to something, or on something?
 
 Lies, Damned Lies and Health Care &apos;Facts&apos; 

Robert S. Wieder debunks some of the alarmist claims made of the Affordable Health Care Act and shares lesser-known details about the Republican health care plan.
 
 Lab Notes: Obesity in Pregnancy May Lower Babies&apos; Iron; Heaviest Living Woman Losing Weight with Sex 

Yesterday&apos;s top story: Obesity during pregnancy may increase the likelihood of having babies with low iron levels because of increased levels of a hormone that makes the transfer of iron from mom to fetus less efficient, according to results from a small study.
 
 Lab Notes: Study Shows HPV Vaccine Protects Unvaccinated; Dogs May Boost Immune System in Babies 

Yesterday&apos;s top story: When young women get vaccinated against HPV, they are not only protecting themselves according to results from a new study.
 
 Calorielab supplies a calorie calculator for generic foods, nutrition facts for brand name foods, a calorie counter for fast food chains, and nutritional information for table service restaurants. In addition to calorie content, you&apos;ll find carbohydrate information for low carb diets, and, for many foods, trans fat, sodium, sugar, and other food composition data to help you plan a weight loss or fitness diet. The values in the &quot;Pts&quot; column are computed by CalorieLab from our nutrient database, and are not endorsed by or connected with Weight Watchers International, Inc.
 
 McAlister&apos;s Deli Calorie Counter 
 
 Food Serving Prot Carb Fat Pts Cals Menu Category: Signature Sandwiches McAlister&apos;s Club™ (Turkey, ham, Applewood Smoked bacon, cheddar and Swiss cheese, lettuce, tomatoes, McAlister&apos;s Honey Mustard™ and lite mayo on toasted wheat bread) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Grilled Chicken Breast Club (A tender marinated chicken breast, Applewood Smoked bacon, cheddar and Swiss cheese, lettuce, tomatoes, lite mayo, and McAlister&apos;s Honey Mustard™ on toasted wheat bread) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Orange Cranberry Club (Turkey, ham, bacon, lettuce, tomatoes, lite mayo, Swiss and cheddar cheese on Wheatberry bread with our signature Orange Cranberry Sauce) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Peepers, Onions&amp;Beef (Choice roast beef, steamed onions and bell peppers topped with provolone cheese on a 6&quot;white hoagie served with a cup of steaming Au Jus) NA NA NA NA NA MORE The Reuben (Piles of thin-sliced corned beef topped with sauerkraut, Swiss cheese and Thousand Island dressing on rye) NA NA NA NA NA MORE The Patriot™ (Smoked turkey, lettuce, tomatoes, lite mayo, Swiss cheese on Wheatberry bread with our signature Orange Cranberry Sauce) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Muffuletta (New Orleans-style toasted muffuletta bread, hickory smoked ham, Genoa salami, fresh olive salad and provolone cheese. Whole, Half or Quarter) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Grilled Chicken Breast (A tender marinated chicken breast topped with Swiss cheese served on a toasted onion roll with lite mayo, lettuce, tomatoes and McAlister&apos;s Honey Mustard™) NA NA NA NA NA MORE The Big Nasty (Choice roast beef served open-faced on a toasted 12&quot;wheat hoagie with McAlister&apos;s Come-Back&quot;Gravy™, topped with grated cheddar and Swiss cheese and green onions) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Chicken Salad (All white meat chicken, celery and spices on a toasted croissant with lite mayo, lettuce and tomatoes) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Memphian (Layers of choice roast beef, ham, turkey and provolone cheese on a 6&quot;wheat hoagie, Dressed!&quot;) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Menu Category: Combination Sandwiches Turkey Melt (Hickory smoked turkey, Applewood Smoked bacon and cheddar cheese, Dressed!&quot;on a 6&quot;wheat hoagie) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Hickory Melt™ (Hickory smoked ham, Applewood Smoked bacon and cheddar cheese, Dressed!&quot;on a 6&quot;wheat hoagie) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Mac&apos;s Melt™ (Choice roast beef, Applewood Smoked bacon and cheddar cheese, Dressed!&quot;on a 6&quot;wheat hoagie) NA NA NA NA NA MORE The Godfather™ (Roast beef, pizza sauce and mozzarella cheese on a 6&quot;white hoagie) NA NA NA NA NA MORE California Classic™ (Provolone and mozzarella cheese, lettuce, tomatoes, bell peppers, onions and fresh olive salad on pita) NA NA NA NA NA MORE The Veggie™ (Swiss cheese, lettuce, tomatoes, cucumbers, bell peppers and roasted red peppers on pita with a side of Parmesan peppercorn dressing) NA NA NA NA NA MORE French Dip (Choice roast beef and cheddar cheese on a toasted 6&quot;white hoagie served with a cup of steaming Au Jus) NA NA NA NA NA MORE BLT (Applewood Smoked bacon, lettuce, tomatoes and lite mayo on toasted sourdough) NA NA NA NA NA MORE The New Yorker™ (Loads of our famous corned beef and New York-style pastrami with Swiss cheese on toasted rye) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Delta Delight (Choice roast beef, ham, provolone cheese, sliced jalapenos and BBQ sauce on a 6&quot;white hoagie) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Beef&amp;Provolone with BBQ Sauce (Choice roast beef topped with our BBQ sauce and provolone cheese on a 6&quot;white hoagie) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Submarine (Salami, smoked ham, Swiss cheese, lettuce, tomatoes, onions, bell peppers, black olives, oil and vinegar, salt and pepper, and spicy brown mustard on a toasted 6&quot;white hoagie) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Sweetb erry Chicken™ (Grilled chicken breast, lettuce, tomatoes, lite mayo, Swiss cheese on Wheatberry bread with our signature Orange Cranberry Sauce) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Menu Category: Wraps Grilled Chicken Caesar Wrap (Grilled chicken strips, crispy Romaine, Caesar dressing, Parmesan cheese in a flax wrap) NA NA NA NA NA MORE McAlist er&apos;s Club™ (Wrap Turkey, ham, Applewood Smoked bacon, cheddar and Swiss cheese, lettuce, tomatoes, McAlister&apos;s Honey Mustard™ and lite mayo in a wrap) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Turkey Melt Wrap (Hickory smoked turkey, Applewood Smoked bacon and cheddar cheese, Dressed!&quot;in a wrap) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Greek Chicken Wrap (Fresh greens, black olives, roasted red peppers and Feta cheese, with strips of grilled chicken breast and Greek dressing in a wrap) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Menu Category: Deli Sandwiches Smoked Turkey (Hickory smoked boneless breast of turkey, Dressed&quot;) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Roast Beef (Lean sliced roast beef and a side of McAlister&apos;s Come-Back&quot;Gravy™, Dressed!&quot;) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Ham (Thinly sliced, hickory smoked, Dressed!&quot;) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Salami (Slices of Genoa salami, Dressed!&quot;) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Tuna (Salad Yellow fin tuna, lettuce, tomatoes and lite mayo on your choice of bread) NA NA NA NA NA MORE The Big Cheese (Your choice of three cheeses, dressed to order) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Pastrami (Lean and delicious New York-style pastrami, dressed to order) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Corned Beef (Thinly sliced, lean corned beef, dressed) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Menu Category: Spuds Justaspud (Lite sour cream, green onions on the side) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Cheese Spud (Loaded with cheddar and Swiss cheese) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Spud Olé™ (Covered with chili(can substitute vegetarian chili), cheddar and Swiss cheese and sliced jalapeños, served with red onions on the side) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Spud Max™ (Loaded with ham, turkey, bacon, cheddar and Swiss cheese, green onions and black olives served with lite sour cream on the side — about two pounds) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Bacon Spud (Loaded with cooked real bacon, cheddar and Swiss cheese) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Beef&amp;Cheddar Spud (Hot roast beef topped with cheddar and served with a large side of McAlister&apos;s Come-Back&quot;Gravy™) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Veggie Spud (Loaded with diced red onions, bell peppers, diced tomatoes, black olives, green onions, mozzarella cheese and a side of salsa) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Grilled Chicken Spud (Grilled strips of chicken topped with Swiss cheese, diced tomatoes and green onions) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Chicken Fajita Spud (Grilled strips of marinated chicken, onions, bell peppers, cheddar cheese, topped with sliced jalapeños and diced tomatoes, lite sour cream and a side of salsa) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Pot Roast Potato (Tender pot roast and carrots, smothered in McAlister&apos;s Come-Back&quot;Gravy™) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Menu Category: Salads Soup and Salad (Soup or Chili in a Bread Bowl with Regular Garden or Caesar Salad) NA NA NA NA NA MORE McAlister&apos;s Chef™ (Fresh greens, cucumbers, tomatoes, diced ham and turkey topped with grated cheddar and Swiss cheese, croutons and a salad pepper) NA NA NA NA NA MORE The Chicken Grill (Salad Fresh greens, cucumbers, tomatoes, real bacon, grated cheddar and Swiss cheese, with strips of grilled chicken breast, croutons and a salad pepper) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Taco Salad (Fresh greens, chili(can substitute vegetarian chili), grated cheddar cheese, diced tomatoes, lite sour cream, sliced jalapeños and black olives on a bed of warm tortilla chips, served with a side of salsa) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Garden Salad (Fresh greens, tomatoes, cucumbers, topped with grated Swiss and cheddar cheese, croutons and a salad pepper — Regular or Large) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Tuna Salad (Salad Yellow fin tuna salad, served on a bed of greens with cucumbers, tomatoes, croutons and a salad pepper) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Chicken Salad (Salad Chicken salad served on a bed of greens with cucumbers, tomatoes, croutons and a salad pepper) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Caesar Salad (Fresh Romaine lettuce tossed with our tasty Caesar dressing, crisp croutons and topped with Parmesan cheese — Regular or Large) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Grilled Chicken Caesar Salad (Our large Caesar salad, topped with strips of grilled chicken breast) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Greek Salad (Fresh greens, tomatoes, cucumbers, black olives, roasted red peppers and Feta cheese, with croutons, a salad pepper and Greek dressing) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Greek Chicken Salad (Fresh greens, tomatoes, cucumbers, black olives, roasted red peppers and Feta cheese, with strips of grilled chicken breast, croutons, a salad pepper and Greek dressing) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Menu Category: Desserts Cookies-Fresh From The Oven (Choose from chocolate chip, oatmeal raisin or white chocolate with macadamia nuts) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Chocolate Brownie (A favorite with delectable morsels of rich chocolate) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Brownie Delight (A warm chocolate brownie topped with vanilla ice cream, whipped cream, chocolate syrup and a cherry) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Kentucky Pie (The Staff&apos;s Favorite! A hot chocolate chip pecan pie topped with vanilla ice cream, whipped cream, chocolate syrup and a cherry) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Chocolate Loving Spoon Cake (A chocolate lover&apos;s delight. Add vanilla ice cream) NA NA NA NA NA MORE New York Cheesecake (Strawberry topping or chocolate syrup) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Chocolate or Strawberry Sundae (Two scoops of vanilla ice cream, choice of topping, whipped cream and a cherry) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Menu Category: Just For Kids Toasted Cheese Sandwich NA NA NA NA NA MORE PB&amp;J (Peanut butter and grape jelly on sliced wheat bread) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Mac&apos;s Dog™ (All-beef hot dog with mustard and ketchup on the side) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Kid&apos;s Nacho (A smaller version of mom and dad&apos;s without the jalapeños) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Ham&amp;Cheese (Hickory smoked ham and melted American cheese on toasted wheat bread) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Turkey&amp;Cheese (Hickory smoked turkey and melted American cheese on toasted wheat bread) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Cheese Pita Pizza (Pizza sauce, mozzarella and cheddar cheese) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Menu Category: Soup&amp;Chili Soup of the Day in a Bread Bowl NA NA NA NA NA MORE Cup of Soup, Chili or Vegetarian Chili NA NA NA NA NA MORE Chili in a Bread Bowl (Your choice of chili with meat and no beans, or vegetarian chili with beans and no meat) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Soup and Salad (Soup or Chili in a Bread Bowl with Regular Garden or Caesar Salad) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Menu Category: Appetizers Chips&amp;Salsa (Warm tortilla chips and salsa) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Nacho Basket (Rotel cheese sauce, sliced jalapeños and warm tortilla chips) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Chili Nacho(Meal in Itself) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Chili Cheese Dip (Rotel cheese sauce, chili(can substitute vegetarian chili), sliced jalapeños and warm tortilla chips) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Menu Category: Beverages McAlister&apos;s Famous Sweet Tea™ or Unsweet 32 oz. NA NA NA NA NA MORE All Natural Lemonade 32 oz. NA NA NA NA NA MORE Coke NA NA NA NA NA MORE Diet Coke NA NA NA NA NA MORE Sprite(caffeine free) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Barq&apos;s Root Beer NA NA NA NA NA MORE Dr. Pepper NA NA NA NA NA MORE Fruit Punch 32 oz. NA NA NA NA NA MORE Kid&apos;s Cup (Any beverage) NA NA NA NA NA MORE Bottled Water NA NA NA NA NA MORE Coffee (House Blend and Decaf, 12 oz.) NA NA NA NA NA MORE The Works! (McAlister&apos;s Famous Sweet Tea™ or Unsweet or Lemonade Gallon, serves 5-6. Includes cups, lids, straws, lemons and sweeteners) NA NA NA NA NA MORE By The Gallon (Tea or lemonade) NA NA NA NA NA MORE 
 
Copyright 2000-2012 CalorieLab, Inc. | About CalorieLab® | By using CalorieLab you agree to our User Agreement | Privacy | 2360 Corporate Circle, Henderson, NV 89074
	</body>
</document>
