<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001305" url="http://forum.bodybuilding.com/showthread.php?t=124213711&amp;page=1" time="2012-07-12-16:48" support="11" score="0.04312490798511127" bingtitle="Am I the only one who &quot;enjoys&quot; his fast food job? - Bodybuilding ..." webtitle="Am I the only one whoenjoyshis fast food job? - Bodybuilding.com Forums">
			<query id="000101" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="001166" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="000883" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000538" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="001511" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="001481" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000600" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000350" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000226" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="001040" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="001103" bing-rank="82"/>
	<description>inb4 &quot;you suck cause you work at a fast food restaurant&quot;. ... I heard that working at a fast food place would be ... to their co-workers rather than taking my order.</description>
	<body>
		24/7 Customer Service 1-877-991-3411 Contact Us Need Help? View Cart 
 
 in: Whole Site BodySpace Store SuperSite Reviews BodyGroups BodyBlogs Exercises Videos 
 Free Gift! Any Order Over $ 75 Discounts&amp;Deals - Sign Up! 
 Find A Plan Store BodySpace SuperSite Forum 
 

The Worlds #1 Bodybuilding And Fitness Forum - Save Up To 50% Off Retail Prices In Our Bodybuilding.com Store !

 
 
 
 
 Today&apos;s Posts FAQ Community 
 BodySpace BodyGroups Pictures&amp;Albums Members List BodyBlogs 
 Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 
 View Forum Leaders Who&apos;s Online 
 
 
 Advanced 
 
 Forum » Specifically For You » Teen Bodybuilding » Teen Misc. » Am I the only one who&quot;enjoys&quot;his fast food job? 
 Results 1 to 25 of 25 
Thread: Am I the only one who&quot;enjoys&quot;his fast food job? 
 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Email this Page… Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Search Thread 
 
   Advanced Search 
 
 Display 

 Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 
 05-01-2010, 10:06 PM #1 Vidiot 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: May 2009 Age: 20 Stats: 6&apos;0&quot;, 201 lbs Posts: 1,595 Rep Power: 37 
Am I the only one who&quot;enjoys&quot;his fast food job?
 I recently got hired at Jack in the Box. The work is somewhat easy and I spend a lot of time standing around chatting...with my super awesome co workers. I heard that working at a fast food place would be terrible but I&apos;m actually enjoying it.

Working the grill is pretty tough cause it&apos;s the hardest position but it keeps me busy.


Any other brahs who work at a fast food joint?

inb4&quot;you suck cause you work at a fast food restaurant&quot;. I know a lot of you don&apos;t even HAVE jobs so suck it! 05-01-2010, 10:09 PM #2 cocoaustin 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Apr 2010 Age: 18 Stats: 6&apos;4&quot;, 195 lbs Posts: 1,691 Rep Power: 195 Originally Posted by Vidiot I recently got hired at Jack in the Box. The work is somewhat easy and I spend a lot of time standing around chatting...with my super awesome co workers. I heard that working at a fast food place would be terrible but I&apos;m actually enjoying it.

Working the grill is pretty tough cause it&apos;s the hardest position but it keeps me busy.


Any other brahs who work at a fast food joint?

inb4&quot;you suck cause you work at a fast food restaurant&quot;. I know a lot of you don&apos;t even HAVE jobs so suck it! why would someone say u suck for having a job at a fast food place???
a job is a job and if u enjoy wat your doing i think no one has the right to judge you for that ILS is a primal threat/mating display observed in the human male. The ILS display involves the male human holding out its arms away from its body at approximately a 20-40 degree angle and then walking with a slow deliberate gait inorder to look more imposing to other humans. The posture is used primarily as a form of non-verbal communication such as a mating display to attract or impress females or as a defense or dominance posture to appear larger to a threat or to intimidate rival males. 05-01-2010, 10:20 PM #3 SLapCHop 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Jul 2009 Age: 22 Stats: 5&apos;6&quot;, 122 lbs Posts: 2,132 Rep Power: 216 i didnt work at a fastfood but i worked at some bagel/coffee kiosk and it was overall a positive experience. 05-01-2010, 10:54 PM #4 V3lcity 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Dec 2009 Location: Houston, Texas, United States Age: 18 Stats: 5&apos;6&quot;, 164 lbs Posts: 1,173 Rep Power: 69 you suck cause you work at a fast food restaurant 05-01-2010, 11:23 PM #5 Gt3x24x7 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Virgin not by choice Join Date: Jun 2009 Location: California, United States Age: 17 Stats: 6&apos;0&quot;, 215 lbs Posts: 5,971 Rep Power: 1141 Originally Posted by V3lcity you suck cause you work at a fast food restaurant you suck cause you work at a fast food restaurant SF Bay Area brah
Ron Paul 2012
Misc Persian Crew

750+ 05-01-2010, 11:24 PM #6 the pumper 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Aug 2005 Posts: 1,259 BodyPoints: 10 Rep Power: 347 Originally Posted by Vidiot I recently got hired at Jack in the Box. The work is somewhat easy and I spend a lot of time standing around chatting...with my super awesome co workers. I heard that working at a fast food place would be terrible but I&apos;m actually enjoying it.

Working the grill is pretty tough cause it&apos;s the hardest position but it keeps me busy.


Any other brahs who work at a fast food joint?

inb4&quot;you suck cause you work at a fast food restaurant&quot;. I know a lot of you don&apos;t even HAVE jobs so suck it! alot of people work at fast food places. like burget king wendys and so on . do u get free food ----------------------------------------------------

See who is a virgin here at the Virgin poll:

http://forum.bodybuilding.com/poll.php?do=showresults&amp;pollid=7326
--------------------------------- 05-01-2010, 11:33 PM #7 Psychochris619 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Psychochris619 Join Date: Jan 2010 Location: San Diego, California, United States Age: 23 Stats: 5&apos;11&quot;, 190 lbs Posts: 131 Rep Power: 5 
 
 a job is a job, and theyre not only there for money, but for experience...

...and as long as you&apos;re happy with your job...then its all good! 05-01-2010, 11:59 PM #8 Thetal0n 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 My body wasnt ready Join Date: Jun 2008 Location: Utah, United States Age: 19 Stats: 6&apos;0&quot;, 192 lbs Posts: 4,198 Rep Power: 334 i used to serve food at a local theme park when i was 14. I did not really enjoy it but i stole alot of food and drinks. 05-02-2010, 12:07 AM #9 the pumper 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Aug 2005 Posts: 1,259 BodyPoints: 10 Rep Power: 347 Originally Posted by Thetal0n i used to serve food at a local theme park when i was 14. I did not really enjoy it but i stole alot of food and drinks. i dont think they minded if you eat for free. do u know how much profit they make? a **** load! ----------------------------------------------------

See who is a virgin here at the Virgin poll:

http://forum.bodybuilding.com/poll.php?do=showresults&amp;pollid=7326
--------------------------------- 05-02-2010, 12:18 AM #10 Ruckus91 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 BRB clean bulk to 197 Join Date: Dec 2008 Location: Salt Lake City, Utah, United States Age: 20 Stats: 5&apos;10&quot;, 176 lbs Posts: 1,374 Rep Power: 254 I&apos;ve worked retail before, which I imagine is similar in many ways, and although it&apos;s alright, it&apos;s really not a great job.

Working at a university library now in special collections and I have to say it&apos;s much more interesting work, I enjoy it a lot more, find it more fulfilling, etc. 05-02-2010, 11:16 AM #11 Clide Whit 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Porn King/Fappaholic&apos; Join Date: Aug 2005 Location: Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, United States Age: 26 Stats: 6&apos;3&quot;, 200 lbs Posts: 7,841 BodyPoints: 12605 Rep Power: 11339 I respect fastfood workers, I just hate the people at the drive-through window who seem to busy talking to their co-workers rather than taking my order. Then after 5-6 attempts repeating my order at the window they still get it wrong when I drive up. Xbox 360 GT: Clide Whit

- Eagles - Phillies - Sixers - Flyers -

OFFICIAL BF3 MISC SERVER
http://miscserver.gaming.multiplay.co.uk/ 05-02-2010, 11:17 AM #12 ljd15 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Apr 2009 Stats: 6&apos;0&quot;, 210 lbs Posts: 3,784 Rep Power: 1414 Originally Posted by deepthr0at I respect fastfood workers, I just hate the people at the drive-through window who seem to busy talking to their co-workers rather than taking my order. Then after 5-6 attempts repeating my order at the window they still get it wrong when I drive up. strong username to post ratio 05-02-2010, 11:22 AM #13 Wegzyzz 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Visit Homepage 
 Custom User Title Join Date: May 2009 Location: Canada Stats: 6&apos;0&quot;, 195 lbs Posts: 6,294 Rep Power: 283 Sup Vid
wigz here

I work at McD&apos;s, an actual good one with good people I used to know from middle school but I still dont really enjoy it. I&apos;m doing fries, making sandwiches (fffuuu) or flipping burgers. Its a job, and you get paid. So cant complain too much.

I got another job though at a home hardware store and im starting on monday. Just keep throwing out applications and attach resumes and even cover letters to them introducing yourself to show that you&apos;re really interested.

I&apos;m still not satisfied though haha, i&apos;ll see how it goes on monday. If not i&apos;ll apply at two of the gyms I go to. Bench265x1//Squat435x1//Deadlift405x1
.:Honda4Lyfe:.
.:RIP Zyzz:.

who needs reps 05-02-2010, 11:25 AM #14 yochilllllllll 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Oct 2009 Location: New Jersey, United States Age: 19 Stats: 5&apos;9&quot;, 138 lbs Posts: 2,344 Rep Power: 168 Originally Posted by Vidiot I recently got hired at Jack in the Box. The work is somewhat easy and I spend a lot of time standing around chatting...with my super awesome co workers. I heard that working at a fast food place would be terrible but I&apos;m actually enjoying it.

Working the grill is pretty tough cause it&apos;s the hardest position but it keeps me busy.


Any other brahs who work at a fast food joint?

inb4&quot;you suck cause you work at a fast food restaurant&quot;. I know a lot of you don&apos;t even HAVE jobs so suck it! Has anyone ever told you you smell like Jack in the Box ?

thats why fast food jobs suck, you tend to smell like the food. 05-02-2010, 11:54 AM #15 scarboro 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 bring da ambalamps Join Date: Sep 2009 Location: Toronto, Ontario, Canada Age: 21 Stats: 5&apos;7&quot;, 163 lbs Posts: 7,257 Rep Power: 3374 So you just got hired? Come back in a year and tell me how you like it. Misc Strength Crew 05-02-2010, 11:56 AM #16 Mugaman 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Feb 2010 Age: 19 Stats: 6&apos;0&quot;, 182 lbs Posts: 48 Rep Power: 0 it sucks when you have a bunch of high school drop outs working with you =/ 05-02-2010, 11:58 AM #17 chase007 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Banned Join Date: Sep 2009 Stats: 0&apos;1&quot;, 1 lbs Posts: 4,726 Rep Power: 0 Originally Posted by Mugaman it sucks when you have a bunch of high school drop outs working with you =/ my friends been working at mc donnalds for a year now people give him **** all the time but money is money 05-02-2010, 12:01 PM #18 NJMscle 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Taylor Gang Join Date: Mar 2009 Location: United States Age: 18 Stats: 6&apos;1&quot;, 190 lbs Posts: 4,465 Rep Power: 274 I&apos;m lifeguarding this summer. I&apos;m probably going to wind up blowing my ****ing brains out from boredom. From what I&apos;ve heard it&apos;s pretty much sitting in a chair for six hours. 05-02-2010, 12:04 PM #19 ShakedownSt 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Apr 2010 Age: 19 Stats: 5&apos;10&quot;, 179 lbs Posts: 7 Rep Power: 0 I worked at Baja Fresh for 8 months, by month 3 I wanted to kill myself. It was the 30 hour weeks that killed me (plus the 20 pounds I gained eating free food all the time). 05-02-2010, 01:09 PM #20 PopOverride 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Jun 2009 Age: 18 Stats: 5&apos;10&quot;, 185 lbs Posts: 1,033 Rep Power: 63 It was cool having a friend working at a MC D&apos;s giving free food.

You or coworkers ever mess with the food? 05-02-2010, 01:21 PM #21 CalebRM 
 View Profile View Forum Posts Visit Homepage 
 SkateboarderBrah Join Date: Apr 2010 Location: Oklahoma City, Oklahoma, United States Age: 22 Stats: 6&apos;1&quot;, 202 lbs Posts: 5,906 Rep Power: 8664 I used to have a job at chic-fil-e and between the greese, crappay, and my co workers it was overall one of the worst experiences of my life. I&apos;d rather work on a farm. I smelled just like a fried chicken when Id get home and all my roomates would get all hungry because they were already baked. Now I&apos;m working at walgreens and its wayy better. 05-02-2010, 01:26 PM #22 CriticalAcclaim 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Brb Growing Join Date: Sep 2008 Location: United States Age: 20 Stats: 6&apos;1&quot;, 170 lbs Posts: 1,268 Rep Power: 1210 I work at a Pizzeria with a bunch of my buddies... It&apos;s usually pretty fun actually.. Friday afternoons are busy as **** though. We are always making our own pizza&apos;s to eat when we get hungry n shiz... It&apos;s a good job, pay sucks tho... ~No-Avi Crew~
bulkin baby

Xbox Live GT: Type efx

Dream Theater FTW 05-02-2010, 06:39 PM #23 swander57 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Oct 2009 Age: 20 Stats: 6&apos;2&quot;, 210 lbs Posts: 153 Rep Power: 0 i used to work at one. it&apos;s easy but my managers were ***gots 05-02-2010, 07:30 PM #24 freakballer12 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Repping Nor*Jers Join Date: Mar 2008 Age: 23 Stats: 5&apos;11&quot;, 180 lbs Posts: 251 Rep Power: 6 I actually used to work at McD&apos;s, it was my first job when I was 14. I worked there for three years and was a manager for awhile too. I loved that place SOMETIMES. I worked there back when cheap labor was kids, but now adays it&apos;s mexicans so the place has changed alot. I used to work weekend morning shifts with all kids my age so it was pretty cool. I have alot of memories from working there. Goal:(New Years)
Bench- 225
Dead 405
squat- 315
Bw: 195(10-14% bf) 05-02-2010, 07:52 PM #25 Iron Chicano 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Plan: Lean&gt;Swole&gt;Ripped Join Date: Jul 2009 Location: South Carolina, United States Age: 21 Stats: 6&apos;1&quot;, 190 lbs Posts: 1,025 Rep Power: 73 It can be fun. You can meet tons of people working at a fast food joint. Main problems I have are you can&apos;t chose who you work with (slackers that don&apos;t get fired) and the extremely rude customers you gotta deal with. ~Sh!tty Chest Crew~
My Double-T 10 Week Challenge Log - http://forum.bodybuilding.com/showthread.php?t=122543661
Cutting till theres nothing left. 
 Quick Navigation Teen Misc. Top 
 Site Areas Settings Private Messages Subscriptions Who&apos;s Online Search Forums Forums Home Forums Main Forums 
 Supplements 
 Supplement Company Transformation Contests And More Product Reviews - Help Out! 
 Supplement Logs Sponsored Supplement Logs Company Promotion Supplement Misc. 
 Supplement Wars! Supplement Science 
 BodySpace Profiles And BodyBlogs Workout Programs 
 Advanced fat loss HELL RAISER TRAINING Workout Journals Derek Charlebois&apos; Contest Prep Section! 
 Exercises 
 Injury Recovery And Prevention 
 
 Specifically For You 
 Teen Bodybuilding 
 Teen Misc. Teen Workout Logs 
 Over Age 35 
 Over 35 Workout Journals Over 35 Misc 
 Female Bodybuilding 
 Nutrition and Supplements Training General Chat Journaling Fat Loss Female Misc. 
 Powerlifting/Strongman 
 Powerlifting Workouts - Training Journals MMA Fighting 
 MMA Training Logs 
 Olympic Lifting Powerlifting Video Library 
 For Personal Trainers 
 More General Categories 
 Post Your Pictures Post Your Own Articles! Sports Training 
 Sports Training Journals Outdoor Recreation 
 Fitness Competitions IFBB Pro Bodybuilding Nutrition 
 Nutrition Logs Nutrition Misc Keto 
 Keto Logs Keto Recipes 
 Advanced Nutrition 
 Contest Preparation 
 INBF-WNBF NPC Contest Prep Journals OCB-IFPA FAME 
 Losing Fat 
 Advanced fat loss Losing Fat Logs 
 Motivation Personals - Meet Other Bodybuilders Misc. 
 Science and Technology Sports 
 Fantasy Sports 
 WWE Wrestling Forum Religion / Politics Music Relationship Help 
 Workout Equipment 
 Latest Bodybuilding Issues 
 Topic Of The Week! 
 Workout Of The Week Wallpaper Of The Week - Create Your Own And Win! 
 BB.com - Give Us Your Ideas! Article Reviews! Careers At Bodybuilding.com 
 
 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
Similar Threads
 
 
 Am I the only one who hates Hornswoggle and his DX antics?!?! 
 By SiKkBaSs in forum WWE Wrestling Forum Replies: 21 Last Post: 01-01-2010, 03:22 AM 
 Am i the only one who wants to look like a&quot;More built&quot;version of a abercrombie? 
 By mortious in forum Teen Bodybuilding Replies: 8 Last Post: 03-23-2009, 11:26 PM 
 Am I the only one who can&apos;t stand tyler perry&apos;s&quot;house of payne&quot;? 
 By UsernameTaken in forum Misc. Replies: 53 Last Post: 07-31-2008, 06:03 PM 
 Am I the only one who thinks the words&quot;BEATOFF CONTEST&quot;are homo? 
 By anikey in forum Misc. Replies: 0 Last Post: 01-08-2008, 12:02 AM 
 Am I the only one who is going crazy because racists are&quot;popular?&quot; 
 By SeniorDiscount in forum Misc. Replies: 15 Last Post: 02-08-2006, 10:11 PM 
 
Bookmarks
 
Bookmarks

 Digg del.icio.us StumbleUpon Google Facebook Twitter 
 
 Posting Permissions
 
 You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts 
 
 BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On HTML code is Off 
 
 Forum Rules 
 -- BBcom Default -- BBcom Black -- BBcom Mobile 
 Contact Us Bodybuilding.com Archive Top 
 Member Login 
 Remember Me 
 
 Forgot Login Info? 
 
 
 All times are GMT -7. The time now is 07:48 AM . Archive Home Store Products Careers Help Contact Us Terms of Use Checkout
	</body>
</document>
