<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001575" url="http://www.webmd.com/diet/guide/fast-food-alternatives" time="2012-07-12-17:21" support="15" score="0.034859294223512395" bingtitle="Fast-Food Alternatives, Fast-Food Nutrition" webtitle="Fast-Food Alternatives, Fast-Food Nutrition">
			<query id="000363" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000467" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="000047" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000050" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="001120" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000720" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000460" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000865" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000447" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="001129" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001152" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000742" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="001116" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000856" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000041" bing-rank="82"/>
	<description>Good nutrition and good fast food go hand in hand -- when you start with these quick ... prepared away from home, but that only accounts for about 21% of the meals they eat ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to content 
 Home&amp;News 
 WebMD Home WebMD News Home Free Health Newsletters 
 Health A-Z 
 ADD/ADHD Allergies Alzheimer&apos;s Anxiety Disorders Arthritis Asthma Back Pain Bipolar Disorder Breast Cancer Cancer Carpal Tunnel Syndrome Cholesterol Cold, Flu,&amp;Cough Colorectal Cancer COPD 
 
 Depression Diabetes Erectile Dysfunction Eye Health Fibromyalgia Heart Disease Heartburn/GERD Herpes HPV/Genital Warts Hypertension IBS Incontinence/OAB Inflammatory Bowel Lupus 

 
 Melanoma/Skin Cancer Menopause Mental Health Migraine Multiple Sclerosis Osteoporosis Pain Management Rheumatoid Arthritis Sexual Conditions Shingles Skin Problems Sleep Disorders Stroke See All Topics 

 
 Tools&amp;Video First Aid Games Mobile Apps Slideshows Symptom Checker Vaccine Tracker Tests&amp;Tools Videos Community Experts&amp;Blogs WebMD Community 
 Drugs&amp;Medications Center 
 Find or Review a Drug Vitamins or Supplements Pill Identifier Drug News Mobile Drug Information 
 Healthy Living 
 Women&apos;s Health Men&apos;s Health 50+: Live Better, Longer Emotional Health Healthy Beauty Sex&amp;Relationships Oral Health See All Topics 
 Healthy Eating&amp;Diet 
 Weight Loss&amp;Diet Plans BMI Plus Calculator Food&amp;Fitness Planner Food-o-Meter Personal Diet Evaluator Portion Size Helper All Diet Tools Food&amp;Recipes Fitness&amp;Exercise Fit-o-Meter 
 Parenting&amp;Pregnancy 
 Pregnancy Newborn&amp;Baby Children&apos;s Health Children&apos;s Vaccines Parenting Raising Fit Kids Mom&apos;s Guide to Summer Family Health WebMD for Kids 
 Teen Health 
 Teen Girls Teen Boys WebMD FIT Teen Food Move Recharge Mood 
 Pet Health 
 Healthy Dogs Healthy Cats 
 
   Enter Search Keywords: 

 Other search tools: Symptoms Doctors Medical Dictionary 
Find us on:

 
 WebMD Home Children&apos;s Health Child Nutrition Email a Friend Print Article 
Easy Steps to Your Child&apos;s Nutrition
 
This article is from the WebMD Feature Archive 
 Font Size A A A 
Make and Take Meals: Fast-Food Alternatives
 Good nutrition and good fast food can go hand in hand. By Elizabeth M. Ward, MS, RD 
WebMD Feature Reviewed by Brunilda Nazario, MD 


It&apos;s late, your kids are hungry, and you don&apos;t have time to cook. Put down
the phone and pass up the drive-through. You can rustle up a number of
fast-food alternatives in minutes.

Not only can you put together a faster, healthier meal -- with fewer
calories and less fat and sodium -- but you can save money, too.
 
Editor&apos;s Note: Food Pyramid Replaced
 
In June 2011, the USDA replaced the food pyramid with a new plate icon .
 © 2011 WebMD, LLC. All rights reserved. 
&quot;Americans spend nearly half their food dollars on food prepared away from
home, but that only accounts for about 21% of the meals they eat,&quot; says Joanne
Lichten, PhD, RD, author of How to Stay Healthy&amp;Fit on the
Road. 

Here are tips to show you how -- whether you&apos;re at home or on the road.

Healthy Fast Food: For the Road

When you want an alternative to the fast-food joints calling your name,
think cool: an insulated cooler, that is. Then stock it with:

 Water, low-fat milk, or 100% juice. But beware of the calories in drinks
other than water, says Lichten.Take that cooled milk and douse it over
whole-grain cereals that come in their own single-serve cups. A great snack or
part of a meal when you&apos;re in transit. Low-fat cheese sticks to go with rolls and fruit. Tubes or cartons of yogurt. Cut veggies or washed baby carrots and cherry tomatoes. Add a container of
low-fat dip. Sliced bananas, apples, grapes and pears. 

Other single portion items for portable feasts include:

 Peanut butter in a tube or a small tub to go with crackers or bread
sticks. Single-serve cans of tuna with easy-open tops and crackers. Cans or cups of fruit packed in their own juice. Dehydrated bean soups (get hot water at a roadside rest
stop). 

&quot;Always have fruit and vegetables along for the ride,&quot; Lichten recommends.
&quot;They are the foods we miss out on when traveling.&quot;

Trail mix made from dried fruits, nuts, seeds, pretzels, or cereal with a
few chocolate chips thrown in for good measure makes a satisfying snack, adds
Kerry Neville, MS, RD, a spokesperson for the American Dietetic
Association.

And in a pinch -- when you&apos;re on the road with children and didn&apos;t plan
ahead -- pull into the supermarket instead of the fast-food drive-in. You can
pick up fresh fruit, cheese, and bread for a satisfying meal to go.

Healthy Fast Food: At Home

 Stock Your Cabinets With Fast, Nutritious Food 

Planning helps you pull your own fast-food act together. Get out the
calendar and figure out your food needs for the week ahead. Make a quick list.
Now it&apos;s time to shop. Consider stocking:

 Whole-grain breads and cereals, pasta, and prepared pizza crust. Milk, reduced-fat shredded cheese, eggs, canned tuna, canned beans, peanut
butter, lean ground beef patties, chicken, and meatballs. Fresh, frozen, or no-added-salt canned vegetables; fresh and dried fruit;
and fruit canned in juice. Quick-cooking grains such as 10-minute brown rice and whole-wheat
couscous. Cartons of 100% orange juice, milk, applesauce, peanut butter, and yogurt
in your fridge and cabinets. These work great for road trips, too. 
 1 | 2 | 3 Next Page &gt; 
parenting and children&apos;s health newsletter
 
Vaccinations, developmental milestones, healthy eating. Keep your little ones safe and strong. Sign up for WebMD&apos;s Parenting and Children&apos;s Health newsletter.
 Next Article: Child Nutrition Doctor Video Series Children With Special Dietary Needs Quiz: Is Your Child Hooked on Sugar? Parent&apos;s Potluck: Tips From Parents Video: Healthy Eating Habits for Kids 10 Brain Foods for kids Simple Snack Ideas School Lunch Choices Top Healthy Summer Foods for Children Grocery Shopping With Young Kids Grocery Shopping With School-Age Kids Fast Food Alternatives Video: How Parents Influence Their Kids Diet Children&apos;s Needs 
 Doctor Video Special Diet Needs Hooked on Sugar? At Home Parents&apos; Potluck Healthy Eats Video At School 10 Brain Foods Simple Snacks School Lunches At The Grocery Store Top Summer Foods Young Kids School-Age Kids On the Go Healthy Choices Parents Video 
 
 Children&apos;s Health 

 Children&apos;s Health News Children&apos;s Health Videos Boards&amp;Blogs 
 
Related Health Centers

 Parenting Food&amp;Cooking 
 
At school, does your child usually:

 Bring lunch from home Buy lunch at school 
 &gt;View Results 
 
 Help a friend by sharing this health information 
 
Health Solutions From Our Sponsors 
 
 Aching Back Center Alzheimer’s Progression 

 Birth Control for Moms Diagnosed With Low T? 

 Options for Depression Advanced Prostate Cancer? 

 Osteoarthritis Center RA Patient Stories 

 Injectable RA Treatment Understand Fibromyalgia 
 
In-depth coverage:
 Is Your Psoriasis Treatment on Target? | Your Guide to a Healthy Mouth | Rheumatoid Arthritis Health Check | Teen Girls and Puberty | Diabetes and Your Body 
Find us on:

 
 URAC: Accredited Health Web Site HonCode: Health on the Net Foundation AdChoices
	</body>
</document>
