<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001498" url="http://www.pistonheads.co.uk/gassing/topic.asp?h=0&amp;t=974380&amp;mid=0&amp;nmt=Audi+Q7+TDi+catastrophic+engine+failure" time="2012-07-12-17:16" support="2" score="0.0009597156713999678" bingtitle="Audi Q7 TDi catastrophic engine failure - PistonHeads.com :: Speed ..." webtitle="Audi Q7 TDi catastrophic engine failure">
			<query id="000990" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="000986" bing-rank="207"/>
	<description>... the car, and it is reasonable to expect it ... the customer for betterment is in order if ... where Honda replaced the engine in a near 5 yr old CRV which threw a rod. The car ...</description>
	<body>
		Login | Register PistonHeads Gassing Station Other Marques Audi, VW, Seat&amp;Skoda Audi Q7 TDi catastrophic engine failure Search MyStuff What&apos;sNew : 3 : 12 : 24 : 72 MyProfile MyPreferences MyMates RSS Feed 2 Reply to Topic 
 Author Discussion 
 ChasW 

Original Poster 

290 posts

61 months
 
 [report] [news] Monday 7th March 2011 My pal has a 4 year old Q7 3.0TDi auto with 51000 on the clock. It was recently bought second hand from a local reputable independent that specialises in Audi/BMW/Merc/Porsche etc. The car has a full Audi service history.

Driving sedately on a dual carriageway without warning he heard a loud rattling sound from the engine followed instantly by a loud bang. It has been explained to him that a drop in oil pressure caused something inside to wear so badly it broke and then exploded through the bottom if the engine. So, pretty serious.

The issue now is determining who is responsible for fixing/replacing the engine. The dealer has had their engineer examine the car. Their position is that such a failure could not have occurred without prior warning. In other words there should have been a gradual build up of unusual noise or warning lights indicating to the driver that something was about to fail. Whilst no mechanic my pal does drive 30-40k pa and would be alert to anything untoward in a car. He has been doing these sorts of distances for 20+ years. I can see the dealer’s position moving towards driver fault.

A further complication is the dealer’s warranty cover. My pal bought the car with 6 months warranty unaware that there was a 1000 mile limitation. This is because the dealer forgot to send the warranty paperwork after the sale. The car has done 5000 miles but well within 6 months. 1000 miles seems a bit low to me.

I have two questions.

Has anyone had engine problems with this model?
Any suggestions on handling the situation with the dealer?

Any feedback would be much appreciated.

 
 
 Dr G 

7,532 posts

101 months
 
 [report] [news] Monday 7th March 2011 I&apos;ve never seen any 3.0 TDI go pop in this fashion, generally speaking they&apos;re as tough as tough things (even the very early ones are well behaved!). Q7s suffer gremlins with the inlet manifold (usually with miles) but worse than this I have not seen.

Difficult to comment without knowing things first hand. Has the car missed a service? Was it driven with low oil pressure? Has it been ragged? Was there any oil in it? Was it the right oil?

From:

 http://www.adviceguide.org.uk/index/c_secondhand_c... 

&quot;If the car is faulty and you have left it too late to claim a refund or you don&apos;t want one, you can ask the dealer to replace or repair it free of charge. If you do this within six months of receiving the car, and it is reasonable to expect it to have lasted for the period of time you have had it, it will be assumed that the problem existed when you bought the car, unless the dealer can show otherwise.&quot;

On the assumption that your friend has owned the car for less than 6 months and has not done a billion miles then the onus is on the dealer to prove that the defect was not present at the point of sale.

If said friend has done something to cause the fault (see comments above) then the dealer can quite reasonably refuse to assist.


 
 
 Dilligaf10 

1,586 posts

69 months
 
 [report] [news] Tuesday 8th March 2011 1000 mile limit on a 6 month warranty seems unduly restrictive, 1000 miles per month maybe.

I think you could show that after only 5000 miles you could&quot;reasonably expect&quot;a vehicle to last longer than that, especially as the car has only done average mileage. IIRC the law likes the term&quot;reasonably expect&quot;.
 
 
 Dracoro 

6,049 posts

104 months
 
 [report] [news] Tuesday 8th March 2011 Check out the SOGA as the car was bought within the last 6 months.
 
 
 Tame Technician 

2,131 posts

63 months
 
 [report] [news] Tuesday 8th March 2011 Was there actually any oil in it?

Only seen two V6 TDI&apos;s blow up like that, One had been driven through a flood and filled the engine with water, the other the customer had run dry of oil.

They really dont just blow up.


 Advertisement
 
 
 Raven Flyer 

1,051 posts

83 months
 
 [report] [news] Tuesday 8th March 2011 How long since the last main dealer service?
 
 
 ChasW 

Original Poster 

290 posts

61 months
 
 [report] [news] Wednesday 9th March 2011 Thanks for comments and suggestions. I&apos;ll find out how recent the last service was. As for oil we can only assume that if there was a loss of oil it was very sudden.
 
 
 Soovy 

30,252 posts

130 months
 
 [report] [news] Wednesday 9th March 2011 ChasW said: The issue now is determining who is responsible for fixing/replacing the engine. Not bought from Audi, no warranty.

He is. Next.


 
 
 Dr G 

7,532 posts

101 months
 
 [report] [news] Wednesday 9th March 2011 That&apos;s not true; it is possible that it was a sudden mechanical failure due to an underlying manufacturing defect. In that case the engine was not reasonably durable. The dealer could well argue that a contribution from the customer for betterment is in order if a new unit was to be fitted but the responsibility for making good would be with the dealer.

If it was run dry of oil (or similar negligence) however...
 
 
 Soovy 

30,252 posts

130 months
 
 [report] [news] Wednesday 9th March 2011 Dr G said: That&apos;s not true; it is possible that it was a sudden mechanical failure due to an underlying manufacturing defect. In that case the engine was not reasonably durable. The dealer could well argue that a contribution from the customer for betterment is in order if a new unit was to be fitted but the responsibility for making good would be with the dealer.

If it was run dry of oil (or similar negligence) however... A very optimistic view.

Car out of Audi warranty, car bought from outside Audi network.

Zero hope.

 
 
 DickSkruttock 

1,462 posts

27 months
 
 [report] [news] Wednesday 9th March 2011 Soovy said: A very optimistic view.

Car out of Audi warranty, car bought from outside Audi network.

Zero hope. I&apos;ve had an out of warranty repair approved by Audi from an A4 that wasn&apos;t bought from an Audi dealership, so it does happen.

Mind you, it was a broken glovebox lid @£80, as opposed to a 3.0 TDI engine at a few pounds more 

 
 
 Deva Link 

22,284 posts

104 months
 
 [report] [news] Wednesday 9th March 2011 DickSkruttock said: I&apos;ve had an out of warranty repair approved by Audi from an A4 that wasn&apos;t bought from an Audi dealership, so it does happen.

Mind you, it was a broken glovebox lid @£80, as opposed to a 3.0 TDI engine at a few pounds more On a trim item I&apos;m beyond astonished.

I did see a thread on HonestJohn where Honda replaced the engine in a near 5 yr old CRV which threw a rod. The car had been sold by a non-Honda dealer and had had a service at an indie. I can&apos;t for the life of me imagine Audi doing anything like that.

In the OP&apos;s mate&apos;s position, surely responsibility lies with the seller. Especially if they&quot;forgot&quot;to send the paperwork off (I gather that&apos;s not ususual - they don&apos;t have to pay for the warranty then).

If the oil level was too low or it suddenly lost pressure then wouldn&apos;t the STOP warning flash up? Do these engines suffer the VAG oil pump drive failure - I would imagine that would be quickly catastrophic?

 Edited by Deva Link on Wednesday 9th March 17:03 
 
 
 Raven Flyer 

1,051 posts

83 months
 
 [report] [news] Wednesday 9th March 2011 A 3.0 TDI will be an auto. If the oil pressure was lost at motorway speed, by the time the car was steered to the hard shoulder and stopped, the engine would have carried out a lot of revolutions and would be Big Metal Soup.
 
 
 Dr G 

7,532 posts

101 months
 
 [report] [news] Wednesday 9th March 2011 The grievance is with the dealer, not the manufacturer.
 
 
 Barkychoc 

6,746 posts

63 months
 
 [report] [news] Wednesday 9th March 2011 Get your own inspection done with someone credible, not the garage&apos;s best buddy.

I don&apos;t know if this guy would come as far as you but I have used him before for a vehicle inspection before a purchase and he was worth every penny.
If he won&apos;t come to you it might be worth asking if he could recommend someone.

 http://www.boddington-mee.co.uk/ 



 
 
 cptsideways 

9,027 posts

111 months
 
 [report] [news] Wednesday 9th March 2011 Usually a sudden failure like this would be caused by:

Oil pump failure - oil still in sump is a good indication - sheared off oil pump shaft, pulley etc

Sudden oil leak&amp;running dry - Possibly fairly obvious, from somewhere like an oil cooler or loose oil filter etc

Cambelt or camchain failure - easy to check

If there&apos;s a big hole in the side of the block then its often less obvious what the initial cause might be.

Also worth checking that the oil pressure light actually works 





 
 
 Deva Link 

22,284 posts

104 months
 
 [report] [news] Wednesday 9th March 2011 The only time I&apos;ve experienced this kind of thing personally was many years ago while I was at college and I worked part-time in a garage.

We were delivering a new Mini (the orginal type) to a customer (it was the sort of garage that had the sort of customers who required that). I was following the salesman to bring him back, just driving normally and I was suddenly covered in big cloud as the Mini had thrown a rod. It was absolutely instant.

Funnily enough, the garage owner had exactly the same thing happen in his Ferrari 308, and it was in the last week of its (then) 6 mth from new warranty.

I gather if the oil pump fails then the engine is pretty immediately (ie seconds) rubber ducked.
 
 
 DickSkruttock 

1,462 posts

27 months
 
 [report] [news] Wednesday 9th March 2011 Deva Link said: DickSkruttock said: I&apos;ve had an out of warranty repair approved by Audi from an A4 that wasn&apos;t bought from an Audi dealership, so it does happen.

Mind you, it was a broken glovebox lid @£80, as opposed to a 3.0 TDI engine at a few pounds more On a trim item I&apos;m beyond astonished. Me too. I thought I&apos;d chance my arm though.

The lid hinge just broke, must have been poorly made.
 
 
 DPX 

1,002 posts

59 months
 
 [report] [news] Wednesday 9th March 2011 Do faults in the computers have a date / time stamp , I have seen a few with a km reading. If so get the logs dumped and see if it should have put a warning light on.

I would be suprised if it was not detected and logged something my audi seems to know everything before it goes wrong .
 
 
 remoh 

136 posts

123 months
 
 [report] [news] Saturday 12th March 2011 Dr G said: The grievance is with the dealer, not the manufacturer. Yep, proves the value of paying a little extra and getting a proper audi warranty...

They could chance their arm with Audi UK and ask for help, they might get lucky, if not just some help in getting the cost of the parts down......
 
 
 2 Reply to Topic 
 Gassing Station | Other Marques | Audi, VW, Seat&amp;Skoda 

 What&apos;s New | My Stuff | Top of Page 
 
 Terms and Conditions | Posting Rules 
 Term and Conditions Hosted by Carrenza Copyright PistonHeads 1998-2011
	</body>
</document>
