<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001803" url="http://audubon-omaha.org/bestofbbml/titmice.htm" time="2012-07-12-17:35" support="1" score="0.0005225684861966462" bingtitle="Titmice (part 1) - Audubon Society of Omaha" webtitle="Titmice (part 1)">
			<query id="001251" bing-rank="147"/>
	<description>I have seen neither bill ... lonely male and moves on to the closest fast food restaurant!!! ... find and pierce and throw ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to The Bluebird Box since 1995
 Best of Bluebird Mailing Lists Classified 
 
 
Titmice (Part 1)
 Date: Thu, 30 Mar 2000 08:50:22 -0600
From:&quot;Keith&amp;Sandy Kridler&quot;kridler&quot;at&quot;1starnet.com
Subject: tufted titmouse and related species
The entrance hole&quot;recommended&quot;for most titmice 
 is 1&amp;1/4&quot;. This is small enough to stop all bluebird 
 species from entering easily. This does not stop all House sparrows! 
 I do not know if 1&amp;1/8&quot;will allow all titmice species 
 to enter a nest box. Tufted titmice in this area do not seem 
 to be able to enter 1&amp;1/8&quot;or just the newness of a 
 guard bothers them. They will not&quot;choose&quot;a 1&amp;1/4&quot;entrance preferring the 1&amp;1/2&quot;but will use the 1&amp;1/4&quot;entrance hole after it is added. These MUST be round and not 
 oval to exclude the bluebirds and house sparrows. Bluebirds 
 will enter and nest in a box with a 1&amp;1/8&quot;slot! House 
 Sparrows are smaller than bluebirds when entering box entrances. 
 KK Those in the west please comment on your species of titmice!
 Date: Tue, 25 Apr 2000 10:36:20 -0400
From:&quot;Gary Springer&quot;springer&quot;at&quot;alltel.net
Subject: Tufted Titmouse Egg laying
...Regarding the possibility of the Tufted Titmouse laying
 more than one egg per day:

In my experience, determining when the first eggs were laid 
 by a Tufted Titmouse would require removing and sifting 
 the nesting material to determine if any eggs were in the nest 
 box. Not only is the nest material very loose and the 
 eggs small, but the Tufted Titmouse buries the eggs in
the nest material. So, while I do not have the scientific
 background to know if laying more than one egg per day is
 possible, I do know that without taking extraordinary means
 during monitoring, it is unlikely you would know there were
 eggs in the nest box until there were several. And,
 I strongly
recommend that the nest not be disturbed to determine the exact
 number of eggs in the nest while early in the egg laying phase
 because the eggs are very fragile.

Gary Springer
 Date: Thu, 18 May 2000 13:26:30 -0700
From: Gail Townsend gailtown&quot;at&quot;intercomm.com
Subject: Titmouse - Box and location preference
...Thanks for all the info about titmice (Is that the correct
 plural?). I live in Nevada so I see the Juniper Titmouse (erstwhile
 Plain Titmouse) all the time. I was hoping that I would have
 a pair nesting in one of the boxes this year. They showed
 a lot of interest in one earlier, but didn&apos;t nest. This box
 is near the feeders, so the interest might have been related
 to looking for seeds, rather than looking for nest sites.

I&apos;ll have to look through the&quot;Best of Bluebird&apos;l&quot;site to see what you all have written about boxes used by Titmice. 
 I&apos;d be interested in knowing what habitats are preferred by 
 the Titmouse, and what kind of boxes they prefer (if any). I 
 think our western Oak-Juniper-Plain Titmouse is slightly smaller 
 than the eastern Tufted Titmouse, and might be able to use a 
 smaller box. They certainly can use a box with a smaller opening 
 than the 1 9/16&quot;the Mountain Bluebirds prefer.

If the Juniper Titmice (are they JUTIs) nest in my yard (and 
 they must, they are year-round residents and are always around), 
 then they must be using the natural cavities in the junipers. I&apos;ll have to start 
 surveying my trees for nests to find out exactly who is nesting 
 and when etc. Are there other listers that live in Juniper-Sage 
 Country? Who lives in your trees?
 
Date: Fri, 19 May 2000 05:52:56 -0700
From: Hatch Graham birdsfly&quot;at&quot;innercite.com
Subject: OATI

Dee answered your questions about Oak Titmouse pretty -- Why 
 Oak? Because it lives in and about oak trees and, to my knowledge, 
 no where else. I&apos;ve seen them in other trees but there is always 
 an oak of some species in sight.

Here in California we have a number of oaks throughout the 
 state. The OATI is most common in the blue oaks, coast and interior 
 live oaks, valley oaks, and scrub oaks. It is uncommon in the 
 Calif black oak (Kellogg oak). Likewise, the JUTI is closely 
 associated with the Pinyon-Juniper forests of the arid southwest. 
 No one tries to distinguish them by sight, though the guide 
 claims the JUTI is paler than the OATI. Both lack the black 
 on the head and the rufous sides of the eastern TUTI. From what 
 you folks tell us on the List, their habits are similar.

A proper OATI nest is a three layered affair: a base of moss 
 gathered from the base of the oaks, next fine grass, then a 
 thick topping of fur. The cup is deep and usually is filled 
 with a wad of fur as a plug while the hen is laying. When she&apos;s 
 out foraging she puts the plug in over the eggs. The plug gets 
 incorporated into the nest when she starts incubating and you 
 may be surprised to find 7 eggs in a nest that looked empty 
 the day before. Neat little bird and has declined 35% in the 
 last 30 years because of urban sprawl in California. I personally 
 care more for them than (ahem) a blue thrush I know of.

Hatch
In Central California....
 
Date: Sun, 21 May 2000 12:28:14 -0400
From:&quot;Katherine S. Wolfthal&quot;kate&quot;at&quot;nirvana.ziplink.net
Subject: Fledging titmice

Yesterday was, according to my count which I believe to be 
 accurate, the earliest possible fledging date for my TUfted 
 TItmice.

We were out of town, so I was delighted to see, this morning, 
 that the parents are still going back and forth, removing fetal 
 sacs, etc.

I hope some more experienced monitors than myself will be able 
 to answer the following questions:

Does the weather influence fledging dates? (It&apos;s been nasty 
 here for the past few days - cold and rainy).

Is there any way of knowing when the babies are about to fledge? 
 Do I have to watch the box 24-7 in order to see them go, or 
 will the parents give some hint of when this is about to happen? 
 Do they always fledge in the morning?

Will they all fledge at once, or might some go today (or yesterday? 
 - except I haven&apos;t seen anything that looks like a fledgling) 
 and some tomorrow?

--
Katherine
Weston, MA
-------------
kate&quot;at&quot;nirvana.ziplink.net
 
Date: Tue, 23 May 2000 10:30:50 -0400
From:&quot;Katherine S. Wolfthal&quot;kate&quot;at&quot;nirvana.ziplink.net
Subject: Dern titmice!!

These titmice are driving me bats!! They refuse to fledge, 
 or at least some of them do. I have been watching assiduously 
 since Sunday (day 16), it is now day 18 and the parents are 
 still going back and forth from the nest, feeding, removing 
 fecal sacs, etc. Sometimes I think I see a young&apos;un flying about 
 but then I think it&apos;s a&quot;helper&quot;, because they all 
 have the black forehead patch and they don&apos;t seem to be wing-quivering 
 or begging for food or follwing adults around. None of the coaxing 
 or peeking procedures described so eloquently by Linda Violett. 
 Sometimes I think some of them may be out, and other times I 
 don&apos;t, and meanwhile I have been neglecting work, cooking, laundry, 
 marketing, and my cats are out of kibble... But none of the 
 usual wing quivering or begging for food; The parents are in 
 and out, in and out... It&apos;s cold and clammy outside and I&apos;m 
 chilled to the bone from sitting out there with my binoculars.

So I&apos;m going to do some work and some marketing, and you&apos;ll 
 see... when I come back, they&apos;ll have all fledged without me!!

--
Katherine
Weston, MA
 
Date: Wed, 24 May 2000 11:22:21 -0400
From:&quot;Katherine S. Wolfthal&quot;kate&quot;at&quot;nirvana.ziplink.net
Subject: Happy Fledge-day Titmice!

Needless to say, while I was sitting up here writing&quot;Yuck!&quot;and the rain was pouring down in torrents and cascading over 
 the gutters and down the windows, those dern titmice started 
 fledging. Rain or no rain. At about 8:00 when I finished writing 
 and reading, I went downstairs and was privileged to see three 
 of them exit the box. It happened pretty quickly once they started: 
 a peek, another peek, squiggle through the hole (tiny feet clutching 
 the rim) and out.

I&apos;m pretty sure those were not the first three, and they may 
 have not have been the last, but I had to prepare breakfast 
 and couldn&apos;t watch continuously.

It was a real thrill to see them leave... my throat choked 
 up and I blinked back tears. I stood there rooting for them, 
 whispering&quot;Go!&quot;Two flew out straight, but the last 
 one turned around as though he wanted to go back in and therefore 
 took off in a sort of twisted trajectory. Too many trees and 
 bushes to see where he landed, but I think he&apos;s probably ok 
 because I didn&apos;t hear or see any commotion. Later today, if 
 it clears up, I&apos;ll go up there and make sure there are none 
 on the ground. There&apos;s lots of thick cover, so I can only hope 
 the little ones aren&apos;t getting too wet. I guess when you gotta 
 go, you gotta go.

I think the nest is empty now, but I&apos;m not entirely sure because 
 I saw an adult come back, peek in and then leave. Marvin said&quot;Are you going to watch that box all day?&quot;I guess 
 I will, off and on. Tomorrow I&apos;ll go up and check to see if 
 there are any dead nestlings :-( so I can get an accurate fledgling 
 count. I know there were 8 hatchlings.

Question: Will the parents abandon a nestling that is reluctant 
 to fledge?

Now the adults are taking mealworms from the window feeder 
 - so glad I have them, because insect food must be hard to come 
 by on a day like this. I haven&apos;t seen the fledglings again, 
 but I imagine I will when (if ?) the sun comes out.
--
Katherine
Weston, MA
 
Date: Thu, 25 May 2000 14:01:09 -0400
From:&quot;Katherine S. Wolfthal&quot;kate&quot;at&quot;nirvana.ziplink.net
Subject: Empty nest

Today, with a sense of dread, I went up on the hill to check 
 the nestbox from which the TUfted TItmice fledged yesterday 
 morning. I had last monitored on May 15 (expecting them to hatch 
 within 4 days), and at that time was unable to get an accurate 
 count because the chicks were all hunkered down, but I knew 
 there were 8 hatchlings. I put off the reality check all morning, 
 certain that, given the cold, rainy weather, some would have 
 succumbed. I opened the box, and the nest was ......... empty!!

So mama TUTI is to be congratulated on a job well done. I have 
 seen neither bill nor feather of them since. I just hope they 
 didn&apos;t catch pleurisy yesterday and that she brings them back 
 to the feeders before they&apos;re all grown up.

--
Katherine
Weston, MA
 
Date: Sat, 27 May 2000 14:23:01 -0400
From:&quot;Katherine S. Wolfthal&quot;
Subject: Titmice - 2nd brood?

I have not seen the titmouse kids since they fledged on Wednesday, 
 and I&apos;ve seen very little of the adults. But I just saw two 
 adult titmice peering into the nestbox, the same one that was 
 used before but which has since been cleaned out.

Is it possible they may be considering a 2nd brood? Should I 
 put out more cat fur?

I was under the impression that, this far north, they usually 
 only have one brood per season. It&apos;s true they started early 
 this year, but the fledglings are only 3 days old. Could this 
 mean all the fledglings have died? I can hardly believe that, 
 having survived the nestling stage, all eight would have succumbed 
 to other things in only two days!

Any expert timouse landlords out there?

--
Katherine
Weston, MA
 Date: Sat, 27 May 2000 15:38:22 -0400
From:&quot;Bruce Burdett&quot;
Subject: Re: Titmice - 2nd brood?

Katherine: Many fledglings, including Bluebirds, seem to&quot;vanish&quot;after
 they leave the nest. I&apos;m convinced that that&apos;s nothing to worry
 about. Chances are they&apos;re just keeping out of sight during
 this vulnerable period in their young lives, - maybe quite
 close at hand, maybe in another neighborhood where there&apos;s
 better cover and the food supply is better. My money says they&apos;re
 just fine somewhere, where neither you nor their predators
 can locate them. Many creatures, both furred and feathered,
 do similar things until they can fend for themselves. The fact
 that the adult Titmice still check out the nestbox suggests
 that the fledglings are probably nearby. I don&apos;t know whether
 Titmice nest a second time.
Bruce Burdett, NH Bluebird Conspiracy, Sunapee NH
blueburd&quot;at&quot;srnet.com
... Date: Sat, 27 May 2000 22:10:28 -0500
From:&quot;R_C Walshaw&quot;
To:&quot;Bluebird Listserve&quot;
Subject: Cheryl - Tufted Titmouse nest

Cheryl asked what Tufted Titmice nests look like. In this area 
 there is a lot of variation. One pair will use only pieces of 
 old oak leaves, and the next pair will use both moss and leaves. 
 I often have to wait until a nest is built to see whether it 
 is a Titmouse or a Carolina Chickadee. Bluebird Bob, Northeast 
 Oklahoma. (no grass).

 Date: Sat, 27 May 2000 22:17:10 -0500
From:&quot;R_C Walshaw&quot;
Subject: Bruce, Katherine, all.

Re: second nestings of Titmice (Chickadees too) - My understanding 
 is that they have only one brood per year. This has been my 
 experience here in this area in upwards of 100 nestings over 
 5 years. With both I have never had a second nest. Bluebird 
 Bob, Northeast Oklahoma. (Tufted Titmice and Carolina Chickadees).
  Date: Sat, 27 May 2000 23:16:35 -0400
From:&quot;Katherine S. Wolfthal&quot;kate&quot;at&quot;nirvana.ziplink.net
Subject: Re: Titmice - 2nd brood?

Thanks to all those who answered my query about a second TUfted
 TItmouse brood. I know, in fact, that it is unusual for them
 to have two broods this far north, but I was not aware that
 the parents often peek back into the nest, so I wondered. According
 to Cornell&apos;s cavity-nester website, TUTI&quot;tend&quot;to
 have only one brood in the northern part of their range - but
 they are a good two weeks ahead of schedule, so, as I am rapidly
 learning, the key word is&quot;unusual&quot;not&quot;impossible&quot;.
 I will keep my eyes peeled.

I have seen the adults around, and I hear them calling, so
 the fledglings are probably close at hand... I&apos;m just a worrywart.
 You know kids...&quot;they never
come, they never call, they never write...&quot;:-) And I
 can assure you there is no better cover or food anywhere in
 town! Harrumph!!

Today, incidentally, I saw the PIleated WOodpecker for the second 
 time in a few days. Today it was Mrs., the other day I&apos;m not 
 sure. Do PIWOs eat mealworms? What a thrill it would be to see 
 one at my mealworm feeder, which is just outside my window!

...
 Date: Sun, 28 May 2000 11:13:31 -0400
From:&quot;Katherine S. Wolfthal&quot;kate&quot;at&quot;nirvana.ziplink.net
Subject: Re: Titmice - 2nd brood?
This morning the titmice were back at their old box again.
 Old home week? Maybe. But they were also checking out the box
 next door (about 25 feet away, about the same height, on another
 tree but facing west rather than south) which has not yet been
 used by anyone. I haven&apos;t seen them bringing nesting material,
 but my eyes are still peeled...
 
Date: Sun, 04 Jun 2000 11:43:28 -0400
From:&quot;Katherine S. Wolfthal&quot;kate&quot;at&quot;nirvana.ziplink.net
Subject: Clutch size question

I checked on the TUfted TItmouse nest yesterday, at midday. 
 On Thursday when I last checked, there were 2 eggs in the box, 
 so yesterday I expected to find four eggs and no bird in the 
 box. Instead, I found the titmouse on the nest, and there were 
 three eggs. This seems to suggest that three eggs are all there 
 will be. I will try to check again today if I see the female 
 leave the box, just to make sure. Since there were eight eggs 
 the last time, (which is above average for TUTI), what is the 
 implication of the small clutch? Different, younger female, 
 or same female but less energy/investment in 2nd brood?

--
Katherine
Weston, MA
 Date: Sun, 4 Jun 2000 12:44:37 -0400
From:&quot;Paul Murray&quot;paul&quot;at&quot;fifthdaycreations.com
Subject: Re: Clutch size question
According to the book, The Backyard Birdhouse Book, the clutch 
 size of a tufted titmouse is 3 to 9, usually 5 to 6. The incubation 
 period is about 2 weeks and is done only by the female.

,Paul ...
 Date: Sun, 04 Jun 2000 18:16:29 -0400
From:&quot;Katherine S. Wolfthal&quot;kate&quot;at&quot;nirvana.ziplink.net
Subject: Re: Clutch size question
I checked again this afternoon, being sure to wait till the 
 TUTI was off the nest, and there were five eggs. So clearly, 
 my count was wrong yesterday. And yet, I could *swear there 
 were only three eggs there, because she was interrupted and 
 therefore did not cover them, and I looked *very carefully and 
 even felt gently with my fingers. So, yes, maybe she was in 
 the process of laying the fourth egg at noon yesterday when 
 I flushed her - but isn&apos;t that sort of late in the day? Or - 
 and weren&apos;t you the one who suggested this, Barry? - maybe she 
 laid two this morning? Well, as more than one person has said, 
 birds don&apos;t read the bird books. Or maybe - and most likely 
 - I was simply wrong. It&apos;s been known to happen. So now I will 
 have to check again in a few days to try and determine the final 
 number.

This nest is much less&quot;refined&quot;than the previous 
 one in the same box, with much less fur and other soft lining 
 material; mainly just moss and leaves... and a piece of cellophane. 
 As I mentioned in an earlier post, it was built in only 3 days. 
 But I think it&apos;s about the same depth as the other one.

Another question: In counting days to hatching, do you start 
 counting incubation from the day the last egg is laid, or the 
 day after?

...

Katherine
Weston, MA
 Date: Tue, 20 Mar 2001 20:29:53 -0600
From:&quot;Pauline Tom&quot;bluebirds&quot;at&quot;austin.rr.com
Subject: Titmice in Bluebird Nestboxes? You bet!
Yesterday Cathy Cowan in California mentioned,&quot;I&apos;ve seen 
 some postings suggesting that it might be uncommon to see titmice 
 in BB boxes? We&apos;ve had the boxes up for 4 years, and have had 
 oak titmice nesting in them every year.&quot;

Here in Mountain City TX a clutch of Tufted Titmice was in 
 the process of hatching this very afternoon. What an awesome 
 experience to take a quick peek in the PVC nest box on my front 
 lawn and see the miracle in process. The first babies for me 
 this year!

Tufted Titmice and Bewicks Wrens (not House Wrens) are the 
 most frequent occupants of my&quot;cavity nesting birds&quot;nest boxes. :-)

Pauline Tom
Mountain City (no mountains) TX
 
Date: Tue, 20 Mar 2001 21:59:37 -0800 (PST)
From: Karen Nisbett mknisbet&quot;at&quot;yahoo.com
Subject: Re: Titmice in Bluebird Nestboxes? You bet!

Titmice commonly nest in my bluebird houses, too. They have 
 taken one by our barn for the last several years. I watch them 
 gather dog hair in the backyard and then fly off to the house 
 up the hill, trying to time their &apos;swoops&apos; so they can land 
 in the opening of the house and not splat against the wall ;-) 
 Chickadees and Carolina Wrens are also frequent residents in 
 my bluebird boxes.

You guys in Texas seem worlds ahead of us here in the mid-West! 
 I haven&apos;t noticed any nesting going on yet.

Karen
Central MO near Rolla
 
Date: Thu, 29 Mar 2001 06:15:49 -0800 (PST)
From: Horace Sher hjsher1&quot;at&quot;yahoo.com
Subject: EABL chasing away Titmouse from nestbox

Greetings...I have 2 boxes (front&amp;back boxes) that the
 EABL have been interested in.. on&amp;off for a couple months.
 Also, the Tufted Titmouse have been interested in the same
 boxes. The Titmouse has started a nest in the back box now.
 On prior occasions I have seen the EABL chase away Titmouse&amp;Chickadees
 from these 2 boxes, thus leading me to believe that the EABL
 will pick at least 1 of the boxes. But the last few days
 I get a feeling that the EABL is losing interest in these
 2 boxes, since at least the Titmouse has managed to start
 his nest in the back one.The 2 boxes in question, I think
 are good ones..location, etc. (Actually, the back box was
 occupied by a EABL last year)...Question? Has anyone had experience
 or observations watching their Bluebirds seriously chasing
 away Tufted Titmouse after the Titmouse has started a nest?
 And the EABL ending up nesting in the claimed box. We&apos;ve
 had a good discussion about the Chickadee interaction, but
 what about the Titmouse..&amp;while we&apos;re at it..what about some other nice competitive birds,
 such as the Nuthatch, Carolina Wren, P. Warbler... Anyone
 with some observations, please let me know..Thanks...Horace
 in NC.
 
From:&quot;Gary Springer&quot;springer&quot;at&quot;alltel.net
Sent: Friday, March 30, 2001 3:46 AM
Subject: Tufted Titmice

I asked earlier if any one has ever seen tufted titmice nest
 in natural cavities. ... There sure are plenty of them around.

Gary Springer
 
Date: Fri, 30 Mar 2001 08:12:30 -0500
From:&quot;MJShearer&quot;eshearer&quot;at&quot;mediaone.net
Subject: Re: Tufted Titmice

...I did have a Titmouse nest in a natural cavity, but it
 was too high and well-hidden to tell much about it. I watched
 the adults come and go feeding the young whom they brought
 to the feeder after they fledged.

Bluebirds are now building in a box about 15 feet from one 
 in which the chickadee is incubating 6 eggs. How far apart are 
 your 5 chickadee nests? It&apos;s my understanding that they are 
 very territorial and require about 1/4 acre per nest.

Mary Jane ShearerTucker, GA
 
Date: Fri, 30 Mar 2001 16:14:36 EST
From: TomGaryH&quot;at&quot;aol.com
Subject: Bluebird/Titmouse/Hole Restrictor

Hi Folks,

Yesterday and the day before I watched a pair of bluebirds 
 spend some time harrassing tufted titmice at a nestbox in which 
 the titmice had been building a nest. The box has a 1 1/2 inch 
 hole which had been protected by a 1/4 inch thick hole protector 
 made from industrial-grade, vulcanized rubber, conveyor belt 
 material. Each day the bluebirds spent at least 20 to 30 minutes 
 at a time on the box and hanging onto and poking their heads 
 into the entrance. An unoccupied, recently refurbished and painted, 
 wide-bodied Peterson with a small oval entrance is about 50 
 feet from and in sight of the titmouse-bluebird box. Bluebirds 
 had played at this Peterson, going in and out, during the beginning 
 of the winter until a red-bellied woodpecker enlarged the entrance 
 and used the box as a night roost.

Today the male bluebird seemed determined to dislodge the titmouse. 
 I didn&apos;t want that to happen because I figured the nest was 
 very near complete and could even have an egg or two. I decided 
 to put a hole restrictor on the box. Rather than use a quick 
 fix restrictor I decided to replace the conveyor material with 
 a commercially made 1 1/4 inch metal portal.

I backed a pickup truck next to the box so I could stand on 
 the lowered tailgate. A titmouse was in nearby blooming azaleas 
 and I heard it as I began the work which would require removal 
 of the one-piece, forward-sloping roof. I worked as fast as 
 I could. Just about the time I had gotten all the roof screws 
 loose I heard what I&apos;ll call&quot;stomping&quot;noises coming 
 from the box. These noises subsided quickly. The entrance was 
 wide open, but the bird stayed in. I repositioned the roof toward 
 the rear to temporarily eliminate the overhang so I could work 
 on the front. As I was removing the conveyor material I thought 
 it would be better if the bird stayed in the box until all work 
 was complete and the white pickup truck was removed from the 
 immediate vicinity of the box. So, I put an&quot;X&quot;of 
 masking tape over the hole after neutralizing some of the sticky 
 part so as to lessen the likelihood of feather damage if the 
 bird tried to squeeze out of the hole.

A quiet hand-cranked drill - remember those - was used for 
 the pilot holes for the screws that would hold the portal to 
 the box. The portal was put on, the roof reinstalled and the 
 truck driven away. I removed the tape as gently as I could and 
 walked into some shade about 60 feet away. A couple of minutes 
 later the titmouse came out then perched about 20 feet from 
 the box. I was feeling pretty good about everything until about 
 10 minutes after the titmouse came out of the box.

Those bluebirds must have watched all the activity. They returned 
 to the box and took up their stations. The male bluebird got 
 into the box through the 1 1/4 inch portal. Well, that surprised 
 me. Is that news to any of you experienced folks? I watched 
 until he came out. The female bluebird may have gotten into 
 the box as well. I didn&apos;t stay to confirm that.

I figure I did what I could to save the titmouse nest. Last 
 I saw of the bluebirds they were going in and out of the Peterson. 
 That&apos;s encouraging. It will take a little time to see if the 
 titmouse abandons.

Tom in NW Florida
 Date: Fri, 30 Mar 2001 22:59:25 -0500 (EST)
From: hubertrap&quot;at&quot;webtv.net (Joe Huber)
Subject: Re: Bluebird/Titmouse/Hole Restrictor
Hi Tom and all, As you have learned a eastern bluebird can 
 squeeze in a 1-1/4&quot;entrance hole. this has been known 
 for some time but it was learned that 1-1/2&quot;size was best 
 suited for them because of wear on feathers. the Titmouse can 
 use a 1-1/8&quot;entrance which generally keeps larger birds 
 out. I don&apos;t suggest you go thru that same process of changing 
 the entrance size again but rather let it play out now as it 
 will. the Bluebirds may still choose your other box since this 
 one has a tight entrance. Lets hope they know to pick the other 
 box. if the titmouse stays after your disturbance he may win 
 out yet. keep us informed on the progress. Joe Huber Venice,Fl.

Charter member NABS, Charter member OBS, Life member OBS Joe 
 Huber
hubertrap&quot;at&quot;webtv.net
 Date: Sat, 31 Mar 2001 09:59:42 EST
From: TomGaryH&quot;at&quot;aol.com
Subject: Re: Bluebird/Titmouse/Hole Restrictor
Joe and All, A quick and final report. The female Bluebird 
 began building in the Peterson box while Mr. Blue sings and 
 watches. Titmouse nest building activity that was temporarily 
 halted for installation of a smaller entrance to the box has 
 resumed. Luck was with us - this time. Tom in NW Florida
 
Date: Sat, 31 Mar 2001 10:21:52 -0500 (EST)
From: hubertrap&quot;at&quot;webtv.net (Joe Huber
Subject: Re: Bluebird/Titmouse/Hole Restrictor

Tom,thats good news. I had a feeling that the bluebirds would 
 end up in the box with a normal size entrance. my concern was 
 that the Titmouse would abandon the box you placed the 1-1/4&quot;restrictor on while they were using it and one inside. They 
 don&apos;t tolerate as much manipulation with a nest box as bluebirds 
 do. since they are back you should be in the clear. The only 
 fear now would be that a house sparrow comes since they can 
 also enter the 1-1/4&quot;entrance. keep your eye out for them 
 unless you are in a area free of them. Enjoy the birds. Joe 
 Huber Venice Fl.

Charter member NABS, Charter member OBS, Life member OBS Joe 
 Huber
hubertrap&quot;at&quot;webtv.net ...
 
Date: Sun, 1 Apr 2001 12:07:20 -0700
From:&quot;Dusty Bleher&quot;dusty&quot;at&quot;fsinc.com
Subject: Re: Tufted Titmice nesting preferences

Sounds like a perfect spot-on observation, Gary. I&apos;ve got my 
 second Titmouse nesting this year. And it too is in one of my 
 very high hanging boxes. I used that level only because it was 
 the only place that I could reach on that tree. The tree was 
 selected for it&apos;s spacing from the other WEBL boxes. I hadn&apos;t 
 connected height with location. But for the moment, I&apos;m 2 for 
 2. Seeing that I have another WEBL box that&apos;s been unused for 
 two seasons (except by a woodpecker that made the entrance hole 
 3X3), I&apos;m going to see if I can get another one to use that 
 box.

FWIW; I&apos;ve got 2 eggs in the first OATI box...(:-)!

Dusty
San Jose, Ca.
 
Date: Sun, 1 Apr 2001 14:28:13 -0600
From:&quot;Pauline Tom&quot;bluebirds&quot;at&quot;austin.rr.com
Subject: Titmice: 3 adults bringing food to nest

Three adult Black-Crested Tufted Titmice are bringing food 
 to the nestlings in the nest box on my front lawn. (Young will 
 fledge mid-week) It&apos;s both parents and who else? What&apos;s the 
 relationship of Adult #3?

Thanks!

Pauline Tom
Mountain City (no mountains) TX...
 
Date: Mon, 2 Apr 2001 07:00:16 -0500
From:&quot;Wright, Merlin C.&quot;mcwrigh&quot;at&quot;nppd.com
Subject: TITMOUSE TERRITORY

Dear Friends, As I recall from last year there was a person 
 who wrote in telling us how much area was claimed by several 
 different birds and again, as I recall, a bluebird needs approximately 
 1/2 to 1 acre (~43000 sq ft) and the TITMOUSE needs 45 acres. 
 Since I didn&apos;t believe that, I paid more attention at home and 
 sure enough, that is the bird that shrieks PETA, PETA, PETA, 
 pause and repeat all during nesting season and it has started 
 now for this year. PETA, PETA, PETA is how one of my books describes 
 it. I am not sure about the 45 acre statement but I believe 
 that if it were at the center of a 45 acre circle, it could 
 be heard throughout the circle. No wonder you can&apos;t get one 
 to use your nestbox.
 
Date: Mon, 2 Apr 2001 11:19:15 -0700 (PDT)
From: Horace Sher hjsher1&quot;at&quot;yahoo.com
Subject: Tufted Titmouse&amp;EABL

Greetings to everyone..I currently have my 2 backyard boxes
 with TUTI nesting in them..2 different pairs I think..30-40
 ft. apart. The front yard box (a 3rd) has had EABL interested
 in it on&amp;off for a couple months. Last week they (EABL)
 did bring in a little nesting material into that box. Actually
 yesterday 2 males fought almost to the death over that box&amp;the nearby watching female. So the EABL pair led me to believe
 that they wanted that box. But today the Titmouse have been
 bringing in their nesting material to that very same box.
 So I&apos;m wondering what&apos;s up with the EABL. On a couple other
 occasions in the past the EABL did chase away the TUTI from
 that box. Question to people with TUTI observations&amp;experience..would
 you remove some of or all of the TUTI nesting material to
 help the EABL or just leave it alone&amp;hope? As I&apos;ve mentioned,
 I already have 2 other boxes in the backyard with TUTI nesting
 in them. Apparently the EABL didn&apos;t choose either of them.
 So what&apos;s going on with the front box? I would think the EABL
 is big enough to claim this box from the TUTI..but now I may
 have doubts..Also, does anyone know the nesting cycle of the
 TUTI? Is it basically the same as the Chickadee? ..egg laying,
 incubation, brooding, nestling&amp;fledgling period.. Thanks
 for any opinions&amp;info...Horace in NC.
 
Date: Mon, 02 Apr 2001 21:55:33 -0400
From:&quot;Katherine S. Wolfthal&quot;kate&quot;at&quot;nirvana.weichi.com
Subject: Re: Tufted Titmouse&amp;EABL

Horace Sher wrote:

Question to people with TUTI observations&amp;experience..would
 you remove some of or all of the TUTI nesting material to
 help the EABL or just leave it alone&amp;hope?

It is STRICTLY ILLEGAL to remove nesting material from a TUTI 
 nest. TUTI are just as rigorously protected as bluebirds and 
 just as deserving of our respect and consideration. Leave their 
 nests alone and let them duke it out.

Also, does anyone know the nesting cycle of the TUTI? Is it basically the same as the Chickadee? ..egg laying, incubation, brooding, nestling&amp;fledgling period.. Thanks for any opinions&amp;info...Horace 
 in NC.

I have had TUTI nesting in my boxes for the past couple of 
 years now. They can lay up to 8 eggs, one a day, usually in 
 the morning, and they often hide the eggs under nesting material when they leave the 
 nest. Eggs are incubated for about 2 weeks (more if it&apos;s cold). 
 The nestlings fledge after about 15-16 days (again, more if 
 it&apos;s cold. It took my first brood of TUTI about 17 days last 
 year). In the north, TUTI are supposed to have only one brood, 
 so I presume that the 2nd family nesting in the same box was 
 a different one from the first, and may have been less experienced. 
 The nest was built in a hurry, and 6 eggs, rather than 8, were 
 laid. In both cases, all fledged successfully, and left a clean 
 nest.

--
Katherine
Weston, MA
 
Date: Mon, 2 Apr 2001 21:07:41 -0700 (PDT)
From: Horace Sher hjsher1&quot;at&quot;yahoo.com
Subject: Re: TITMOUSE TERRITORY

Greetings.. Merlin, it may have been me last year that said 
 I read it in a bird book that the TUTI&apos;s territory is 45 acres. 
 Actually, I did read that, but the book had a misprint. I&apos;m 
 sure the decimal point was printed in the wrong place more like 
 .45 acres, because I have 3 pairs of TUTI nesting in my yard..2 
 in the backyard&amp;1 in the front. My yard is a whole lot 
 smaller than 45 acres..more like 1/4 acre....Horace in NC.
... 
Date: Tue, 3 Apr 2001 10:11:13 -0700
From:&quot;judymellin&quot;judymellin&quot;at&quot;netzero.net
Subject: Re: TITMOUSE TERRITORY

Per John Eastman&apos;s book Birds of Forest, Yard and Thicket, 
 he writes of the titmouse: Breeding territories typically comprise 
 about two to five acres, depending on habitat.

In Birds of Field and Shore, he says of Eastern Bluebirds:
 Males establish territories of 2 to 25 acres, depending on
 habitat resources and bluebird population density.

Hope this helps!

Judy Mellin
NE IL.
 
Date: Tue, 3 Apr 2001 13:43:49 -0700 (PDT)
From: Horace Sher hjsher1&quot;at&quot;yahoo.com
Subject: EABL building on a Titmouse nest

Greetings to everyone..Has anyone ever seen a Bluebird take
 over a Tufted Titmouse nest that was in the process of being
 built&amp;eventually claim&amp;nest in the box? If so,
 did the Bluebird build right over the Titmouse nest or remove
 some material&amp;then build? 
 Thanks for your
reply...Horace in NC.
 
Date: Thu, 05 Apr 2001 15:34:09 -0500
From: Kathleen Oschwald nestbox&quot;at&quot;1starnet.com
Subject: Re: Tufted Titmouse&amp;EABL

At 11:19 AM 4/2/01 -0700, you wrote:

snipped

Question to people with TUTI observations&amp;experience..would
 you remove some of or all of the TUTI nesting material to help
 the EABL or just leave it alone&amp;hope?
...Horace in NC.

I personally would not disturb the titmouse nests, and I&apos;m 
 know it&apos;s not legal. The tufted titmouse is a protected songbird 
 and these are not&quot;dummy nests&quot;like male house wrens build to stuff all nearby 
 nestboxes.

Many people on this list would give anything to have one choose 
 one of their nestboxes, myself included. I consider you fortunate 
 indeed!

Kate Oschwald
Sumner, TX..
 
Date: Sat, 21 Apr 2001 13:32:14 -0400
From:&quot;Gary Springer&quot;springer&quot;at&quot;alltel.net

Subject: Tufted Titmouse

The Tufted Titmouse nesting in a nest box just down over the 
 hill from my house would be upset if I didn&apos;t mention her in 
 my posts today as I did the bluebirds, chickadees and carolina 
 wrens.

I&apos;ve mentioned the sounds they make during monitoring of the 
 nest box before. But this morning, incubating Mrs. Titmouse 
 must have been in no mood to be messed with.

I whistled a couple soft tones, lightly tapped on the box a 
 couple times, carefully twisted out the screw that holds the 
 side of the nest box closed, then began to open the box very 
 slowly.

All of a sudden, when the box was open just a crack, it was 
 as though the box burst into life with a loud

THUD/HISSSSSSSSSSSSSS THUD/HISSSSSSSSSSSSSS THUD/HISSSSSSSSSSSSSS

again and again at least 10 times, and it continued loudly 
 as I gently closed the box, folded my step ladder and walked 
 away..

It REALLY sounded like an angry striking snake on the inside 
 of that nest box. Anyone hearing it without knowing what was 
 making the noise would have definitely jumped clear of that 
 box in a hurry for fear of getting snake bitten.

Gary Springer
 
Date: Fri, 11 May 2001 22:46:03 -0700 (PDT)
From: Horace Sher hjsher1&quot;at&quot;yahoo.com
Subject: Fledging TUTI today... a magnificent day

Dear people on the list...I feel like telling this short story 
 about my 2 TUTI boxes located about 15-20 ft. from my deck. 
 My 2 backyard TUTI boxes are located about 30-40 ft. from each 
 other&amp;each about 15-20 ft. from the deck where I can observe 
 almost everything. Well, today most of the nestlings in 
 these 2 boxes are 16 days old,&amp;as I was looking at the 
 boxes from the deck with&amp;without binoculars..I started 
 seeing a nestling in each box poke its head out through the 
 opening while flapping its wings&amp;still being inside. This 
 went on for about 1/2 hour. Then 1 flew out&amp;to a nearby 
 tree. One of its parents flew right to him. They both flew to 
 another higher nearby tree&amp;disappeared on me. But what 
 happened a little later on at the 2nd box, I feel as though 
 it was a once in a lifetime occurance for me. Same thing as 
 1st box. Nestling poking it head out, etc. Then it flew out 
 onto the nearby ground&amp;hopped around..then didn&apos;t move. 
 Meanwhile, a 2nd nestling is poking its head out of the 2nd 
 box, etc.&amp;guess what? (Remember, I&apos;m still standing on 
 the deck.) It flew out of the box&amp;straight to me&amp;landed on the deck rail, right in front of me. I gently picked 
 it up,&amp;I helped it perch on my right forefinger... a 16 
 day old TUTI fledgling..can you believe this? After letting 
 it stay there on my finger for a few minutes to see if it would 
 fly away..no, it wouldn&apos;t. So I took it down the steps from 
 the deck&amp;brought it right next to its sibling which was 
 still on the ground near the box..&amp;I left to go back up 
 on the deck. So these 2 siblings hobbled&amp;hopped around.. 
 flapping their wings for at least 20 minutes,&amp;then both 
 flew shakedly up to a nearby treesy bush. I saw a parent go 
 to them,&amp;they disappeared on me. Well, not seeing anymore 
 activity around the 2nd box..I went to check the 2nd box gently 
 to see who was still there. And guess what..that little nestling 
 that flew right to me which I had thought was #2...apparently 
 was the last of the 5 fledglings to leave the 2nd box. Well, 
 it&apos;s now about 8:00 PM&amp;getting darker. At the 1st box, 
 1 or 2 nestlings had fledged,&amp;as I gently checked that 
 one, there are still 2 or 3 nestlings still in the box for the 
 night. A parent came near that box about 25 min. before dark&amp;sounded a call which I interpreted as..stay put little 
 ones..I&apos;ll be back in the morning to get you. Well, so 
 far this season, I don&apos;t have any nesting EABL like last year..only 
 3 boxes of TUTI&amp;1 box of Chickadees that fledged last 
 week. (I also saw the CACH fledge, too.) I have to say that 
 this TUTI&amp;Chickadee experience is just as good as my last 
 year EABL experience...Hope everyone is enjoying their Bluebirds....Horace 
 in NC.
 Date: Wed, 24 Apr 2002 08:31:03 -0700 (PDT)
Subject: OT: Titmice
To: BLUEBIRD bluebird-l&quot;at&quot;cornell.edu
I gave my parents a bluebird house last year, and this year 
 a nest was built. It didn&apos;t look like a bluebird nest, and there 
 were chickadees, titmice and nuthatches all going in and out 
 of the house, so we didn&apos;t know who the&quot;owner&quot;was. 
 On Sunday, we discovered it was the titmice and there are 3 
 baby birds they are feeding. I don&apos;t know a lot of about titmice 
 and their nesting habits -- I did see an earlier post about 
 titmice being very timid. I&apos;m just looking for any comments/information 
 that this knowledgeable group might have on titmice that I can 
 share with my parents. If you have resources to direct me to, 
 that would be great, too. I&apos;d like to read up on them. For instance, 
 is the time to fledge about the same as bluebirds -- or shorter/longer?

Thanks in advance.
Kathy Rauschenberg
Alpharetta, GA
 
From:&quot;MJShearer&quot;eshearer&quot;at&quot;attbi.com
Subject: Re: Titmice
Date: Wed, 24 Apr 2002 13:52:31 -0400

Hi Kathy,

I just checked the three nestboxes in my yard and discovered 
 the baby titmice are hatching today. Here&apos;s some titmouse information 
 that I found on http://www.natureserve.org/

**************************

Reproduction Comments: Clutch size is 5-8 (commonly 5-6). Sometimes 
 2 broods per year. Incubation, by female, lasts 12-14 days. 
 Young are tended by both parents (and sometimes young of first 
 brood), leave nest at 15-18 days.

Non-Migrant: Y

Palustrine Habitat(s): RIPARIAN

Terrestrial Habitat(s): FOREST - CONIFER, FOREST - HARDWOOD, 
 FOREST - MIXED, SHRUBLAND/CHAPARRAL, SUBURBAN/ORCHARD, WOODLAND 
 - CONIFER, WOODLAND - HARDWOOD, WOODLAND - MIXED

Special Habitat Factors: STANDING SNAG/HOLLOW TREE

Habitat Comments: Forest, woodland, scrub, and partly open 
 situations with scattered trees, from deciduous and mixed woodland 
 in the northeast to oak-juniper scrub, mesquite, and riparian 
 woodland in the southwest; also wooded parks and residential 
 areas. Nests in natural cavity in tree, or in old woodpecker 
 hole, or in artificial cavity such as pipe, bird box, 1-27 m 
 above ground (Harrison 1978).

Food Habits: FRUGIVORE, GRANIVORE, INVERTIVORE

Food Comments: Eats insects, spiders, small fruits, and seeds 
 (Terres 1980); the latter two items eaten most abundantly in 
 colder months

**********************************

You could also check enature.com or the Cornell site for more 
 info. Although these birds&quot;know&quot;me and feed at 
 feeders on my deck every day, they really didn&apos;t want me looking 
 into their nest. Unless I see signs of a problem with the babies, 
 I won&apos;t open their box again. Hopefully, I&apos;ll get to see them 
 fledge....

MJ
(Mary Jane Shearer; Tucker, GA)
 
Date: Wed, 24 Apr 2002 20:39:24 EDT
From:&quot;Rwatts&quot;rwatts&quot;at&quot;mymailstation.com
Subject: Re:OT: Titmice

If you have resources to direct me to, that would be great, 
 too. I&apos;d like to read up on them. For instance, is the time 
 to fledge about the same as bluebirds -- or shorter/longer?

The Birder&apos;s Handbook gives fledge time as 15-18 days. It&apos;s 
 a great book--ISBN 0-671-62133-5, paperback ISBN 0-671-65989-8.

Rhonda Watts
Wilton, N.H.
 
Date: Tue, 07 May 2002 22:59:23 -0400
From: Haleya Priest mablue&quot;at&quot;gis.net
Subject: TUTI question

Haleya Priest Amherst MA
I have what I believe is the beginnings of my very first Tufted 
 Titmouse nest! This is one of my original boxes with an oval 
 hole.....

I didn&apos;t put a restrictor hole on it. I&apos;ve heard TUTI&apos;s are 
 very shy. Is it too late now to put the restrictor hole on it? 
 Nest was just started.

THANKS folks for all your great advice! Any is appreciated 
 as I am very green in this department. :-) H
 
To: bluebird-l&quot;at&quot;cornell.edu
Date: Tue, 7 May 2002 23:10:05 -0400
Subject: Re: TUTI question

I waited till the nest is done and one egg before I put the 
 restrictor hole on the box. If I do it before this , the TUTI 
 will not come back. The TUTI is a nice bird to have.

Maynard Sumner
Flint, MI
 
Date: Wed, 8 May 2002 02:50:59 -0700 (PDT)
From: Daniel Sparks dansparks_47448&quot;at&quot;yahoo.com
Subject: Re: TUTI question

After installing a restrictor hole--the TUTI may continue nest-building 
 un-affected or it might make them apprehensive to where they 
 look for another nestbox.Who can predict? It&apos;s your decision.

Dan Sparks
P.O. Box 660
Brown County Bluebird Society
Nashville, IN 47448
 
Date: Wed, 8 May 2002 10:36:38 -0400
From:&quot;Seward, Elizabeth D.
Subject: RE: TUTI question

I&apos;d follow Maynard&apos;s advice. Once the TUTI have eggs 
 they will not abandon the nest lightly. You can monitor 
 them as with the EABL&apos;s. Last year our neighbor&apos;s TUTI nest 
 was totally soaked after a hard rain. I removed the four 
 or five day-old nestlings to a small paper bag filled with tissue, 
 followed advice gained on the list, and placed shredded newspaper 
 on the floor of the box, followed by dry materials (leaves and 
 moss) similar to the TUTI nesting materials. Replaced 
 the chicks. This was done in the early evening, and I 
 did not see the parents return to the nest immediately. Early the next morning I observed the parents feeding their 
 young as usual. My recollection is that they had 6 nestlings, 
 of which 4 fledged. Two were noticeably weak, and the 
 parents apparently removed them from the nest after they expired 
 (within the first week of hatching). 

Diane Seward
Potomac, MD
 
From:&quot;Gary Springer&quot;springer&quot;at&quot;alltel.net
Subject: Tufted titmice/ entrance hole reduction
Date: Wed, 8 May 2002 11:18:48 -0400

Hi Haleya,

I agree with Maynard..

Wait until all tufted titmice eggs are laid and the eggs have 
 been incubated for a couple days before reducing the entrance 
 hole to inch and a quarter.

I recommend this procedure for chickadees and tufted titmice
 for the reason Maynard gave.

The entrance should be reduced to inch and an eighth for chickadees 
 if house sparrows are present. Inch and a quarter is as 
 small as the hole can be reduced for tufted titmice.

Gary Springer
 
From: LauraSue14&quot;at&quot;aol.com
Date: Wed, 8 May 2002 14:57:44 EDT
Subject: Re: TUTI question

Hi Haleya,
I, too, have the first TUTI nest ever in my yard this year. 
 They built in a modified NABS box with a 1 1/2&quot;hole. They 
 do seem very shy compared to Bluebirds. Yesterday I peeked in 
 the nest which has 7 eggs and she was sitting tight. I quickly 
 closed up the box and went away. Every other time I looked (twice, 
 once when the nest was just completed and once when I discovered 
 7 eggs) she wasn&apos;t around. I don&apos;t know about the oval hole, 
 and with all the posts lately about Starlings getting chicks 
 out of that size hole, makes me a little nervous. I have 5 Bluebird 
 chicks in a modified Peterson (Herb&apos;s design) with an oval hole. 
 I don&apos;t see many Starlings around and this past week I have 
 heard and seen a male HOSP chirping for a mate :-(.

This is the first time I&apos;ve ever heard them in my yard. I sure 
 hope he is a lonely male and moves on to the closest fast food 
 restaurant!!! 

Laura, Marlborough, CT
 
From:&quot;Lawrence Herbert&quot;lherbert&quot;at&quot;4state.com
Subject: tuti ?
Date: Thu, 9 May 2002 17:41:13 -0500

Regarding modifying the nest box: since Tufted Titmouse have 
 started building a nest I would leave it alone until after they 
 have finished nesting. They seem to like it the way it is. That&apos;s 
 my vote.
Good birding, Larry H., Joplin MO.
 
From: Jgandy8580&quot;at&quot;aol.com
Date: Thu, 23 May 2002 10:48:24 EDT
Subject: Cigars are out in south Jersey

About 10:30 AM I spotted the female EABB out of the box so 
 I dashed over and quickly checked it. Young are hatched, but 
 they were pressed down low and I didn&apos;t take the time to count 
 them. I can do that in a day or two and, anyway, I&apos;ll gladly 
 take what I get. This encouraged me to check the titmouse box, 
 in the wooded area on a tree about a foot in diameter. I hate 
 to mention the subject of Tree Tanglefoot again, but I had that 
 on hand because I used it on this tree as the only way to keep 
 the field mice out of this box. Anyway, I was greeted by at 
 least 5 tiny heads with wide open beaks. Again, I did not stay 
 to count, but backed off quickly. Titmice must be used to me 
 as I walk by within a few feet of this house 4-5 times daily. 
 I was not 10 feet away watching them steadily return with food. 
 Not used to having titmice and was totally surprised to see 
 both go in box at same time. I think of my boxes as small, but 
 I guess they seem large to titmice.
 
From:&quot;ke4fej1&quot;ke4fej1&quot;at&quot;email.msn.com
Subject: Help on Tufted Titmouse
Date: Mon, 7 Apr 2003 18:06:39 -0400

Hi All, Just got a report we have 7 Tufted Titmouse babies...they 
 were noticed today...don&apos;t know if they were there yesterday.

The Monitor wants to know....when the babies fledge...do the 
 Titmouse return to the nest... or can it be cleaned out after 
 they fledge? Or do we keep it in the box for a while.

I read somewhere that in the South they will breed a second 
 time.

Don&apos;t know a think about these little fellows? Any help is 
 welcomed.

Thanks Christy Sarasota, FL
 
From: hubertrap&quot;at&quot;webtv.net (Joe Huber)
Date: Mon, 7 Apr 2003 22:46:26 -0400 (EDT)

Subject: Re: Help on Tufted Titmouse

HI CHristy, The Tufted titmouse generally nests only once so 
 when they finish fledging you can clean out their nest. You 
 will still have time to get Bluebirds to nest afterwards. Joe 
 huber Venice Fl.

Charter member NABS, Charter member OBS, Life member OBS Joe
 Huber
	</body>
</document>
