<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001132" url="http://womenshealth.about.com/od/girlshealth101/a/fastfoodteenwei.htm" time="2012-07-12-16:33" support="87" score="0.43857671859695324" bingtitle="How Eating Fast Food Affects the Health of Teens and Young Adults" webtitle="How Eating Fast Food Affects the Health of Teens and Young Adults">
			<query id="000856" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000720" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="000001" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000861" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000223" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000535" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000906" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000532" bing-rank="102"/>
			<query id="001475" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000865" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="001161" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="001508" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000887" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="001435" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000360" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000862" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000050" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000028" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000749" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="001524" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001107" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="001427" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000060" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000095" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="001515" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="001361" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000038" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="000892" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="001426" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="000345" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="001439" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000853" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000372" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000896" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="001163" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="000870" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000034" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="001125" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000019" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="001529" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="001490" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="000098" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000359" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="001534" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="000055" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000032" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000354" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="001478" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="001113" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000351" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000029" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000046" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="001189" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="001414" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="001104" bing-rank="50"/>
			<query id="000735" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="000907" bing-rank="170"/>
			<query id="000015" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="001348" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="001520" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000347" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="001160" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="001112" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="001351" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000007" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000723" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="001412" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000847" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000878" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="001506" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000002" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="001175" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000846" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="001512" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="000849" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000010" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000368" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="000373" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000363" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="001098" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000016" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="001121" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="000041" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="001116" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="000901" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="001100" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000024" bing-rank="84"/>
	<description>Eating frequent fast food meals causes teens and young ... “It’s extremely difficult to eat in a healthy way at a fast-food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Health 
 Women&apos;s Health Search 
 Women&apos;s Health Topics A-Z Sexual Health Healthy Living 

 Share 
 
 Discuss in our forum 
 
 Eating Fast Food Means Weight Gain, Insulin Resistance for Teens 

Press Release

From Tracee Cornforth , former About.com Guide

Updated July 19, 2009

About.com Health&apos;s Disease and Condition content is reviewed by the Medical Review Board 
 See More About: 
 teen health nutrition diabetes 
 Updated July 19, 2009 Eating frequent fast food meals causes teens and young adults to gain more weight and face an increased risk of developing insulin resistance according to the results of a study funded by the National Heart,Lung, and Blood Institute(NHLBI) and published in the January 1, 2005 issue of The Lancet.*
After 15 years, those who ate at fast-food restaurants more than twice each week compared to less than once a week had gained an extra ten pounds and had a two-fold greater increase in insulin resistance, a risk factor for type 2 diabetes. Diabetes is a major risk factor for heart disease.
“Obesity and diabetes are on the rise in this country and this important study highlights the value of healthy eating habits,”said NHLBI Acting Director Barbara Alving, M.D.
Fast-food consumption has increased in the United States over the past three decades.“It’s extremely difficult to eat in a healthy way at a fast-food restaurant. Despite some of their recent healthful offerings, the menus still tend to include foods high in fat, sugar and calories and low in fiber and nutrients,”said lead author Mark Pereira, Ph.D., assistant professor of epidemiology at the University of Minnesota. People need to evaluate how often they eat meals at fast-food restaurants and think about cutting back, according to Pereira.
One reason for the weight gain may be that a single meal from one of these restaurants often contains enough calories to satisfy a person’s caloric requirement for an entire day.
Participants were asked during the physical examinations given as part of the study how often they ate breakfast, lunch or dinner at fast-food restaurants. Researchers found that the adverse impact on participants’weight and insulin resistance was seen in both blacks and whites who ate frequently at fast-food restaurants, even after adjustment for other lifestyle habits.
Study participants included 3,031 young black and white adults who were between the ages of 18 and 30 in 1985-1986. The participants, who were part of the Coronary Artery Risk Development in Young Adults (CARDIA) study, received dietary assessments over a 15-year period. CARDIA centers are located in Birmingham, AL, Chicago, IL, Minneapolis, MN, and Oakland, CA.
According to the study, men visited fast-food restaurants more frequently than women and blacks more frequently than whites. Black men reported an average frequency of 2.3 visits per week in 2000-01. White women had the lowest frequency, at an average of 1.3 visits per week in 2000-01.
“It is important to watch carefully what you eat, especially at a fast-food restaurant. Knowing the nutritional content is important. Consumers may want to ask for this information,”said NHLBI’s Gina Wei, M.D., project officer for CARDIA. Salads and grilled foods tend to be lower in fat than fried foods, she said.
Keep portion sizes small, and ask that high-fat sauces and condiments, such as salad dressing and mayonnaise, be“on the side”and use them sparingly to reduce calories, Wei said.
For more information and tips on maintaining weight visit the following Web pages:

 Aim for a Healthy Weight Portion Distortion 

*“Fast-food Habits, Weight Gain, and Insulin Resistance (The CARDIA Study): 15-Year Prospective Analysis”. Mark Pereira, Alex I. Kartashov, Cara B. Ebbeling, Linda Van Horn, Martha L. Slattery, David R. Jacobs, Jr., David S. Ludwig. The Lance t, January 1, 2005.
NIH Press Release 
Suggested Reading

 Healthy Food Choices for Pregnant Teens Things That Can Affect Your Period See No Fat! Hear No Fat! Eat No Fat? 
 Related Articles 
 Low-Carb Fast Food - How to Eat Low-Carb at a Fast-Food Restaurant Fast Food - Raising a Two-Year-Old Weight Loss Breakthroughs -- Four New Studies Expand Knowledge Of Hormones,... Diet or Exercise for Weight Loss - Obesity, Food Intake, or Exercise Portion Control - Study About Restaurants and Portion Control 
 Related Searches national heart lung and blood institute fast food restaurants national heart lung fast food restaurant insulin resistance healthy eating habits Explore Women&apos;s Health Must Reads 
 Going to the Gynecologist Menstruation Basics Pregnancy Signs and Symptoms Birth Control Myths Top Causes of Heavy Menstruation 
 Most Popular 
 Causes of Vaginal Bleeding Urinary Tract Infections Bleeding Between Periods what_does_it_mean_if_im Bumps and Lumps Below the Skin 
 See More About: 
 teen health nutrition diabetes 
 By Category 
 Birth Control Menstruation Heart Health Menopause Breast Health and Diseases Sexual Health Female Reproductive Health Fitness and Health Pregnancy Teen Health Mental Health Cancer Women&apos;s Health Glossary Diseases and Conditions Health and Beauty 
 Women&apos;s Health 
 About.com Health Women&apos;s Health Teen Health How Eating Fast Food Affects the Health of Teens and Young Adults 
 
 Most Popular Latest Articles RSS 
 Also from About.com: 
 Calorie Count - Nutrition Database 
 
 Advertise on About.com Our Story News&amp;Events Work at About SiteMap All Topics Reprints Help 

 Write for About User Agreement Ethics Policy Patent Info. Privacy Policy Your Ad Choices 
 
©2012 About.com. All rights reserved.

A part of The New York Times Company .
 We comply with the HONcode standard
for trustworthy health information: verify here .
	</body>
</document>
