<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001200" url="http://www.gosanangelo.com/news/2011/dec/03/police-investigate-armed-robbery-fast-food-restaur/" time="2012-07-12-16:39" support="4" score="0.012082292477244308" bingtitle="Police investigate armed robbery at fast food restaurant ..." webtitle="Police investigate armed robbery at fast food restaurantStandard-Times">
			<query id="001238" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="001222" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="001250" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="001241" bing-rank="148"/>
	<description>Police investigate armed robbery at fast food restaurant ... Daily Chat: &quot;You throw like a girl!&quot; Published 4 ... Realtors; Remodeling; Restaurants; Storage; Veterinarians</description>
	<body>
		Login | Manage Account | Mobile | Contact Us | Site Map | Subscriptions | eEdition | 
 User Name: 
 Password: Forgotten your password?  | Create an account Register or log in using your account on these websites. site web 
Web Search powered by Yahoo! SEARCH
 San Angelo Standard Times 
 News 
 Today Local 
 Public Records Press Releases Eldorado, TX FLDS 
 Obituaries 
 Death Notices 
 My San Angelo 
 Anniversaries Announcements Birthdays Engagements My Town San Angelo Guide Thank You Weddings Community Bulletin Board Youth Sports 
 Data Center 
 Legal Notices Legal Articles Sex Offender Search Searchable Data Bases Property Crimes Map Home Valuation Unclaimed Property Lake Levels Gas Prices 
 State National World Politics Education 
 Central High School Lake View High School TLC Academy NIE 
 Alerts Columnists 
 Nicole Burnett Nicole Lira Sabrina Ogletree Kirsten Peters Mackenzie Shanafelt Rick Smith 
 
 Sports 
 Local High School 
 Blitz Blitz Hoops Stadium Locator 
 College Professional 
 S.A. Colts Football Drag Boat Assn. 
 Golf Rodeo 
 Stock Show&amp;Rodeo Rodeo News Roping Fiesta 
 Recreation Other Columnists 
 Kevin Collins Bill Cullins Jason Hase Jimmy Tidwell Anthony Wilson 
 Olympic Games 
 Business 
 Local Oil&amp;Energy Ag&amp;Natural Resources National / International Technology Columnists 
 Dick Baggett Jerry Lackey Mario Castillo David Erickson Cindy Hartin Paul Howard Peggy Hodges Jessica Lambert Alex Mills 
 
 Opinion 
 Editorial Letters to the Editor Viewpoints Polls Columnists 
 Jack Cowan Dudra Butler Russ Duerstine Linda Shoemaker Bruce McLaren Britt Towery 
 
 Entertainment 
 Local Arts / Theater 
 Books Movies 
 Dining 
 Restaurants Open Now Submit Restaurant Bars&amp;Clubs Food&amp;Drink Specials 
 Event Calendar 
 Nightlife Submit Event San Angelo Venues 
 Contest Zone Celebrity News Bridge Results 
 Lifestyles 
 Fashion&amp;Style Faith&amp;Values Food Health&amp;Fitness Family Attractions Bluebonnet Drive Columnists 
 Kathy Aycock John Begnaud Damon Bell Becky Bray Gus Clemens Shannon Coad JoAnn Dalgard Glenn Dromgoole Linda Grace Jeffrey Hoelle Kyle Hooks Rashda Kahn Terry Mattingly Ross McSwain Jeannie Miley Ami Mizell-Flint Michael Price Dave Ramsey Vianei Robinson Laurel Scott Evi Shaw Howard Taylor Patti Tucker Allison Watkins Keith Wommack 
 
 Media 
 Today&apos;s Photos Photo Archive Photo Galleries Photo Galleries by Topic Buy Staff Photos Videos Audio/Podcasts User Submitted 
 

 Jobs Homes Cars Classified 
 
 
WHO IS DONATING TO WHO?

 Click for database of who donates to the presidential campaigns locally. 
 
$1.8 MILLION IN PAST DUE COURT CASES

 Click for database of past due court cases for the Justice of the Peace Districts. 
 
JUNE 2012 OUTSTANDING WARRANTS LIST

 Any person listed here is subject to arrest at any time. 
 
HISTORICAL RAINFALL DATA

 Click for database of monthly rainfall amounts going back to 1867. 
 
 
Police investigate armed robbery at fast food restaurant

 Posted December 3, 2011 at 1:07 p.m. 

 Discuss Print A A A 
 

 
San Angelo Police were investigating an armed robbery that occurred early Saturday morning at a local drive-through window.

Officers were called to Whataburger, in the 4600 block of Knickerbocker road, about 5:05 a.m. in reference to robbery that had just occurred.

An employee at the restaurant told responding Officer Bary Ratcliff that a dark colored SUV pulled up to the drive-through window when the passenger pointed a gun at the employee, according to a police news release.

The driver demanded that the employee gather all money from the restaurant, police said.

The driver and passenger were described as white men, one about 35 years old and one in his early 20s.

The employee turned over an undisclosed amount of money to the two suspects and they drove away, according to the release.

Officers searched the area, but were unable to find the suspect vehicle. Detective Chris Soto was assigned to the case.

It is still under investigation.
 
 ©2011 San Angelo Standard Times. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 
 Discuss Print 
 


 
 
 Also in Crime and Punishment 

 More 
 
 Report: Penn State could have stopped abuse in &apos;98 Man suspected of gas main bombing indicted Woman on state death row loses federal appeal 
 
Comments » 0 
 
Be the first to post a comment!
 
Share your thoughts

Comments are the sole responsibility of the person posting them. You agree not to post comments that are off topic, defamatory, obscene, abusive, threatening or an invasion of privacy. Violators may be banned. Click here for our full user agreement .
 
 Username * Don&apos;t have an account? Sign up for a new account 

 Password * Can&apos;t remember? Reset your password 

 Comment 
 
 
 
Comments can be shared on 
 
 
 Facebook
 and 
 Yahoo!.
Add both options by connecting your profiles .
 
Newsletters
 
 Go Entertainment News Crave Food&amp;Cooking eSaver Offers Breaking news alerts 
 
Most Popular
 
 Viewed Commented Emailed 
 
 Border Patrol moving workers Published 7/10/2012 at 8:22 p.m. 38 comments Threat to Texas hunting season surfaces Published 7/11/2012 at 7:46 p.m. 0 comments Poor face limited health care choices Updated 7/8/2012 at 10:22 p.m. 43 comments Perry: Medicaid a &apos;failure&apos; akin to Titanic Published 7/9/2012 at 11:05 a.m. 44 comments BUSINESS BULLETIN: Freebirds, Smiling Moose hits with diners Updated 7/8/2012 at 10:18 p.m. 30 comments 
 
Photo Galleries
 2012 women Olympic athletes Mr. Dog fourth annual San Angelo… GOT GAME: Soccer ladies take the &apos;pitch&apos; 
 Perry: Medicaid a &apos;failure&apos; akin to Titanic Updated // at : 44 comments Border Patrol moving workers Updated // at : 38 comments Poor face limited health care choices Updated 7/8/2012 at 10:22 p.m. 43 comments BUSINESS BULLETIN: Freebirds, Smiling Moose hits with diners Updated 7/8/2012 at 10:18 p.m. 30 comments Daily Chat: It just keeps going and going and going... Updated // at : 27 comments 
 
 Addressing the internet malware threat this Monday — exactly what to do Updated // at : 8 comments Malware may knock thousands off Internet on Monday Updated // at : 16 comments Cowboy still knows how to tie one on Updated 7/9/2012 at 11:06 p.m. 2 comments Threat to Texas hunting season surfaces Updated // at : 0 comments Houston police raise cancer funds with bike ride Updated 7/2/2012 at 10:13 p.m. 3 comments 
 
Weather
 
 Currently 36-Hour Your Photos 
 Currently 77 ° Fair Wind: NW 5mph Today 93 ° 72 ° Thu 10:00 PM Partly Cloudy Temp: 83° Fri 10:00 AM Partly Sunny Temp: 83° Fri 10:00 PM Partly Cloudy Temp: 82° 
Feels Like: 83°

Humidity: 48%

Precip: 10%
 
Feels Like: 84°

Humidity: 53%

Precip: 8%
 
Feels Like: 82°

Humidity: 44%

Precip: 7%
 Water flows into Concho 4/10/12
2:52 p.m.
 Water flows into Concho 4/10/12
2:52 p.m.
 Tornado-warned storm 4/9/12
6:41 a.m.
 Beauty of rain 2/18/12
8:43 a.m.
 What a snowy day 2/12/12
8:24 p.m.
 Snow Day at Visitors Center 2/12/12
7:30 p.m.
 More Weather» 
Business Directory
 
 Search Browse 
 Business: e.g. salon Location: e.g. San Angelo, TX 
 Powered by Local.com 
 Auto Dealers Auto Repair Books Carpet Cleaning Child Care Coffee Shops Dentists Doctors Florists Furniture Golf Courses Gyms Hair Salons Hotels Insurance Jewelry Lawn Services Locksmiths Movers Pizza Plumbing Realtors Remodeling Restaurants Storage Veterinarians 
 Powered by Local.com Full Directory» 
Features
 

 
 
 John Rae Powell Can&apos;t Get Enough. 

 
 
 Lowest gas prices in San Angelo 

 Where they are... Report a sighting... 
 
 Sign up today! 

 Get notifications in your email - click here! 
 
 Visitor&apos;s Guide 2012-2013 coming! 

 Your investment guide is here! 
 
 San Angelo Duplicate Bridge 

 Click for June 28-July 4 weekly results. 
 
 ASU Events Calendar 

 Click for comprehensive event list. 
 
 Newsletter sign up 

 For San Angelo Moms — click here! 
 
 Who&apos;s the Best? 

 The readers have spoken. Click here. 
 
 San Angelo Living 2012 

 Check out our San Angelo Living section here! 
 
 June 2012 Outstanding Warrants 

 Subject to arrest at any time. 
 
 Property Crime report/map update 

 99 problems and the cops ain&apos;t one! 
 
 Meh Cat says &quot;Entertain me!&quot; 

 Amusement: click here-Music, events, golf, more! 
 
 Garage Sales Map-Click here 

 Click on a marker for a description of the sale. 
 
 On the Web: Find San Angelo Jobs Special Sections Online Databases Money Clip + Health page Online Exclusives: Visitors Guide Play Online Games Useful Links: User Guide Classified Ads Newspaper archives Restaurant Guide eEdition User Guide Newsletter Signup: Breaking News Go Entertainment Crave Back 9 Daily Headlines Special Features: Tornado Alley Live! San Angelo Moms Strange and Weird Celebrations Newspapers in Education GoSanAngelo.com on Twitter and Facebook Submit: Church Briefs Volunteer Business Directory: San Angelo Apartments San Angelo Attorneys San Angelo Auto Dealers San Angelo Auto Parts San Angelo Auto Repair San Angelo Beauty Salons San Angelo Car Rental San Angelo Dentists San Angelo Doctors San Angelo Flowers San Angelo Hotels San Angelo Insurance San Angelo Loans San Angelo Mortgages San Angelo Movers San Angelo Pizza San Angelo Realtors San Angelo Restaurants San Angelo Storage San Angelo Tax Preparation San Angelo Travel Featured More... 
 Business Directory 
 Business: e.g. salon Location: e.g. San Angelo, TX 
 Powered by Local.com Scripps Interactive Newspapers Group
2012 The E.W. Scripps Co.
 More news from our local partners» Privacy Policy | User Agreement | About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
