<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001509" url="http://www.thekitchn.com/what-to-do-if-you-get-a-foodbo-63039" time="2012-07-12-17:16" support="1" score="0.0005392932864412966" bingtitle="What To Do If You Get A Food-Borne Illness | The Kitchn" webtitle="What To Do If You Get A Food-Borne Illness | The Kitchn">
			<query id="000230" bing-rank="198"/>
	<description>It&apos;s saved me a number of times. If you can&apos;t keep any fluid in, get to the hospital ... Ireland and we ate at a dodgy fast food restaurant ... Instead, drink a lot of water to ...</description>
	<body>
		Main Recipes Advice Supplies Kitchens Drinks Gatherings 

 Apartment Therapy Login 
 
 What To Do If You Get A Food-Borne Illness 
 
 Faith&apos;s post yesterday about what to do when your fridge goes out got us thinking. Sometimes even after all precautions are taken, food-borne illness does happen. Those little guys in the photo above might be microscopic, but they can really ruin your day, or worse. Do you know what to do if one of them finds its way into your system?

Food poisoning symptoms can occur as rapidly as 30 minutes of consuming tainted food and drink. Symptoms of food-borne illness include:

 Diarrhea (sometimes bloody) Nausea and vomiting Abdominal pain and/or cramping Malaise (general uneasiness) Fever 

Most of the times, food poisoning runs its course within 24 to 48 hours. However, in extreme situations one should seek medical care. eMedicineHealth.com has a comprehensive list here on what symptoms should prompt you to see a doctor. Such symptoms include:

 Nausea, vomiting, or diarrhea lasts for more than two days. The ill person is younger than three years. The ill person stops urinating, have decreased urination, or have urine that is dark in color. 

If your symptoms don&apos;t require medical attention, you can easily treat yourself at home. Do not eat any solid foods while you are vomiting. Instead, drink a lot of water to help prevent dehydration. Once vomiting and diarrhea have stopped for a period of time, slowly reintroduce plain, low-sugar foods that are easy on the stomach, such as the BRAT diet . Continue to stay hydrated.

Hopefully, you&apos;ll never have to use this advice, but it is good to know!

 (Images: Clockwise from top left - Listeria , E. coli , Vibrio , and Salmonella .) 
 7 comments 09.16.08 1:30PM Kathryn Hill 
Categories:
 Healthy Living 
Comments (7)
 
I can vouch for it ruining your day (or weekend, in my case). I drank a lot of seltzer with lemon because water just sounded vile for some reason.
 posted by Tiamat_the_Red on 09.16.08 at 09:51AM 
In terms of hydration, liquids like Gatorade or even salted water are good to replenish electrolytes, especially if you can&apos;t eat many bananas/food in general. When my husband got horrible food poisoning in India all he could process for days was Limca (a metallic-tasting Indian version of Squirt) with salt. Nursing someone with food poisoning really takes the realtionship to a whole new level of intimacy!
 posted by Squirrely on 09.16.08 at 10:04AM 
Don&apos;t take an anti-diarrheal drug (like Immodium or Pepto), it can sequester the bacteria and toxins in your intestine and cause major damage and also increases the length of time you&apos;re sick.

My trusted remedy is taking activated charcoal capsules. Don&apos;t be shy - you can take 10-15 in a single dose. The charcoal absorbs the pathogen as well as the toxins the pathogens belch out. You can get activated charcoal at Whole Foods or a health food store. It&apos;s saved me a number of times.

If you can&apos;t keep any fluid in, get to the hospital so that they can put in an IV drip. Getting severely dehydrated and having your electrolytes completely out of balance can be very dangerous (heart attack).
 posted by lailaemir on 09.16.08 at 10:13AM 
Peppermint tea works well for soothing your stomach after a bout, I discovered (I had a case of food poisoning when I was visiting a dear friend in Ireland and we ate at a dodgy fast food restaurant after a night at the pub).
 posted by empresscallipygos on 09.16.08 at 01:27PM 
stay away from subway (i think bad ranch dressing) and coffee bean tea leaf (spoiled milk). ugh city.
 posted by lagirl358 on 09.16.08 at 06:15PM 
&quot;Do not eat any solid foods while you are vomiting. Instead, drink a lot of water to help prevent dehydration.&quot; - is not a very good advice.

In fact, drinking water right after a vomiting bout (when you have a food poisoning) can make things much worse: the irritated stomach will reject the water, causing the person to throw up more, becoming even more dehydrated in the process.

It&apos;s commonly advised by doctors to wait 2 full hours after the last vomiting bout before taking a small sip of luke-warm (not cold!) water. Then it&apos;s a good idea to wait 15 more minutes and take another sip. If after two hours of sipping, the vomiting has not resumed, it&apos;s OK to drink as much water as you&apos;d like. If the vomiting came back, time to head to the ER.
 posted by LuckyMonkey on 09.17.08 at 09:04PM 
Last month I had to treat someone in the field for food poisoning. Poor guy couldnt even keep water down so he had lots of IV fluid, anti-nasuea meds, anti-diarrheals, and pain meds.

Benadryl works to help ease cramping of intestinal muscles.
 posted by bramasoleiowa on 09.19.08 at 07:44AM 
Post a comment
 Comment 
 &lt;a href&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;are allowed, and line breaks are automatic. Please be aware of our comment policy . Seeing spam? Let us know . 
    

Logged in as  |  Sign out . 
Please sign in or register to comment.
 The Kitchn 
 Small Cool Kitchens 2012 Tours 
 Cook&apos;s Kitchen Grower Maker 
 Meals 
 Breakfast Lunch Supper Snack Sweets 
 How To 
 Meat Tutorials Baking Tutorials 
 Questions 
 Ingredient Questions Recipe Questions Dinner Party Questions Health Questions Product&amp;Shopping Questions 
 Food&amp;Ingredients 
 Beverages Type of Dish Ingredients 
 Kitchen Tools 
 Small Electrics Bakeware Cookware Knives&amp;Cutlery Tools&amp;Utensils Kitchen Gadgets Food Containers&amp;Storage Aprons&amp;Clothing Towels&amp;Linens 
 Cookbooks 
 Cookbook Review Cookbook Recipe 
 Life in the Kitchen 
 Projects Gardening Organizing Housekeeping&amp;Cleaning Lifestyle 
 Season 
 Winter Spring Summer Autumn 
 Sweets Quick Budget All Categories 
 
Top Recipes

 How to Cook Moist&amp;Tender Chicken Breasts Every Time How to Make Kombucha Tea at Home How To Make Cake Pops Summer Recipe: Zucchini Boats with Mozzarella and Olives How To Cook Perfect Steak in the Oven 
 See more recipes 
Top Posts

 What Do You Serve Fussy&amp;Picky Eaters? 10 Recipes to Help Meet the Challenge Garlic Sprouting Too Fast? Preserve It for Later With This Tip! 15 Ways to Eat a Cold Salad for Supper The Most Popular Dish for Olympic Athletes in Summer 2012: Can You Guess? Freeze&amp;Preserve Fresh Herbs in Olive Oil 
 
Email Updates
 
Submit a Story

Got a tip, kitchen tour, or other story our readers should see?
 Tell us about it 
Follow Us
 @TheKitchn Like us on Facebook RSS Feed Our reading list See more options 
Read Our Books

 Good Food to Share (2011) The Big Book of Small, Cool Spaces (2010) Apartment Therapy Presents (2008) The Eight-Step Home Cure (2006) 
 
Faith’s Daily Find
 
 Home Cooking: A Wri... Sombrero Juicer fro... TANGKORN Seaweed To... 
 Go to Apartment Therapy Marketplace Inspiring cooks, nourishing homes 
 About Us Our Team Contact Us 
 
Email Updates
 
Apartment Therapy
 
Top Posts

 15 Crazy Ideas to Make Your Life Saner Before&amp;After: Updated Bamboo Etageres 10 DIY Wall Art Ideas That Anyone Can Do Before and After: A Real Life LEGO Bridge Over-Sharing and Over-Caring: Decorating Our Homes in the Digital Age 
 
Top Tours

 Kristina&amp;Tyler&apos;s Whitley Heights Home Myles&amp;Grace&apos;s La Cañada Light House Long Island City: Modern Living at the View Joshua&apos;s Vintage Daydream Eva&apos;s Eclectic&amp;Elegant Pad 
 
The Kitchn
 
Top Posts

 What Do You Serve Fussy&amp;Picky Eaters? 10 Recipes to Help Meet the Challenge Garlic Sprouting Too Fast? Preserve It for Later With This Tip! 15 Ways to Eat a Cold Salad for Supper The Most Popular Dish for Olympic Athletes in Summer 2012: Can You Guess? Freeze&amp;Preserve Fresh Herbs in Olive Oil 
 
Top Recipes

 How to Cook Moist&amp;Tender Chicken Breasts Every Time How to Make Kombucha Tea at Home How To Make Cake Pops Summer Recipe: Zucchini Boats with Mozzarella and Olives How To Cook Perfect Steak in the Oven 
 ©2012 Apartment Therapy Advertising Jobs Legal Privacy Policy Comment Policy
	</body>
</document>
