<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001577" url="http://recipes.howstuffworks.com/10-ingredients-fast-food.htm" time="2012-07-12-17:21" support="20" score="0.099019789417874" bingtitle="TLC Cooking &quot;Top 10 Most Common Ingredients in Fast Food&quot;" webtitle="TLC CookingTop 10 Most Common Ingredients in Fast Food">
			<query id="000610" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="000594" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="000901" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000220" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="001126" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000622" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="001512" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="001348" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="001534" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="001475" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="000887" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000906" bing-rank="42"/>
			<query id="000925" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000909" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="001107" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="001529" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="001104" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000373" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="001515" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000095" bing-rank="244"/>
	<description>5 Failed McDonald&apos;s Menu Items; TreeHugger.com: Will the Recession ... Order a meal in any fast-food restaurant, and you&apos;ll likely walk away with a sandwich, fries and a drink.</description>
	<body>
		SITE SEARCH 
 SHOWS 
 TLC Casting 19 Kids and Counting A Conception Story Cake Boss Craft Wars DC Cupcakes Extreme Couponing Four Houses Four Weddings Hoarding: Buried Alive Kitchen Boss The Little Couple Little People, Big World Long Island Medium My Big Fat American Gypsy Wedding My Big Fat Gypsy Wedding My Crazy Obsession My Strange Addiction Next Great Baker On the Fly Randy to the Rescue Say Yes to the Dress Say Yes to the Dress: Atlanta Say Yes to the Dress: Bridesmaids Sister Wives Strange Sex Toddlers&amp;Tiaras Virgin Diaries What Not to Wear More Shows 
| ON TV 
 Daily TV Schedule Weekly TV Schedule 
| VIDEO 
 Full Episodes Aftershows Building a Home Take Charge of Your Everyday All TLC Videos 
| SOCIAL 
 19 Kids&amp;Counting Cake Boss Extreme Couponing Kate Plus 8 LA Ink NY Ink Say Yes to the Dress Sister Wives What Not to Wear 
| GAMES 
 Coupon Challenge Game Supersized Family Game My Big Fat Gypsy Wedding Game NY Ink Photo Game Virtual Tattoo Game Virtual Bridal Boutique TLC Original Games Web and Downloadable Games Games for Kids 
| SHOP | 
 COOKING | FAMILY | HOME | STYLE | WEDDINGS TLC Store TLC Trivia Giveaway Contest   
 Recipes Menus Tools&amp;Techniques Healthy Living Food Facts&amp;Fun Fresh Ideas for Dinner 
 
 TLC  &gt;  Guides  &gt;  Food  &gt;  Food Facts&amp;Fun  &gt;  Food Processing 
 
 Top 10 Most Common Ingredients in Fast Food 

by William Harris 
   Cite This! Close  Please copy/paste the following text to properly cite this HowStuffWorks article: 

 Harris, William. &quot;Top 10 Most Common Ingredients in Fast Food&quot; 04 May 2009. HowStuffWorks.com.&lt;http://recipes.howstuffworks.com/10-ingredients-fast-food.htm&gt; 12 July 2012. Cite Feedback Fast Food Image Gallery 
On newer fast-food menus you may be able to find the caloric information, but do you know what that food&apos;s made of? See more pictures of fast food .

 AP Photo /Ed Ou
 
Fast-food Nation
 
 10 Restaurant Secrets to Make an Incredible Meal 5 Failed McDonald&apos;s Menu Items TreeHugger.com: Will the Recession Make Us Fat? 
 
Order a meal in any fast-food restaurant, and you&apos;ll likely walk away with a sandwich, fries and a drink. If you had to identify the ingredients of this meal, you might list beef (or chicken), lettuce , tomato , cheese , ketchup, bread , potatoes and soda. Not complicated, right? Wrong.

Burger and chicken joints don&apos;t think of the building blocks of a menu item as ingredients. They think of them as components, which are made of ingredients. For example, McDonald&apos;s famous Big Mac jingle --&quot;two all beef patties, special sauce, lettuce, cheese, pickles, onions on a sesame seed bun&quot;-- suggests the sandwich has seven components. Would you believe it has 67 ingredients?

Clearly, fast food is more complicated than it looks. Many menu items contain processed foods, which have been modified from their natural state for safety or convenience. Processed foods tend to have multiple additives to keep them fresher longer. Across an entire fast-food menu, there are thousands of ingredients, ranging from the commonplace ( water ) to the exotic (xanthan gum).

Considering that some of these ingredients have been implicated in serious health issues, it would be good to know which are the most common. We&apos;ve set out to answer that very question. We started with menus from five popular fast-food chains -- McDonald&apos;s, Burger King, Taco Bell, KFC and Arby&apos;s -- did some tallying, then cross-matched our findings with the U.S. Food and Drug Administration&apos;s list of common food ingredients and colors. The result is the top 10 most common ingredients in fast food, organized by the type of ingredient and what it does.

Up first is the most common preservative.
   
Popular Articles
 10 Common Genetically Modified Foods Top 5 Foods You Should Eat Only When They&apos;re In Season 10 Healthiest School Lunch Plans 10 Foods You Should Buy Organic Top 10 Healthy and Cheap Foods See All Lists» search recipes 
ON TLC Now
 A Conception Story Season 3 Videos Toddlers Unforgettable Moments! 
Trending Now
 
 Crafts Gone Wrong Reinvent Your Home! Take Charge! Share Your Coupons! Cake Boss Delivery Dash 
 OUR SITES 
 Animal Planet Curiosity Discovery Channel Discovery Kids Discovery Fit&amp;Health Investigation Discovery Military Channel Oprah Winfrey Network Destination America Science Channel TLC Velocity 
 
 Consumer Guide Auto Consumer Guide Products Discovery News HowStuffWorks Petfinder Revision3 TreeHugger My Discovery Discovery Education Student Competitions Discovery Music Source Discovery Access Discovery Retreats 
 VIDEO 
 TLC Video Full Episodes 
 MOBILE 
 Mobile Applications Wallpaper&amp;Ringtones Mobile Video Mobile Web Games&amp;Applications Text Alerts 
 SHOP 
 TLC Store DVDs&amp;Books Custom Gear Toys&amp;Games Gift Sets Jon&amp;Kate Plus 8 Sale Discovery Adventures Student Adventures Discovery Times Square Discovery Corporate Sales 
 STAY CONNECTED 
 Email Newsletters RSS Twitter Facebook 
 CORPORATE 
 Discovery Communications, LLC Viewer Relations Advertising Careers @ Discovery Privacy Policy Visitor Agreement 
 
Copyright©2012 Discovery Communications, LLC. The number-one nonfiction media company.
	</body>
</document>
