<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001138" url="http://www.briki.com/briki/Texas/TX/HOUSTON/77090/18203_WESTFIELD_PLACE_DR/18203_WESTFIELD_PLACE_DR_Houston,_TX_77090.html" time="2012-07-12-16:34" support="1" score="0.0007876808337226806" bingtitle="Briki.com &gt; 18203 WESTFIELD PLACE DR Houston, TX 77090" webtitle="Briki.com &gt; 18203 WESTFIELD PLACE DR Houston, TX 77090">
			<query id="000667" bing-rank="98"/>
	<description>Sanborn Coverage: Lookup: Date of Development: Acreage: Number of Stories: Notes: Property Photographs : 18203 WESTFIELD PLACE DR, HOUSTON, TX 77090 The following ...</description>
	<body>
		Briki.com &gt; 18203 WESTFIELD PLACE DR Houston, TX 77090 

 Print This Page Login 
   
Property Overview : 18203 WESTFIELD PLACE DR, HOUSTON, TX 77090

View a brief overview of the data available for 18203 WESTFIELD PLACE DR, HOUSTON, TX 77090.
 
Property Satellite Map

 More... 
 
 
Property Photograph

 More... 
 
Recently Uploaded Files

 More... 
 


No files have been uploaded... Upload One! 
 
Recent Discussion Threads Started

 More... 
 


No discussions have been started... Start One! 
   
Property Location : 18203 WESTFIELD PLACE DR, HOUSTON, TX 77090

View the location of 18203 WESTFIELD PLACE DR, HOUSTON, TX 77090
   
Property Information : 18203 WESTFIELD PLACE DR, HOUSTON, TX 77090

The following information has been added to the Briki for 18203 WESTFIELD PLACE DR, HOUSTON, TX 77090. You can add or edit information. Changes are automatically saved.
 You must be logged in to edit this information. Please Login or Register . 
 Information Saved! 
 Property Use: Tenant: Property Type: Select One... Agribusiness-Auction/Market Agribusiness-Dairy Agribusiness-Feedlot Agribusiness-Grain Elevator Agribusiness-Greenhouse/Nursery Agribusiness-Livestock Farms Agribusiness-Poultry Agribusiness-Swine Pasture/Ranch Permanent Crops-Orchard/Grove/Vineyard Row Crops sub Timberland Armory/Club/Lodge Facility Community/Recreation Center Convention Center Reception Hall/Banquet Facility Religious Facility Acute Care Hospital Ambulatory Surgery Center Behavioral Care Facility Clinical Laboratory Comprehensive Ambulatory Care Center Medical Center Rehabilitation Center/Hospital Commercial Laundry Communications/Server Farm Condominium Bldg(s) Condominium Unit(s) Flex Space Industrial-Business Park Intermodal Facility Manufacturing-Heavy Manufacturing-High Tech Manufacturing-Light Office Showroom Processing/Production/Refinery Facility-Chemical Processing/Refinery Processing/Production/Refinery Facility-Energy Production Processing/Production/Refinery Facility-Food Processing Processing/Production/Refinery Facility-Mineral Processing Processing/Production/Refinery Facility-Waste Treatment Processing/Production/Refinery Facility-Water Treatment Research and Development (R&amp;D;) Salvage Yard Saw Mill/Lumberyard Self Storage/Mini-Storage Facility Storage Yard Tank Farm/Petroleum Storage Truck Terminal/Hub/Transit Facility Underground/Cave Storage Warehouse-Air Cargo Warehouse-Distribution Warehouse Warehouse-Loft/Multi-Story Warehouse-Refrigerated/Cold Storage Warehouse-Storage Warehouse Park/Open Space Undeveloped Commercial Undeveloped Residential (Single-Family) Undeveloped Water Related-Coastal/Island Wilderness Campground/RV-Trailer Camp Convention Hotel Economy/Limited Service Lodging/Hospitality - All-Suites Lodging/Hospitality - Bed&amp;Breakfast Lodging/Hospitality - Casino Hotel Lodging/Hospitality - Extended Stay Lodging/Hospitality - Full Service Lodging/Hospitality - Luxury Lodging/Hospitality - Resort/Spa Mixed Use-Hotel-Office Mixed Use-Hotel-Office Retail Mixed Use-Hotel-Residential Mixed Use-Hotel-Retail Age Restricted Condominium/PUD Bldg(s) Garden/Low-Rise Government Subsidized Homeless Shelter LIHTC Tax Credits Mid/High-Rise Mobile/Manufactured Home Park Student-Oriented Housing-Dormitory Student-Oriented Housing-Fraternity/Sorority Student-Oriented Housing-Student Oriented Apartment Condominium Bldg(s) Condominium Unit(s) Creative/Loft Institutional/Governmental Medical Office Mixed Use-Office-Industrial Mixed Use-Office-Multi-Family Mixed Use-Office-Retail Mixed Use-Office-Retail-Industrial Mixed Use-Office-Retail-Multi-Family Office Building-High-Rise Office Building-Low-Rise Office Building-Mid-Rise Office/Business Park Office/R&amp;D; Office/Warehouse Car Wash-Full Service Car Wash-Hybrid Car Wash-Self Service Condominium Bldg(s) Condominium Unit(s) Convenience Store Day Care Facility/Nursery Free Standing Building-Bank Branch Free Standing Building-Big Box Free Standing Building-Department Store Free Standing Building-Free Standing Free Standing Building-Grocery Store Garden Center Laundramat-Self Serve Mixed Use-Retail-Office Mixed Use-Retail-Office Residential Mixed Use-Retail-Residential Parking Facility-Garage Parking Facility-Surface Post Office Restaurant-Fast Food Restaurant-Full Service Restaurant-Limited Service Restaurant-Sit Down Retail-Pad Service Station/Gas Station Street Retail Tavern, Bar, Nightclub, Micro-Brewery Vehicle Related-Auction Facility Vehicle Related-Dealership Vehicle Related-Lube Shop Vehicle Related-Service&amp;Repair Facility Vehicle Related-Tire Store Vehicle Related-Truck Stop/Travel Center Assisted Living Residences Congregate Seniors Housing Continuing Care Retirement Communities Skilled Nursing Facility Community Center Convenience/Strip Center Fashion/Specialty Center Neighborhood Center Outlet Center Power Center Regional Center Super Regional Center/Mall Theme/Festival Center Airport/Airplane Hangar Cement/Rock/Gravel Plant Cemetery/Mausoleum Courthouse Embassy Compound Fire House Funeral Home/Mortuary Hospital-Veterinarian Jail/Correctional Facility Kennel Landfill Library Marina Marine - Repair/Service Military Facility Mine/Quarry Movie Studio Museum/Gallery Outdoor Sign Radio/TV/Transmission School/University School/University-Athletic Facility School/University-Classroom Building Shipyard/Port Facility Train Station/Bus Terminal Zoo/Nature Facility Amusement Facility-Amusement/Theme Park Amusement Facility-Arcade Amusement Facility-Go-Cart Track Amusement Facility-Miniature Golf Amusement Facility-Waterslide Park Aquatic Facility/Swimming Pool Bowling Alley Casino/Gaming Facility Equestrian Center/Stable Fitness, Court and Spa Facility-Court Facility Fitness, Court and Spa Facility-Health&amp;Fitness Center/Sports Club/Gym Fitness, Court and Spa Facility-Spa Resort Golf Related-Driving Range Golf Related-Golf Course/Club Golf Related-Golf Resort Racetrack-Auto Racetrack-Dog Racetrack-Horse Skating Rink Ski Resort Sports Arena/Stadium-Indoor Sports Arena/Stadium-Outdoor Theatre/Performing Art Facility-Auditorium Theatre/Performing Art Facility-Concert Hall/Arena Theatre/Performing Art Facility-Drive-ln Theatre Theatre/Performing Art Facility-Multi-Screen/Megaplex Theatre Theatre/Performing Art Facility-Outdoor Amphitheatre Theatre/Performing Art Facility-Single-Screen Theatre 2-4 units Attached Condominium Unit(s) Detached View Data Sheet NAICS Code: Lookup Sanborn Coverage: Lookup Date of Development: Acreage: Number of Stories: Notes: 
   
Property Photographs : 18203 WESTFIELD PLACE DR, HOUSTON, TX 77090

The following photographs have been uploaded to the Briki for 18203 WESTFIELD PLACE DR, HOUSTON, TX 77090. To upload more photos, click the &apos;Upload files&apos; button. To view a photo full size, click on the magnifying glass. To edit a photo caption, click on the pencil. To delete a photo, click on the red x.
 You must be logged in to upload photographs. Please Login or Register . 
 

No Photographs have been uploaded...
   
Property Documentation : 18203 WESTFIELD PLACE DR, HOUSTON, TX 77090

The following documents have been uploaded to the Briki for 18203 WESTFIELD PLACE DR, HOUSTON, TX 77090. To upload more documents, click the &apos;Upload files&apos; button. To view a document, click on the view link.
 You must be logged in to upload documents. Please Login or Register . 
 

No Documentation has been uploaded...
   
Property Discussion : 18203 WESTFIELD PLACE DR, HOUSTON, TX 77090

Users can discuss relevant Property Information, such as historical and current developments, changes, etc. Click in the text box to start a discussion, click reply to reply to an existing discussion.
 You must be logged in to participate in the discussion. Please Login or Register . 

No Discussions have been posted to this property.
   
Property Report : 18203 WESTFIELD PLACE DR, HOUSTON, TX 77090

You can download all of the information presented in the Briki for 18203 WESTFIELD PLACE DR, HOUSTON, TX 77090 into a single PDF file. Choose your options and click the Build button below to download your report.
 
 Include? Piece Location Map Information Table Photographs Documents - Name Listed Only Documents - Full Text Printed Government Records Discussions 
   
 Overview View the Property Dashboard Location View the Property Map Information View and Edit Property Information Photographs View and Upload Property Photos Documents View and Upload Relevant Property Documents Discussion Discuss Present and Past Property Information with Other Users Build a Report Build a PDF Report for this Property Partners Find a provider 
   
 ABOUT BRIKI What is Briki? Contact Us 
 
 LINKS Home Login/Register Search the Briki 
 
© 2012 • Environmental Data Resources, Inc. •All Rights Reserved
• Terms and Conditions
	</body>
</document>
