<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001469" url="http://www.city-data.com/va-restaurants/Roger-s-Sports-Pub.html" time="2012-07-12-17:14" support="1" score="0.0095912161554888" bingtitle="Roger&apos;s Sports Pub, 2002 Bainbridge Boulevard, Chesapeake, VA ..." webtitle="Roger&apos;s Sports Pub, 2002 Bainbridge Boulevard, Chesapeake, VA - Restaurant inspection findings and violations, food safety">
			<query id="000508" bing-rank="227"/>
	<description>... soil on the following: tables, shelves, stove drip tray ... Clean the surface at a frequency necessary to preclude ... sink wash, rinse and sanitize basins in that order.</description>
	<body>
		Roger&apos;s Sports Pub, 2002 Bainbridge Boulevard, Chesapeake, VA - Restaurant inspection findings and violations 

 
 
 
Back to Virginia Restaurants , Virginia , VA smaller cities , VA small cities , All Cities .
 Restaurant: Roger&apos;s Sports Pub 
Address: 2002 Bainbridge Boulevard, Chesapeake, Virginia 
Total inspections: 6 
Last inspection: Oct 16, 2009 
 
 
Violation code
 
Inspection Date
 
Inspection Type
 
Critical violations
 
Non-Critical violations
 
Details / Comments
 
 0450 - Critical Employees observed handling ready-to-eat (RTE) food with their bare hands. 0570 - Heavily stained wiping cloths in use. 0820 A 2 - Critical Foods in the walk in cooler cold holding at improper temperatures. 1180 - The metal stem food temperature measuring device (degrees F) is not accurate. 1700 - Critical Repeat Quaternary Ammonium sanitizing solution used was not at an acceptable concentration and had food debris in it. 1770 B - Observed accumulations of food, grease deposits or other soil on the following: tables, shelves, stove drip tray, microwave, utensil drawer, freezers, all bar cabinets and shelves,... 2350 ii - Plumbing connections under the bar sinks and two compartment kitchen sink are leaking. Faucet leaks at the two compartment sink. 2720 - Dumpster or outside refuse container was open or uncovered. 2790 - The indoor ceiling material located in the kitchen and rest rooms does not meet the standard of: 1. smooth, durable and easily cleanable 2. nonabsorbent 3090 - Exhaust fan in ladies room does not work. 3180 - Repeat All kitchen walls, floor, and ceiling grid (tiles to be replaced) noted in need of cleaning. 3180 (Toilet Rooms) - Toilet rooms in need of cleaning. 
 October 16, 2009 Routine 3 9 Details / Comments 
 0470 - Critical ICE FOR CONSUMPTION EXPOSED TO THE TUBING AT THE BAR. 0470 - Critical Repeat Raw foods of animal origin stored WITH ready-to-eat (RTE) food in the refrigeration unit. RAW CHICKEN NEXT TO SLICED MEATS AND FROZEN FULLY COOKED PRODUCTS STORED WITH RAW PRODUCTS IN THE FREEZER. 0470 - Critical The cut or damaged packaging IN THE REACH IN FREEZER is subject to contamination. 0610 - Food stored on the floor or food stored less than 6&quot; above the floor. 0810 - Corrected During Inspection Food containers for cooling food are arranged so as not allow for maximum heat transfer. 0810 - Corrected During Inspection The methods used for cooling were not adequate. 1700 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Quaternary Ammonium sanitizing solution used was not at an acceptable concentration. LOW IN THE KITCHEN AND TOO HIGH IN THE BAR THREE COMPARTMENT SINKS. 1730 - PASTRY BRUSH, PLASTIC FOOD CONTAINERS AND LIDS TO CONTAINERS was observed in a state of repair and condition preventing effective maintenance and easy cleaning. 1770 A - Critical The following utensils were observed soiled to sight and touch: PANS, SEVERAL UTENSILS IN THE STORAGE CONTAINER AND THE COLANDER. 1770 C - Observed accumulations of dust, dirt, food residue or other debris on the following nonfood-food contact surfaces: UTENSIL STORAGE CONTAINERS, STORAGE SHELVES, OUTSIDE SURFACE OF FOOD STORAGE CONTAINERS IN THE REACH IN REFRIGERATOR, EXHAUST HOOD FILTERS AND PIPES. 1800 - The nonfood contact surface of the MOP SINK has accumulations of grime and debris. 2650 - There is no refuse container at the HAND SINK. 2890 - Light bulb in REACH IN FREEZER not shielded, coated, or otherwise shatter-resistant. 3170 - CEILING FRAME/TILES AND FLOOR TILES is not maintained in good repair 3180 - FLOORS IN CORNERS AND UNDER EQUIPMENTnoted in need of cleaning. 
 June 03, 2009 Routine 3 9 Details / Comments 
 0480 - Unlabeled food containers. (Seasoning containers) 0830 - Critical The prepared ready-to-eat (RTE) FOOD in the refrigeration unit is not properly dated for disposition. 1860 - A distinct, separate water rinse after washing and before sanitizing of utensils and equipment was not observed. 2000 - Repeat Racks stored on floor. 2930 - Outer opening of the food establishment is not protected against entry of insects and rodents. (Gap around screen door) 3200 - Vent filters in the hood system are not being maintained in a clean condition. 3220 - Mops not hung up to air dry. 
 December 15, 2008 Routine 1 6 Details / Comments 
 0470 - Critical Raw food of animal origin holding in a manner that may cause cross contamination of to ready-to-eat food (RTE). 0480 - Unlabeled food containers. (DRY INGREDIENT BINS) 0520 - Ice used as a medium for cooling the exterior surfaces of food is also for drink ice or used as food. (CONTAINER OF LEMONS STORED IN DRINK ICE) 0570 - Wiping cloths improperly used UNDER CUTTING BOARDS. 2000 - Repeat TEA MACHINE, PANEL AND RACKS STORED ON FLOOR. 2930 - OUTER DOORS PROPPED OPEN. 3340 1 - Container of SANITIZER not properly stored to prevent the contamination of food, equipment, utensils, linens or single service items. 
 September 18, 2008 Routine 1 6 Details / Comments 
 0240 - Employee observed working in the food service area without proper hair restraints. 0580 - Single-use gloves while worn during multi-tasked food preparation. 0610 - Food stored on the floor or food stored less than 6&quot; above the floor. CASES OF OIL. 0690 - RADIO STORED ON FOOD PREP SHELF. 1080 - The WOODEN PASTRY BRUSH is not designed and constructed to be durable. 1150 - The nonfood contact surface of the UNSEALED WOOD IN THE WALK-IN REFRIGERATOR is not designed or constructed to be easily cleanable. 2000 - TEA CANISTERS, COFFEE MACHINE AND RACKS were found stored ON THE FLOOR. 2000 - Clean ICE BUCKETS were observed stored with the food-contact surface facing upward. 
 July 14, 2008 Routine 0 7 Details / Comments 1570 - HOOD FILTERS ARE NOT IN PLACE. June 13, 2008 Routine 0 1 Details / Comments
	</body>
</document>
