<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001625" url="http://www.highbeam.com/publications/albany-times-union-albany-ny-p408150/jul-10-1998" time="2012-07-12-17:24" support="3" score="0.0046062789091041376" bingtitle="Albany Times Union (Albany, NY) July 10, 1998 Article Archives ..." webtitle="Albany Times Union (Albany, NY) July 10, 1998 Article Archives | HighBeam Research">
			<query id="000801" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="001291" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000788" bing-rank="215"/>
	<description>... Crestar Financial Corp. $600 million of credit card ... closures for bridge replacement work near Exit ... lunch break, about to pay the cashier at a fast-food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Search Options Cancel changes All of these words This exact phrase Any of these words None of these words Apply Cancel Follow us: 
 Subscription benefits Log in 
 
 Sign up for a free, 7-day trial 

 Publications Research topics 
 
 Topics home People 
 Artists and Entertainers Company executives Historical figures Politicians and Government officials World Leaders 
 Issues and Events 
 Health and Medicine Historical Events Religion and Theology Science and Technology 
 Places Organizations A-Z 
 A-G H-O P-T U-Z 0-9 
 
 
 Publications home Journals 
 Academic journals Business journals Education journals Math and Engineering journals Medical journals Science and Technology journals Trade journals 
 Magazines 
 Business magazines Computer magazines Education magazines Industry magazines Lifestyle magazines Medical magazines 
 Newspapers 
 International newspapers and newswires Reports, newsletters, and transcripts U.K. newspapers U.S. newspapers and newswires 
 Reference works and books 
 Almanacs Dictionaries and thesauruses Encyclopedias Non-fiction books 
 
 
 Home » Publications » U.S. newspapers and newswires » New York newspapers » Albany Times Union (Albany, NY) » Jul - Sep 1998 »July 10, 1998» 
 
Publication Finder
 
Popular publications on HighBeam Research 
 The Washington Post Washington D.C. newspapers Newsweek National newspapers The Economist (US) Political magazines Daily Mail (London) U.K. newspapers Chicago Sun-Times Illinois newspapers Sign up now - Free 7-day trial! 
Albany Times Union (Albany, NY)

179 articles
 
 Permalink 
Create a link to this page

Copy and paste this link tag into your Web page or blog:
 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.highbeam.com/publications/albany-times-union-albany-ny-p408150/jul-10-1998&quot; title=&quot;Albany Times Union (Albany, NY) at HighBeam Research&quot;&gt;Albany Times Union (Albany, NY)&lt;/a&gt; RSS 
Your RSS feed has been created

If your RSS reader did not automatically grab the feed, you can copy and paste the URL below into your RSS reader.
 http://services.highbeam.com/rss/HBR/408150-albany-times-union-albany-ny/publication 
 
Publication details
 
 Subject: Daily Newspapers Managing Editor: Rex Smith Publisher: George R. Hearst, III Publishing company: Hearst Communications Inc. 
 Publication&apos;s Web site The Times Union is a Monday to Sunday newspaper published by Hearst Corporation. First published in 1856 as The Morning Times,The Times Union is located in the greater Albany, N.Y. area.The Times Union has one of the largest circulations in the United States and has a diverse readership, with the majority of readers between the ages of 25 and 60. Most readers have a college degree or some college background and an income above the national median. The newspaper covers the greater Albany... area.With award-winning editor Rex Smith, a two-time Pulitzer juror, at its helm, The Times Union is known for its excellence in investigative reporting as well as commentary. In addition to being a leading news contributor during former Governor Eliot Spitzer&apos;s expose regarding his involvement as a client of a high-priced call girl operation in 2008, which led to Spitzer&apos;s resignation, the paper has also investigated an underground weapons operation that involved area police officers. And it also helped expose a state practice of granting parole to violent offenders in order to keep prison populations to a minimum. In addition it has detailed high profile domestic violence disputes and broke the story of how federal agents subpoenaed labor unions that invested pension funds with a Connecticutt company that employed high powered Republican Joseph Bruno as a consultant.Active in the community, The Times Union pledged to pay $3.5 million over a 10-year period for the Albany-based Pepsi Arena naming rights. On January 1, 2007, the arena received the name of the Times Union Center. George R. Hearst, III, is the publisher; Rex Smith is editor; Harry Rosenfeld is editor-at-large and Joann Cruppi is editorial pages editor. Read more 
July 10, 1998

 `LOLITA&apos; HEADS FOR BIG SCREEN.(LIFE&amp;LEISURE) July 10, 1998 Byline: BERNARD WEINRAUB New York Times 
 HOLLYWOOD -- ``Lolita&apos;&apos; is finally reaching the big screen. 
 After more than a year of controversy, in which every major studio rejected... `UNDER THE SKIN&apos; AN AMAZING EVOCATION OF PAIN, CATHARSIS.(LIFE&amp;LEISURE) July 10, 1998 Byline: JAY CARR The Boston Globe 
 British writer-director Carine Adler&apos;s ``Under the Skin&apos;&apos; emblazons the screen with the most startling and gripping film debut by an actress since Emily... 13-YEAR-OLD SENTENCED IN DEATH OF CLASSMATE.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- Associated Press 
 NIAGARA FALLS -- A 13-year-old boy has been sentenced to the maximum 18 months in a juvenile detention center for delivering a fatal punch to a schoolmate. 
 ... 2 BUSINESSES EXPANDING IN GLENS FALLS.(BUSINESS) July 10, 1998 Byline: JO-ANN JOHNSTON Business writer 
 Two business expansions here are bringing new use to old buildings. 
 Northeast Stitches&amp;Ink Inc., now in the Glens Falls Industrial Park, is... 2 GET MAXIMUM PRISON TERM FOR BAKERY ROBBERY IN TROY.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 TROY -- Ronald Roberts of Troy and Lloyd Kelone of Schenectady were sentenced Wednesday to 12 1/2 to 25 years in state prison -- the maximum sentence allowable -- for the robbery of the Vanilla... 2 GUNS LINKED TO EVANS DUG UP.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: CAROL DeMARE and MIKE HUREWITZ Staff writers 
 State Police on Thursday dug up two handguns at Albany Rural Cemetery that they believe are linked to killings committed by Gary Evans,... A THREAT TO PEACE.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 This time of year is known as marching season in Northern Ireland. It&apos;s when hardline loyalists march through the streets of Belfast, Portadown and other cities to celebrate the victory of... ADVISER TO JENNINGS TAKES HEAT OVER `PART-TIME COUNCIL&apos; REMARK.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: EDWARD FITZPATRICK Staff writer 
 Albany Former and current Common Council members shouted in outrage Thursday when an adviser to Mayor Jerry Jennings objected to giving too much... AGENCY LOOKS FOR PEOPLE WHO DESERVE PENSIONS.(BUSINESS) July 10, 1998 Byline: JOHN SOLOMON Associated Press 
 WASHINGTON -- The government is hunting for some 7,200 Americans. It&apos;s scouring Social Security records, checking credit bureaus and even putting out... AIDE SAYS YELTSIN&apos;S ILL HEALTH SHOULD PRECLUDE 2ND TERM.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- Associated Press 
 MOSCOW -- Russian President Boris Yeltsin&apos;s health is so poor that he cannot maintain a vigorous work schedule and should not run for another term, a senior... ALBERTA GALLAGHAR.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 EAST GREENBUSH -- Alberta K. Van Loan Gallaghar, 75, died on July 8, 1998. Born in Albany, she was a lifelong resident. She was employed as a General Manager for New York Mutual Underwriters in... ALDERMAN PROPOSES AUTHORITY TO RUN COHOES POWER PLANT.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: BECHETTA JACKSON Staff writer 
 Cohoes Fourth Ward Alderman Peter Marra on Thursday recommended the city proceed with plans to create a power authority that could move to acquire... ALEX ADORA BULL.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 KNOXVILLE, TN -- Alex Adora Bull, age, 24 days, died Tuesday morning, July 7, 1998 at the University of Tennessee Medical Center in Knoxville, TN. She was the treasured and beloved daughter of... ANALYST THINKS TOBACCO FIRMS WILL SETTLE STATE LAWSUITS.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- Associated Press 
 NEW YORK -- The tobacco industry is discussing settling the rest of the lawsuits by states trying to recover the costs of treating sick smokers, according to an... ANTI-DRUG CAMPAIGN AIMS AT KIDS WHERE THEY SIT -- IN FRONT OF TV.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: Associated Press 
 ATLANTA -- Updating ``just say no&apos;&apos; with images to &quot;knock America upside the head,&apos;&apos; President Clinton and House Speaker Newt Gingrich announced an anti-drug... ARSENAL EXPERIENCES 51ST CHANGE OF COMMAND.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: BECHETTA JACKSON Staff writer 
 Amid military pageantry and precision, employees at the Watervliet Arsenal bid farewell to their commander and welcomed a new leader during Thursday&apos;s... ASSISTANT CLAIMS HOLTZ ASSAULTED HIM.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: Associated Press 
 LAFAYETTE, Ind. -- Earle Mosley, an ex-Notre Dame assistant testifying on tape Thursday in the age-discrimination suit of a former colleague, said that he was... AU PAIR FAILS TO RESPOND TO CIVIL SUIT IN BABY&apos;S DEATH.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- Associated Press 
 BOSTON -- Louise Woodward failed to respond to a lawsuit filed by the parents of the baby she was convicted of killing and a federal court automatically ruled... BAY STATE EYES SIGNING BONUS FOR TEACHERS.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: Washington Post 
 BOSTON -- Can you spell bonus? 
 After 59 percent of their prospective public school teachers flunked a state-mandated certification exam, Massachusetts... BENEFIT CONCERT GRATIFIES MANY TORNADO VICTIMS.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: JANE GOTTLIEB Staff writer 
 After the tornado rammed Mechanicville in May, here&apos;s what Carol Guilianelli&apos;s home needed: 
 ``New roof, windows, siding,&apos;&apos; she said at Thursday ... BEST BETS.(LIFE&amp;LEISURE) July 10, 1998 TV Multitalented 
 Sandra Bernhard has flirted with David Letterman, was best pals with Madonna, and even had a role on ``Roseanne.&apos;&apos; She performs her one-woman show tonight on HBO.... BRAWLEY JURY CITES TALK OF TRIAL IN REQUEST FOR SEQUESTERING.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- Associated Press 
 POUGHKEEPSIE -- Citing intense media attention and talk surrounding the Tawana Brawley defamation trial, jurors deliberating the case reversed themselves on... BRIEFING.(LIFE&amp;LEISURE) July 10, 1998 A shady deal for burglars Keeping the lights and radio on in your house while you&apos;re away on vacation isn&apos;t enough to keep away burglars. One simple thing you can do is leave your shades... BROKERAGE FIRMS EYE DEAL IN NASDAQ SCHEME.(BUSINESS) July 10, 1998 Byline: MARCY GORDON Associated Press 
 WASHINGTON -- Nearly three dozen big Wall Street firms have begun preliminary settlement talks with federal regulators over alleged trading violations... BULLS STILL SEARCHING FOR COACH.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: Associated Press 
 CHICAGO -- There are no shortage of rumors, with a new name surfacing every day as a possible coach for the Chicago Bulls. And there&apos;s a short list, with at least... CAPITAL REGION ALMANAC.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 This almanac of community news provides coverage of local governments, local courts and police calls from selected communities in our region. Government listings focus on communities in Albany... CAR OWNER DRIVEN TO SUCCEED.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: Associated Press 
 LOUDON, N.H. -- Mention great expectations, and Charles Dickens never enters the conversation. 
 No, the first two words out of Jeff Burton&apos;s mouth are Jack ... CATHERINE E. GUILDEA.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 ALBANY -- Catherine E. Guildea, 93, of Old Karner Road, Albany, died July 5, 1998 at Our Lady of Mercy Life Center, Guilderland, NY after a long illness. Mrs. Guildea was born on August 22,... CHINA PRODS TAIWAN FOR UNIFICATION TALKS.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: Washington Post 
 BEIJING -- China urged Taiwan Thursday to &quot;face reality&quot; and submit to holding talks on an eventual reunification with China following comments from President... CLINTON AIDE ATTACKS GE OVER PCBS.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: PAUL ZIELBAUER Staff writer 
 In the Clinton administration&apos;s harshest criticism of the General Electric Co., the head of the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency Thursday accused GE... COLLEGES HONOR GRADUATES.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Here are recent college and university graduates and honorees: 
 State University at Binghamton 
 Jeffery Warrender, son of Robin and Denise Warrender of Castleton, received the George... COME CLEAN, MR. JENNINGS.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 There&apos;s nothing surprising, nor subtle, about Albany Mayor Jerry Jennings&apos; formal endorse- ment of Gary Domalewicz&apos;s candidacy for the state Assembly. Nor is there anything improper about it.... COPPOLA WINS BIG VERDICT AGAINST WARNER BROS.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 In the largest civil verdict ever against a Hollywood studio, a Los Angeles jury on Thursday awarded Francis Ford Coppola $60 million in punitive damages on top of $20 million given him last... CORINTH TO CELEBRATE CENTENNIAL OF INTERNATIONAL PAPER.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: KENNETH C. CROWE II Staff writer 
 In 1948, when he was eight-years-old, Richard Lucia went with his grandparents to what had been this Adirondack gateway community&apos;s biggest party:... COSBY WITNESS COLLECTS `NATIONAL ENQUIRER&apos; AWARD.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- Associated Press 
 SANTA MONICA, Calif. -- With armed guards at his side, the man who led police to the suspect in Ennis Cosby&apos;s killing collected a $100,000 reward Thursday from... COUNTY SHERIFF&apos;S DEPUTY GETS 10 MINUTES OF FAME.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: LAURA LEE Staff writer 
 Deputy Sheriff Jim Moore&apos;s co-workers have been asking him for his autograph and calling him a celebrity. 
 On a trip to New York City last week, Moore and... COURT DISMISSES LAWSUIT BY REASSIGNED DEPUTIES.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: KENNETH C. CROWE II Staff writer 
 Ballston Spa A lawsuit by the union representing Saratoga County&apos;s road patrol deputies seeking reassignment of two technical sergeants was... COURT SAYS KIRYAS JOEL DISTRICT MUST CLOSE.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: MELISSA GRACE Staff writer 
 Once again, a state court has ordered the Kiryas Joel school district in Orange County closed. 
 In a unanimous decision, the Appellate Division of... CYCLING TOUR BENEFITS MS SOCIETY.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Saratoga Springs The Northeastern New York Chapter of the National Multiple Sclerosis Society&apos;s 1998 Trustco Bank MS Cycling Series, a fund-raising bike tour, takes place this weekend. 
 ... D&apos;AMATO CHALLENGER WANTS RIGHT TO LIFE LINE.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: JAMES M. ODATO Capitol bureau 
 Albany Thomas Droleskey, a fierce opponent of abortion and Alfonse D&apos;Amato&apos;s use of the Right To Life Party line, brought his campaign to Albany... DEATH OF WOULD-BE LEADER FUELS MORE RIOTS IN NIGERIA.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: Associated Press 
 LAGOS, Nigeria -- Riots and protests flared anew Thursday over the death of the country&apos;s most prominent political prisoner, while Nigeria&apos;s military junta debated... DEBT COLLECTORS TO PURSUE TICKET SCOFFLAWS.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: JAMES M. ODATO Capitol bureau 
 Professional bill collectors working for the state will soon be pestering people who drive New York&apos;s roadways with suspended licenses. 
 If you... DELTA SUBSIDIARY TO FILL AIRTRAN VOID.(BUSINESS) July 10, 1998 Byline: PAUL ZIELBAUER Staff writer 
 Delta Express, the low-cost subsidiary of Delta Air Lines, will begin daily nonstop service from Albany International Airport to Orlando on Oct. 1,... DEPUTY RESCUES TEENAGER.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: LAURA LEE Staff writer 
 Capt. Lawrence Walraed, highway patrol commander with the Rensselaer County Sheriff&apos;s Department, saved the life of a 13-year-old girl after pulling her from... DOER&apos;S PROFILE.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 DANIEL BREEN Where from WHAT HE DOES: Breen is a licensed cosmetologist who works at Gentleman&apos;s Quarters, 384 Broadway, Saratoga Springs, an upscale newly-opened men&apos;s barbershop. ``I work... DONN P. LIEBENER SR.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 TROY -- Donn P. Liebener Sr., 60, of Parmenter Avenue, died Thursday at St. Mary&apos;s Hospital, Troy, after a brief illness. Born in Troy, he was son of Frances Bayly Liebener of Troy and the late... DRIVING AMBITION SKIDMORE GRAD HITS THE ROAD TO PURSUE GOLF CAREER.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: TIM REYNOLDS Staff writer 
 Malta It&apos;s usually the same drill for college graduates. Set up job interviews, hope to get hire, start making some money. 
 Malta resident Bryan... DRUG CHARGE REDUCED FOR A WITNESS.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Schenectady A city woman who testified against her former boyfriend during his murder trial pleaded guilty Thursday to an unrelated charge of seventh-degree criminal possession of a... EDITORIAL ON GUN CHECKS HAS SOMETHING TO APPLAUD.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: JOSEPH J. MESSIER Schenectady 
 Your June 25 editorial, and previous front-page story, regarding the ``Brady Law&apos;&apos; background check having prevented 69,000 prohibited persons from... EDWARD J. BRONSON, SR.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 WESTMERE -- Edward J. Bronson, Sr., 60, passed away on Tuesday afternoon, July 7, 1998. Eddie was the general manager with Denny&apos;s Restaurants in the Albany area; he formerly owned and operated... EXPERTS TO APPRAISE HEIRLOOMS.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 SARATOGA SPRINGS -- A Sotheby&apos;s Heirloom Discovery Day takes place at the Saratoga Springs city Center 10 a.m.- 4 p.m. Saturday. 
 Sotheby&apos;s Fine and Decorative Arts specialists will provide ... FAMILY CHANNEL LINEUP BEING SCRAPPED BY FOX.(LIFE&amp;LEISURE) July 10, 1998 Byline: JEFFERSON GRAHAM USA Today 
 Fans of ``Hawaii Five-O,&apos;&apos; ``Father Dowling Mysteries&apos;&apos; and other Family Channel staples, brace yourself. 
 With the exception of one show, the entire... FED PLANS LAB AT UALBANY FACILITY.(BUSINESS)(Correction notice) July 10, 1998 Byline: CLAIRE HUGHES Business writer 
 FED Corp., a developer and maker of high-tech flat-panel displays, is opening a chemical synthesis laboratory at University at Albany&apos;s East Campus. ... FINDING FAME IN TELLING FIBS.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: JIM McGRATH 
 This one is all about lying. The sad truth is that it&apos;s evolving into a lucrative and worthwhile practice, particularly so in our own business. Seventeen years ago, one... FIRST LADY&apos;S VISIT SPARKS NEIGHBORHOOD CLEANUP.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: TIM O&apos;BRIEN Staff writer 
 A week before Hillary Rodham Clinton&apos;s arrival, Eighth Street is abuzz with more activity than neighbors say they have seen in years. 
 Trees are being... FLEET TO BUY CREDIT CARD LOANS.(BUSINESS) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- Bloomberg News 
 BOSTON -- Fleet Financial Group agreed to buy from Crestar Financial Corp. $600 million of credit card loans from customers outside Virginia, Maryland and... FRENCH REALLY KNOW HOW TO CELEBRATE.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: BERNIE LINCICOME 
 PARIS -- Now, this is what I call a sports bar. While not a bar in the strictest sense -- it has no roof or walls -- it does have the two required ingredients, a... FUND-RAISER TO ADMIT SEEKING FOREIGN DONOR.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: Associated Press 
 WASHINGTON -- Miami business executive Howard Glicken was charged Thursday with soliciting a $20,000 foreign contribution in 1993 to Democratic election campaigns.... GAMES DRAW CZECH TEAMS.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: TIM REYNOLDS Staff writer - 
 About 150 teams will play this weekend in the 22nd annual Fleet Bank/Clifton Park International Soccer Classic, but it&apos;s safe to say that two teams will... GEBRSELASSIE FAILS IN BID FOR RECORD.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 OSLO, Norway -- The cold weather spoiled Haile Gebrselassie&apos;s attempt to break a third world record this season, while Michael Johnson showed he still hasn&apos;t recovered from injuries, finishing... GOVERNMENT ACTION.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Wednesday, July 8 Action items: Approved final site plan for McDonald&apos;s on Route 4 in spite of vocal opposition from neighbors who contend that a previous board had promised to keep the site ... GOVERNMENT TO APPEAL COURT&apos;S WITNESS RULING.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: Washington Post 
 WASHINGTON -- Justice Depaartment officials said thursday that they will appeal a startling ruling by a federal appeals court in Denver that forbids prosecutors... GREEN MANAGEMENT KEY FOR BYRUM AT QUAD CITY.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: Associated Press 
 COASTAL, Ill. -- Curt Byrum sank a 20-foot putt on his final hole Thursday for a 7-under-par 63 and a one-stroke lead over four players in the first round of the... GREEN PARTY HAS A VISION OF ITS OWN.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: MARK A. DUNLEA 
 ``Bold and progressive&apos;&apos; is how a July 1 Times Union editorial describes the Green Party. While acknowledging that there is increasingly little difference in the... HELEN V. HERRINGTON.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 MECHANICVILLE -- Helen V. Herrington, 88, of North Crystal Street, Hemstreet Park, Mechanicville, died Wednesday at St. Mary&apos;s Hospital, Troy following a long illness. She was born, June 13,... HEROLD RUNS TO 2ND-PLACE FINISH.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 BOLTON LANDING -- Several Saratoga County residents took part in the 22nd annual Adirondack Distance Run, a 10-mile road race from Lake George to Bolton Landing, Sunday morning. 
 The... HVCC WINS $40,000 GRANT FOR WORK FORCE DEVELOPMENT.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 TROY -- Hudson Valley Community College Office of Technical/Professional Training was awarded a Workforce Development Contract Course Grant of $40,000 by the State University at New York ... IMPROVING EDUCATION WITH BETTER PARENTING SKILLS.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: WILLIAM RASPBERRY 
 WASHINGTON -- While we&apos;re trying to figure out how to get better teachers for inner-city children -- stiffer college screening, sterner teacher exams, better pay... INDONESIAN LEADER SAYS EFFORT TO SPARK ECONOMY IS FAILING.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- Associated Press 
 JAKARTA, Indonesia -- President B.J. Habibie urged the ruling party to break from its authoritarian past, and said Thursday that steps to revive the economy... JENNINGS&apos; ALLEGIANCE IS QUESTIONED.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: TRACEY TULLY Staff writer 
 When Mayor Jerry Jennings, a Democrat, flirted with the idea of running for the state Assembly against the Democratic incumbent, it raised eyebrows. 
 ... JUDGE ORDERS RAP ARTIST TO PAY $2.7M TO SYRACUSE MAN.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- Associated Press 
 SYRACUSE -- When rap star M.C. Hammer brought his ``Please Hammer Don&apos;t Hurt &apos;Em&apos;&apos; tour to the Onondaga War Memorial in 1990, a Syracuse resident was left... JUDGE: ROTTERDAM CAN&apos;T SEE GE&apos;S ACCOUNTING BOOKS.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- Melissa Grace 
 ALBANY -- A state court Thursday dismissed an appeal by the town of Rotterdam to open General Electric&apos;s accounting books, which GE said would reveal trade... KING INNOCENT OF FRAUD CHARGES.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: Associated Press 
 NEW YORK -- Boxing promoter Don King was found innocent on all counts Thursday in his second trial on charges he altered a contract with a fighter in order to... KODAK ENGINEER FAULTED ON FILES.(BUSINESS) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- Bloomberg News 
 ROCHESTER -- Eastman Kodak Co. is accusing a software engineer of illegally transmitting secret computer files to a Xerox Corp. computer in her final days as an... LANE CLOSURES WILL CONTINUE ON NORTHWAY.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: BRENDAN LYONS Staff writer 
 Recent Northway lane closures for bridge replacement work near Exit 10 are going to continue through the summer, but traffic tie-ups will be avoided as... LATHAM FIRM GETS GRANT TO IMPROVE ARTIFICIAL HEART.(BUSINESS) July 10, 1998 Byline: CLAIRE HUGHES Business writer 
 Foster-Miller Technologies Inc. of Latham is part of a team that has received a federal grant toward development of a longer-lasting, more durable... LAW CAN&apos;T FORCE CHILD, PARENT TALKS.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: ELLEN GOODMAN 
 BOSTON -- Sooner or later, it always comes down to earrings. 
 At some point in the debate, a legislator, politician, or moralist who has never previously shown the... LIBRARY TO INCLUDE DRIVE-THRU.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: SCOTT PATTERSON Staff writer 
 By now most people are used to drive-thrus at fast-food restaurants, banks and even drug stores. But the East Greenbush community may soon have a new... LUCKILY FOR US, IT&apos;S `CAMELOT&apos; IN THE PARK.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: MICHAEL ECK Special to the Times Union 
 ALBANY -- There&apos;s something to be said for playing favorites. 
 In the program notes for Park Playhouse&apos;s ``Camelot&apos;&apos; it mentions that King... MARDI GRAS SWEEPS THROUGH FRENCH STREETS, FOR NOW.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: WILLIAM GILDEA The Washington Post 
 PARIS -- The day after France&apos;s greatest soccer victory, the team rested. Les Bleus seemed almost serene Thursday morning at the national... MAYDENE MORAN.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 EAST GREENBUSH -- Maydene Moran, 70, of Park Ave, East Greenbush, died Wednesday after a long illness. Born in Athens, she lived in the Capital District most of her life. Retired after 16 years... MCNULTY IN MARYLAND HOSPITAL FOR SURGERY ON SHOULDER.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 U.S. Rep. Michael R. McNulty went to Bethesda Naval Hospital in Bethesda, Md., Thursday, for shoulder surgery, his office said. 
 McNulty will have an operation today to repair the rotator... MEDIATION SOFTENS THE BLOW OF DIVORCE.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: LAURA LEE Staff writer 
 Divorce and cooperation are two words that do not go together in most people&apos;s minds. Communication between former partners is often lost on a legal... MEXICO WILL TIGHTEN ITS BELT AGAIN AS A RESULT OF OIL GLUT.(BUSINESS) July 10, 1998 Byline: CHRIS KRAUL Los Angeles Times 
 MEXICO CITY -- The Mexican government Wednesday announced its third round of spending cuts this year after determining that the global oil glut will... MORE AIRLINES COULD CANCEL FLIGHTS DUE TO PILOT PROTEST.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- Associated Press 
 SPRINGFIELD, Va. -- Hundreds of flights a day could be canceled this summer as pilot hours are stretched beyond contract limits, pilot union officials said... MORE KIDS IN POVERTY, STUDY FINDS.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: Gannett News Service 
 WASHINGTON -- A new study released Thursday found that despite a robust economy nearly one-fourth of youngsters under age 6 live in households with incomes... MOVING A TRAFFIC LIGHT WILL HELP YMCA PROJECT.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: KIMBERLY MARTINEAU Staff writer 
 A problem that has stalled plans for building a YMCA for almost three years has been solved. 
 The solution rests on a traffic light. 
 ... NEGOTIATORS DIFFER ON GM STRIKE DEAL.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: Associated Press 
 FLINT, Mich. -- Top negotiators for General Motors Corp. and the United Auto Workers differed Thursday on whether a deal to end two strikes against the automaker... NEVADA STILL WAITING TO HEAR FROM TYSON.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: Combined wire services 
 LAS VEGAS -- If Mike Tyson wants to fight again, he&apos;s going to have to pick up a telephone and let Nevada boxing officials know his intentions. 
 On the... NEW ASSIGNMENT FOR KAPOSTASY.(LIFE&amp;LEISURE) July 10, 1998 In yet another in what has been a growing pile of assignments for Chris Kapostasy, the former WNYT, Ch. 13, newsperson will anchor the Sunday NBC Nightly News part of this fall. 
 ``I will... NEW STUDY SAYS TAMOXIFEN DOES NOT PREVENT CANCER.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- Associated Press 
 LONDON -- Contradicting U.S. findings, British scientists who conducted the longest-running study of tamoxifen have concluded there is not enough evidence the... NEW YORK MADE RIGHT DECISION REGARDING VIAGRA.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: PAULINE BRUNDAGE Rensselaer 
 As reported in the July 4 Times Union, bravo to New York state for resisting the federal Medicaid must-pay-for-Viagra decree. Medicaid still doesn&apos;t... NICKLAUS SCRAPES OFF RUST FOR GOLDEN FINISH.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: HARRY ATKINS Associated Press 
 DEARBORN, Mich. -- Jack Nicklaus was more than just a sentimental favorite. 
 Nicklaus, whose streak of 154 majors will end when he skips the ... NIGHTSPOT FOR TEENS TURNS OUT TO BE A HIT.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: MICHELE MORGAN BOLTON Staff writer 
 When Nassau bar and restaurant owner Butch Primero&apos;s 10-year-old son, Nick, told him he should schedule something special for kids at Graffiti&apos;s,... NINE MORE HOLES IN YEAR 2000.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: BILL DOUGLAS Staff writer 
 The idea of adding nine more holes to Burden Lake Country Club&apos;s layout has been percolating in owner Ron Choquette&apos;s mind for 15 years. In another two,... NO NEW NAMES TOP SURVEY FOR NEW YORKERS&apos; NEWBORNS.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 In the name game, tradition still rules: New Yorkers remain loyal to a handful of preambles when naming their newborns. 
 For the 26th year, Michael topped the list as the most popular baby ... NORTH ROAD TO REOPEN.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 WILTON -- The town hopes to have North Road reopened to traffic by Monday morning, Supervisor Roy J. McDonald said. 
 The town shut a portion of the road near its south end by Ballard Road... NOTHING FISHY ABOUT REMOVING BONES BY HAND.(LIFE&amp;LEISURE) July 10, 1998 DEAR MISS MANNERS: As time passes and circumstances change, what may have been socially unacceptable or improper at one time may today pass for acceptable behavior or perhaps be completely... NOVOTNA ADVANCES TO QUARTERS.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: Associated Press 
 PRAGUE, Czech Republic -- Wimbledon champion Jana Novotna defeated Radka Bobkova 6-2, 7-6 (7-3) Thursday to advance to the quarterfinals of the Skoda Czech Open. ... NYC BALLET PUTS PASSION IN `ZAKOUSKI&apos;.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: TIMOTHY CAHILL Staff writer 
 The New York City Ballet finally premiered Peter Martins&apos; ``Zakouski&apos;&apos; in Saratoga Thursday evening, six years after the ballet&apos;s New York debut in... ON THIS DATE...(LIFE&amp;LEISURE) July 10, 1998 Byline: Associated Press 
 Today is Friday, July 10, the 191st day of 1998. There are 174 days left in the year. In 1940, in World War II, the 114-day Battle of Britain began as Nazi... ON-SCREEN `MADELINE&apos; IS CHARMING.(LIFE&amp;LEISURE) July 10, 1998 Byline: KAREN HERSHENSON Knight Ridder 
 Today&apos;s trend in children&apos;s movies is to pump them up with as much edge as the ratings board will allow, the better to please boomer parents and... OPENING SET FOR NEIGHBORHOOD CENTER.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 SARATOGA SPRINGS -- A grand opening ceremony of the William H. Ford Neighborhood Center at Vanderbilt and Jefferson Terrace will be held Saturday at 11 a.m. by the Saratoga Springs Housing... OTBZZ IMPRESS IN OPENER.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: BUZZ GRAY Staff writer 
 SCHENECTADY -- A new era began for the New York OTBzz Thursday night. Not only did their fans put their money where their mouths had been, but the players... OUSTED COLUMNIST TO READ POEMS IN ALBANY.(LIFE&amp;LEISURE) July 10, 1998 Byline: PAUL GRONDAHL Staff writer 
 In her writing, Patricia Smith has always played with fire. 
 Known as a dynamic performance poet, an iconoclastic writing teacher and an incendiary... OWNERS APPROVE SCHEDULE FORMAT.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: Associated Press 
 CHICAGO -- Baseball owners approved a 1999 schedule format Thursday that will increase interleague games for some teams and switch the American League to an... PEDICURES JUST ANOTHER SUMMER TREAT.(LIFE&amp;LEISURE) July 10, 1998 Byline: GINA HORAN Knight Ridder 
 Summer is here. Which begs one question: Have you checked your feet? 
 After months of living in galoshes and wool socks, it&apos;s at least warm enough to... PLAYING `SOLDIERS&apos; A 10-YEAR-OLD REVIEWER GIVES US HIS TAKE ON THE NEW MOVIE ``SMALL SOLDIERS&apos; BY MAX BLACKBURN SPECIAL TO THE TIMES UNION.(LIFE&amp;LEISURE)(Movie review) July 10, 1998 ``Small Soldiers,&apos;&apos; opening today, is an action movie definitely geared to the younger set, so we asked Max Blackburn, son of staff writer Doug Blackburn, 10 years old and a fifth-grader at... POINT REDUCTION, PRE-TEST DRIVING CLASSES SET.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 TROY -- The following classes for drivers will be offered. 
 A six-hour, point/insurance reduction course will be held from 8:30 a.m. to 3 p.m., Saturday, July 18, at Catholic Central High... POLICE BLOTTER.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 STATE POLICE, CLIFTON PARK 
 Monday, July 6 
 TWO-CAR ACCIDENT. In a pharmacy parking lot in Halfmoon, a car reportedly pulled into a parking space, the driver hit the accelerator and... POLICE BLOTTER.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 NORTH GREENBUSH Monday, July 6 2:28 p.m. BAD CHECK. A 24-year-old Van Woert Court, Wynantskill, woman allegedly bounced a check. Officer: Mark Peverly. 
 RECKLESS DRIVER. While turning into... POLICE CONTINUE INVESTIGATION INTO FATAL HEAD-ON CRASH.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- Scott Patterson 
 The investigation continued Thursday into a head-on collision that killed a 57-year-old Pittstown woman. 
 Janet A. Yetto was killed when her car collided with... PORTADOWN BRACES FOR VIOLENCE.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: LARA JAKES Staff writer with wire reports 
 PORTADOWN, Northern Ireland -- Hard-line Protestants determined to force a march through a hostile Catholic neighborhood broke through a ... PRINCE WILLIAM FINALLY MEETS DAD&apos;S LONGTIME COMPANION.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 For the first time, Prince William has met his father&apos;s longtime companion -- the woman Princess Diana blamed for the breakup of her marriage to Prince Charles. 
 In an unusual move... PRISON AWAITS EX-SWEETHEARTS.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: Associated Press 
 WILMINGTON, Del. -- Without ever looking at each other across the courtroom, two former high school sweethearts once threatened with the death penalty for killing... PROGRAM TO BRING BIBLICAL ERA TO LIFE.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 WEST SAND LAKE -- First Bible Baptist Church will hold its Market Place 29 A.D. from 6:30 to 8:30 p.m. Wednesday through Friday, July 29-31. The experience of reliving bible time events,... PROMOTION OF TOURISM BENEFITS THE ENTIRE COUNTY.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: JOE DALTON 
 Tourism is a big business is Saratoga County. 
 In 1998 alone, its economic impact is anticipated to be in excess of $50 million, one-quarter of which comes during the... RAMSEYS LASH OUT AT POLICE DURING BRITISH TV INTERVIEW.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- Associated Press 
 LONDON -- The parents of JonBenet Ramsey broke a 14-month silence in a British television documentary aired Thursday that portrayed them as victims of a police... RANGERS HOPE MACLEAN CAN ADD SCORING PUNCH.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: Combined wire services 
 NEW YORK -- The New York Rangers signed former New Jersey Devils right wing John MacLean to a three-year, $7.2 million contract Thursday, adding depth and a... RETAIL SALES CONTINUE TO SURGE.(BUSINESS) July 10, 1998 Byline: RACHEL BECK Associated Press 
 NEW YORK -- Americans continued their shopping spree in June, giving the nation&apos;s retailers their sixth straight month of gains. 
 The Merrill Lynch... RONALDO LEADS NATION MINUS SUPPORTING CAST.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Rio De Janeiro Rua General Cesar Obino is like any other suburban Brazilian street. 
 It has a bar, a primary school and an evangelical church. An old woman sits in the sun on the steps... RONNIE JOHNSON MAKING HIS OWN NAME.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: ROBIN YASINSAC 
 Ronnie Johnson, son of modified sensation Jack Johnson, secured his first career 358-modified feature event victory Friday night at the Albany Saratoga Speedway. 
... ROSEANNE, WHOOPI READY FOR NEW TV ROLES.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Biting comic Roseanne credits an interview with boxer Mike Tyson, known for biting of another sort, to get her started on the road to hosting a talk show. 
 In November, the producers of the... ROTTWEILER ATTACKED GUIDE DOG EARLIER.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: MELISSA GRACE Staff writer 
 Albany A Rottweiler seized this week after it viciously attacked a guide dog on Madison Avenue has bitten a Seeing Eye dog at least once before,... RPI CENTER TO RESEARCH THEORIES OF CREATION.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: BRUCE A. SCRUTON Staff writer 
 The origins of life could be discovered on the Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute campus, with the creation of a new NASA-funded research center. 
 ... SARATOGA FILM FORUM IS SPONSORING SWING DANCE BENEFIT.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: KATHLEEN DOOLEY Staff writer 
 ``Shall We Dance&apos;&apos; is the name of an award winning film about a shy, conservative Japanese businessman whose life is transformed by the delights he... SCHODACK GROUP STARTS YOUTH BASKETBALL LEAGUE.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: BILL DOUGLAS Staff writer 
 Membership in the Schodack Youth Basketball League was growing, and parents of players were growing tired of traveling to Rensselaer and East Greenbush... SCHOOL DISTRICT HONORS SUPPORTERS.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 EAST GREENBUSH -- The East Greenbush Central School District Board of Education recently recognized staff and community members who have supported and contributed to the district. The following... SCHOOL DISTRICT WORKS ON VIOLENCE PREVENTION.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: THERESA M. PORTELLI Secretary, Albany School Board Albany 
 The Times Union recently printed an Associated Press report concerning the problem of violence nationwide among our... SCOUTS DEDICATE A CHURCH BENCH TO MEMORY OF A FRIEND WHO DIED BY KATHLEEN DOOLEY STAFF WRITER.(LIFE&amp;LEISURE) July 10, 1998 When Justin John Bonafide, 9, a member of Den 3, Cub Pack 67, died suddenly on April 21, 1997, from cardiac arrhythmia, it was a very difficult time for members of the Cub Scouts who were his... SCULPTURES HONOR THE GREAT MARTYRS.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Stone sculptures of Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. and El Salvador&apos;s Roman Catholic Archbishop Oscar Romero and eight other people were unveiled Thursday on the medieval front of Westminster Abbey ... SELIG POPULAR CHOICE.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: MURRAY CHASS New York Times 
 CHICAGO -- On his 2,130th day as acting commissioner, Major League Baseball club owners looked at Bud Selig and liked what they saw. So Thursday they... SENATE AFFIRMS IRS OVERHAUL.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: DAVID HESS Knight Ridder 
 WASHINGTON -- American taxpayers soon will have less to fear from an old nemesis -- the Internal Revenue Service. 
 No longer will they have to prove... SENATE DEMOCRATS BLOCK VOTE ON PRODUCT LIABILITY BILL.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: Associated Press 
 WASHINGTON -- Senate Democrats blocked action Thursday on legislation to limit punitive damage lawsuits, casting doubt on the future of a compromise worked out... SENATE EXEMPTS FARM CREDITS FROM SANCTIONS ON INDIA, PAKISTAN.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: Associated Press 
 WASHINGTON -- With millions of dollars of U.S. wheat exports on the line, the Senate voted Thursday to exempt agriculture credits from sanctions imposed on India... SENIOR HOUSING PLAN DIVIDES RESIDENTS.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: KIMBERLY MARTINEAU Staff writer 
 A plan to build senior housing in the center of Delmar sparked debate among more than 100 people at a Town Board meeting Wednesday. 
 The... SERVICE SET FOR FORMER LASALLE DIRECTOR.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: SCOTT PATTERSON Staff writer 
 Albany A memorial service will be held Saturday for Brother Brice Wilder, a religious school administrator known for his generosity and loyalty. He... SHAKER HERITAGE SOCIETY PLANS GUIDED TOURS.(LIFE&amp;LEISURE) July 10, 1998 COLONIE -- The Shaker Heritage Society will be offering guided tours at 11:30 a.m. and 1:30 p.m. every Saturday in July and August. 
 The tours of the Shaker Historic Site, located on the... SIENA COLLEGE ANNOUNCES 1998 GRADUATES.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Here is a list of recent Siena College graduates. Averill Park 
 Arthur J. Gagnon, accounting; Erin R. Lilly, English; Kathryn Vejvoda, biology; and Linda F. Wager, accounting. Berlin... SOCCER SLATE.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 1998 Fleet Bank/Clifton Park International Soccer Classic Participating Clubs Club, Hometown Addison United, North Ferrisburgh, Vt. Adirondack, Adirondack Ballston Spa, Ballston Spa Berkshire... SOME CHARTER COMMISSION MEMBERS PASS UP SESSIONS.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: EDWARD FITZPATRICK Staff writer 
 While public attendance at Charter Review Commission meetings can be sparse, some commission members are compiling abysmal attendance records of... STACKHOUSE IS WAITING TO SEE WHAT FUTURE HOLDS.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: MARK SINGELAIS Staff writer 
 TROY -- Free agent Jerry Stackhouse said Thursday he thinks he&apos;ll return to the Detroit Pistons next season. 
 But Stackhouse also mentioned possibly... STATE WINS COURT RULING ON COLLECTING INDIAN TAXES.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: JOHN CAHER State editor 
 New York&apos;s top court on Thursday overturned two lower rulings ordering the state to begin collecting sales taxes on gas and petroleum products sold on... STATUE FOR PENNOCK MEETS WITH RESISTANCE.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 KENNETT SQUARE, Pa. -- Baseball&apos;s struggle with integration during Jackie Robinson&apos;s rookie season wasn&apos;t made any easier by the Philadelphia Phillies or their general manager, Herb Pennock. ... STRIP CLUB OWNER&apos;S WIFE HASN&apos;T REPLACED DISQUALIFIED COUNSEL.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Schenectady Anne Segrue, the wife of Toy Box owner James Segrue, appeared in Schenectady County Court Thursday to tell a judge that she still has not obtained an attorney to represent her in... STUDENT VANDALS ARE MORE THAN JUST DISRUPTIVE.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: JIM HYER Athens 
 A reader recently commented on Dan Lynch&apos;s column concerning punishment for students who caused damage to a local school. 
 The reader uses the word... STUDY LINKS SOME JEWS TO HIGH PRIEST.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: Baltimore Sun 
 Some scientists say they&apos;ve used modern genetics to prove a biblical tradition -- that today&apos;s members of the Jewish priestly class who consider themselves... TASK FORCE AIMS TO KEEP WMHT IN COUNTY.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: CHRIS STURGIS Staff writer 
 Schenectady A bipartisan group of local, county and state officials gathered Thursday to vow ``any necessary assistance&apos;&apos; to keep public television... THANKS GO TO MANY FOR CELEBRATION AT PLAZA.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: PETER BORNN Latham 
 Many thanks are in order without question to the organizers and participants of the Fourth of July Celebration at the Empire State Plaza. 
 The Air Force... THE SCORECARD.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 GOLF EVERGREEN CC NON-PAR GOLF LEAGUE Gross: Joe Romer 41, Bill Thompson 43, John DeFrees 44, Bob Mason 44. Net: Fred Hellmuth 29, Bob Beckwith 32, Jim Kois 32. 508 GOLF LEAGUE Week of... THE WACKY LOOK IN SOME EYES IS NOTHING BUT A PRICEY NOVELTY.(LIFE&amp;LEISURE) July 10, 1998 Byline: KATHERINE L. DYKSTRA Knight Ridder 
 You&apos;re on your lunch break, about to pay the cashier at a fast-food restaurant. You glance up and suddenly notice -- gasp! -- his eyes are... THIRD PARTIES OFFER VOTERS A POLITICAL ALTERNATIVE.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: JOSEPH LAUX Vice Chairperson Liberal Party of New York State New Baltimore - 
 To paraphrase a former President, ``there you go, again.&apos;&apos; I am referring to your July 1 editorial... THOMAS DONATO.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 TULLY, NY -- Thomas Donato, 43, of Lincoln Ave., Tully, NY, died Wednesday, July 8, 1998 at his home. Born in Albany, he resided in Altamont, NY prior to moving to Tully seven years ago. He was... THOUGHTS OF A JOURNALIST, COUCH POTATO, PARENT.(LIFE&amp;LEISURE) July 10, 1998 Byline: MARK McGUIRE Staff writer 
 OK, let me see if I&apos;ve got this right: 
 1. I have to watch television. Lots of television. 
 2. When I&apos;m not watching television, I listen to the... TODAY FRIDAY, JULY 10 AMERICAN RED CROSS BLOODMOBILE. 8 A.M.-1 P.M.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Sand Lake Ambulance, 3643 Route 43, West Sand Lake. Appointments: 800-272-4543. 
 Chicken Barbecue. 4-7 p.m. Prince of Peace Lutheran Church, Third Avenue and 111th Street, Troy. Take out... TODAY FRIDAY, JULY 10.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 ``The Miss Firecracker Contest,&apos;&apos; 8 p.m., a play by Beth Henley. 8 p.m. Round Lake Auditorium. Exit 11, Northway, Round Lake. $10-12. 899-2130. Student Jazz Concert. 1 p.m. Filene Recital Hall.... TOUR SHOWCASES CITY GARDENS.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: KATHLEEN DOOLEY Staff writer 
 If you&apos;re dying for a peek at some of those picturesque backyard gardens in this community, the fourth annual Soroptimist Secret Garden Tour takes off... TRACK JOBS OPEN.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 SARATOGA SPRINGS -- The New York Racing Association is conducting interviews to fill 100 mutual and 100 security positions for the Saratoga meet running July 29-Sept. 7. 
 Interviews will be... TRIPP FACES JURY A 4TH DAY.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: Associated Press 
 WASHINGTON -- Linda Tripp testified Thursday for a fourth day in the Monica Lewinsky investigation while her lawyers and a Maryland prosecutor squabbled over... TRIVIA QUESTION.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Today&apos;s question: 
 What major league baseball stadium -- still in use today -- was opened in 1912, the same year that the Titanic sank? 
 Answer to yesterday&apos;s question: 
 Al Kaline of... TROOPER SAYS EVANS FEARS BEING LABELED AS A MONSTER.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: MIKE HUREWITZ Staff writer 
 Gary Evans, suspected of killing at least five people, is worried about his image. 
 ``He basically said to me, `I don&apos;t want to come across as a ... TROY LIBRARY REACHES OUT TO KIDS.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: LAURA LEE Staff writer 
 For the past four summers, Nancy Pedersen has hit the road bringing stories to area children. Pedersen is the story teller for the Troy Public Library&apos;s... TROY WINS A ROUND IN FIGHT TO KEEP CASE OUT OF U.S. BANKRUPTCY COURT.(BUSINESS) July 10, 1998 Byline: CLAIRE HUGHES Business writer 
 Troy The City of Troy won a small, interim victory Thursday in its effort to keep its case against Capital District Sports, which is now in state... TWO DIFFERENT STORIES TOUCHED ONE READER&apos;S LIFE.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: ANN M. PRIESTER East Greenbush 
 I cannot resist responding to two articles, only two days apart, that seem to summarize the past two and a half years of my life. 
 On Sunday, June... TYLENOL LABEL WARNS AGAINST MIXING PILLS WITH ALCOHOL.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- USA Today 
 New warnings appear this week on boxes of Tylenol in a stepped-up effort to halt a potentially deadly mixture: alcohol and the world&apos;s leading pain pill. 
 Each... U.N. ALLOWS TRIP TO CHECK ON KHADAFY&apos;S HEALTH.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- Associated Press 
 CAIRO, Egypt -- Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak flew to Libya on Thursday to see Col. Moammar Khadafy, a trip requiring special permission from the U.N.... U.S. EXPECTED TO HELP ITALIAN TOURISM.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: Associated Press 
 CAVALESE, Italy -- The United States should help restore tourism in a region of the Italian Alps where a Marine Corps jet severed the cable of a ski lift, killing... U.S. TRIES SHUTTLE DIPLOMACY BETWEEN KOSOVO FACTIONS.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- Associated Press 
 WASHINGTON -- The Clinton administration is launching a diplomatic shuttle between Serbs and Albanians to attempt an arrangement that would restore autonomy to... UNDERVALUED AMY GRANT INVIGORATING AT PALACE.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: P.C. ``PETE&apos;&apos; KUTSCHERA Colonie 
 Thanks to Steve Barnes for the insightful review of Amy Grant&apos;s ``Behind the Eyes&apos;&apos; tour performance June 24 at Albany Palace Theatre. For devoted... UNSCATHED BY ASIAN CRISIS, GE ENJOYS BOOM.(BUSINESS) July 10, 1998 Byline: RACHEL LAYNE Bloomberg News 
 General Electric Co.&apos;s second-quarter profit rose 13 percent, driven by another period of record sales at the maker of everything from light bulbs to... UPCOMING SATURDAY, JULY 11.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 11th annual Ole Tyme Fishing Derby. 8 a.m.-noon. Hampton Lake Park, East Greenbush. Sponsored by the Greenbush Bass Association, Kiwanis Club of East Greenbush-Nassau and Cumberland Farms Third... VACATION BIBLE SCHOOL JULY 20-24.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 BUSKIRK -- Buskirk Reformed Church, in cooperation with the Covered Bridge Circuit Methodist Churches, will hold a vacation Bible school from 10 a.m. until noon Monday through Friday, July... VIAGRA PRESCRIPTION FOILED THIEF, COPS SAY.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: BRENDAN LYONS Staff writer 
 Malta A 39-year-old man who allegedly used his neighbor&apos;s credit card to purchase 15 Viagra tablets at a Malta pharmacy was tracked by State Police... W. WARD BRYAN.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 STILLWATER -- W. Ward Bryan, 86, of South Hudson Avenue, Stillwater, died Wednesday at St. Mary&apos;s Hospital, Troy, following a short illness. Born in Mechanicville, he was the son of the late... WARMING TREND KILLS SEA LIFE.(MAIN) July 10, 1998 Byline: Associated Press 
 WASHINGTON -- Twenty years of warmer water is causing a severe decline in fish, birds, seaweed and mammals along the West Coast, say researchers who warn the trend... WEST TO BOLSTER RUSSIAN ECONOMY.(BUSINESS) July 10, 1998 Byline: MITCHELL LANDSBERG Associated Press 
 MOSCOW -- All major issues should be settled this week in talks with two Western lending agencies that are drafting plans to bail out Russia&apos;s... WILTON TRAIL PLAN OUTLINED.(CAPITAL REGION) July 10, 1998 Byline: KENNETH C. CROWE II Staff writer 
 Katy Price jogs through her Bradford Drive neighborhood worrying about traffic. Her husband, Chris, rides his bicycle to Skidmore College to use... YAHOO! UP AFTER STOCK SPLIT.(BUSINESS) July 10, 1998 Byline: -- Bloomberg News 
 SANTA CLARA, Calif. -- Yahoo! Inc. rose as much as 10 percent after the top Internet directory reported better-than-expected second-quarter earnings, revenue... YANKEES RESUME WINNING.(SPORTS) July 10, 1998 Byline: FRED GOODALL Associated Press 
 ST. PETERSBURG, Fla. -- The All-Star break didn&apos;t slow down the New York Yankees. 
 The AL East leaders won their seventh straight game and built on... 
 
 Company About us Subscription benefits Group subscriptions Partnership opportunities Careers Privacy policy Terms and conditions Contact us 

 Help topics FAQ Search tips Using the Research Center Billing questions Rights inquiries Customer Service 

 From our blog All posts Trending news Research How-to guides News and updates Testimonials 

 Cengage Learning Network Questia CengageBrain.com HighBeam Business Encyclopedia.com ed2go   
 HighBeam Research Follow us: 
HighBeam Research is operated by Cengage Learning .©Copyright 2012. All rights reserved.

The HighBeam advertising network includes: womensforum.com GlamFamily
	</body>
</document>
