<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001950" url="http://www.softcafe.com/menu-trivia.htm" time="2012-07-12-17:51" support="13" score="0.07616238595024222" bingtitle="Menu and Food Trivia - Restaurant Menu Software, Menu Design ..." webtitle="Menu and Food Trivia">
			<query id="001157" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000351" bing-rank="249"/>
			<query id="001145" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="000399" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="001115" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000269" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000372" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="001156" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000617" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="000274" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001147" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000362" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000895" bing-rank="44"/>
	<description>... to offer fresh-brewed coffee in to-go cups ... in 1928, is the world&apos;s largest drive-in fast-food restaurant. ... William Alcott opened the first store ...</description>
	<body>
		SoftCafe 

 Home Products Upgrades How to Order Support About 
 
Menu and Food Trivia

 
   
The first American restaurant to use printed menus was Delmonico&apos;s Steak House in New York City in 1837. They also created many 
 dishes including Lobster Newburg, Oysters Rockefeller, Eggs Benedict, 
 and, of course, Delmonico&apos;s Steak. In 1838 their menu had grown to 100 
 pages. 
   
Americans spend $1 billion dining out every day.
 
   
Approximately 150 people are killed each year by coconuts, more than are 
 killed by sharks .
 
   
 NASA included the hot 
 dog as a regular menu item on its Apollo moon flights. 
   
The Union Oyster House in 
 Boston, established in 1826, is the oldest restaurant in continuous service 
 in the United States.
 
   
Table salt is the only food 
 commodity that hasn&apos;t dramatically increased in price in the last 150 years.
 
   
The first credit card was 
 issued in 1951 when Diners Club issued cards to 200 people who could use them in 
 27 restaurants in New York City.
 
 
   
 7-Eleven was the 
 first retailer to offer fresh-brewed coffee in to-go cups, introducing it in their 
 Northeast stores in 1964.
 
   
Carrots were prized by early 
 Greek and Roman gardeners as aphrodisiacs. 
   
 The Varsity in Atlanta, 
 Georgia, established in 1928, is the world&apos;s largest drive-in fast-food restaurant.
 
   
The deep-dish pizza was 
 invented in Chicago by pizza entrepreneur Ike Sewell .
 
   There are about 3,500 ethnic 
 restaurants in New York City . 
   
Many restaurant menus 
 feature&quot;monkfish&quot;, but actually there is no such fish. It&apos;s a marketing name for fishes 
 belonging to the goosefish family. The edible meat comes only from the tail part 
 of the fish. 
   
Americans eat about 150 
 sandwiches a year--or 45 billion in 2002.
 
   
 Pizza Hut is the largest 
 pizza purveyor in the world, with more than 12,500 restaurants in the United 
 States and in more than 90 countries.
 
   Snake is a delicacy in China. 
   
The first-ever all-glass 
 undersea restaurant opened its doors recently at the
 Hilton 
 Maldives Resort&amp;Spa. Named Ithaa, it sits 16 feet below the Indian 
 Ocean 
   
In 1982, a Chicago restaurant 
 commissioned a sculptor to create a statue of Brooke Shields...made of 
 chopped liver.
 
   
An estimated 13 percent of the 
 food taken home in doggie bags from restaurants is actually fed to dogs .
 
   
About 25 percent of American 
 commuters eat breakfast in their cars.
 
   
In 1903, a German importer 
 tried to save a shipment of coffee beans that had been soaked in 
 saltwater. The result was de-caffeinated coffee, which he marketed as 
 Sanka.
 
   
 Italy produces more wine than 
 any other country in the world.
 
   
The world&apos;s largest restaurant 
 is Bangkok, Thailand&apos;s Royal Dragon , serving 5,000.
 
   
The average American spends 
 $20,000 on fast food in a lifetime.
 
   
Newport, Rhode Island&apos;s White 
 Horse Tavern , built in 1673, is the oldest tavern building in continuous use in 
 the United States.
 
   
About 2 percent of all Americans 
 are employed as a waiter or waitress.
 
   
The vintage date on a bottle 
 of wine denotes the year the grapes were picked, not the year of bottling.
 
   
About 10 percent of the 
 world&apos;s total fish catch is cod.
 
   
Cherrystone clams were named 
 after a creek in Virginia .
 
   
The average check at a diner 
 in 1920: 28 cents.
 
   
Chinese scholars praised 
 garlic as both a medicine and a food as long as 3,000 years ago.
 
   
The National Oyster Shucking 
 Championship (since 1967) is held each October at the St. Mary&apos;s County Oyster Festival in 
 Maryland, and pits the best female shucker against the top male shucker for the 
 national title.
 
   
Before dandelions became 
 weeds, they were cultivated purposely and people ate the leaves as a vegetable and 
 ground the roots for a coffee-like drink.
 
   
William Alcott opened the 
 first store specializing in health foods in Boston in 1830.
 
   
The first pizzeria in the 
 United States opened in New York City in 1905.
 
   
Vegetables should be gathered 
 from a garden in the morning or evening. If gathered when the sun is upon 
 them, they will be tough and discolored.
 
   
About 40 percent of the 
 world&apos;s cranberries are grown in just one state--Massachusetts.
 
   
There are more than 1,000 
 chemicals in a cup of coffee.
 
   
 Sliced bread and fortune 
 cookies were both invented in the U.S.
 
   
 The waters of North America 
 are home to more species of edible crabs than any other continent.
 
   
There are more than 20,000 
 brands of beer.
 
   
The oldest vegetable known to 
 man: peas .
 

 
 
Profit Center Articles
 
» Menu Profit Center Home 

» Menu Marketing 

» Daily Specials 

» Fancy Fonts 

» Menu English 

» Menu Covers 

» Website Tips 

» Free Web Presence 

» Online Ordering 

» Dining Ambience 

» Restaurant Menu Trivia 

» Menu Resources 
 
Great Menu Design
 
“A great menu does not have to be costly. If you take all the factors into account and create a simple, informative menu, that&apos;s really all you need”
 — Pizza Today Magazine , Nov. 2007 
 
 30-Day Guarantee Privacy Policy Free Menu Design Profit Tips Contact Us 
 
©2011 SoftCafe, LLC | MenuPro is registered trademark of SoftCafe, LLC
	</body>
</document>
