<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001281" url="http://ezinearticles.com/?Fast-Food-and-Restaurant-Secret-Recipes-Finally-Exposed&amp;id=1254231" time="2012-07-12-16:43" support="2" score="0.003386539044508325" bingtitle="Fast Food and Restaurant Secret Recipes Finally Exposed" webtitle="Fast Food and Restaurant Secret Recipes Finally Exposed">
			<query id="000052" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="001396" bing-rank="5"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant Recipes; Fast Food Feeding; The Fast Food Health Threat; Why Fast Food Companies Must Be Held Accountable for Their Ingredients</description>
	<body>
		Search Home » Food and Drink » Recipes Jerry Baubut 
 Platinum Author |   67 Articles 
 Joined: February 15, 2007 Was this article helpful? 0 0 
Fast Food and Restaurant Secret Recipes Finally Exposed

 By Jerry Baubut 
 
How would you like to stop paying for overpriced meals in restaurants? How would you like the ability to create all of those delicious &quot;top secret restaurant recipes at home&quot;?

Take, for example, Pizza Hut. In my opinion, you just can&apos;t buy pizza sauce like theirs. It is one of a kind, and is a big part of what makes their pizza just so delicious. I&apos;ll admit it, I&apos;m a sucker for pizza hut. I&apos;ve spent more then I&apos;d care to admit there over the course of the past few years.

So when money got tighter, pizza hut&apos;s prices started to bother me more and more. All I could think about was how much cheaper it would be for us to make our own pizza. Unfortunately we didn&apos;t have the secret recipes!

We started searching on the web, and quickly found out that there is actually a pretty big group of people out there that like posting what they call &quot;copycat recipes&quot;. Essentially what this is, is people taking their best guess at how to make famous food, and sharing their recipes.

I was super excited to find pizza hut&apos;s sauce on one of the lists. Unfortunately the more I looked, the more recipes I found. Tons and tons of different recipes, all for the same pizza sauce!

I was about to give up, when a friend told me about this secret cookbook that supposedly contained a heap full of the recipes used in the actual famous and popular restaurants. I reluctantly picked up a copy and gave it a try.

The result was a resounding success! Before the week was up, I had cooked several dishes that matched their restaurant counterparts. What a fantastic way to eat at home and save money!
 
How would you like to recreate the most famous popular recipes at home? This famous cookbook exposes all of the most famous and most delicious secret recipes on the planet including restaurants such as Applebee&apos;s and KFC.

You can learn more about it here .
 
Article Source: http://EzineArticles.com/?expert=Jerry_Baubut 
 Did you find this article helpful? 0 0 Get Involved 0 comments Suggest a topic Article Tools Print this article E-mail to a friend EzinePublisher Report this article Cite this article Stay Informed Get notified by email when new articles are added to this category or written by this author. 
Subscribe to New Article Alerts:
 
 Food and Drink: Recipes 
 Jerry Baubut 
 Email Address: Subscribe Recipes Article Feed Find More Articles Search 
Similar Articles

 Fast Food And Restaurant Secret Recipes The Perfect Fast Food Gourmet Breakfast at Home - No Drive-Through Restaurant Involved! Fast Food Duplicates - Copycat Cook Your Way to Your Favorite Recipes Restaurant Imitation Recipes - Who, What, Where and Why Fast Food Restaurant Recipes Fast Food Feeding The Fast Food Health Threat Why Fast Food Companies Must Be Held Accountable for Their Ingredients Fast Food and Obesity Are Conquering the World Fast Food Will Cost You More Than Money In The Long Run 
 
Recent Articles

 Recipe for Chicken Lentil Stew Filipino Fish Recipe - Rellenong Bangus Egg in the Hole With Mexican Cheese and Fire-Roasted Chiles Cheesy Baked Eggs - Quick, Tasty, Protein-Packed Meal Quick and Easy Veg Cheese Wrap Panzetta: Stuffed Breast of Veal Indian Cuisines With Growing Demand Crispy Egg Sandwich Straciatella, Escarole Soup 4th of July Chicken Marinade Recipe! 
 
Submitted On June 17, 2008. Viewed 3,198 times. Word count: 293.
 MLA Style Citation: 
Baubut, Jerry &quot;Fast Food and Restaurant Secret Recipes Finally Exposed.&quot; Fast Food and Restaurant Secret Recipes Finally Exposed .
 17 Jun. 2008 EzineArticles.com. 12 Jul. 2012&lt; http://ezinearticles.com/?Fast-­Food-­and-­Restaurant-­Secret-­Recipes-­Finally-­Exposed&amp;id=1254231 &gt;. APA Style Citation: 
Baubut, J. (2008, June 17). Fast Food and Restaurant Secret Recipes Finally Exposed .
 Retrieved July 12, 2012, from http://ezinearticles.com/?Fast-­Food-­and-­Restaurant-­Secret-­Recipes-­Finally-­Exposed&amp;id=1254231 Chicago Style Citation: 
Baubut, Jerry &quot;Fast Food and Restaurant Secret Recipes Finally Exposed.&quot; Fast Food and Restaurant Secret Recipes Finally Exposed EzineArticles.com . http://ezinearticles.com/?Fast-­Food-­and-­Restaurant-­Secret-­Recipes-­Finally-­Exposed&amp;id=1254231 
 EzineArticles.com 

©2012 EzineArticles.com
All Rights Reserved Worldwide
 
 About Us FAQ Contact Us Member Benefits Privacy Policy Shop Site Map 

 Blog Training Video Library Advertising Affiliates Cartoons 
 
Authors
 
 Submit Articles Members Login Premium Membership Expert Authors Endorsements Editorial Guidelines Terms of Service 
 
Publishers

Follow Us
 
 Terms Of Service Ezines / Email Alerts Manage Subscriptions EzineArticles RSS
	</body>
</document>
