<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001516" url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fast_casual_restaurant" time="2012-07-12-17:17" support="5" score="0.01980873818766072" bingtitle="Fast casual restaurant - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia" webtitle="Fast casual restaurant - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia">
			<query id="000615" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000898" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001023" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000972" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000992" bing-rank="22"/>
	<description>... higher quality of food and atmosphere than a fast food restaurant. ... Health-conscious items have a larger-than-normal ... Made-to-order food with more complex flavors than ...</description>
	<body>
		Fast casual restaurant 
 From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia Jump to: navigation , search 
A fast casual restaurant is a type of restaurant that does not offer full table service, but promises a higher quality of food and atmosphere than a fast food restaurant . In the US, it is a relatively new and growing concept positioned between fast food and casual dining . The typical cost per meal is in the US$8–$15 range. [ 1 ] 

 
Contents
 
 1 History 2 Logistics 3 See also 4 References 
 

 [ edit ] History 

The concept did not become a popular and common one for restaurants until the early to mid 1990s, and did not truly become mainstream until the beginning of the 2010s. [ 2 ] 

During the economic downturn beginning in 2007 , fast casual dining saw an uptick in sales from the 18–34 demographic . [ 3 ] Customers with limited discretionary meal spending tend to use it on dining perceived as healthier. [ 3 ] 

 [ edit ] Logistics 

Counter service accompanied by handmade food (often visible via an open kitchen) is typical. Alcohol may be served. Dishes like steak may be offered. The menu is usually limited to an extended over-counter display, and options in the way the food is prepared are emphasized. Health-conscious items have a larger-than-normal portion of the menu. Some restaurants may emphasize high quality ingredients like free range chicken and freshly made salsas . While full table service is not offered, conveniences like non-plastic utensils and plates are common.

Publisher and founder of FastCasual.com Paul Barron is credited for coining the term &quot;Fast Casual&quot; in the late 1990s, [ 4 ] while the company Technomic Information Services defined the term &quot;fast casual restaurants&quot; as meeting the following criteria: [ 5 ] 

 Limited-service or self-service format Average meal price between $7 and $11 Made-to-order food with more complex flavors than fast food restaurants Upscale or highly developed decor 

 [ edit ] See also 

 List of casual dining restaurant chains Types of restaurants 

 [ edit ] References 
 
 ^ &quot;Fast Casual – Insights for Innovative Restaurants&quot; . FastCasual.com . http://www.fastcasual.com/ . Retrieved 29 June 2011 .   ^ &quot;2010’s Twenty Largest Fast-Casual Franchises&quot; . BlueMauMau . http://www.bluemaumau.org/9057/2010%E2%80%99s_twenty_largest_fastcasual_franchises . Retrieved 29 June 2011 .   ^ a b Jargon, Julie (1 February 2010). &quot;As Sales Drop, Burger King Draws Critics for Courting &apos;Super Fans&apos;&quot; . The Wall Street Journal (Yahoo! Finance) . http://finance.yahoo.com/career-work/article/108728/burger-king-draws-critics . Retrieved 1 February 2010 .   ^ Wheelen, Thomas L.; Hunger, J. David (2006). Strategic Management and Business Policy: Cases (10th ed.). Upper Saddle River, N.J: Pearson Prentice Hall. ISBN   978-0-13-149460-2 .   ^ &quot;What exactly is fast casual?&quot; . Franchise Times . January 2008 . http://www.franchisetimes.com/content/story.php?article=00643 . Retrieved 23 January 2011 .   
 Retrieved from &quot; http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Fast_casual_restaurant&amp;oldid=496929677 &quot; Categories :
 Fast casual restaurants 
 Hidden categories:
 Use dmy dates from April 2012 
 
Personal tools

 Create account Log in 
 
Namespaces

 Article Talk 
 


 Variants 
 

 
Views

 Read Edit View history 
 
 Actions 
 

 
 Search 
 
Navigation
 
 Main page Contents Featured content Current events Random article Donate to Wikipedia 
 
Interaction
 
 Help About Wikipedia Community portal Recent changes Contact Wikipedia 
 
Toolbox
 
 What links here Related changes Upload file Special pages Permanent link Cite this page 
 
Print/export
 
 Create a book Download as PDF Printable version 
 
Languages
 
 日本語 
 
 This page was last modified on 10 June 2012 at 17:34.
 Text is available under the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike License ;
additional terms may apply.
See Terms of use for details.
Wikipedia®is a registered trademark of the Wikimedia Foundation, Inc. , a non-profit organization.
 Contact us 

 Privacy policy About Wikipedia Disclaimers Mobile view
	</body>
</document>
