<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001008" url="http://news.pcamerica.com/pcamericanewsletter401.html" time="2012-07-12-16:25" support="8" score="0.007740843391409555" bingtitle="pcAmerica Newsletter #401-March 15, 2011" webtitle="pcAmerica Newsletter #401-March 15, 2011">
			<query id="001196" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="001416" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="001213" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001432" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="001219" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="001201" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="000274" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="001434" bing-rank="170"/>
	<description>... of Sale, barcode readers, cash drawers and receipt ... I have noticed that these energy shot bottles keep ... I had an experience in a very busy fast food restaurant that has 6 ...</description>
	<body>
		pcAmerica Newsletter #401   March 15, 2011 

 
 
 In This Issue pcAmerica Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ) Energy Shots Grow by 40.2% Drive-thru Rage: Problem? Or are People Just Crazy? Who Has the Largest Restaurant Chain? 

 Contacting pcAmerica  
 Toll Free 1-800-PC-AMERICA or 1-800-722-6374 
 Local Number 1-845-920-0800 
 Fax Number 1-845-920-0880 
 Tech Support Number   1-845-920-0888 
 
=================== 
pcAmerica One Blue Hill Plaza 
 Second Floor 
 Box 1546 
 Pearl River NY 10965 
   ======================= 
 
 JOIN OUR BLOG!    www.talkpos.com 
     ======================== 

 C.E.O. David J. Gosman ( djg@pcamerica.com )
 
 President Richard F. Rotbard ( rotbard@pcamerica.com ) 
 
Newsletter Editor Howard Y. Gosman ( hgosman@pcamerica.com )
 
 Contributing Editor/Database Administration Steven M. Kahan ( stevekahan@pcamerica.com )
 
 Sales Manager Steve Rimpici ( SRimpici@pcamerica.com ) 

 Your pcAmerica Account Managers 
 Elisa Alonzo X292 ( ealonzo@pcamerica.com ) 
   Ken May X226 ( kensmay@pcamerica.com ) 
   Martin Sheridan X227 ( msheridan@pcamerica.com ) 
   Ralph Frascone X279 ( rfrascone@pcamerica.com ) 
   Robert Purdy X280 ( rpurdy@pcamerica.com ) 
   Ryan Christman X225 ( ryan@pcamerica.com ) 
   Sam Kahan X223 ( skahan@pcamerica.com ) 
   
 Tony Scarpa X224 

  ( tscarpa@pcamerica.com ) 
    

 Frank Fullam X288 ( frankfullam@pcamerica.com ) 
 
 

 More Information  For more information on Cash Register Express, Restaurant Pro Express, Asset Management Software, Portable and Wireless Point of Sale, barcode readers, cash drawers and receipt printers, call PC America at
 
 1-800-PC-AMERICA or 1-800-722-6374 or 1-845-920-0800. 
 You may also purchase directly on the internet at:
 
 http://www.pcamerica.com 
Email sales questions to:

 sales@pcamerica.com   
 Email newsletter comments to: 
 newsletter@pcamerica.com 

 Removal  
 You are receiving this email because you either own Cash Register Express (or Restaurant Pro Express) or have contacted PC America and requested information about Cash Register Express or Restaurant Pro Express. If you wish to be removed from our email newsletter list, please click on the link below or email your removal request to:

 newsletter@pcamerica.com 
 
or write to: 
PC America
 One Blue Hill Plaza
 Second Floor
 Box 1546
Pearl River NY 10965. 

 Previous Newsletters 
 
 See Previous Newsletters at:   
 pcamerica.com/newsletter.html 

 
 FAQ (Frequently Asked Questions) 
 Find documents and answers to many of the most commonly asked questions about Restaurant Pro Express, Cash Register Express, and other pcAmerica products.    The site is constantly updated. If there is a queston you have that is not answered email pcAmerica at:   pcAmerica Support Center 
 
 
 
 
 

 pcAmerica Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ) 

 

     

 The answer is on our website. 

   

pcAmerica has an exceptional FAQ website that will answer many of your questions and is being constantly updated. If you can&apos;t find your answer, you can reach our telephone tech support 24 hours per day, 7 days per week at the number on the left. You can also reach our support center by emailing to:

 

 pcAmerica Support Center (Via Email) 

 

Prior to calling or emailing support, please check out our Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ) at:

 

 pcAmerica Online Support Center 

 

Start by clicking on he Navigation options located on the left side of the web page.

 

Your link to the Technical Support Center along with tech support phone number and email address appear on the left side of our newsletters. Phone support is available to all pcAmerica customers who have an up to date technical support contract. If you don&apos;t know you tech support expiration date, please give your Account Manager a call. 

   
 
 
 
 
 
 Energy Shots Grow by 40.2%   
 

 The Energy Shot market has grown by 40.2%. Only I would know this because I read Convenience Store News. I have to admit that as of last week, I didn&apos;t have a clue about the subject of energy shots. I have noticed that these energy shot bottles keep taking up more space in convenience stores. I&apos;ve also seen them displayed in some clothing stores and gyms. 

   

 Owning a convenience store is a real challenge. 

   

 The average convenience store nets $17,616 from selling lottery tickets which does not include labor costs or fixed costs such as rent. Lottery sales have stagnated in the past year. 

   

 Tobacco sales, the old staple for convenience stores, are on a continuous decline. 

   

 For those convenience stores with gas pumps, sales are a mess. Most of the higher gas prices go to taxes. Convenience store owners frequently lock in their gas prices months in advance. Any temporary flood of profits that they may see when prices go up are quickly lost when gas prices go down due to higher contracted prices. In other words, convenience stores are just making it at the gas pumps. 

   

 Along comes Energy Shots . One of the most popular energy shots is called 5-Hour Energy . I&apos;ve seen this drink stacked up on shelves within many convenience stores. 

    

 The drink comes in lemon-lime, orange, pomegranate, grape, and decaf citrus. For those students who need to pull an all nighter studying for a test, you can get Extra Strength Berry . 

    

 According to WebMD: 

    

Tired, stressed-out college students and workers have embraced energy shots, which promise a quick, convenient boost with fewer calories and less sugar than full-size energy drinks.

 

The popular energy shots come in little 2-3 ounce containers and tend to have about the same amount of caffeine as an 8-ounce Red Bull.

 

The amount of caffeine in a typical energy shot is about the same as an 8 ounce cup of coffee from Starbucks. For comparison purposes, you would need to drink a little more than 5 cans of Coke to digest the same amount of caffeine found in a Starbucks 8 ounce cup of coffee or single energy shot.

 

According to WebMD, too much caffeine can cause nervousness, trouble sleeping, nausea, vomiting, rapid heartbeats, and higher blood pressure. Many makers of energy shots say children and those who are pregnant, nursing, or sensitive to caffeine should avoid the beverage. 5-Hour Energy advises no more than two bottles a day.

 

 You can read all about 5-hour Energy (and even order online) at: 

 

 5-Hour Energy Shots 

 You can purchase energy shots at your local 7-Eleven. 

 Read Energy Shots Review: Do They Work? Are They Safe? on WebMD at: 

 Energy Shots According to WebMD 

 
   
 
 
 
 Drive-thru Rage: Problem? Or are People Just Crazy?   
     

 A little levity for those businesses having problem customers. 

   

 At a Denny&apos;s restaurant in Massachusetts, &quot;grand slam&quot; took a whole new meaning when a huge group fight broke out over syrup. 

   

 At McDonalds, a customer jumped through the drive-thru window because the employee refused to serve Chicken McNuggets during breakfast hours. 

   

 A Burger King employee was attacked because the customer suspected that the employee spit in her food. 

 
 
 Stephen Westmoreland, a mental health counselor, says this kind of behavior is getting worse each year.  

 

 I had an experience in a very busy fast food restaurant that has 6 checkout registers. My friend made a $9.45 purchase. He gave the cashier a $20 bill and received 55 cents in change. I saw it with my own eyes. The manager became irate and had the employee recount the entire drawer which turned out to have a $10 overage. The manager finally refunded the $10 to my quite upset friend who had to wait ten minutes or so for that refund. 

   

 I know a particular car wash that trains its employees never to argue with customers related to change. If a customer states that he was not given the correct change, the employee is supposed to graciously rectify the situation by giving the customer, with a smile, whatever he is asking for without having the manager intervene (obviously within reason). A happy customer is the best customer (even if the customer is wrong). 

   

 If you have a minute and need some comic relief, you can read more and see a video with the Burger King Drive-thru incident, the syrup fight video, and the McDonalds McNuggets incident by going to: 

   

 Restaurant Rage 

    
 
 
 
 
 Who Has the Largest Restaurant Chain?  
 
 Is it: 
    

 (A) Starbucks 

    

 (B) Burger King 

 

 (C) McDonalds 

 

 (D) Dunkin Donuts 

 

 (E) None of the above. 

 

 If you chose (E) you are correct. Subway is now #1 in terms of units. 

 

 Subway now has 33,749 restaurants compared to 32,737 for McDonald&apos;s. 

 

 McDonald&apos;s still leads Subway in revenues ($24 billion compared to $15 billion). 

 

 At last count, Starbucks only has 16,635 stores (which does not include the one that just opened down the corner). 

 

 The count for Dunkin Donuts is approximately 7,000 stores.
	</body>
</document>
