<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001852" url="http://www.agrsveml.com/page/3/" time="2012-07-12-17:38" support="7" score="0.005086669795863208" bingtitle="Aggressive Skates, Aggressive skate news, aggressive skating blog (3)" webtitle="Aggressive Skates, Aggressive skate news, aggressive skating blog (3)">
			<query id="000272" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="001201" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="001275" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="001390" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="001150" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="000961" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="001213" bing-rank="133"/>
	<description>Can someone confirm this for me? No? Fine. F@#$! ... on the back side of a Burger King receipt. Which, by the way was just recently voted the worst fast food restaurant on the ...</description>
	<body>
		AG + RS + VE + ML 
 
 Trust Spec Ops Liner Review 
 April 30th, 2012 by Radsac 
I normally skate the stock liners in all of my skates because I never have any problems with them but when I saw the Trust Spec Ops liners I knew that I needed to try them out. Just look at those bad boys sitting there screaming Special Forces all over.

 
 The liners look awesome with all of the subtle details in their design. Cool Trust logos throughout! 

 

The first thing that you will notice when taking the liners out of their professional looking Apple style box (is iBox the correct term?) is that the liners are extremely light. A lightweight liner is something that we can all appreciate because it allows you to use less energy all day long when your constantly jumping up for grinds and airs. Also it is just plum nice having your skates feel light on your feet and not feel like your dragging around a bunch of heavy clunkers.

I put the size 9 Spec Ops liners in my size 9 Valo x AM EB Denim skates and they fit in the skates perfectly. The main thing that I noticed when skating the liners was that they made my skates feel more solid on my feet because I was able to properly tighten the liners with their lacing system. The Valo liners do not have laces which makes putting your skates on faster but having the laces on the Spec Ops liners really makes a difference in getting a nice, tight fit.

After skating the liners a couple of sessions they felt even more comfortable as they broke in and conformed to my feet. I wouldn’t say that they require a break in period but I definitely felt that they were even better feeling after putting some hours in them.

The liners also come with good insoles and other features such as a grippy bottom created from some type of classified material that is specially formulated to grip the inside of your skates to prevent liner slippage.

 
 The liners in my Valo skates. A perfect match! 

I’ve now had them for about 2 months and everything is holding up in the construction of the liners. The Spec Ops liners have kept their integrity and the foam used for the padding has not broken down and still provides an excellent fit along with good comfort on my feet.

My overall experience with the liners is a 5 out of 5 stars and I would definitely recommend them to all Valo skaters. If you are skating the standard Valo skates such as the TV 2’s, 3’s, Broskows, Baileys etc. you can just get the same liner size as your skate size. If you are skating the new Valo Lights, you can actually fit a bigger sized liner in the skates allowing you to size down in shell sizes. For example you can fit a size 10 Trust Spec Ops liner in the size 9 Valo Lights.

“Unlock the World”- Quote overheard from the owner of Trust…or maybe it was his pickup line he used at the local watering hole. I forget but either way, these liners made my day.

 Click here to pick up a pair: Also available in black.
 
 
Posted in Inventory , trust mfg , 2012 | 2 Comments» 
 
 Youth Size 1 Frames are Here 
 April 27th, 2012 by Radsac 
Jon Julio stopped by the shop today and dropped off his new Youth frames in size 1. With an all star team of Jon himself, Chris Haffey and Chris Farmer, you know the Youth frames are going to be good. Kyle Nolte already bolted a pair on his Xsjado Jeff Stockwell 4 skates and is looking forward to giving them a try this weekend.

 

 Youth Jon Julio Pro Frame ($49.95)
 
 
Youth Chris Haffey Pro Frame ($49.95)
 
 
Youth Chris Farmer Pro Frame ($49.95)
 

 Click here for the Youth Frameworks entire product line. 
 
Posted in New Products , 2012 | 6 Comments» 
 
 Valo TV 3 Skates: Available Now! 
 April 27th, 2012 by Radsac 
Valo just released their new TV 3 skates in white and black for those of you who are in need of some new skates. The TV 3’s have a new skin design and they feature the new Valo 2 piece souls as well as 58mm wheels for increased speed and longer wheel life.

Peep the edit Jon Julio put together for them:
 

 
Valo TV 3 Skate White ($224.00)
 
 

 Valo TV 3 Skate Black ($224.00)
 
 

 Valo TV 3 White Boot Only ($189.00)
 
 
Valo TV 3 Black Boot Only ($189.00)
 

 Valo TV 3 White Custom Skate (Get it the way you want)
 

 Valo TV 3 Black Custom Skate (Get it the way you want)
 
 
Click here for our entire selection of Valo aggressive skates. 
 
Posted in Valo skates , vimeo , 2012 | No Comments» 
 
 Amall Trick Tip: True Top Soyal 
 April 27th, 2012 by Radsac 
Tim breaks down the True Top Soyal for those of you looking to add one of the most stylish tricks to your blader game.

Filmed and edited by Kyle G and Gene.

 
 
Posted in youtube , 2012 | 6 Comments» 
 
 ITS FRIDAY 
 April 27th, 2012 by Juicy Hamburger 
 
 
Posted in A BANANA , 2012 | 2 Comments» 
 
 Amall Staff Picks #2 
 April 25th, 2012 by Juicy Hamburger 
 

Check out the Staff Pick for 4/25/2012 with amall staffer and custom skate builder extraordinaire Tim Kahana, right here on the AMALL web site.
 
Posted in A BANANA , 2012 | 3 Comments» 
 
 Local Edit: Platinum Cookies 
 April 24th, 2012 by Radsac 
Platinum Cookies: A local edit by Erik Newman or a strain you might find at your local dispensary.

Filmed&amp;Edited By : Erik Newman
Starring : Gene Steagall, Danny Bovee, Erik Newman, and Ryan Evanchik

 
 
Posted in youtube , 2012 | 1 Comment» 
 
 Dre’s Monday Photo Submission 
 April 23rd, 2012 by Radsac 
Nick Lindsey caught Dre doing this gap over the weekend. 760 is the code. Somebody should go one up him on the gap and submit their photo to derek@aggressivemall.com. If it’s good enough maybe I’ll send out a free prize and put the photo on the blog.*

 
 
*Not an official contest, maybe means maybe. At the very least you will have a cool photo of yourself to put on your social networking front pages. Always feel free to try and collect from Dre.
 
 
Posted in photos , A BANANA , 2012 | 8 Comments» 
 
 GC Featherlite 2 Purple Frames Promo: Aragon and Powell 
 April 18th, 2012 by Radsac 
New edit from Razor News that features a promo for the Ground Control Purple Featherlite 2 frames with Brian Aragon and Dre Powell and a promo for the new Razors spring clothing line with Chris Calkins.

 

Edited/Filmed By: Max Manning
Starring: Dre Powell&amp;Brian Aragon
Additional Filming By: Scott Olsen

 Ground Control Featherlite 2 Frames Purple
 
 Razors Double Barrel Tee (Available in black, white or blue)
 

 Razors Double Barrel Hoodie (Available in black or white)
 

Also known as the Double R tee and hoodie, we just decided to name them after the double barrel shotgun.
 
Click here for our entire selection of GC frames. 
 
Click here for our entire selection of Razors clothing. 
 
Posted in razors skates , New Products , ground control frames , youtube , 2012 | No Comments» 
 
 The Breakfast Club DVD 
 April 11th, 2012 by Radsac 
The Breakfast Club: Five strangers with nothing in common except their skating.

Dear Cavin B,

We accept the fact that we had to skate the whole year, despite our injuries and busy schedules. But we think you’re creazy to make us write an essay telling you who we think we are. You see us as you want to see us. In the simplest terms and the most convenient definitions. But what we found out is that each one of us is a brain and an athlete and a basket case, a princess and a criminal.

Does that answer your question?

Sincerely yours,

The Breakfast Club

One team, one year, many places…

“Cool 80’s music, sexual tension, good looking teenagers and most importantly, dollops of attitude.”-TEEN Magazine

 

 Pick up your copy today for $19.95
 

 Click here to check out our entire selection of aggressive skate DVDs. 
 
Posted in New Products , Rollerblading magazines&amp;DVD&apos;s , 2012 | 1 Comment» 
 
 Create Originals Spring Clothing Line 
 April 10th, 2012 by Radsac 
Create Originals just released their new line of clothing which included some dog tags, beanies, tee’s, a v-neck and polo.
 
Laser Engraved OG Dog Tag
 

 Create Originals Slouch Beanie
 

 
Create Originals Scribble Skull Tee
 

 Create Originals OG Burnout V-Neck Earth Tone
 
 
Create Originals Crested Burnout Polo
 
 
Click here for our entire selection of Create Originals clothing. 
 
Posted in New Products , Create Originals , 2012 | No Comments» 
 
 New Rollerblade Solo Skates 
 April 10th, 2012 by Radsac 
Rollerblade has their new Rob G. 2 pro model Solo skates and their all white Trooper’s available for you to pick up right now to give yourself a fresh pair of skates this spring. The new skates feature their new blank frame and come ready to go with nice and big 60mm wheels, quick bearings and 47mm anti rockers.

 Rollerblade Solo Estilo Rob G 2 Skates
 

 Rob G 2 Boot Only
 

 Rollerblade Solo Trooper Skate
 
 
RB Solo Trooper Boot Only
 

 Click here for entire selection of Rollerblade skates. 
 
Posted in Rollerblade skates , 2012 | 2 Comments» 
 
 Prometheus 
 April 4th, 2012 by Radsac 
“Big things have small beginnings”

 

At Amall we like aliens of all types, especially the type that is one day going to abduct Thee JH. Seriously it’s going to happen. Anyways I saw the Prometheus trailer a little while back and got inspired to put together a package deal in anticipation for the movie. I suppose I could have made a Power Rangers pack if Eulogy made pink wheels, but I think those fools are long gone and dead anyways.

We already had someone use this pack for party favors to give out which made me think that I wish I went to parties with Eulogy wheels as the party favor gift.
 
Prometheus Pack ($159.95)
 

 Click here to check out all of our package deals. 
 
Posted in Misc. News , New Products , youtube , Eulogy Wheels , 2012 | 1 Comment» 
 
 Youth Frameworks Clothing&amp;Backpacks 
 April 3rd, 2012 by Radsac 
I know you probably really want to try the new Youth frames, but they are just not quite out yet. Those of you at BCSD had a chance to pick some up and are probably out skating them right now. Either way, here are a couple t-shirts, hats and backpacks from Youth to get you geared up in anticipation for their frames.

I picked up the Barcelona backpack at BCSD and have been using it every day since. It’s a nice, light backpack that keeps everything simple for those of you like me who don’t need a house for a backpack.

 Youth Cord Hat Red
 
 
Youth Cord Hat Black
 

 Youth Seal Tee (Available in black or white)
 
 
We Are Youth Tee (Available in black or white)
	</body>
</document>
