<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001751" url="http://www.sk-gaming.com/content/20501-World_of_Warcraft_the_restaurant" time="2012-07-12-17:31" support="1" score="0.0023051694255231663" bingtitle="World of Warcraft: World of Warcraft, the restaurant | SK Gaming" webtitle="World of Warcraft: World of Warcraft, the restaurant | SK Gaming">
			<query id="000312" bing-rank="92"/>
	<description>The owner of the restaurant said he, &quot;created the diner in the hope that people who ... Counter-Strike • Warcraft III • World of Warcraft • Heroes of Newerth • ...</description>
	<body>
		Time:   17:31:50 CET   08:31:50 PST   11:31:50 EST   00:31:50 Seoul   23:31:50 Beijing CS: Esport Index WC3: Esport Index WoW: Esport Index FIFA: 1v1 Clothes&amp;Hardware SK Fan Wear Games 
 You are here: Home / News / World of Warcraft: World of Warcraft, the restaurant NEWS World of Warcraft, the restaurant 

 By - &apos;shagrath&apos; - Dec 11, 2008 07:46 
 China&apos;s online gaming themed service industry appears to be booming, riding its fascination with online gaming all the way to the top is a Chinese restaurateur with his World of Warcraft inspired eatery. Tweet 

 Blizzard themselves once joked about opening a chain of Blizzard themed fast food restaurants aptly named&quot;Burgercraft&quot;, but as we all know, China takes the internet very seriously.

The restaurant is decked out with World of Warcraft paraphernalia, from the wallpaper to the menus, everything is themed. The front door of the restaurant is designed to resemble the&apos;Dark Portal&apos;from the opening cinematic of the&quot;Burning Crusade&quot;. Paintings of game characters line the walls and a large television centered in the restaurant plays game footage for patrons.

The owner of the restaurant said he,&quot;created the diner in the hope that people who share his enthusiasm for the World of Warcraft would find a comfortable gathering place.&quot;

Check out video footage of the restaurant at CCTV.com .
 

 RELATED NEWS Team Ninjapull Live at the RPC in Cologne! (1) SteelSeries announce WoW Legendary Mouse (5) Cooperation between Ninjapull and SK Gaming (3) 
 78 comments 
 Loading comments... 
 
 Most read last month 
 Most discussed last month 
 COMMENTS 
 «Previous 1 2 Next» Tufast 3 years ago +1 thumbs holy .... Crap cakes Reply   holy .... Crap cakes 
 Thund- 3 years ago +1 thumbs sounds like fun Reply   sounds like fun 
 SK|SPILLOUT 3 years ago +4 thumbs there seems to be nothing that doesn&apos;t exist. Reply   there seems to be nothing that doesn&apos;t exist. 
 Krasher 3 years ago +1 thumbs hello there i just wanna say that this is a very good idea i hope they get noticed and become
popular like all the other restaurants that we see everyday
good luck guys ! Reply   hello there i just wanna say that this is a very good idea i hope they get noticed and become
popular like all the other restaurants that we see everyday 
good luck guys ! 
 Gandros 3 years ago +2 thumbs Can I pay my bill with WoW Gold? Reply   Can I pay my bill with WoW Gold? 
 diG1tY 3 years ago +1 thumbs Ownage Reply   Ownage 
 Yiedra 3 years ago +0 thumbs Geif WoW theme parks and restaurants in spain plix? :o( Reply   Geif WoW theme parks and restaurants in spain plix? :o( 
 Lunny 3 years ago +0 thumbs Hi can i take your order?

Yes, i&apos;d like a tauren stake with friend gnomes on it. Possible some mage food also... Reply   Hi can i take your order?

Yes, i&apos;d like a tauren stake with friend gnomes on it. Possible some mage food also... 
 PAFii 3 years ago +0 thumbs lol sick indeed :D Reply   lol sick indeed :D 
 Zaffew0w 3 years ago +0 thumbs Conjured Cinnamon Rolls please Reply   Conjured Cinnamon Rolls please 
 Toshirou 3 years ago +1 thumbs Wahaha.. I&apos;ve had the most crappy week in my life with some shitty education-project. I went home, checked SK-gaming.com and saw this topic. It really made my day, i had an amazing laugh... haha.. thank you China! :) Reply   Wahaha.. I&apos;ve had the most crappy week in my life with some shitty education-project. I went home, checked SK-gaming.com and saw this topic. It really made my day, i had an amazing laugh... haha.. thank you China! :) 
 bsidebg 3 years ago +2 thumbs OMG xD Burgercraft ... daaamn this China take things to serious :/ Reply   OMG xD Burgercraft ... daaamn this China take things to serious :/ 
 lindoNz 3 years ago +2 thumbs &quot;but as we all know, China takes the internet very seriously.&quot;QFT HAHA Reply   &quot;but as we all know, China takes the internet very seriously.&quot;QFT HAHA 
 Jeffgoldblum 3 years ago +2 thumbs O.o Sooooo crazy and nerdy lol, but you know I and everyone else here, would be eating dinner there at least once a week. Reply   O.o Sooooo crazy and nerdy lol, but you know I and everyone else here, would be eating dinner there at least once a week. 
 Toshirou 3 years ago +1 thumbs I dont know about that! Depends on the prices ;) Im poor and nerdy :) Reply   I dont know about that! Depends on the prices ;) Im poor and nerdy :) 
 Cylia 3 years ago +1 thumbs Nerdy, don&apos;t know, I think it&apos;s awesome :)

And that it&apos;s a serious restaurant makes it better, it&apos;s not some 2nd hand burger place lol, and the athmosphere seems awesome aswell =P Reply   Nerdy, don&apos;t know, I think it&apos;s awesome :)

And that it&apos;s a serious restaurant makes it better, it&apos;s not some 2nd hand burger place lol, and the athmosphere seems awesome aswell =P 
 RiPLAYYY 3 years ago -1 thumbs omagad, i need to try this restaurant !
but, i hope there won&apos;t have a queue at raiding time, or insane lags to get the bill ! xD Reply   omagad, i need to try this restaurant !
but, i hope there won&apos;t have a queue at raiding time, or insane lags to get the bill ! xD 
 Lunny 3 years ago +6 thumbs You need to be exalted with China to enter this restaurant. Reply   You need to be exalted with China to enter this restaurant. 
 ThE_KlasK 3 years ago +2 thumbs well i aint puttin my teeth in that dragon shit unless they got max cooking skill :) Reply   well i aint puttin my teeth in that dragon shit unless they got max cooking skill :) 
 tricky11 3 years ago +1 thumbs That&apos;s wonderful, I saw the video and the ambiance is really for gamers. OMG I should come to china and visit that restaurant. Did I see it right, you can play and farm wow gold inside the restaurant? I&apos;m excited to there. Reply   That&apos;s wonderful, I saw the video and the ambiance is really for gamers. OMG I should come to china and visit that restaurant. Did I see it right, you can play and farm wow gold inside the restaurant? I&apos;m excited to there. 
 tricky11 3 years ago +1 thumbs That&apos;s wonderful, I saw the video and the ambiance is really for gamers. OMG I should come to china and visit that restaurant. Did I see it right, you can play and farm wow gold http://wowgoldpig.com inside the restaurant? I&apos;m excited to go there. Reply   That&apos;s wonderful, I saw the video and the ambiance is really for gamers. OMG I should come to china and visit that restaurant. Did I see it right, you can play and farm wow gold http://wowgoldpig.com inside the restaurant? I&apos;m excited to go there. 
 nzk- 3 years ago +1 thumbs wOw... not for me :( Reply   wOw... not for me :( 
 Ishiwatari 3 years ago +2 thumbs Go pex reputation :D for enter the restaurant. in win the recompense.
Nice Quest in the restaurant. :D Reply   Go pex reputation :D for enter the restaurant. in win the recompense. 
Nice Quest in the restaurant. :D 
 Maetrik 3 years ago +1 thumbs Jveut bienêtre béta testeur :&gt; Reply   Jveut bienêtre béta testeur :&gt; 
 Jik- 3 years ago +0 thumbs haha :&gt;its like mc10, an movie from a swedish filmgroup named krullproductions. They did a parody with cs an restaurant, bet it&apos;ll come in china aswell McFisker, chili concArn, seven hp, colt cola, NiP med Dip etc :D Reply   haha :&gt;its like mc10, an movie from a swedish filmgroup named krullproductions. They did a parody with cs an restaurant, bet it&apos;ll come in china aswell McFisker, chili concArn, seven hp, colt cola, NiP med Dip etc :D 
 GarsonProduction 3 years ago +1 thumbs Buy 10 burger meals and get a game card! now only at Mcdonalds.cn

Edit: or get Illidan, Arthas some of the other cool lore chars in your happy meal! Reply   Buy 10 burger meals and get a game card! now only at Mcdonalds.cn

Edit: or get Illidan, Arthas some of the other cool lore chars in your happy meal! 
 Maetrik 3 years ago +1 thumbs hahaha :) Reply   hahaha :) 
 betrayal666 3 years ago +1 thumbs what. the. fuck. :O Reply   what. the. fuck. :O 
 
 «Previous 1 2 Next» Not logged in 
 Site Links News • Features • Videos • Albums • Files • Blogs • Groups • Community • Forums • Esport Index • Shop • Jobs 
 SK Gaming Players • Awards • Media • Partners • About • Logos • Hall of fame 
 Game channels Counter-Strike • Warcraft III • World of Warcraft • Heroes of Newerth • Starcraft 2 • CONSOLE 
 Misc Contact • Privacy Policy • Terms of Agreement • RSS feeds • Twitter • Facebook Pages • Facebook Group 

Copyright©SK Gaming 1997-2012. All rights reserved. Developed by Geekboys . querbau | Webdesign und Corporate Design aus Hamburg Robert Lacroix casualizer - Neue Leute Treffen Hamburg
	</body>
</document>
