<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001673" url="http://www.restaurantthing.com/ca/ab/edmonton/listing.php?ID=1953" time="2012-07-12-17:26" support="2" score="0.004173684450483854" bingtitle="Edmonton restaurant listings and reviews - Your premier source for ..." webtitle="Edmonton restaurant listings and reviews">
			<query id="000658" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000942" bing-rank="124"/>
	<description>It&apos;s good quality food for a reasonable ... are VERY cool and are attentive to my food ... For once, a healthy fast-food restaurant. Unlike most sub places, you can ...</description>
	<body>
		Badass Jack&apos;s Subs and Wraps         

 
 Home Login VIP Area View Restaurants
 List By Type View All Entries Restaurant Map Search 
 Search Contribute
 Add Restaurant Add Review 
 What&apos;s New About
 About RestaurantThing Contact Us 
 
 Page Viewed: 4752 times Top CA AB Edmonton View All Entries Badass Jack&apos;s Subs and Wraps 
 General Map 
   
Badass Jack&apos;s Subs and Wraps
 Neighborhood: Old Strathcona Price Range: Inexpensive 5.8 Based on 27 reviews


 
8621 109 Street
Edmonton


 Tel: 780-438-4083

 Categories: 
 Deli 


 

 


 
        
 

Reviews

 
 User Review Rating Bond (10000007) 
 2008-Nov-24 
 14:40:33 


 Contribution Status: 
 Regular
 (33.00) 

 Run of the mill I would stick with Oodle Noodle if I were to choose lunch in a box. Food is not made to order really, it&apos;s like - if you order butter chicken the mix is premade then&quot;nuked&quot;. Just not that good -- Bond (10000007) Won&apos;t 
Visit
Again Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating edmmom 
 2008-Oct-08 
 15:35:29 


 Contribution Status: 
 Frequent
 (20.20) 

 Skip it and your stomach will thank you later. Tried the St. Albert location thinking it would be a healthy lunch, and it was just awful food. The wraps were not good. There&apos;s nothing much to say other than that peas in a wrap taste awful, the sauce was awful, the meat was bland, and I was sorry I ate here.

Yeah, won&apos;t be doing that again. I&apos;d pick Pita Pit over this place. -- edmmom Won&apos;t 
Visit
Again Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating harvey123 
 2008-Jul-26 
 20:45:13 


 Contribution Status: 
 Occasional
 (8.10) 

 Visited on 2008-Jun-19 Wraps good,&quot;food bowls&quot;lousy I used to live near the 109th Street location (across the street from the Garneau Theatre). I would always go to Badass Jack&apos;s for a healthier alternative to McDonald&apos;s or KFC just a few blocks south.

The wraps were consistently good. You can choose different&quot;shells&quot;like spinach or cheese (and more flavors) and have noodles or rice in your wrap. The choice of sauces was quite extensive. They charge you extra if you want cheese in your wrap. I always liked the spinach shell wraps on noodles with chicken (in thai or teriyaki sauce).

The&quot;food bowls&quot;were pretty lousy. The&quot;Wok Box&quot;has something similar... and it is a money grab. A few shards of meat with sauce on white rice... You can do better than that!

Decent wraps... a healthy alternative to a hamburger. Don&apos;t waste your time on the&quot;food bowls&quot;. -- harvey123 Will 
Visit
Again Show this persons past visits... (2) Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating Curtis 
 2008-Jan-23 
 19:08:34 


 Contribution Status: 
 Frequent
 (23.00) 

 Above Average Bad ass jacks is always a good meal if you want a nice full wrap as opposed to about 80% of the wraps you get other places, while it doesnt have the best facilities to go in and relax for awhile it is a good spot to stop on the way home and grab a good meal. -- Curtis Will 
Visit
Again Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating SpaghettiSlinger 
 2008-Jan-05 
 16:43:32 


 Contribution Status: 
 Novice
 (2.00) 

 Visited on 2007-Jul-17 A healthy alternative to fast food... I came here a while ago, looking for a respite from A&amp;W, McDonald&apos;s, what have you. The portions were large, the service was decent, and the food was very flavorful and fresh. There were plenty of options, and more than enough sauce choices for their wraps.
I would recommend this place. It&apos;s good quality food for a reasonable price. -- SpaghettiSlinger Will 
Visit
Again Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating Visitor (visitor1) 
 2006-Apr-24 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Frequent
 (22.00) 

 A smelly experience. Stinky smell...just awful. -- Visitor (visitor1) Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating anonymous user
 2005-Jan-05 
 22:00:00 


 It&apos;s a horrible place. The staff at the 109 st. University area location are kind of weird and not friendly at all...the have some attitude problems. That girl with the razor cuts all over her arm made my wrap too and it was very unappetizing. The food tasted really gross as well. Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating S Webber 
 2004-Nov-11 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Novice
 (3.00) 

 Why does this place only have a 3 star rating? What&apos;s wrong with these folks? This place is amazing - the food is fresh, made right in front of you, the meats have no fillers, the food is relatively cheap, there&apos;s plenty of selection from the food to the sauces to the sandwich fillings, the service is great and friendly, and best of all THE FOOD ITSELF IS AMAZING! As for the reviewer who said gross...I would hardly pay attention to a one word review that doesn&apos;t even identify what exactly the problem was. Gross? The food? The atmosphere? BE MORE SPECIFIC. This place easily deserves 4 or 5 stars. -- S Webber Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating Strider 
 2004-Jul-08 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Novice
 (3.00) 

 A couple of days ago, at the University/Garneau location (109 St and 87 Ave), there was a girl working the till with razor cuts all over her arm...at least one of them was still open! Health violations notwithstanding, that&apos;s an appetite killer. -- Strider No Rating Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating anonymous user
 2002-Apr-21 
 22:00:00 


 Excellent alternative to fast food, with good vegetarian options. Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating Elaine (elaine1) 
 2001-Nov-29 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Newbie
 (1.00) 

 The staff at Bad Ass&apos; are VERY cool and are attentive to my food allergies. I like that the meats are not processed, but that also means you get a little grisstle in the chicken every once in a while. The only bad experience I had at this restaurant was the time I had a Jerk sauce Chicken wrap - and the cook put a WHOLE laddle of jerk sauce in - both my friend and I who are Hot Sauce freaks nearly died because the wrap was too spicy! I&apos;ve ordered large take-outs from the 109St location and they were on time, and labled all the wraps like I had asked. Thank you! -- Elaine (elaine1) No Rating Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating George (george1) 
 2001-Feb-10 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Occasional
 (6.00) 

 For once, a healthy fast-food restaurant. Unlike most sub places, you can actually IDENTIFY all of the meat. The roast beef is carved off of a roast right in front of you. So is the ham. The chicken, well, looks like chicken. This can&apos;t be said of Subway, where you get assorted&quot;meat&quot;that&apos;s pre-wrapped in wax paper and has been sitting in a fridge for days. The food is excellent, and I&apos;m now a regular. If you&apos;re on the go, try their rice bowls (they&apos;re a lot easier to eat without having stuff fall out). :-) -- George (george1) No Rating Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating Ryshtyan 
 2000-Dec-04 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Frequent
 (22.00) 

 For those who have a problem with this place, you are considered a minority. Almost every person I&apos;ve encountered in the province of Alberta has commented how impressed they are with B.A.J. and have become loyal repeat customers as a result. GROSS? Compared to who, McDonald&apos;s? Everything is prepared in front of you so you get to choose exactly what you want in your meal. I prefer the wraps over the subs, but that&apos;s just my personal preference. I work in a hotel environment and have recommended these guys. For those who actually went there agreed that it was a fantastic place to go for a healthier alternative to typical fast food. -- Ryshtyan No Rating Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating Jason Ewasiuk 
 2000-Nov-07 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Novice
 (4.00) 

 For a fast food type of place, I found it much better quality than a comparable Mr. Sub or Subway. Reminds me of a excellent deli I went to in the USA, where you could mix and match everything there too. -- Jason Ewasiuk No Rating Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating Rod Day (rodday) 
 2000-Jul-19 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Novice
 (3.00) 

 G R O S S ! -- Rod Day (rodday) No Rating Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating Dugg S 
 2000-Jun-10 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Newbie
 (1.00) 

 Ok food, wraps are big enuf to justify the price, but certainly deserving of a 4 star rating.. -- Dugg S No Rating Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating Nancy Voort 
 2000-May-31 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Newbie
 (1.00) 

 This is not about your food its about your advertisment in Medicine Hat (on the billboard), you got some nasty publicity and all I have to say is WELL DONE - GOOD MARKETING and you did EXACTLY what you set out to do...... I did not find it offensive but I did comment on how it caught my attention - Could not have done it better myself!!!! -- Nancy Voort No Rating Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating Jimmy 
 2000-May-28 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Newbie
 (1.00) 

 I don&apos;t see the big deal about this place. I find the food rather bland, even with spicy sauces, and the bread of the sub I tried before switching to the wraps was terribly dry, despite the fact that the filling was moist. I was really not impressed. Subway is a better deal pricewise, and the quality is at least the same if not better. -- Jimmy No Rating Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating Marc (marc) 
 1999-Dec-15 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Occasional
 (7.00) 

 The best place to go for a fast-food lunch. -- Marc (marc) No Rating Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating Nolan Walker 
 1999-Jul-04 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Newbie
 (1.00) 

 Healthy alterative from greasy fast food. -- Nolan Walker No Rating Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating Kent Danyluk 
 1999-Jun-01 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Newbie
 (1.00) 

 If you are looking for a tasty and healthy change from the usual burger, Badass Jacks is worth checking out. The wraps they have are healthly,and very tasty since you have it made the way you want. And the size of the wrap makes for a filling lunch. The quality and speed of service complements the excellent food. -- Kent Danyluk No Rating Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating Peter Didow 
 1999-May-24 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Newbie
 (1.00) 

 BadAss Jack&apos;s kicks. I found the service to be fast and friendly, and this is probably the tastiest health-wiser alternative to the usual fast food. try it...everyone at my workplace is hooked! -- Peter Didow No Rating Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating Claudio Cividino 
 1999-May-11 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Newbie
 (1.00) 

 There is no better place in the city to buy a sub or wrap. No processed meat here folks just freshly cooked that day. All vegetables are also fresh and the bread is made on site. The food is not only fast it&apos;s also healthy and VERY Delicious! -- Claudio Cividino No Rating Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating Jody Halyk 
 1999-Feb-19 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Newbie
 (1.00) 

 Add your review her. -- Jody Halyk No Rating Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating Mark Volk 
 1999-Feb-19 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Occasional
 (5.00) 

 A nice change from a traditional submarine sandwich restaurant. Not the cheapest subs and wraps, but worth a try. Staff are usually friendly. -- Mark Volk No Rating Comments (0) ...         


 User Review Rating Gary Anderson (garyanderson) 
 1999-Jan-23 
 22:00:00 


 Contribution Status: 
 Novice
 (3.00) 

 I have just added Badass Jack&apos;s to the site to garner feedback on how we are performing for you. We will be monitoring the site to see what we are doing right and to find the areas where we can improve. Thanks. Gary Anderson Ps feel free to call us direct through one of the stores -- Gary Anderson (garyanderson) No Rating Comments (0) ...         

 


 
        
       
Please be sure to notify the restaurant owner that you 
 found them here on the Internet using restaurantthing.com

restaurantthing.com is not responsible for the accuracy of 
 information supplied by users of this site. By using this web 
 site, you agree to our terms and conditions of use. 
 restaurantthing.com is committed to your privacy .

There are 47 people viewing the site right now.
	</body>
</document>
