<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001319" url="http://www2.timesdispatch.com/news/2011/jan/06/teen-convicted-rockwood-park-shooting-ar-757331/" time="2012-07-12-16:49" support="1" score="0.0004221357480017713" bingtitle="Teen convicted in Rockwood Park shooting | Richmond Times-Dispatch" webtitle="Teen convicted in Rockwood Park shooting | Richmond Times-Dispatch">
			<query id="000717" bing-rank="113"/>
	<description>... scene from the video game Grand Theft Auto. Vance fled the park with a friend and was dropped off at fast-food restaurant on ... Bill&apos;s Back Porch: 104 birthdays... ...</description>
	<body>
		TimesDispatch.com: Welcome Guest | | Register | Contact Us Richmond Times-Dispatch: Place a Classified | Subscribe | Manage Subscription | Advertise With Us 
 News 
 Columnists&amp;Blogs Crime Local News Virginia News Virginia Politics Education Traffic&amp;Transportation National&amp;World News Data Center 
 Business 
 Columnists&amp;Blogs Metro Business Moneywise Economy 
 Opinion 
 Editorials Letters Commentary Op Ed 
 Sports 
 Columnists&amp;Blogs HSXtra College Sports Flying Squirrels Kickers Pro Sports Auto Racing Outdoors Community Sports 
 Entertainment/Life 
 Columnists&amp;Blogs Contests&amp;Promotions Food&amp;Dining Music, Movies&amp;TV Arts&amp;Literature Home&amp;Garden Health Events Calendar Submit an event Weddings&amp;Celebrations Faith&amp;Values Travel Games and Puzzles Specialty Publications 
 Weather Obituaries 
 News Obituaries 
 Video 
 News Sports Entertainment/Life Business Your Video Submit Video 
 Services 
 Advertise With Us Archives Buy Photos Contact Us Email Alerts&amp;Newsletters Manage Subscription Mobile Alerts Press Pass Public Notices RSS RTD on Mobile Subscriber Services TD-Digital User Submitted Photos 
 Cars 
 find a car virtual marketplace Sell Your Car Top Autos 
 Shopping/Deals 
 Business Directory Buy Photos Times-Dispatch Shop virtual marketplace Grocery Coupons 
 Real Estate 
 New Homes apts&amp;Rentals homes for sale commercial property farms&amp;land virtual marketplace mortgage center top homes top rentals Top open houses Sell Your Home 
 Jobs 
 find a job Top Jobs Employers 
 Classifieds 
 homes Sell Your Cool Cheap Stuff cars Merchandise pets Place An Ad Public Notices Top Stuff 
 
 You forgot to enter your search term. Web Search powered by YAHOO! Richmond.com | Mechanicsville Local | Midlothian Exchange | Powhatan Today | Goochland Gazette | PolitiFact Virginia |   News News RSS Text Size Print  Share This Home / news / local / 
Teen convicted in Rockwood Park shooting
 
Credit: CHESTERFIELD COUNTY POLICE
 
Matthew D. Vance could be sentenced to up to 28 years in prison for three offenses.
 
 By: Mark Bowes | Richmond Times-Dispatch 
 Published: January 06, 2011 Updated: January 06, 2011 - 1:34 PM »  Comments | Post a Comment 
A Chesterfield County teen was convicted today of maliciously wounding another teen after firing indiscriminately into a crowd in a shooting that sparked concern about crime at one of the county&apos;s oldest and most popular parks.

 Matthew D. Vance , 18, pleaded no contest to malicious wounding, discharging a firearm in a public place with injury and felonious use of a firearm in a July 20 incident at Rockwood Park that left 17-year-old Terrell Bailey with a gunshot wound to the stomach.

Circuit Judge Frederick G. Rockwell III accepted Vance’s pleas and set sentencing for April 7. He could be sentenced up to 28 years in prison for all three offenses.

The shooting was sparked by an altercation on Rockwood’s basketball courts that quickly escalated after Vance left but then returned with a .38-caliber revolver that he had acquired just a week earlier.

According to a summary of evidence by prosecutor Laura S. Khawaja , the incident began as Vance was playing basketball with others about 6:30 p.m. During a game, Vance accused another participant of playing too rough and punched that person in the back of the head.

 Vance left in a car but returned a short time later with two friends after retrieving a gun from a home where he was staying. Meanwhile, the player that Vance had punched earlier called some of his friends, although he told Vance that everything was OK between them.

But the friends approached Vance as he was sitting on a park bench, and at one point Vance stood up, pulled a gun from his waistband and fired a single shot into the air that scattered the crowd. Vance then leveled the weapon and fired two more shots as the crowd dispersed.

One shot struck Bailey , a bystander not involved in the altercation, in his lower right abdomen.

An acquaintance of Vance later described the shooting to police as being similar to a scene from the video game Grand Theft Auto.

 Vance fled the park with a friend and was dropped off at fast- food restaurant on Midlothian Turnpike . About 1:30 the next morning, Vance was arrested during a traffic stop after police identified him as a suspect.

Defense attorneys Mark Englisby and Randy Carl suggested that Vance acted in self defense after he was surrounded by as many as eight people and was punched and kicked two or three times. However, Khawaja said the evidence is in dispute about whether Vance was attacked or approached aggressively.

 Vance also claimed that he saw another person at the park with a gun -–an assertion that couldn’t be corroborated by police.

The 17-year-old victim, who attended today’s hearing with his father, was hospitalized four days after the shooting and required another two weeks to physically recover.

“He was very, very lucky,” Khawaja said.

 Rockwell postponed Vance’s sentencing after the teen’s attorneys briefly described some physical and sexual abuse he suffered as a child and placement in foster homes. At the time of the shooting, Vance had been living with a friend on Newbys Bridge Road after leaving a group home on July 1.

Until his arrest for the shooting, Vance had no criminal record. He now faces additional charges of breaking and entering and grand larceny for an unrelated offense.

“I need a picture of who this young man is,” the judge said.


 Terms and Conditions 
Share This:
  Email  Facebook  Google  Twitter  Favorites  More 
Advertisement
   View More : Chesterfield County , Food , Frederick G. Rockwell Iii , Judge , Laura S. Khawaja , Law_Crime , Mark Englisby , Matthew D. Vance , Midlothian Turnpike , Player , Prosecutor , Randy Carl , Terrell Bailey Not what you&apos;re looking for? Try our quick search:   
More from this channel:

 Sullivan makes first remarks to faculty and staff since reinstatement Midlothian man to be sentenced today for $6 million fraud Virginia business briefs for July 12 11 years after drag race death, man pleads guilty Former Chesterfield bus driver avoids prison sentence for having sex with student 
 
 

 Henrico police shoot pet as they notify family of son&apos;s homicide Hopewell man&apos;s death ruled a drowning Volunteers from Greater Richmond ARC help at Lewis Ginter Rejected Richmond candidates want an appeal process Bill Lohmann: Hanover farmers trying to recover crops after storms 
   
Advertisement
 
Reader Comments
 *Facebook Account Required to Comment. If you are not already logged into Facebook, please click the comment button to do so. 
Deal of the Day
 
Advertisement
 
 VCU Rams&apos;Gear 
 
Get all your Rams&apos; gear right here.
 
Advertisement
 
 Daily Email Newsletter 
 
Get the morning&apos;s top headlines delivered directly to your inbox every morning. Sign up now! 
   
 Top Videos 
 
 
 2:42 Mike&apos;s Take: Friction between... ( ) 0 0:44 Cheerleading coach found guilty... ( ) 0 0:56 Marco Rubio in Chesterfield ( ) 0 
 
 2:41 Bill&apos;s Back Porch: Thanking a tough... ( ) 0 1:27 In memory of Miss Ruby Turner... ( ) 0 0:44 VIDEO: Bottle Rocket Challenge at... ( ) 0 
 
 2:54 Culinary Clues: Pesto ( ) 0 29:42 Airwaves of Yesteryear ( ) 0 0:45 Lining Up For Obama ( ) 0 
 
   
Most Popular
 
 1. UPDATE: Henrico police shot dead man&apos;s pit bull, family says 2. UPDATE: Chesterfield police release photos of Wendy&apos;s robbery suspects 3. UPDATE: Obama to visit Glen Allen on Saturday 4. 70-year-old woman described 2 killings, detective testifies 5. Death of inmate at Richmond Jail scrutinized 
 
Purchase RTD Photos
 Sailor Bob - then and now   
 User Submitted Photos »More of your photos 
 
 
 Virginia State Champions - Varina... 5 Lightning from recent storms 5 Damage From Storm West End 0 
 
 Rafting on the James 5 Monster Squash 0 Blue Morpho Up Close 0 
 
 Teasing 0 Last Out 0 Indians State Title 0 
 
 
Advertisement
 Richmond Times-Dispatch   ©2012 World Media Enterprises Inc Terms and Conditions Web Links: Advertise With Us | Contact Us | Email Alerts | Find Richmond Jobs | Mobile Alerts | RSS Feeds | Search | Times-Dispatch Shop | Public Notices 
 Newspaper Links: Subscribe to the Newspaper | TD-Digital | Kindle Edition | Place a Classified | Submit News Tips | Contact Us | Photo Reprints 
 Main Media Partners: Richmond.com | Goochland Gazette | Mechanicsville Local | Midlothian Exchange | Powhatan Today | PolitiFact Virginia
	</body>
</document>
