<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001021" url="http://www.newsobserver.com/2010/03/27/409181/school-out-two-teens-hit-by-car.html" time="2012-07-12-16:25" support="2" score="0.0014706005282858349" bingtitle="School out, two teens hit by car - Local/State - NewsObserver.com" webtitle="School out, two teens hit by car - 

 
        Local/State
 - NewsObserver.com">
			<query id="001053" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000990" bing-rank="151"/>
	<description>A Durant Middle School student hit by a car ... The fast food restaurant is a popular hangout for teens whose ... Make a Payment; e-edition; Kindle; Subscriber Services</description>
	<body>
		[an error occurred while processing this directive] Local/State 
 N&amp;O ZONE | Home Delivery  
 Subscribe Vacation Stop Delivery Problem Make a Payment e-edition Kindle Subscriber Services 
 | Stay Connected  
 Contact Us Report Problem iPhone iPad Android Tablet e-edition Mobile Kindle Nook Kobo Facebook Twitter Email and Text Alerts Email Updates RSS Print Archives Newspapers in Education My Accounts 
 | 75°F 
 
 
 Search stories on N&amp;O.com Web Search Search N&amp;O print archives 
 
 Web Search powered by YAHOO! SEARCH 
 Home News 
 Sections 
 Weather Local/State Nation/World Crime/Safety Education Religion Health/Science Science/Technology Traffic Weird Thumbs Up 


 Counties 
 Wake Durham Orange Johnston Chatham 

 
 Columnists 
 Drescher Road Worrier Saunders Shaffer Wheeler 


 Multimedia 
 Photo Galleries Videos 

 
 Blogs 
 Wake Ed Durham: Bulls Eye Orange Chat Eastern Wake Buzz Crosstown Traffic The Raleigh Report Investigations The Green Scene The Editors Blog Turning the Scales Fact Check 

 Sports 
 Sections 
 Canes NHL High Schools Panthers NFL NBA Outdoors Baseball Racing Soccer Golf Tennis Cycling 

 
 Blogs 
 ACC Now Canes Now Duke Now Preps Now State Now UNC Now Raleigh Prep Zone SWake Sports Best Blog 


 Colleges 
 N.C. State North Carolina Duke East Carolina Wake Forest N.C. Central 

 
 COLUMNISTS 
 DeCock Tudor Fowler Giglio Sorensen Simpson Stevens 


 Multimedia 
 Photo Galleries Videos 

 Business 
 Sections 
 Stocks Center Consumer/Retail Economy Local/State Real Estate Technology 


 Columnists 
 Real Deals Lacy Nicholson Stump the Geeks Gilster 

 
 BLOGS 
 .Biz Centsible Saver Tech Junkie 


 Multimedia 
 Photo Galleries Videos 

 Politics 
 Sections 
 Local State National Elections 


 COLUMNISTS 
 Christensen 

 
 Blogs 
 Under the Dome Fact Check 


 MULTIMEDIA 
 Photo Galleries 

 Life 
 Sections 
 Fitness Food Home/Garden Family Style Travel Celebrations Horoscope 


 COLUMNISTS 
 A.C. Snow 

 
 BLOGS 
 Mouthful Happiness is a Warm TV Past Times The Green Scene Turning the Scales 


 MULTIMEDIA 
 Photo Galleries Videos 

 Entertainment 
 SECTIONS 
 Arts Books Dining Music People TV/Movies 


 BLOGS 
 On The Beat Happiness is a Warm TV Tech Junkie 

 
 MULTIMEDIA 
 Photo Galleries Videos 

 Opinion 
 SECTIONS 
 Editorials Other Views Letters to the Editor 


 BLOGS 
 The Opinion Shop Blog 

 
 COLUMNISTS 
 Ford Jenkins Martinez 

 Obits 
 SECTIONS 
 Today&apos;s Notices Browse by City Life Stories 

 Find n Save 
 SECTIONS 
 Today&apos;s Deal Coupons Newspaper Ads Special Sections Store Circulars Business Directory N&amp;O;Photos N&amp;O;Store 

 Classifieds 
 SECTIONS 
 All ads Jobs Cars Real Estate Rentals Legal Notices Yard/Garage Sales Dogs and Pets Place a classified ad 

 Jobs 
 SECTIONS 
 Search by City Top Jobs in the Triangle Video Jobs Advanced Search Post a Job 

 Real estate 
 SECTIONS 
 Homes for Sale Featured Homes Commercial Real Estate Apartments and Other Rentals Your Guide to the Triangle 

 Cars 
 SECTIONS 
 New/Used Car Search Hot Deals Buying Guides Research Advanced Search Sell Your Car 

 Place ad 
 SECTIONS 
 N&amp;O Advertising Network Classified Ad Announcments Obituary Notice Online Advertising In-print Advertising 

 
 
 Top photos: Air show | Comic-Con | Day&apos;s Best | Running of the Bulls | &apos;Batman&apos; stars | Classic sailboats | Great concerts 
 Published Sat, Mar 27, 2010 02:00 AM 
 Modified Sat, Mar 27, 2010 12:07 PM 
School out, two teens hit by car
 
 Article 0 COMMENTS 
 Email Print Order Reprint Share This Share Text 
tool name
 close x tool goes here BY THOMASI MCDONALD - Staff Writer BY THOMASI MCDONALD 
RALEIGH -- A Durant Middle School student hit by a car Friday afternoon was upgraded to good condition, hospital officials said today.

Krista Carcaterra, 13, had been in serious condition Friday night after the car accident that killed another student, Lindsey Fesmire, 14, an eighth-grader at the middle school.

The two girls were struck by a vehicle driven by Ronald Blackwell, 44, of Wilson. Based on the information collected by investigators Friday, said Raleigh police spokesman Jim Sughrue said they do not expect to bring charges against Blackwell.
 
A somber mood permeated the Bojangles&apos; on Durant Road after the accident. The fast food restaurant is a popular hangout for teens whose school is a three- to four-minute walk away.

The final bell at Durant Middle School rings each weekday at 2:37 p.m.

&quot;People come here every day from school,&quot; said Richie Bryant, 14, a seventh-grader at the school.

Bryant said he caught a ride with a friend to the restaurant after school and wondered why there was a traffic jam that slowed the short car ride to the restaurant.

Students who walk up the sidewalk to the restaurant must cross five lanes of traffic on the busy thoroughfare without the benefit of a traffic light.

Kim Cooper, who works nearby, said her daughter was friends with Fesmire and Carcaterra. She said she had often seen students crossing Durant to the restaurant on the other side.

Police say the girls were crossing the street after leaving Bojangles&apos; and were struck by Blackwell&apos;s vehicle just before they got to the other side, near the entrance of the Anson Grove subdivision.
 thomasi.mcdonald@newsobserver.com or 919-829-4533 
 Get the biggest news in your email or cellphone as it&apos;s happening. Sign up for breaking news alerts. 
 Email Print Order Reprint Share This Share Text 
tool name
 close x tool goes here We welcome your comments on this story, but please be civil. Do not use profanity, hate speech, threats, personal abuse, images, internet links or any device to draw undue attention. Read our full comment policy. 
More 

 
 Local/State 
 
 
 One person wounded in Raleigh shooting 
Police responded to a call shortly before 11:30 p.m. at 3104-D Calumet Drive and found one person with a gunshot wound in the torso. 
 UNC downplayed tutor&apos;s actions to NCAA 
 Newly released records say the player asked for help and that the tutor said sheexpandedthe paper. UNC, however, said it wasnt clear what changes were made. 
 Duke CEO Jim Rogers tries to calm Progress employees 
 In a 2 1/2-hour meeting in downtown Raleigh, Rogers urges employees to give him a chance to regain their trust. Meanwhile, a Wall Street analyst expects the fallout from Johnson’s firing will cost the company dearly. 
 New year brings longer rides for Wake students 
 Wake County students are dealing with longer bus rides this year in the new school year because of a transportation plan that cuts costs by putting fewer buses on the road to serve more riders. 
 N.C. soldier among six killed in weekend Afghan bombing 
Six U.S. soldiers killed in a weekend enemy bombing in Afghanistan have now been identified as Fort Bliss troops. 
 Reps. Ross and Weiss accuse GOP of &apos;war on women&apos; 
 Two legislators visiting a clinic in Durham say GOP cuts to health care for low-income female patients are part of a national attack on women. 
 Last week&apos;s heat sent more than 350 Tar Heels to the emergency room 
Emergency responders received 365 calls due to heat from June 29 to July 7, according to a report from the states Division of Public Health. 
 McCrory calls for more tax cuts and less regulation 
 OP gubernatorial candidate Pat McCrory on Wednesday outlined a series of proposals including tax cuts, more aggressive energy exploration, and a more business-friendly regulatory environment to help jump-start North Carolinas economy. 
 Duke lands big federal grant for HIV/AIDS research 
The university has been awarded a seven-year federal grant worth up to $139 million to fund research aimed at creating effective HIV vaccines. 
 Garner man charged with selling marijuana, fake crack cocaine 
 Police accused Michael Griffis of crushing up Tic Tacs and then trying to sell the breath mints as crack cocaine. 
 
Get local news updates

Keep up with the latest stories with our free local news e-mail newsletters, delivered straight to your inbox!

 Subscribe to Afternoon Update - it&apos;s free!

 Subscribe to Breaking News - it&apos;s free!

 Subscribe to Local&amp;State News - it&apos;s free!

 Subscribe to Today at a Glance - it&apos;s free!

 Subscribe to Crime&amp;Safety - it&apos;s free!

 Subscribe to Education - it&apos;s free!

 Subscribe to Health&amp;Science - it&apos;s free!
 
 Hot Deals View All 
 

 Find a Car Make Model Zip Go 
 Top Jobs View All
	</body>
</document>
