<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001523" url="http://sharifbd.free.fr/tour/tour.html" time="2012-07-12-17:17" support="1" score="0.00026945003767650153" bingtitle="Tourism in Bangladesh - Freebox, la meilleure offre ADSL ..." webtitle="Tourism in Bangladesh">
			<query id="001363" bing-rank="224"/>
	<description>... in order to ... 100 seating). Mary Anderson Floating Restaurant, Paglaghat (First Class Restaurant and Bar–80 seating). Waterfront Restaurant (Fast Food Restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Tourism in Bangladesh
 Bangladesh is a fascinating country for those visitors who 
are keen to know the unknown and unspoiled natural beauty and resources. These natural
 phenomena are composed of hills and vales, forests, rivers, sea-beaches, lakes and the
 evergreen landscape embracing the country.
 
Main Tourist Attractions
The topography is mainly flat alluvial plain, 
crisscrossed by the world&apos;s three mighty river systems viz. padma (Ganges), 
Jamuna and Meghna and their innumerable tributaries. The west, north and most 
of east are bounded by India and south-eastern part by Myanmar. The north eastern
 part comprises Chittagong and the three hilly districts with an average alleviation 
 of 2000 feet from the sea level. In the south and south-west, along side the coast
 of the Bay of Bengal, lies the Sundarbans the largest mangrove forest in the 
 world which is the home of Royal Bengal Tiger.
 The country has a sea-beach of unique character at Cox&apos;s Bazar. The 120 km. lay 
beach is straight, smooth and sandy, going deep into the sea with forested high 
hills by the side.
 The Sundarbans, the largest mangrove forest in the world, is the abode of 
Royal Bengal Tigers, crocodiles and deer. The whole area is crisscrossed by rivers
 and rivulets, and a journey by boat through that area is simply fascinating.
 Other attractions are 
the tribal people of the Hilly Districts in the South-east and hilly areas of 
Mymensingh in the north with their distinctive way of life, with an ancient cultural
 heritage and colourful tribal folklore. The zigzag hill sloppy tea gardens in 
 Sylhet regions are yet another attraction for tourists. The archaeological 
 remains of the 3rd century AD at Mainamati, Paharpur and Mahasthangar and other 
 areas or Rajshahi are the testimonials of an ancient rich cultural heritage.
 Apart from these, Bangladesh has also the largest manmade lake in the sub-continent,
 which is in Rangamati District and surrounded by forested high hills presenting
 an unprecedented natural beauty.
 Back to top 

Tourism Development in Bangladesh
 Tourism in Bangladesh is still dominated by the state owned programme. 
In a developing economy where an over-whelming majority of the people have marginal 
standard of living and a society that is much influenced by its economic conditions;
 steps taken by the government for the development of tourism so far had been largely
 to promote tourism by creating facilities for the tourists.
 But large-scale investment, particularly in the private sector, that is necessary
 in order to achieve economic gains, has not been forthcoming significantly despite
 some incentives allowed by the government. There is vast scope for future prospects
 and possibilities for development of tourism in Bangladesh. If product development,
 marketing and promotion of tourism can be achieved, more and more tourists would be
 attracted to visit Bangladesh.
 Various tourism facilities have so far been developed in many of the tourism potential
 areas by Bangladesh Parjatan (Tourism) Corporation, other government, semi-government
 and non-government agencies. Apart from this, the Government of Bangladesh has 
 formulated the National Tourism Policy in February 1992. The main objective of this policy is to attract investment in tourism sector from
 the domestic private investors as well as from the foreign investors.
 It is hoped that this step would encourage both local and foreign investments in
 tourism sector in Bangladesh. It could be either in the form of joint venture 
 or on 100% foreign ownership basis. The government has declared a number of incentives
 like tax exemption on foreign loans, capital gains and royalty, avoidance of double 
 taxation, remittance of 50% of salaries of foreign employees repatriation of capital etc.
 Back to top 
Existing Tourism Facilities
The Corporation has the following facilities in Dhaka and other places of the country :
 Dhaka : 
Hotel Abakash (First Class Hotel, 40 A/C suites/rooms80 beds, Restaurant 100 seating,
 Banquet Hall 125 seating, 200 buffet, Conference Room35 seating, Pastry Shop; 
 Suites and A/C Rooms with Colour TV with satellite, hot and cold running water) 
 Golfers&apos; Inn (Deluxe Restaurant250 seating and Bar). Joy Restaurant, Savar 
 (First Class Restaurant100 seating). Mary Anderson Floating Restaurant, Paglaghat 
 (First Class Restaurant and Bar80 seating). Waterfront Restaurant (Fast Food
 Restaurant30 seating, snacks and boat facilities). 
Rent-A-Car Service (a fleet of comfortable and luxury A/C and non-A/C Cars, 
Microbuses and Coasters), Sightseeing tours and River Cruises, Picnic spots and
 Chandra and Shalna, Dutyfree Shop at Dhaka International Airport, Osmany International
 Airport, Sylhet; Diplomats and Privileged Persons Tax-free Shop.
 Cox&apos;s Bazar : 
Hotel Shaibal (Deluxe Hotel, 24 A/C suites/rooms48 beds, Sagarika Restaurant130 seating,
 Swimming pool, Sunbathing deck, Tennis, Health Club, Colour TV with satellite, hot 
 and cold running water, Squash, Conference Hall 100 seating, video games, Indoor
 games, Gift shop). Motel Upal (Standard, 38 A/C and non A/C rooms74 beds, hot 
 and cold running water, Bangladesh Biman Office, Gift Shop), Motel Probal 
 (Moderate 36 non A/C twin rooms, Panahar Restaurant 50 seating), Motel Labonee
 (Economy 60 non A/C twin rooms, Conference Hall), Honeymoon Cottage 
 (1st Classt A/C, Non-AC twin room, small cottage, 5 Nos. lounge, a pantry).
 Chittagong : 
Motel Shaikat (Standard 2 A/C suites, 26 A/C and non A/C twin rooms, Restaurant60 seating).
 Rangpur : 
Parjatan Motel (Standard 2 A/C suite, 32 A/C and non A.C twin room, Restaurant 100 seating,
 Conference Hall 150 seating, Colour TV, hot and cold running water).
 Rangamati : 
Parjatan Motel (1st Class 18 A/C and non A/C twin room, Labiyat Restaurant 32 seating, 
Cottage, Picnic Spot, Lake Cruise by Engine boat, Hanging Bridge).
 Rajshahi : 
Parjatan Motel (Standard 38 A/C and non A/C room, Mahananda Restaurant 40 seating,
 Conference Hall 100 seating, Shopping Arcade).
 Bogra : Parjatan Motel (Standard 17 A/C and non A/C room, Karotoa Restaurant 60 seating).
 Dinajpur : Parjatan Motel (Standard 7 A/C and non A/C room).
 Kuakata : Parjatan Motel (Standard 10 A/C and non A/C room, Dormitory 30 bed).
 Sylhet : Parjatan Motel (Standard 26 A/C and non A/C room, Restaurant 60 seating).
 Madhabkunda : Picnic Sport, Rest room and toilet facility.
At present the tourism environment in Bangladesh is very good and congenial. 
Bangladesh parjatan Corporation has taken up plans to establish new facilities in
 areas like Banderban, Khagrachari, Benapole, Mongla and other areas of tourist interest. 
 Efforts are being made to provide cheaper accommodation and transport for the tourists, 
 domestic as well as foreign. It is hoped that in the new millennium, Bangladesh would
 be able to attract increasing number of tourists from abroad. At the same time, local 
 tourism is getting momentum.
 Back to top 
  Home | The Embassy | About Bangladesh | Consular Services | Investment | Trade&amp;Commerce 
 Tourism | Bangladesh-Italy Relations | Bangladesh in Multilateral Organisations at Rome 
 Useful Links | Archive | News | Contact us | Guestbook | Site Map | Disclaimer
	</body>
</document>
