<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001197" url="http://www.bizrate.com/baby-kids-furniture/babys-first-chair/" time="2012-07-12-16:38" support="3" score="0.0012410418543990652" bingtitle="Babys first chair in Baby &amp; Kids&apos; Furniture - Compare Prices, Read ..." webtitle="Babys first chair in BabyKids&apos; Furniture - Compare Prices, Read Reviews and Buy at Bizrate.">
			<query id="000766" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="001017" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="001269" bing-rank="76"/>
	<description>Super-sized tray with deep lip prevents spills ... Rapid growth in the past five years has put Trend Lab ... The First Years Carry Me Near 5 in 1 Sleep System is a ...</description>
	<body>
		follow us:

 
 
 
 Suggestions 

 
 shop by categories     
 Appliances Automotive Babies&amp;Kids Books&amp;Magazines Clothing&amp;Accessories 
 
 Computers&amp;Software DVDs&amp;Videos Digital Cameras Electronics Furniture 
 
 Gifts, Flowers&amp;Food Health&amp;Beauty Home&amp;Garden Jewelry&amp;Watches Laptop Computers 
 
 Music Musical Instruments Office Supplies Pet Supplies Sports Equipment 
 
 Toys&amp;Games Video Games Women&apos;s Shoes see all categories 
 
 Set Price Alert We&apos;ll send you an email when we find a lower price on: Today&apos;s Best Price:  Notify me when the price drops to: $   
Your email is safe - Privacy 
 Yes, I&apos;d like to be notified of other relevant products and savings. Home ›  Babies&amp;Kids 
›  Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture › babys first chair 
 
You&apos;re in Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture
 
See Matches in:

 High Chairs / Boosters Strollers / Joggers Baby Rattles&amp;Teethers Party Supplies 
 
Narrow Search Results
 
Price Range
 
 Under
$160 

 $160
-
$320 

 $320
-
$520 

 $520
-
$830 

 Over
$830 
 
 $ to $ Update&gt;&gt; 
 
By Brand

 Cosco Fun Furnishings GuideCraft Pottery Barn Pottery Barn Kids 
 
By Seller

 Buy.com ChildrensTablesandChairs.com eBay Hayneedle Homeclick Pottery Barn Kids Walmart.com Wayfair more... 
 
By Product Type

 Kids&apos; Chairs 
 
By Age Range

 2 - 4 Years Birth - 12 Months 

By Kid&apos;s Furniture Type

 Chairs Tables 

By Features

 Folding Rocking Round 

By Chair Type

 Standard Chairs 

By General Themes

 Car&amp;Truck Construction Nautical Outer Space 

By Color

 Blue Brown Green Pink Red White 

Additional Options

 Material Brand Kid&apos;s Furniture Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture Sitemap 
 
By Keyword

 
 
 Sort: Best Match Price Low-High Price High-Low Product Rating Show: Free Shipping Sales Tax&amp;Shipping: 
 
 
 Deluxe Victorian Rocking Chair -White 

 An heirloom This is the best rocking chair we have found in our travels. Super sturdy construction of Canadian maple and timeless detail... high back ornate spindals and smooth finish lends to a Victorian feel. A cherished baby gift to be l... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From MyBambino 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By My Bambino From MyBambino With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 MyBambino 
 
 $129.99 
 

 
 Ciao! Baby Portable Travel High Chair , Black 

 ciao! baby portable high chair, folding, portable, go-anywhere, light weight, flexible, no assembly required, comes with carrying bag, unfold, lock and ready to use, weighs ariund 8 pounds. Its for children up to 3 years old, great for camp... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Amazon.com 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail From Amazon.com With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 baby portable cribs kids cot portable travel bed 
 
 Amazon.com 
 (1,000+) 
 $74.31 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Baby High Chairs &amp;Booster Seats: Baby Stokke Trip Trap High Chair , Br - Walnut Tripp Trapp Baby Rai... 

 Stokke&apos;sTripp Trapp®high chair is practical and good looking. Adjustable seat heights allow this chair to grow with the child for years. Now, if only Stokkecould figure out how to get them to eat all of their vegetables. Crafted from B... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Land of Nod 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Stokke From Land of Nod With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 unique baby high chair baby high chair parts 
 
 
 
 $69.99 
 

 
 Baby Doll Bedding Heavenly Soft Child Rocking Chair Cushion Pad Set, Chocolate 

 Machine washable Polyester Made in USA 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Amazon.com 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail From Amazon.com With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 newborn baby doll rocker chair cushion set 
 
 Amazon.com 
 (1,000+) 
 $40.00 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Baby High Chairs &amp;Booster Seats: Baby Stokke Trip Trap High Chair , Re - Red Tripp Trapp Baby Rail 

 Stokke&apos;sTripp Trapp®high chair is practical and good looking. Adjustable seat heights allow this chair to grow with the child for years. Now, if only Stokkecould figure out how to get them to eat all of their vegetables. Crafted from B... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Land of Nod 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Stokke From Land of Nod With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 
 
 $69.99 
 

 
 Baby High Chairs &amp;Booster Seats: Baby Stokke Trip Trapp Trend Baby Rail, Gy - Grey Tripp Trapp Baby ... 

 Gy-Grey Tripp Trapp Baby Rail 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Land of Nod 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Stokke From Land of Nod With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 
 
 $69.99 
 

 
 Baby High Chairs &amp;Booster Seats: Baby Stokke Trip Trap High Chair , Na - Natural Tripp Trapp Baby Ra... 

 Stokke&apos;sTripp Trapp®high chair is practical and good looking. Adjustable seat heights allow this chair to grow with the child for years. Now, if only Stokkecould figure out how to get them to eat all of their vegetables. Crafted from B... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Land of Nod 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Stokke From Land of Nod With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 
 
 $69.99 
 

 
 3 Pc. Comfort Chairs and Table Set (Red) - Baby &amp;Preschool Furniture - Baby &amp;Preschool Furniture 

 Just my size! An attractive, bentwood seating group featuring two chairs and one table made of fine hardwood. Chairs feature attractive, removable cushions filled with thick 2inch foam, and rubber braces on the legs to prevent tipping. Back... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Sam&apos;s Club 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail From Sam&apos;s Club With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 kitchen table set preschool furniture 
 
 Sam&apos;s Club 
 
 $104.56 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Fun Furnishings My First Chair 

 My First Chair is the toddler-sized armchair your young child will love. Made entirely of high-density foam for the utmost in comfort and durability, this little chair comes with a handle on the cover so even the smallest young ones can arr... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From ChildrensTablesandChairs.com 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Fun Furnishings From ChildrensTablesandChairs.com With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 ChildrensTablesandChairs.... 
 
 $89.98 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Safety 1st - Nod-A-Way Bassinet, Fairlane 

 The Safety 1st Nod-A-Way Bassinet Fairlane provides several features to keep your baby happy and comfortable at all times. The baby bassinet with music can play five songs and five sounds. The infant bassinet has been created using the uniq... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Walmart.com 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail From Walmart.com With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 safety 1st nod way bassinet get a way chairs 
 
 Walmart.com 
 (25,000+) 
 $99.99 
 

 
 Baby High Chairs &amp;Booster Seats: Baby Stokke Trip Trapp Trend Baby Rail, Pi - Pink Tripp Trapp Baby ... 

 Pi-Pink Tripp Trapp Baby Rail 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Land of Nod 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Stokke From Land of Nod With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 
 
 $69.99 $49.95 
 

 
 Graco Avalon Glider&amp;Ottoman Combo - Espresso, 25.75L x 27W x 38.13H inches ( Chair ) 

 Rock baby to sleep in style. The Graco Avalon Glider&amp;Ottoman Combo - Espresso brings you the comfort you deserve in the look you want. Crafted from durable solid hardwoods to last, this glider/ottoman combo features comfy foam cushions su... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Hayneedle 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Avalon From Hayneedle With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 graco avalon blue glider ottoman 
 
 Hayneedle 
 
 $199.99 
 

 
 Kids Table and Chair Set: CoCaLo Monkey Mania Baby Tbl Chairs Set 

 Find kids table sets at Target.com! Cocalo monkey mania baby tbl chairs set 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Target.com 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Cocalo From Target.com With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 table chair set toddler table chair set 
 
 Target.com 
 (50,000+) 
 $139.99 
 

 
 Kids Table and Chair Set: CoCaLo Daniella Baby Table Chairs Set 

 Find kids table sets at Target.com! Cocalo daniella baby table chairs set 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Target.com 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Cocalo From Target.com With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Target.com 
 (50,000+) 
 $139.99 
 

 
 Kids Table and Chair Set: CoCaLo Nali Jungle Baby Table Chairs Set 

 Find kids table sets at Target.com! Cocalo nali jungle baby table chairs set 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Target.com 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Cocalo From Target.com With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Target.com 
 (50,000+) 
 $139.99 
 

 
 Kids Dining Chair : Levels of Discovery Rock-A-My- Baby Child&apos;s Chair 

 Find kids stools and hardback chairs at Target.com! Levels of discovery rock-a-my-baby child&apos;s chair 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Target.com 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Levels Of Discovery From Target.com With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Target.com 
 (50,000+) 
 $76.95 
 

 
 Kids Dining Chair : Levels of Discovery Rock-A-My- Baby Doll Chair 

 Find kids stools and hardback chairs at Target.com! Levels of discovery rock-a-my-baby doll chair 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Target.com 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Levels Of Discovery From Target.com With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Target.com 
 (50,000+) 
 $76.95 
 

 
 Kids Table and Chair Set: CoCaLo Jacana Baby Table Chairs Set 

 Find kids table sets at Target.com! Cocalo jacana baby table chairs set 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Target.com 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Cocalo From Target.com With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Target.com 
 (50,000+) 
 $139.99 
 

 
 Baby Appleseed Davenport 3 in 1 Convertible Crib - 

 When baby&apos;s on board, you need the three-in-one Baby Appleseed Davenport Convertible Crib - Espresso. Designed to first be a safe haven for infants during their baby months, this convertible crib transforms easily into a toddler bed when th... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Cribs.com 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Nursery Smart From Cribs.com With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 convertible crib nursery smart cribs 
 
 Cribs.com 
 
 $799.98 
 

 
 Baby Doll Bedding Heavenly Soft Child Rocking Chair Cushion Pad Set, Ivory 

 Machine washable Polyester Made in USA 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Amazon.com 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail From Amazon.com With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Amazon.com 
 (1,000+) 
 $33.11 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Pottery Barn Kids Navy My First Anywhere Chair 

 Kids Furniture: Free embroidered personalization! As welcoming as a cozy lap, our soft chair is perfect for little ones just learning to walk. 20&quot;square, 20&quot;high Slipcover is pure cotton. Insert is made with recycled foam containing up to... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Pottery Barn Kids 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Pottery Barn Kids From Pottery Barn Kids With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 pottery barn kids pottery barn kids furniture 
 
 Pottery Barn Kids 
 
 $79.00 
 

 
 Baby S Chair Set of 2 by Zuo Modern 

 Baby S Chair Set of 2 by Zuo Modern Light weight and durable. The Baby S childrens chair adds curves to any setting. Based on Zuo&apos;s S chair, The Baby S compliments all spaces in need of a glossy shine. Available in Green, Blue, Orange, Red,... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From MadisonSeating 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail From MadisonSeating With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 s chair 
 
 MadisonSeating 
 
 $149.99 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Safety 1st - Children&apos;s Pinch-free Chairs - Set of 4, Red 

 The Safety 1st Pinch-free Children&apos;s Chair Set is perfect for taking along for camping trips, picnics, sporting events and family gatherings. Sized just right for your toddler, these children s chairs have Cosco&apos;s pinch-free piston fold, so... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Walmart.com 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Cosco From Walmart.com With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Walmart.com 
 (25,000+) 
 $30.00 
 

 
 Parri Baby Chair Baby 

 Parri Baby Chair *This product is made to order and thus customer orders cannot be canceled or returned once the product goes into production. Marco Maran was born in Siena in 1963. His work with various companies has gained him considerabl... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From AllModern 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail From AllModern With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 baby chair attached table 
 
 AllModern 
 (500+) 
 $581.11 $491.00 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Pottery Barn Kids Red My First Anywhere Chair 

 Kids Furniture: Free embroidered personalization! As welcoming as a cozy lap, our soft chair is perfect for little ones just learning to walk. 20&quot;wide x 20&quot;deep x 20&quot;high Insert is made in the USA with recyclable foam containing up to 30... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Pottery Barn Kids 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Pottery Barn Kids From Pottery Barn Kids With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Pottery Barn Kids 
 
 $79.00 
 

 
 Fun Furnishings Personalized My First Chair , Blue, Small - Blue, Small 

 My First Chair is the toddler-sized armchair your young child will love. Made entirely of high-density foam for the utmost in comfort and durability, this little chair comes with a handle on the cover so even the smallest young ones can arr... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Hayneedle 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Fun Furnishings From Hayneedle With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Hayneedle 
 
 $101.00 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Gorham Little Boy Blue Babys First 5&quot;x 7&quot;Frame 

 Make the memories last with a Gorham frame.&quot;Baby&apos;s First&quot;graphics and a striped pattern adorn this frame for charming touches. Just add your favorite captured moment for the finishing touch. In blue/green/white. 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Kohl&apos;s 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail From Kohl&apos;s With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 

Related Searches:

 bed boy blue 
 
 
 
 $30.00 
 

 
 Pottery Barn Kids Navy Madras My First Anywhere Chair 

 Kids Furniture: As welcoming as a cozy lap, our soft chair is a perfect spot for little ones. 20&quot;wide x 20&quot;deep x 20&quot;high Slipcover is pure cotton twill. Insert is made in the USA with recyclable foam containing up to 30% soy-based mater... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Pottery Barn Kids 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Pottery Barn Kids From Pottery Barn Kids With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Pottery Barn Kids 
 
 $109.00 
 

 
 Fun Furnishings My First Chair - Sweet Jane 

 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Walmart.com 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail By Fun Furnishings From Walmart.com With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Walmart.com 
 (25,000+) 
 $159.99 

FREE shipping
 

 
 Ciao! Baby Portable Travel High Chair , Black 

 ciao! baby portable high chair, folding, portable, go-anywhere, light weight, flexible, no assembly required, comes with carrying bag, unfold, lock and ready to use, weighs ariund 8 pounds. Its for children up to 3 years old, great for camp... 
 More like this |   Set price alert 
See More Results...

 From Amazon Marketplace 

Find other Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture...

 Product Detail From Amazon Marketplace With Free Shipping With Sales&amp;Deals 
 
 Amazon Marketplace 
 (1,000+) 
 $69.35 
 
 show 30 60 90 120 items 
 1 2 3 4 5 next 
 
Stores Selling babys first chair
  (Sponsored Links) 
 Baby first chair - Baby First Milestones with Disney Disney Baby Magical Moments www.disney baby .com/ Baby Magical Moments - Getting Ready for Your Baby - Baby Playtime - Baby Mealtime 

 Land of Nod - Nod Chairs Shop for Fun Kids&apos;Seating In Colorful Patterns. Only $99 Now! www.landofnod.com/ 

 Baby Chair Save Up to 70% on Baby Chairs . Exclusive Sales - Shop Now! www.zulily.com/ 

 Babys First Chair - Find Classic Kids&apos;Tables&amp; Chairs Exclusively at Pottery Barn Kids®. www.potterybarnkids.com/ potterybarnkids.com is rated ( 53 reviews ) 

 Baby Sofa Search Baby Sofa Find Baby Sofa www.aol.com/ Baby +Sofa 

 Chairs at Office Depot - Buy Office Chairs Online Today. Fast Delivery from Office Depot! www.officedepot.com/ Office Chairs - Folding&amp;Stacking - Reception Seating - Leather Chairs 

 Chair babies - Browse 710+ Chairs . Reviews, Deals, Coupons, and More. chairs .finecomb.com/ 
 
More information about
 babys first chair
 Best prices on Babys first chair in Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture online. Visit Bizrate to find the best deals on Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture from Cosco, Fun Furnishings and GuideCraft. See which Babies&amp;Kid stores have the Baby&amp;Kids&apos; Furniture that you want. Read reviews on Babies&amp;Kids merchants and buy with confidence. Your Price Alert has been set! Set a price alert to be notified when the price drops. 
 Product Details for HP Pavillion DV6-6C10US 15 Inch 640GB Hard Drive Laptop PC - Steel Gray... 
 
$500.00

Today&apos;s Best Price
 
$499.00

Price I want to beat
 
Notifications will be sent to: CharlesJohnson@jfamstudios.com 

 Manage My Price Alerts 
 
$
 
Notify me when the price drops to or below
 
Your email is safe - Privacy Policy 
 

 Send me other relevant products and savings. 
 
 
 
 Show Recently Viewed Products 

 Hide 
 
Recently Viewed Products
 
 Share Page: 
 
 Hide 
 See the 2011 Circle of Excellence Winners! 

 Follow us: 
 
 Bizrate Sitemap Index Bizrate Store Ratings See All Categories 
©Shopzilla 2012
 
 
save money win money 

Sign up for our emails to save cash.

PLUS a chance to win our Daily Cash Giveaway! 
 
We won&apos;t share your email with anyone. Official Rules 
 

 
Muze for Music: Copyright 1984-2010 Muze Inc. For personal non-commercial use only. All rights reserved.
 
Stores are responsible for providing Bizrate with correct and current prices. Sales taxes and shipping costs are estimates; please check store for exact amounts. Product specifications are obtained from merchants or third parties. Although we make every effort to present accurate information, Bizrate is not responsible for inaccuracies. We encourage you to notify us of any discrepancies by clicking here .

Store ratings and product reviews are submitted by online shoppers; they do not reflect our opinions and we have no responsibility for their content.
 
 Email Signup   Get the hottest deals, products and exclusive offers.
 
Your email is safe - Privacy | Contest Rules 
 
 Congrats!   You&apos;re Bizrate&apos;s newest email subscriber.

 Please check your inbox to complete your signup (and enter sweepstakes).
 X
	</body>
</document>
