<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001186" url="http://www.personaltrainingcalgary.com/?p=854" time="2012-07-12-16:37" support="3" score="0.010647474931896396" bingtitle="How To Eat Healthy At A Fast Food Restaurant" webtitle="Calgary Weight Loss experts explain: Eating Healthy Fast Food | Bridgeland, Calgary Personal Training and Group Fitness - Results Fitness">
			<query id="000124" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000118" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="001378" bing-rank="213"/>
	<description>... in a fast food restaurant it ... calorie count in check. Opt For A Basic Salad . If you want to be really smart and healthy when dining at a fast food restaurant ... is the place ...</description>
	<body>
		How To Eat Healthy At A Fast Food Restaurant

Aug, 12, 2011
 
 As you go about your Calgary weight loss program, there’s going to come a time when you are about to hit the drive thru for a quick bite on the run. In a perfect world you would prepare each and every meal and snack you were going to consume at home so that you could control all the nutrients you were taking in, but life gets busy and we all know that it isn’t a‘perfect world’.

When times get tight you are better off making some smart choices than forgoing food altogether as that could just set you up for extreme hunger and an all-out binge later on.

Fortunately, if you choose wisely when pulling through the drive-thru it doesn’t mean your entire Calgary weight loss diet has to be thrown off track.  Let’s have a quick look at some of the key tips to keep in mind when dining at a fast food restaurant so that you can succeed with your weight loss program.

 Keep Portion Size Under Control 

If there’s one thing that you absolutely must do when dining in a fast food restaurant it’s to be mindful of your portion size.  Remember, you can have a small bite to eat now and then have a healthier snack in an hour or two’s time when you are around foods that are part of your diet.

So rather than ordering a full blown meal and really racking up the calories, consider this just a light snack to tide you through for the next few hours.  This will automatically reduce the calories you consume by at least half, making it that much less detrimental to your diet plan.

 Choose Grilled Protein 

The second must-know tip when dining in a fast food location is to always opt for grilled protein, namely grilled chicken breast.  Most fast food restaurants will offer grilled chicken breast as an option and you typically can’t go wrong here.

The big problem comes when you choose breaded over grilled as then you’ll easily add another 100-200 calories in that breading.

Choosing grilled will help you maintain a lower carb diet and keep your calorie count in check.

 Opt For A Basic Salad 

If you want to be really smart and healthy when dining at a fast food restaurant, choose a very basic salad. Since a salad isn’t cooked there’s no way the chefs can add any hidden fats or sugars in during the cooking process, so what you see is what you get.

Just be sure to request the dressing on the side and avoid high-fat add-ins like croutons, cheese, dried fruit, ramen noodles, or high amounts of nuts.  While some nuts will be okay since they’re healthy fats, sprinkle these on yourself so you can keep the calorie count under control.

 Consider Soup Or Chili 

Finally, don’t overlook the option of soup or chilli. Most soup or chilli dishes at fast food restaurants are around 100-200 calories and are quite low in fat.  For a quick snack to tide you over, these tend to work perfect and will even supply some vegetables as well.

Thinking away from the traditional burger or sandwich may just be the perfect way to keep your Calgary weight loss diet in tact.

So don’t let fast food dining ruin your diet any longer. Follow these tips and you can eat out and stick with your plan.

 This entry was posted on August 12, 2011 at 5:16 pm. You can follow any responses to this entry through the RSS 2.0 feed. 
 Responses are currently closed, but you can trackback from your own site. 

Posted in Health , Newest Articles , Nutrition , Nutrition/Diet by admin | No Comments Yet 

 

 
 

Comments are closed.
 
 
 
 Please enable Javascript in order to get HealCode functionality Join our team! 
If you&apos;re interested in being part of a growing team of personal trainers, this is the place to call home.
 Name:
 Email:
 Phone Number:
 
 
 Home Services/Pricing New classes About Us Free Newsletter Contact 
 
 Event/News Newest Articles 
 Exercise Articles Fitness Articles Health Motivation/Mindset Nutrition Nutrition/Diet Supplements 
 Recipes Success Stories 
 
 Client Login 
 
 
Pages

 Calgary personal training deal Contact FAQ’s Fit Videos Free Newsletter My Story New classes Quick Workouts Services/Pricing The News The Schedule/Rates The Workouts Why Results 
 
 Copyright©Bridgeland, Calgary Personal Training and Group Fitness–Results Fitness |  Personal Trainer Marketing  |  Log In
	</body>
</document>
