<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001928" url="http://simplygreendesignblog.blogspot.com/" time="2012-07-12-17:50" support="3" score="0.002241928749179" bingtitle="Environmental Viewpoint" webtitle="Environmental Viewpoint">
			<query id="000386" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="000745" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="000404" bing-rank="86"/>
	<description>The best part about a waste-less program - no ... of potato chips (what you usually get at a fast food restaurant). ... further delay as climate change is the number one ...</description>
	<body>
		skip to main | skip to sidebar 
Environmental Viewpoint
 
 
 
 Monday, February 1, 2010 
 
 10% Meat 
 What’s a sure fire way to create angst between environmentalists and American consumers? Suggest that everyone give up their carnivorous appetite for bacon burgers, char-broiled steaks, thick-cut pork chops, and crisp fried chicken in the name of saving the environment. Facts are facts: Raising animals and the feed to feed them, the water to water and process them, and the pollution created along the chain has a much bigger environmental impact than eating a vegan diet.

Facts are facts: Meat is a celebratory food in the history of most cultures that subsisted on so little–celebrating with meat suggests a small victory over malnutrition. Transportable animals also shaped the European expansion in the United States territories and settling of the West. The mere suggestion that meat should be abolished is a slap in the face of culture, history, and farming. It’s no wonder so few people have gotten on board that wagon train.

So, how about a different approach? It is fact that a large portion of our population is overweight or obese. We don’t need to“celebrate”a victory over lack of food. We are at a point where we should be looking to celebrate weight loss and improved health. Why not lose weight by reducing meat consumption? Data from the 1999 census  shows that, on average, people in the U.S. ate 126 pounds of meat and poultry that year–or 5.5 ounces per day. A 10% reduction would still allow you to eat 5.0 ounces of meat per day or 113 pounds per year. That’s still a lot of burgers, chops, steaks, and tenderloins. And, what is a half ounce less meat anyway? 1 to 2 bites? The loss is so little it hardly seems worth arguing over.

Yet, the value of that small gesture is big. Imagine if 300 million Americans each ate 10% less meat per year. Total meat consumption would decrease by nearly 4 BILLION pounds. And, each person could lose four pounds of holiday party weight. Green house gas emissions, water consumption, and waste would decrease.

Now, if every year for four years we continued to decrease meat consumption by 10%, we would finally be consuming the recommended daily serving size of meat - 3.5 ounces. Each overweight person could lose 16 pounds. And, we would significantly reduce the impact of animal farming on the environment–all without giving up meat.

10% less meat: It’s what should be for dinner. Posted by Simply Green Design at 9:05 AM No comments: 
 Tuesday, January 26, 2010 
 
 No Membership Fees Required 
 Could it be that we have reached the tipping point–that we have touched bottom so recovery is inevitable? While you might think I am talking about the economy, I am referring to the epidemic of obesity and excess weight. According to an October report by the World Health Organization (WHO), more than one-quarter of people worldwide carry around more weight than a healthy body should. More people now die from being overweight than being underweight: more deaths occur from being over nourished instead of undernourished. The February 2010 Reader’s Digest said it best,“…it’s our appetite for prosperity and all its spoils that’s more likely to kill us now.”


The good news, memberships at health clubs and gyms is growing in the U.S.–and predicted to double in the next 20 years http://www.articlesbase.com/business-articles/health-club-memberships-good-for-you-864104.html . Is the growth due to an increased understanding of the relationship between health and exercise? Is it the social aspect of exercising with others? Perhaps it’s the cool membership card. Whatever the reason, it appears we’ve had enough of the consequences of prosperity–at least as they relate to our weight.

What about the consequences of prosperity and the health of the environment? Could it be that we will begin to take a collective responsibility for the consequences of prosperity now that we are experiencing a collective wake-up call about an unhealthy environment? Solar panels will help provide clean energy, but reliance on them won’t stop our demand for more–more products, more wasted energy to run those products, more solid waste to create and dispose of those products.

Are we hitting the bottom of wasting too much money, too much energy, too many resources?

It appears so. Jackie Crosby’s article“A New Consumer”in the Sunday 1/24/10 Star Tribune Money&amp;Business section talks about the“frugal mindset”of consumers not willing to live beyond their means. While the article doesn’t directly address personal goals for improving the environment, the environment will benefit from a frugal consumer–those growing masses tired of paying high utility bills, that are disgusted with sub-par construction standards in housing, and who cringe weekly at the gas pump.

The best part about a waste-less program - no membership fees are required. Posted by Simply Green Design at 9:02 AM No comments: 
 Monday, January 25, 2010 
 
 Ten Percent in 2010–The Beginning of the Slow Green Movement 
 Are you concerned about the effort it would take to make your family more energy efficient so you can actually reduce your energy bills? Are you afraid that asking for change will create resistance? Do you want success? Then do what successful dieters do - take it slow, set reasonable goals, and establish exciting rewards.


A dieter that reduces their calories by 10% a day for a year will lose 20 pounds at the end of the year. This slow weight loss usually results in the weight being kept off because the steps to achieve the goal are reasonable. How do you eliminate 200 calories? Drink 12-16 oz. less regular beer. Or, eat¼cup less M&amp;M candies. Or, eat 2-3 less cookies. Or, eat 1 ounce less of potato chips (what you usually get at a fast food restaurant). In other words, do a little. Save a lot.

If you reduce your electrical usage by just 10% this year, and 10% again every year for the next six years, you will find that you have reduced your annual electrical use by 50%. A 50% reduction could mean that solar is an affordable option. It could mean that the accumulated savings result in a family vacation.

The average household in the U.S. uses about 900 kWh of electrical energy per month at an average cost of $1,034 per year. A 10% reduction means reducing your electrical needs by 90 kWh per month and saving nearly $ 86.00 for the year. How do you do that? Here’s one example:

Plug home electronics products - computers, printers, and entertainment equipment(TV, VCR, DVD) into power strips and turn them off when not in use–don’t leave them in stand-by mode    http://www.energystar.gov/index.cfm?fuseaction=find_a_product.showProductCategory&amp;pcw_code=HEF . This action alone may save $100/year, which is more than 10%, and took little effort.

Just imagine if everyone joined the Slow Green Movement. In six years, homes would be using 50% less electricity, and residential buildings would be having a huge impact on energy security–without the need for drastic, unsustainable change. Take it slow and steady. But, do it. Posted by Simply Green Design at 3:50 PM No comments: 
 Monday, December 21, 2009 
 
 Eco-Oblivious and the EarthCare Challenge 
 Haven’t yet heard of the EarthCare Challenge? Aren’t you just a bit curious to see what the six“eco-oblivious”contestants are doing to Green their lifestyles and homes for a chance to win earth-friendly furniture? You are invited to follow the  Hickory Springs EarthCare Challange  and join in the conversation.


Why is this contest important? These six people represent you. They are expressing the same questions and concerns that I hear every day as a Green designer. Their goals range from small changes to big investments. Some have spouses and family members to consider as they make decisions. Some are looking to reduce their monthly bills. Others are looking to declutter their life. There are even a few that want to learn more so they can lead by example. Whatever your interests and needs are, you can follow what they are doing, what the Green experts are saying, and help decide which contestant wins the challenge.

This contest brings up an interesting item of note. There are many industries battling the tide to keep business as usual so they don’t have to change–they willingly choose to remain eco-oblivious. But, the smartest industries realize that status quo is not good for long-term growth. The furniture industry is starting to respond to consumer demand for healthier products and long-term environmental need.

Hickory Spring, who supports the EarthCare Challenge, manufactures furniture and components used to make furniture and bedding–stuff like springs and foam. They are using a new formula that replaces some of the petroleum in foam with a bio-based derivative to reduce dependence on oil. They also use recycled-content metals to make their springs. While nothing they do yet is 100% Green, they are transparent about the process: They promote their commitment to making positive change and the hard effort it takes to turn a big boat.

Why is all this significant? Hickory Springs also sells products like foam and springs to the automobile and airplane industries–two industries that remain eco-oblivious. Yet, just like the contestants in the EarthCare Challenge, every visible change leads by example. Posted by Simply Green Design at 8:54 AM No comments: 
 Wednesday, December 2, 2009 
 
 Outta Control 
 How well did you manage the Thanksgiving abundance? A friend told me he has become determined to not overeat. Too many of his holidays ended with him feeling sick instead of joyous. His comment made me wonder how many other people had come to this same conclusion. It reminded me of an article I have held onto since November 8. It was written by Kara McGuire for the Star Tribune“Obeisty of our spending and our bodies” http://www.startribune.com/lifestyle/yourmoney/69404587.html 


John Hanselman, a financial planner, is the metaphor for the story. At the age of 37 he found himself severely overweight and on major medications to offset the negative health effects of obesity. A wake up call from his doctor sounded the alarm about poor behavioral choices and risk of premature death. It made him think about the negative effects of allowing convenience and complacency to override self control. In his own life he saw the effects of too many fast food meals, lack of exercise, and stress. He likened it to the consumers he knows or those he reads about that make irrational decisions about purchasing on credit, buying homes they can’t afford, or investing without due diligence. All around us is an epidemic of obesity and overspending. John’s new attitude became one of sustainability–making informed decisions that will allow him to lose weight in a manner that will promote long-term health.

Reading about John made me want to ask Kara to retitle her article to read“Obesity of our spending and our bodies and environmental consumption.”Just because we have an abundance of resources in this country does not mean we should abandon self control and consume them all until we are sick. It doesn’t feel good and it doesn’t model good behavior for future generations that are counting on us to be good leaders. We already know what happens when you eat too much and over spend without regard for the consequences. Why should over indulgence in environmental consumption lead to any different end result?

Make this holiday season joyful. Indulge in self-control while spending, eating, and leaving footprints on this planet. Posted by Simply Green Design at 8:55 PM No comments: 
 Tuesday, November 17, 2009 
 
 Urging Impatience 
 “I urge impatience,”boomed Dr. Mitch Thomashow, President of Unity College in Unity, Maine. This gregarious man who filled the stage with importance and compassion delivered what I thought was the most compelling presentation in the three days of GreenBuild. He urged the audience of Green architects, builders, designers, remodelers, and city officials to move ahead quickly and without further delay as climate change is the number one threat to a quality future.


He talked about AASHE–The Association for the Advancement of Sustainability in Higher Education and the thousands of members that are committed to“…a prosperous, equitable, and ecologically healthy world”where“…. higher education plays a vital role in ensuring that people have an understanding of the interdependencies between environmental, social, and economic forces and the skills and abilities to meet sustainability challenges.”

(You might be surprised to see what schools have committed to the AASHE challenge: Notre Dame (my alma mater), U of MN, Century College (another alma mater), Augsburg College, Dakota County Technical College, Hamline U, Gustavus Adolphus, Macalester, UW-River Falls, UW-Stout…and many too numerous to mention http://www.aashe.org/membership/members/institutional_members 

Dr. Thomashow talked about the 9 elements of a sustainable culture to which Unity adheres (with“governance”being the most influential element of change). He also showed pictures of the 1,900 square foot Green home where he and his wife live that was designed to doubles as an environmental teaching lab. He is teaching the Unity Board of Directors what it means to truly be an environmental liberal arts college. He is teaching them to walk the talk all the while urging impatience. Posted by Simply Green Design at 9:47 AM No comments: 
 Monday, November 9, 2009 
 
 GreenBuild Means Money for Business and Community Leaders 
 Each November marks a significant milestone in the march towards a sustainable human existence. While the majority of the American population continues to avoid addressing truly committed sustainability issues, a notable population of professionals will be gathering for the world’s largest conference on Green building. Over 28,000 contractors, architects, designers, landscape designers, engineers, city planners, developers, non-profits, lawyers, realtors, manufacturers, retailers, hospital officials, government employees, military personnel, school planners…are expected to attend the U.S. Green Building Council’s (USGBC) GreenBuild conference in Phoenix.


If 28,000 people can’t convince you that sustainability matters, ask the 150,000 LEED APs what they think. USGBC introduced a rigorous testing process to measure a person’s knowledge and ability to apply Green building strategies to buildings and community development. Successful passing of the test awarded a professional the“LEED AP”(Leadership in Energy&amp;Environmental Design Accredited Professional) designation. When I became a LEED AP in 2005, the pass rate was less than 60%. There were only 4,000 individuals accredited at the time. In four years, the test rigor has increased to a pass rate of only 20% while the number of LEED APs grown to over 150,000!
Why has interest in a LEED AP designation grown given the obstacles to achieve success? The moral side of me wishes we were all committed to Green for quality of life issues, yet the main fact stands that LEED AP means you know something about Green buildings and Green buildings mean money.

Why GreenBuild? You can attend workshops to prepare you for the LEED AP test. You can listen to keynote speakers such as Al Gore, business leaders like Arthur Rubinfeld of Starbucks, and Steve Thomas–host of Renovation Nation. But mostly it is the annual November destination for business and community leaders to gather strategies to improve return on investment and preserve quality of life. Posted by Simply Green Design at 2:29 PM No comments: Older Posts Home Subscribe to: Posts (Atom) 
Great Green Links
 
 Simply Green Design Verified Green Michael Anchel&apos;s blog Green Designs and Supply Natural Built Home MN GreenStar U.S. Green Building Council Scherer Brothers Lumber Katherine Salant Blog Shaw/Stewart Lumber Company 
 
 
About Me
 Simply Green Design White Bear Lake, Minnesota, United States Welcome to Simply Green Design–an interior design firm committed to quality design, quality of life, and return on investment for all who seek something better in the spaces where they live. View my complete profile 
Blog Archive
 
 ▼  2010 (3) 
 ▼  February (1) 
 10% Meat 
 

 ►  January (2) 
 No Membership Fees Required Ten Percent in 2010–The Beginning of the Slow Gr... 
 
 

 ►  2009 (19) 
 ►  December (2) 
 Eco-Oblivious and the EarthCare Challenge Outta Control 
 

 ►  November (4) 
 Urging Impatience GreenBuild Means Money for Business and Community ... Where&apos;s Your Fire Extinguisher? Do or Do Not. There is No Try. 
 

 ►  October (4) 
 The End of the Cancer Scare Winter is Coming - Is Your Home Ready? The Great Lighting Debate: LED or CFL When Toilets are Exciting 
 

 ►  September (3) 
 Whispers from the Woods Buying and Selling Crap Boil 2 Minutes 
 

 ►  August (2) 
 I Agree with Shawn McCadden $5 Billion in Green Homes by 2013 
 

 ►  July (4) 
 Free Government Money Complications of a S&apos;More It&apos;s summer, and nothing introduces a conversatio... Fail Forward Fast 
 
 

 ►  2008 (1) 
 ►  December (1) 
 Cindy Ojczyk: Environmental Blogger for Press Publ...
	</body>
</document>
