<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001192" url="http://meemoskitchen.blogspot.com/2009/09/hardees-cinnamon-n-raisin-biscuit.html" time="2012-07-12-16:38" support="1" score="0.000622507061935519" bingtitle="Meemo&apos;s Kitchen: HARDEE&apos;S® CINNAMON &apos;N&apos; RAISIN® BISCUIT" webtitle="Meemo&apos;s Kitchen: HARDEE&apos;SCINNAMON &apos;N&apos; RAISINBISCUIT">
			<query id="000305" bing-rank="114"/>
	<description>Since Hardee&apos;s is a fast food restaurant I am guessing the version made from bisquick ... Starbucks® Passion Tea Lemonade 3 or 4 Tazo Passion Tea bags 3 cups ...</description>
	<body>
		Meemo&apos;s Kitchen 
 
 The best little authentic restaurant recipes and copycat recipes blog on the internet. 

Authentic Restaurant Recipes, Super 
Secret Recipe Copycats, Traditional Recipes and Original Recipes. 
 
MEEMO 1992-2010
 
 Fearless Leader Meemo 
 Friday, September 18, 2009 
 
 HARDEE&apos;S®CINNAMON &apos;N&apos; RAISIN®BISCUIT 
 
 I have two very old recipes for Hardee&apos;s Cinnamon &apos;N&apos; Raisin Biscuits. I have had them for years and don&apos;t know who or where they were originally posted. Since Hardee&apos;s is a fast food restaurant I am guessing the version made from bisquick is closer to what is used in their restaurants. It may be another company&apos;s baking mix since they most likely purchase their food products from large food service suppliers such as Sysco, Golden State, etc. With teenagers preparing the food a premixed biscuit would help to insure they conform to corporate recipes (as much of a recipe you would find in a fast food restaurant). So, to make a long story short, I will post the biscuit mix version. . Hardee&apos;s®Cinnamon &apos;n&apos; Raisin®Biscuits .
2-1/4 to 2-1/2 cups Bisquick®baking mix 1/2 cup raisins 1 teaspoon cinnamon 2/3 cup milk
2 tablespoons sugar .
Melted butter
. Glaze 2/3 cup powdered sugar 1/2 teaspoon vanilla 1 tablespoon warm water
. Preheat oven to 450ºF. Mix Bisquick,milk, raisins, cinnamon and sugar until a soft dough forms. Turn dough onto a floured surface and knead 20 times. Roll 1/2&quot; thick. Cut into round biscuits and palce in an ungreased 8 x 8&quot; pan. Flatten slightly. Brush with melted butter. Bake for 8-10 minutes. . Remove and brush with more butter, then drizzle with glaze. . Glaze: Mix all ingredients together in bowl until smooth. If necessary add more warm water, a teaspoon at a time, until the glaze is at the desired consistency.
 Posted by Pattie Kaykes at 6:00 AM Labels: cinnamon n raison biscuit , copycat recipe , hardee&apos;s Newer Post Older Post Home 
Subscribe
 Posts Atom Posts Comments Atom Comments 
FIRE BOOKS AND APPS
 
KINDLE BOOKS
 
FOR THE SERIOUS READER; THE BEST e-READER AT THE LOWEST PRICE
 
FIRE!
 
Click Link to
 Shop at
Amazon.com! 
Follow Me
 
Thank you for supporting Meemo&apos;s Kitchen
 
Popular Posts
 
 STARBUCKS®PASSION TEA LEMONADE Starbucks®Passion Tea Lemonade 3 or 4 Tazo Passion Tea bags 3 cups cold water 1 can (12 ounces) frozen lemonade concentrate 1 teaspoo... BUFFALO WILD WINGS®AND BUFFALO SAUCES From the midwest based chain BUFFALO WILD WINGS - BUFFALO WINGS AND SAUCES - SPICY GARLIC WING SAUCE - MEDIUM WING SAUCE - HOT WING SA... TEXAS ROADHOUSE®SWEET YEAST ROLLS I&apos;ve included the recipe Tammy (see comments) shared for Texas Roadhouse Cinnamon Butter following the recipe for the rolls. It&apos;s great! Th... KENTUCKY FRIED CHICKEN ORIGINAL RECIPE (CopyCat) Kentucky Fried Chicken or KFC, whatever you call it, those 11 herbs and spices have remained a long sought after mystery. Unfortunately for... OLIVE GARDEN®CHICKEN ALFREDO Olive Garden®Chicken Alfredo 1 small boneless/skinless chicken breast per serving Olive Oil Seasoning of choice, if desired Olive Garden A... CHILI&apos;S®QUESADILLA EXPLOSION SALAD This salad has a lot of components but when you get them all put together it is worth the effort. The good part is if you don&apos;t want to mak... BENIHANA®JAPANESE ONION SOUP Another super secret recipe from Benihana. The recipe doesn&apos;t quite match the menu description. Menu Description: Benihana Soup - Simmere... CHEESECAKE FACTORY®THAI LETTUCE WRAPS Here is a super secret version of the popular lettuce wraps served at The Cheesecake Factory. The Cheesecake Factory®Thai Lettuce Wraps ... BUCA DI BEPPO APPLE GORGONZOLA SALAD AND ITALIAN VINAIGRETTE The recipe below courtesy of a Buca di Beppo chef uses walnuts and bottle Italian vinaigrette. If you want to make your salad more like t... MCDONALD&apos;S SWEET TEA June is National Iced Tea Month! McDonald&apos;s Sweet Tea I don&apos;t do sweet with iced tea. I drink it &quot;straight&quot;, tea, water and ice. Wild Ber... 
 
If you re-post a recipe, please give credit and link to recipe on this site.
 
 Meemo&apos;s Kitchen Recipes by Pattie Kaykes is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-Noncommercial 3.0 United States License . 
 
 Enter your search terms 
 Web meemoskitchen.blogspot.com 
 Submit search form 
 
.
 
Email Subscriptions powered by FeedBlitz
 
Your email address:
 
 
Powered by FeedBlitz 
 My recipes can only be use for private, non-commerical, non-profit generation uses.
Do not post or publish my recipes without full and clear credit, a direct link to the original post. E-mail me with any requests and questions
 
About Me
 View my complete profile 
When I am bored
 
 Sheep Reaction Test JigZone Escapa! BoredMuch.com 
 
Helpful and Informative Links
 
 Naturopathic: Naturo-what? DinnerTool 
 
Gourmet Food Gifts From Amazon
 
Cookware and Bakeware from Amazon
 
Cookbooks from Amazon
 
.
 Feedjit Live Blog Stats 
 Free Counter 
2011
 Calendar Loading... 
 
 
MEEMO&apos;S FAVORITE THINGS
 
 
 Powered by Blogger . 
.
 
Archives
 
 ►  2012 (60) 
 ►  July (1) 
 BACK IN THE DAY BAKERY COCONUT MACAROONS 
 

 ►  June (4) 
 THE CHOCOLATE ROOM&apos;S THREE-LAYER CHOCOLATE CAKE WI... SALTED CARAMEL ICE CREAM BROWNIES WITH COCONUT FROSTING MAGNOLIA BAKERY PEANUT BUTTER PIE 
 

 ►  May (3) 
 PAUL DEEN&apos;S GRANDMOTHER PAUL&apos;S SOUTHERN FRIED CHIC... OREO&amp;FUDGE ICE CREAM CAKE EMERIL&apos;S BANANA CREAM PIE WITH CARAMEL DRIZZLES AN... 
 

 ►  April (1) 
 AVOIDING CELL PHONE DANGERS 
 

 ►  February (22) 
 5 YEARS LATER TACO BELL FIRE SAUCE PERKIN&apos;S FAMILY RESTAURANT SMOKED HAM, BACON AND C... PERKIN&apos;S FAMILY RESTAURANT FARMER&apos;S OMELETTE PERKIN&apos;S FAMILY RESTAURANT EVERYTHING OMELETTE MORTON&apos;S THE STEAKHOUSE RASPBERRY SOUFFLE CHOCOLATE COVERED PEANUT BUTTER PIE PAUL DEEN&apos;S DOUBLE CHOCOLATE GOOEY BUTTER CAKE LOVELESS CAFE RED VELVET CAKE BAKED BAKERY SWEET AND SALTY CHOCOLATE CAKE CHOCOLATE VELVET DESSERT SARABETH&apos;S BAKERY CHOCOLATE TRUFFLE CAKE HUMMINGBIRD BAKERY VANILLA CUPCAKES DREAMCAKES BAKERY STUPID CUPID CUPCAKES BAKED BAKERY RED VELVET CUPCAKES WITH CINNAMON BUT... HOMEMADE CHOCOLATE LIQUOR CHOCOLATE PEANUT BUTTER GIANDUJA LOADED BAKED POTATO DIP CLAIM JUMPER CRUNCHY SPINACH SALAD WITH CITRUS DRE... GORDON BIERSCH BREWERY&amp;RESTAURANT CHOPPED SALAD ... BENIHANA YAKISOBA DINNER ROSA MEXICANO GUACAMOLE 
 

 ►  January (29) 
 PAULA DEEN&apos;S WHITE CHOCOLATE LEMON TRIFLE BROWNIE BITES WITH CARAMEL FROSTING McCORMICK&amp;SCHMICK&apos;S SEAFOOD RESTAURANT CLAM CHOW... NOODLES&amp;COMPANY MACARONI AND CHEESE ROCK BOTTOM RESTAURANT AND BREWERY SPICY SPINACH D... FLEMING&apos;S PRIME STEAKHOUSE POTATOES 6TH STREET BISTRO AND LOFT PEAR AND WALNUT SALAD W... SEVEN FOODS THE EXPERTS WON&apos;T EAT CHOCOLATE CARAMEL PIE PANERA BREAD BACON TURKEY BRAVO SANDWICH SALTY&apos;S SEAFOOD GRILL BEST CHOCOLATE CAKE EVER! FIREBIRDS RESTAURANTS AND WOOD FIRED GRILL PARMESA... MORTON&apos;S THE STEAKHOUSE MACARONI AND CHEESE RIGO JANCSI; CHOCOLATE RIGO SQUARES HEATH BITS CRUNCH ICE CREAM QUICK AND EASY CHOCOLATE CHIP CAKE PANERA BREAD SIGNATURE MACARONI&amp;CHEESE BAHAMA BREEZE BREEZE WOOD GRILLED CHICKEN BREAST PAULA DEEN&apos;S LADY AND SONS CHICKEN POT PIE 
 
 

 ►  2011 (359) 
 ►  December (31) 

 ►  November (30) 

 ►  October (31) 

 ►  September (29) 

 ►  August (32) 

 ►  July (30) 

 ►  June (30) 

 ►  May (32) 

 ►  April (28) 

 ►  March (28) 

 ►  February (29) 

 ►  January (29) 
 

 ►  2010 (360) 
 ►  December (32) 

 ►  November (34) 

 ►  October (32) 

 ►  September (30) 

 ►  August (30) 

 ►  July (31) 

 ►  June (31) 

 ►  May (30) 

 ►  April (27) 

 ►  March (30) 

 ►  February (27) 

 ►  January (26) 
 

 ▼  2009 (361) 
 ►  December (33) 

 ►  November (33) 

 ►  October (32) 

 ▼  September (28) 
 OLIVE GARDEN®TUSCAN GARLIC CHICKEN ROMANO&apos;S MACARONI GRILL®BELLINI KOO KOO ROO®CHICKEN BISTRO ORIGINAL SKINLESS FLAM... ROMANO&apos;S MACARONI GRILL®FOCCACIA BREAD RED ROBIN®WHISKEY RIVER®BBQ CHICKEN SALAD P. F. CHANG CHINA BISTRO®GARLIC NOODLES MCDONALD&apos;S®M&amp;M MCFLURRY ARIZONA GREEN TEA WITH GINSENG AND HONEY BUCA DI BEPPO®LINGUINI FRUTTI DI MARE BUCA DI BEPPO®MOZZARELLA CAPRESE STARBUCKS®LEMON-RASPBERRY LOAF SALTY&apos;S SEAFOOD GRILLS®WHITE CHOCOLATE BROWNIES HARDEE&apos;S®CINNAMON&apos;N&apos;RAISIN®BISCUIT MRS KNOTT&apos;S BUTTERMILK BISCUITS POPEYE&apos;S®BUTTERMILK BISCUITS BUCA DI BEPPO®CHICKEN WITH LEMON RICE TO RICHES SEX, DRUGS AND ROCKY ROAD RICE PUDD... CALIFORNIA PIZZA KITCHEN®RASPBERRY LEMON DROP MA... BRAVO! PASTA BRAVO CHIPOTLE MEXICAN GRILL®BARBACOA BURRITO ROMANO&apos;S MACARONI GRILL®CHICKEN PORTOBELLO T.G. I. FRIDAY®ELECTRIC LEMONADE CHEESECAKE FACTORY®LOUISIANA CHICKEN PASTA RASPBERRY LEMONADE WATERMELON LEMONADE EL POLLO LOCO®FLAME GRILLED CHICKEN EL POLLO LOCO®AVOCADO SALSA THE 20 MOST ANTIOXIDENT RICH FOODS 
 

 ►  August (32) 

 ►  July (28) 

 ►  June (26) 

 ►  May (30) 

 ►  April (30) 

 ►  March (30) 

 ►  February (29) 

 ►  January (30) 
 

 ►  2008 (415) 
 ►  December (50) 

 ►  November (42) 

 ►  October (32) 

 ►  September (33) 

 ►  August (38) 

 ►  July (41) 

 ►  June (32) 

 ►  May (36) 

 ►  April (30) 

 ►  March (35) 

 ►  February (26) 

 ►  January (20) 
 

 ►  2007 (81) 
 ►  December (26) 

 ►  November (17) 

 ►  October (11) 

 ►  August (1) 

 ►  July (2) 

 ►  June (4) 

 ►  May (2) 

 ►  April (5) 

 ►  March (8) 

 ►  February (5)
	</body>
</document>
