<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001081" url="http://www.tcmag.com/magazine/god_bless_america" time="2012-07-12-16:30" support="1" score="0.0007949509404737563" bingtitle="God Bless America Trailer - TCMag.com" webtitle="God Bless America Trailer - TCMag.com">
			<query id="000395" bing-rank="87"/>
	<description>Truck vs Wooden Bridge Marines Humiliating Dead ... Guy Shot Outside Of Fast Food Restaurant Welcome To TCmag ... I have seen inbred trash, no teeth begging for ...</description>
	<body>
		totallycoolpix.com vkmag.com watkijkjij.tv mediabom.tv beglium.be vitter.be totallynsfw.com (18+) 
 TCMag.com 
 Home Videos Galleries Categories 
 ahhh fail ftw hot lol news nsfw ouch wow wtf 
 Contact Archive Friends Quick search 
 
 Friends 
 
 Inessa Chimato ANNA LENA Jessica Simpson Is HUGE Doutzen Kroes Lingerie Sexiness The Extremely Hot LEAH Francis 14 Sexy Video Game Babes Madden And Her Ass Awesome 3D Art Pics 30 Athletes Who Have Posed Nude Sexy Coed Kyra Transtrum 

 Latest Greatest 

 Galleries More galleries 
 
   Daniela Hantuchova naked for ESPN Body Magazine   Mario Gotze Is Very Horny   Pix Dump #60   The Mask Hits Chinese Beaches   Builder’s Bum Becomes Babe’s Boobies   Kickass Celebrity Photos Galore 

   Mercedes SLR McLaren Turned Into Crap   Extreme Food   Brooke Hogan Going For Raunchy   Pix Dump #43   Zombie Run In Massachusetts   Christina Aguilera At The Michael Forever Tribute 

 Latest Greatest 

 Videos More videos 
 
   San Diego Fireworks 2012 Up close   Breaking Batman   Monkey Dive Bombing In India   Big Ass Shark Steals Little Fish   Chuck Test feat. Sabotage   How To Make A Big Mac 

   LaCrosse Mass Brawl   Marines Humiliating Dead Taliban Insurgents   Malaysian Woman Abusing A Baby   Racist British Slag On The Tram   Guy Shot Outside Of Fast Food Restaurant   Welcome To TCmag 

Now on totallycoolpix.com
 
 
 
 «World’s Craziest Fan Goes Crazy Lauren Budd 4 Frederick’s of Hollywood» 
 
God Bless America Trailer

This is going to break a few conservative pacemakers.

 Videoplayer 
 
 wow Posted on January 31, 2012 Link 14 
 
Join us on Twitter and Facebook !
 
Take a look at these posts as well
   San Diego Fireworks 2012 Up...   Breaking Batman   Monkey Dive Bombing In India   Big Ass Shark Steals Little...   Chuck Test feat. Sabotage   How To Make A Big Mac   The Delite-o-matic   What Snake Venom Does to Blood   Daniela Hantuchova naked for...   Pharaoh’s Second LIfe Great story bro. And I mean it.
You shouldn&apos;t take it too hard tho.
Truth is, you&apos;re not supposed to judge a book by it&apos;s cover, but I think, that is a Utopian motto. In everyday life you do it, and I believe there often is no other way. On many occasions the first, or the few impressions you get are all you can base on. Maybe it&apos;s wrong but I don&apos;t feel like I should spend my time and energy to better know everything.
Absolutely true, there is trash in every country. What surprises me is what you think of Europeans, that they think they are perfect, because frankly, that&apos;s my main impression of USA and it&apos;s mentality and citizens. But that of course is taught to those people by the system. We are THE USA. And truth is, I am well sure about all the great people that are from USA. unfortunately, you don&apos;t see much of those on the web, in the comments, or wherever... maybe I&apos;m looking wrong places, but I guess it&apos;s just the scale. Population and the percentage of ppl with internet access just makes certain people more visible thank other countries I guess.
So of course it is a generalization and stereotyping. But it&apos;s not just a random idea it all came from somewhere. Maybe people also don&apos;t like how USA is poking their nose into whole worlds business. That it is at war for virtually 200 years non stop.
I&apos;m sorry you get hurt by it, that&apos;s why I think, with what you have written you should just feel it kinda doesn&apos;t concern you. Maybe the truth is trash are in every country and you&apos;re just trying to fight some of the foreign ones, and the better people don&apos;t hate USA?
Just keep doing the good things, if you feel good about it, you shouldn&apos;t be touhed by such shit talking.
Cheers!
 Posted by Random on 2012-02-02 23:04:47 I am a blue collar hard working american. I joined the military, went to a stupid, pointless war, came back to nothing and now I work a dead end job while these over paid white collar bastards reap the benefits of being rich while I lose money and become poorer. Ive lived in Spain, England, Scotland and Bahrain and I have seen and met every single one of these countries trash. I know everyone in Europe thinks they are perfect, and that America is this holy grail of fat fucks, but you have your inbred trash as well. I want to see this movie because it&apos;s everything people wish they can do but cannot. What I don&apos;t fathom is why there is such animosity towards us? Yes, we have our own assholes, trash, inbred swine, but you know what? We have a lot of good people too. I am tired of people placing our people in this one bag. You know nothing of this country. Our government is corrupt. People grow up by the society they live in. If you grow up poor, you will take on the role of that stereotype. If you grow up rich you grow up to that stereotype. American&apos;s, have their issues. They grow up with corrupt politicians who take and never give, fluctuating laws, corrupt police and authority figures, over populated jails for minor offenses and the idolization of reality TV stars because sometimes life is so mundane all you have is a television. Kids are getting lazier because the system has gotten lazier. Ive seen overweight trash in India, but I don&apos;t see any of you bashing them, or their country. I have seen inbred trash, no teeth begging for euros in England, but I don&apos;t see you pointing out your own countries flaws. So who are any of you to actively judge an entire nation on the television it puts out and New York City? the cesspool of the US? Have you ever been to rural Oregon? Have you ever been to upstate Connecticut in the fall? Have you ever had the balls to step in south Boston and lived a day in the life of a true hard worker? no. You haven&apos;t. You watch your TV, scan the internet for stupid Americans and pan an entire country to make yourself feel better because thats how YOU grew up. Judgmental and arrogant. I love my country but hate how it&apos;s run. I vote, but sadly my vote is only one among many brainwashed by the television you get your American education from. I enjoy blues, but also enjoy my hard rock. I enjoy cooking but try to stay healthy. I read, but I enjoy the occasional video game. I enjoy riding my motorcycle when I can, but I take time to hike and reconnect with nature. I love American football and yell when my team loses. I&apos;ve seen huge riots over European football, and yet Americans are horrible. C&apos;mon guys, we live on the same planet, breathe the same air and work for the same things. To live life fully. You don&apos;t have to have a hard on for America, but you know what? What did I ever do to you?
 Posted by Justthatguy on 2012-02-02 20:26:21 You are hilarious, i almost farted.
 Posted by Gargamel on 2012-02-02 18:16:06 Looks great, can&apos;t wait to pirate it.
 Posted by anarchy2OO7 on 2012-02-01 11:27:20 I am actually looking forward for this show. I am really excited.
 Posted by Carpet Cleaning Raleigh NC on 2012-02-01 10:21:18 Don&apos;t really see how this would piss off conservatives. They&apos;re using guns to take out what is perceived as narcissistic self-involved materialistic facets of popular society using firearms while driving around in a gas guzzling camaro. Sounds like a conservative gun lovers wet dream.
 Posted by fatunclesam on 2012-02-01 08:52:28 I feel that this is a glorious and most pivotal moment in cinema...about FUCKING TIIIIMMMMEE.
 Posted by Sulelikmari on 2012-02-01 08:11:06 Anyone else reminded of &apos; SUPER &apos; ?
 Posted by Epsilonace on 2012-02-01 07:47:35 I for one have felt the same way, especially while driving.
 Posted by floorguy on 2012-02-01 07:22:35 Is this for real? AWESOME!!
 Posted by WORTHLESS4 on 2012-02-01 00:39:12 Is this a genuine movie which is Falling Down meets Leon ?
 Posted by Whackaday on 2012-01-31 22:12:27 Someone finally gets it. Someone who is American. Thanks to this movie I now believe there are more and more descent people living in America, and not just dumb, fat, brainwashed idiots. But you need more smart people and you need them on top. Not just wondering the streets.
 Posted by Jimmy on 2012-01-31 20:40:40 Katharsis.
 Posted by Barabara on 2012-01-31 18:01:32 Nice
 Posted by Tohuvabohu on 2012-01-31 17:27:45 
In the TC forums

 Action Hitler You Slaggggg!!!!!! Normandy Before And After. If you ever won the ‘lottery’...Which ‘Stately Home/Castle’ would you buy?..These are all for sale in the UK.. @Humper..You need to check in on the forum.. Andy Murray what a twat Riddle of the Day 1 
 
Linktips

Got something we missed? Send it to us and we&apos;ll check it out.
 
TC Network

 TotallyCrap Forums TotallyCrap Archive TotallyCoolPix VKMag.com WatKijkJij.tv Mediabom.tv Beglium.be TotallyNSFW (18+) Website Monitoring 
 
Friends of TC MAG
	</body>
</document>
