<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001788" url="http://www.chacha.com/question/what-is-wendy%27s-fast-food-restaurant%27s-tax-employee-identification-number" time="2012-07-12-17:34" support="8" score="0.022121425525777214" bingtitle="What is Wendy&apos;s fast food restaurant&apos;s tax employee identification ..." webtitle="What is Wendy&apos;s fast food restaurant&apos;s tax employee identification number? | ChaCha">
			<query id="000720" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000422" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000185" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000740" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000173" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000430" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000416" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000743" bing-rank="49"/>
	<description>What is Wendy&apos;s fast food restaurant&apos;s tax employee identification number? ChaCha Answer: Wendy&apos;s/Arby&apos;s Group, Inc.&apos;s Federal Tax ID...</description>
	<body>
		About ChaCha 
 
 ChaCha 

 Questions Categories 
 Entertainment 
 Art&amp;Design Celebrities Events Games Humor Literature Movie Showings Movies Music Song Lyrics TV&amp;Radio Theater 
 Sports 
 Baseball Basketball Football Golf Hockey Motorsports Olympics Scores Soccer Tennis 
 Culture 
 Christianity Cultures&amp;Groups Demographics Education Family Historic Figures History Islam Judaism Mormonism Mythology&amp;Folklore Name Etymology Relationships&amp;Dating Religion&amp;Spirituality 
 Politics 
 Campaigns&amp;Elections Law Military Political Figures State&amp;Local Gov. U.S. Government Wars&amp;Conflicts World Governments 
 Lifestyle 
 Bars&amp;Nightlife Dining Out Food&amp;Drink GLBT Green Living Home&amp;Garden Pets Recreation Shopping Style&amp;Beauty 
 Lookup 
 Definitions Mail&amp;Shipping Non-Famous People Puzzles Translations Weather&amp;Time White Pages Yellow Pages 
 SciTech 
 Animals&amp;Plants Astronomy Automotive Biology Chemistry Computers Consumer Electronics Earth Sciences Internet Math Physics Science 
 Business Health Travel 
 Galleries Quizzes 
 Sign In 
 Please enable JavaScript in your browser to immerse yourself in our rich user experience. 
 X 
 
 
What is Wendy&apos;s fast food restaurant&apos;s tax employee identification number? 

In: Business › Corporate Info › Tax 
 
Rate This Answer
 
Wendy&apos;s/Arby&apos;s Group, Inc.&apos;s Federal Tax ID number is 38-0471180. 
 Answered

 by Melanie J. - 1184 days ago at 11:49pm on Apr 14 2009 
Related Tax Questions

 
 If A limited liability company offers the tax advantage of a partnership. True or false? 

The answer is false. A limited liability compan...

in Business | 14 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 What is the tax in North Olmsted, Ohio? 

In North Olmstead, Ohio, the sales taxe is 7.75...

in Business | 31 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 Is medical insurance tax deductible? 

If you have self-employment income, then you ca...

in Business | 50 days ago via Android app 
 
 How do i find sales tax of 0.06%? 

If sales tax is 6%, and you spend 15 dollars, y...

in Business | 61 days ago via sms text 
 
 Where can I file for tax return online? 

You can file your tax return online at turbotax...

in Business | 62 days ago via sms text 
 
 What is an example of a tax-exempt benefit? 

Hospitals and churches are examples of tax-exem...

in Business | 62 days ago via sms text 
 
 Is interest you earn on a certificate of deposit exempt from state and local taxes? 

According to forbes they are not tax free. Than...

in Business | 71 days ago via sms text 
 
 When selling a product Is taking sales tax off illegal? 

No. Sales tax does not apply to personal sales....

in Business | 80 days ago via Android app 
 
 Do I have to file taxes if I am under the age of 18? 

Certain conditions apply that will determine if...

in Business | 87 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 What form is used to file a tax extension for business taxes? 

Form 4868 will extend the deadline by six month...

in Business | 90 days ago via web 
 
 Where is the best place to do your taxes? 

TaxACT is highly recommended for people with re...

in Business | 103 days ago via web 
 
 What is the best tax company? 

H and R Block is a really good company for taxe...

in Business | 111 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 See All Questions ▶ 
Last Week&apos;s Popular Questions for Tax 

 
 What is cigaretes tax class? 

Cigarette taxes are considered an excise tax. T...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 6 days ago via sms text 
 
 What is the tax percentage of new jersey? 

If your income range is between $35,001 and $40...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 1 day ago via sms text 
 
 How much is tax in the state of missouri? 

State sales tax rate: 4.225%. Thanks for asking...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 2 hr 53 min ago via iPhone app 
 
 What is tax on 100 dollars in Kentucky? 

In Kentucky it is 6 cents on the dollar. For $1...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 7 days ago via sms text 
 
 How much is sales tax in the state of california? 

California has a statewide sales tax rate of 7....

in Finance&amp;Economy | 7 days ago via sms text 
 
 What is Missouris income tax percentage? 

There are 10 income tax brackets for Missouri. ...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 12 min ago via Android app 
 
 What is the tax percent in ohio? 

The state sales tax rate in Ohio is currently 5...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 1 day ago via web 
 
 What is the Federal Tax rate in Texas? 

The Federal tax rate is the same for everyone i...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 2 days ago via Android app 
 
 What is the sales tax in Bolingbrook IL? 

The sale tax in Bolingbrook, IL is 6.25%. Even ...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 1 day ago via sms text 
 
 What is the tax percentage in Texas? 

The sales tax percentage in Texas is 8 1/4 perc...

in State&amp;Local Government | 4 days ago via sms text 
 
 See All Questions ▶ 
Last Month&apos;s Popular Questions for Tax 

 
 What is the tax percent in ohio? 

The state sales tax rate in Ohio is currently 5...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 1 day ago via web 
 
 What is the tax percentage in Texas? 

The sales tax percentage in Texas is 8 1/4 perc...

in State&amp;Local Government | 4 days ago via sms text 
 
 What is FICA Tax? 

FICA stands for the Federal Insurance Contribut...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 11 hr 28 min ago via Android app 
 
 What is cigaretes tax class? 

Cigarette taxes are considered an excise tax. T...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 6 days ago via sms text 
 
 What is the tax percentage of new jersey? 

If your income range is between $35,001 and $40...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 1 day ago via sms text 
 
 What is the Federal Tax rate in Texas? 

The Federal tax rate is the same for everyone i...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 2 days ago via Android app 
 
 How much is tax in the state of missouri? 

State sales tax rate: 4.225%. Thanks for asking...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 2 hr 53 min ago via iPhone app 
 
 What is property tax in Wyoming? 

Property tax in Wyoming is 7%. Wyoming brings i...

in Real Estate | 9 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 What are the tax brackets? 

For the 2008 tax year the Federal income bracke...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 10 days ago via sms text 
 
 What is car sales tax in ohio? 

The sales tax for a vehicle in the state of Ohi...

in Finance&amp;Economy | 9 days ago via sms text 
 
 See All Questions ▶   
Related Tax Galleries

 
 
 
 The Impact of Brand Significance 
 
 
 
 The World&apos;s Most Recognized Logos 
 Viewed 623 times 
 
 
 
 Top 10 Celeb Endorsements 
 Viewed 112 times 
 
 
 
 Best Buy Closing Stores 
 Viewed 63 times 
 
 
 
 Yahoo Cuts 2,000 Jobs 
 
 
 
 Fun Facts About Apple Inc. 
 Viewed 1344 times 
 
 See All Galleries ▶ 
Related Tax Quizzes

 
 
 
 Do You Recognize That 90&apos;s Logo? 
 Viewed 8127 times 
 
 
 
 How Much Do You Really Know About Facebook? 
 Viewed 15061 times 
 
 
 
 Do You Know Company Slogans? 
 Viewed 16333 times 
 
 
 
 Do You Recognize These Famous Logos? 
 Viewed 583274 times 
 
 
 
 Is Your Boss a Jerk? 
 Viewed 2023 times 
 
 
 
 Can You Match the Insurance Company to its Slogan? 
 Viewed 5790 times 
 
 See All Quizzes ▶ 
Share This Page:

 Facebook Tweet Email 
 Advertisement 
About Federal Tax 
 
Federal Taxes are administered through the Internal Revenue Service (IRS), a bureau of the Treasury. The US tax code is intended to provide revenue for the federal government. Federal taxes are also for public policy reasons, such as encouraging home ownership.

 More about Federal Tax »
 
Top Trends in Corporate Info 

 Bell Coupons» 
 
Top Trends in Business 

 Job Application» Savings» Rent» ATM» Resume» Brands» Visa» Work Permit» Bankruptcy» Start a Business» 
 
Top Trends

 Love» 100 Floors» Say in Spanish» Boy» Facebook» Illegal» Website» Area Code» Hurt» Ford» 
 Advertisement Home › Categories › Business › Corporate Info › Tax 
Text Your Question

* ChaCha does not charge for its service.
Message and Data Rates May Apply.
If you need help, text HELP to 242-242 .
To cancel your service, text STOP to 242-242 .
 
ChaCha Mobile Apps
 
 ChaCha for iPhone ChaCha for iPad ChaCha for Android 
 
Connect

 Become a ChaCha Fan on Facebook Follow ChaCha on Twitter Follow ChaCha on Pinterest Follow ChaCha on Google+ Follow ChaCha on Apple Follow ChaCha on Android 

 About Contact FAQs 
 
Services

 Questions&amp;Answers Become a Guide Work for ChaCha 

 Advertise With Us ChaCha Mobile Affiliate Program 
 
©Copyright 2006-2012 ChaCha Search, Inc.–Experimental Use, All Rights Reserved, May Be Covered by US or Foreign Patents or Patents Pending. Copyright Notice | Terms of Use | Privacy
	</body>
</document>
