<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001353" url="http://cathyturley.wordpress.com/2012/03/16/chicago-indi-national-whirl-wind-tour/" time="2012-07-12-16:51" support="1" score="0.00036414805816425744" bingtitle="Chicago: A Multi-National Whirl Wind Tour « Cathy Turley" webtitle="Chicago: A Multi-National Whirl Wind TourCathy Turley">
			<query id="000015" bing-rank="127"/>
	<description>I found a seat, but Brian chose to stand. It ... and – BAM!- in front of us was a local fast food restaurant ... sauce (and all forms of pickled/curried condiments ...</description>
	<body>
		Cathy Turley 

Crafty, Green and DIY
 
 Home About 
 Mar 16 
Chicago: A Multi-National Whirl Wind Tour
 Posted on March 16, 2012 by Cathy Turley Chicago: A Multi-National Whirl Wind Tour 
Monday was a red-letter day: a date and an excursion to India and Pakistan – all within two bus rides of our Chicago apartment!

Monday Brian and I rode the Chicago Transit Authority bus #36 north. The bus was rather crowded. I found a seat, but Brian chose to stand.

 It takes all kinds! 

I was thankful Brian was nearby when a young man across the aisle started singing – loudly. At first it sounded innocent. Something like, “Pancakes and syrup, beans and rice. Pancakes and syrup, spinach and grits. Biscuits and gravy, and…”

The chorus was not related, “Wet t-shirt contest, wet t-shirt contest, wet t-shirt contest…on Thursday…” (?!). It was painful.

Then, the young man started talking (again, loudly) to women as they got on the bus. I tried to read. I was afraid he’d yell out a description of my hair and my clothes too.

None of his comments were off-color, just friendly – and loud –  with a pinch of crazy thrown in. I gave up reading and tried to remember all the great things he was saying.

 Is there something in the water? 

We got off the bus, crossed the street and–BAM!- in front of us was a local fast food restaurant that sold fried chicken, burgers and fries. On one of their windows was something I never expected to see.
 
Rather cheeky...
 
Wow!

I snapped a picture and a woman assured me the chicken was delicious.

Jake’s on the north-east corner of Montrose and Broadway.

 Nifty Thrift 

Brian and I love to thrift shop. We find that if we are picky enough, we can usually find something we like. Our local “Unique” thrift store sells everything for half price on Mondays.

I had just read a style magazine, so I was prepared! Hooray! We both found a couple of things!

 http://www.uniquethriftstore.com 

 North and west…to India?! 

We stashed everything in our bags and headed further north on the #36 to Devon Avenue. We switched over to the #155 Devon bus to go west to Rockwell. Our destination: the Indian/Pakistani shops: Patel Brothers and Sukhadia’s Sweets and Snacks.
 
Awesome sauce (and all forms of pickled/curried condiments) at Patel Brothers. Photo courtesy of Google maps.
 
Here’s an annotated list of our purchases at Patel Brothers.

 Natural Dahi , 5 pounds plain yogurt. This stuff is really good. It’s plain but not as tart as many plain yogurts. It reminds me of Greek yogurt – just $5.99 for 5 pounds!
 
Plain yogurt: my favorite way to temper the heat of spicy curry.
 Figs – our favorite. They are dried, not mushy like mission figs from our normal “American” grocery store. Dates – 850 grams (nearly 2 lbs) of natural dates. These are like candy. Less than a week later, we have nearly finished them! Chapatti – in a recloseable package that allows you to take the flat bread from the freezer directly to a pan. The package says, “ready to puff”! 
 
Instant chappati just 0.99
 
Other highlights:

 green onions at 4 bunches /$1.00 yellow onions 5 pounds/$1.00 fresh ginger&amp;garlic at 79 cents per pound Flavor packets – make it easy to have Indian food. – Be ready to convert grams to oz.
 
The real deal: spice mixes for chicken and chickpea curry, and a vegetable spice mix.
 Tetley Chai tea is delicious–less obvious than the Starbuck’s variety. Lentils and beans $2.99 per 4 lbs of dried beans. We picked up two bags. 
 
Basmati rice, lentils and other delights!
 
All this and more…for just $65.00.

 http://patelbros.com/ 

Patel Brothers have several stores across the country. Their closest location is at 2610 West Devon Avenue, Chicago, IL.

 Sukhadia 
 
The facade of Sukhadia&apos;s only hints of the sugar-high waiting inside. Photo courtesy of Google maps.
 
After shopping, we were ready for a break. We headed to a favorite snack place…Sukhadia. Their counter is a big u-shape. One side with sweets and the other with savory pastries. In the middle is Mr. Sukhadia at the cash register. It always seems busy; several people paying at the same time–money changing hands. Since I don’t speak any of the languages of India, I just smile and bob deferentially!
 
A sample package of sweets from Sukhadia -- some of these sweets are made with flour from chickpeas and lentils and, from the taste, quite a bit of honey!
 
Sukhadia is at 2559 West Devon Avenue, Chicago, IL 60659.

 Sukhadiasweetschicago.com 

I hope you can visit our part of the world. Have a great weekend!
 
Share this:
 
 Twitter Facebook Pinterest 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. Filed under Chicago and tagged Chicago , Chicago Transit Authority , City Walk , Devon Avenue , India , International Foods , Low-cost | 1 Comment 
About Cathy Turley
I am a graphic designer, writer, quilter and knitter. 

I&apos;m currently looking for a new design position-- ideally that would allow me to combine all these interests! View all posts by Cathy Turley » 
Post navigation
 Previous Post Next Post 
One Response » 

 lilrongal on March 19, 2012 at 11:33 am said: 
These posts are so great! And the guy on the bus! Ha ha ha ha! I hardly ever hear things like that’cause I am usually listening to my iPod. Maybe I should unplug sometimes.
 Reply↓ 
 
Interact! Let me know what you think about this post! Thanks! -Cathy Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 

 Notify me of new posts via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 
Past posts
 Select Month June 2012 (1) May 2012 (1) April 2012 (3) March 2012 (3) February 2012 (4) January 2012 (4) 
 Follow Me! 
 
Enter your email address to receive notifications of new posts by email.

Join 33 other followers

 

 
 
I’m glad you stopped by!

 
 
Categories
 Select Category Book Review  (4) Chicago  (2) Crafts  (4) Green Living  (1) Home decor  (2) How-to  (3) Movie Review  (1) Quilting  (4) Sewing  (4) Store Review  (1) 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 (1) May 2012 (1) April 2012 (3) March 2012 (3) February 2012 (4) January 2012 (4) 
What I write about…
 Advertising Apple cider vinegar Artist: Leia Bell beauty Bust Chicago City Walk color green Colors Crafts Debbie Stoller Design Ideas DIY Doll clothes Dolls Essential oil Fiber Arts Food storage Free Grandmother Green How-to Inspiration Inspriational Knitting Lakeview in Chicago Leftovers Lincoln Park Local Shops Low-cost Memory Lane Non-fiction Notions Quilt Quilting Sewing Sewing Kit Sew Katie Did Blog skin care Stitch &apos;n Bitch Threads Toner Tutorial Using Scraps window display Search for: Blog at WordPress.com . | Theme: Matala by Nicolo Volpato . Follow 
 Follow“Cathy Turley” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



Join 33 other followers

 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
