<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001330" url="http://dirtydiningblog.wordpress.com/about/" time="2012-07-12-16:49" support="19" score="0.031045281028416614" bingtitle="About « Jeff Weinsier&apos;s Dirty Dining Blog" webtitle="AboutJeff Weinsiers Dirty Dining Blog">
			<query id="000018" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000131" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="000627" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000651" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000655" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="000127" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000379" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000643" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="000141" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="000286" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="000005" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="001414" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000564" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="001412" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="000630" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000644" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="000566" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000638" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="000144" bing-rank="167"/>
	<description>Plus, by the condiments and plasticware area, there ... he told me it’s because I was using my credit card! ... This fast food restaurant is always dirty, stinky, most of the ...</description>
	<body>
		Jeff Weinsier&apos;s Dirty Dining Blog 
 Local 10&apos;s Dirty Dining reporters is on the case in Miami-Dade and Broward counties. 
 Home About 
 
About
 
Jeff Weinsier has created a public service for Miami-Dade and Broward county diners with his Dirty Dining segments on WPLG-TV Local 10. His segments, and now his blog, keep restaurant owners and managers on their toes. Dirty Dining is community journalism, serving the people.
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 


90 Responses

 
Jeff,

I love that you expose dirty restaurants.
You have Shipwreck listed as in Miami.
THAT’S WRONG. Its in Ft.Lauderdale.
I don’t want them saying to patrons,
“hey that was Shipwreck in Miami, not us…”
Please correct your list ASAP.
Thank you
 Vinnie StJohn - May 22, 2008 at 4:55 pm Reply 
 
Jeff,
Thank you for exposing these dirty restaurants. Does anyone know what the law is about food preparers wearing gloves? I went to the Burger King at 20505 Old Cutler Rd. last Friday and noticed that the food preparers were not wearing gloves. This guy was placing the patties and cheese (removing the cheese slices with his fingernail) on the buns without gloves. The lady on the other side had just emptied out two garbage cans by the counters and simply just went back to work on the line without wearing gloves or washing her hands. I asked the manager why they were not wearing gloves and he simply said“We don’t have to”. Of course I left and will NEVER patronize another BK again.
 e. torres - August 24, 2009 at 1:18 am Reply 
 
they have to wear gloves when you deal with the garbage and you have to wash your hands to protect the customer from geting sick
 manny - June 25, 2010 at 9:35 pm 
 
 
wHAT’S THE POINT OF LISTING FOOD AREAS THAT HAD CITATIONS MORE THAN A YEAR AGO. nOTE 2006/2007.
 LARRY - June 14, 2008 at 3:38 am Reply 
Dear Jeff,

Would you please check out the restaurants in the Homestead area. ex. WhiteLion, Royal Palm Drugstore Rest. Guilloto, Genesis, LA Casita, Taco Toro, Sams Country Kitichen, Marios Cuban Cruisine, and many more take your pick. You will find some interesting results.
 rosemary fuller - June 20, 2008 at 6:13 am Reply 
 
Please have someone check the Church’s Chicken at 560 NW 7th ave, Ft Lauderdale, FL 33311. Roach and Rodent infested. It is a shame what kind of cross-contamination is going on in a restauraunt. This is an old facility and it has too many equipment promblems that is contributing to unsanitized cooking. Please hurry and check this place before someone finds themself in the hospital.
 Hurry - July 16, 2009 at 9:16 pm Reply 
 
PLEASE HAVE SOMEONE CHECK Doris Italian Market&amp;Bakery Pembroke Pines on Palm and Pines. The market is dirty, food spoiled, coolers broken and it is generally unsanitary
 Liz Munroe - June 21, 2008 at 10:47 am Reply 
ANYONE THAT LIVES CLOSE TO AVENTURA OR HALLANDALE BEWARE WERNER STAUBS RUNS RESTURANTS THAT ARE NOT UP TO PAR. THE PEPPERMILL IS FULL OF CORNER CUTTING, HIRING ILLEGALS AND CHEATING CUSTOMERS.
HE ALSO ONCE ONWNED LAPOLOMA IN MIAMI BUT I BELIEVE LOST TO BANK.
HE OWNS WINE CELLAR IN HALLANDALE, I HAVE SEEN MANY RATS, ONE RAN INTO MY LEG WHILE WORKING ATLEAST A POUND OU TWO.. THE KITCHEN STAFF HAS KILLED ATLEAST 42 RATS THAT I AM AWARE OF, NOT TO MENTION THE FIND THE OVEN A WARM PLACE TO BREED.
HE HAS 42 VIOLATIONS AT PEPPERMILL THIS MAN DOES NOT CARE ABOUT PUBLICS WELLBEING. JUST MONEY. I HAVE HIS OWN DVR VIDEO SHOWING SATFF KICKING RATS IN ALLEY.
FOR YOUR SAFTERY DONT EAT THERE!!!!
 CHRIS - June 28, 2008 at 2:38 pm Reply 
Please have someone check out the Chicken Kitchen at 15053 S Dixie Hwy in miami. I decided to eat in there yesterday for a change instead of take out and was disgusted and appalled to see at how dirty the restaurant was. Plus, by the condiments and plasticware area, there were a million little bugs flying around. If this is the way they keep the area where the customers eat, I can’t even begin to imagine how the food preparation area is kept, or what it is like in the back behind closed doors. It is a real shame that the management,if there is any, can’t take care of a small neighborhood chicken restaurant. Thanks
 Joanne - July 12, 2008 at 4:42 am Reply 
Hello.Love your segment. I went to Tony the Pizza Chef on Saturday and ordered chicken wings. When I opened the box there were roach legs inside and dead roaches inside! Yuk! I complained to the owner by cell and he said there was nothing that he could do. They had“changed”the oil on Friday and that was all he could do! Could you do a segment on this restaurant? Tony’s I 3806 S. Ocean Drive Hollywood,Fl. It’s right on the corner of Hallandale Beach Blvd and S.Ocean Dr.

Many thanks to you. Keep up the good work!
Adria
 Adria - July 21, 2008 at 7:32 am Reply 
TODAY MY BOYFRIEND AND I ATE AT“TEX MEX CAFE”ON 120TH STREET SW 117 AVE IN KENDALL FOR LUNCH. I WAS SITTING AT A TABLE AGAINST THE WALL. AS WE WAITED FOR OUR FOOD WE NOTICED FLYS AROUND US..WE JUST SWOSHED THEM AWAY, NO BIG DEAL….BUT…JUST WHEN THE WAITER BROUGHT MY FOOD I LOOKED AT THE WALL AND THERE WAS A“GERMAN ROACH”(I THINK IT’S CALLED A GERMAN ROACH, IT WAS MEDIUM SIZE, NOT TOO SMALL AND NOT A BIG ONE) I WAS SOOOO DISGUSTED!!!! I THINK THE WAITER NOTICED THAT I WAS MORTIFIED BUT HE WALKED AWAY AND DIDN’T SAY ANYTHING. I MOVED MY SEAT AND SAT AWAY FROM THE WALL, BUT I WAS SICK TO MY STOMACH THE ENTIRE DAY….SOMEONE REALLY NEEDS TO DO SOMETHING ABOUT THAT PLACE!!!
 Nancy - July 26, 2008 at 5:29 pm Reply 
I enjoy your blog and even have it on my Yahoo page.

I would like to suggest that you also highlight restaurants that get exceptionally good inspections as well. I think they deserve the attention for maintaining a healhy environment.
 KCK - July 30, 2008 at 2:29 am Reply 
might want to check out this one in miami beach. its a chinese food restaurant by 41st and alton road
this is how they wash and dry their veggies in the back alley
 http://tinyurl.com/59y8pa 
on boxes in the back alley underneath telephone poles with pigeons sitting on the wires
you look into the kitchen from the back alley and it looks disgusting. i dont work up that way any more but i think its called yeungs chinese and its right on the corner.
ive showed that picture to alot of people but no one seems to care.
 cixel - July 31, 2008 at 3:51 am Reply 
CHECK OUT CIELITO LINDO RESTAURANTS ONE IS IN
POMPANO BEACH AND THE OTHER OAKLAND PARK.
 MARIA - August 4, 2008 at 2:21 am Reply 
 
i also ate at celito lindo on preospect road and got FOOD poisioning. i love it there, but will not go back.
 antonio - March 29, 2010 at 12:07 pm Reply 
 
Jeff,

Have you ever done any serious journalism or do you only recite what’s available on the websites of state agencies?

Spencer
 Spencer Frank - August 11, 2008 at 5:45 am Reply 
Hi Jeff:

I would like to see a future report on The Samurai Restaurant on South Dixie Hwy and S.W. 136th St in Miami, I think it will be interesting for viewers.

Thank you for your great public service.
 Maria Diaz-Santiago - August 14, 2008 at 5:14 pm Reply 
SPENCER….
WHAT’S YOUR PROBLEM? YOU OBVIOUSLY HAVE AN ISSUE WITH JEFF…
I’M JUST HAPPY THAT AFTER MY BLOG REGARDING TEX MEX…4 DAYS LATER THEY WERE CLOSED DOWN!!!! THEY OBVIOUSLY DESERVED IT!!
KEEP YOUR PLACE CLEAN AND YOU WONT HAVE TO DEAL WITH JEFF, DON’T BLAME HIM FOR YOUR LACK OF RESPONSIBILITY TO THE PEOPLE WHO PUT MONEY IN YOUR POCKET…EASY AS THAT!!
 Nancy - August 18, 2008 at 1:46 pm Reply 
Nancy—it’s a simple question and maybe one day Jeff will answer it.
 Spencer - August 19, 2008 at 4:23 am Reply 
Spencer, Thanks for reading this blog continuously
and making it so successful.
 jweinsier - August 19, 2008 at 6:00 am Reply 
Direct link

 http://dirtydiningblog.wordpress.com/ 
 Kris - August 20, 2008 at 12:52 am Reply 
I was reading you article about Mr. M’s and how it is illegal to charge for credit card use. And it reminded me of something that upset me the other day. I was at the Hess gas station on US1 across from South Broward High School; at the time the sign stated $3.79 a gallon for regular, when I inserted my credit card to pay for the gas the price changed to $3.89 per gallon. When I asked the store clerk why the pricing was different, he told me it’s because I was using my credit card! I left and went to the gas station down the street. Does this law also apply to the gas station?
 Susie - August 22, 2008 at 2:22 am Reply 
I know this is not a dining business, bust theres a nail salon on SW 67 ave and 8 st that charges $2.00 per transactions. Im not sure if this is legal but I think its not right.
 H&gt;G - August 25, 2008 at 11:42 am Reply 
Ever do a check in Hollywood?
Start with
Mama Mia’s on Young Circle. Besides hiring every illegal, it’s a mess.
 chauncey - August 26, 2008 at 9:39 am Reply 
Jeff Weinsier, I appreciate your level of reporting. You are NOT afraid to ask the right questions and to probe. The one story that stands out for me the most is the one of the road rage killing of“a customs”agent. When I first heard the story break, before I saw your report I immediately suspected a cover up by the police. Normally they would be overjoyed to leak out how the“none law enforcement”civilian did this or that. They were very evasive and still are, so I suspected the story had allot more to it. Then I saw your report. You asked very specific questions of law enforcement. The lack of cooperation to me tells it all. I do not advocate death, naturally. But just because a law enforcement person was killed does not mean that the agent was a victim automatically. Everyone has a boiling point…I think the truth is now coming out slowly. but not after the other person was tried in the media by law enforcement. The level of“we will find the guy”was over the top. If it is a citizen, law enforcement does not go to the same extreme, setting up a vast command center 24/7. That has and always bothers me because actions speak louder than words. A police officer sworn to uphold and protect the citizen gets more attention than the citizens they have sworn to protect. Thank you so much for being who you are. Keep asking the questions that are on the viewers minds.
 Louis West - August 30, 2008 at 4:58 pm Reply 
I have to agree with Chauncey. Mama Mia’s is a mess. You should do a review of the hollywood area. Mainly that restaurant. I had eaten there in early august with some co-workers and had the most vile experience. There was a german roach on the table. The waitress used the excuse of the table were just brought inside. But the next day after we left i had taken left overs from the restaurant an there was a dead roach in my food. The nasty part is that the i personally put the food from my plate into the container at the restaurant. I used the link from your page and filed a complaint. They did the investigation and found 12 critical violations and 4 non critical. the did a follow up investigation the next day and they had none. Yeah ok. The cleaned up a roach infestion overnight. OK!! The Hollywood Young circle would be the ideal place for a review this week. If one restaurant could be so nasty imagine the others next to it.
 Nina - September 3, 2008 at 2:48 am Reply 
Jeff-
I have never seen a report on the restaurants in Coconut Grove. With it being such a popular dining area, I’d be curious to see what you find.
Thanks and keep up the good work!
 R. - September 4, 2008 at 9:12 am Reply 
Jeff- Please look into the MANY resturants in the JMH area. Especially the“chinese”ones.
Also the Publix on SW 7th St and SW 3rd Ave….Bakery frequently has flies in baked goods case.
 Amy - September 5, 2008 at 5:05 am Reply 
Hi Jeff,
Great work with the blog. I’m not so happy that I finally read this. You definitely are providing a very important service to the public, and, to the restaurants that you are reporting on. This is particularly true even for those who have many violations. Time to clean up!!! Nevertheless, I think I’ll be eating at home a little more often.
Keep up the good work!!!!!
 Scott Fineman - September 14, 2008 at 4:00 pm Reply 
I am extremely grateful for your information, as many times you have listed an establishment I was considering visiting.

However, every once in a while, as previously suggested, it would be nice to see comments on restaurants that have passed inspections and are acceptable eating establishments.
 I. - September 17, 2008 at 5:37 am Reply 
Jeff, can you please check the chinese restaurant call China Cafe is located at 4174 East 4th Avenue in Hialeah.
I frequently eat but I think something is going on in the kitchen. I just want to make sure that is no roach activity or rodent activity there.
I am very grateful for this information on Local 10
Thanks
Carmen
 carmen - September 23, 2008 at 11:20 pm Reply 
My wife and I visited the Pollo Tropical in homestead on South Dixie Hwy last night and ordered 3 wraps, one of which was a chicken wrap. We came home and I was shocked to find a good size metal shaving in the wrap. When I tried to calling the restaurant and speak to the manager there was no one available and when I called the main office all I got was a recording. I would appreciate you bringing this issue to light as I believe someone could be seriously hurt if they swallow a metal shaving. Feel free to contact me if necessary via email and I will provide you with a phone number. By the way when I called channel 7 to tell them about the incident they didn’t seem very interested at all. Maybe you have to be sent to the hospital before any action is take !

Thank You
-Artie Ayala-
Miami
 Artie Ayala - October 4, 2008 at 8:11 am Reply 
I recently placed an order through the drive-thru at the Burger King on NW 7st and 37th Avenue. I paid at the first window and proceeded to the pick up window. While I waited for the food, which was taking some time I looked through the window at the person preparing the Wrap and the Whopper I ordered. Guess what…the person was not wearing any gloves–not even to pick up the lettuce or the meats. I asked for my money back and explained the reason why I wanted my money back to the girl who took the order. Her response was“It is not me, it is the way the Company works”. I got my money back from the Manager all the while the person continued to prepare the sandwiches without gloves. No apologies explanations or anything from the Manager!
 Betty - October 6, 2008 at 5:18 am Reply 
Check Cafe de Paris on Las Olas EVERY MORNING at 10am. They come out the alley entrance to the kitchen (this door is never closed—alley cats, bugs have free access) and load pastries into the back of a waiting SUV. The pastries are NEVER covered—and the car is parked 2 feet away from a filthy dumpster in the most disgusting alley you have ever smelled. Well, maybe not. This turns my stomach every morning: dumpster-fresh flies taste-testing all those fancy french pastries…I have photos…
 Anne - October 15, 2008 at 12:42 pm Reply 
Jeff

Visit Tropics restaurant on Wilton Drive in Wilton Manors. Having been in the f&amp;b business for 25 yrs generally a bathroom is a indicator of the cleanliness of the kitchen and this place fails miserably.

The whole place needs a pressure washing and disinfecting along with some of the worse bar odor.

Thanks

Bob
 Bob Hansel - October 19, 2008 at 4:05 am Reply 
Please bring your cameras to Le Tub–thse people are dirty -dirty -dirty—- even their wait staff is dirty, there is these rude russian waitress that looks like she just came out of a brothel.

HOURS: 12:00pm to 4:00am
OPEN: Daily weather permitting.

1100 N. Ocean Drive
Hollywood, Florida 33019
954-921-9425
 Carmen Sanchez - October 21, 2008 at 3:53 am Reply 
The Olive Garden in Plantation on University has extremely dirty and moldy vents in the ceiling. I pointed it out to the manager and he said it was just an eye sore and I told him it was an issue of cleanliness. He talked over me (he didn’t appreciate anyone pointing it out) and said good bye. The air vent was so badly covered that it went out over a large part of the ceiling. The place needs to be looked into. I don’t want to eat there until it is cleaned.
 Jennifer - November 4, 2008 at 2:58 am Reply 
Please check out Canton Chinese Restaurant on Cypress in Pompano Beach. They have roaches crawling on their walls. Also, the place is filthy!!!! Should be seriously considered before someone gets sick!
 Missy - November 15, 2008 at 2:52 pm Reply 
Please check Joy’s Roti Shop in Lauderhill. The place is not sanitary. They do not have a sink for their employees to wash their hands
 Z - November 24, 2008 at 10:09 am Reply 
You need to check out the Golden Corrals in Pompano and off commercial. The food that is layed out looks old and looking at the inspections they are failing. The public needs to know whats going on there
 K - December 22, 2008 at 4:00 am Reply 
Was at South China Resturant this evening in Cooper City at the Countryside Shoppes on Flamingo road and found BUGS in my rice. The waiter said they were not bugs but spice. I asked for the manager and he said he was and for me to leave. I assured him that spice does not have legs. As I was leaving I made sure the other people in there knew what was happening. Most followed me out and will not return. Please do something about this. I would like to see this place get what it deserves, SHUT DOWN!!!
 Bruce N. - December 29, 2008 at 4:09 pm Reply 
I like what you are doing. I have one question for you, are you able to give me a list of Resturants that are up to code in the Miami and Fort Lauderdale.
 Amc - January 21, 2009 at 6:38 pm Reply 
My mom is going to kill me for this because It’s her favorite restaurant, but we went to The Lobster House in Tamarac (I think) and as soon as we walked in and looked at the lobster tank we were ready to hurl. The green color reminded me of the turtle bowl I had as a kid that I never cleaned.Also my sister noticed as the waitress was cleaning off the table she used the napkins that the previous customers used on their faces. If you check it out let me know. Maybe you shouldn’t tell me my gag reflex has just stopped.Thanks
 shelley finkelstein - January 29, 2009 at 5:57 am Reply 
 
Shelley, I totally agree with you!! The Lobster House is located in Sunrise (Pine Island Rd. and Oakland Park Blvd.) one first look and we turned back. There was this guy that I think is one of the owners was totally rude when we decided to leave–you should investigate this restaurant.
 Maria - July 28, 2009 at 2:24 am Reply 
 
Would appreciate you check/inspect Bougainvillea Bar/Restaurant in South Miami, I believe address is 7225 SW 58 Ave.

The past few times I’ve been there the glass or dishwashing and outside area is filthy and though I have never ordered food there, I’m thinking of never going again even for drinks.

Thank you.
 Diana - February 13, 2009 at 11:05 am Reply 
Unfortunately, while having my birthday party on November 19, 2008 at Lemongrass Restaurant we were appauled that a rat had crawled up someone’s leg. We were sick about it and will never go back. In fact, we had six girls all together–I can assure you that six couple will no longer be dining at Lemongrass.
 Pam - February 19, 2009 at 5:12 pm Reply 
Dear Mr. Weinsier:

Yesterday, March 13, 2009, I went to Dragon Village Chinese Take-Out Resturant located at 5567 W. Oakland Park Blvd., Lauderhill, FL. It was about 11:35am and I wanted a quick meal. After ordering from their Express Menu I noticed small black dots on the stand which the fax machine was located. I asked the cashier“Sir, what is that on the counter?”He immeidately got irrate and started screaming and saying very bad words to me. He even stated he could refuse to service me and gave back my money. In addition, he called me a black bitch and said I must be the police and never come back.

After I left the store/resturant a customer was waiting outside and asked if I was fighting with another customer. I stated no and expalined with had happen. This customer first name is James and he provided me with his telephone number and stated I needed to report Dragon Village, because I had every right to ask what was on the counter.

It look like rat droppings and because the cashier got so emotional it probably was rat droppings.

How can I report this and to whom?

Carolyn
 Carolyn Evans - March 14, 2009 at 9:06 am Reply 
Jeff hasn’t interviewed anybody for years, they all just run&amp;hide when they see him coming.
 Spencer - March 20, 2009 at 2:50 am Reply 
Many people travel thru Terminal 1 at the Ft Lauderdale Airport. I saw today one of the filthiest Dunkin Donuts, with trash on counters and floors, open fridge and workers wiping their nose, handling money and not washing hands, nor wearing gloves while selecting food items. Secondly the only good restarurant named Island Grill was also very dirty. Fries, food, trash on the ground and long lines of people…(not sure why…B/C only place after security). Would be great to get a story on this place considering the Broward County Aviation Department owns the building. Certainly the issues are with the contracted company who runs the food services! Not the welcoming or“Thanks for visiting”that FLL deserves!!

 http://www.naturescapebroward.com/airport/airport_map_level1_terminal1.htm 
 Jeff - March 29, 2009 at 2:36 pm Reply 
What happened to the list of closures by county and the links to the videos?
 Miranda Quo - April 7, 2009 at 9:57 am Reply 
Spencer:

Either you own a filthy restaurant or you are a frustrated journalist“wanna-be”……..

Jeff’s coverage has been a blessing for those who eat out!

Jeff: Keep it up……
 Frank - April 14, 2009 at 3:52 am Reply 
Frank: Keep guessing—even a blind squirrel finds an acorn once in a while.
 Spencer - April 20, 2009 at 7:14 am Reply 
Spencer: I guessed right! LOL two for two
 Frank - April 20, 2009 at 7:19 am Reply 
You need to check out Don Burrito on Sunset and 102
 Mike - April 28, 2009 at 5:51 am Reply 
You should goto Sukhothai in Fort Lauderdale…checkout their Health Department Inspection…GROSS!!

26 Critical and 18 Not Critical!!

 https://www.myfloridalicense.com/inspectionDetail.asp?InspVisitID=3526526&amp;id=2144434 
 FoodMan - May 12, 2009 at 1:13 am Reply 
Jeff,
Did any one inspect BIG FISH at 55 SW Miami Ave. Road Miami, Fl 33130. If any inspector visited this Eatery/Bar and didn’t sight them for a whole host of violations, they are either On The Take or Just Didn’t Look. This place is is the arm pit of Brickell. Off the beaten path and hard to find, obviously overlooked. Have the city of Miami Code Inforcement to include Building code inforcement, Health code inspectors, OSHA and Fire Code inforcement check this place. I guarentee they will shut this place down! Please, Please have this inspected. Shut Down this Brickell Blight! Fire inspectors; They still keep the Fire exits Chained and locked shut. What ever agency enforces water polution, they are still pumping raw sewage into the Miami River.
 Dave - May 17, 2009 at 2:05 am Reply 
Love what you do and couldn’t thank you enough; if it’s even you who reads this…I think your page could use a lot of work, hate to be such a critic, but it’s very hard to find and not as amped up as it could be, in my opinion. Try a zip code search bar, where one has the option to see what around him has been cited. Food for thought I guess. I figured instead of telling you another place to go inspect or have inspected, i’de offer a message that could help you out, or atleast your site.
 Marc F - June 4, 2009 at 5:22 pm Reply 
Marc F—Try this State of Florida website which is where all these reports (minus photos of Jeff getting thrown out) are coming from

 https://www.myfloridalicense.com/wl11.asp?mode=1&amp;SID=&amp;brd=H&amp;typ= 

SPENCER
 Spencer - June 23, 2009 at 7:16 am Reply 
Dear Jeff,
You may want to look into El Toro Taco located on Krome Ave. in Homestead. Currently there is an article in Miami New Times titled“Death and Tacos”. They were cited in January with 53 violations and more than 30 were“critical”Take a look at that article, very scarry!!!
 Rebecca - June 27, 2009 at 6:36 am Reply 
Golden Corral Buffet in Pembroke Pines….NASTY, DIRTY, DIRTY FLOORS, FILTHY, DIRTY BATHROOMS AND CARPETS….PLEASE PLEASE PLEASE CHECK THEM OUT…NOT TO MENTION DISGUISTING FOOD
 Nay - June 29, 2009 at 4:27 pm Reply 
Hungry Bear, across the street from Miami Dade Kendall campus, charges a service fee for all credit card/check card transactions. It’s really annoying.
 Robert - July 14, 2009 at 3:38 pm Reply 
i want people to know if they want to experience disgusting,foul, ill treated dining feel free to go to mott street chinese resturant. your pork fried rice must be refried at least 10 times a day the employees there are nasty and rude and the rest. should be invesigated for food violations and emploment violations. jeff if i were you this rest. should be our next case!!!!!
 lucy - July 14, 2009 at 3:45 pm Reply 
Was eating a chicken at a rotissery chicken on 805 north state road 7 in the city of hollywood in broward county ,when a roach showed up in my table ,I jump discusted and accidentally nock down the soda and pretty much lost my appetite the ownwer was not very understandable and it seems he did not care, had some kind of attitude also,so I ask for the check and the waitress pick up the silverware and put it back on the table ,I was discusted , pay and left. I wish you could send a health and food inspector to this place and put them up to code!!!.thank you for providing a good service.
 john duran - July 28, 2009 at 6:28 am Reply 
pls look into tony chan at tony chan’s water club. he is offering $$$ to rescue groups to cook their cats and dogs. says it is common practice in china.
 Sara Gutierrez - August 3, 2009 at 7:12 am Reply 
 
That is horrific to read.

I wonder if“Tony Chans”is also paying people for horsemeat to add to his“gourmet”menu.

I’m hoping that the rescue groups tell him where to go but for the horses left in pastures that don’t have any protection and are left to fend for themselves when their owners aren’t present.

I pray that they catch these killers and hope that whoever eats the horsemeat (knowingly) gets violently ill due to the medications that are used on horses and specifically state“not for use on livestock to be consumed by humans”.

It has to be some third world country type of establishment doing this. Someone has to go undercover to find the killers and their enablers.
 suzi - January 2, 2010 at 3:58 am Reply 
 
Jeff
I want the people beware about La Carreta Restaurant at Bird Road in Miami. My family and I went to that restaurant for dinner last July 30th, we all became ill right at night,the worse was underwent by my son. It was the most horrible experience; spending all night and the next day trying to recover from such conditions.Last Sunday my wife knew of same incident happening to couple we have met there. I already reported this to the proper authorities. I hope they correct this for other people not to suffer this nightmare

Mike
 Mike Sanchez - August 4, 2009 at 5:25 pm Reply 
Please go see“All’n One”right on West Flagler ST and 83 Ave; located in the same shopping center where there’s a Publix, Office Depot, etc. This fast food restaurant is always dirty, stinky, most of the times with water everywhere on the floor, the bathrooms are really nasty and disgusting. Today was the last day I visited that place, the smell was horrible and had to leave. Please go ahead and give them a visit soon!!!!!!
 J. Hernandez - August 15, 2009 at 12:30 pm Reply 
The newly opened COLD STONE CREAMERY on Alton Rd. at Lincoln does not have any hot water. Please inform me how to report this to the proper authorities.
 Vivian Renolds - August 16, 2009 at 11:26 am Reply 
Please check Bonjour Bakery on 17th street in Fort Lauderdale. Went there for breakfast yesterday. Found a dead roach in my quiche. Totally disgusitng! Also, so a roach crawling on the wall by the kitchen when I was gettting my money back.
 sherry - August 30, 2009 at 2:56 am Reply 
Please have someone check Siam Bistro on 7348 Sw 117th Ave
Miami, FL. I was there last week and my food was served with an orange and an umbrella in it as decoration. Some friends were meeting us much later so we decided to mark the umbrella with a pen to see if it would be served to one of our friends. To my amazement, it was reused in one of our friends meal. Imagine what else they recycle. They don’t know if I picked my teeth or nails with it. This was nasty. I will never go here again.
 Margie - September 3, 2009 at 9:34 am Reply 
hi jeff, thanks for your helpful investigations!

please check the taco rico on US1, just south of Ponce Blvd in Miami…last time I was there there were flies and gnats in the juicers and on and around that tables…

also, please check Big Fish in Brickell on the river.

Last but not least, can you please check a supermarket/lunch cafe called“la virgen de la caridad supermarket”? its on the corner of SW 17th avenue and 14 street in miami. it looks super dirty!
 anabel - September 28, 2009 at 6:32 pm Reply 
DEAR JEFF…
YOU THINK YOU HAVE SEEN IT ALL?? PLEASE GO TO SHORTY’S ON US1 (DADELAND BLVD.) THE KITCHEN IS OPEN FOR EVERYONE TO SEE WHILE YOU EAT…ALL THE MALE COOKS WEAR THEIR PANTS LOW, YOU CAN SEE UNDERWEAR, BEACH RUBBER SLIPPERS, LONG HAIR (DREADLOCKS)NO NETS..SPILLED FOOD ON THE FLOOR,COOKED FOOD NEXT TO CONTAINERS WITH RECENTLY COLLECTED DIRTY PLATES,ETC….
I LOVE THEIR FOOD, BUT CAN’T BEAR TO WATCH WHAT GOES ON THERE..
THANKS…
CRISTINA
 cristina - October 6, 2009 at 10:18 am Reply 
I am amazed at all the responses…”please check out this filthy restaurant…etc, etc.”Do any of you have anything better to do? Yes, I have been in the restaurant business since I was 15 yrs. old and I have seen it all and I am still living to tell about it. Let me ask a question..do any of you purchase food from supermarkets? Do you wash your hands everytime you get out of your car from touching your stirring wheel? Do you wash your hands after you handle money? Those two things alone will cause you to get sick. Granted there are restaurants that truly deserve to be closed or exposed, but most of them are caring contributors to your local economies and get cited for having a bottle of windex next to a prep table or cited for not washing their hands in between putting another pair of gloves on. And the roach activity? There is absolutely no excuse, but I have never worked in a restaurant that didn’t have them..sorry but that is the plain truth. We live in Florida people where we breed roaches along with those playful alligators. If the health inspectors see even one dead or alive they have the authority to close a restaurant down. The health inspectors do a great job, they really do, but let us not forget that the DBPR is a business too and the more citations or repeat violations the more money they make. There have been many times the health inspector would come in and not site for something, but then cite it the next time they come for their routine inspection. I think what is pathetic about Jeff (I agree with Spencer) is that there isn’t a positve flipside to this website or“investigative reporting.”He doesn’t mention that once a restaurant gets closed they have 24 hours til the health inspector will re-inspect the restaurant. 99% of the time that restaurant will re-open within that 24 hr. period b/c they did exactly what was asked of them. Regarding the roach problems the health inspector usually will not open a restaurant back up if they come back and still find roaches. He doesn’t report the restaurants that re-opened 24 hours later due to passing the re-inspection. So Jeff withholding this crucial information in his“investigative reporting”in this hard economic time does a disservice to the local businesses and hurts the local economy…but hey his paycheck doesn’t stop coming just b/c a restaurant he reports on closes…just ours! So, keep up the good investigative reporting, Jeff, I am sure CNN will be calling soon!
 Jackie - October 17, 2009 at 2:32 am Reply 
 
Who said“Dirty Dining”was Investigative?

Jeff Weinsier has created a public service for Miami-Dade and Broward county diners with his Dirty Dining segments on WPLG-TV Local 10. His segments, and now his blog, keep restaurant owners and managers on their toes. Dirty Dining is community journalism, serving the people.
 jweinsier - October 20, 2009 at 10:02 am Reply 
 
I can’t believe my reply was deleted…I can see Jeff can’t handle his devoted followers seeing the truth about his“investigative reporting.”Shouldn’t known…
 Jackie - October 17, 2009 at 2:23 pm Reply 
Jeff–thanks for putting my comment back up Now I don’t think that bad of you…you are doing a public service and exposing the restaurants that really deserve to be exposed, and for that the public and myself are very grateful, but for those restauarants(the ones you just list that you get off the DBPR website) that are in strip malls, are in a constant battle with other business owners and the landlord to keep bugs out….you would do a public service by reporting things like that. That is why 90% of free standing buildings are bug free….they are not ping ponging it with other tenents. Roaches don’t just eat“dirty kitchens”they love the glue that the boxes are held together with and are brought in every week when that restaurant orders its’food. Also, if a restaurant is in a strip mall with avacuum cleaner shop your“community journalism”should report that. Why? Go into your local vacuum cleaner place and ask them how many roaches come out of the canister vacuums when they open them up for repair…Again, I am not making excuses..I just see most of your dirty diners are closed due to roach activity and thought it would be a public service to give a little more information of other causes not just some fat, disgusting cook in the kitchen, picking his nose while he is scratching himself, sliding raw chicken under the oven over night….that is what most people think when they think of dirty restaurant kitchens, right? At least that is what I think of…then again, what do I know…I am just part of the public that your serving 
 Jackie - October 22, 2009 at 5:49 am Reply 
Please check out chinese garden at 1100 w broward blvd, fort lauderdale. It is unbelievable!!!!! You will not believe the place of business-inside and out!!!
 george - January 7, 2010 at 7:24 pm Reply 
I am so glad that there is someone informing the public of these nasty greedy restaurants. As far as I am concerned, once rodents and rodent contaiminated food is found, the restaurant should be shut down for good! These owners are knowingly serving food in conditions not fit for dogs!
 Tina - January 12, 2010 at 5:12 am Reply 
Jeff,

You should take a look at the The Lido Restaurant at the Standard 40 Island Avenue Miami Beach, FL 33139. I have heard that they are wiping down cups plates, spoons, forks, knives, etc with a cloth and giving it to guest. also there is a pre-cooked food for days before they serve.

i feel real bad for the people spending large amounts in this restaurant with out knowing what is really going on in the kitchen.

hope you visit soon before someone gets sick.
 Mike - January 18, 2010 at 5:38 pm Reply 
Yes I worked at 110 Bistro Tower at 110 SE 6th Street the old AutoNations Bldg.7th floor for 7 years and they have a rat problem in their kitchen it is an old kitchen they live in the ceiling.I would not recommend any body to eat their food because of this problem.Thanks Brad Jones
 Brad Jones - January 23, 2010 at 11:00 pm Reply 
Jeff: PLEASE PLEASE check out the East Fusion Buffet at 2101 N Univ Dr in Coral Springs next to Doris store. I was there today Tues w/a group of woman&amp;we just started eating when a roach ran across our table. We killed it&amp;called the waitress who didn’t know what we were talking about. We showed her the dead road&amp;she proceeded to take the napkin, but we stopped her as we wanted to show it to the mgr. One of the woman went to the mgr&amp;he came over&amp;we spoke to him about this. We told him we should be reciprocated for this. He went to the person in our group handling this. Not knowing what entailed, we then decided ok, so it happend. Upon getting another plate of food&amp;starting to eat again, another roach this one bigger ran again across our table (which we killed again)&amp;by then we jumped up&amp;refused to eat anymore&amp;again called the mgr. Some of the girls left the restarant. He came took the napkin away didn’t say anything&amp;went again to the same person to talk to her. Also, when we got our food, we told him it was ice cold. The hot food was cold&amp;he said“give it to the girl&amp;she will heat it up”What? This is not acceptable. We definitely will not eat there again. I have to call the girl that handled this&amp;see if anything was done about this. So that is our experience w/this East Fusion Buffet. I will tell everyone I know not to eat there.

This place should be shut down&amp;the Health Dept notified for another inspection. By the way the last inspection was done on 6/4/09&amp;they had 27 violations then. Sorry this is so long, but I had to follow up on this&amp;your the only one I know that gets results&amp;love the show.
 elaine - January 26, 2010 at 3:52 pm Reply 
Jeff,
has anyone been hospitalized when they store fish next to pasta in their fridge @ home…I have not…I don’t understand some of these violations.

Question: is it slander for someone to say not to eat somewhere specific and give negative details about a restaurant on your website before the health dept. has even written them up yet? anyone can make up anything about a place and post it on your web site with out any proof other than their word…I hope your readers remember that the negative comments posted could be coming from a worker who was upset they got fired for stealing or got laid off because of the economy and is trying to get back @ their former employer by making up some nonsense about being dirty and posting it without any official report from the DBPR…

I enjoy this website very much and it gives alot of good info but everyone needs to take the comments with a grain of salt..thank-you
 jerry - March 3, 2010 at 4:14 pm Reply 
CHECK THE POLLO TROPICAL ON U.S.1 IN CUTLER BAY. EMPLOYEE’S EATING IN COOKING/SERVING AREA. DEALING WITH MONEY AND FOOD, WITHOUT GLOVES
 D.ROULHAC - April 23, 2010 at 3:18 am Reply 
Maybe you should ask the Key West Citizen and local media why they do not publish these things. Are they under pressure from the Tourism&amp;Development Council to hush up? Thanks for keeping us informed.
 DJ Sticht - April 30, 2010 at 4:57 am Reply 
Can you please list a few of the CLEAN Chinese restaurants between North Miami and Hollywood. It seems very hard to find as most have violations. Thank you…Liane Beck
 LIANE BECK - June 17, 2010 at 10:19 am Reply 
Hi Jeff,

Can you please tell me the web address to actually check Restaurant inspections here in south florida? I used to have it as a bookmark on my prior laptop and cannot find it.

Thank you. Gerry
 Gerry Dinkin - June 18, 2010 at 10:45 am Reply 
Have you ever noticed how many restaurants (and other businesses) have the back door propped open for the convenience of employees who want to go out and smoke?

This can be a health risk and/or a security risk, letting bugs, rodents, and unauthorized people in.

I wonder if they wash their hands when they return, after leaning on the dumpster and sitting on discarded furniture or crates for 15 minutes.
 David - August 18, 2010 at 5:46 am Reply 
Jerry asks“has anyone been hospitalized when they store fish next to pasta in their fridge @ home?”

Maybe not. But ask a vegetarian or someone with a fish allergy what they think of it.
 David - August 18, 2010 at 5:50 am Reply 
you should really check out the johnny rockets in the center of coconut grove that place is disgusting. i have seen water come down from the ceiling tiles and all kinds of grossness!
 maggie - September 24, 2010 at 7:21 am Reply 
Hello,
I would like some action to be taken on a deliberate and malicious act of a restaurant manager at the LITTLE INDIAN RESTAURANT in Sunrise, Florida. My husband and I enjoy indian cuisine and went to this restuarant last Friday October 1, 2010. It was empty except for another couple who left before finishing their meal. While we were oredering our drinks the manager who overheard us talking to the lone waiter shouted with a smile,“Try the King Fisher beer, it’s an Indian beer, very good!”so we ordered two. Just as the waiter walked away we noticed that he and the manager looked at heach other and chuckled. I became very uneasy with this and when the waiter returned with our beers I cautiously poured mine in a glass and sipped. The taste was bad but I considered it to be the type of beer but then I held it up to the light and there were sediments in the bottle. I went to the kitchen door and called the waiter to the table and we showed him the beer. He stood there without a word looking at the bottle. We left. I then called the restuarant and spoke with the manager Mr. Singh who said he didn’t know anything about it and it was the waiters fault for packing bad product in the cooler. He then became defensive and said“So what do you want me to do?”. I guess he thought he could get rid of his stock by serving to unsuspecting patrons. This needs to be exposed, we could have been poisoned.
 Pam - October 4, 2010 at 5:10 am Reply 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
Categories

 Uncategorized (76) 
 
Archives

 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 
 
Meta

 Register Log in Valid XHTML XFN WordPress 
 
 
Theme: Day Dream by Jim Whimpey . Blog at WordPress.com .
 Follow 
 Follow“Jeff Weinsier&apos;s Dirty Dining Blog” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



Join 25 other followers

 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
