<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001349" url="http://www.sarnosrestaurant.com/index" time="2012-07-12-16:50" support="1" score="0.002557193028743461" bingtitle="Sarno&apos;s Restaurant | Great Italian Food | Friendly Atomosphere |" webtitle="Sarno&apos;s Restaurant | Great Italian Food | Friendly Atomosphere |">
			<query id="001142" bing-rank="51"/>
	<description>... of sitting at your grandmother’s bountiful table ... Tired of hitting the same fast food restaurant for lunch? ... Stop by for one of our famous specials or a cup of ...</description>
	<body>
		b See Our Menus 
 Breakfast 
 Lunch Call: 708-656-0797 
 
 
 Breakfast Menu Lunch Menu 
 
 Box Lunch Catering 
 60 Years of Experience 
 Breakfast, lunch or just a coffee; sit-down Italian meal or delicious take-out, Sarno&apos;s can delight your taste buds anytime. 
 
 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 SEE TESTIMONIALS  
 Tradition and Quality... 
 WE ARE CLOSED..... WE WILL 
 RE-OPEN MON JULY 16TH 
 THANK YOU
JAN&amp;ANTHONY SARNO 
 
 From Our Family To Yours 
 Happy Dining!
 Our family restaurant in Cicero, IL serves only the best culinary creations that we ourselves enjoy as a family. 

 BREAKFAST MENU / LUNCH MENU 
 ...With a Modern Flavor 
 

 Sarno’s Restaurant Takes Comfort Food to a Whole New Level of Culinary Delight! 

 Recreate some of your warmest childhood memories of sitting at your grandmother’s bountiful table eating fresh pasta with special Sunday gravy when you dine at Sarno’s Restaurant.  

 At Sarno’s, happy memories occur every day because our meals are created with the freshest ingredients, made the old fashioned way—with care and love. We never cut corners or skimp on quality. When you want a homemade breakfast or lunch made with the finest ingredients, come to Sarno’s Restaurant. 

 From our famous omelets and pancakes to our award winning house specials and authentic Italian pizza, Sarno’s Restaurant tantalizes your taste buds with every bite. Tired of hitting the same fast food restaurant for lunch? Come to Sarno’s for a taste of home and quality during your busy day. In fact if you are craving breakfast for lunch, we are one of the only restaurants in Cicero that serves breakfast until 3:30pm! 

 Sarno’s is also the #1 breakfast spot in Cicero, Illinois. Our Mediterranean spin on the classic American breakfast has made the morning meal at Sarno’s a weekly (and sometimes daily) thing for the locals. 

 The Sarno family invites you to dine with us Monday through Friday from 8:30am–3:30pm. We’ll deliver or call us for take-out at 708-656-0797. 

 Consider Sarno’s for your next celebration or event! 

 Proudly Celebrating 60 Years in Business—You Know we’re Doing Something Right! 

 Since 1954, Sarno’s Restaurant has been the #1 meeting and eating place in Cicero! Stop by for one of our famous specials or a cup of coffee and a smile! 

 Read More 
 
 

 RESTAURANT LOCATION : 5615 W. Roosevelt Road, Cicero, IL 60804 - Tel. 708-656-0797, Email: menu@sarnosrestaurant.com » SEE MAP 

 
 Home • Menu • Catering Menu • Contact Us • Site Map 
©2010 Sarno’s Restaurant. Created and Maintained by WSI .
	</body>
</document>
