<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001658" url="http://healthfood-guide.com/fastfood.aspx" time="2012-07-12-17:26" support="19" score="0.052047831648031735" bingtitle="Fast Food Effects On Health - Health Food Guide" webtitle="Fast Food Effects On Health - Health Food Guide">
			<query id="000720" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="000050" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000370" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="001123" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="001116" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000041" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000369" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="001443" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="001121" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="001515" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="001107" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000056" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000376" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001530" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="000363" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000354" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="001531" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001529" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="001524" bing-rank="124"/>
	<description>In today&apos;s age of convenience, fast food needs no introduction. Everyone from a 2 ... obesity is not simply an eyesore &quot;“ it is a major risk factor for a large number of ...</description>
	<body>
		Health Food Guide 

 Health Food For A Healthy Life Style 
 
 Tweet 
 
 
 
 Home Anti Aging Foods Diet and Exercise Programs Fast Food Effects On Health 
 On Childhood Obesity Fast Food Health Issues fast food and health prob Obesity&amp;Gum Disease 
 Dark Chocolate Health Benefits Healthy Food Gift Basket Mercury poisoning Tea | Tea Benefits Heart Healthy Foods Healthy Food Green Buildings New Food Pyramid Obesity Cure Addiction Food Health Whole Foods Food Nutrition Health food vitamin Health food diet Health Products Online Healthy Fakes Meat Labels - Truths And Healthy Oils Fruit&amp;Veggie Benefits Health Benefits Of Herbs Honey health benefits Resveratrol Health Supplement Healthy Snacks Vegan Food Probiotics Health Food Drink Health Benefits Of Mushro Healing Foods 
 
 
Fast Food Effects on Health
 In today&apos;s age of convenience, fast food needs no introduction. Everyone from a 2-year-old toddler to a 60-year-old grandpa seems to be enjoying it every chance they get. And why not? It&apos;s delicious, it&apos;s filling, is really affordable, and readily available just any time of the day, being only a drive through phone call away. What more can you ask for when you are living life in the fast lane? Well, plenty &quot;“ fast food is all good tasting, except that it is not nutritionally balanced and, therefore, unhealthy in the long run if consumed on a regular basis. Fast food is loaded with calories from refined sugar and fats (especially, the artery-clogging saturated and hydrogenated fats, which are repeatedly reheated to high temperatures for frying purposes). It is also very high in sodium, coming from common salt and other additives. On top of all this, fast food is deficient in dietary fiber and essential micro-nutrients like vitamins and minerals. To make matters worse, heaps of fast food are normally guzzled down with gallons of sugar-rich colas which many fast-food restaurants serve free with food as an incentive. To make a long story short, all this results in piling up of unused empty calories in the body, which get stored as body fat &quot;“ till one day you look in the mirror and realize that your great figure has been replaced by this creature in the mirror.

But that&apos;s not the end of the story, it&apos;s just the beginning. Consuming too much fast food not only turns a handsome guy into an unsightly obese man, but as Eric Schlosser points out in his book it is a big health hazard too.

And being physically inactive only adds to the problem of obesity. Not many people who love fast food are ready to acknowledge that obesity is not simply an eyesore. It is a major risk factor for a large number of deadly diseases like hypertension, diabetes, high cholesterol, heart disease, and even many types of cancers.

Recent scientific studies have shown that high-calorie foods rich in fats, refined sugar and salt could reconfigure the hormones in the body in such a way that they make you crave for such foods and always leave you asking for more.

In other words, fast food is kind of addictive; you get hooked on to it and continue consuming it in an uncontrolled way in spite of knowing that it is unhealthy. The more you consume, the more difficult it is for you to opt for healthy foods .

The situation is worse in case of children who from a very young age get hooked on fast food. Making them change their food habits from fatty and sweet foods and develop a taste for health-promoting fruits and vegetables is a task easier said than done. Such children would grow up to be obese adults who have never felt the advantages of being a healthy weight.

To sum up, consuming fast food on a regular basis leads to many health hazards. But bringing about changes in eating habits is not easy.

To start with, a simple change that one could make is to successively reduce the frequency of eating fast food and eat more frequently home-cooked food, with plenty of fresh foods and vegetables. 
If your a female there is a great free suport group called Diet Bug. They are there to encourage and help you.

 Slowly your taste will change and your body will respond with new found energy.That doesn&apos;t mean you can never have fast food again. All it means is that you cut the fast food way back. I still occasionally(once a month)will have my #1 at McDonalds. Big Mac Rules! 

 Sharing is Caring: 
 Tweet 


 
 
 
 Copyright © HealthFood-Guide.com All rights reserved.       Disclaimer - Privacy Policy - Contact
	</body>
</document>
