<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001464" url="http://diningout.blog.my/2011/04/how-much-do-you-tip-a-hibachi-chef-assuming-you-are-tipping-the-waiter-20-percent/" time="2012-07-12-17:14" support="2" score="0.004053652205883419" bingtitle="How much do you tip a hibachi chef assuming you are tipping the ..." webtitle="How much do you tip a hibachi chef assuming you are tipping the waiter 20 percent? | http://diningout.blog.my">
			<query id="000139" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000135" bing-rank="129"/>
	<description>... where the chefs cook right in front of you on the table called? What is your favorite fast food restaurant?→ ... mop, make training chopstick, fold hundreds of napkins ...</description>
	<body>
		http://diningout.blog.my 
Dining Out
 Skip to Content↓ 
 Contact Us 
 
How much do you tip a hibachi chef assuming you are tipping the waiter 20 percent?
 Apr 27th, 2011 by Guest . 
 Posted in: Dining Out . 
 Tagged: Hibachi · Tipping · Waiter 
 
 ← What are the resturants where the chefs cook right in front of you on the table called? What is your favorite fast food restaurant? → 
4 Comments

 hitchnj says: April 27, 2011 at 6:59 pm 
I usually give the hibachi chef $5-20 depending on the size of our group.. I tend to give wait staff the minimum tip since they don’t do much and we rarely get good service with the drink refills and such..
 Reply BLCOHEN529 says: April 27, 2011 at 6:59 pm 
I surmise and believe most waiters in Japanese restaurants with hibachi&quot;chefs&quot;divide tips. But that alone does not provide adequate recompense to the hibachi&quot;chef&quot;who is more an entertainer than a waiter or&quot;chef&quot;. What do you give a piano player who plays your favorite songs at your request or a singer doing the same. If you are asking for your special music, you are denying them an opportunity to perform for others. You need to pay for their time, trouble and talent.

I believe 15%-20% to the food server and the same for the&quot;chef&quot;depending upon your satisfaction levels.

Of course, I am a former food service employee from 40 years ago and still tend to tip heavily.
 Reply 
 jak says: June 4, 2011 at 4:09 pm 
Do NOT tip the chef extra without leaving a generous tip for the server! I work at a restaurant with a teppan grill, and we give the chefs 8.5% of the tips from hibachi sales. Between tipping the chef, bar, busser, sushi, hostess and kitchen, we take home less than 50% of our tips. There are occasions where we actually pay to wait on a table.
As for how much the server does, how is that much different from eating in a dining room? We don’t cook the food there either, the only difference is that we bring it to you. People don’t realize that in almost all restaurants the server is responsible for paying the salaries of almost everyone in the restaurant. The only difference is, if we get lousy service, we can’t refuse to tip out.
 Reply 
 Julie T says: July 19, 2011 at 5:42 am 
I had work at 2 hibachi Restaurant so far in Michigan on call Kobe and One call Fuji Yama.

Chef gets pay salary depending on their skills and if they are part time and full time. they get to keep any side tips if customer give to them. Server in other hand what ever we make we have to give chef 50% so sometime the Chef end up with 75% of the over all tips for that table basically chef get double tip time to time. Also there are customer out there who don’t think server did much because we don’t serve the main dish. Those are the customer who leave 10-15% tip or less with out knowing we spilt it. and if there is a bus person or a bartender 4-7% each and we get paid server wage not much and our check aren’t nothing after taxes. Customers think chef does all the work because the cook and do the show. Server does quite a bit to, We set the table restock, package, clean, sweep, mop, make training chopstick, fold hundreds of napkins, clean silver ware, refill soy sauce, drink, salt and pepper. peal pea pods and green bean. We also clean trays break down the pop machine refill the ice box, bar-tend if there no bartender, Make soup and salad, we have to know who is who and divide the tab correctly and make sure if there is any discount and take it off. so we have to have a good memory to run out food and appetizing clean up after the chef does there trick for example egg on the ground oil spill or sake mess, and if a chef is at the table the need something such as something they forgot or some more sauce for there cart As a server we go get it for them because they can’t just leave the table. all that good stuff that take time from server. chef don’t do it server does. Remember we only make about 35% to 40% of our overall night tips and only get pay server wage. remember we do all the side work. sometime customer don’t see and appreciated it. Do you think it is fair? Also if a family came in and only half order hibachi and the other half have Chinese or sushi. we still need to spilt half with chef even though it doesn’t relate to the chef at all. those are the item server bring out and ask questions about like choices of sides.
I am an honest person i help manage the other hibachi server. I make sure non of them still btw we go camera up and either I, the manager or the hostess bring up the tab so it hard for the server to pocket money. If the server bring it up they are monitor by someone.

Another thing i like to mention hibachi table can hold 8 to 12 people on a busy night chef are only cooking one table at time. For example there are 4 chef and 3 to 4 sever we have 10 hibachi table. do the math. server is server 2 to 3 time the customer. we have to make sure the waiting table are doing ok we have to time everything so consumer don’t wait extremely long we have to make sure to get drink soup salad appetizers napkin chop stick and all the little thing before chef comes to the table it a high pressure work place for a server. I can write so much more but that is all i can say for now.. I know my grammar while typing isn’t the best. Thank you for your time reading this and have a great day ^_^

p.s hibachi chef nothing against you. I wanted and tried for year to become one to but both work place refuse to train a female, I keep saying its sexist and this America. there are customer who rather sometime see something different such as a female chef. but most the chef I work and had worked with don’t like the ideal. It hurts for me to be an Asian american who was born in the state, be treated this way from some of the immigrant co-worker. The ways in your home country isn’t the way here sorry to tell all you racist sexist out there.
 Reply 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 
 
   
 Select Language Afrikaans Albanian Arabic Armenian Azerbaijani Basque Belarusian Bulgarian Catalan Chinese (Simplified) Chinese (Traditional) Croatian Czech Danish Dutch English Estonian Filipino Finnish French Galician Georgian German Greek Haitian Creole Hebrew Hindi Hungarian Icelandic Indonesian Irish Italian Japanese Korean Latvian Lithuanian Macedonian Malay Maltese Norwegian Persian Polish Portuguese Romanian Russian Serbian Slovak Slovenian Spanish Swahili Swedish Thai Turkish Ukrainian Urdu Vietnamese Welsh Yiddish Subscribe to our Feed via RSS 
 
 
Recent Posts

 how to apply as a service crew at MCDONALD&apos;S? Is it rude to not tip the pizza driver? What are good places to eat brunch at? ? Why do people not know how to tip their server? How to download a Subway *censored* long and soda? What is best and worst food to eat on a date? Where to go for a 21st birthday in Dallas? What is the best San Jose area Restaurantt to have a small (30 people) office party? What are the best places to dine in Bloomington IN? How much would it cost for me to take me and three friends to Andiamos restaurant for dinner? 
 
 
 
Categories

 Dining Out 
 
Archives

 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 
 
 
 


 
Calendar
 
 April 2011 M T W T F S S «Mar   May»   1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30   
 
Pages

 Contact Us 
 
Meta

 Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.org 
 
 
©2012 http://diningout.blog.my | Powered by WordPress 

A WordPress theme by Ravi Varma
	</body>
</document>
