<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001224" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Champaign/Steak--Shake" time="2012-07-12-16:40" support="1" score="0.0034091364645463347" bingtitle="Steak &amp; Shake - Fast Food Restaurant Champaign, IL" webtitle="Steak&amp;Shake - Fast Food Restaurant  Champaign, IL">
			<query id="000187" bing-rank="238"/>
	<description>Steak &amp; Shake is a Fast Food restaurant located at 2010 N ... Corp., have announced price increases to counter the ... You will soon begin to receive the newsletters you ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Steak&amp;Shake
 
Average User Rating
 
5
 
Average
 
Sponsored Link


 
(217) 398-1606

 http://www.steaknshake.com/ 
 IL &gt; Champaign &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Steak&amp;Shake listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Steak&amp;Shake to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Steak&amp;Shake
 Steak&amp;Shake is a Fast Food restaurant located at 2010 N Prospect Ave in Champaign, IL . Steak&amp;Shake has been described as an Good Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 5 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food, Steak Houses, American Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Steak&amp;Shake
 
 
 
All Reviews for Steak&amp;Shake


 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Steak&amp;Shake:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   0

 
Comments
 
 
Steak&amp;Shake News
 Can landmark steak burger chain beat In-N-Out? is expected to open a new takeout concept next month in New York City. Traditional Steak &apos;n Shake restaurants offer full-service dining and a drive-through lane. However, this new concept, dubbed the Steak &apos;n Shake &quot;Signature&quot; design ... Blue Smoke Restaurant Blows Downtown to Battery Park City with Second Location Blue Smoke is part of Danny Meyer’s Union Square Hospitality Group (USHG), which includes several of New York City’s most celebrated restaurants: Union Square Cafe, Gramercy Tavern, Shake Shack, The Modern, Cafe 2 and Terrace 5 (located at The Museum ... Starbucks, Denny&apos;s to raise prices in 2012 A new year and a handful of national ... in southwestern Pennsylvania. But one restaurant chain with stores in Pittsburgh said Tuesday it won&apos;t be raising prices anytime soon. Steak &apos;n Shake said that will keep prices the way they are through ... Denny’s Will Raise Menu Prices in 2012 to Offset Food Costs 3 (Bloomberg) -- Denny’s Corp., a family restaurant ... in New York and had gained 5 percent last year. As other chains, including Starbucks Corp., have announced price increases to counter the rising costs of ingredients, Steak ‘n Shake ... Dining out: Red Rock solid but a bit pricey Since hitting the downtown restaurant scene in 1994 ... For meat lovers, a 12-ounce New York steak ($25.99) ticked several boxes. The hunk of meat was well marbled and cooked to the requested doneness, coming to the table seared and hot from ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing Steak &apos;n Shake Welcome to the Steak &apos;n Shake website. Locate a restaurant near you, shop for merchandise, play games, or join the eclub. Del Frisco&apos;s Double Eagle Steak House, New York City - Restaurant ... &quot;If you are a steak house supporter Del Frisco should be at the top of you list ...&quot; · &quot;As expected, food was phenomenal. But, it was so loud, with both ... Steak Restaurant In New York&amp;Las Vegas | Striphouse Welcome To Strip House. Experience the combination of charred cuts, perfectly paired with decadent sides set in a siren-red interior where old-world glamour meets ... Sparks Steak House - New York Restaurant - MenuPages Steakhouses ... Thanks for subscribing! You will soon begin to receive the newsletters you selected. To enjoy more benefits and personalization available on MenuPages.com, register now! Long Island Restaurants | J&amp;R;&apos;s Steak House Restaurants | Stony ... Long Island Steak House. Get Coupons for J&amp;R;&apos;s Restaurants in Stony Brook, Rocky Point, Medford, Calverton, Islip and Patchogue Long Island, New York. Great steaks ... 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 71° 
Fri
 
 70° - 88° 
Sat
 
 70° - 88° 
Sun
 
 72° - 91° 
 
Address
 
Steak&amp;Shake

2010 N Prospect Ave

Champaign, IL 
 

 
Telephone
 (217) 398-1606 
Steak&amp;Shake
 
 Rating :  5 out of 10 based on 5 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Steak&amp;Shake Photos
 
 Fast Food Steak Houses American 
 
 Local Places
 
 Lai Lai Chinese Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Steak&amp;Shake 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Arby&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Silver Mine Subs 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food KFC 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Taco Bell 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Wienerschnitzel 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Jimmy Johns 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Quiznos 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Framers Market 
Cuisine: Art Craft Supplies Wind Water Light 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Champaign County Historical Museum 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Glass FX 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Hill Street Gallery 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries 
 

See all Champaign Art Craft Supplies 
See all Champaign Art Museums Galleries 
See all Champaign ATMs 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Steak&amp;Shake Coupons 

 Steak&amp;Shake Champaign 

 Steak&amp;Shake Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Champaign Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P Q | R | S | T | U | V | W | Y Z 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
