<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001610" url="http://blackpool.askalo.co.uk/tag/restaurants/" time="2012-07-12-17:23" support="3" score="0.014584888464124743" bingtitle="Restaurants Blackpool - askalo™ tips" webtitle="Restaurants Blackpool - askalo™ tips">
			<query id="001161" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="000658" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000096" bing-rank="91"/>
	<description>I don&apos;t like to wait for my food. I just like to order and start eating a few minutes after I order. Where is the best fast food restaurant ... Would you tell me please where ...</description>
	<body>
		restaurants Blackpool
 I want to know where is the best place to eat Spanish food in Blackpool? 
 I like Spanish food, especially tapas, so I am searching for the best Spanish restaurant in Blackpool. 
 0   Add Category: Dining Out Blackpool Tags: restaurants spanish food Where is the best restaurant in Blackpool? 
 I love going to the best restaurants in every city. What is the most popular restaurant overall in Blackpool in terms of good tasting food, service, and cost? 
 0   Add Category: Dining Out Blackpool Tags: restaurants best restaurant What is the best family restaurant in Blackpool? 
 My family and I eat out often, and prefer to go to more family-oriented restaurants. Is there a most family-oriented restaurant in the Blackpool area? 
 0   Add Category: Dining Out Blackpool Tags: restaurants family restaurant What is the healthiest restaurant in Blackpool? 
 I prefer to eat healthy meals over meals that simply taste good which is why I am looking for a restaurant in Blackpool that is well-known for providing healthy cuisine. 
 0   Add Category: Dining Out Blackpool Tags: healthy dining restaurants Where is the best place in Blackpool to eat fast food? 
 I love fast food. I don&apos;t like to wait for my food. I just like to order and start eating a few minutes after I order. Where is the best fast food restaurant in Blackpool? 
 0   Add Category: Dining Out Blackpool Tags: restaurants fast food Do you know where is the most luxurious restaurant in Blackpool? 
 The most expensive restaurants usually have the best quality and service, and I don&apos;t mind spending a good amount of money for a great tasting dish. I also always meet the most ... 
 0   Add Category: Dining Out Blackpool Tags: restaurants luxurious restaurant Would you tell me please where is the best place to eat Chinese food in Blackpool? 
 I am looking for a place to eat some good Chinese food in Blackpool. Is there a particular place that makes really good chicken fried rice? 
 0   Add Category: Dining Out Blackpool Tags: restaurants chinese food Where is the best place to eat Italian food in Blackpool? 
 I love to eat different kinds of pasta, and would very much love to find a place in Blackpool that serves great-tasting Italian food. 
 0   Add Category: Dining Out Blackpool Tags: restaurants italian restaurants Adjust your search 
 Search nearby 
 Blackpool + 0 2 5 10 25 mi 
 Go! Category Going Out Beauty&amp;Wellness Education&amp;Care Services Shopping New in Town Sports&amp;Activities Tourism Everything Else Tags for Blackpool accessories bank bars cars central consultants Blackpool discounts entertainment gifts home services Blackpool hospital Blackpool hotel information largest lawyers nightclub restaurants school second-hand service shop sports Blackpool store transportation travel      ... more Change location askalo Blackpool Results 1 - 8 of 8 for restaurants in Blackpool Sort by date Sort by distance 
 Thu 12 Jul 2012 16:23:48 Results 1 - 8 of 8 for restaurants in Blackpool 
 askalo tips Do you like askalo?

Then be a part of the askalo facebook community and “like“ askalo on facebook to share tips and meet other askalo users! Visit the askalo facebook page now! Ask a question for free about restaurants Blackpool . Ask a Question 
 ( 0 ) | Help | | Change location | My askalo 
 Ask a Question Going Out Beauty Education Services Shopping New in Town Sports Tourism Everything Else &gt; Browse: unanswered | answered | popular Last viewed 
 Terms of Use Privacy Policy Blog Contact Spread the word Points&amp;Awards 


 Copyright © 2012 askalo ™ 

    sun2
	</body>
</document>
