<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001362" url="http://reliabilityweb.com/art04/maint_storeroom.htm" time="2012-07-12-16:51" support="19" score="0.057279739490989405" bingtitle="the_Maintenance_storeroom" webtitle="the_Maintenance_storeroom">
			<query id="000209" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="001275" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000772" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000781" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="001346" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000323" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000198" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000196" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="001389" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="001405" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="000761" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="001337" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000343" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000334" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000218" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="001420" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="000397" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="000321" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="000758" bing-rank="198"/>
	<description>... who has ordered food from a fast-food restaurant can ... service they will receive ... Parts Receipts and Parts Issues . As has already been ...</description>
	<body>
		Focal Points : Sponsored links 
 New CMMS! MVP Plant - Smart Software for Smart Maintenance 
   Join The Association For 
 Maintenance Professionals 
 RCM-EAM-MTrain-2009 Daytona Beach   Infrared windows and safety 
 products 
 Follow us on 
 Twitter 
 
 

 

 

 

 

 
 

 


 
 
 Return to Home Page 
   
 
 
 
 
 The Maintenance Storeroom:  

 Keys to Efficient Maintenance Operation 
 by Jeff Zeiler of York 
 Consulting Group 

  Originally presented at the International Maintenance Conference 

 Click here for a 
 print friendly 500k pdf version 

 Besides being the central hub for maintenance, the 
 storeroom also provides functions that are absolutely 
 critical to the maintenance operation. These functions 
 are so important that when the storeroom is operating in 
 a best practices mode, the rest of the maintenance 
 operation can excel the storeroom is the enabler. Put 
 another way, if the storeroom is run improperly (such as 
 poor inventory accuracy, parts unavailable when needed 
 due to poor replenishment and procurement practices, 
 etc), the rest of the maintenance operation has no 
 chance of achieving high service levels of equipment 
 availability and reliability. 

 The 
 sections that follow will provide methods and practices 
 to achieving storeroom excellence, which will, in turn, 
 enable excellence in the entire maintenance operation. 

 The 
 Storeroom As Service Provider 

 If you follow the flow of technicians and materials in a 
 typical maintenance operation, a common pattern 
 emerges. In general, you have a central hub and the 
 spokes of a wheel - where the hub is the storeroom, and 
 the spokes are the paths to the equipment or machinery 
 in the facility or site that are undergoing 
 maintenance.   The following flow chart (Figure 1) 
 shows the flow of parts between the storeroom and a 
 single work center. The number of work centers on the 
 site multiplies the actual material flow. This analogy 
 illustrates the pivotal role of the maintenance 
 storeroom.
	</body>
</document>
