<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001775" url="http://www.hamburgercalculus.com/blog/?p=7255" time="2012-07-12-17:33" support="3" score="0.004351727143712863" bingtitle="Not Bad for Fast Food, BK Fire-Grilled Ribs at Burger King" webtitle="Not Bad for Fast Food, BK Fire-Grilled Ribs at Burger King">
			<query id="000662" bing-rank="249"/>
			<query id="000537" bing-rank="201"/>
			<query id="000977" bing-rank="157"/>
	<description>... actual real food, complete with bones, at a fast food restaurant. ... But, when Dave ordered, the cashier revealed that you ... you know that by stopping there in the first place ...</description>
	<body>
		Home About 
 Hamburger Calculus 
 The integration of great tastes. 
 
 books hall of fame hamburgers barbecue hot dogs 
 May 27 
 Not Bad for Fast Food, BK Fire-Grilled Ribs at Burger King 
 
Actual Bone-In Ribs at Burger King
 
I’ve seen some reviews about the new Ribs at Burger King. I knew that I needed to give them a try and was expecting the very worst . But, it’s actual real food, complete with bones, at a fast food restaurant. Why not give them a try?
 
If the Creepy King Didn&apos;t Give It Away, the Sack Your Ribs Come In Should, You&apos;re Not In Texas
 
The 6 piece order of Ribs as a combo meal (with fries and drink) was a little pricey at $7.59. You could add on two more ribs to make an 8 piece meal for $8.99. Dave and I weren’t sure what the best plan should be, so we initially thought to split a 6 piece combo and then get something else as a backup plan (it was lunch and we were hungry). But, when Dave ordered, the cashier revealed that you can add on a 3-piece order of ribs to any combo meal for $2.59. Not too expensive, so we both went that route.

The first rib that I tried was actually pretty incredible. It’s the one in the top picture and it was actually quite juicy. It was smoky tasting and didn’t need any sauce. It slid right off the bone. I was impressed. And Dave was looking at me like I was insane because his rib wasn’t quite that good. My second rib was a bit closer to what I expected. It was a bit tougher and drier, so I went for the barbecue sauce. Burger King’s barbecue sauce is a little spicy, but a little honey sweet. Not too bad as sauces go, but nothing amazing. The slightly drier rib plus sauce wasn’t bad. The third rib was somewhere in between the two, a little moist, but not as amazing as the first. Dave’s sack of ribs had this striation of juiciness, as well. All in all, we were pretty happy. For fast food, this was real food like you might cook yourself and really wasn’t that bad. Sure, it’s nowhere near as good as Texas barbecue or really most other authentic spots, but it’s not bad if you’re craving some barbecue.
 
The Three Little (St. Louis) Ribs
 
I have this theory that fast food in cities is generally not prepared up to the same standards as fast food outside of larger metropolitan areas. There is a lot of variability in fast food, even though so much care has gone into controlling everything. I mean, based on personal experience, the Taco Bell Shrimp Tacos that I had in both Philadelphia and Bala Cynwd didn’t compare to those had further away from the city limits. So, not sure if I’m blessed to have fast food franchisees who actually follow the instructions or not.

Here’s the end all argument for me: Burger King’s actual Ribs are better than a McDonald’s McRib . Sure, it would be nice to take the rib meat and add some onions and pickles, but real pork to pressed pork patty, the real pork comes out on top. And while McDonald’s keeps pussyfootin’around with whether the McRib is on the menu or retired or whatever, Burger King has decisively put these things on the menu. A clear winner.

In any case, these ribs weren’t really that bad. In fact, one of the three ribs was actually pretty good and, if I could be guaranteed they’d all taste like that, I’d probably eat these on a regular basis. Sure, Burger King is not a small mom and pop establishment in Texas cranking out the magic to a select crowd in the know, but you know that by stopping there in the first place, you can’t expect much more than that. All in all, I’d eat them again.

 

 

 

 

 

 
 
The Third Dimension
 
 Two Integrals. Really not that bad for fast food and one of the ribs was really decent, with fall off the bone tenderness. If all three were that good, the rating would be much higher. 
 Share 
Tags: barbecue , burger king , mcrib , ribs 
 Posted by hatchy barbecue , fast food , snacks Subscribe to RSS feed 
2 Responses to“Not Bad for Fast Food, BK Fire-Grilled Ribs at Burger King”

 Fidel Gastro 
 June 7th, 2010 at 10:45 am 
They tasted like hot dogs to me. I even got a preservative headache after my third one, but I’ll probably eat them again.
 hatchy 
 June 7th, 2010 at 1:11 pm 
That’s what fast food is all about, right?! I think you might be visiting some inferior Burger King if they tasted like hot dogs, though…
 

Leave a Reply
 
 Name (required) 

 Email (required) 

 Website 
 Please select one of these third-party accounts: 
 Wordpress | Google | Blogger | Livejournal | Yahoo | AOL | Flickr | MyOpenID | Technorati | Verisign | Vidoop | ClaimID | OpenId 
 Or enter your OpenId URL: 
 
 You can use these tags:&lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 

 
 Authenticate this comment using OpenID . Search for: 
Food Blogs

 a hamburger today all tenderloins, all the time beer by bike bloomington eats (and drinks) burgatory candy blog chicago burger project dmanburger drawing for food fidel gastro foodaphilia fries with that shake hamburger america holly eats hoosier burger boy japanese snack reviews jen ken&apos;s kit kat blog on second scoop phoodie roadfood texas burger guy the blognut the impulsive buy the knowledge for thirst weeg eats would i buy it again? 

Friends

 blog*log hymy industries tangzine twitch film wearelancaster 

music

 arthur burnt toast vinyl last plane to jakarta leaf o rosa of sound mind p.w. elverum&amp;sun resonance rumraket secretly canadian signal to noise sublime frequencies 

places

 brouwerij&apos;t ij (amsterdam) brouwerij de prael (amsterdam) doughnut plant hot doug’s in-n-out burger 
 
 July 2012 M T W T F S S «Jul       1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31   

Tags

 bacon barbecue beer belgian beer boston breakfast burger king cheese chicago chicken chocolate coffee doritos doughnuts fast food french fries hall of fame hamburger america hamburgers hot dogs ice cream indiana Japanese japanese snack food week 2009 japanese snacks kit kat kit kat week 2009 limited edition products mcdonald&apos;s milkshakes new york city onion rings pennsylvania philadelphia pie pizza potato chips roadfood sausage taco bell tacos tastykake texas texas barbecue tour 2009 who put that on my plate 

Meta

 Log in Comments RSS 
 RSS Copyright©2012 Hamburger Calculus All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
