<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001844" url="http://www.jobisjob.ca/montreal/restaurant/jobs" time="2012-07-12-17:37" support="1" score="0.0014689047665674979" bingtitle="Montreal Restaurant Jobs and Top Restaurant Career Opportunities ..." webtitle="Montreal Restaurant Jobs and Top Restaurant Career Opportunities in Montreal - JobisJob Canada">
			<query id="001480" bing-rank="223"/>
	<description>restaurant cashier Add to shortlist. RESTAURANT PRINCE D ... shift manager, fast food restaurant Add to shortlist ... including staff, facilities and equipment in order ...</description>
	<body>
		FREE Job Posting 
 Sign In - Post a Job 
 My Network My jobs (0) Sign In 
 Search jobs: 
 What: Job title, keywords or company name Where: Town, County, Region (Optional) 
 
Restaurant Jobs in Montreal
 
Sort by:  Date | Relevance 
 Distance: Exact location only Within 10 km Within 25 km Within 50 km Within 75 km Within 100 km 
 1 to 10 of 145 vacancies 
 
Related Jobs
 Restaurant Manager Greek Restaurant Restaurant Restaurant Manager Montreal Restaurant Toronto Subway Restaurant Restaurant Calgary Fast Food Restaurant Restaurant Edmonton Restaurant Vancouver Assistant Restaurant Manager Restaurant Server Restaurant Ottawa Restaurant Mississauga Gerant Restaurant Restaurant Waitress See More… 
Top locations near Montreal hiring now Restaurant Jobs :

 Montreal (145) Laval (15) Repentigny (10) Longueuil (8) 

 St-Jérôme (8) Brossard (6) Terrebonne (6) Boucherville (5) 

 Dorval (5) St-Sauveur (5) 
 
 fast food restaurant manager Add to shortlist 

 DAMSAR Inc. ( Tim Hortons ) -
Montreal (Québec)

(The following information has not been translated.): En tant que gérant de restaurant , vous habilitez et dirigez votre équipe afin d’offrir des expériences d’invité exceptionnelles. Vous favorisez un climat de respect au sein de l’équipe de travail en...
horeca jobs montreal…

 6 days ago from: emploiquebec.net
 
 restaurant cashier Add to shortlist 

 A&amp;W -
Montreal (Québec)

(The following information has not been translated.): Caissiere au service a la clientelle...
average hostess pay restaurant montreal…

 11 days ago from: emploiquebec.net
 
 
People you know

who work at this company
 
 You 

 know 
 Your Friend 
 Facebook Off LinkedIn Off 
 
 
 New Restaurants Trainer Add to shortlist 

 Tim Hortons Inc -
Montr, QC Canada

Tim Hortons Inc. is currently seeking New restaurant trainers who are willing to travel across Quebec to open up New Tim Hortons store locations and work in our corporate restaurants situated throughout the province. Being a leader in the Quick-Service...
canadian jobs that accept mexicans in laval montreal…

 8 days ago from: working.com
 
 shift manager, fast food restaurant Add to shortlist 

 DAMSAR Inc. ( Tim Hortons ) -
Montreal (Québec)

(The following information has not been translated.): En tant qu&apos;assistant-gérant de restaurant , vous habilitez et dirigez votre équipe afin d’offrir des expériences d’invité exceptionnelles. Vous favorisez un climat de respect au sein de l’équipe de...
high volume restaurants in montreal…

 6 days ago from: emploiquebec.net
 
 shift manager, fast food restaurant Add to shortlist 

 PIZZA HUT - Redberry Resto Brands Inc. -
Pointe-aux Trembles (Québec)

(The following information has not been translated.): Le chef de quart est responsable de la gestion et de l’administration du personnel durant un quart de travail assigné. Il est un membre intégrant de l’équipe de gestion du restaurant . Responsabilités...
hiring restaurants in montreal…

 7 days ago from: emploiquebec.net
 
 Formateur pour nouveaux restaurants Add to shortlist 

 Tim Hortons -
Montreal, Canada Area

En ce moment, Tim Hortons Inc. recherche des Formateurs - nouveaux restaurants qui soient prêt(e)s à voyager à travers le Québec pour ouvrir de nouveaux restaurants Tim Hortons et travailler dans nos restaurants corporatifs partout au Québec. Chef de...
jobs as a washdisher in canada in greek restaurant…

 20 days ago from: linkedin.com
 
 restaurant cashier Add to shortlist 

 TIM HORTON -
Anjou (Québec)

(The following information has not been translated.): Les caissiers exercent une partie ou l&apos;ensemble des fonctions suivantes : * accueillir les clients; * établir ou trouver le prix des produits, des services ou des billets à l&apos;aide d&apos;une caisse enregistreuse...
part-time job montreal bistro…

 3 days ago from: emploiquebec.net
 
 restaurant manager Add to shortlist 

 Drakkar Ressources Humaines -
Montréal (Québec)

(The following information has not been translated.): Vous avez un coeur de leader et une passion pour le service à la clientèle? Nous sommes à la recherche d’une personne hautement motivée pour gérer un établissement d’une grande chaîne de restauration...
reastaurant job montreal…

 15 days ago from: emploiquebec.net
 
 Up and coming Bar Managers - Amazing chain restaurant Add to shortlist 

 MindHr -
Various in montreal - QC/Montréal

If you are young, energetic, experienced, have the passion to grow your career, are a people person, and love the thrill of...
summer job restaurant canada…

 15 days ago from: bestjobsca.com
 
 
People you know

who work at this company
 
 You 

 know 
 Your Friend 
 Facebook Off LinkedIn Off 
 
 
 fast food restaurant manager Add to shortlist 

 LE GRAND CAFE METCALFE INC. -
montreal (Québec)

(The following information has not been translated.): prendre en charge un café bistro,appliquer les normes du franchiseur,promouvoir...

 7 days ago from: emploiquebec.net
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Next 
 
 Get email alerts for the latest
Restaurant Jobs in Montreal 
 
 My email 
You can cancel email alerts at anytime. We will not share your email address with anyone.
 
 
Job Trends on Restaurant in Montreal
 
 More Trends 
 
Restaurant
 The Food Service encompasses those places, institutions, and companies responsible for any meal eaten away from home. This industry includes restaurants , school and hospital cafeterias , catering operations, and many other formats. The companies that supply Food Service operators are called Food Service distributors and sell goods like kitchen utensils and bulk foods. Some of these companies manufacture products in both consumer and Food Service versions. 
 Other jobs in Restaurant category 
Other information
 
 View all Restaurant Jobs . View all Jobs in Montreal . More information on Montreal . 
 
Share Options

 
 
Filter jobs by
 Job Title All Dishwasher (12) Licensed Cook (7) Restaurant Cashier (7) Cook (6) Shift Manager, Fast Food Restaurant (5) Waiter/waitress (5) Executive Sous-chef (4) Restaurant Cook (4) Restaurant Manager (4) Fast Food Restaurant Manager (3) See More… Company All Tim Hortons (6) Restaurant Vallier (5) Sir (5) Ge (4) Jack Astors Dorval (4) Les Entreprises Amico R.s (4) Restaurant Alexandre (4) Restaurant Burger King (4) Gestion Cassinc (3) Hotelleriejobs.com (3) See More… Job Type All Permanent, Full Time (39) Others (20) Permanent (18) Permanent, Part-time (15) Permanent, Shifts (12) Any (10) Full Time (9) Casual Or Temporary (3) Casual (2) Seasonal (1) See More… Date Posted Last 24 hours (6) Last week (34) Last 2 weeks (55) Last month (140) 
Related sections
 My recent searches You have no recent searches at the moment.
Use our  Job Search  to find your new job.   Create email alert My email 
 Search jobs: 
 What: Job title, keywords or company name Where: Town, County, Region (Optional) 
 
Refine your search
 Job Title All Dishwasher (12) Licensed Cook (7) Restaurant Cashier (7) Cook (6) Shift Manager, Fast Food Restaurant (5) Waiter/waitress (5) Executive Sous-chef (4) Restaurant Cook (4) Restaurant Manager (4) Fast Food Restaurant Manager (3) See More… Company All Tim Hortons (6) Restaurant Vallier (5) Sir (5) Ge (4) Jack Astors Dorval (4) Les Entreprises Amico R.s (4) Restaurant Alexandre (4) Restaurant Burger King (4) Gestion Cassinc (3) Hotelleriejobs.com (3) See More… Job Type All Permanent, Full Time (39) Others (20) Permanent (18) Permanent, Part-time (15) Permanent, Shifts (12) Any (10) Full Time (9) Casual Or Temporary (3) Casual (2) Seasonal (1) See More… My recent searches Restaurant in Montreal 
 JobisJob: About us Legal information Contact us Help Top job searches Top locations Resume Review ©JobisJob, SL
	</body>
</document>
