<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001050" url="http://www.livestrong.com/article/84536-nutrition-information-fast-restaurants/" time="2012-07-12-16:27" support="43" score="0.18247750691332953" bingtitle="How To Get Nutrition Information For Fast Food Restaurants ..." webtitle="How To Get Nutrition Information For Fast Food Restaurants | LIVESTRONG.COM">
			<query id="001357" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000218" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000775" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="001317" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000532" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000540" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000758" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000415" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="001499" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="000413" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000603" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="000166" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="001106" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000767" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000776" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000198" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000182" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000430" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000216" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="000431" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000181" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000436" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000212" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="001326" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000781" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000855" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="000761" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000416" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="001484" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000779" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000164" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="000204" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000556" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000434" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="000167" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="000173" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000886" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="001483" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000751" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="000187" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000196" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000229" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="000422" bing-rank="61"/>
	<description>... grams are in the number five value meal you order ... Visit the fast food restaurant&apos;s website. Recent legislation ... may be posted on the wall or hiding under the tray ...</description>
	<body>
		Login or Register Lose 25 percent more weight LIVESTRONG.COM The limitless potential of you 
 Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
 

 
 Home Food&amp;Drink Nutrition Information for Restaurants Fast Food Nutrition Information How to Get Nutrition Information for Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 How to Get Nutrition Information for Fast Food Restaurants 
 Aug 24, 2010 | By Laura Kenny Photo Credit french fries image by Wimbledon from Fotolia.com 
Have you ever wondered how many calories and fat grams are in the number five value meal you order three times a week? Would knowing exactly what you are eating help you make better choices? With over 100 billion dollars spent annually on fast food, and links between fast food consumption and obesity, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration encourages consumers to learn about fast food nutrition content. As long as you plan ahead, finding nutrition information on fast food products is easy. Along with self-control, fast food nutrition knowledge can help you make healthier choices without giving up on eating out altogether.
 
Step 1

Visit the fast food restaurant&apos;s website. Recent legislation requires restaurants&apos; cooperation in posting all nutrition information online.
 
Step 2

Look at the option bar at the top or side of the home page. Generally, nutrition information will be listed under a specific nutrition section or under the food section.
 
Step 3

Locate the product of interest. Some websites have drop-down menus to choose from that are divided into salads, fries, sandwiches and so forth, while others list all foods and corresponding information.
 
Step 4

Identify the nutrient(s) of interest. You may be attempting to lower cholesterol levels, and thus will check saturated fat and cholesterol content. Or you may be focused on weight loss, and evaluating protein, calorie and/or fiber content.
 
Step 5

Browse through other choices and find a healthier alternative. Try choosing a lower-calorie, higher-fiber, lower-fat or higher-protein option. Opt to order a smaller meal and choose a healthier side. Some websites allow you to create a meal in which you choose multiple items and the nutrient information is automatically calculated for the entire meal.
 
Step 6

Order the healthier choice. It is easy to find the better choice online and mentally commit to choosing it the next time you&apos;re in the restaurant; however, actually ordering it may be more difficult. Stick to your commitment to better health and do not deviate from the healthier choice.
 
Tips and Warnings

 If you do not have Internet access or are unable to plan ahead, most fast food restaurants have the nutrition facts on site. The information may be posted on the wall or hiding under the tray covers. Before ordering, ask the closest associate where the nutrition facts are located.

Fast food nutrition information books are available at bookstores and online. Due to constant fast food menu additions, these books may not always be completely up-to-date. However, they do contain basic menu items and associated nutrition information. Most are small and can fit into a purse or glove box for easy access. 

Some food journal websites also contain fast food nutrition information. Smaller, family-owned fast food restaurants may not have nutrition information available. 
 
References

 FDA: Guidance for Industry: A Labeling Guide for Retaurants and Other Retail Establishments Selling Away-From-Home Foods McDonald&apos;s USA: Nutrition Information Wendy&apos;s: Nutrition Facts 
 
Article reviewed by J.A. Rist Last updated on: Aug 24, 2010
 
 Trending Now 
 
 Must see: Slideshows&amp;Video 
 
 The Best Dog Breeds For Running 
 
 LIVESTRONG.COM
Original Video 
 
 23 Ways To Improve Your BBQ 
 
 Member Comments 
 advertisement 
 People Are Reading Related Topics 
 
 Nutrition Facts for Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 Restaurants With Nutrition Information 
 
 How to Compare the Nutritional Value of Foods From Restaurants 
 
 Nutritional Labeling in Restaurants 
 
 How to Compare the Nutrition of Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 Nutrition Guide for Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 Low-Sodium Menu Items at Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 How to Eat Healthy at Fast-Food Restaurants 
 
 Fast Food Restaurant Nutrition 
 
 Healthy Ways to Eat at Restaurants 
 
 Restaurants That Serve Heart-Healthy Foods 
 
 Dangers of Fast-Food Restaurants 
 
 How Can a Diabetic Eat Right at Restaurants? 
 
 Fast Food Burger Nutrition Facts 
 
 Effects of Fast Food Restaurants on Diabetes 
 
 Nutrition Facts for Wendy&apos;s Fast-Food Restaurant 
 
 Healthy Food Choices at Restaurants 
 
 Explain the Effects of Eating at Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 Gluten-Free Foods at Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 Nutrition Facts Required for Fast Food 
 more Fast Food Menu Nutrition For Fast Food Nutrition For Restaurants Fast Food&amp;Restaurant Nutrition Nutrition In Fast Food advertisement 
You May Also Be Interested In
 
 Nutritional Information for Wine 
 
 Houston&apos;s Restaurant Nutrition Information 
 
 Weight Watchers Restaurant Nutrition Facts 
 
 Finley&apos;s Restaurant Nutritional Information 
 
 EZ Fiber&amp;Diabetes Control 
 
 Nutritional Information for O&apos;Charley&apos;s Restaurant 
 
 5 Things You Need to Know About Fit For Life Diet 
 
 Nutrition Facts for the Subway Chicken Pizzaiola 
 
 Applebee Restaurants Menus&amp;Calories 
 
 Wendy&apos;s Menu&amp;Calories 
 
 Nutrition Info for Mints 
 
 Nutritional Information on Bread 
 
 Chili&apos;s Restaurant Nutrition Information 
 
 BBQ Restaurant Nutrition 
 
 Restaurant Nutrition Facts for Szechuan Spicy Eggplant 
 
 Friendly&apos;s Restaurant Nutritional Information 
 
 EZ Bar Vs. Barbell 
 
 Nutritional Information for Champps Restaurant 
 
 How to Eat to Be Fit for Life 
 
 Nutrition Facts About Food for Kids 
 Show More Food Fitness Health Community Tools 
Sign-up for our
 newsletter

Get the latest tips on diet, exercise and healthy living.


 
Your email is safe with us. We hate spam too!
 About Blog Contact us&amp;FAQ Advertise with us Press Sitemap
	</body>
</document>
