<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001222" url="http://arstechnica.com/civis/viewtopic.php?f=23&amp;t=1071714" time="2012-07-12-16:40" support="9" score="0.03396101854202322" bingtitle="I tried to eat mcdonalds in a pizza place and they kicked me out ..." webtitle="I tried to eat mcdonalds in a pizza place and they kicked me out(what the hell!!) - Ars Technica OpenForum">
			<query id="000783" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="000852" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000663" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="000812" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000132" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000790" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000789" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000808" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="000796" bing-rank="63"/>
	<description>... when I got exactly six feet from the exit ... of difference between bringing fast food from/to another fast food restaurant ... proud of but if you do bring another place&apos;s food ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to the Ars OpenForum.
 
 Register Login 
 Posting Guidelines | E-mail Moderators Ars Technica &gt; Forums &gt; Ars Lykaion &gt; The Lounge Jump to: Select a forum ------------------ Hardware&amp;Tweaking   Audio/Visual Club   Case and Cooling Fetish   CPU&amp;Motherboard Technologia   Mobile Computing Outpost   Networking Matrix   Other Hardware   Agora Classifieds Operating Systems&amp;Software   Battlefront   Microsoft OS&amp;Software Colloquium   Linux Kung Fu   Windows Technical Mojo   Distributed Computing Arcana   Macintoshian Achaia   Programmer&apos;s Symposium   The Server Room Ars Lykaion   Gaming, Extra Strength Caplets   The Lounge   The Soap Box   The Boardroom   The Observatory   Ars Help&amp;Feedback Ars Subscription Member Areas   Image Galleries 
I tried to eat mcdonalds in a pizza place and they kicked me out(what the hell!!)
 45 posts • 1 2    Next 
 Ruffahsta Smack-Fu Master, in training Registered: Apr 13, 2000 Posts: 14 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 2:40 pm Last wk i ate at a cheap ass pizza place called ccs with my girlfriend,she likes the place but i cant stand it so i got mcdonalds and was going to eat it in there with here.So as shes getting her food i am opening my bag to get my delicious mcchicken sandwich and this guy comes up to me and says(thats like a slap in the face)and i say what?(bringing a competers food in here thats like a slap in the face,So i say well im here with my girlfriend she is eating here,and he says why arent you eating here? and i say cause i think ccs sux ass.and he says your going to have to leave with that,leave now(making a big sceen like i was causing a problem or somthing)so i go to my girlfriend and tell her whats going on told the mnger that was chicken shit,and asked for a refund he said i cant give you a refund but here is a card so next time she can eat free,(this will bother me for the rest of my life chicken shit establishments like that really piss me off anyone have any suggestions?) 

 One90proof Ars Tribunus Militum Tribus: Mobile, AL Registered: May 26, 1999 Posts: 1815 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 2:46 pm I don&apos;t know about your legal right to bring your McChicken sandwich into the place but IMO it&apos;s tacky as hell at the very least. 

 SeaRuidoso Ars Scholae Palatinae Registered: Feb 11, 2000 Posts: 960 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 2:48 pm concur, that is moronic 

 TremeIune Wise, Aged Ars Veteran Registered: Apr 9, 2000 Posts: 139 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 2:50 pm On the way home from Mardi Gras, my friends and I (all wearing Mardi-Gras-Logo-Badged skivvies on our heads) were stopped at the door by the portly manager lady at a Burger King...I hadn&apos;t realised it was such a classy establishment until I walked in to numerous teal Megadeth tanktops and white jeans.
 http://www.mulletsgalore.com/ 

 hazel-rah Ars Praetorian Registered: Jul 1, 1999 Posts: 558 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 3:27 pm If you tried to bring something from McDonald&apos;s into my place I&apos;d kick you out too. Especially if you talked to me that way. That said, CiCi&apos;s Pizza has that weird corporate-mandated forced cheerfulness thing going with their employees which makes it kind of unpleasant to eat there. Last time I went, the whole staff waved goodbye to me as I walked out the door. The scary thing is, as soon as I threw my napkin down on my plate, it&apos;s like they all stopped what they were doing so they could gear up to wave goodbye to me when I got exactly six feet from the exit. Sends a chill down my spine, you know? Almost triggered my fight-or-flight reflex.
-fh 

 DrPizza &quot;100% Medically Accurate&quot;
Moderator
et Subscriptor Tribus: Airstrip One, Oceania || illegitimis non carborundum Registered: May 10, 1999 Posts: 82089 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 3:45 pm That&apos;s not at all unusual, and I fully agree with it.
It&apos;s downright rude to eat food from one place in another place. 

 pimplit Wise, Aged Ars Veteran Registered: Mar 14, 2000 Posts: 151 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 3:47 pm true... true 

 BitJockey Ars Tribunus Militum Registered: Jul 24, 1999 Posts: 2217 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 4:04 pm I think that the manager missed a good oppurtunity to ask someone how he could improve his restaraunt... if you didn&apos;t like it, obviously there was something that he could do better. If he had been polite and asked what was wrong, he could&apos;ve gotten some free market research. Idiot. 
\\BitJockey 

 fuzz Ars Tribunus Angusticlavius Tribus: Cincinnati, OH Registered: Feb 4, 2000 Posts: 8889 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 4:10 pm hey, man. don&apos;t mess with those cc&apos;s pizza place managers. they love their cheap ass pizza, and damn all those who choose greasy fast food!
snicker. i think it was dumb by both. ruffahsta shouldn&apos;t have tried to bring shit in, and the manager shouldn&apos;t have been such an asshole about it.
wow. mom was correct. two wrong&apos;s don&apos;t make a right. they just make two idiots... 

 FreeRadical* Ars Legatus Legionis
et Subscriptor Registered: Jun 4, 1999 Posts: 12148 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 4:27 pm I don&apos;t mean to be rude, but the advertisements at this site are geared towards PC enthusiasts. The lounge is a place where &quot;geeks&quot;, as we call ourselves, come to vent our angst. The owner and operators of this site rely totally on advertisement revenues. While I sympathize with your plight, you are taking up valuable disk space and bandwidth meant for those with geek angst not fast food angst. Venting here is like a slap in the face to the owners and the paying customers at Ars Technica. It would be appreciate it if you would just move on to a Fast Food Enthusiast Website.
Thank you
&lt;font size=-2&gt;..of course you know I am being facetious don&apos;t you? &lt;/font&gt; 

 SeaRuidoso Ars Scholae Palatinae Registered: Feb 11, 2000 Posts: 960 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 6:14 pm lol 

 jemfinch Ars Praefectus Tribus: Leavenworth, KS Registered: Nov 28, 1999 Posts: 4534 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 7:28 pm While it is tacky to bring food from one place into another place, I think the manager was in the wrong.
I managed a restaurant for awhile, and my biggest priority as manager was to make sure the owners made money. If that meant letting someone bring McDonalds into the restaurant so his girlfriend could eat there, that&apos;s what I did. It wasn&apos;t my place to keep the owners from making money.
It&apos;s not like people are going to walk in my restaurant, see someone eating mcdonalds, and say &quot;Oh, what I *really* wanted was mcdonalds. Let&apos;s go there instead,&quot; and then leave.
IMO, the only thing the manager did was lose business for the owner. If I owned that restaurant I&apos;d be sure to have a long talk with that manager.
Jeremy 

 Digitali &quot;Optimistic Cynic&quot;
Ars Legatus Legionis Tribus: CeVA Registered: Dec 27, 1999 Posts: 17593 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 7:29 pm I think he has every right in the world to eat another establishment&apos;s food there.
I also wouldn&apos;t go so far as to call it a &apos;competitors&apos; grub. Pizza vs McDonald&apos;s; while the marketing dept may try to say that, I don&apos;t imagine myself saying, &quot;Damn, I sure would like some McDonalds, but hey, CiCi&apos;s nasty, cheap-ass pizza is having a sale this weekend. . .&quot;
He had a valid reason for consuming his food there. It&apos;s not his fault if his girlfriend has no taste in pizza (no offense intended).
I don&apos;t think was either rude or moronic. I&apos;ve done the same thing with Burger King. McDonald&apos;s is as nasty as CiCi&apos;s. I bought BK and went with my friends to McDonald&apos;s a couple of years ago. The management looked at me askance, but he could tell that the entire place would be redecorated in burger brown if he tried to screw with us. We&apos;re not trouble-makers, but we don&apos;t take kindly to having a manager make a scene, especially when it&apos;s uncalled for.
If the manager handled this with as little tact as the poster indicated, then he is seriously remiss and it doesn&apos;t surprise me that his old ass (they always are) is managing a lousy CiCi&apos;s pizza.
BTW, who the hell can eat there with the nasty smell and kids running all over the thrice-damned place? Don&apos;t get me wrong, I love the little nippers, except when they&apos;re throwing food and running around like little dervishes (as they are wont to do).
Ruffhasa (sic): I think you were well within your rights to do that. I&apos;d definitely call up his superior or franchise manager (or however the hell these two-bit &apos;eating&apos; places are run) and let him know that he had a loyal, repeat customer in your girlie-friend as well as someone who at least &apos;tolerated&apos; CiCi&apos;s (you could have insisted that they go somewhere where they both could enjoy the food) that he has now lost. They can&apos;t have that great a profit-margin from that cheap-ass food (out of respect for the Italians, I think I will no longer call CiCi&apos;s crap, pizza).
As far as not receiving a refund, police presence would have been required to remove me from the premises after he rudely asked that we leave and refused a refund, especially if my girlie was still in hunger-mode.
I&apos;d go so far as to ask him how he would like his life to become a living hell just because someone in his transient CiCi&apos;s job didn&apos;t like their nasty shit. All ya gotta do is peep his license tag, after that, you can get more info on his ass than TRW. Give him a choice of being an asshole and accepting the not-so-pleasant consequences or &apos;politely&apos; asking me to leave with a refund. Believe you me, that whole place would&apos;ve been cleared the hell out. Disrespecting my girl--in public--whilst I&apos;m there. I don&apos;t think so.
I hate these sorry ass 40 year olds that are managing a Jack in da Box. They see an opportunity where they can finally be on the giving side of life&apos;s shitstick and they take it for all it&apos;s worth.
One thing that has always worked for me: Let him know that his attitude is probably the reason his middle-aged ass is working a CiCi&apos;s for a barely livable wage. Shut&apos;s their old ass up everytime. While I respect anyone who breaks a sweat to feed themselves, assholes like this gets no props from me.
dB 

 deidre Ars Scholae Palatinae Registered: Oct 6, 1999 Posts: 1349 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 7:30 pm did your momma ever teach you any manners? when i was working for a family restaurant (at 16 it can be difficult finding a job in the summer *sigh*), i&lt;strong&gt;did&lt;/strong&gt;throw out people (with some help considering i&apos;m short ) who brought in food from other establishments with the intent of eating it there. what you did was very rude and disrespectful. were you honestly looking for sympathy here? dumbass... 

 dasein Ars Tribunus Angusticlavius Registered: Jan 7, 2000 Posts: 9429 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 7:34 pm Restaurants are private establishments and you are there as a guest of the management. They have every right to ask anyone to leave their establishment so long as they do not violate any civil rights laws. (E.G. refusing to serve black people.)
I have friends who manage a small coffee shop and they have very little tolerance for people who bring food or drinks from other establishments in. Either you order something from them, or you get out. That is just the way it works.
dasein 

 Surge Ars Praefectus Tribus: /dev/null Registered: Jun 12, 1999 Posts: 3276 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 7:40 pm It would have been had he not been patronizing the place. However, his girlfriend of whom he was with was eating there. So they didn&apos;t only kick out him(which would have made sense if he was alone) they kicked out paying customer cause she was eating with someone who decided to eat somewhere else. That was rudeness on their part. So what if the guy was in the mood for a Big Mac instead of a Pizza. All that says is this guy was in the mood for McDonald&apos;s it isn&apos;t like he walked in with McDonald&apos;s pizza which would be an item in direct competition and would have made them look bad. Does McDonald&apos;s compete with Pizza Hut? No it competes with Wendy&apos;s or Burger King, and Pizza Hut competes with Dominos.
P.S.: Oh, and I happen to like CiCi&apos;s but then again it depends on who&apos;s cooking that day.
[This message has been edited by godlike (edited April 18, 2000).] 

 Digitali &quot;Optimistic Cynic&quot;
Ars Legatus Legionis Tribus: CeVA Registered: Dec 27, 1999 Posts: 17593 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 7:42 pm quote: Originally posted by deidre:
 did your momma ever teach you any manners? when i was working for a family restaurant (at 16 it can be difficult finding a job in the summer *sigh*), i&lt;strong&gt;did&lt;/strong&gt;throw out people (with some help considering i&apos;m short ) who brought in food from other establishments with the intent of eating it there. what you did was very rude and disrespectful. were you honestly looking for sympathy here? dumbass... 
I wonder if the managers momma taught him any manners. If he did anything beyond quietly and politely asking him to leave, he was remiss. Don&apos;t tell me that he had a right to be &apos;upset&apos;. A professional _never_ gets upset, regardless of customer attitude. You might have to use physical force or call the police, but all of this can be done in a courteous manner (ever see anyone get their ass kicked by someone being polite and courteous?).
I think the fact that he was willing to eat his Mickey-D&apos;s in an establishment that his girlfriend preferred indicated a complete grasp of social manners. Screw CiCi&apos;s. Do they think that they&apos;ll lose customers to McDonald&apos;s just because some guys knocking back a chicken sandwich there?
The fact that he posted what happened and how he felt does not call for him to be labeled a dumbass.
Deidre: I wonder where your momma was when she was supposed to be teaching _you_ manners. If she&apos;s the one who taught you to call someone a dumbass, she would seem to be seriously remiss as well. Remiss at a job and remiss at parenting are two different things. Who do you think ended up with the shitbag? I&apos;d wager, you.
dB
 

 dasein Ars Tribunus Angusticlavius Registered: Jan 7, 2000 Posts: 9429 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 7:44 pm Competition is not the issue. (And all fast-food places compete with each other, ever see the Subway ads comparing their subs to burgers?) The issue is that the manager of the restaurant, no matter how bad the food, has the right to remove anyone from the premises. The fact that he is not eating their food means he is not a customer and therefore taking up their space which could have been used by a paying customer.
dasein 

 Surge Ars Praefectus Tribus: /dev/null Registered: Jun 12, 1999 Posts: 3276 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 7:47 pm Dasien: HE WAS WITH A PAYING CUSTOMER, KICKING HIM OUT IS KICKING OUT THE PAYING CUSTOMER. It&apos;s either eat there or eat inside the McDonald&apos;s Restarant, but since CiCi&apos;s isn&apos;t aimed towards making your stuff to go that wasn&apos;t really an option. 

 Ramen Pride! Ars Praefectus Registered: Apr 8, 2000 Posts: 5229 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 8:07 pm It&apos;s not like Pizza and McChicken sandwiches compete in the same bracket. I&apos;ve done similar things before. Once, when on the road, the rest of my crew wanted to eat at a DQ. I am addicted to Gorditas, however, and there was a Taco Bell right up the road. So I walked there, got my order and came back. No biggie.
Now, the management at DQ didn&apos;t say anything if they were offended, but I don&apos;t think they were. After all, it&apos;s not like they could offer me a BETTER Gordita?
It would be different if someone was alone, went into a Mc Donalds, got a happy meal, walked over to a Burger King, and proceeded to feast in front of them, refilling their drink several times.... then used the restrooms, and walked out playing happily with the toy that came in the meal.
That&apos;s where it would get rude.
Hehehehehehehe

Oh, and what IS with the odd CiCi&apos;s pizza behavior someone mentioned? The last time I went there they acted like I was the Messiah or something when I said it was my first time. It was disturbing/bizarre.
 

 Surge Ars Praefectus Tribus: /dev/null Registered: Jun 12, 1999 Posts: 3276 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 8:13 pm Hehe, they do that, they continuously ask me if I know how to &quot;work the buffet&quot;, &quot;hell yeah, I work it for all its worth&quot; I usually tell them and pat my stomach then go on to eat leaving a worried look on the managers face that I&apos;m about to eat them out of business. Then they remember how skinny I am and stop worrying. 

 MR2DI4 Ars Praefectus
et Subscriptor Tribus: Next to Nowhere, AK Registered: Feb 22, 2000 Posts: 5347 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 8:17 pm Ok, I understand.
I&apos;ve had much the same thing happen to me. I had just gotten back on campus with my McDonalds when I saw some friends who were heading out to lunch. Not having an immediate class I decided to go along. They went to a small local cafe with nothing like McD&apos;s food on the menu. We took a spot outside on the deck where no one was around. When the waitress came up she informs me that they don&apos;t allow other food in their establishment because they don&apos;t serve that kind of food. So I got sit in the Jeep and wait fot them to finish before getting back to class.
WTF! Well of course you don&apos;t serve that kind of food, can&apos;t you see the big letters on the bag and wrappers identifing my meal as McDonalds, not the food from your establishment! I mean really!
I was pretty pissed about this until I began to consider the courtesy of someone walking in with hot McD&apos;s fries and a Big Mac, into a crowd eating soup and sandwiches. That could be classified as torture, as no one can resist hot McD fries.
But we didn&apos;t walk through the place. We went straight out to the deck from the outside. No one in the place paid us any attention. The only time they did was when that annoying waitress started chewing me out about bringing my lunch with me. But I just left quietly, making a mental note never to eat there. By doing this they lost a potential customer.
There is a degree of courtesy to be paid to food establishments, the line for me is very thin as to what is right or not. I don&apos;t think its right to go and eat your food from somewhere else inside another restaurant but I don&apos;t think the way the guy treated you was proper either. He forgot the golden rule of customer service. &quot;The customer is always right.&quot; If you were there with your GF, a customer, then he should have left you alone or given you a small advisment against eating other food in there.
Remember the second you allow yourself to become emotionally involved in an argument, you lose. If you would have walked out of there and across the street to Domino&apos;s you would have made that guy look like a real ass. But by getting emotional and saying crude remarks about the establishment you&apos;re just making the excuse he needs to make you look like the ass and kick you out.
The definition of tolerance is one group putting up with another group&apos;s actions. By doing so the person, or establishment, allowing you to eat McD&apos;s in their place is showing strength over McD&apos;s because they aren&apos;t threatened by some guy with McD&apos;s and his girl eating lunch. Obviously this place must really have problems if they are so threatend by just some guy having a burger in a pizza place. Since they are weak and intolerant they have displayed that to all the customers and that will continue to hurt their business.
Just put up with their sh_t and stay cool. Yes it is a bit rude to bring other food into an establishment but for them to tolerate your actions would have been a better demonstration of doing good business than tossing you out with all the fanfare.
Oh yeah, burn the card outside their door. LOL
Just Kidding
Logic and knowledge prevail again...
MR2DI4 
[This message has been edited by MR2DI4 (edited April 18, 2000).] 

 Ramen Pride! Ars Praefectus Registered: Apr 8, 2000 Posts: 5229 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 8:38 pm I would say there is a large degree of difference between bringing fast food from/to another fast food restaurant, and bringing fast food to a REAL restaurant, cafe, or coffee shop.
 

 deidre Ars Scholae Palatinae Registered: Oct 6, 1999 Posts: 1349 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 8:58 pm hmmmm...perhaps i just don&apos;t understand. i don&apos;t particularly like mcdonalds food and it&apos;s been several months since i&apos;ve had any fast food (cept for chinese, vietnamese, and thai...mmmm)...so maybe i shouldn&apos;t have opened my mouth, but i don&apos;t think it was right to take a personal attack at me (as if you couldn&apos;t have told, my remark about &apos;didn&apos;t his momma teach him any manners&apos; was a bit facetious, and meant to be taken very lightly), and subsiquently my momma.
 quote: Originally posted by Digitali:
 I think the fact that he was willing to eat his Mickey-D&apos;s in an establishment that his girlfriend preferred indicated a complete grasp of social manners. 
again, maybe i just don&apos;t have a good grasp on fast food establishment etiquette, but i would disagree. i still think it was rude and tactless.
 quote: The fact that he posted what happened and how he felt does not call for him to be labeled a dumbass. 
alright, i&apos;ll admit that i probably should not have tacted on that remark.&lt;h5&gt;jeez, some people take everything so personally&lt;/h5&gt;
 quote: Deidre: I wonder where your momma was when she was supposed to be teaching _you_ manners. If she&apos;s the one who taught you to call someone a dumbass, she would seem to be seriously remiss as well. 
now this is a bit uncalled for. it&apos;s a tad bit low dragging someone&apos;s momma into conversation, wouldn&apos;t you think? especially since my remark was meant to be taken so lightly.
 quote: Who do you think ended up with the shitbag? I&apos;d wager, you. 
what the hell is this supposed to mean anyhow? call me dumb, but i just don&apos;t see what it&apos;s supposed to be refering to...
 

 dasein Ars Tribunus Angusticlavius Registered: Jan 7, 2000 Posts: 9429 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 9:01 pm There is really no room for debate after we establish the fact that the manager has the right to ask anyone to leave the premises of the restaurant.
Granted, not all restaurants will do this, nor should they, but if and when they do, there is no room to dispute it.
Second, whether this particular manager was rude is not the issue. Naturally, he will seem rather obnoxious, but then we have to look at the source of this description. He has no obligation to offer a refund, nor even a voucher for a free meal.
Finally, while his girlfriend was a paying customer, he was not. If a group of people comes into a restaurant and one orders a meal, they are all not paying customers.
dasein 

 deidre Ars Scholae Palatinae Registered: Oct 6, 1999 Posts: 1349 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 11:19 pm oops...my bad...didn&apos;t mean to post a second time just yet...
[This message has been edited by deidre (edited April 18, 2000).] 

 Fixxer Ars Praefectus Tribus: The 9th Circle Ω Registered: Feb 13, 2000 Posts: 3522 Posted: Tue Apr 18, 2000 11:39 pm haha.. thats the funniest thing I&apos;ve ever heard.. I&apos;d feel stupid doing that 

 Digitali &quot;Optimistic Cynic&quot;
Ars Legatus Legionis Tribus: CeVA Registered: Dec 27, 1999 Posts: 17593 Posted: Wed Apr 19, 2000 12:04 am quote: Originally posted by deidre:
 hmmmm...perhaps i just don&apos;t understand. i don&apos;t particularly like mcdonalds food and it&apos;s been several months since i&apos;ve had any fast food (cept for chinese, vietnamese, and thai...mmmm)...so maybe i shouldn&apos;t have opened my mouth, but i don&apos;t think it was right to take a personal attack at me (as if you couldn&apos;t have told, my remark about &apos;didn&apos;t his momma teach him any manners&apos; was a bit facetious, and meant to be taken very lightly), and subsiquently my momma.
what the hell is this supposed to mean anyhow? call me dumb, but i just don&apos;t see what it&apos;s supposed to be refering to...
 
I apologize for the close to home remark about your matriarch. I took your comment to indicate a lack of parenting on his momma&apos;s part.
While you can either side with the guy or not, I sometimes take (inappropriate?) offense at having someone belittled merely because they posted a wrong they thought they had been done.
I agree with Dasein in that the manager has the right to ask anyone to leave the premises, but asking them to leave without having refunded her money was rude and unprofessional. It seems like after he was publicly told to move his ass, the manager found one more petty shot to get in. I would suspect it would be bad business practice as well. It&apos;s not the manager&apos;s job to &apos;get even&apos; with an errant customer, but to handle his store in a courteous and friendly manner. That includes tact and discretion.
If he also did anything other than politely and quietly ask them to leave, without offering a refund on the uneaten buffet, then he was in the wrong.
I don&apos;t think what he did was any more rude then if I drove my Chevrolet to my girlfriend&apos;s Ford dealership to pick up her car after repairs, then waited for her to make sure that it was actually ready to go. I gotta leave because being there may make someone want to purchase a Chevy instead?
dB
p.s. At least he came here to vent instead of with, say, a Desert Eagle at CiCi&apos;s. . .
 

 Dj Easy Dick Ars Praefectus Registered: Sep 6, 1999 Posts: 3241 Posted: Wed Apr 19, 2000 12:09 am Sheit, I&apos;m the KING of fast food transportation for eatation upon oter propertiation.

I eat DQ at McDonalds. Usually just Mr. Misty drinks, but often times chicken.
But never alone. I usually eat with someone who&apos;s eating at McDonalds with me.

And sometimes I order McDonalds treats! 

 TD Ars Tribunus Militum Registered: Oct 20, 1999 Posts: 1562 Posted: Wed Apr 19, 2000 1:32 am You think you can do anything you want in private property? A restaurant might seem open. A mall might seem open. But they are far from being public places.
Morons... 

 Enkidu &quot;Shaka, when the walls fell.&quot;
Ars Praefectus
et Subscriptor Tribus: Seattle, WA Registered: Apr 11, 2000 Posts: 4620 Posted: Wed Apr 19, 2000 2:01 am &quot;That&apos;s pretty low mister. If I had a rubber hose I would beat you - &quot;
 

 Dusty Smack-Fu Master, in training Registered: Nov 11, 1999 Posts: 64 Posted: Wed Apr 19, 2000 2:24 am For the sake of argument: did anyone stop to think that bringing food from one establishment into another may constitute a violation of health department laws? Much like bringing flora into the USA from another country without permission and trying to get it through customs. And what if a restaurant which sat 30 people had 15 people eating there with food from another establishment,occupying seats which could be filled by paying customers of that establishment??? 1,2,or 15...do you make an exception? Think about it...what would you do if you were the manager??? Cheers 

 continuum Moderator
et Subscriptor Tribus: California Registered: Jul 1, 1999 Posts: 66884 Posted: Wed Apr 19, 2000 2:24 am Legally, they&apos;ve got the right to kick you out. If they have a specific health reason or whatever, fine... but if they didn&apos;t. Well.
That&apos;s just rude. The fact that your GF had paid and was eating there made it intolerable, IMHO... 

 MR2DI4 Ars Praefectus
et Subscriptor Tribus: Next to Nowhere, AK Registered: Feb 22, 2000 Posts: 5347 Posted: Wed Apr 19, 2000 3:43 am Thank you for that quote from &quot;National Lampoons Christmas Vacation&quot; Enkidu. I love that movie, watch it every Christmas.
I agree with the general consensus that this has been blown way out of proportion.
Ruffahsta, just be cool and you&apos;ll be fine.
MR2DI4 
[This message has been edited by MR2DI4 (edited April 19, 2000).] 

 Ruffahsta Smack-Fu Master, in training Registered: Apr 13, 2000 Posts: 14 Posted: Wed Apr 19, 2000 6:13 am quote: Originally posted by Dusty:
 For the sake of argument: did anyone stop to think that bringing food from one establishment into another may constitute a violation of health department laws? Much like bringing flora into the USA from another country without permission and trying to get it through customs. And what if a restaurant which sat 30 people had 15 people eating there with food from another establishment,occupying seats which could be filled by paying customers of that establishment??? 1,2,or 15...do you make an exception? Think about it...what would you do if you were the manager??? Cheers Mcdonalds is very trustable billions and billions served, the mger better hope i dont see him in public ,cause i will beat his ccs ass
[This message has been edited by Ruffahsta (edited April 19, 2000).] 

 Gavacho Smack-Fu Master, in training Registered: Feb 6, 2000 Posts: 74 Posted: Wed Apr 19, 2000 6:29 am quote: Originally posted by Dusty:
 For the sake of argument: did anyone stop to think that bringing food from one establishment into another may constitute a violation of health department laws? Much like bringing flora into the USA from another country without permission and trying to get it through customs. And what if a restaurant which sat 30 people had 15 people eating there with food from another establishment,occupying seats which could be filled by paying customers of that establishment??? 1,2,or 15...do you make an exception? Think about it...what would you do if you were the manager??? Cheers 
If I were the Manager, I would ask him if he wanted to buy a drink.
Or ignore him. As long as someone at the table was buying from me/my place I wouldn&apos;t have a problem. Unless it became epidemic. If, say 30% of the people were eating stuff from other restaurants AND I was low on seating space, I would have to ask those not eating my stuff to make room for the paying customers; olitely: .
 

 MrBigglesworth Ars Tribunus Angusticlavius Tribus: OKC Registered: Mar 18, 2000 Posts: 8643 Posted: Wed Apr 19, 2000 7:04 am Go Ruff...Go Ruff.... Bwaahahaha...Open up a CAN!!! 

 XaiaX &quot;pedicabo ego vos et irrumabo&quot;
Senator
et Subscriptor Tribus: A Sufficiently Advanced Parody is Indistinguishable from Madness Registered: Aug 31, 1999 Posts: 29999 Posted: Wed Apr 19, 2000 7:53 am Sadly, none of you see the problem with the manager&apos;s attitude that many corporate food service places like to impound upon.
When people have a bad time, they tell other people. Other people remember this bad time, and it reflects on the business.
The manager, whatever may have been his &quot;right&quot; was stupid. He offended a paying customer, in full view of other customers, who may also have thought the manager rude and stupid. He lost more than one person&apos;s business.
It was a bad business decision, regardless of however much you think it was his &quot;right&quot; to make that bad business decision.
If he had said nothing, there wouldn&apos;t have been a problem, no sales lost, nothing. Instead, for some sort of moral vindication he breaks the very core model of any business, to make money. If you drive away your customers, no matter how valid your reason, you&apos;re not making money.
Go talk to his regional manager, if it&apos;s a corporate store. An old manager of mine had some people towed off our property--we share a lot with a clothing sales place, and our drivers ran out of places to park--so they complained to the area manager, who told our store manager that it isn&apos;t worth it to piss people off simply because you think you have some sort of justification.
In short, the manager was a dumbass mofo. 

 Rand Ars Scholae Palatinae Registered: Feb 8, 2000 Posts: 1069 Posted: Wed Apr 19, 2000 10:21 am While I agree that it isn&apos;t good etiquette to bring food from one establishment to a different one, I don&apos;t think that you necessarily deserve to be kicked out. Deciding where to eat in a group of people can be tough. Sometimes you want to get food from different places, but you still want to eat together. Now, it isn&apos;t something to be proud of but if you do bring another place&apos;s food someplace with you when others of your group are eating at there I think it is rude of them to kick you out. While they may be well within their rights, it is still rude and you would be well within your rights to bitch about it. 

 Surge Ars Praefectus Tribus: /dev/null Registered: Jun 12, 1999 Posts: 3276 Posted: Wed Apr 19, 2000 3:32 pm My thing is its bad etiquette to bring another businesses food into another place if you were eating alone. However if you are eating there because you are with someone else who is eating there that doesn&apos;t make any sense. What is he supposed to eat inside the McDonald&apos;s while his girlfriend eats at CiCi&apos;s all by her lonesome self. That would be rude of him. And it was rude of the manager to kick out someone who was with a paying customer, because that is just as much a slap in the face to the customer as it is to them if not more(I say more). Also, its not like they served an alternative on the menu. If he was eating McDonald&apos;s chicken sandwich and fries all that says is that he is in the mood for a chicken sandwich and fries, but CiCi&apos;s doesn&apos;t sell chicken sandwichs or fries so he went next door to get it and came back to eat with his companion. That&apos;s all the customers would assume. It doesn&apos;t reflect badly on CiCi&apos;s except it just points out that CiCi&apos;s doesn&apos;t serve chicken sandwichs. That&apos;s all. If he had come back in with Pizza from Dominoes then that would have been rude because CiCi&apos;s offers a viable alternative and that says that CiCi&apos;s makes bad Pizza. All his bringing McD&apos;s in says is that CiCi&apos;s doesn&apos;t make chicken sandwiches and that he wanted to eat with his girlfriend which is a hard fact.

[This message has been edited by godlike (edited April 19, 2000).] 
 45 posts • 1 2    Next Ars Technica &gt; Forums &gt; Ars Lykaion &gt; The Lounge Jump to: Select a forum ------------------ Hardware&amp;Tweaking   Audio/Visual Club   Case and Cooling Fetish   CPU&amp;Motherboard Technologia   Mobile Computing Outpost   Networking Matrix   Other Hardware   Agora Classifieds Operating Systems&amp;Software   Battlefront   Microsoft OS&amp;Software Colloquium   Linux Kung Fu   Windows Technical Mojo   Distributed Computing Arcana   Macintoshian Achaia   Programmer&apos;s Symposium   The Server Room Ars Lykaion   Gaming, Extra Strength Caplets   The Lounge   The Soap Box   The Boardroom   The Observatory   Ars Help&amp;Feedback Ars Subscription Member Areas   Image Galleries 
 Contact Us | Ars Technica 

 ©Ars Technica 1998-2012 

Powered by phpBB and...

 

©2012 CondéNast. All rights reserved
Use of this Site constitutes acceptance of our User Agreement (effective 3/21/12) and Privacy Policy (effective 3/21/12)
 Your California Privacy Rights 
The material on this site may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, cached or otherwise used, except with the prior written permission of CondéNast.
 Ad Choices
	</body>
</document>
