<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001911" url="http://www.yelp.com/biz/burger-king-san-francisco-14" time="2012-07-12-17:49" support="1" score="0.002237826034265285" bingtitle="Burger King - Fisherman&apos;s Wharf - San Francisco, CA" webtitle="Burger King - Fisherman&apos;s Wharf - San Francisco, CA">
			<query id="001196" bing-rank="78"/>
	<description>Worst Burger King (or any fast food restaurant I&apos;ve ... The guy kept offering me my receipt ... I guess the tourist will keep it functional for now. And cashier, either ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Search Form Skip to Navigation Skip to Page Content 

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 Log In Sign Up for Yelp Friends&apos; Activity 0 Loading... 
 Yelp is using Facebook to personalize your experience. What is this? Not you?
 Log out of Facebook Don&apos;t want to be connected?
 How to turn this off 
 
 Yelp 
 Real people. Real reviews. ® 
 
 Search for (e.g. taco, cheap dinner, Max&apos;s) 

 Near (Address, Neighborhood , City, State or Zip) 
 Search 
 Welcome About Me Write a Review Find Reviews Find Friends Messaging Talk 

 Member Search 
   
Burger King
 12 reviews Rating Details 
 Category: Restaurants Fast Food Fast Food   [Edit] 
 2739 Taylor St 
(between Beach St&amp;Jefferson St)
 San Francisco , CA 94133 
Neighborhood: Fisherman&apos;s Wharf
 (415) 674-8159 http://www.burgerking.com Menu 
 
 Add Photos Price Range: $ 
 Accepts Credit Cards: Yes
 Parking: Street
 Attire: Casual
 Good for Groups: No
 Good for Kids: Yes
 Takes Reservations: No
 Delivery: No
 Take-out: Yes
 Waiter Service: No
 Outdoor Seating: No
 Wi-Fi: No
 Good For: Lunch, Dinner, Breakfast
 Alcohol: No
 Drive-Thru: No
 Noise Level: Loud
 Has TV: No
 Caters: No
 Wheelchair Accessible: Yes
 First to Review Angela H. 
 Edit Business Info Work Here? Unlock This Business Page 
 Send to Friend Bookmark Send to Phone Write a Review Yelp Ad Wiki Wiki Hawaiian 90 reviews 
 Kevin P. said: &quot;This is one of my many go-to&apos;s in Berkeley.  The place is spacious enough and I the food is USUALLY (see note) delicious. I think the one thing that stands out about Wiki Wiki are their portions. Their regular-sized dishes should be…&quot;   read more» 
 
12 reviews for Burger King
 Reviews Matching: Search Reviews Sort by: Yelp Sort | Date | Rating | Elites&apos; | Facebook Friends&apos; 
Facebook Friends


 
From Reviewers You&apos;re Following 


 
Reviews from Your Friends


 
12 reviews in English

 
Review from Elaine H. 
 
 133 friends 819 reviews 

 Elaine H. 
 
San Francisco, CA
 11/4/2008 
Service - there was close to none. But what do you expect from fast food companies??
Whooper Junior - cheap, and sure beats the crap out of McDonalds cause it has freakin lettuce!! Bigger too. But of course I still can&apos;t help thinking that McDonalds is supposed to be the &quot;happy place&quot; for kids.

This location is huge and opens until 12am.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Lasairiona M. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 13 friends 158 reviews 

 Lasairiona M. 
 
Missouri City, TX
 12/30/2011 
Worst Burger King (or any fast food restaurant I&apos;ve ever been to).

I just wanted to use the restroom (seriously San Franciscans, where the hell do you pee? 3 coffee shops, 2 Starbucks and NO toilet!!!!) and to queue up to use it, I had to buy something and get a token from the manager - something that wasn&apos;t just a drink.

The food was disgusting, cold, obviously reheated, the place was disgustingly dirty, trash strewn everywhere and the toilet, that I queued up for 10 minutes to use and paid $10 for the pleasure was equally as disgusting.

Avoid at all costs!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Zain D. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 7 friends 141 reviews 

 Zain D. 
 
San Francisco, CA
 10/10/2011 
Service: Crappy, the guy working the register is cranky and doesn&apos;t speak English.

Price: Overpriced and underserved like most BK places.

Food: As over overpriced as it is, BK food is delicious, unless you buy it from here.  The veggie burger was sloppy and falling apart.  The fries were stale and cold.

You&apos;re MUCH better off walking down to In-N-Out or McDonalds, both are just a few minutes away.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Monica N. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 108 friends 296 reviews 

 Monica N. 
 
San Francisco, CA
 1/30/2011 1 Check-in Here 
Ugh. Slow service, the cashier was handling cash and food...yuck!
I was observing the cashier, they food people made the fries, placed it in the ready to serve fries box. This guy goes and pours it back into the pile, flips the fries a little, and place in back into the box again? I waited for over 15 minutes for my turn, and there were precisely 3 person in front of me. Wow. I wonder how long this place will survive. I guess the tourist will keep it functional for now.
And cashier, either put on some gloves, or wash your hands each time you touch food... cuz them money is hecka dirty.. that your handling!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Angela H. 
 
 140 friends 497 reviews 

 Angela H. 
 
Daly City, CA
 10/21/2007 
I didn&apos;t think that my culinary experience at Fisherman&apos;s Wharf could get any more miserable than it already was, but I was wrong- you can enter an even deeper level of gastronomic hell by dining at this Burger King!  So after a miserable experience eating the crappy shrimp sandwich, I decided I wanted some onion rings.  Burger King is close by and I figure that you can&apos;t go wrong with a national chain.  I realize that I must have been suffering from heat stroke if I actually thought that Burger King was going to be any good.

So first off, there is a ridiculously long line full of tourists eager to partake in what the King is offering.  Nothing unexpected about that at Fisherman&apos;s Wharf, but having only one cashier work that line is just plain stupid.  It also didn&apos;t help that the family in front of me decided to order just about one of everything off the menu and take a good 10 minutes doing it.

Finally, I get to the front of the line, order my onion rings, and wait.  And wait.  And wait some more.  I eventually get what was supposed to be a medium order of rings, but oh wait, the box is only half full.  I&apos;m normally not one to confront anyone, but the indignity of having to wait that long for one crappy order of onion rings take over and I can&apos;t help but bitch to the worker about the missing half of the order.  Not that he cares, because he looks at the half empty box and says that is what a medium order should be.  Sigh...I guess today really was my day in food hell.

Needless to say, after today&apos;s debacle, heading back to the Wharf to eat is not on my list of to-do&apos;s.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (4) Funny (3) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jennifer L. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 73 friends 325 reviews 

 Jennifer L. 
 
San Francisco, CA
 9/28/2011 1 Check-in Here 
I ordered a soda, and this was a mistake.  I think that we have all been spoiled by McDonald&apos;s offering $1 soda&apos;s all the time, so I had a little sticker shock when I plaid $2.16 for a SMALL soda.  The guy kept offering me my receipt although I told him I didn&apos;t need it.  SO, either he was being way too pushy or he didn&apos;t speak english.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Veronica O. 
 
 32 friends 53 reviews 

 Veronica O. 
 
Los Angeles, CA
 12/8/2008 
Fast food what can you expect, and you cant get any sauce unless you pay extra for it wich is pretty lame.
The reason i gave it 2 stars is because i rather eat this horrible cancer food then buy the overpriced gimpy sea food along the side. As for going mcdonalds .. -.- i dont think they have vegi burger so burger king it is i guess if your at fishermans wharf
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Satina N. 
 
 2 friends 1 review 

 Satina N. 
 
San Fernando, Cádiz
 Spain 11/17/2011 
I would say burger king is ok regarding that its a fast food restaurant , there meal is big enough price is average, and the meals taste ok
 
 Listed in: Fast for Hungry 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Bennett W. 
 
 73 friends 824 reviews 

 Bennett W. 
 
San Francisco, CA
 8/28/2011 
Located very conveniently in Fisherman&apos;s Wharf, this is one of the best Burger King locations even though I&apos;ve been here once.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Kyle S. 
 
 28 friends 113 reviews 

 Kyle S. 
 
Mill Valley, CA
 7/7/2011 
This has to be the cleanest Burger King I&apos;ve seen, which is surprising as its in the city. The order was fast and the food was nice and hot, no complaints.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Kevin G. 
 
 53 friends 332 reviews 

 Kevin G. 
 
Clemmons, NC
 5/12/2009 
I used to work on Pier 39 and walked by this place every morning.  Two stars for being able to order a Whopper for breakfast.  Im not a pancake or biscuit person so much.  Minus three stars for management allowing panhandlers to hang out in the restaurant.  I see nothing wrong with allowing them to be there but I&apos;d get asked for money more than once each time I was there.  Plus I never really got used to saying no and feeling comfortable with it.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Rhiana J. 
 
 10 friends 20 reviews 

 Rhiana J. 
 
Manteca, CA
 8/3/2009 
Avoid the place at all costs. I work nearby and have been ripped of more than once by going here. The food is standard burger king fare at twice the normal price. The employees don&apos;t speak a word of English so it&apos;s almost possible to order and they often make substituons without asking you first.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
 ( 7 Filtered )  
 
 Write a Review View Larger Map/Directions 
Browse Nearby:
 
 Restaurants | Nightlife | Shopping | Movies | All 
 
Deals Nearby
 More» 
 $20 for $40 Deal Arabian Nights San Francisco, CA $10 for $20 Deal Kama Sushi San Francisco, CA 
 
People Who Viewed This Also Viewed...
 
 In-N-Out Burger  846 reviews &quot;Animal style was amazing with chopped grilled onions.&quot; China Station  9 reviews &quot;...dive inside the anchorage shopping center along the wharf.&quot; IHOP  75 reviews &quot;The Strawberry Passion Fruit Pancakes was delish too.&quot; China House Bar&amp;Restaurant  23 reviews &quot;...so friendly and attentive (but not *too* attentive) and the...&quot; New Golden Daisy  119 reviews &quot;This place has the BEST fried chicken drummettes.&quot; 
 
Related Lists
 More» 
 Fast for Hungry 
Where you can drive to in a hurry and get a quick bite
 
 
People Viewed This After Searching For...
 
 Fast Food San Francisco 
 
About

 About Yelp Yelp Blog Press Investor Relations Terms of Service Privacy Policy 
 
Help

 FAQ Advertise Content Guidelines Contact Yelp Business Support Developers 
 
More

 Careers Yelp Mobile The Weekly Yelp Yelp Apparel RSS Top Searches 
 
Countries

 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany 

 Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom 
 
Language

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 
 
 San Francisco Business Listings # A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z | Newly Added 

 Site Map | Atlanta | Austin | Boston | Chicago | Dallas | Denver | Detroit | Honolulu | Houston | Los Angeles | Miami | Minneapolis | New York | Philadelphia | Portland | Sacramento | San Diego | San Francisco | San Jose | Seattle | Washington, DC | More Cities 

Copyright©2004-2012 Yelp Inc. Yelp logo and related marks are registered trademarks of Yelp. All rights reserved.
 
 Email Address Step 1 of 2 Zip Code 
 
Hey , you can use Facebook to make signing up for Yelp even faster . Yes, use Facebook to sign up 
 Already have an account? Log In Now 
 Email Address Password Zip Code Birthdate (Optional) --- Jan Feb Mar Apr May Jun Jul Aug Sep Oct Nov Dec --- 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 --- 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 2000 1999 1998 1997 1996 1995 1994 1993 1992 1991 1990 1989 1988 1987 1986 1985 1984 1983 1982 1981 1980 1979 1978 1977 1976 1975 1974 1973 1972 1971 1970 1969 1968 1967 1966 1965 1964 1963 1962 1961 1960 1959 1958 1957 1956 1955 1954 1953 1952 1951 1950 1949 1948 1947 1946 1945 1944 1943 1942 1941 1940 1939 1938 1937 1936 1935 1934 1933 1932 1931 1930 1929 1928 1927 1926 1925 1924 1923 1922 1921 1920 1919 1918 1917 1916 1915 1914 1913 1912 1911 1910 1909 1908 1907 1906 1905 1904 1903 1902 1901 Country 
 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom United States 
 
 United States Change 
 
By clicking the button below, you agree to the Yelp Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .
 
 
 Cancel Sign Up 
 
 Use Facebook to sign up faster! 
 Already have an account? Log In Now 
 First Name Last Name Email Address Password City / Town: Zip Code Birthdate (Optional) --- Jan Feb Mar Apr May Jun Jul Aug Sep Oct Nov Dec --- 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 --- 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 2000 1999 1998 1997 1996 1995 1994 1993 1992 1991 1990 1989 1988 1987 1986 1985 1984 1983 1982 1981 1980 1979 1978 1977 1976 1975 1974 1973 1972 1971 1970 1969 1968 1967 1966 1965 1964 1963 1962 1961 1960 1959 1958 1957 1956 1955 1954 1953 1952 1951 1950 1949 1948 1947 1946 1945 1944 1943 1942 1941 1940 1939 1938 1937 1936 1935 1934 1933 1932 1931 1930 1929 1928 1927 1926 1925 1924 1923 1922 1921 1920 1919 1918 1917 1916 1915 1914 1913 1912 1911 1910 1909 1908 1907 1906 1905 1904 1903 1902 1901 Gender (Optional) Male Female Country 
 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom United States 
 
 United States Change 
 
By clicking the button below, you agree to the Yelp Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .
 
 
 Cancel Sign Up 
 No account yet? Create an Account 
 Email Password 
 
 Cancel Log In 
 
Add a Profile Picture

More people will read your reviews and you will be one step closer to the Yelp Elite Squad if you have a profile picture.
 Import Facebook Photo You don&apos;t have Flash installed, Facebook Connect requires the latest version of Flash
	</body>
</document>
