<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001208" url="http://www.ehow.co.uk/about_6579137_restaurant-industry-information.html" time="2012-07-12-16:39" support="6" score="0.025273202437506914" bingtitle="Restaurant Business Marketing Information | eHow.co.uk" webtitle="Fast Food Restaurant Business Plan | eHow.co.uk">
			<query id="000314" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000342" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000329" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000341" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="000321" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="000603" bing-rank="234"/>
	<description>For example, large fast food restaurant chains run ... to track their advertising to estimate the return ... Tempting trays: festive party food</description>
	<body>
		Food Home Style Money Family Health more 

 Computers&amp;electronics Hobbies 

 Lifestyle 

 Science&amp;education 

 
 
 eHow.co.uk » Money » Fast Food Restaurant Business Plan 
 
 
 
Fast Food Restaurant Business Plan
 Written by Contributing Writer 
Starting a fast-food restaurant requires a business plan.
 
 Success in any new business begins with a business plan, and a fast-food restaurant is no exception. Business plans open with an executive summary, which is an overview of the information provided throughout the plan. The business plan functions like a blueprint that guides the business owners from the start-up into the first three to five years of operation. A start-up business plan for a fast-food restaurant documents every detail of how the location will operate. 
 
Executive Summary
 
The executive summary estimates how much funding will be required to start and operate the fast food restaurant until it becomes profitable. Income projections for the first three to five years also should be identified in the executive summary. A description of the proposed fast-food restaurant, which identifies the unique aspects of the operation, should be included in the executive summary. The break-even date is an important milestone in any start-up business plan and must be identified in the executive summary. Even though the executive summary is placed at the beginning of the business plan document, it should be the last part written. You need to have the content of the plan for your restaurant in place before you can draft an executive summary.
 

 
Restaurant Concept
 
The concept, theme and type of cuisine to be served are essential components that should be documented in detail in the fast-food restaurant start-up business plan.
 

 
Start-Up Expenses
 
The restaurant start-up business plan budget must document each anticipated expense. There will be one-time start-up costs, such as initial construction, building alterations and equipment and furniture purchases. Administrative costs, such as a business license, permits and labor, also are included in the start-up business plan for a restaurant. Ongoing expenses, such as packaging and supplies, also should be included.
 

 
Budgets
 
The start-up budget identifies the costs to open the fast-food restaurant. Every business has fixed expenses and variable expenses. The fixed expenses are expenses that are the same every month, such as mortgage payments and utilities. Variable expenses can occur monthly, quarterly or annually, such as marketing activities and advertising expenses. Emergency repairs would be an example of a variable expense.
 

 
Marketing and Advertising
 
Advertising and marketing plans are essential components in a restaurant business plan. The advertising and marketing plans determine what methods will be implemented to promote the restaurant. Media advertising campaigns, such as print and television and network marketing, are examples of marketing and advertising plans. Advertising and marketing account executives assist restaurant owners in the development of newspaper advertisements, radio ads and marketing activities. Marketing activities, such as participating in Chamber of Commerce events, are popular methods of promoting a restaurant.
 

 
 References 

 Food Equipment News: Loans for Restaurant Business 
 
 Resources 

 Entrepreneur.com: How to Start a Restaurant BusinessInfoGuide: Start a Food Service Business 
 
 Don’t miss: Slideshows 
 
 The top 10 baby books for mummies 10 odd band food demands Kings of social media, the most popular Facebook pages 
 
 Comments 
 
Editors’ pick
 Your guide to affordable flats in London 
Social activity

What your friends are reading
 
You may also like…

 How to Write a Business Plan for a Soul Food Restaurant Drafting a Restaurant Business Plan How to Write a Restaurant Business Plan How to Start a Fast Food Restaurant How to Open a Fast Food Business 
 
More editors’ picks

 When good food goes bad: 12 rotten food signs The UK&apos;s top affordable restaurants 9 home-made baby food recipes 20 Ways to improve your life 
 
Copyright©1999-2012 Demand Media, Inc. About us 

Use of this site constitutes acceptance of the Terms of use and Privacy policy of eHow. Ad Choices en-GB
	</body>
</document>
