<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001770" url="http://www.jmposner.co.uk/the-dog-hut-hotdog-steamer-p-360.html" time="2012-07-12-17:33" support="7" score="0.009687590889914235" bingtitle="The Dog Hut Hotdog Steamer Dog Hut Hotdog Steamer [] - £449.95 ..." webtitle="The Dog Hut Hotdog Steamer Dog Hut Hotdog Steamer [] -449.95 : JM Posner, for Professional Caterers, chocolate fountains, popcorn makers and chocolate">
			<query id="000229" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="000337" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="001536" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="000531" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000343" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000251" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000344" bing-rank="8"/>
	<description>Drink Fountains n BBQ; Supplies; Candelabras; Distributors ... concession stand, vending cart, break room, fast food restaurant ... • Removable product trays and sliding doors allow for ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Log In 
   
 
 
 Products for Home Chocolate Fountains Popcorn Makers Candy Floss Waffles Made in America Chocolate Popcorn Seasoning Drink Fountains n BBQ Supplies Candelabras Distributors 
 
 
Wish List
 
 Log In to be able to add this product to your Wish List.
 
Translations

 
 
Need Help?
 
 
 (0)20 8421 9482 
 E-Mail us 
 
 
Chat with IM
 

 
Latest Blog Posts
 
 Spotlight on Semar Italia. New waffle making venture in Italy… Vintage inspired wedding ideas A Chocolate Twist to a Wimbledon Favourite! 
 
New 2012 Brochure
 
 
 
Notifications
 
Notify me of updates to The Dog Hut Hotdog Steamer Home  ::  Made in America  :: The Dog Hut Hotdog Steamer 
 
 Made in America 
Product 22/22
 
 larger image 
The Dog Hut Hotdog Steamer

£449.95 Excl VAT
 Add to Cart: 

 
 £449.95 + VAT 

 You will find everything that you need in a hot dog machine, from The Paragon Hot Dog Hut, ideal if you want one for a rental shop, convenience store, concession stand, vending cart, break room, fast food restaurant, snack bar, cafeteria and many others uses! It is packed full of features that makes it easy for you to use, flexible enough that you can offer a range of hot dog or sausage options and durable enough for you to use every day. 

 
 Features: 
• Heavy Duty 20 gauge stainless steel construction throughout, making the Dog Hut™ the most durable hotdog steamer in its class.
• Removable product trays and sliding doors allow for easy access to hotdogs and buns and makes for simple easy clean up.
• Dishwasher safe!
• Revolutionary proprietary heating system featuring heavy duty submersible stainless steel element and automatic shutoff feature when water gets below a certain level.
• Low water indicator light and illuminated on/off switch.
• variable adjustable thermostat increases versatility of the Dog Hut™ being able to perform in any and all cooking and holding conditions.
• accommodates any size hotdog (or sausage) and bun holding up to a maximum of 200 hotdogs and 42 buns.
• 13 pint water reservoir for increased holding times is the largest in the business! Plus, the quick turn water release valve eliminates burned fingers and spilt water.
• Standard divided hotdog tray accommodates any size hotdogs and sausages and allows for various sizes of hotdogs or sausages to be cooked and merchandised simultaneously.
• Graphics on both sides allow for either front-counter or rear-counter merchandising. 

 Product Specs: 
34 w x 41 d x 51 h cm
230 volts
1200 watts 
 
 Add to Cart: 

 
 Manufactured by: Paragon 

 
 larger image 
 larger image 
 
Product 22/22
 
 
 
 
Like, Join, Follow us
 
 Follow @jmposneruk 
 
Need Supplies?
 
Tell A Friend
   
Tell someone you know about this product. 
 Reviews  [more] 
 
Write a review on this product. 
 
 Home Contact Us  ::  News  ::  About  ::  Shipping  ::  Returns Policy  ::  T&amp;C  ::  Links  ::  Privacy Statement  ::  Site Map  ::  Wish List  ::  Chocolate Fountains  ::  Popcorn Makers  ::  Candy Floss  ::  New Products  ::  Waffles  ::  Waffles  ::  Chocolate  ::  Popcorn Seasoning  ::  Juice, Drinks Fountains and BBQ  ::  Supplies  ::  Candelabras  ::  Distributors 
 Your IP Address is: 212.185.208.100 Copyright©2012 JM Posner for Professional Caterers . Powered by Zen Cart 
Designed and Maintained by Fluid Works UK 
 
Chocolate Fountains and accessories to buy, Chocolate for Chocolate Fountains, Popcorn Makers and accessories to buy, Popcorn Seasoning, Candy Floss Makers and accessories, Candy Floss Sugars and other food entertainment products.

Chocolate Fountain Products and Information
 
JM Posner ltd has a wide range of Professional Chocolate Fountains to buy for chocolate fountain businesses and all the chocolate fountain accessories and supplies you may need to run your chocolate fountain business, from chocolate fountain surrounds to chocolate for chocolate fountains. We also offer advice on how to get the most from your chocolate fountain business, including articles on Chocolate Efficiency , Easy ways to make your Chocolate Fountain Profitable , Trouble shooting guide for melting chocolate for chocolate fountains , Chocolate Fountain Buyers Guide , and discussing new trends in chocolate fountains.
 
Popcorn Makers and Popcorn accessories
 
Here at JM Posner we have a wide range of popcorn makers for home and business , including the highly acclaimed range of Paragon Popcorn Makers from the States! The range includes differing popcorn machine functions and styles to suit your needs, and popcorn maker accessories and supplies include a range of popcorn kernels , popcorn seasoning , popcorn bags and popcorn boxes; so you can find everything you need for you’re the popcorn offering you have in your business. If you want a popcorn maker to complete your home cinema experience, then why not look into the Home Cinema Popcorn Kit , which includes a 2.5oz Popcorn Maker, popcorn kernels, popcorn seasoning , popcorn boxes and a popcorn recipe book to use with popcorn seasonings, for a 26% saving! Our Blog also includes information and advice on popcorn makers including Popping profits: using a popcorn maker in your business , How to make sweet popcorn , Delicious Popcorn Recipes , Popcorn and Nutrition: is popcorn good for you? Popcorn Maker Buyers Guide , FAQ’s about popcorn and popcorn makers , Perfect Popcorn: easy how-to guide to get the best results from your popcorn maker .


Get a free Hot Dogs Steamer or Waffle Maker for your business

JM Posner specialises in products that make you money, and we pride ourselves on offering everything you might need for your business offering, whether its catering grade equipment or supplies and accessories to support you business. So what could be better than getting a ready made business, saving you time, effort and money, using the UKs most recognised hotdog brand Herta? Hot dogs are a convenient, tasty snack for the whole family and easy for you to produce, the margins are great and with minimal effort you can have a hot dog steamer and business in next to no time. For more details on how to get your hot dog steamer and start serving hot dogs in your business, contact us for details.


If hot dogs arent your thing; try one of our many waffle makers , in a range of shapes and with dry waffle mix, minimal hassle. Round Belgian waffles , Stick Waffles and Square American Breakfast waffles all give off enticing aromas to pull customers in, are incredibly verstaile as they can be served savoury or sweet with a range of toppings. If you want to add a waffle offering your business, then call us today to find out how we can help.
	</body>
</document>
