<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001240" url="http://orangecounty.citysearch.com/profile/40106379/tustin_ca/ono_ono_hawaiian_bbq_veggie.html" time="2012-07-12-16:41" support="7" score="0.017495543851949433" bingtitle="Ono Ono Hawaiian BBQ &amp; Veggie - Tustin, CA, 92780 - Citysearch" webtitle="Ono Ono Hawaiian BBQ&amp;Veggie - Tustin, CA, 92780 - Citysearch">
			<query id="001260" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="000978" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="001417" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="000101" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000947" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="001040" bing-rank="231"/>
			<query id="000443" bing-rank="144"/>
	<description>This is essentially a fast food restaurant, so it&apos;s not like ... Big menu selection of different variety of ... have to guess when he finishes bagging my order</description>
	<body>
		Deals Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Hotels Shopping Best Of Citysearch 

 Mobile Login / Join 
 More More Go! Advertise With Us 
 Citysearch has shed its old skin! In addition to our new look, there&apos;s a boatload of new features. Poke around! Tell us what you think! 
 Orange County, CA Metro &gt; Tustin &gt; Restaurants &gt; Ono Ono Hawaiian BBQ&amp;Veggie 
Ono Ono Hawaiian BBQ&amp;Veggie
 (714) 505-0750 
 17582 17th St Ste 104 , Tustin , CA | Directions  
 92780 33.759600 -117.825501 View Website 
 
 Hours 
 Sunday Closed ,Monday 10:00AM - 9:00PM ,Tuesday 10:00AM - 9:00PM ,Wednesday 10:00AM - 9:00PM ,Thursday 10:00AM - 9:00PM ,Friday 10:00AM - 9:00PM ,Saturday 10:00AM - 9:00PM Menu Order Share Save 
 Recommend this business? Thumbs Up Thumbs Down ? 75 % 100 12 8 Votes Add a Photo Categories: Barbecue Restaurants , Restaurants 
 View Less 
 Site Feedback 
 Overview Tips (12) Photos (0) 
 Write a Tip for Ono Ono Hawaiian BBQ&amp;Veg… 
 Sign in to Write a Tip 
 Write a Tip... optional 
 
 
Tips for Ono Ono Hawaiian BBQ&amp;Veggie
 Recommends twicegiving Joined 2 years ago 5.0 August 15, 2010 
 New Home Page done!. Good Hawaiian Food&amp;Good Luau Party Caterer..
 0 Heart Doesn&apos;t Recommend Sallieann Joined 4 years ago 2.0 December 21, 2008 
 Food&amp;service needs improving. went there to meet some old friends from highschool for lunch. The place was nice, clean and well lit. The lady that took our order was sweet and helped us pick out our food since it was our first time being there, and those are about the only things that were&quot;good&quot;about that place. It took awhile for us to get our food about 25mins not to mention the noodles and rice were already cold. YUCK!!! The waiter acted like he was jacked up on coffee, he was running around all over the place and DIDNOT pay ANY attention to us at all when all I wanted was to ask him if he could re-do my rice and noodles.

Thanks to the WAITER I highly-doubt I will eat there again!!!!!!!! … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends dpgyrl026 Joined 5 years ago 5.0 January 30, 2008 
 Best Hawaiian food, good price, and sweet owners.. Excellent, authentic food (with added korean menu items). I can&apos;t recommend anything because everything is good. People seriously need to shut up about the service. This is essentially a fast food restaurant, so it&apos;s not like the&quot;screening process&quot;is going to be like that of government. That was simply bad luck.

It&apos;s a Mom and Pop shop owned by two very sweet people name Kris and Keith. I only know that because they are always super friendly when we come. While they are owners, they are very personable. But again...good service or not, the food is good enough and cheap enough that I would dismiss any bad service if existent. This is definitely a home for&quot;regulars&quot;and locals... much better than L&amp;L&apos;s, The Loft...Aloha..you name it. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends remqnguyen Joined 7 years ago 3.0 January 10, 2008 
 Good Hawaiian Food but hold onto your belongings tight!!!. Decided to try Ono Ono because of decent reviews. Big menu selection of different variety of&quot;Hawaiian Food&quot;. I decided to go with beef and fish. Food was well prepared and actually tasted good. Portion size was just right. Fish wasn&apos;t fresh but hey you can&apos;t expect at that price they were charging. So far no complaints. I thought, this is nice change from the burger joints. This is where the other reviewer was right about their service. After I got back from work, my friend gave me call stated that his bag was missing. He went back to Ono Ono and the bus boy told him he didn&apos;t see it. So my buddy rushes home to cancel his credit cards, etc. An hour later, the Tustin PD called him. Well it turns out the Police pulled some joker over with his registration scratched off. They found a bag of pakalolo and my friend&apos;s bag. The guy had his bag and was with his friends driving south on the 55 in his buddy&apos;s car. It was the bus boy from Ono Ono and he straight out lied to my buddy when he asked him about it. The Tustin PD asked what they were doing with the bag and the bus boy said he was going to turn it into work the next day. After they got the police report he changed his story that he was just going to throw everything away when he got home. I can only give Ono Ono low marks, this incident left a bad taste in our mouths. Its worth a try, just make sure you hold on belongings tight or just do take out! … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Doesn&apos;t Recommend rrh888 Joined 5 years ago 1.0 May 14, 2007 
 Food is decent - service needs LOT&apos;s of improvement. Food is decent, but the couple times I tried it, the service was bad. I gave the place a 2nd chance but doubt I&apos;ll go back.
Here&apos;s the problem:
- I order take out. - The server never bothers to call out when take out is ready.

- I have to guess when he finishes bagging my order

- I finally notice several people that order after me pick up their orders

- Then I ask about mine and he pulls it up.

- Guy could have saved me 10 min if he bothered to call out orders

2nd

Hi didn&apos;t properly put the caps on any of the sauces and they all leak out.

What incompetence.

If you don&apos;t care about the service, the food is fine though. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart 
 See more tips for Ono Ono Hawaiian BBQ&amp;Veggie 
 Write a Tip for Ono Ono Hawaiian BBQ&amp;Veg… 
 Sign in to Write a Tip 
 Write a Tip... optional 
 
 
People who viewed this also viewed…
 
 Mc Charles House Restau… 335 S C St 
 Tustin, CA 
1.2 mi away 100 % Kai Sushi 13112 Newport Ave 
 Tustin, CA 
1.1 mi away 100 % Christakis Greek Cuisin… 13011 Newport Ave Ste 113 
 Tustin, CA 
1.1 mi away 
 
Things to do near Ono Ono Hawaiian BBQ&amp;Veggie
 
 Restaurants Movie Theaters Banks 

 Bars Shopping&amp;Malls Hotels 
 
 About Apps Careers Privacy Policy Terms of Use Contact Us Blog FAQs 
 
Partner Sites:

 Ask Kids     Bloglines     Expedia     Hotels     Hotwire     Insider Pages     MerchantCircle     Reference     The Daily Beast     Thesaurus     Urbanspoon 
 ©2011. Citysearch is a registered trademark of CityGrid Media. Data provided by Infogroup. All rights reserved. 
 Popular Categories Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Shopping Hotels Deals Sports&amp;Recreation Cafes Movie Theaters Directory&amp;Services 

 Change City New York City Los Angeles Houston Chicago Atlanta Seattle Portland Philadelphia Austin San Francisco More…
	</body>
</document>
