<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001301" url="http://www.1up.com/news/subway-spokesman-nintendo-hate" time="2012-07-12-16:44" support="1" score="0.0019261695654679495" bingtitle="Subway Spokesman&apos;s Six Inches of Nintendo Hate: News from 1UP.com" webtitle="Subway Spokesman&apos;s Six Inches of Nintendo Hate: News from 1UP.com">
			<query id="000066" bing-rank="132"/>
	<description>But only if he ate them without condiments or dressing... ... bag of Lays potatoe chips or a big 20 ounce soda ... If anything games can make you NOT go to a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		UGO.com 1UP.com MyCheats GameVideos Free Games Actress Archives GameTab HeroMachine DVD and Blu-ray 
 Where Gamers Call Home 
 My 1UP 
 Points: 5 Rank: 
 Nooblet 
 Sign in to save your progress! Log In 
 
 PS3 Xbox 360 Wii PC DS PSP 
 Games News&amp;Reviews 
 News Reviews Previews Features Blogs Cover Stories 
 Cheats Videos 
 Gameplay Trailers Funny Shows 
 Shows 
 Games, Dammit! Retronauts Active-Time Babble 1UP @ YouTube 
 Community 
 My 1UP Page Latest Blogs Who&apos;s Online Clubs Trivia Contests Boards 1UP @ Facebook 1UP @ Twitter 
 
 
Subway Spokesman&apos;s Six Inches of Nintendo Hate

Jared Fogle blames NES and fatty foods for girth.
 By Dan Dormer , 01/18/2006 
 Share it: Tweet 
 Try this one on for size. The now 190lbs. Jared &quot;I lost a lot of weight eating only two Subway subs a day and walking a bunch, and now serve as the company&apos;s spokesperson&quot; Fogle, a man not half as famous as his tan, pleated pants recently outlined exactly why he reached 425 lbs., and it&apos;s not something gamers (or Nintendo fans) want to hear.
In a story by the Columbia Daily News, Jared revealed at a lecture at the University of Missouri-Columbia that he could trace his weight problems back to the source now, &quot;the best birthday present of my life: a Nintendo.&quot; And with his new found love of 8-bit princesses, Jared discovered another new love in junk food.
&quot;I usually had one hand on the controller and one in a bag of chips,&quot; said Jared. His parents, noticing the problem, tried to limit Jared&apos;s time playing videogames, but in his own words, &quot;... I found ways to get around it.&quot; Though, his tale gets worse. Instead of going on the bike rides he told his parents he was embarking on, the young Fogle instead booked it to the nearest fast food joint and order the &quot;fattiest meal possible with his allowance.&quot;
First Jack Thomspon... and now the huggable Jared Fogle? File this one under WTF, folks.
 

 
 Share it: E-mail it 120 
 Please Recommend 1UP on Facebook 
Comments (119)
 
 
 
Jared fogle is so inoying
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  coke399 
 I really hate that fat @$$.I remember I had a nes and ate at mcdonalds and I&apos;m not overweghit.What a lame name.Jared fogle.Sounds like jaret fordgole.I remember i ate at mcdonalds and orderd a bigmac.and when i got home i turned the tv on and i saw jareds dumb commercial saying how healthy subways sandwitchs are healther than mcdonalds bigmac.I have to say this.Suckway eat $hit.Go to mcdonalds.And mcdonalds papapapa.I&apos;m loving it and forget your subway diet jareds a pussy. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Whatever
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Pac-attack 
 Its clear to me that Jared had an eating problem, I&apos;ve been playing video games longer than he has, and I did not go over weight at all.
It looks to me that he wants to blame his guilt on Nintendo, if that helps him sleep better at night, then so be it. Flag | Reply 
 
 
one handed
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  TreyTable 
 I just wanna know how that fat f--- played one handed. 

Really, I remember when I got my NES, I too have a weigh problem, but when I&apos;m gaming, food is the last thing on my mind, maybe after six hours or so I may have a bite to eat, but busting his fat butt to get the&quot;biggest, fattiest meal possible with his allowance&quot;, how could that have anything to do with Nintendo or the NES? That sounds more like bi-polar.

Jared? Only six inches? No wonder you still don&apos;t have a girlfriend. ;) Flag | Reply 
 
 
I like subway and my nes
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  SectionZ 
 Sounds to me like old jared was just lazy. No one says you must play games and eat junkfood. Games just like food must not be played or eatin until you die. With that I would like a turkey wrap please.. no cheese! Flag | Reply 
 
 
Hey Jared......
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  urbanhispanic 
 just because you&apos;re the new Subway spokesman doesn&apos;t mean anything that comes out of your mouth is fact. The fact that that you always ate JUNK food while you played games and quite possibly ate junk food more than you played games was what made you FAT. Many kids played through lots of Nintendo games and were active in sports and just going outside to play. 

And Jared, your parents should have realized that you were eating so much junk food thus you blowing up faster than ballons for a birthday party. Now how about you shut your hole you call a mouth and stuff it with a Subway sandwhich full of fried meat and extra mayo, bee-atch!!! LOL :) Flag | Reply 
 
 
Fatty...
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  xLongShotx 
 I weigh 150lbs and i&apos;ve been playing for 22 years! Hahahahah! Flag | Reply 
 
 
Hmm...
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  JesusWasaZombie 
 He must not have been very good if he only kept one hand on the controller. If he kept both hands on it like he was supposed to, he wouldn&apos;t have been able to eat the junk food (unless he devised some sort of IV-method, or a dispensing device on the ceiling that put the food directly into his mouth). Personally, no one&apos;s been allowed to eat while playing any of my video games...it gets the controllers all grubby. Maybe Jared needs to take some responsibility and place the blame for his obesity where it belongs...on himself. 
And the fast food nation.(No one really knew how bad that stuff was for you when Jared was getting fat. Seriously, don&apos;t eat fast food, it will kill you). But not video games. Unless he actually ate the video games. In that case, he can blame them. But only if he ate them without condiments or dressing... Flag | Reply 
 
 
Yes it&apos;s all Nintendo&apos;s fault
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  ReyMode 
 Give me a break. No one wants to take responsiblity for their own problems these days. First cookie monster fault that kids are eating too much sweeties. And now Nintendo and fast food place are to blame people obesity. Give me a break. If you&apos;re fat it&apos;s your own fault. Flag | Reply 
 
 
It&apos;s a CONSPIRACY !
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Faust74 
 That&apos;s Japan&apos;s master plan! They want to get all the American&apos;s future generations fat.Our children get fat playing videogames and then our Grandchildren get fat,and so on and so on.Then when all of the U.S.A will be too fat to defend themself,that&apos;s when Japan well ATTACK! MARK MY WOOOOOORDS! Flag | Reply 
 
 
He is more of the Exception than the rule.
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  D0ubleDrag0n 
 I&apos;ve been playing games since well.. forever and I am 6&apos;2 and about 190lbs. I am not overweight and I probably spend more than 20 hours a week playing something ie the pc or handhelds or consoles. I single-handedly keep Mcdonalds, harvey&apos;s and Burger King in business. Obesity is more about the individual than it is to blame on Video games. True, gaming generally doesn&apos;t promote active lifestyles (DDR is the obvious exception) it still isn&apos;t the reason why people are so huge. It&apos;s diet. Bottom Line. I hate it when people blame other factors in life rather than taking responsibility for their own Actions. Just because you (Jared)have a&quot;overactive thyroid&quot;or whatever your excuse is, don&apos;t blame the gaming community just because you want to scape goat the issue rather than be responsible. You are the exception, not the rule. Flag | Reply 
 
 
First we&apos;re murderers, now we&apos;re obese.
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  pavia_erik 
 Hey, it is true; inactivity can lead to obesity, but to generalize his problem on just games... I wonder if this guy even knows that what he&apos;s saying will erupt in some big argument over games making people fat. Politicians and reporters like to overhype about us. Flag | Reply 
 
 
whoa whoa
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  the_eel 
 ok if you can&apos;t see your feet or anything else down there than put the 45 pound of bucket of lard down and eat right and go out for walks man. Flag | Reply 
 
 
worst thing to happen to videogames since shadow the hedgehog
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  e2ekiel520 
 oh man, first mcdonalds lawsuits, then &apos;nintendo made me fat!&apos; i thought this was at its worst till this guy happened!! Flag | Reply 
 
 
Let&apos;s be honest...
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  WonderDogZilcho 
 If he would have kept BOTH hands on the controller, he wouldn&apos;t have gained as much weight(and would have been a better gamer); and how can you blame nintendo for lying to your parents about what you&apos;re doing. If his parents would have gotten him the power pad bundle he wouldn&apos;t have had that problem(look now it&apos;s his parents fault and not nintendos) Flag | Reply 
 
 
It&apos;s a me, gluttony!
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Huricos 
 Of course he&apos;s not really saying Nintendo was to blame, His bad diet and no exercise (by sitting behind his NES all day) made him overweight, I don&apos;t see him blaming the gaming industry. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Just sad.
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Maverick14120 
 And here i thought playing NES back in the 80&apos;s only meant you didn&apos;t get any. Joking aside Nintendo realized it was a possibility this could happen with people that was part of the reason they released the Power Pad and games like World Class Track Meet. Sadly the market didn&apos;t want games where you had to get off the couch and move anything other then your thumbs so not many games were made and it bombed. The artical also said how he wasn&apos;t riding his bike like he said he was to his parents but goin to the fast food places and eatting instead. If he hadn&apos;t gotten that NES he&apos;d of still probaly of been at the fast food places eatting only difference is he&apos;d be blaming the arcade games there for bringing him in the door instead of sitting on the couch playing NES. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Lets look closley at what he said
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  SecretAnswer42 
 Um, OK, let&apos;s diagnose his comments since there are those of you who seem to defend this idiot&apos;s accusation:

....&quot;Most people know part of Fogle&apos;s story, he said, but don&apos;t realize he started gaining weight in third grade.&quot;I can trace it back to when I was given the best birthday present of my life: a Nintendo.&quot;Hmm, initial blame; His first Nintendo. Wow, his first excuse is Nintendo started it.

....At that point, Fogle said, he started playing video games more and riding his bike and playing sports less. He became sedentary. With his love of video games, he developed a love of junk food.

Hmm. Nintendo was the initial blame for his road to supreme fattiness, and now he is insinuating that the video games took control of his life and made him quite riding his bike.

....&quot;I usually had one hand on the controller and one in a bag of chips,&quot;he said.

OK, out of the three comments made about Videogames relating to his fat ass, this is the only one that doesn&apos;t directly insinuate any direct wrong doing. But if you read a little closer and examine the whole piece, you can see where this is just another attempt to shift the blame off of him and on to something arbitrary.

Something you people who are defending this should consider:

Jarred is out to make money as all of us are in life. He has a good gig as the &apos;health conscious&apos; spokesman for Subway. This position only looks better if he comes off looking like the victim. Then he can seem to rise above what &apos;somebody else&apos; did to him and come out looking all clean and shiny. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Hope this doesn&apos;t become..
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  fiasco8 
 This is not a very good story at all. I hope this doesn&apos;t become a habit for 1up stories. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Lard A$$ Feedback?
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  softerfury 
 Did your hero Jerod hit a touchy spot for a few of you fat bodies or what? He isn&apos;t blaming NES for his weight gain, he&apos;s blaming his own personal eating problem coupled with sitting on his ass all day long in front of a TV. 

News flash, people will and DO get fat from that. He didn&apos;t say he stopped playing games to lose weight, he said he ate a sammich and started eating smaller portions. Grow up fellas. Hero or not to tubby kidz, he stated what was the start to an unhealthy lifestyle. He&apos;s not blaming anything or anyone but himself. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Even so.. It&apos;s your own will.
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Tahldon 
 Ah, I don&apos;t see him really dissing Nintendo or gamers in general. Basically what I got out of it was that the guy had little to no self control and he was hardheaded. 

Moral of the story? Don&apos;t sit up and eat junk all day while playing your games.. Do like I do, procrastinate! If you put EVERYTHING off until you reach 3 save points after the first one where you were SUPPOSED to stop at and you put off eating, going to the bathroom, drinking anything, answering people, or even getting up then you won&apos;t have that problem... Or at least that&apos;s my weird thoughts about it.. Hey I weighed 118 for a long time playing games...I&apos;m just 5&apos;2 though so.. yeah.. Anyways.. Self control is the key! Flag | Reply 
 
 
Hey, I am like Jared
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  PS2Blows! 
 The genesis of my fatness commenced with the nes. I refused to do anything but play nintendo 12 to 14 hours a day. I went from being a slim athletic kid who liked to play outdoors to a Burger king heavyweight, right after I got my Nintendo. At one point I beat Zelda 2-3 times a day for an entire year, each time collecting all of the items, including all 255 coins. I turned into a sedentary hog thanks to Nintendo. They are an amazing company, I have mad love for them. Flag | Reply 
 
 
More Fat in a Subway than in an NES...
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Mr_Bucket 
 The NES, according to a recent study, has absolutely no nutritional value when you eat the console, the controllers, or the cartridges.

The meatball&amp;cheese-sub at Subway has approximately 578 calories per square-inch...

Fuzzy math, Jared...fuzzy indeed! Flag | Reply 
 
 
fat sh!t
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  ChuckSteak0331 
 I dont give a flying nun&apos;s ass how much weight you lost and what your Christmas present was back in 1985. I cannot feel sorry for some fat ass kid who cant keep his hands out of a bag of chips. Nor can I feel bad because his parents just let him eat himself into fathood. Jarred you money grabbing whore, die. Please do us all a favor and die. Hang yourself, or invest in a brain tumor. Thanks. 

Articles like this are dumb. Flag | Reply 
 
 
I thought he was just big boned!
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  ComradeOne 
 But, seriously, I don&apos;t think he was blaming the games themselves. It could verywell have been TV if it wasn&apos;t a nintendo. Flag | Reply 
 
 
JARRED
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Zanicnight 
 Jarred does not place the blame on nintendo or on the fodo he eats. He blames himself for failing to over come his passion for video games and food. That simple, Don&apos;t fall for no word twisting or putting words in his mouth. show me a quote that directly says&quot;Nintendo MADE me eat junk food.&quot;&quot;Nintendo MADE me ride my bike to get fatty foods.&quot;or&quot;Nintendo is to blame it is all the dam video games I played that made me a fat A$$.&quot; Flag | Reply 
 
 
I&apos;m with Jediborg2
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Aerophis 
 I don&apos;t think Jared is specifically blaming video games. In fact, it seems like he is almost solely blaming junk food. He said himself that he would go and eat extremely fatty fast food when he wasn&apos;t playing. When you look at it that way, video game playing was obviously at least the lesser of two evils.

People are always looking for someone or something to blame for everything bad in life. TV and alchohol are too popular so why not go for an easy target like video games. Flag | Reply 
 
 
He&apos;s not blaming games
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  jediborg2 
 I agree with the_Hawk_X. Read his post.
Jared&apos;s not&quot;Blaming&quot;nintendo. If you actually read the linked article, he describes how his bad eating habits and sedentary lifestyle playing videogames made him gain weight. This is bad news reporting on behalf of 1up.com they&apos;re simply twisting his words to get readers riled up. Flag | Reply 
 
 
RE: Boycott?
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  mariopainter 
 Word. I sit on my ass and play video games all day too, but I don&apos;t eat shitty food and I work out a lot. It&apos;s pretty stupid that this fatass said somethin so dumb. I&apos;m in on the boycott, and I&apos;ll cover the denver area. Who else wants in on this? (I think we&apos;ve covered Louisville and Denver.) Flag | Reply 
 
 
It&apos;s so true!
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  bananaboy32 
 i think im going to go out and get run over by a truck now and blame the pavement because if it wasnt there I wouldnt be walking on the road where I got hit. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Accountability
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  slyguy13 
 Funny thing, I played videogames when I was younger, and I did get over 400 LBS. Matter of fact, I still play video games, and I&apos;m not even over 200 LBS. It kills me that we live in a society where people can&apos;t take accountability for their own failings.

In the immortal words of Forest Gump -&quot;Stupid is as Stupid does&quot;. Flag | Reply 
 
 
I suggest a &apos;maximum quality standard&apos; on games and tv shows
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Slavik81 
 I suggest that we impement a &apos;maximum quality standard&apos; on all video games and tv shows.

They have to be just good enough you erk some entertainment from using them, but they&apos;re still annoying enough to make you want to do other things instead.

Also, from now on, all fast-food must be soaked in vinegar before being served to customers.

Remember. Promote healthy living. Clearly, anything enjoyable that is unhealthy for you when consumed excessively must be regulated to reduce enjoyment.


I hope you all can agree with me on this. Flag | Reply 
 
 
vttym - Blame Defined
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  TiberiusJones 
 Maybe YOU shold try reading the entire article without inserting your own thoughts into reality.

He does NOT blame video games. He says he played Nintendo and ate too much, he doesn&apos;t blame Nintendo.

Blame Definition: 

Blame is the assignment of responsibility from one entity to another. Blaming is the action of assigning this blame to another, often from oneself.

He put the blame on himself. He just says his problem was an addiction to Nintendo and food, but he does not BLAME Nintendo. Now you know. Flag | Reply 
 
 
That&apos;s frickin&apos; funny!
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  mandatory_insanity 
 Waaa! Waaa! Fatty foods, irresponsible parents! Waaa!
That&apos;s all I got out of it, and I laughed hysterically.
Besides, it should be the person&apos;s own responsibly to maintain a healthy diet and weight. I know games are addicting, but try to imagine you&apos;re Mario or Sonic running and jumping on baddies you made out of Legos. Worked for me, and I&apos;m a healthy 185.
I believe a famous EGM article addressed this very issue;&quot;No, the act of playing video games won&apos;t make you flabby, but if all you do is play video games morning, noon, and night, without lifting a finger except for the act of flipping pringles into your pie hole, you&apos;ll turn into a tub of lard faster than you can say John Popper...and you&apos;ll wind up with an even bigger problem than just a titanic ass.&quot;I&apos;ll say; a nasty anti-game disposition. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Really Irresponsible
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Doug_BlueFang 
 I think it&apos;s pretty obvious that this is an irresponsible statement made by Jared Fogle, and he should be confronted about this. Perhaps he meant to illustrate that he was eating junk food while not pursuing any sort of physical activity, but it&apos;s still his own fault for not being responsible for his own actions, and he definately sounds like he&apos;s trying to pass off blame here to Nintendo.
Here we are dealing in an age where parents want to blame everyone and everything else (including video games) for their failures in raising their children, and now we have Jared Fogle apparently trying to take the easy way out too with regards to his weight problems. I&apos;d like to hear how he feels about being this week&apos;s&quot;shining example of ignorance?&quot; Flag | Reply 
 
 
i wish this were true a little bit
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  inf1 
 i wish this were true a little bit so skinny people all over the world like myself can play videogames to gain some weight. iOi Flag | Reply 
 
 
What a toOl...
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  gcpnoy 
 Shiet, Jared ran his portly round self to McDeez to buy a Happy Meal so he did get in some sort excercise! Its not video games that made him fat, its being a lazy lard-@$$ and his genetics! Quit putting the blame on everything around you for not getting in some excercise because he could have gotten equally as rotund had he played with his G.I. Joes or He-Man toys with his hand in a bag or Funyans while sipping on his Tab cola! I&apos;m fat because I sat around and drew pictures all day. I should hold a press conference and blame Marvel&amp;DC comics for that! Maybe I should call them out on that one! ;) Gawd, people will do anything to be famous! Flag | Reply 
 
 
RE: Boycott
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  SecretAnswer42 
 I say we all call every Subway near us and bitch about this dumbass comment tha chubby little weasle made.

I&apos;ll take care of all the SW&apos;s in Louisville. Anybody else game? Flag | Reply 
 
 
To the person saying Jared never said vid games made him fat..
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  vttym 
 Try reading the linked story that the article quotes come from. He does, in fact, directly blame video games, as well as reducing his bike riding.

But who wants to read the whole story, I guess.. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Boycot FTW
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  JeffD1121 
 no more subway for me Flag | Reply 
 
 
Bravo!
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  M3g4tr0n 
 Great job at jumping on the anti-video game bandwagon, bitch. Will you be bashing Microsoft next? Perhaps you wouldn&apos;t have been so fat if your parents had taught you a little self control, fatty.

I will never eat subway again. Not that I did before, but I&apos;ll make sure to never go in one. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Up yours, Jared!
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  king_e_dawg 
 FUCK YOU, JARED! I challenge you to a street brawl, you sandwich-gobbling, Nintendo-hating son of a bitch!!! Anytime, anywhere... Right after I finish this delicious SUBWAY low-carb wrap... Flag | Reply 
 
 
What a chach
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  ZiggyMoShriff 
 He shouldn&apos;t even be famous in the first place Flag | Reply 
 
 
What a Fag
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  spaniard0069 
 I played Nintendo and ate fatty foods and I never in my life weighed more than 160lbs. This fat f_ck probably weighed that at the age of 10 and whose fault is that. Not Nintendo&apos;s or Wise potato chips, its mami and daddy&apos;s fault. Go eat a sub Jarod. Flag | Reply 
 
 
&apos;Its not my fault!&apos;
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  SecretAnswer42 
 This guy is still a fat head idiot. I suppose the Nintendo forced his hand into that bag of chips......I guess Mario peered him into going to McDonalds for three Big Mac&apos;s.....

This is the problem with most people today. They refuse to take responsibility for their actions. Im a 33 year old gamer and Im about 20 pounds over weight. Do I blame Half Life 2?

HELL NO!

Im the one who chugs Red Bull by the gallon just so I can go on 2 hours sleep and play lots of DM! Of course the fudge and twinkies dont help either:)

Jarred! I call on you to be a real man and admitt that YOU MADE YOU FAT! Flag | Reply 
 
 
The Blame Game
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  jrhawk42 
 People like Jared are always trying to blame someone else for their problems. Jared is an obsessor, and he follows things past the point where normal personalities would. Thats how he got so fat, thats how he lost his weight, and thats why he&apos;ll continue obsessing about social issues. Next he&apos;ll be blaming bovine growth hormone for the sexual devience of teenagers. (ok that might be true) Flag | Reply 
 
 
Jared, it&apos;s not videogames that make you a fat ass...
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  bambamthepyro 
 It&apos;s your lazy fat ass that makes you a lazy fat ass. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Love the Article Title
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  digitaldick 
 &quot;Subway Spokesman&apos;s Six Inches of Nintendo Hate&quot;sounds like th3 pr0n in Bizarro World. Can no one take responsibility for their own actions anymore? Flag | Reply 
 
 
ROFLMFAO
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  swordsnsnipers 
 Omg this dude cant be serious. Hey hey ... listen to this...... I turned gay cuz i started playing video games. OMG..... lmao.. how about blaming fast food you fucktard.... or your self for that matter dummy. Get off our nuts. Flag | Reply 
 
 
that subway guy
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Nintendoian666 
 needs to stop and blame the fact that he couldn&apos;t put down fork! FACE!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!( moded family guy quote) Flag | Reply 
 
 
WTF, WTF
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Devils_God 
 This is for real?!?!?!?!?!?!, I thought this was some dumb/funny shit xbox/usa made up. HOLY FUCK, I WILL NEVER PLAY NINTENDO AGAIN!!!!!!!!!!! Flag | Reply 
 
 
lol you cant blame personal irresponsibility on a company like that
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  l33tw33z3rg33k 
 hmm, nintendo and all the developers for the NES made great games that he loved to play and then he got fat due to the fact he ate junk food and didnt excersice. therefore, by jared&apos;s perfect logic, nintendo made him fat.

well lets all give him a round of appluase. really, wtf? i can see attacking malboro becuase their product directly harms you, but nintendo is not harmful just by casual or moderate use. if he would have ate subway and excersiced, and still played nintendo, he wouldnt have gotten fat, so wTF? is it temping to play nintendo all day? yes. is it nintendos fault he was fat? no. Flag | Reply 
 
 
One more reason for me not support Subway
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  BJWanlund 
 WTF?? I am still not supporting that piece of sh*t Subway, not even after this. I will never support Subway, I much prefer Blimpie&apos;s and Quizno&apos;s to Subway.

Jared Fogle, no dice.

BJ Flag | Reply 
 
 
If this is true then Nintendo is also responsible for his success
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Taraalcar 
 If he hadnt recieved an NES, then he wouldnt have become overweight, he wouldnt have lost that weight, and he wouldnt have become the successful famous Subway spokesperson. So... Nintendo helped him. Flag | Reply 
 
 
jared is a really creepy ex-fatass
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  xbox/usa 
 that jared guy was cool at first but now he is just sort of creepy like a carny or that guy that lives on your street that wants you to come over to his house to eat ice cream. I really think he is the new john wayne gacy. If hes starts dressing like a clown I am never eating at subway again. Flag | Reply 
 
 
PEOPLE NEED MODERATION!
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Nintendoian666 
 dont eat so much dont drink so much and exercise! jered you stupid fat fuck! Flag | Reply 
 
 
Poor Dumbass/Fatass
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  T_Soldier19 
 This overall ass can&apos;t blame anything on his fatty figure other than his own stupid self. I play video games and eat junk food in extreme excess. BUT I also have the intellect to exercise. I can play video games and eat all day and then just run for 3 miles or lift weights and I am in good shape. There is no excuse to be a fatty. Flag | Reply 
 
 
1UP blames Jared &apos;s girth on NES and fatty foods
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  CheapyD 
 If you actually read Jared&apos;s quotes, he does not blame anyone or anything for his weight problems. The word blame does not appear anywhere, except in 1UP&apos;s article.&amp;quot;I can trace it back to when I was given the best birthday present of my life: a Nintendo.&amp;quot;&amp;quot;I usually had one hand on the controller and one in a bag of chips,&amp;quot;

How does&amp;quot;the best birthday present of my life: a Nintendo&amp;quot; = hate?

Come on, guys...this isn&apos;t reporting. Flag | Reply 
 
 
games don&apos;t make people fat, people make people fat
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  METAzraeL 
 What an idiot...next he&apos;ll use Doom as an excuse to kill people. Ha, I think playing games helped me get thin back when I was a fat-ass little kid...I mean, if you are a real gamer you play, not click the d-pad with your left hand and eat with your right...now, maybe if he had a handheld rpg for the GBA when he was little it might be different...Idk, kinda sounds like he was payed to say this...by Bill Gates:o Flag | Reply 
 
 
Just remember Jared has Aides
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  drewglassman 
 Trey Parker and Matt Stone reminded the world that Jared had Aides to get skinny. Flag | Reply 
 
 
He lost weight with AIDS
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  D3adcell 
 You know the type of ades that help people. Like a teachers ade etc.

BTW if he got fat playing nintendo it wasn&apos;t nintendo&apos;s fault. It was his own fault for being a lazy fat ass that was too stupid to realize that eating a good meal and doing some excersize is good for you. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Consider the source
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  sharktastic 
 No self-control? That&apos;s a shocker. This is the guy who ate crap until he was over 400 lbs. Some people just can&apos;t do things in moderation. Jared was obviously one of those people. It&apos;s not necessarily his fault, and it&apos;s DEFINITELY not Nintendo&apos;s. It&apos;s genetics. It&apos;s like me blaming the XBox for my blond hair. Flag | Reply 
 
 
WHAT!!!!
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  vgamer369 
 (I&apos;m not going for anyone except this guy!)Why does he blame his Nintendo on his obesity. Nintendo didn&apos;t tell him to eat junk food or not to do a little exercise. It is his own fault-he has choices, nobody else made these choices but him. He just doesn&apos;t want to blame himself so he has to blame it on something he wasn&apos;t good at! Flag | Reply 
 
 
Uwe Boll made Jared Fat.
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  andyluvsu 
 Please join the Uwe Boll Fan Club now and become a fatass. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Jared had aids.
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  ElderJedi 
 I wait for the day when people can take responsibility for their own actions. Stupid fatass. Flag | Reply 
 
 
this can be good
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  psgamer92 
 since i guess subway hates games know and they hate burger joints mabye games and mc dolands can come together and go agaist subway! Flag | Reply 
 
 
misplaced blame
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  swordguy 
 I may be an NES fan but that&apos;s just dumb. Some people know how to play games in regulation and not stuff their fat faces with crap. I admit you won&apos;t get much exercise with your system hooked up but I also doubt you&apos;ll play for 24 hours with only stops for more food. This is strictly a matter of some jack-off having no self controll. The blame lies with him, not a controller. Flag | Reply 
 
 
hoe
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  konami&apos;sqrenix 
 if that ass couldnt control himself 2 bad and even so shoudnt he just be happy thats hes not fat anymore just forget it and get on its not nintendos fault its a lack of self control beacuse of a newly found craving for fatty foods Flag | Reply 
 
 
Well, its true
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  gopro 
 Its not a lie, Games make people fat, have no life, skip school, drop outta school, kill themsleves etc.. 

How old is he anyways? He was like 20 when NES came out and he was still getting allowances. So sad. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Bad Role model for videogames!
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  projectrunaway 
 This is the dumbest piece of garbage that i have ever heard. Its true if you do sit and play videogames and eat&quot;junk food&quot;and don&apos;t get out then the pounds build. I can personally say that i did play videogames in my youth but didn&apos;t eat have one hand on the joystick and another in a bag of Lays potatoe chips or a big 20 ounce soda next to my side. I had an 8-bit NES back in the early 80&apos;s but it didn&apos;t consume my life. This man blames Nintendo but the real person you have to blame is yourself. I love Subway but after what this&quot;Poser&quot;Wannabe&quot;said about videogames in general makes me sad to eat another Subway sandwich. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Jared&apos;s a phony
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  momomo66 
 Jared Fogle is just a multiple DUI&apos;er who had to walk to Subway everyday (because it was the only eatery close enough) -- that&apos;s how he lost all the weight. 

True story. Flag | Reply 
 
 
some people can&apos;t balance it out
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Drifter288 
 Hey now with all the fun games like ddr there are ways to have fun and loose weight but him using that as an excuse is no way. We all remember track and field and it was pre-ddr dance pad status!!! At least he had enough energy to go get junk food.... Flag | Reply 
 
 
Calm down people!
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  full_auto 
 He did not even come close to saying&quot;Nintendo made me get fat.&quot;He is not going around linking weight problems to Nintendo. He even says it was his favorite birthday present.

He says that he ended up riding his bike to Micky D&apos;s and loading up (so to speak) there. Flag | Reply 
 
 
There are no stupid questions, only stupid people!
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  TiberiusJones 
 Why are we even discussing this drivel? It&apos;s painful. Flag | Reply 
 
 
You have got to be kidding me.....
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  CoLdFuSioN167 
 the reason people get fat are because all they do is eat and sit on their fat asses! The Nintendo didn&apos;t make you fat, nor did it force you to sit there and eat junk food all day long. I can&apos;t stand when overweight people try and blame other things for their guilt of being fat. Get off your fat ass and work out or something! Stop blaming McDonalds, videogames, and the tv! Flag | Reply 
 
 
one word,&lt;STFU&gt;!
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  mr/anti/esrb 
 ok hillary clinton, what was it, mario jumping on monsters and popping mushrooms too much for u?? Flag | Reply 
 
 
You all are missing the point
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  TiberiusJones 
 He didn&apos;t&quot;blame&quot;Nintendo. He just said he got a Nintendo as a present and liked it so much, he spent all his time playing and eating. He even admitted that he would take his allowance and sneak off to Mickey D&apos;s or some other place to get the fattiest meal possible. I just assume Mickey D&apos;s &apos;cause let&apos;s face it, that is some fatty damn food!

But it&apos;s not like he said&quot;Nintendo is at fault for my weight gain, they shouldn&apos;t be allowed to manufacture games that are fun because people like me might get fat playing them!&quot;And it&apos;s somewhat irresponsible for 1up to label this story&quot;Subway Spokesman&apos;s Six Inches of Nintendo Hate&quot;when he is actually expousing his love for Nintendo. A love he unfortunately couldn&apos;t control.

Poor fat dude! OK, I couldn&apos;t resist. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Goddamn Monkeyman...
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Ambergryph 
 He even admits himself, he got around his videogame/junk food limitation. Not by going to a friend&apos;s house to play Nintendo. To buy fast food. Feckin&apos; monkey shoots up his own argument.

So you lost a buttload of weight eating Subway. I never cared. Ever. You know who cared? People who thought that their fat wasn&apos;t their fault, and that Subway would magically make them skinny. I know my fat&apos;s my fault. I&apos;m 6&apos;4&quot;and 230-odd lbs. Not&quot;OMFG UR LIEK A PLANET&quot;fat, but enough that I should lose some. And you know what? It&apos;s &apos;cause I don&apos;t get active as much as I should. Get a life, you asshole. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Games dont make people fat, bad habbits do
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Hawkeye6004 
 Look at me, I am a gamer. I always have been and always will be. But, here I am, 165lb, 6&apos;2&quot;and the body of a male fasion model. Weird how two people can share one of the same hobbies yet be so diffrent. Oh I know what it is... I dont eat greasy junk food too often and enjoy working out. Thats got to be it. Flag | Reply 
 
 
astonishing!
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  DodgeballCannon 
 Some kid ate potato chips and then spent all his allowance on fast food and he got fat. Sounds to me like he became obsessed with greasy food and not Nintendo. Because as we all know, we would have gone without food for a week to buy Super Mario Bros. 3. But instead of saving his money up for games, Jared ran his tubby ass down to Burger King and chowed down on Whoppers. Just because he also happened to own a Nintendo doesn&apos;t make it Nintendo&apos;s fault. If Jared hadn&apos;t ruined his brain by starving himself until he lost 300 pounds maybe he&apos;d realize that like everyone else. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Breaking news! This just in...
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  acrazycanadian 
 ... reports of Nintendo brainwashing youth into rampant consumption of potato chips continues to cause a mass media panic.

Insider sources claim that&quot;Nintendo has been brainwashing youth for years, utilizing subversive franchises such as Super Mario Bros. and Pokemon.&quot;Super Mario, a popular video game among children and plumber labour unions, features players consuming round, yellow chips as a key gameplay mechanic.&quot;In fact, they expect you to &apos;collect&apos; as many of these &apos;coins&apos; as possible!&quot;states an anonymous Nintendo employee.&quot;An Asian friend of mine even went so far as to say Bomberman &apos;ate&apos; powerups! And he&apos;d been speaking English for a whole two months!&quot;Rumours abound of secret deals between Nintendo and various potato farmers. Nintendo representatives were unavailable for comment. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Amazing...
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  wembley1967 
 Just when I thought they couldn&apos;t blame anything else on video games Fogle proved me wrong.Once again,because Jarod decided not to eat responsibly and exercise,and because he refuses to take responsibility for his own actions he wants to shift the blame to where it doesn&apos;t belong.So does that mean if Jarod had spent his time at a church instead that there would be something wrong with religion?
Not hardly.Don&apos;t blame the size of your behind on video games,Jarod.Blame it on being too damned lazy to exercise.
By the way,I&apos;m sick of those commercials anyways.Jarod Fogle and his attitude that anything not done his way is wrong sucks just like him. Flag | Reply 
 
 
It is nice to point fingers
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  toodze 
 This is not the first time I have heard someone place the blame of weight gain on something other than his or her own fault. I am a big fan of video games and food. I am also tipping the scales at 280. It was my bad eating habits and drinking after the Army that made me balloon up. Jared, do not blame others for the problem you had. Granted, you did lose the weight, but you are to blame, not Nintendo. Flag | Reply 
 
 
who cares
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  mratedgamer 
 Jared is not that popular now (even though he wasn&apos;t even that popular). So who cares. It is not the fault of video games, the blame goes to fatty fast food (alliteration kicks ass)and irresponsible parents. fuck Jared, Jared sucks. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Those In small pants shouldnt throw stones
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  BigBadDrew 
 I can find you Jared and when I do I will make you eat a handful of pig fat and force you to play until you beat Halo on Legendary. I will turn you back to the fat side.&lt;insert maniacal laugh here&gt; Flag | Reply 
 
 
Customer Service Form
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Orange-Duck 
 He should also blame the comfy couch manufacture and his grandparents for his all his problems.

Oh, and if you would like to share your opinions with Subway, contact them here?

http://www.subway.com/subwayroot/Applications/CustServ/frmCustomerServi ce.aspx Flag | Reply 
 
 
cockamamie
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  arctica_dios 
 Even such a term as this or more&quot;elementary&quot;words like dumbass, stupid fuck and retarded-ass bitch are just too good for me to waste on the likes of Chubbs here Flag | Reply 
 
 
Fat Boy!!!!
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  shady316 
 Oh yeah, blame it on the video games fat boy. I love video games so much, that it makes me eat all this junk food!!!! Blah Blah Blah. Shut your pie hole. Flag | Reply 
 
 
It&apos;s not Nintendo&apos;s problem
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  escaped_shoplifter 
 It&apos;s his. It was his decision to eat chips and play Nintendo. So quite blaming Nintendo for your fatness Jared. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Jared has AIDES
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  ibeatganonwheniwas5 
 the reason jared lost weight is cuz he got AIDES. for more bout this watch south park Flag | Reply 
 
 
so what
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  bwv2002 
 Is his contract running out at Subway or something. He probably wants to be a spoke person for Dance Dance Revolution or something. He has to relize that he did it to him self. I actually eat less food due to video games. Flag | Reply 
 
 
the dynamic duo: Jared and Jack
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  $kyscraper_Antfarm 
 What do you get when you combine a has been 400 lb loser with a right wing nutjob? The antichrist of gaming made fresh. Flag | Reply 
 
 
hmmm
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  ErinGrapejuice 
 because he was lazy and his parent&apos;s didn&apos;t stop him, it&apos;s Nintendo&apos;s fault? Yeah, that makes perfect sense to me. I was fat when I was little. You know what I did? Got off my ass and went outside to play with other kids. I still played games, I ate healthy.. I just made sure I got up and did something as well.

It&apos;s no one&apos;s fault but your own for letting yourself go. Flag | Reply 
 
 
I wonder...
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Bombader 
 ...If he ment to blame the DS in a way for partnering with the fast food in a way, which would be even funnier since he is talking about the NES, before this happens.

Gotta love Americans. Flag | Reply 
 
 
He loved food more than games!
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Direct_Hit3000 
 If anything games can make you NOT go to a fast food restaurant since they&apos;re getting so expensive. Just get em all the systems and don&apos;t buy em any games. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Jared is a retard.
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  bambamthepyro 
 I&apos;ve been doing the same thing he mentioned ever since my first NES, and I weigh a whopping 125 lbs. Jared, it&apos;s not the food that makes you a lazy fat-ass. It&apos;s you that makes you a lazy fat-ass. Maybe you should put the blame on yourself like the rest of the country needs to start doing. DAMNIT I hate Jared, and now I will no longer eat Subway. Flag | Reply 
 
 
and who cares?
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  gmsgamer 
 Yeah, blame the fatty foods and games? Cuz, you know, we really care.

Any retard knows that it&apos;s better to go on a bike ride than go to McDonalds and eat fatty foods. And I&apos;m a game addict but guess what- I lost 25 pounds from August to now eating less and going to the gym! Flag | Reply 
 
 
Christ
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Captain_C 
 well theres another F*cker who wants to put video games down. whos gonna be next? wieght watchers? or jenny craig... Flag | Reply 
 
 
lame
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  perri 
 Nintendo has nothing to do with the fact that he loved his chips and fast food. No corelation what so ever. It&apos;s lame that He would say something like that, but even lamer that 1up posted this as news....

Anything to hate on Nintendo, eh 1up? Bravo - you suck.






Revolt. Flag | Reply 
 
 
WARNING: This product has been found hazardous to morons in laboratory tests.
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Man_In_Black_77 
 We should just slap this label on everything manufactured anywhere from now until the end of time. That should cover about 95% of all warning labels and save a lot of paper work. Flag | Reply 
 
 
RE: reklesgemini
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  xfileagentjlj 
 LOL! Good one!

Jared needs to go to counseling on his way to the gym. If he&apos;s placing blame on someone or something else he needs to take a look at the mirror a bit longer. Nintendo didn&apos;t make him fat, he did it to himself. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Not their fault.....
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  mr.critic 
 It&apos;s not Nintendo&apos;s fault you were overwight it&apos;s your own. You have to accept you made a mistake and not blame others. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Funny stuff...
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  GroverFD 
 This is a funny thread all round. Fat-guy uses Nintendo console as excuse.. Nintendo fans respond with&quot;Jared sucks&quot;... 

HAHAHAH.. you gotta love people and their vanity.. Flag | Reply 
 
 
I guess nintendo made him stupid and gay too
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  paulzeppelin 
 jared sucks, hes a fat loser. Flag | Reply 
 
 
good for him...
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Dantemaster82 
 Why is Jared Fogle even famous? He is a delusional once fat man thinking Nintendo did this to him. In reality, he shouldn&apos;t have kept munching potato chips. Maybe we wouldn&apos;t have had to listen to him if he spent his allowance on more Nintendo games instead of food. Flag | Reply 
 
 
LOL
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  DarkStrikeSX 
 Funniest thing i have ever heard. HUGE burn for Nintendo. Even though it kind of isn&apos;t really a valid point. But funny none the less. Flag | Reply 
 
 
HAHAHAHAHA loser
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  TokoYami200 
 He blames the fact that he is 400 pounds on videogames. Do videogames make you want to eat so much junk food until you weigh 400 pounds? No, or all of us gamers would be fat too. I mean, sometimes I eat chips while playing videogames, but not so much as to become 400 pounds. I hope he gets a heart attack while taking a big bite of one of those awful tasting subway sandwiches. Flag | Reply 
 
 
suck my footlong!!!1
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  unclepeyj 
 this guy is the sleaziest piece of shit to climb out of the swamp since gary glitter. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Oh Please
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  G_Kidd3603R 
 Videogames does not cause ppl to be fat. Being a lazy (for lack of a better term) fat ass does. If you exercise for 30 mins and don&apos;t over eat, you won&apos;t have a weight problem.

END OF STORY Flag | Reply 
 
 
How to not get fat...
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Halofreak 
 Don&apos;t eat so much, jeese, its not that hard. Heck if parents didnt buy their kids so much crap then they wouldnt be fat in the first place. Flag | Reply 
 
 
katamari-sized spokesman
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  _sean_ 
 what a douche. he lied to parents, boughht fatty foods, and blames nintendo. Hes so ugly my tv screen cracked when a subway commercial came on. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Jared....
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  hehepupitre 
 Its the damn food. WOW, holy crap I thought you were cool. Now I know why you were fat. Does anyone else realize the stupididty behind that. Its not the games doing this. Its the damn food. HE SAYS THAT HE ATE POTATO CHIPS AND ATE AT FAST FOOD RESTAURANTS! HOLY CRAP are they that dumb to not put 2 and 2 together. He ate fatty food. THATS HIS PROBLEM! Holy crap people can be stupid. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Nothing out of the ordinary........
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  ion-neon 
 and certainly this won&apos;t stop the Revo from being a succes. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Son of a.......!
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  yam83 
 He&apos;s undermining the lifestyles of all us fatasses!
Bastard! :D Flag | Reply 
 
 
Jared has Aids
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  giants360 
 Anyone whose an avid fan of South Park knows that Jared had Aids and personal trainers that helped him get skinny. Besides he wouldnt need them if he ran a few laps or did some push ups in between all those Twinkies. Christ I grew up playing NES too and I can bench his dumb ass. Video games dont make people over weight. Over eating - Exercise = weight gain. I hate when people try to give gaming a bad name. Flag | Reply 
 
 
what an idiot.
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  taichininja 
 everything he said he did was all his choice. he just can&apos;t accept the blame, so he makes up a scapegoat. since he seems to be in control of himself now, why doesn&apos;t he just start working out and changing his own diet? Flag | Reply 
 
 
It´s no the NES... it´s your freaking mind.
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Zeichrat 
 I love the blame game... because it´s NES is guilty of creating a horde of lazy fat people... why don´t he just blamed on himself???... oh that´s right... because he´s a spokeman trying to create concience... idiot. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Idiot
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  Reenee 
 Games played=/= Junk food of choice. Ever heard of DDR, dumbass? Drinking soda with that makes you puke.

It was YOUR CHOICE for junk foods, not that system. Flag | Reply 
 
 
Jared Suxs!
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  my_effect 
 Jared is a dumd ass who comes what he says I mean come. All he is some Fat guy gone skinny because he starved him self to death and only ate 2 6 in subs a day. What a loser now saying videosgames a one cause of non-active people! f*^k him Flag | Reply 
 
 
I guess the Revo would change that
 Posted: userComment.createdDate by  reklesgemini 
 He&apos;ll have some strong arms. Flag | Reply 
 
 Title Of Comment 
 
 Maximum characters for title is 120 

 Comment 
 
 
 
 
Popular on 1UP
 
 Gallery: Games as the Comics That Inspired Them 

We pay homage to the classic comic books that gave life to our favorite games.


 17 hours ago  3 55 

 
 Sons of Big Bucks: Metal Gear Solid 4 and the Video Game Economy 

An in-depth look at how MGS4 doesn&apos;t care who you kill and, in the process, talks about the trend toward gamification.


 5 days ago  13 48 

 
 Metal Gear: The Reigning King of Pop Culture References 

A brief look at the series&apos;stew of homages.


 7 days ago  24 45
	</body>
</document>
