<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001004" url="http://www.scribd.com/doc/13069130/Introduction-to-Cost-and-Management-Accounting-in-a-Global-Business-Environment" time="2012-07-12-16:24" support="1" score="0.001229435696082498" bingtitle="Introduction to Cost and Management Accounting in a Global ..." webtitle="Introduction to Cost and Management Accounting in a Global Business Environment">
			<query id="000137" bing-rank="81"/>
	<description>• Buy franchises for and open 15 locations of a fast-food restaurant in areas of the former Soviet Union. a. Discuss the competitive influences that will impact each of ...</description>
	<body>
		Scribd Upload Search Explore 
 Documents 

 Books - Fiction Books - Non-fiction Health&amp;Medicine Brochures/Catalogs Government Docs How-To Guides/Manuals Magazines/Newspapers Recipes/Menus School Work + all categories Featured Recent 
 
 People 

 Authors Students Researchers Publishers Government&amp;Nonprofits Businesses Musicians Artists&amp;Designers Teachers + all categories Most Followed Popular 
 
 Sign Up | Log In 
 Tweet 
 Embed Doc Copy Link Readcast Collections 
 
 3 Comment Go Back 
 Download   Introduction to Cost and Management Accounting in a Global Business Environment C H A P T E R LEARNING OBJECTIVES After completing this chapter, you should be able to answer the following questions: 1 How do financial and management accounting relate to each other? 2 How does cost accounting relate to financial and management accounting? 3 What is the role of a code of ethics in guiding the behaviors of an organization’s global workforce? 4 What factors have influenced the globalization of businesses and why have these factors been significant? 5 What are the primary factors and constraints that influence an organization’s strategy and why are these factors important? 6 How does an organization’s competitive environment impact its strategy and how might an organization respond to competition? 7 How does the accounting function impact an organization’s ability to successfully achieve its strategic goals and objectives? 8 Why is a company segment’s mission affected by product life cycle? 9 What is the value chain and why is it important in managing a business?   ABN AMRO Bank INTRODUCING he Netherlands-based bank, ABN AMRO, was formed in 1990 when Algemene Bank Nederland merged with Amsterdam-Rotterdam Bank. Following the merger, ABN AMRO has established itself as a global bank with operations in 76 countries and territories including the United States, where the bank has a 16% share of the Midwest market. ABN AMRO’s global expansion was driven initially by mergers but more recently by innovative web- based delivery of products and services. By traditional measures (such as its $505 billion in as- sets and its capital position), ABN AMRO is the largest bank in Holland, the fourth largest in Europe, and the eighth largest in the world. ABN AMRO’s core lending business is solid. Over half of ABN AMRO’s revenues come from Dutch clients—a very stable source of business that includes such companies as Royal Dutch Shell, Philips Electronics, and Unilever. ABN AMRO formulated an identity statement in 1992 to reflect its corporate aspirations: “ABN AMRO Bank is a long-established, solid, multi-faceted bank of international reputation and standing. We will strive to fulfill the bank’s ambition in being a frontrunner in value-added banking, both on a loca l and w orldw ide le vel. . . .” The c orpor ate values statement was formalized in 1997, although the values have been important priorities since the bank was established in the 1800s. The four values forming the basis of the bank’s activities are integrity, teamwork, respect, and professionalism. Bank managers believe that the values need to be formalized even though they are and should be self-evident. The formalization provides external parties criteria by which the bank can be assessed. ABN AMRO perceives its corporate identity and values as the underlying tenets of the organization. ABN AMRO is successfully pursuing a corporate identity as a “bank of international reputation and standing.” ABN AMRO was ranked as the fifth largest commercial and savings bank and the seventy-third largest corporation in the 1999 Fortune Global 500. The corporation (with its foreign subsidiaries and affiliates) is com- prised of over 3,500 branches and offices in 76 countries and territories across five continents. Although internatio nal trade was once confined to extremely large cor- porations such as ABN AMRO, the explosion of World Wide Web usage has en- abled any business with the right infrastructure capabilities and the necessary funds for Web site development to market its products and services around the world. Organizations operating globally face three primary challenges. First, managers must understand factors influencing international business markets so they can iden- tify locations in which the company has the strengths and desire to compete. Sec- ond, managers must devise a long-term plan to achieve organizational goals. Third, the company must devise information systems that keep operations consistent with its plans and goals. This chapter introduces cost accounting and describes the global environment of business, internation al market structures, trade agreements, e-commerce, and legal and ethical considerations. It addresses the importance of strategic planning and links strategy creation and implementation to the accounting information system. The chapter discussion applies equally well to large and small profit-seeking businesses, and most discussion is appropriate for not-for-profit and governmental entities. SOURCE : www.abnamro.com/profile ; Chris Costanzo, “ABN AMRO Says Web Will Anchor Its Expansion,” American Banker (December 9, 1999), p. 16. 3 http:// www.abnamro.com   T INTRODUCTION TO COST ACCOUNTING To manage a diverse, international banking organization, ABN AMRO’s leaders need monetary and nonmoneta ry information that helps them to analyze and solve   problems by reducing uncertainty. Accounting, often referred to as the language of business, provides much of that necessary information. Accounting language has two primary “variations”: financial accounting and management accounting. Cost accounting is a bridge between financial and management accounting. Accounting information addresses three different functions: (1) providing infor- mation to external parties (stockholders, creditors, and various regulatory bodies) for investment and credit decisions; (2) estimating the cost of products produced and services provided by the organization; and (3) providing information useful to internal managers who are responsible for planning, controlling, decision making, and evaluating performance. Financial accounting is designed to meet external in- formation needs and to comply with generally accepted accounting principles. Man- agement accounting attempts to satisfy internal information needs and to provide product costing information for external financial statements. The primary differ- ences between these two accounting disciplines are given in Exhibit 1–1. Financial accounting must comply with the generally accepted accounting prin- ciples (currently established by the Financial Accounting Standards Board [FASB], a private-sector body). The information used in financial accounting is typically historical, quantifiable, monetary, and verifiable. These characteristics are essential to the uniformity and consistency needed for external financial statements. Finan- cial accounting information is usually quite aggregated and related to the organi- zation as a whole. In some cases, a regulatory agency such as the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) or an industry commission (such as banking or in- surance) may mandate financial accounting practices. In other cases, financial ac- counting information is required for obtaining loans, preparing tax returns, and un- derstanding how well or poorly the business is performing. By comparison, management accounting provides information for internal users. Because managers are often concerned with individual parts or segments of the business rather than the whole organization, management accounting information commonly addresses such individualized concerns rather than the “big picture” of financial accounting. Management accounting is not required to adhere to gener- ally accepted accounting principles in providing information for managers’ inter- nal purposes. It is, however, expected to be flexible in serving management’s needs Part 1 Overview F i n a n c i a l A c c o u n t i n g M a n a g e m e n t A c c o u n t i n g P r i m a r y u s e r s E x t e r n a l I n t e r n a l Primary organizational f o c u s W h o l e ( a g g r e g a t e d ) P a r t s ( s e g m e n t e d ) Information c h a r a c t e r i s t i c s M u s t b e M a y b e • Historical • Current or forecasted • Quantitative • Quantitative or qualitative • Monetary • Monetary or nonmonetary • Verifiable • Timely and, at a minimum, reasonably estimated O v e r r i d i n g c r i t e r i a G e n e r a l l y a c c e p t e d S i t u a t i o n a l r e l e v a n c e a c c o u n t i n g p r i n c i p l e s ( u s e f u l n e s s ) C o n s i s t e n c y B e n e f i t s i n e x c e s s o f c o s t s V e r i f i a b i l i t y F l e x i b i l i t y R e c o r d k e e p i n g F o r m a l C o m b i n a t i o n o f f o r m a l a n d informal EXHIBIT 1–1 Financial and Management Accounting Differences of 00 
Leave a Comment
 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... e_Nomad 
Thaks for sharing. Hope to keep it up.
 reply 03 / 24 / 2010 boy_quyet 
thank
 reply 12 / 27 / 2009 vidz_amazinggrace9536 
this is a good book.....
 reply 03 / 25 / 2009 Comment must not be empty. You must be logged in to leave a comment. Submit Characters: ... 
Introduction to Cost and Management Accounting in a Global Business Environment
 Download or Print 30,404 Reads Info and Rating 
 Category: Uncategorized. Rating: ( 3 Ratings) Upload Date: 03/07/2009 Copyright: Attribution Non-commercial Tags: This document has no tags. 
 Free ebook download as PDF File (.pdf), text file (.txt) or read book online for free. Flag document for inapproriate content This is a private document.
	</body>
</document>
