<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001536" url="http://fuerza-laboral.org/news.php" time="2012-07-12-17:18" support="1" score="0.00101844027369262" bingtitle="Fuerza Laboral" webtitle="Fuerza Laboral">
			<query id="000801" bing-rank="237"/>
	<description>Click here to buy tickets using your credit card. ... We will have two meeting places: at 10am at the ... for nearly three years, at an Olneyville fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Home
 
About Us
 
News
 
Campaigns
 
Videos
 
Support Us
 
Contact
 
 
 
News

Fuerza Laboral in the National Quaker Conference

 Tuesday July 10, 2012 


On July 5th, Fuerza Laboral participated in the National Quaker Conference. Representing Fuerza Laboral were Carmen Atencia, Flor Isaza and Heiny Maldonado. Carmen gave a wonderful testimony (attached below) which led to a two hour focus on our organization after her participation, later followed by the participation of a student from the Dream Act movement. Carmen spoke of our community as that of hard working people, unwilling to characterize us a victimized people who seek out pity.

 

 Good morning dear audience!:

My name is Carmen Atencia, I’m a community leader of Fuerza Laboral. I’d like to thank you in my name and that of the organization for the opportunity of participating in this National Quaker Conference. Our desire is to share the reality of our working community in the Unites States, our challenges and risky situations that we confront daily.

We live in an age of capitalist globalization. The basic characteristics of this age are a great economic inequality, huge poverty for most and great riches in the hands of few. The role of multinational corporations and the systemic violation of the rights of workers and their working conditions are well known, especially in third world countries, forcing immigration in search of opportunity and a dignified life.

In the last few years, this great nation has developed feelings of adversity towards the immigrant community, and this has unleashed the creation of unjust laws in the state level and violations of worker and cultural rights of “minorities” (Example: part of law SB1070).

The media informs us of continuous detention and deportation of immigrants, and the problem of illegal immigration continues to cause controversy and unleashing emotions. We are very worried because we are seeing how phenomena such as racism, xenophobia, neo-fascist practices and organized attacks against immigrants have become stronger.

I see the need in talking to you and to talk about some of the myths and realities about us, immigrants, which have fed a hostile debate around the theme of immigration. It is time to clarify things!

 Myth: “Undocumented workers take advantage of the welfare system”
 Reality: Undocumented workers do not qualify for most of state and federal benefits. In a newsletter sent out yesterday, the conservative Institute Cato cites an analysis done by the congress about census data that demonstrate that only about 6.2% of foreign-born (those with a legal status and whom have children who qualify) use the “Food Stamps” program. 

 Myth: “Undocumented immigrants are the cause for the rise in crime rates”
 Reality: Criminal rates are the lowest in the states with the largest majority of immigrants, including Arizona, according to a 2008 report by the conservative organization American Majority. 

 Myth: “Undocumented immigrants don’t pay taxes”
 Reality: Undocumented workers pay sales taxes. Many do pay income taxes, just as it is demonstrated by the Social Security Administration’s suspense file (thousands of millions of dollars in tax declarations that do not coincide with workers, names or social security numbers). 

 Myth: “Undocumented workers take away jobs and opportunities that belong to native workers”
 Reality: Immigrant workers help fill voids in the labor markets, often working hard, underpaid jobs that natives reject. Some analysts say that the presence of undocumented workers has a minimum effect over native workers that don’t have a high school diploma. But very often, they do not stress that it is unscrupulous employers who reduce the pay of workers by paying them under the table, that way avoiding having to pay taxes over payroll. As workers, innovators and small business owners, immigrants fill voids in the service sector. And because they widen consumer bases, lower end and administrative positions filled by native workers are created. 

 Myth: “Undocumented workers don’t want to learn English”
 Reality: It is not only a reality that study after study has demonstrated that immigrants consider learning English a top priority but also many ESOL classes have to put students on waiting lists. 

 Myth: “The use of undocumented workers in public services is affecting negatively our economy”
 Reality: According to a study led by the Standards of Poverty Research Agency, the cost of provision of services to undocumented immigrants is in large part compensated by the economic benefits they generate. 

Immigrants and Employment.
 Myth: “Immigrants lower the American workers’ salary”
 Reality: Economic researchers have concluded that inequality of income in the lower half of the salary scale has not grown since the mid 1980’s. There’s been a general decrease in the salary for low-skilled workers, an economist of the Dallas Federal Reserve says that the studies show that it is in part affected by immigrants. According to the New York Times there is little evidence that illegal immigrants have caused significant damage to the salaries of American workers. The fact is that the factor that allows us to predict salary disparity is not whether one is an immigrant, independent of their situation, or native. It is education. 

 Myth: “Immigrants only perform domestic jobs when they arrive in the United States”
 Reality: The Dallas Federal Reserve estimates that 40% of doctorates, scientists and engineers have been born in another country. Furthermore, foreign-born businessmen are behind 25% of all technological advances in the US in the last 10 years, according to Duke University research. 

 Myth: “Most undocumented immigrants work day jobs.”
 Reality: Data gathered by researchers at UCLA, the University of Illinois and NYU indicate that less that 2% of the approximate 7.5 million undocumented workers are day laborers. 

 Myth: “Undocumented workers work almost exclusively low-paying jobs”
 Reality: Undocumented workers represent less that 10 % of the 43 million low salary workers in the United States, according to the Pew Hispanic Center. 

 Myth: “Undocumented workers come here to receive free government services”
 Reality: Most come here to work. Of the total of 11.5 to 12 million undocumented workers that live in the United States, 7.5 of them are employed, and undocumented men come almost exclusively to work. Their participation in the work force, the 96%, is superior to those that are legal immigrants or U.S citizens (Facts and Figures of Undocumented Immigrants, Urban Institute). On the other hand, undocumented immigrants are not eligible for social assistance, food stamps, Medicaid and most public services. 

 Myth: “Undocumented workers are stealing low-paying jobs that Americans need”
 Reality: There is no evidence that immigrants have an impact in the result of native employment with low education level, and that are 25 – 34. In fact, there is proof that immigrants actually create job openings. For example, the efforts of an agricultural worker supports three job openings in neighboring economies – machinery, processing, insurance, agricultural loans – that would otherwise disappear (Ohio Republican Senator George Voinovich, cited by the Wall Street Journal). 

Now I wish to share with you my reality in the United States. My name, as I mentioned at the beginning of this conference is Carmen Atencia, and I’m a first generation immigrant. I have a son, his name is Jeremy Cumplido, he turned 9 yesterday and is an American citizen. I’m proud of him because he’s a studious boy and at the end of the school year he received honorable mentions due to his high grades. He’s my inspiration to succeed in this country and I want him to have the same sense of pride for his mother; I wish for him to be a man that is good for society.

I’m learning English with much dedication, and I work hard because my wish is to become a nurse. Currently I’m working through the relevant procedures to enroll in a health program in the fall.

I’m a member and leader of Fuerza Laboral and of the Episcopal Church; I feel love for and vocation to help my community.

The challenges and risky situations will always be recurrent for a first generation immigrant, such as racial profiling, labor injustices, amongst many. But the difference is that I know and defend my rights, organizing to combat social injustices with the support of ally organization such as yours, and we want from this moment on to seal a strong alliance for the reasons that brings us together: all human being deserve to be treated with equality, dignity and respect. Thank you. 


We are Looking for Participants in a Non-payment of Wages Study

 Monday June 25, 2012 


Have you ever experienced:
• Unpaid wages?
• Unpaid overtime?
• Been classified as an independent contractor when you were actually an employee?

We want to hear your story! Join Fuerza Laboral and URI&apos;s study on non-payment of wages! Requirements:
• Participate in a focus group for 2 hours. We will compensate your time, if you need childcare please call ahead.
• Be 18 years or older.
• You must work in Rhode Island in one of the following industries: construction, landscaping, cleaning, car wash, retail, restaurants, temporary employment agency, manufacturing.
• You must not be self-employed/contractor.

Please call Josie or Heiny at (401) 725-2700, or send an email to estudio.fuerza.laboral[a]gmail.com to participate or find out more.

Time to renew your membership (or join for the first time)

 Friday June 1, 2012 


If it&apos;s time to renew your membership, or to join for the first time, click here to donate with your credit card. Individual membership is $25, family membership $30. If you&apos;re not sure if it&apos;s time for you to renew, don&apos;t hesitate to call us at 401-725-2700.

Your membership is an investment in the community, and helps sustain our organization in the long term, as we work to achieve our mission. As a member, you enjoy the following benefits:
-Profound understanding of your rights.
-Participation in creating real changes that benefit the whole community.
-The satisfaction of belonging to an organization that fights for a just society.
-Opportunities for local and national training.
-The ability to vote for our Board and guide our campaigns.


Eleven Fuerza leaders and allies attended the NPA Conference

 Friday June 1, 2012 


Leaders from Fuerza, along with three of our allies from the Metrowest Worker Center, took the trip to Washington, D.C. to participate in the National People&apos;s Action Conference May 19-21. In addition to presenting as part of workshops on Justice for Immigrants and Justice for Workers, the group took part in the NPA actions. These included a 1,000 person march to the house of Treasury Secretary Timothy Geithner, and a coordinated take-over of the lobbies of 3 Wells Fargo branches to demand that they stop funding the private prison industry and deportations. For videos, descriptions, and photos, click here! 
Community Forum on Wage Theft

 Thursday February 23, 2012 


 Why are hundreds of workers in RI getting cheated out of their just wages?
And how much is this costing the state? 

We invite you to a forum to learn about wage theft – the crime wave no one talks about – and what can be done to protect workers, promote good businesses, and bring revenue into RI.

 When: Thursday, March 1, 2012, 5:30pm-7:30pm

 Where: Saint Patrick Church, 244 Smith St. Providence, RI 02908
(A few blocks away from the State House)


What we are demanding: Stronger penalties and enforcement when bad employers stealing wages. Right now RI’s penalties for wage theft are very weak, as well as enforcement. Bad employers manipulate the system and continue to practice wage theft, free from punishment. End the practice of paying less than minimum wage, paying overtime as if it were regular hours, misclassification of employees as “independent contractors”, and plant closings with no notice. Join with Fuerza in this fight to demand justice for everybody!



Please call us at 401-725-2700 with any questions.

 Every day, millions of responsible, profitable employers in this country comply with minimum wage and overtime laws. When we allow their unscrupulous competitors to undercut them on labor costs, we are starting a race to the bottom that will reverberate throughout the entire labor market in a cascading loss of good jobs. 

-Winning Wage Justice by the National Employment Law Project (January, 2011).

 Some will rob you with a six-gun,
And some with a fountain pen. 

-Pretty Boy Floyd, by Woodie Guthrie (1958)


Happy New Year

 Monday December 19, 2011 


We wish you a happy new year, from all of us at Fuerza Laboral! We look forward to seeing you at our events and activities in 2012.

 **The office will be closed between December 26 - January 13** 
Celebrate 5 Years With Us - November 18 - Buy your tickets now!

 Friday September 23, 2011 


We cordially invite you to celebrate our first 5 years with dancing, food, and presentations on our victories.

Friday, November 18, 2011
6pm-12am

***Featuring the fabulous DJ Salsa Stereo spinning the best merengue, bachata, salsa, and American hits. With a LIVE performance by Latin reggae artist Rabbit (El Conejo)***

Portuguese Social Club
131 School Street, Pawtucket, RI 02860
Large parking lot ❺ Exit 28 from 95 North or 27 from 95 South
Food is included with the ticket price ❺ Cash bar

Tickets: $10 in advance, $15 at the door

Call us at 401.725.2700 with questions or to buy tickets,

 Click here to buy tickets using your credit card. Be sure to enter your full name so that we can hold your tickets at the door.




Labor Rights Week - this week!

 Monday August 29, 2011 


Join Fuerza Laboral at one of the Labor Rights Week events below. All events are organized by the Guatemalan General Consulate and are a great opportunity to learn more about workers rights!

Saturday, August 27, 2011, 10am-12 noon: Inaugural Event, Chelsea Collaborative (318 Broadway Street, Chelsea, MA 02150)

Sunday, August 28, 2011, 4pm-8pm: Interview on People&apos;s Radio 1490 AM in Springfield, MA

Monday, August 29, 2011, 2pm-4pm: Interview on WTCC 90.7 FM of Springfield, MA

Tuesday, August 30, 2011, 6pm-8pm: Info Fair in the Biblical Institute (370 Hartford Ave., Providence, RI 02909)

Thursday, September 1, 2011, 6pm-8pm: Info Fair in Progreso Latino (626 Broad Street, Central Falls, RI 02888)

Friday, September 2, 2011, 6pm-8pm: Closing Events in the Guatemalan General Consulate (555 Valley Street, Providence, RI 02908)
Join Us! Family Picnic, July 30

 Friday June 24, 2011 


Dear friends,

We invite you to join us for a fun day of food and games in a beautiful spot near the ocean!

 When : Saturday, July 30, 2011, 11am-5pm
 Where : Colt State Park (Bristol, RI), click here to see more information on the Park, including directions.
 Details : We will have talent contests, potato sack races, traditional foods and many other entertaining activities. Since it is a picnic we will all bring food to share. Some suggestions; Fruit, snacks, traditional foods, hot dogs, hamburgers, salads, sodas, or any other kind of food you like.

We will have two meeting places: at 10am at the office of Fuerza (127 Clay St., Central Falls). Then we will go to Saint Teresa Church (275 Manton Ave.) to meet up with our members in Providence at 10:30am. From there we will all go to the park in a caravan.

Please call us to RSVP by Monday, July 25: 401.725.2700

Fuerza - and the problem of wage theft - in the News

 Friday June 17, 2011 


Elias Cabrera says he worked as a cook, seven days a week for nearly three years, at an Olneyville fast-food restaurant but never got paid overtime.

Cabrera testified before a legislative committee that his former employer owes him $12,214.50 all told. That includes not being paid for his final week, during which he worked 57 hours, Cabrera said.

“When I went to ask for the money from my work, what I got were insults and threats, and also my former boss saying not to return there,” Cabrera alleged to the House Labor Committee on Tuesday.

For the full story, click here .


 Friday June 10, 2011 



OSHA at Fuerza

 Monday May 16, 2011 


Protect yourself: You have the right to a safe and healthy work place!

Saturday, May 21, 2011, 3pm-5pm. MaryAnn Medeiros, OSHA
Compliance Assistance Specialist, will present information on the laws
that regulate your right to a safe and healthy work place. In addition,
we will be giving out certificates to those who have completed our Basic
Workers Rights course. Free babysitting will be available at this event.

Location: Headquarters of Fuerza Laboral, 127 Clay St. Central Falls, RI 02863
For more information, call: Fuerza Laboral 401-725-2700, Contact person: Heiny Maldonado


Thanks everyone!

 Monday April 11, 2011 


Our Salsa with Fuerza party this past Saturday was a big success! Thank you to everyone who helped organize it, Saint George&apos;s Episcopal Church for hosting it, and of course everyone who came to dance and have a good time. You helped strengthen our movement to build the power of workers and immigrants with your presence and your generosity!

Check out photos from the party on our Facebook page! Click here to see them or to join our Facebook group.

And it is not too late to donate! Click here to give.


Salsa with Fuerza!

 Tuesday April 5, 2011 


Join us on Saturday, April 9, 2011 for a special salsa dance party to have a great time and strengthen a movement with your generosity.

Place: Saint George&apos;s Episcopal Church, 12 Clinton Street, Central Falls, RI
6pm-7pm: Salsa lessons with professional dance instructor Emiliano Luna
7pm-11:30pm: Dancing, food, fun

Tickets: $10 ahead of time, $15 at the door

To purchase tickets, please mail your check to Fuerza Laboral (P.O. Box 202, Central Falls, RI 02863), bring cash to the party, or click here to use your credit card:
https://www.justgive.org/nonprofits/donate.jsp?ein=20-5428607
(Be sure to note that the donation is for Salsa with Fuerza)

Fuerza Leaders Meet With US Labor Secretary Hilda Solis

 Monday November 22, 2010 


As part of a delegation of grassroots leaders of National People&apos;s Action, this past Monday November 15th two Fuerza leaders, Shirley Samayoa and Joanna Rodriguez, met with the country&apos;s top decision-maker in labor issues: US Secretary of Labor Hilda Solis. The meeting focused on alliance building and strengthening enforcement of wage theft. Additionally, Shirley, an ex-Colibri worker, pushed for Sec. Solis to assign a division of the USDOL to enforce the WARN Act, a law that is on the books without anyone responsible for it. We will be following up on this issue.
Check out the USDOL&apos;s slideshow from the event, especially the photo of Fuerza leader Shirley speaking about the WARN Act .
Public Meeting: Results and Commitments

 Monday September 27, 2010 


This past Saturday 116 people came out to a public meeting organized by Fuerza Laboral called: Fuerza Laboral and the US Department of Labor: Solutions to Labor Abuses. Two US DOL investigators attended along with the Regional Deputy Director.

In this meeting, Fuerza Laboral members presented testimony of real abuses occurring in RI workplaces as well as our platform for change. The following commitments were made by local decision makers at our meeting:
1. Rep. Grace Diaz will introduce two legislative proposals against wage theft in the upcoming session. One will provide double-to-triple damages to the aggrieved worker and increase the administrative fines going to the state. The other would make an employer who still refuses to pay within a reasonable time from a guilty verdict by the RI Department of Labor and Training criminally responsible for larceny.
2. Central Falls City Councilman James Diossa pledged to work with Fuerza Laboral in introducing a wage theft ordinance in the city of Central Falls. He will be in communication with organizations and lawmakers in Miami, where such an ordinance has passed already, and New Orleans, where one is in the works.
3. Rep. Bob DaSilva pledged to reintroduce the RI WARN Act in the upcoming session, and Patrick Quinn of SEIU pledged to help it gain traction.
4. Officials from the USDOL will be working more closely with Fuerza Laboral to ensure worker protections.

Fuerza Laboral members also put out a call for the need to stop the abuse of misclassifying workers as independent contractors to later refuse to pay them. Legislation was introduced this year, but it penalizes innocent workers as opposed to unscrupulous employers.

All around the country, organizations like us that are part of National People&apos;s Action are meeting with US DOL representatives and preparing for a face-to-face meeting between grassroots worker-leaders and Secretary Hilda Solis in November.

Here is a link to an article in the Providence Journal. 
Public Meeting w/ US Dept. of Labor: Presenting Solutions to Labor Abuses

 Wednesday September 15, 2010 


Date: September 25
Time: 3:00pm - 5:00pm
Place: St. George&apos;s Episcopal Church,12 Clinton Street, corner of Central St., Central Falls, RI

Fuerza Laboral will present our platform of concrete solutions to end the problem of wage theft and the lack of protections for unemployed workers. Officials from the US Department of Labor in Washington DC will be present. The event is open to all who support the rights of workers! Let&apos;s pack the place!
Policy makers are invited to attend and listen to the testimonies, learn about the problems and what steps they can take. We expect several announcements from legislators regarding commitments they will make to ensure workers protections in the coming year.

Respond on Facebook if you can come!
Seeking: Our Next Executive Director

 Wednesday August 18, 2010 


Fuerza Laboral is seeking candidates to be our next executive director, specifically, someone with experience in organizing and administration, who is fully committed to leadership by the community and who can take our organization to the next level in terms of funding, staffing, systems, membership and victories.
Check out the position profile and application process here. 
Tomorrow, Thursday, July 29: National Day of Action Against SB1070

 Wednesday July 28, 2010 


Stand tall against inhumane immigration policies like what was introduced in Arizona. 12:15 pm: Faith-based rally and vigil. State House Lawn

4 pm People&apos;s Rally: Protest Racism from Arizona to RI, Armory Park, at Cranston and Dexter Streets in Providence.

Wage Theft Clinic

 Tuesday July 20, 2010 


Tonight! (and every first and third Tuesday): Wage Theft Clinic at Fuerza Laboral 6 -7:30 pm. 127 Clay St, Central Falls, RI 02863. If you have worked and been paid with a bad check, underpaid, or not paid at all, come to the clinic to learn how you can fight back and get your pay!



 Tuesday July 20, 2010 





 Thursday June 17, 2010 



Take Back Democracy in Central Falls

 Monday June 7, 2010 


Tonight at 6pm in our office at 127 Clay Street there will be a community forum about the receivership (bankruptcy) of the City of Central Falls. What does this mean for Central Falls residents in terms of local and state representation and essential services? Come find out! Meeting will be bilingual English/ Spanish, and facilitated by a coalition that includes Fuerza Laboral, RI Jobs With Justice, AFSCME, and the Central Falls Firefighters.
UPDATE: Over 130 people particpated in the meeting! Check out press: Providence Journal and Channel 10 NBC. 

RI Will Not Be the Next Arizona!

 Friday May 21, 2010 


Yesterday a coalition of community organizations, including Fuerza Laboral, Olneyville Neighborhood Association, DARE, Providence SDS, Ocean State Action and others responded rapidly to Rep. Peter Palumbo&apos;s Arizona-copycat legislation. Over 100 folks of all races, ages and genders took over the floor of the House of Representatives to say, &quot;Never here!&quot; Check out press coverage here. 
Fuerza Laboral in the Washington Post

 Tuesday May 18, 2010 


Today in the pre-dawn hours, Fuerza members returned from the Showdown on K Street, where thousands of everyday people took to the streets to ask our government, Which side are you on? The people or the monied lobbyists and corporations?
Click here for quotes from Fuerza leaders Shirley and Gustavo Samayoa in the Washington Post.
Fuerza in Washington for the Showdown on K Street

 Friday May 14, 2010 


12 representatives of Fuerza Laboral will board a van at 5am tomorrow to head to Washington DC for the annual National People&apos;s Action conference with thousands of community leaders from across the country, sharing strategies and holding decision-makers, banks and corporations accountable. During the Showdown on K Street, we&apos;ll take on monied lobbyists and big banks who continue to wreak havoc on our economy and then get bailed out by taxpayers. This year Fuerza Laboral&apos;s Theatre Brigade will perform.
May 1st Unity Day

 Wednesday May 5, 2010 


Fuerza Laboral was among the many diverse organizations that turned out in force for the May 1st Unity Day Rally in front of the RI State House. Three of our leaders had roles in the agenda (click on the names for videos): Shirley Samayoa led a rallying cry for workers to fight back, Joanna Rodriguez inspired all who heard, and Bernardo Chamorro read a moving poem he composed specifically for May First about the surging movement for immigrant rights.
Ready to March!

 Thursday March 18, 2010 


Over 200 Rhode Islanders will be attending the March for America: Comprehensive Immigration Reform Now in Washington DC this Sunday, March 21.
Fuerza Laboral has been a lead organization in Rhode Island, coordinating with the Immigrants in Action Committee, United We Dream, SEIU, and from New Bedford: Catholic Social Services, the Community Workers&apos; Center, and United Interfaith Action.
We march to hold Obama accountable to his promise to pass Comprehensive Immigration Reform, and to ensure Congress is on board.
Over 100,000 people are expected in D.C. This will be an historical moment!

Direct Action Training in Spanish

 Wednesday March 3, 2010 


This Saturday, March 6
3pm - 6 pm
127 Clay Street, Central Falls
Free and Open to the Community
(Conducted in Spanish. English trainings at a later date)

Fuerza Laboral will be sharing our methodology of direct action with the goal of growing our rapid-response team, &quot;the Wage Protectors,&quot; to end wage theft. Members of this team work together to confront abusive employers.

Come and learn how to plan and carry out a direct action (a protest that gets concrete results). Interactive, fun and important information for these times.

Please call us at 401-725-2700 to confirm your presence. Onward!
Fuerza Leader Speaks to Press about Unscrupulous Employers

 Friday February 12, 2010 


Today&apos;s Providence Journal had an article about Thursday&apos;s press conference with the Gillette stadium workers who were picked up in an ICE raid. Don Bernardo Chamorro represented Fuerza Laboral in the press conference and spoke strongly and eloquently about how unscrupulous employers take advantage of the lack of labor law enforcement to exploit workers. Check out the article and video here. 
One Year Since Colibri&apos;s Closure, the Fight Goes On!

 Thursday January 14, 2010 


One year ago today, Founders&apos; Equity petitioned for Colibri to enter receivership and Colibri CEO Jim Fleet let his 280 workers know by email that their workplace had closed. Knowing this was a violation of the Federal WARN Act, workers protested, committed civil disobedience, and filed a Federal lawsuit to get justice.
This past Monday, the workers&apos; representative, Attorney Marc Gursky attended a pretrial with the judge and the defendants&apos; lawyers. The judge called for a 60 day discovery period, in which the defendants have to turn over to Marc any materials,documents, or communications relating to the employer relationship. After this time, both parties return to court to try to reach a settlement with the help of a court appointed mediator.
We are pleased to report that the Impact Fund in California has awarded funding specifically to pay for costs associated with the lawsuit. With a dedicated expert lawyer like Marc, and the support of a major legal justice foundation we are confident justice will be done.
Support Comprehensive Immigration Reform!

 Friday January 8, 2010 


Fuerza Laboral has joined the Reform Immigration FOR America Campaign to achieve comprehensive immigration reform this year. The Campaign has a text message component in which individuals can receive updates on the struggle on their cell phones, and also send electronic faxes to their congresspeople urging their support! Sent the text message &quot;JUSTICE&quot;to #69866 to participate. More info: www.reformimmigrationforamerica.org 
Fuerza Laboral at the Showdown in Chicago

 Tuesday October 27, 2009 


Fuerza Laboral has been at the Showdown in Chicago, organized by National People&apos;s Action (of which we&apos;re an affiliate member) these past few days--the first organized mass demonstration against the banker robber barons since the bailout. We&apos;ve given the banks 19 trillion dollars in bailout money, most of which has gone to CEOs. It&apos;s about time for some accountability. Check out video
	</body>
</document>
