<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001615" url="http://www.cocktail.uk.com/shop/products/home-cinema-entertainment.asp" time="2012-07-12-17:23" support="2" score="0.008773571248467815" bingtitle="Buy Home Cinema | Cocktail : UK Bar Equipment Shop" webtitle="Buy Home Cinema | Cocktail : UK Bar Equipment Shop">
			<query id="000916" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="000235" bing-rank="193"/>
	<description>... beverage cooler/warmer, you&apos;ll never want to leave ... if you want one for a rental shop, convenience store, concession stand, vending cart, break room, fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		My Basket 
 0 Items £0.00 
 
 Cocktail : UK &gt; Bar Equipment Shop &gt; Home Cinema 
 
 
 
 View my basket (0 Items£0.00) 
 
 
 
 FREE standard UK delivery on orders over£75 250,000 orders since 1999 
 Go to:   Select a department... New Arrivals Euro 2012 Party Best Selling Bar Cocktail Wine Glassware Plastic Glasses Catering Bar Stools Party Games Room Gifts Home&amp;Garden Inflatable Hot Tubs Coming Soon Sale Clearance Sale Bundles Shop by Brand Olympics London 2012 Party 
 

 
Home Cinema
 Show 5 10 20 All products 

 «Back To Games Room 
 
 
 
New in 13-Jun 
 
 Slushie Maker 
 


This Slushie Maker is a perfect way to quench your thirst. Makes perfect slushies or cocktails. Can make up to 1 Litre worth of slush each use. Great for kids or adults. High speed motor for making fast slushie drinks. Easy assembly and dismantle mak
 
 More details 
 
 
 
 £49.99 In Stock&amp;Available For Immediate Dispatch 
   
 
 
 
 
 
 Genware Barrier Post with Retractable Black Belt 
 


Quick, simple&amp;easy to use barrier, belt extends up to 2m. Secure weighted base, quick&amp;easy to assemble.

 Dimensions: 
H 910mmØ320mm
 
 More details 
 
 
 
 Click here for prices... Single 
 -£44.99 Case of 2 
 -£84.99 All Items In 
 Stock&amp;Available For Immediate Dispatch 
   
 
 
 
 
 
 Hollywood Popcorn Boxes 
 


These Hollywood Popcorn Boxes are ideal for home movie nights and parties. Cardboard, disposable.

 Dimensions: 
H 135mm W 70mm D 40mm
 
 More details 
 
 
 
 Click here for prices... Pack of 8 
 -£2.99 
 Out Of Stock Case of 96 
 -£26.99 
 Out Of Stock Some Items 
 Out Of Stock - Check List Above.. Email me when back in stock 
   
 
 
 
 
 
 Tefcold TM50G Mini Bar 
 


The Tefcold TM50G Glass Door Mini Bar features a large 50 litre storage capacity, making it ideal for storing plenty of drinks and snacks. Perfect for use in hotel rooms, offices and student accommodation. Features a lockable door, 2 adjustable shelv
 
 More details 
 
 
 
 £399.99 In Stock&amp;Available For Immediate Dispatch 
   
 
 
 
 
 
 Premiere Home Cinema Seating 
 


Get the most out of your private home cinema with the Premiere Home Cinema Seating. Featuring a motorised incliner, remote controlled massage/heating system, and a beverage cooler/warmer, you&apos;ll never want to leave the comfort of this luxury set of s
 
 More details 
 
 
 
 Click here for prices... 1 Seater Black Leather 
 -£1,199.99 1 Seater Brown Leather 
 -£1,199.99 2 Seater Black Leather With Mini Fridge 
 -£2,399.99 2 Seater Brown Leather With Mini Fridge 
 -£2,399.99 3 Seater Black Leather With Mini Fridge 
 -£3,449.99 3 Seater Brown Leather With Mini Fridge 
 -£3,449.99 4 Seater Black Leather With Mini Fridge 
 -£4,499.99 4 Seater Brown Leather With Mini Fridge 
 -£4,499.99 5 Seater Black Leather With Mini Fridge 
 -£5,499.99 5 Seater Brown Leather With Mini Fridge 
 -£5,499.99 Leather&amp;Suede Fabric Samples 
 -£1.50 All Items In 
 Stock&amp;Available For Immediate Dispatch 
   
 
 
 
 
 
 Home Cinema Popcorn Pack 
 


The Home Cinema Pack contains 2 of Zaramama&apos;s most popular varieties of popping corn. The popping oil is UK grown, cold pressed, extra virgin rapeseed oil. This has a light nutty flavour and a high smoke point, making it ideal for popping corn.

 
 More details 
 
 
 
 £13.99 In Stock&amp;Available For Immediate Dispatch 
   
 
 
 
 
 
 7 Colour Changing LED Strip Lights 
 


The 7 Colour Changing LED Strip Light Kit includes a plug in power supply, 2 x LED strips, an RF remote receiver and key fob remote. The LEDS can be turned on and off with the remote switched to a single colour, or set to gently phase through the wol
 
 More details 
 
 
 
 £39.99 (Pack of 2) In Stock&amp;Available For Immediate Dispatch 
   
 
 
 
 
 
 Cocktail Fountain 53oz / 15ltr 
 


This Cocktail Fountain features a large capacity of 15 litres, a lit central column and clear dome at the
top to showcase your cocktail of choice and is hand polished and custom made.

 Dimensions: 
H 560mm W 420mm L
 
 More details 
 
 
 
 £1,134.99 In Stock&amp;Available For Immediate Dispatch 
   
 
 
 
 
 
 Premiere Home Cinema Chair Black 
 


Get the most out of your private home cinema with the Premiere Home Cinema Seating. Featuring a motorised incliner, remote controlled massage/heating system, and a beverage cooler/warmer, you&apos;ll never want to leave the comfort of this luxury set of s
 
 More details 
 
 
 
 Click here for prices... Single Seat Chair 
 -£1,199.99 4-Socket Ext. Lead 
 -£4.99 All Items In 
 Stock&amp;Available For Immediate Dispatch 
   
 
 
 
 
 
 The Dog Hut Hotdog Steamer 
 


You will find everything that you need in a hot dog machine, from The Paragon Hot Dog Hut, ideal if you want one for a rental shop, convenience store, concession stand, vending cart, break room, fast food restaurant, snack bar, cafeteria and many oth
 
 More details 
 
 
 
 £689.99 In Stock&amp;Available For Immediate Dispatch 
   
 
 
 More products: 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Next&gt;&gt; 

 

 
  Cocktail recipes 
 
  Shooters 
 
  Naughty XXX drinks 
 
  Non-alcoholic cocktails 
 
  Drink 
of the day 
 
  Cocktail&amp;flair courses 
 
  Latest drinks 
 
  Random drink 
 
  Submit a drink 
 
  Top ten 
 
  Drink generator 
 
  Log in 
 
  Register (free) 

 
  Mobile bar service 
 
  Drinking games 
 
  Desktop backgrounds 
 
 
 New arrivals    
 
 Euro 2012 party    
 
 Best selling    
 
 Bar    
 
 Cocktail    
 
 Wine    
 
 Glassware    
 
 Plastic glasses    
 
 Catering    
 
 Bar stools    
 
 Party    
 
 Games room    
 
 Gifts    
 
 Home&amp;garden    
 
 Inflatable hot tubs    
 
 Coming soon    
 
 Sale    
 
 Clearance sale    
 
 Bundles    
 
 Shop by brand    
 
 Olympics london 2012 party    
 
 View my basket    
 
 Delivery prices    
 
 About Drinkstuff    
 
 Customer services    
 
 
 
 
 
   
 Partners: Cocktail Equipment | Drinkstuff | CES | Barmans 
   HTML to PDF conversion by ABCpdf ©2012  About us | Contact us | Privacy policy | Mobile Cocktail : UK
	</body>
</document>
