<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001942" url="http://tech.ca.msn.com/apples-iphone-event-is-near-5-predictions" time="2012-07-12-17:51" support="1" score="0.0013861600743639115" bingtitle="Apple&apos;s iPhone Event is Near: 5 Predictions - PC World Article ..." webtitle="Apple&apos;s iPhone Event is Near: 5 Predictions -  PC World Article - TechGadget - MSN CA">
			<query id="001468" bing-rank="193"/>
	<description>Apple&apos;s iPhone Event is Near: 5 Predictions. Apple will put an end to the rumors and introduce its next iPhone on October 4--it ...</description>
	<body>
		Remind me later No, Thanks 
 All MSN 
 Hotmail Messenger My MSN MSN Directory 

 Autos Bing Toolbar Careers Celebs Dating 

 Entertainment Games Fitbie Horoscopes Lifestyle 

 Mobile Money Movies Music News 

 Shopping Sports Tech&amp;Gadgets Travel Video 

 Weather Yellow Pages ™ MORE… 
 Hotmail Messenger MSN Home 
 Make MSN your Homepage 
 Français Page Options 
 Make text larger Support Like MSN on Facebook RSS 
 Sign In 
 Tech&amp;Gadgets 
Live search:
 Live search: Follow 
 Home PC World 
 Tech news Product reviews How-to guide 
 Hot Gadgets Video Consumer Reports Windows 8 Preview Blog: Geektown.ca Cloud 
 Home editorial articles advertorial content microsoft private cloud 
 Video games Site Map 
 
 
 By Jared Newman 
Apple&apos;s iPhone Event is Near: 5 Predictions


 
 
 
 
Apple will put an end to the rumors and introduce its next iPhone on October 4--it&apos;s already sent out invitations to an iPhone-specific event that will be held at Apple&apos;s Cupertino campus. New Apple CEO Tim Cook is expected to take the stage and make the big announcement.


This means we&apos;ve got just one more week for some good, old-fashioned speculation. Here&apos;s what I think we&apos;ll see at Apple&apos;s upcoming iPhone event:

Prediction #1: The New iPhone Will Look Different

Depending on which story you&apos;re reading, the next iPhone will either have a completely new design or be exactly the same, aesthetically, as the iPhone 4.

 
 
 
In other words, Apple has managed to keep the tech press guessing. But considering that Apple has gone 16 months without announcing a new iPhone, I would be surprised if the iPhone 5&apos;s design offers nothing new.


Prediction #2: Hardware Will be New, but Predictable

The iPhone 4 had a new design, but it didn&apos;t surprise us with its specs--it received the same A4 chip as the iPad. Following the same lines, I think the next iPhone will have the same dual-core A5 chip that debuted in the iPad 2.

I think we can probably look forward to a new camera--not only do rumors suggest that the next iPhone will have an 8MP camera, but Apple has a history of improving the iPhone&apos;s camera with each generation . To go with the new chip and camera, the next iPhone will also probably have 1GB of RAM--but Apple probably won&apos;t say much about this. After all, Apple doesn&apos;t usually spend a lot of time discussing specs.

Prediction #3: Hardware Isn&apos;t Everything

Rumor has it that the next iPhone will have software improvements , including expanded voice commands. The new voice commands--part of a feature reportedly called Assistant --are based on Siri , the virtual assistant software maker that Apple acquired last year.

This system-wide voice navigation system could be a standout feature that&apos;s exclusive to the iPhone 5, and a big focus at next Tuesday&apos;s event. Apple did make voice commands exclusive to the iPhone 3GS in 2009, so requiring an iPhone 5 for expanded voice commands isn&apos;t without precedent.

Bonus prediction: The event invitation includes a photo of the iPhone&apos;s maps application icon, which has me wondering if Apple will finally add turn-by-turn directions.

 
 
 
Prediction #4: A Cheaper iPhone


The use of the singular in the invitation (&quot;Let&apos;s talk iPhone&quot;) has led pundits such as John Gruber to speculate that Apple will only launch one new iPhone, despite rumors to the contrary .

While Apple may not launch an iPhone 4S, it will still drop the price on its old iPhones--AT&amp;T and Verizon iPhone 4&apos;s--as it has in the past. Low-cost, older-generation iPhones have proven to be very successful, and are one of the reasons AT&amp;T far outpaced Verizon in sales in the second quarter, despite Verizon having the iPhone 4. I doubt Apple will give up that market.

 
 
 
Prediction #5: Sprint Gets Love


Between the Wall Street Journal&apos;s unnamed sources, Bloomberg&apos;s unnamed sources, and Sprint&apos;s internal memos telling employees to keep quiet, a Sprint iPhone 5 seems like a good bet.

T-Mobile, on the other hand, probably won&apos;t be part of Apple&apos;s announcement. When asked if T-Mobile would be getting the next iPhone, T-Mobile CEO Cole Brodman recently said , &quot;To my knowledge, not in October.&quot;

 Follow Jared on Facebook , Twitter or Google+ for even more tech news and commentary. 

 Copyright (c) 2011 PCWorld Communications, Inc. 
 Related Videos 
 Share 5 

 0 
 Share with Friends 
 5 Share 
 Latest tech galleries 
 The 10 Commandments of social media etiquette Tech&apos;s worst security breaches How the mighty fell Nature&apos;s strangest defence mechanisms The world’s oldest creatures 15 signs it&apos;s time to quit Facebook Can the Microsoft Surface tablet topple the iPad? Microsoft debuts Surface tablets When Facebook changes the real world The 10 best video games of E3 Best &apos;Draw Something&apos; pictures New stunning images from Hubble The worst countries for cybercrime When exotic pets attack How Facebook updates can get you arrested The tech world’s most pathetic ailments Costumes, celebrities and comics make up Fan Expo Vancouver The best of Canadian video games Make your smartphone the only gadget you&apos;ll ever need Tough gadgets with style Terrifying new species discovered Complex Lego through the ages Laptops: Then and now The wonders of the sky, as seen by NASA Animal imposters 10 things you should never reveal on Facebook Is Pinterest a threat to Facebook? In pictures: Japanese macaques! New Apple iPad: what you need to know Apple unveils new iPad Creatures that never see daylight Windows 8 Consumer Preview screenshots The best smartphones from MWC 2012 Nokia 808 PureView - in pictures Most memorable smartphones - then and now HTC One X - in pictures Most desirable music gadgets 10 robots that could take over the world Companies ditching BlackBerry Augmented reality’s potential uses The world&apos;s biggest and smallest gadgets Facebook Timeline - what you need to know Sony Xperia S and other hot new gadgets Top ten best alternative gadgets The world’s tiniest animals Incredible photos from Antarctica’s ‘Lost World’ Tech’s greatest rivalries Wildest hybrid animals Award-winning tech innovations - in pictures 10 most anticipated console games of 2012 Best console video games of 2011 Cyborg technology Bing’s top tech searches of 2011 $#*! my Siri says 10 of the world’s creepiest robots Southeast Asia’s unbelievable new species Endangered species recently declared extinct Communication etiquette for the 21st century When technology accidentally saves lives Apple iPhone 4S Best bedtime gadgets Weird household inventions Species you might not have known are threatened 11 gadgets that might save your life Creative uses of the new Facebook Timeline City animals that drive us nuts Simple ways to stay safe online The dangerous side of household electronics Leaders react to Steve Jobs&apos; death The remarkable career of Steve Jobs The world’s best-selling cell phones Top 10 smartphones out now High-tech home essentials for the single girl High-tech home essentials for the single guy The web’s most memorable hoaxes Cracking the myths of cryptozoology 10 superhero games that didn&apos;t suck The best non-shooters coming this fall Beautiful and creative QR codes Animals found in unusual places How the web is ruining our lives PC World - 06/09/2011 5:14 PM Most notorious Facebook arrests Who will be the next Steve Jobs? Ten most ridiculous lawsuits of the 21st century World’s wildest transparent creatures Ways the Internet can land you behind bars Facebook’s most controversial features New Guinea’s most breathtaking new species 15 signs it&apos;s time to quit Facebook The history of Research In Motion 12 tech revolutions that fizzled Teammates at odds 10 things you should never do on Facebook Most expensive real estate on the web Google+ vs. Facebook: See How They Compare 10 films that redefined special effects The final space shuttle launch Declared dead online 10 Things You Shouldn&apos;t Be Able to Buy Online PC World - 01/07/2011 12:01 PM 
 advertisement Technology videos Blog: Geektown.ca 
 Yoga instructor fired for giving texting Facebook employee the look NYC converting payphones into Wi-Fi hotspots Windows 8 could boot in half the time it takes to start Windows 7 Man posting to Facebook hit by baseball at game, video goes viral Facebook reportedly testing out new ‘Want’ button Google Now and Project Glass - a creepy match made in heaven? Tim Hortons to offer free Wi-Fi Want a free data plan? Just watch some ads 
 Consumer Reports reviews 
 Security software 
Failing to protect your computer from online threats can shorten your machine&apos;s life and lead to the theft or corruption of data, including sensitive personal information. But you don&apos;t have to spend a lot on security software. We found that free programs are fine for most people.
 E-book readers 
E-book readers are portable devices, usually with display screens optimized to show the electronic text of digital books. These electronic book readers are typically larger than cell phones and smaller than most tablet computers. Tablets with e-book apps, Web browsers and more robust processors typically offer more versatile than e-readers.
 Humidifiers 
Who needs a humidifier? Anyone who has uncomfortably dry or itchy eyes, throat or skin, or whose asthma is a problem indoors during the heating season. In addition to the health benefits, a humidifier can also reduce static electricity, peeling wallpaper, and cracks in paint and furniture.
 
 more... Poll 
Enable JavaScript to see this poll.
 
Are you worried about your online security?
 
Thanks for being one of the first people to vote. Results will be available soon.  Check for results 
 
 Yes, I&apos;ve already been hacked   40
% Yes, I&apos;ve already been hacked 
 855 votes A little, but not enough to do anything   50
% A little, but not enough to do anything 
 1,067 votes No, my passwords are un-hackable   10
% No, my passwords are un-hackable 
 218 votes Skip to results Back to voting 
 
Total Responses: 2,140
Not scientifically valid. Results are updated every minute.
 Bing searches 
 Online safety tips 
 Next More from MSN.ca 
 Check out new cars on MSN Autos Browse vacation deals View grocery flyers Get the latest NHL scores&amp;standings Get a virtual makeover! Track your investments Search for a used car Catch up with your favourite shows Get weather updates Follow us on Facebook 
 MSN Tech Site Map 
 PC World Product reviews How-to guide Buyers guide 

 Microsoft Bing Internet Explorer 8 Windows Xbox 

 Video Windows 7 Geektown Blog 
 
 Terms of use Advertise Privacy Statement Code of Conduct 

 Support Feedback RSS 
 © 2012 Microsoft
	</body>
</document>
