<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001903" url="http://ezinearticles.com/?3-Effects-of-Eating-Fast-Food&amp;id=6539401" time="2012-07-12-17:48" support="2" score="0.004063853998598308" bingtitle="3 Effects of Eating Fast Food - EzineArticles Submission - Submit ..." webtitle="3 Effects of Eating Fast Food">
			<query id="000847" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="001130" bing-rank="132"/>
	<description>... not so good with the exception of eating a salad at a fast food restaurant. ... would not enjoy having my food cooked in ... Protein to Your Muscle Building Meal Plan; Eat More ...</description>
	<body>
		Search Home » Health and Fitness » Nutrition Daylo D Swidward 
 Basic PLUS Author |   23 Articles 
 Joined: August 20, 2011 Was this article helpful? 0 0 
3 Effects of Eating Fast Food

 By Daylo D Swidward 
 
I can remember a time in my youth when I loved to eat fast foods. Never once did I consider the effects of eating fast foods. It was not so much the taste of the food as it was the convenience. I guess I&apos;m embellishing quite a bit because I loved the taste of fast food burgers! White castles, McDonald&apos;s, Burger King, Wendy&apos;s and Coney Island were some of my favorite fast food spots. As I grew older and learned the importance of nutrition, I began to eat more of my meals at home. Not only did I start preparing my own meals but I soon found that I could make better tasting food at a cheaper price.

The truth of the matter is that the effects of eating fast foods are not so good with the exception of eating a salad at a fast food restaurant. If you are old enough to think back to the early 1990&apos;s you will notice that chicken salads and fruit salads were not a part of the menu in fast food chain restaurants. The insertion of green salads and fruit cups started to become commonplace as nutritional education began to spread and consumers became more health conscious. As a consumer, you must take your health into your own hands and prepare your own meals in your home if you truly want to be healthier. Below are 3 effects of eating fast foods.

1. You have no knowledge of the ingredients . Sure those burgers and fries taste good but do you know what&apos;s inside of them? Marketing gimmicks contain words like secret sauce and special ingredients to entice the consumer to buy their product. In this case, what you don&apos;t know can kill you.

2. The cooking oils are used over and over . As someone who does not consume pork or pork byproducts, I would not enjoy having my food cooked in oil that has been previously used to cook a pork product. All health experts will tell you that cooking oil is only supposed to be used one time. If it is used more than once then you stand the chance of consuming carcinogens which are cancer causing agents.

3. It is very expensive . All products and foods have risen in price because of the current state of oil and gas prices. A quarter pound hamburger from most restaurants will cost you anywhere between two and four dollars. If you were to cook that same quarter pound hamburger at home it would cost you less than a dollar. In fact you could buy a pack of USDA choice beef for four dollars or less and make five to six hamburgers.
 
Daylo is a health researcher and author. He has spent the last 14 years traveling to over 35 countries on 5 continents and documenting simple health-enhancing principles that can be applied by anyone who desires to achieve optimal health. For more information on Daylo&apos;s findings, visit http://www.damienmcswineshealthhub.blogspot.com/ 
 
Article Source: http://EzineArticles.com/?expert=Daylo_D_Swidward 
 Did you find this article helpful? 0 0 Get Involved 0 comments Suggest a topic Article Tools Print this article E-mail to a friend EzinePublisher Report this article Cite this article Stay Informed Get notified by email when new articles are added to this category or written by this author. 
Subscribe to New Article Alerts:
 
 Health and Fitness: Nutrition 
 Daylo D Swidward 
 Email Address: Subscribe Nutrition Article Feed Find More Articles Search 
Similar Articles

 Ten Cholesterol Lowering Food Tips How to Stop Eating Fast Food The Real Way! The Hypnotic McNuggets Everyday Diet Tips Meal Ideas For Two 
 
Recent Articles

 The Stone Age Diet: Free of Gluten and Processed Foods Food Supplements - Boosting Your Nutritional Requirements Truth About Six Pack Abs Review Mother Always Knows Best Amino Acids and Proteins: What Are They? What Do They Do? Maca Side Effects How Much Calcium Should You Have Each Day? &apos;It Is What It Is&apos; Syndrome Food Dehydrators - Why Everyone Should Have One Get Your Summer Vitamin D 
 
Submitted On September 04, 2011. Viewed 71 times. Word count: 447.
 MLA Style Citation: 
Swidward, Daylo D. &quot;3 Effects of Eating Fast Food.&quot; 3 Effects of Eating Fast Food .
 4 Sep. 2011 EzineArticles.com. 12 Jul. 2012&lt; http://ezinearticles.com/?3-­Effects-­of-­Eating-­Fast-­Food&amp;id=6539401 &gt;. APA Style Citation: 
Swidward, D. D. (2011, September 4). 3 Effects of Eating Fast Food .
 Retrieved July 12, 2012, from http://ezinearticles.com/?3-­Effects-­of-­Eating-­Fast-­Food&amp;id=6539401 Chicago Style Citation: 
Swidward, Daylo D. &quot;3 Effects of Eating Fast Food.&quot; 3 Effects of Eating Fast Food EzineArticles.com . http://ezinearticles.com/?3-­Effects-­of-­Eating-­Fast-­Food&amp;id=6539401 
 EzineArticles.com 

©2012 EzineArticles.com
All Rights Reserved Worldwide
 
 About Us FAQ Contact Us Member Benefits Privacy Policy Shop Site Map 

 Blog Training Video Library Advertising Affiliates Cartoons 
 
Authors
 
 Submit Articles Members Login Premium Membership Expert Authors Endorsements Editorial Guidelines Terms of Service 
 
Publishers

Follow Us
 
 Terms Of Service Ezines / Email Alerts Manage Subscriptions EzineArticles RSS
	</body>
</document>
