<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001074" url="http://www.greenbiz.com/blog/2012/03/21/mcdonalds-launches-pilot-program-drop-polystyrene-coffee-cups" time="2012-07-12-16:29" support="7" score="0.00596897533711572" bingtitle="McDonald&apos;s launches pilot program to drop polystyrene coffee cups ..." webtitle="McDonalds launches pilot program to drop polystyrene coffee cups | GreenBiz.com">
			<query id="000152" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="001339" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="001466" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000149" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000135" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000305" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000243" bing-rank="166"/>
	<description>... paper, used in its food containers, bags, and napkins. ... Germany there hasn&apos;t been polystyrene in any fast food restaurant ... as a McDs maintenance man and the amount of trash ...</description>
	<body>
		GreenBiz.com Events GreenBiz Intelligence 
 Your inside track on sustainability: GreenBuzz Enter your keywords: 
 Login About Us 
 Browse 
 Business Operations Buildings&amp;Facilities Energy&amp;Climate Computing&amp;IT Design&amp;Packaging Marketing&amp;Communications 
 Engage News , Blogs , Careers / Jobs , Events , Newsletters , Webcasts , Videos , Hot Topics , Podcasts Research VERGE , Reports , Tools , Bookstore , Professional Services Featured Sponsor 
 
Blogs
 Tweet 
McDonald&apos;s launches pilot program to drop polystyrene coffee cups
 By Conrad MacKerron Published March 21, 2012 Email | Print | Single Page View Tags: Commitments&amp;Goals , Consumer Products , More... Commitments&amp;Goals , Consumer Products , Packaging , Restaurants 
 McDonald&apos;s has just announced a major environmental initiative: The company is launching a pilot program to phase out polystyrene beverage cups (McD&apos;s long ago gave up Styrofoam for its food packaging, but hot beverages have still been served in polystyrene).

The move comes in response to a 2011 shareholder resolution [PDF] by As You Sow , which asked the company to re-evaluate the use of foam cups. The company recently informed us it is testing replacement of polystyrene with a double-walled paper hot cup at approximately 2,000 of its restaurants in the U.S., primarily on the West Coast -- that represents nearly 15 percent its U.S. restaurants.

The shareholder proposal received the support of nearly 30 percent of total company shares voted, a high result for an environmental issue proposal, and the highest vote to date for any As You Sow proposal on recycling.

The ongoing controversy about the environmental impacts of polystyrene led McDonald&apos;s to phase out foam-based clamshell food containers amid concerns that petroleum-based food packaging that persists in the environment for hundreds of years after use.

Over the next decade, McDonald&apos;s eliminated more than 300 million pounds of packaging and reduced restaurant waste by 30 percent, saving an estimated $6 million per year. It is now one of the largest purchasers of recycled paper, used in its food containers, bags, and napkins.

Polystyrene is controversial because the International Agency for Research on Cancer has determined that styrene, used to make polystyrene, is a possible human carcinogen . In 2009, the California Office of Environmental Health Hazard Assessment proposed that styrene be listed as a known human carcinogen.

Last June, styrene was listed as a possible carcinogen by the National Institutes of Health&apos;s National Toxicology Program. Several epidemiologic studies suggest an association between occupational styrene exposure and an increased risk of leukemia and lymphoma.

Polystyrene is not widely recycled. The Environmental Protection Agency&apos;s annual report on solid waste recycling lists polystyrene cup recycling as&quot;negligible.&quot;Foam particles are among the most common items found by environmental groups leading beach cleanups. Foam cups and containers break into small pieces that are easily blown in all directions by the wind.

Carried through storm drains to the ocean, foam containers break down into small indigestible pellets which animals perceive as food, resulting in the death of birds and fish. Due to such concerns, more than 50 cities in California and 100 cities in the U.S. have banned or restricted the use of polystyrene food packaging.

The objective of the McDonald&apos;s pilot is to assess customer acceptance, operational impact, and overall performance of the paper cups. The hope is that the company will make the switch to paper cups permanent and expand it to all of its restaurants. Also, given its history of using high levels of recycled content in other food packaging, we hope that it begins to use recycled content in the paper cups and establishes a robust recycling program for both post-consumer waste left in its restaurants.
 
 1 2 next › last » 
 Tweet Conrad MacKerron is Director of the Corporate Social Responsibility Program at As You Sow Foundation , which uses dialogue and shareholder advocacy to promote better social and environmental policies at publicly traded companies.
Read more from Conrad MacKerron 
 «Prev Post Why We&apos;re Pushing P&amp;G and General Mills to Cut Packaging Waste All Posts Next Post» Innovating a sea change in reducing plastic waste Related News&amp;Blogs How Apple&apos;s withdrawal from green registry affects purchasers College campuses&apos;climate lessons for companies Staples&apos;journey to sustainability Lessons from Ecologic Brands: How to make sustainability sexy 
Comments (10)
 
 The concern for our 
 Anonymous (not verified), April 19, 2012 - 08:05 
The concern for our environment here is nice to see. However, there is a lot more to this than polystyrene not being able to biodegrade. The manufacturing of paper is much more damaging to our environment then polystyrene is by a considerable amount. Both wax coated paper and polystyrene are difficult to recycle, however in my medium size town there are 10 places that you can drop off polystyrene for reuse in packaging. I realize that most people will just end up dumping this in the garbage. Modern landfills are designed not to let things biodegrade (so paper will always be paper in a landfill). This is a good thing, and is done so that the paper does not release methane gas, which is damaging to our ozone. In my city our garbage is incinerated. The polystyrene releases considerable more energy than paper, which we transform into heat and power.

I love my earth. Let’s be smart and save it!
 
 Those cups aren&apos;t recyclable 
 Anonymous (not verified), March 27, 2012 - 22:49 
Those cups aren&apos;t recyclable either. More disposable plastic coated cups in the litter stream. We don&apos;t need any more.
Offer reusable cups and cutlery, plates etc. Offer incentives to customers bringing their own cups.
Educate your customers about waste. Have competitions that generate interest and action about waste.
The size of your responsibility should match your profits and wealth of real estate. There are few coorporates better placed to meaningfully tackle this world&apos;s excessive waste and disposable culture.
 
 Glad to hear McDonalds will 
 Brenda (not verified), March 27, 2012 - 14:05 
Glad to hear McDonalds will be exploring alternatives to polystyrene. One clarification: Last June, styrene was listed as reasonably anticipated to be a human carcinogen by the National Institutes of Health&apos;s National Toxicology Program. It was previously listed as a suspected human carcinogen.
Polystyrene should be banned from use as food service ware. Kudos to Seattle for leading the way.
I work with a Young Activist Club in MD trying to get rid of disposable styrofoam lunch trays. They want a dishwasher for their school and have raised thousands of dollars for it. Unfortunately school administrators won&apos;t let the pilot go through. Nice to see corporations taking steps when our public sector won&apos;t.
 
 Challenging Starbucks? Yes, 
 Anonymous (not verified), March 26, 2012 - 07:32 
Challenging Starbucks? Yes, when the initial coffee quality push happened, McD made a good cup of coffee. For about a year. Since then, the locations around here have backslid and produce pretty poor coffee.
 
 The replacement may not be 
 Anonymous (not verified), March 22, 2012 - 05:51 
The replacement may not be better, and may be worse. Things have to be added to paper for a hot beverage cup, such as wax and thin plastic coatings. These make the paper not practical to recycle. And cutting more trees can cause more harm than alternatives. We have very little true sustainable forestry.
 
 I agree with Andre, this 
 Rick Swartz (not verified), March 21, 2012 - 20:38 
I agree with Andre, this seems to be an entirely US problem. In Germany there hasn&apos;t been polystyrene in any fast food restaurant for years. Why you would need a pilot program to test this is beyond me. Just switch. You&apos;re already making the paper packaging for your international operations anyway.
 
 It is no technical problem. 
 Andre (not verified), March 21, 2012 - 11:08 
It is no technical problem. Is this an US issue? If you go to Europe, especially to Germany or Switzerland, there are no polystyrene cups at all, nowhere. You just don&apos;t have them - it&apos;s all paper cups. Yes, even at Starbucks and McDonald&apos;s. So it seems to me more like a consumer acceptance issue, not a technical or financial problem. OR a consumer pressure issue.
 
 .... and the mega-corp 
 Nikki Florio (not verified), March 21, 2012 - 09:46 
.... and the mega-corp greenwash continues.
 
 Good move. I remember back in 
 Mike Nemeth (not verified), March 21, 2012 - 08:31 
Good move. I remember back in the early 80s working as a McDs maintenance man and the amount of trash our one restaurant created. Just the volume of foam containers back then was fantastic. This subsequent step should be followed by others.
 
 A move that is long overdue. 
 Anonymous (not verified), March 21, 2012 - 06:51 
A move that is long overdue. These petroleum based polymer plastic paper wrapped polystyrene cups are not recyclable and are a scourge on the earth. Ozone-depleting CFCs are used as physical blowing agents during the manufacturing process while VOCs are also released. And we eat and drink from this stuff.
 Sponsored Links Related Content 
 What&apos;s keeping electric vehicles from the mainstream? Electric vehicles are gaining popularity in fleets, car-sharing services and consumers, but remain far from mainstream. What&apos;s missing? Infrastructure, public awareness and better -- and cheaper -- batteries. 3 firms win contest to help Kaiser design greener hospital Aditazz, Mazzetti Nash Lipsey Burch and Perkins+Will win Kaiser&apos;s&quot;Small Hospital, Big Idea&quot;design contest for concepts to build an innovative, net-zero energy hospital.  ... What to do when you&apos;ve picked all the low-hanging fruit With just eight years remaining for Interface to reach its target of zero environmental footprint by 2020, it&apos;s clear that there&apos;s no more low-hanging fruit. How does a company adapt to a&quot;tall canopy&quot;landscape? How to turn shuttered suburban stores into sustainability showcases With all the talk about sustainable cities, it&apos;s important to remember that the concept can apply to suburbs as well as metro centers. Kaid Benfield explores a vision of green suburbia from two designers.  ... Making cities sustainability centerpieces Here&apos;s what businesses need to know to leverage technology to help cities overcome some of their biggest problems, including traffic, water treatment and infrastructure upgrades. What Apple could learn from Amazon While Apple&apos;s planned headquarters in Cupertino, Calif., choked off streets and reduced walkability, Amazon&apos;s new headquarters keep streets connected and uses public transportation. Why the world needs a better way to measure cities&apos;emissions There&apos;s a mountain of research that indicates cities are the prime laboratories to create real solutions to climate change. And the recent launch of new guidelines for cities means that they can start taking action today. ... 5 ways to boost employee engagement How can you get more employees engaged in sustainability and other goals? Here are four strategies, including a bigger commitment to social responsibility. 
 
 GreenBiz Events 
 Loading... Catch all of our upcoming events, including VERGE SF @ Greenbuild , GreenBiz webcasts , as well as our upcoming Cities 2.0 virtual event. Advertisement &gt;See All Featured Resources 
 How technology enables the shared economy Zipcar&apos;s co-founder and former CEO discusses how sharing taps into excess capacity in... ... 5 Management Principles to Modernize Cars, Buildings&amp;the Grid Insights from the world&apos;s biggest companies on how to capitalize on the connected... ... Building the motorcycle of the future An Internet-enabled vehicle that combines the efficiency and freedom of a motorcycle with... ... Accelerating green building market transformation The role of information as a tool for market transformation in the buildings sector, how... ... 
 What&apos;s New on GreenBiz TV 
Redscout Ventures&apos; Roo Rogers&apos; One Great Idea: Transforming consumption . See our entire video collection 
 Sustainability Consultants Directory 
Find great consultants specializing in sustainability. GreenBiz.com&apos;s Sustainability Consultants Directory lists great resources in sustainability strategies, energy efficiency, marketing, supply chain, recruiting and HR, and many more.
 State of Green Business 2012 
The fifth annual edition of our State of Green Business report continues our efforts to measure the environmental impacts of the emerging green economy. In addition to documenting what progress companies are making -- if any -- in improving their environmental performance, we track larger trends that will affect corporate America in 2012.


 Read the stories and download the report . 
 
 Catch all the coverage of the 2012 GreenBiz Forums . 
 Green&amp;Sustainability Job Board 
Find the green job that&apos;s right for you. GreenBiz.com&apos;s green&amp;sustainability job board has jobs in energy efficiency, protecting ecosystems, research and development, green building, administrative, and more. Employers can post jobs and internships for free. »Find jobs 
 Autodesk: Sponsored Content ADEPT Airmotive 
ADEPT Airmotive used Autodesk® Inventor® to develop a lighter, more fuel-efficient general aviation engine. Click here to learn more. Site Sponsors Advertisement Sponsored Links ©2011 GreenBiz Group - GreenBiz.com®is a registered trademark of GreenBiz Group Inc. About Us | Browse | Engage | Research | Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
