<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001270" url="http://www.slideshare.net/Foboni/cda-esm-waste-oil-disposal-applications" time="2012-07-12-16:43" support="7" score="0.016749619176221506" bingtitle="Cda Esm Waste Oil Disposal Applications - Upload &amp; Share ..." webtitle="Cda Esm Waste Oil Disposal Applications">
			<query id="001500" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="001261" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="001278" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="000903" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="001469" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="001284" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000966" bing-rank="50"/>
	<description>In order to show how Comparative Decision ... for example an ”average sized” fast food restaurant, ... 41-79-621’8795 How to get the most out of (Vegetable) Waste Oil for ...</description>
	<body>
		SlideShare 
 Upload Browse   
 Popular Downloaded Favorited Channels Videos Zipcasts 
 
 
 Go Pro Login Signup 
 
 Email Favorite Favorited × Download Embed   Flag Private Content Copy and paste this code into your blog or website Copy Customize… Without related content Start from slide number 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 Size (px) 460×349 Shortcode for WordPress.com blogs ? Copy Old embed code ? Copy Close Flagged as inappropriate Flag as inappropriate Flag as inappropriate 
Select your reason for flagging this presentation as inappropriate. If needed, use the feedback form to let us know more details.
 None Pornographic Defamatory Illegal/Unlawful Spam Other Terms Of Service Violation Cancel File a copyright complaint 
We have emailed the verification/download link to &quot; &quot; .
Login to your email and click the link to download the file directly.
 To request the link at a different email address, update it here. Close 
 Validation messages. Success message. Fail message. 
 Check your bulk/spam folders if you can&apos;t find our mail. 
 
 
 Related More 

 

 Heating with Waste Vegetable Oil or Biod… Biodiesel Production from Waste Vegetabl… Biodiesel: Do-it-yourself Production Bas… Fleet manager biodiesel_guide Fleet manager biodiesel_guide Use of biodiesel in transit Use of biodiesel in transit Use of biodiesel in transit Converting A Home Heating Oil Furnace To… Biodiesel 101 Biofuel Biofuels: A Guide for Coordinating a Fry… Biodiesel 2 Dual fuel Waste Vegetable Oil Burner Bro… Nfpa 85 Stop Global Warming Run Your Car on Wast… Cda esm waste oil disposal application p… Comparing Alternatives Using CDA-ESM Cda Esm Comparative Decision Analysis… Cda Esm Comparative Decision Analysis… 

 Optimum Risk Estimates are the solution Systemic organizational constellations a… Bogota 02 10-011 Risk Management Mining… Balangero asbestos mine dumps restoratio… Oboni Riskope Conference on Risk Based D… Review ICS Guidelines Cassass presentation WLF2 Rome Road Safety- Sicurezza Stradale Tolerability today vs Whitman Tolerability and Decision Making Discuss… Rims Metal and Mining Session talk by F+… Rims Metals and Mining Session Generalized tolerability and risk based… Terapia2 City Thermal Center Franchisin… Force Majeure: a Time Bomb Oboni02 castellano Oboni01 castellano Cda esm waste oil disposal application p… Force Majeure Clause in Contracts Terapia2 City Thermal Center Franchisin… 
 Remove Related 
 Tweet 
 + Follow 
Cda Esm Waste Oil Disposal Applications

by Oboni Riskope Associates Inc. on Dec 05, 2009 
 
 1,193 views 

Reportedly, some fast food chains started (2007) to use their waste cooking oil to make bio-diesel. In one example encompassing 1200 restaurants, the entire corporate truck fleet of 155 vehicles was
	</body>
</document>
