<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001151" url="http://www.insidestl.com/insideSTLcom/STLSports/STLCardinals/tabid/91/articleType/ArticleView/articleId/1507/Busch-Stadium-Food-Review.aspx" time="2012-07-12-16:35" support="5" score="0.003421110794043518" bingtitle="Busch Stadium Food Review &gt; insideSTL.com &gt; STL Cardinals" webtitle="Busch Stadium Food Review &gt; insideSTL.com &gt; STL Cardinals">
			<query id="000078" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000087" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="001520" bing-rank="210"/>
			<query id="000091" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="000766" bing-rank="175"/>
	<description>+ Fountain Soda: The fact that that this cracks the ... in some stands, but in other pricier seats the ‘Za ... + Hardees’s: A huge fast food restaurant featuring gigantic thick ...</description>
	<body>
		home | contact us 
 insideSTL.com 
 Home 
 McKernan 
 The Archives - From The Desk Of Tim McKernan 
 KMFP 
 STL Nightlife 
 Gallery 
 Gallery 
 Picture Gallery 
 Directory 
 The Side Bar 
 Hair of the Dog 
 The EDGE 
 NL_Admin 
 STL Sports 
 Daily Redbird 
 STL Blues 
 STL Cardinals 
 The Archives - STL Cardinals 
 STL Rams 
 The Archives - STL Rams 
 STL Sports Blog 
 The Archives - STL Sports 
 STL Soccer 
 STL Golf 
 Puffers and Duffers Golf League at Quail Creek 
 Missouri Tigers 
 Mizzou Photo Gallery 
 Daily Redbird 
 STL Golf 
 The Archives - STL Golf 
 Golf Tournament Calendar 
 Wrestling&amp;MMA 
 Billiken TV 
 STL Poker 
 The Archives - STL Poker 
 Fantasy Focus 
 STL Soccer 
 insideSTL Newsroom 
 Community 
 Mardi Gras 2012 
 STL Music 
 STL Music Archive 
 The Archives - STL Music Headlines 
 Music Calendar 
 Venue Calendar - The Pageant 
 STL Movies 
 STL Ladies 
 The Archives - STL Ladies 
 Dad Life STL 
 STL Finance 
 The Man Hole 
 Sex&amp;Women 
 Health&amp;Fitness 
 Man Holes 
 STL Politics 
 The Archives - Politics 
 STL Videos 
 Video Channel 
 Youtube Channel 
 Video Admin 
 VIDEO TEST 
 Videos Test 
 VIDEOS 
 VIDEO CONFIG 
 ADD NEW VIDEO 
 Video Channel 
 STL Weather 
 Contests 
 Bar Olympics 
 Events Calendar 
 Links of the Day 
 The Ticket Center 
 STL Events Calendar 
 Announcements 
 Live Blog 
 Radio Shows 
 Spring Training Pics 
 ITD Morning After 
 Morning After Photo Gallery 
 TMA @ Spring Training 
 Video Webcast 
 The 1-3 Show 
 One To Three Show Remote Calendar 
 One To Three Show Remote Calendar 
 One To Three Show Remote Calendar 
 Thom&amp;Jeff 
 Buck&amp;McKernan 
 Late Night Score 
 Nick and the Badger 
 The Hockey Guys 
 Sapaugh Baseball Show 
 Late Night Score 
 IBON in the AM 
 Iggy&apos;s STTW 
 Keggler&apos;s Corner 
 Podcasts 
 Girl Next Door 
 GND Submission 
 Bios 
 GNDOTY Voting 
 GNDOTY VOTING 
 GNDOTY VOTE 
 GND Voting 
 Current GND 
 Archive 2011 
 Archive 2012 
 Archive 2011 
 Archive 2010 
 Archive 2009 
 Archive 2008 
 Archive 2007 
 Past Winners 
 2009 GND Winners 
 GND Submission 
 GND Archive 
 2008 GND Winners 
 2007 GND Winners 
 ALBUMS 
 About Us 
 About Us 
 Our Staff 
 Advertise 
 Site Map 
 Our Friends 
 Contact Us 
 ADMIN HOST 
 Banner Ad Manager 
 TABS 
 Latest Articles 
 USER REPORT 
 TESTERR 
 test of comment removal 
 MSG Board 
 Log In 
 Registration 
 Search Results 
 Message Board 
 FAQ 
 Forum 
 Today&apos;s Links 
 Daily Redbird 
 Headlines 
 Girl Next Door1 
 Our Sections 
 The Complete Archive - The Morning After 
 Template Page 2 
 Email a Friend 
 Our Content 
 Image Gallery Parameters 
 Today-Links 
 Users Report 
 Site Track Server 
 Site Track Control Panel 
 STL NIGHTLIFE 
 STL Store 
 Administration 
 Submit Things 
 My Template Page 
 Contest Page 
 Where To Drink 
 KSHE 95 / Hooters Pigskin Challenge 
 Hooters Hot 64 
 Exit Poll 
 Where To Eat 
 Emerald Greens 
 Suntrup 
 Poker Calendar 
 Volleyball Registration 
 test 
 New Nightlife 
 New Nightlife Admin 
 New Tabs Test 
 Menu Test 
 Login Page 
 Privacy Policy 
 Terms of Use 
 Banner Ad Display Test 
 WIN Tickets to 311&amp;Slightly Stoopid 
 Previous Winners 2010 
 Admin 
 Site Settings 
 Pages 
 Security Roles 
 User Accounts 
 Vendors 
 Site Log 
 Newsletters 
 File Manager 
 Recycle Bin 
 Event Viewer 
 Skins 
 Languages 
 Site Wizard 
 Authentication 
 Solutions Explorer 
 Page Urls 
 Host 
 Host Settings 
 Portals 
 Module Definitions 
 File Manager 
 Vendors 
 SQL 
 Schedule 
 Languages 
 Search Admin 
 Lists 
 Host Accounts 
 Skins 
 What&apos;s New 
 Dashboard 
 Friendly Url Settings 
 
 Remember me     Register 
     Forgot Password?       
 
   
 JAdams: Cardinals Midterm Grades 
By J. Adams :: July 09, 2012 Relieve Two Birds With One Greinke 
By Andy Portico :: July 06, 2012 Hate to Say I Told You So… 
By Chris Russell :: July 05, 2012 The Tony La Russa All Star Conspiracy 
By Chris Reed :: July 02, 2012 7th-Inning Stench 
By KMFP :: June 29, 2012 The Quest For Momentum 
By Chris Reed :: June 25, 2012 Closing Arguments 
By Chris Russell :: June 20, 2012 The Complete Archive 
     
   Current Articles | Archives | Search 24 
 Busch Stadium Food Review 
 AT Hooks posted on November 24, 2008 11:30 
 The kind folks over @ Hugging Harold Reynolds told me about their newest project- a guide to stadium food- and asked if I would write the Busch Stadium food review for Fan Foodie . I sent them this crap…


St. Louisan’s like their food like they like their women- fat and sloppy. Hence this nugget from SportsService, the official food and beverage vendor of Busch Stadium III, shouldn’t surprise you:“Cardinals fans in 2008 consumed more nacho cheese than in any other Major League Baseball stadium.”


During the course of my e-mail exchange with SS’s director of Standing Partnership, the wonderful Kristin Gumper, I wondered how Cardinals fans could consume more cheese than any other baseball venue, yet lag into the double digits when it comes to tortilla chips.“St. Louis fans put cheese on everything.”says SportsService,“We sell almost as much cheese on the side in cups as we dispense on nacho chips.”


 Makes sense. Cheesy pretzels. Cheesy hot dogs. Hell, I’m pretty sure I’ve seen some guy put cheese on his cheese. It’s not the quality; stupid…it’s the quantity. And when you come to St. Louis in the summer to watch Cardinals baseball, well, you’re going to get a lot of something (beer, food, VD’s). Don’t like it? You can take your fancy pants to San Francisco.


Recently the pride and joy of being a St. Louis resident was ripped by those evil child molesting (probably) Belgians. Anheuser-Bush was bought by InBev and one of America’s last, great independent companies became just another huge conglomerate more worried about the stock ticker than the taste buds of people drinking their beer. (Although, some may ask what the difference between Bud Light and tap water actually is.) Jingoism aside, beer consumption- and more specifically Bud, Bud Light, Bud Select, Michelob, Mich Light and the Michelob family of beers is the main course, the meal, if you will when you’re in and around Busch Stadium. Not A meal. Not part of the meal…THE meal.


Alyssa Horace, 23, of Clayton MO explains:“I think most girls over the age of twenty one and under the age of 30 prefer to drink their meals.... Mmmmmm.... Bud Light.... so yummy. Wieners usually follow... I&apos;m talking about the kind that come in a bun.... and no not the kind you&apos;re probably thinking. Get your head out of the gutter!”


If you served the food SportsService does to Cardinals fans in a restaurant, you’d be shot. But since you’re pretty sloppy drunk people have a pretty favorable view of the fare. Seeing as this is a website dedicated solely to the food, this particular column may seem unnecessarily harsh. Just remember that we, and probably you, would like the food roughly 7 to 10 times better after 6 massive 32 oz. Bud Diesels.


To make it as easy as possible, let’s break this down into 3 categories: The Good, The Bad and The Ugly. Cool? I’ve even tossed the food query out to several Cardinal fans that attend games regularly for their input. Some of their quotes are below…


 THE GOOD 

+ Beer. If you aren’t drinking, you aren’t trying.
 
+ Bratzel. NY Times approved! 

+“I personally am a big fan of&quot;the dessert cart&quot;. If you are lucky enough to visit the&quot;exclusive suites&quot;there is a dessert cart that comes around during the latter half of the game. It is heaven on wheels! A true vehicle of pleasure at your suite doorstep! It boasts trays of cakes, cookies, bars and more. Some of its specialties include Crème Brule Cheesecake, 6-Layer red velvet Cardinals Cake, chocolate and white chocolate brownies, fruit cups, ice cream bowls, 5-layer carrot cake, Death-by-Chocolate Cake, cookies as big as your head, chocolate mousse, and on and on. That is the sweet to usually a bitter defeat you are watching on the field! Well and that and beers large enough to sit in = heaven!”Kerin Abbey, 29, O’Fallon MO

+ Nachos: Like we mentioned before, not good on the surface, but a Cardinal tradition.“I don’t like these nachos at all. They are soggy, the cheese is bland and the jalapenos give me explosive bowel movements. In short, they are my favorite Busch Stadium food.”Ryan Riggle, 32, Fenton MO

+ Fountain Soda: The fact that that this cracks the‘Good’list should speak volumes. That being said, this soda takes like liquid cocaine. Or so I assume. Sniff.


 THE BAD 

+ Asian Action Cart: Overcoming a terrible name is one thing, but trying to convince drunken hoosiers that al la cart stir-fry is a good idea in 98 degrees and 120% humidity is a different beast. The food isn’t in and of itself terrible, but the placement is a little bit like a having a porno on at a prison-not smart thinking.

+ Fry Action Stand: Create your own fries. #1 topping? You guessed it- cheese! A promising addition to the roster in 2008 couldn’t quite make it to the good list since the namesake of the stand were limper than Hugh Jackman at the Bunny Ranch.
 
+ Hot Dogs/Brats: Much better in the New Busch Stadium than the old one. Kosher dogs are available and all are grilled on actual grills now with onions and kraut options that are free. I think they actually chopped Larry Bigbe up and made sausages out of him now that I think about it.

+“I&apos;m far more concerned with the BBQ outside of the strip clubs- I end up in Sauget after most games. That being said, it&apos;s the best BBQ in the country.”Chris Jenkins, 28, San Diego CA.

+ Pizza: Papa John’s has it’s integration in some stands, but in other pricier seats the‘Za is made by hand. Bread, tomato paste and cheese is pretty hard to F up. Luckily Busch Stadium doesn’t too bad. It’s pretty doughy for a city that is famous for thin crust pies.

+ Hardees’s: A huge fast food restaurant featuring gigantic thick burgers and 800 calorie diet busting meal deals? Fits in much more conspicuously than you’d imagine.

+ Funnel Cakes: And as a special bonus the stand only hires reformed sex offenders!

 
THE UGLY 

+ Toasted Ravioli: A STL tradition gone horribly, horribly wrong. I’m pretty sure they’re using cat meat. Stray cat meat.

+ Popcorn: A double whammy of tasting like its 3 days old and having enough salt to give deer heart attacks.

+“Don’t get the chicken breast. Please.”Gina Alles, 29, St. Louis MO.

 + Philly Cheese Steaks: Have you ever tasted death in between two buns? Do you want to?

+ Fried Cannelloni: With a name like SportsService, how could you not make fried cannelloni to die for? Also, people reading this that have actually been to Busch Stadium will be shocked this is on the menu. I’m sure of that.

+ Hot Chocolate: Most certainly the vilest thing to ever cross your mouth in public. Unless you’ve happened to have given head to Rosie O’Donnell. Hi-yo!~


***As a special bonus and just because we care…SportsService has revealed exclusively to Fan Foodie and InsideSTL the new menu items coming to Busch Stadium in 2009 (all tentative and subject to change…)

+ Chialquillas (pronounced chill - a - key - es) A traditional Mexican corn tortilla casserole (nacho casserole): corn tortillas tossed w/ chorizo sausage, corn, black beans and a spicy chile-tomato sauce. This may be an action station as well as an item sold in the El Birdos concession stands.

+ BBQ Pork Potato Skins

+ Smoked Beef Brisket Enchiladas w/ caramelized onions and white cheddar.

+ Lobster-Potato Crepes w/ Sherried Corn Cream

That’s it. That’s the food review for Busch Stadium in downtown St Louis MO, home of the 2009 All-Star Game. Happy eating.

Aaron Hooks every Monday for InsideSTL and regularly for www.CardsDiaspora.com 
 SHARE: E-mail | Permalink | Comments (0) | | Tweet | | 
 
 There are currently no comments, be the first to post one. 
 Post Comment 
 Only registered users may post comments.    
 
   McKernan 
 ITD Morning After 
 Thom&amp;Jeff 
 Podcasts 
 STL Nightlife Gallery 
 KMFP 
 Iggy&apos;s STTW 
 Video Channel 
 Cardinals 
 Blues 
 Mizzou 
 Rams 
 Sports Blog 
 STL Soccer 
 Wrestling&amp;MMA 
 Message Board 

 Our Staff 
 Our Friends 
 Links of the Day 
 Events Calendar 
 STL Movies 
 STL Music 
 The Man Hole 
 STL Ladies Home 
 Terms of Use 
 Privacy Policy 
 Register Now 
 Site Map 
 Contact Us 
 Advertise With Us 
 
 
Follow insideSTL on:
      
RSS:
 

 

 Copyright © 2012 insideSTL.com
All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
