<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001893" url="http://www.cleaningproductsworld.com/plastic-food-storage-bags.html" time="2012-07-12-17:48" support="5" score="0.009317189087474555" bingtitle="Plastic Food Storage Bags - Cleaning Products and Janitorial ..." webtitle="Plastic Food Storage Bags">
			<query id="000156" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000917" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="000343" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000935" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000918" bing-rank="28"/>
	<description>... bags feature compact &quot;size on size&quot; packaging to help save you your valuable counter ... Napkin &amp; Tampon Vending Dispensers; Toilet Seat Covers; Sanitary Napkin Disposal Cans</description>
	<body>
		Home | About Us | Shipping Information | Privacy Policy | FAQ | Blog | Contact Us Free Shipping on Orders over $50! Call us Toll Free: 1-877-403-6537 
 Refer A Friend Bathroom 
 Toilet Paper&amp;Facial Tissue Bathroom Cleaners Toilet Bowl Cleaners Bath&amp;Bar Hand Soaps Hand Sanitizer Air Freshener Spray 
 Kitchen 
 All Purpose Cleaners Household Paper Towels Machine Dishwashing Detergents Hand Dishwashing Soaps Latex Rubber Gloves Sponges&amp;Scouring Pads 
 Eco-Friendly 
 Marcal Pro Clorox Green Works Seventh Generation Nature&apos;s Source Arm&amp;Hammer Essentials Eco-Friendly Simple Green Home Products Janitorial Products Eco Friendly Soap Recycled Paper Products 
 Brands 
 Soft Scrub Clorox Windex Lysol Simple Green Cascade GOJO Charmin Kleenex Tissues Glad Boraxo Hand Soap Ajax Comet Mr. Clean Fabuloso Febreze 
 Expert Advice 
 Home &gt; Restaurant&amp;Foodservice Supply &gt; Plastic Food Storage Bags Home &gt; Food Service Supplies &gt; Plastic Food Storage Bags 
Plastic Food Storage Bags
 FREE Shipping and 2 Day Delivery Available! Buy your plastic food storage bags today and have them shipped to you tomorrow! These plastic food bags feature compact &quot;size on size&quot; packaging to help save you your valuable counter and freezer space. They are designed for quick dispensing and easy access, freeing up valuable prep time as well. Available in Food&amp;Utility Bags, Bread&amp;Bakery Bags, and Bun Rack&amp;Pan Covers. Also, try Ziploc&apos;s Resealable Commercial bags for the reliability of Ziploc we love with restaurant quality plastic food bags. Buy today and have these at your restaurant in just 2-3 days!
 
 You must enable Javascript to see the advanced sorting and paging features of this store. 
 

 
 Poly Bag For A Large Bun Rack&amp;Pan Cover 15 microns 52x80&quot; 
 Poly Bags For Food&amp;Utility 1.00 mil 22 Quart 10x8x24&quot; 
 Poly Bags For Food&amp;Utility 1.00 mil 24 Quart 12x8x30&quot; 
 Poly Bags For Food&amp;Utility 1.00 mil 3.5 Quart 6x3x15&quot; 
 Poly Bags For Food&amp;Utility 1.00 mil 8 Quart 8x4x18&quot; 
 Poly Bags For Food&amp;Utility 1.20 mil 22 Quart 10x8x24&quot; 
 Poly Bags For Food&amp;Utility 1.20 mil 8 Quart 8x4x18&quot; 
 Poly Bags For Food&amp;Utility .68 mil 18 Quart 10x4x20&quot; 
 Poly Bags For Food&amp;Utility .68 mil 2 Quart 6x3x12&quot; 
 Poly Bags For Food&amp;Utility .68 mil 3.5 Quart 6x3x15&quot; 
 Poly Bags For Food&amp;Utility .68 mil 4.5 Quart 8x3x15&quot; 
 Poly Bags For Food&amp;Utility .68 mil 8 Quart 8x4x18&quot; 
 Poly Bags For Food&amp;Utility .68 mil Pint 4x2x8&quot; 
 Poly Bags For Food&amp;Utility .68 mil Quart 4x2x12&quot; 
 Poly Bags For Food&amp;Utility .85 mil 22 Quart 10x8x24&quot; 
 Poly Bags For Food&amp;Utility .85 mil 8 Quart 8x4x18&quot; 
 Ziploc Resealable Poly Storage Bag, Sandwich Size, 1.2 mil, 6.5 x 6 in 
 Ziploc Resealable Poly Storage Bag, Double Zipper, 1.7 mil, Quart 
 Ziploc Resealable Poly Storage Bag, Double Zipper, 1.7 mil, 1 Gallon 
 Ziploc Resealable Poly Bag Storage 1.7 mil 2 Gallon 
 Ziploc Resealable Poly Freezer Storage Bag, Double Zipper, 2.7 mil, 1 Gallon 
 Ziploc Resealable Poly Bag Storage 2.7 mil 2 Gallon 
 
 

 
 
 Summer Special! 
 *FREE SHIPPING* for all orders $50 or more! 
 
 We carry the top Cleaning Products and Janitorial Supplies 


 CleaningProductsWorld.com carries over 4,000 cleaning and janitorial products, so you can get all the supplies you need, in one convenient place, without ever having to leave your home or office. We ship next day from 31 strategically located warehouses across the US so you can get your order fast in 2-3 business days. Having been in the industry for over 60 years, we know our cleaning products and janitorial supplies and guarantee their quality.

 If you ever have any questions, comments, or requests, please feel free to contact me directly. I love hearing from our customers and assisting you in any way possible.

Sincerely,
Kenn 
President

CleaningProductsWorld.com 
 
 Cleaning Products 
 Cleaning Wipes All Purpose Cleaners Heavy Duty All Purpose Cleaners Creme Cleaners Powdered Cleaners Bathroom Cleaners Dish&amp;Glassware Detergents Auto Care Armor All Degreaser Cleaners Drain Openers Solvent Spray Cleaners Glass Cleaners Furniture Polishes Stainless Steel Polish Toilet Bowl Cleaners Laundry Detergents Oven&amp;Grill Cleaners Graffiti, Gum&amp;Specialty Cleaners 
 Air Fresheners&amp;Refills 
 Air Freshener Spray Yankee Candle Metered Dispensers&amp;Refills Bolt Metered Dispensers&amp;Refills TimeMist Standard Metered Dispensers&amp;Refills TimeMist Metered Air Sanitizers Air Wick Freshmatic Metered Dispensers&amp;Refills TimeMist Micro Metered Dispensers&amp;Refills Gels&amp;Fan Dispensers TimeMist 9000 Metered Dispensers&amp;Refills Misty Metered Dispensers&amp;Refills Solid Air Fresheners&amp;Plug-Ins TimeMist Plus Metered Dispensers SeBreeze Metered Dispensers&amp;Refills SeBreeze Fan Dispensers&amp;Gels 
 Disinfectant Deodorant Cleaners 
 Disinfectant Spray Deodorant Clay&amp;Powder Liquid Deodorizer Disinfectant Cleaner Cleaning Wipes 
 Commercial Bathroom Supplies 
 Baby Changing Tables Sanitary Napkins&amp;Tampons Toilet Bowl Plunger Bathroom Electric Hand Dryers Napkin&amp;Tampon Vending Dispensers Toilet Seat Covers Sanitary Napkin Disposal Cans Hotel Bathroom Supplies Bathroom Floor Mats Urinal Blocks and Urinal Screens Toilet Bowl Brushes 
 Janitorial Cleaning Equipment 
 Vacuums Sponges&amp;Utility Cleaning Pads Tank&amp;Hand Sprayers Utility Carts Unger Window&amp;Cleaning Items Trigger Spray Bottles Housekeeping Janitorial Carts Drum Pumps&amp;Water Hook Ups Air Moving Floor Fans Overhead Dusting Products Floor&amp;Window Scrapers 
 Carpet&amp;Fabric Cleaners 
 Odor Care for Carpets&amp;Fabrics Carpet Cleaners Carpet Magnets Stain Remover for Carpets&amp;Fabrics Carpet Cleaning Machines Carpet Yarn Bonnet Machine Pads Stain Protection for Carpets&amp;Fabrics 
 Floor Cleaning Supplies 
 Floor Cleaning Chemicals Rotary Machine Floor Pads Floor Dusting Products Floor Finishing Chemicals Rotary Floor Machines Floor Squeegees Floor Mops Floor Safety Signs Floor Sponge Mops Microfiber Mops&amp;Floor Pads Cleaning Brushes Floor&amp;Window Scrapers Floor Mop Handles Floor Mop Buckets, Wringers&amp;Pails Floor Brooms 
 Trash Bags&amp;Waste Can Liners 
 Repro Recycled Trash Bags High Density Trash Bags&amp;Can Liners Low Density Trash Bags&amp;Can Liners Super Heavy Grey Trash Bags Glad Drawstring Trash Bags White Trash Can Liner Bags Medical Infectious Waste Can Liners 
 Hand Soaps 
 Safeguard Foam Soap Dispenser&amp;Refills GOJO Hand Soap Systems Provon Hand Soap Systems Heavy Duty Soaps&amp;Dispensers Dial Hand Soap Systems Micrell Antibacterial Soap System Boraxo Powdered Hand Soap Kimcare Hand Soap Systems Liquid Lotion Soap Flat Top Gallon Liquid&amp;Foam Hand Soaps - Bulk Softsoap Liquid Hand Soap System Hand Soap Wipes Hand Soap Pump Bottles Bath&amp;Bar Hand Soaps Touch-Free Hand Soap Dispenser System 
 Hand Sanitizing 
 Hand Sanitizing Wipes Hand Sanitizer Hand Sanitizing Spray Purell Bag-in-Box Hand Sanitizing System 800 ml Purell NXT Hand Sanitizing System 1000 ml Purell TFX Touch Free Hand Sanitizing System 1200 ml Purell Hand Sanitizing System 250 ml Purell FMX 12 Foam Hand Sanitizing System 1200-ml 
 Paper Towels 
 Household Paper Towels Windshield Towels Scott Slimroll Paper Towel System Industrial Roll Paper Towels Industrial Roll Towel Dispensers Centerpull Paper Towels Centerpull Paper Towel Dispensers Singlefold Paper Towels Slimfold Paper Towels Scottfold Paper Towels C-Fold&amp;Multi-Fold Paper Towel Dispensers Multifold Paper Towels C-Fold Paper Towels 
 Toilet Paper&amp;Facial Tissue 
 Facial Tissue Household Toilet Paper Industrial Toilet Paper Dispensers Jumbo Coreless Toilet Paper Jumbo Toilet Paper Super Jumbo Toilet Paper Coreless Toilet Paper Interfold Sheet Toilet Paper 
 Wipers, Rags&amp;Wipes 
 Light Duty Wipers Cloth Rags Foodservice Wipers Medium Duty Wipers Dust Cloth Wipers Lens&amp;Low Lint Critical Wipers Heavy Duty Wipers Wiper Roll Dispenser Microfiber Cleaning Cloths Premoistened Wipes Personal Bath Paper Towel Personal Wet Wipes, Adult and Baby 
 Floor Mats 
 3M Entrance Floor Mats Indoor Wiper Floor Mats Anti-Fatigue Cushion Floor Mats 3M Vinyl Loop Floor Mats Indoor Floor Runner Mat Adhesive&amp;Anti Static Floor Mats 3M Scraper Floor Mats Indoor Outdoor Scraper Mats 3M Safety Walk Floor Treads Super Soaker Indoor Floor Mats 
 Cafeteria Dinnerware 
 Eco-Friendly Plates Eco-Friendly Cups&amp;Lids Plates&amp;Bowls Dinnerware Dinner&amp;Beverage Paper Napkins Disposable Food Trays - Paper, Foam, Plastic Plasticware Cutlery Dispenser Paper Napkins Foam Containers Paper Cups&amp;Lids Cup Dispensers Paper Doilies Paper Placemat and Table Covers Plastic Cups and Lids Styrofoam Cups&amp;Lids Straws, Stirrers, Swizzle Sticks,&amp;Toothpicks 
 Food Service Supplies 
 Aluminum Foil&amp;Sheets Butcher Paper Rolls Coffee&amp;Breakroom Supplies Foodservice Aprons, Hairnets&amp;Hats Pizza Delivery Aluminum Pans&amp;Trays Foodservice Bus Trays&amp;Bins Plastic Pitchers Ice Buckets, Scoops,&amp;Chests Poly Food Handling Gloves Insulated Water Coolers&amp;Bags Restaurant Register Rolls&amp;Guest Checks Deli Containers Kitchen Tools&amp;Cooking Items Butane Stove and Fuel Cartridges Sterno Catering Fuel Food Preparation Food Buckets Restaurant Candles Food Storage Containers Moist Towelettes Wax Paper Food Wrap Film Plastic Food Storage Bags Ziplock Plastic Bags Takeout Containers 
 Safety, Gloves&amp;Medical Items 
 Work Gloves Medical First Aid Kits Lens Cleaning Stations Nitrile Rubber Gloves Vinyl Gloves Ear Protection Insect Repellents Latex Rubber Gloves Medicine Cups Neoprene Gloves Exam Table Paper Rolls Disposable Coveralls 
 Facility&amp;Work Supplies 
 Batteries Insecticides Storage Boxes Bulb Changer Key Control Stretch Film Clipboards&amp;Permanent Markers Packing List Envelopes Extension Cords Call Bells Master Lock Padlocks&amp;Combination Locks Wedge Doorstop ADA Signs Tape Measurer Flashlights ACME Scissors Utility and Tool Kits Folding Chairs Sorbents, Pillows and Booms Utility Knives&amp;Blades Grabbers&amp;Pickers Utility Carts Hand Trucks Step Stools&amp;Ladders Wet Dry Vacuums Industrial Lubricants&amp;Adhesives 
 Waste Containers&amp;Receptacles 
 Medical Waste Containers Step on Desk Wastebaskets Outdoor Waste Containers Fire Safe Plastic Step On Containers Indoor Trash Cans Brute Trash Cans Fire Safe Indoor Waste Containers Recycling Containers Brute Waste Container Dollies Cigarette Receptacles Recycling Container Labels 
 Coupons 
 
 
&quot;This is the first time I have ordered from your company, and I must say that I am VERY impressed! The items I ordered were very reasonably priced, and they arrived in an EXTREMELY timely fashion. Actually, the shipping time was incredible! Keep up the good work.&quot;

- Nancy, PA
 
 view more... 

 

 
 
 Get exclusive offers and notices of new cleaning products emailed directly to you! Privacy Policy 
 
 2 Consumers Avenue
Norwich, CT 06360

1-877-403-6537 
 About Us Our Blog FAQ Contact Us 

 Shipping Returns Privacy Policy Repeat Shopping List 

 Expert Advice Resources MSDS MovingBoxWorld.com 
 ©2012 Cleaning Products World. All rights reserved.   Website design by Solid Cactus .
	</body>
</document>
