<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001179" url="http://www.thevillager.com/villager_157/talkingpoint.html" time="2012-07-12-16:37" support="1" score="0.0005069790769247723" bingtitle="Where to buy drugs — and no it’s not at a gay disco" webtitle="Where to buy drugsand no its not at a gay disco">
			<query id="000806" bing-rank="227"/>
	<description>And I think drunken revelers trying to exit should ... View bar on Eighth Ave. as the police lit the place ... and users is like fighting diabetes by jailing fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Volume 75, Number 50 | May 3 - 9 2006
 
 Talking Point
 

 Where to buy drugsand no its not at a gay disco 

By Tim Gay


O.K., O.K., some people might remember that I was aclean up the discoscrusader back in the90s. But Ive changed my perspective since those days when shooting bullets on the dance floor seemed to be a part of many clubsallure.


I still believe in a New Yorkers right to sleep. If you ask me, any liquor-licensed nonrestaurant establishment with an occupancy of 103 to 30,000 should be located west of 13th Ave.or at least below ground somewhere near the new water tunnel.


And I think drunken revelers trying to exit should instead be locked inside these disco vaults until theyve slept off whatever substance they are on.


Or, they should be taught that polite partiers do not sing and set off car alarms at 4 a.m.


But that will not happen. We can only hope that the city enacts legislation that mandates soundproofing and noisy-crowd control.


Where Ive changed my perspective is about drugs and clubs.


Recently, police raided and closed two discos, two bars and a gymall of which happened to be, like, 92 percent gayfor drug dealing and underage drinking. I was walking past The View bar on Eighth Ave. as the police lit the place with klieg lights and led patrons out the doorit reminded me of a 1940s Weejee photo from the Daily News.


Could it be that the New York City drug trade was focused on these five venues? Hardly.


Back in the70s and80s, dealing was common in bars and discos. But so was smoking reefer in Bryant Part while on ones lunch break. That all changed in the90s.


Neighborhood bars and big-time discos, valuing their liquor licenses, cant afford to allow dealing. In fact, last summer, every gay bar on Eighth Ave. was told by the 10th Precinct to have door guards checking IDs and monitoring the premises as well as the streets for any sign of drug dealing.


Astute New Yorkers, whether sophisticatedrecreational usersor full-blown addicts, just dont wait in line for hours and pay $20 admission fees to get inside a vibrating, pulsating blast of chaos only to crawl through 3,000 writhing bodies to find a dealer.


On the contrary, club people buy their drugs well in advance. They begin using those drugs several hours before going out for the night. Their drugs arekicking inwhile waiting in line.


And somewhere on their persons theyve concealed the evenings (and early mornings)bumpthat will help them through the night.


For the jaded partygoer, buying drugs at a disco is a sign of an amateuror a desperate addict who needs more-more-more.


Frankly, I wouldnt know where to buy drugs. I can hardly find a Lotto dealer on Eighth Ave. these days.


So I asked some current, former and recovered users of recreational drugs about where they go to make a score or meet and greet their dealers. This is certainly not an inclusive list. And many users focus on one primary dealer and one backup source.



Trendy and not-so-trendy Avenue A and B bars (straight ones.)
Chat rooms (AOL) using code words to set up meetings.
Certain Midtown theater blocks, lower Eighth Ave., far W. 10th St.
Introductions from other friends/ users (Youve got to know someone.)
Waiting forfriendsoutside of movie theaters.
Starbucks
Big Cup on Eighth Ave. (recently closed, not because of drugs but due to an exorbitant rent increase).
Outside of Whole Foods
The fountain at Lincoln Center
By delivery to ones office (Payment was prearranged.)
Garden State Plaza Mall (one respondent)

Among those I talked to, several mention buying drugs at clubs, butonly once or twiceoras a last resortits way too expensive.A number of users reported doing drugs with strangers in discreet after-hours clubs, quiet environments or simply sitting at home.


However, I think the real problem is how we view drug use and addiction.


We havent learned anything since the marijuana-benzedrine-narcotics busts of the50s, the60s acid years, the cocained80s and the Ecstasy-induced raves of the90s, not to mention the Rockefeller Drug Laws.


Our unsuccessful long-term policy of arresting dealers and users is like fighting diabetes by jailing fast-food restaurant workers and diabetics.
 


 
 
 
 
 Reader Services
 
 
 
 


 thevillager.com 
 
 
 
 
 Email our editor 
 
 View our previous issues 

 Report Distribution Problems 
 
Also Read: 
 

 
 ADVERTISING
 


 
 
 


 
 Home 

 The Villager is published by
Community Media LLC. 
 The Villager | 487 Greenwich St., Suite 6A | New York, NY 10013

Phone: 212.229.1890 | Fax: 212.229.2790
Email: news@thevillager.com 
 
 

 
Written permission of the publisher must be obtainedbefore any of the contents of this newspaper, in whole or in part, can be reproduced or redistributed.
	</body>
</document>
