<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001608" url="http://www.grubgrade.com/2012/03/04/food-for-thought-wendys-revamping/" time="2012-07-12-17:23" support="17" score="0.04316897845351806" bingtitle="GrubGrade | Food for Thought: Wendy’s Revamping" webtitle="GrubGrade | Food for Thought: Wendys Revamping">
			<query id="000891" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000671" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="000358" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000923" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001519" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000942" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="000954" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="001457" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="001048" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000608" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000438" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="001111" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="001173" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000045" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="000658" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="001016" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000451" bing-rank="19"/>
	<description>However, for a fast food restaurant, I don’t ... their restaurants more appealing as a place to sit ... unfriendly looks for bothering to order and receiving my food ...</description>
	<body>
		GrubGrade 
 We Make You Hungry 
 Home About Contact GrubGrading Privacy Policy Reviews While I’m Out 
 
 Food for Thought: Wendy’s Revamping 

 March 04, 2012 By: Mitchery Category: Food for Thought 
 
 
 It was recently announced that Wendy’s is going to be revamping the inside of all of their restaurants.  They are going for a more upscale fast food look.  I’m not a big fan of remodeling, revamping and changing what works.  I’m not saying that change isn’t needed in some environments, because it especially is for anything remotely related to technology.  However, for a fast food restaurant, I don’t see a purpose for it.  I remember my first time walking into a Wendy’s and since then it has never changed (except the menu).  For me, I don’t have many fond memories of Wendy’s to begin with, other than that one time that I was able to get a Jr. Bacon Cheeseburger for 99 cents. I don’t walk into a Wendy’s and think“this place looks like my great grandmothers basement”.

 

If McDonalds ever changed their look too drastically, I would be heartbroken.  One of my greatest child hood memories is when I used to ride on the back of Fry Kids on the merry-go-round at my local McDonalds.

 I also have another great memory of my father taking me out of school for a day for some quality bonding time at the Staten Island Zoo and then to pick up a Happy Meal for lunch.  When I received my Happy Meal, I opened the box and saw that I got a Moon Man toy.  I played with that for days. Every now and then I find myself looking it up on Ebay to see if I could pick it up again.

 I don’t understand why fast food restaurants are trying to appear as if they are upscale.  I’m not at any time planning on ordering a filet mignon at my local Wendy’s. Fast food to me is a place where I go to eat at a rapid pace and then I get the hell out of there. I don’t sit around and ponder the mysteries of the world as I’m sinking my teeth into a Baconator .  I wish Wendy’s would work more on getting all of their menus standardized rather than getting all of their stores to look more modern.  On a side note, do you remember when UPS changed their logo?  It cost them millions of dollars to change their logo from a box look to a more rounded look.  Ridiculous.

Was this change worth millions?

 Would the general appearance of a fast food restaurant make you decide yay or nay?

 
 
 Tags: food for thought , marketing , mcdonalds merry go round , Wendy&apos;s , Wendy&apos;s Restaurant Makeover , Wendy&apos;s Revamping 
53 Comments to“Food for Thought: Wendy’s Revamping”
 

 Ryan says: March 4, 2012 at 10:38 am 
Ronald called, he wants his shoes back.
 1 Reply Justin ST says: March 4, 2012 at 10:49 am 
Well said Mitchery. I bet the franchisees are not happy.
 2 Reply Rick says: March 4, 2012 at 10:51 am 
I remember my local Wendy’s had the salad bar (for awhile) and old-school tables with a collage of old newspapers as the tabletops. That Wendy’s burned down in 2003 in a failed attempt to collect insurance money. The new Wendy’s looks just about the same, minus the cool tables. I would trade the stupid flatscreens for a customer-facing coke fountain though–the employees at the Wendy’s around DC are mean as hell and I’m tired of getting grilled for my love of Dr. Pepper.
 3 Reply 
 Ryan says: March 4, 2012 at 10:55 am 
I remember those old tables I think all restaurants should have the Coca-Cola Freestyle machines btw.
 4 Reply 
 Crysta says: March 4, 2012 at 2:44 pm 
YES. The Freestyle is amazing.
 5 Reply Justin ST says: March 4, 2012 at 5:25 pm 
Truth!
 6 Reply 
 
 Lauren G. says: March 4, 2012 at 11:14 am 
But McDonald’s IS changing their look rather drastically. The ones in NY probably represent the extreme- but I can tell you they are UNRECOGNIZABLE.

 http://www.usatoday.com/money/industries/food/2011-05-06-mcdonalds-revamp_n.htm 
 7 Reply 
 Mike N says: March 4, 2012 at 11:52 am 
I was going to say the same thing—many McD’s in my area have been renovated and are really unrecognizable from the old days.
 8 Reply `Raiders757 says: March 4, 2012 at 12:09 pm 
We have one of the remodeled versions not far from me near the Christopher Newport University campus. It was remodeled several years ago and looks nothing like a McDonald’s. It’s built where a Hardee’s used to be, and I remember when it was being built, nobody had a clue it was going to be a McD’s until the signs went up.
 9 Reply Crysta says: March 4, 2012 at 12:15 pm 
We’ve got one of those revamped McDonalds in town. The outside looks silly, and the inside looks like they’re trying too hard to be Starbucks. Personally, I hate it. I’d rather go to the“old”McDonalds.

I’ve seen some themed McDonalds restaurants that were done well, but they didn’t do away with what made them recognizable either…
 10 Reply Justin ST says: March 4, 2012 at 5:24 pm 
I love the new McDonald’s. The problem is that the food is horrible. It needs to improve, a lot.
 11 Reply 
 Chefprotoss says: March 4, 2012 at 11:26 am 
Coming out with new spins on the baked potato would bring in more cash than changing the aesthetic of something we can’t eat.
 12 Reply 
 Ray says: March 4, 2012 at 5:05 pm 
Technically, you could eat quite a bit of the interior of a Wendy’s restaurant. It wouldn’t be healthy, and will probably cause health problems, but it’s possible.
 13 Reply Peter says: March 6, 2012 at 8:55 pm 
Baked sweet potatoes are coming soon
 14 Reply 
 Mikey F Baby says: March 4, 2012 at 11:36 am 
“I don’t have many fond memories of Wendy’s to begin with, other than that one time that I was able to get a Jr. Bacon Cheeseburger for 99 cents.”

AHA! Right on the money.
 15 Reply `Raiders757 says: March 4, 2012 at 12:04 pm 
I used to love those old newspaper add tables as a kid, and wish they would bring them back for some odd reason. Anyway, our original Wendy’s recently went through the new upgrade. They pretty much ripped the whole place down and built a completely new modern looking store with a fireplace and widescreen TV’s. The change was actually needed, because the store was over thirty years old and looked dated. It really made no difference for me though, as I only use the drive-thru. I did notice that their normally juicy/greasy burgers were rather dry after the reopening though. No, it wasn’t the new burger that was at fault, but it seems the new equipment was throwing the staff off their game. Now, after a few months, everything is back to normal and the burgers are juicy/greasy once again.

This store needed the remodeling, as it was one of the oldest in the entire region. I would find it rather silly to do it to many of the other ones near me though. Three of them are barely over ten years old. Really, bringing back the newspaper add tables would be enough of a remodeling for me.
 16 Reply Manavee says: March 4, 2012 at 12:06 pm 
I’ve been thinking that if a lot of these places continue to go upscale and try to get closer to a fast casual type of concept that there should be room in the market for a pure value based fast food type place.

If I was Burger King, I would think long and hard about the need to go“upscale”when there competitors are already trying to do the same thing. That market I suspect will be saturated at some point, if it isn’t already. They might be best served by concentrating on value (a la Subway) rather than quality per se.
 17 Reply 
 Zachary Jacob Zblewski says: March 4, 2012 at 10:27 pm 
One of our Burger King’s has the old cheap look and one remodeled to a nice modern place with flatscreen TVs and lounge chairs. I prefer the remodeled one.
 18 Reply 
 Mary says: March 4, 2012 at 1:57 pm 
I’m not bothered by the upgrades they’ve done with McDonald’s and Taco Bell. The new looks are cleaner but still colorful. BK and Subway though I’ve preferred the older look. You can hardly noticed the old Subway style (made to resemble the NY underground subway) unless you look really hard at the wallpaper. Same goes with Wendy’s. Their identity has always been about“Old Fashioned Burgers”and getting rid of the Old Fashioned style would be rather conflicting
 19 Reply TheWarden says: March 4, 2012 at 2:10 pm 
If I so desired, I would load up GIMP with the“Aliens”meme guy jpg and put“Marketing”at the bottom instead.
 20 Reply 
 Mike N says: March 4, 2012 at 6:27 pm 
I know those words, but that sign makes no sense.
 21 Reply 
 Jason says: March 4, 2012 at 2:37 pm 
I remember Wendys employees used to clear the tables. That was sort of nice but I would prefer a self serv soda machine.
 22 Reply 
 Mitchery says: March 4, 2012 at 7:48 pm 
If I want good service anymore at a fast food place, I go to Chick-Fil-A. I get better service there than going to my grandmothers house for breakfast, and my grandma is awesome.
 23 Reply Rick says: March 4, 2012 at 9:09 pm 
I forgot about that! That was great too
 24 Reply George says: March 7, 2012 at 11:21 am 
I’m not sure if this was just in my area, but as a kid, I remember Wendy’s and Burger King having full-time mentally handicapped people there who would clear the tables. Random memory.
 25 Reply 
 scott says: March 4, 2012 at 2:45 pm 
They really have to change the appearance of their restaurants if they keep raising their prices.

People are probably going to be unwilling to pay 9 bucks for a spicy chicken meal at a fast food place, but if they somehow successfully market themselves as something else, maybe people will end up thinking its worth it.
 26 Reply 
 Justin ST says: March 4, 2012 at 5:28 pm 
I’m telling you, Wendy is running this company down, and it will be a few years before the corporation tells her to hit the door. She’s trying to make Wendy’s into something it isn’t. The food is getting way too overpriced and the decor inside is classic. There’s no need to make it look like Chipotle. What is her deal? Oh yeah, she got rid of the old fries. What was she thinking?
 27 Reply 
 Mitchery says: March 4, 2012 at 7:46 pm 
Indeed Justin….Indeed.
 28 Reply Zachary Jacob Zblewski says: March 4, 2012 at 10:31 pm 
Wendy has nothing to do with the corporate structure of Wendy’s. Other than personally owning/co-owning some of their stores, she is simply a mascot/spokesperson for the company.

Advertising can work wonders on people’s perceptions.
 29 Reply 
 Justin ST says: March 5, 2012 at 5:15 pm 
You’re right, lol. Do you work for Wendy’s corporate?
 30 Reply 
 Zachary Jacob Zblewski says: March 10, 2012 at 3:56 pm 
I do not.
 31 
 
 
 
 Scrape says: March 4, 2012 at 3:51 pm 
This vaires greatly depending on where the restaurant is and who has the franchise. Some owners take much more pride in their stores. You can tell by how clean they are, how well the food is prepared, and even how new the store is. It is good for business. If your store is dirty and run down, you lose business. Period.

Round here, all the McD’s have been extensively remodeled. One was even torn down and rebuilt 180 degrees from it’s previous layout, and it wasn’t that old. The new interiors are really nice and comfortable. They also make the place actually function better. Free wi-fi, free refills, dim lighting, high-quality finish materials, high-top tables for the McCafe, an indoor redbox, and a few of the sauces (bbq, s&amp;s, tartar, ketchup) available to self-serve via pump. Fantastic. I go to this store over any other in the area. I stopped at one recently that hadn’t had a remodel, and it was like a different restaurant, altogether.

Wendy’s here has been doing some remodels, with most of the work being on the ouside. Frankly, they look cheap by using bottom of the barrel fake stone materials and not doing enough work to make the old restaurant look architecturally correct. On the inside, they are just recarpeting with a similar style, and sometimes putting in soda machines for customers to fill/refill. Some have them, some don’t. Wendy’s needs some MAJOR work. Most are very old and are falling apart, and some are downright filthy. They have no real‘style’to speak of (even the brand new one down the street has an interior out of the’90s), and are probably the least comfortable of the big three quick service chains. The bar has been raised; the public is demanding more and more these days. We have already seen this with the variety and quality of the food getting much better, and some chains (McDs, Arbys) have really invested in making their restaurants more appealing as a place to sit and have a meal with the family, not to just shove a burger down your throat on a 30 year old plastic bench.

Besides further work on their food, Wendys needs to lay down the law with their franchisees if they are to succeed. All restaurants will have soda machines out front for refills. Management will have consitency trainaing to ensure the product is the same coast to coast. Restaurants will be remodeled as needed, and with an upgraded and quality design; Not the cheap crap they are doing now which will need redoing in 5 years. And bring back the classic $.99 value menu. They are by far the most expensive chain, and that is hurting sales.
 32 Reply 
 Raiders757 says: March 5, 2012 at 10:42 pm 
You reminded me. Our newly rebuilt Wendy’s has the new Freestyle Coke dispensers, so they are indeed moving soda refills out front for the customer to use themselves.
 33 Reply George says: March 8, 2012 at 10:27 pm 
I agree with the dollar menu needing to come back. I used to have lunch at Wendy’s at least once every couple weeks, and now I will maybe go through the drive thru for a quick bite every couple months. I’ve always eaten off the value menu there, and my standard order used to be something like $5.50. A couple years ago now(a few months before they decided to change the fries), I went and ordered my standard order, and it ended up being like $8.75.

Now, I wouldn’t have minded if they raised prices on each item like $.20 or something, because inflation happens. But this was an abrupt massive change of basically everything on the dollar menu. It definitely stopped me from eating there(maybe a good thing for my health, though).
 34 Reply 
 Steven says: March 4, 2012 at 4:14 pm 
Marketing sells. The building and decor is as much a part of that as anything else. There are 2 Wendys in close proximity to me. One is an old building with a single drive thru window. The other is a modern building with a double window and is very well lit at night. I very rarely go to the older building. I feel better about the new one in many ways. Does that actually affect the food any? Probably not but nonetheless as a customer it matters. Similarly there are 2 Taco Bells close to me. One has an order verification screen in the drive thru. The other does not. Guess which one I go to?
 35 Reply 
 Mitchery says: March 4, 2012 at 7:45 pm 
I wouldn’t classify enhancing the customer experience as marketing. There are a lot of the older fast food chains that are being brought up to date with technology and are also being updated for means of quicker service. I’m personally fine with those changes and embrace them. It is when a company goes for years and years branding themselves in a certain light and then all of a sudden decide to take that name in a different direction is when I have a problem with it.
 36 Reply 
 rondoman says: March 5, 2012 at 4:57 pm 
Umm, Wendys has been moving in this direction with their food for years and years now, so now they are updating the decor to match.

Huge fan of GG, but the article is nonsense.
 37 Reply 
 Justin ST says: March 4, 2012 at 8:34 pm 
Not really. It doesn’t. Location matters the most for any business. Maintenance and age don’t if you like the food, unless there are serious problems with the place, like Restaurant Impossible bad. There are all sorts of dumps that survive. If the location and the convenience of going to the place are good, appearance matters little.
 38 Reply 
 JF says: March 4, 2012 at 8:22 pm 
While I agree branding is a huge part of any company’s success, I still think it all boils down to the products you offer. I do like Wendy’s, but don’t think they are great. If I want FF, I’d take Carls Jr. over anyone else (just my opinion).

Personally, I think making a better product line is a much better investment in money than the astethics. No remodeling of Wendy’s (or anyone else) would draw me to their business. It’s all about the products / service you provide.

Maybe this will work, maybe not, but I was so disappointed with the whole Hot and Juicy line. Just go back to the basics. What you do well and what made you money (famous) in the first place.

You could serve out of a cardboard box, but if the food and service meets my expectations, I don’t care about your looks.
 39 Reply Sascha says: March 4, 2012 at 11:36 pm 
There’s a lot of talk about Wendy’s being“run into the ground”, so to speak, but aren’t they on the verge, if they haven’t already, of moving ahead of Burger King?

Am I the only one who wants to see the return of the Superbar? With a Coke Freestyle next to it.
 40 Reply 
 ERock says: March 6, 2012 at 11:50 pm 
They are ahead of BK. But if Wendy’s being run into the ground, Burger King by comparison has been run into the erupting volcano pit. Currently the lowest quality product, most run down stores, most slow and surly employees, and not even good prices for what you get.
 41 Reply 
 Zack says: March 5, 2012 at 6:31 am 
As a foodie who secretly loves his fast food, I’m a big fan of GrubGrade, but I just can’t agree with the gist of this article. Namely, I think the Wendy’s people are doing a pretty good job with their turnaround, and these new looks are consistent with that.

Wendy’s had to do something; they were losing money on the average ticket, losing consumers to upscale upstarts and just losing mindshare in the burger business.

They’ve managed to do a few things very well:
• They’ve definitely improved on food quality. People complain about the H&amp;J burgers, and they didn’t seem that much better on paper, but in the store they definitely taste like an improvement, while even the value menu stuff I’ve gotten tastes a lot better then the competition (For example, Wendy’s has the best chicken wrap IMO).
• At least around me, they’ve definitely worked on the customer service. I remember going to my local Wendy’s and getting unfriendly looks for bothering to order and receiving my food pretty much thrown at my through the drive through window.
• They’re getting rid of the cheap feel. Getting rid of the Arby’s weight was a huge load on that front (I know Arby’s has its fans here on GG but I’m not one of them and all the ones around me are pretty lame)

Most importantly, I think they’ve really done good job of figuring out what their niche is in the fast food industry. They knew they were getting beaten by the newer burger places (Smash,5 Guys) but realized there was some folks who didn’t want to always deal with the time/calorie-consuming process at these new upscale chains, while also realizing that they’re never gonna beat McDonalds on value / ubiquity, and I’d say the same about BK but they just did beat them.

It’s a fierce market though, and they’ve definitely got competition; a lot of people mentioning Carls here and I’d throw JITB in the mix. For comparison’s sake, both of those places have had remodels and it’s probably time for Wendy’s to do the same. It seems like the GrubGrade folks aren’t a huge fan of the change (and also seem to have consistency issues with their local franchisee), but IMO it’s needed. The Wendy’s around me have looked the same since the mid 90s, and it’s really just not appealing anymore.x
 42 Reply 
 rondoman says: March 5, 2012 at 4:55 pm 
Agreed with this all Zack.

The reviewer even mentions if they drastically changed McD’s he would be heartbroken, well news flash: THEY HAVE!!! Where have you been?
 43 Reply 
 Mitchery says: March 5, 2012 at 8:38 pm 
I live in the past ^_^
 44 Reply 
 Justin ST says: March 5, 2012 at 5:17 pm 
Ok, you definitely are not some average poster on Grubgrade. Please come out and admit who you really are. This was borderline propaganda.
 45 Reply 
 Mark Reed says: March 5, 2012 at 6:33 am 
That’s not a“Moon Man.”That’s“Mac Tonight.”Try looking on Youtube to see if some of the old Mac Tonight commercials are there.

As I recall this was a promotion to boost the sales of Big Macs at dinnertime.
 46 Reply Lindsay says: March 5, 2012 at 8:35 am 
Boo. I hate when they mess with my childhood nostalgia.
 47 Reply Someone says: March 5, 2012 at 11:06 am 
Wendy’s may be expensive, but it feels like you’re actually getting something. I think BK is in far more trouble.
 48 Reply 
 Mitchery says: March 5, 2012 at 8:36 pm 
I really like your name…
 49 Reply 
 Brad says: March 5, 2012 at 11:26 am 
What Wendy’s really needs to do is get some revamping and standardizing of their menu prices, especially when it comes to their value menu. Once they do that, they can go hog-wild with the look of the place and I wouldn’t care.
 50 Reply 
 JF says: March 5, 2012 at 8:48 pm 
It wasn’t until a few months ago on another Wendy’s thread that I saw people commenting about their“My 99″was not really 99 in all markets. I totally agree with this, particularly if you are doing national commercials. You need to standardize on your pricing, otherwise don’t run them in markets where the don’t apply.

And don’t use tiny words that are on the TV for 2 seconds for your disclaimer.
 51 Reply 
 CulinaryZerg says: March 7, 2012 at 2:33 am 
Wendy’s is in need of a makeover, no question. The new McDonald’s are impressive and definitely broaden the customer base they draw.

Problem is, Wendy needs to broaden it’s customer base with more than just restaurant appearance–it needs to work on its food. McDonalds did just that in the past decade. It’s well established that they captured the female (as a slightly more healthier/upscale) market through offerings like premium salads, yogurts, fruit&amp;oatmeal, McCafe, more chicken options, healthy happy meals etc. McDonald’s new decor perfectly matches their food rebranding.

Wendy’s has gone in an opposite direction. They used to have speciality sandwiches (pita sandwhiches, mushroom melts) and was the favorite fastfood stop of my lady friends. But in the last decade, Wendys has moved markedly in a Burger-King like direction and are all about Baconators, Triple-Decker burgers, and Salty Skin-on Fries. Yeah, they probably got a temporary sales uptick from appealing to the greasy junk food craver (which includes me), but longer terms it’s turned off its core customers. They might as well sell tacos and cheese fries next (tasty but horridly wrong for it’s brand). Their dirty, dingy, franchise restaurants just reinforce this experience.

For Wendy’s to win back it’s old customer segments (which have migrated to McDonalds, Chick-Fil-A, and fast casual), it needs to seriously class up it’s food in addition to its restaurants.
 52 Reply Justin says: March 10, 2012 at 9:28 am 
I work for a company the delivers the food to Wendys. One of my stores is currently closed due to this new remodeling. While I must say the new design ( pictures I have seen at least ) looks good, I’m not sure why they are doing this. Wendys sales as a whole are in the toilet.Will a new design really help that? I’d focus more on the food and menu if I were corporate. The drop in sales should be a cause for concern considering all the advertising they have been doing on TV over the last year. All you see on TV anymore are the new“thick and juicy”burger and cod fish sandwich commercials
 53 Reply 
 

 
Leave a Reply
 Click here to cancel reply. 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 

 

 

 

 Notify me of follow-up comments by email. 

 Notify me of new posts by email. 
   ← Review: Southwest Patty Melt from Hardee’s/Carl’s Jr. Review: Spicy Big Bite from 7-Eleven → 
 
Archives
 Select Month July 2012 (13) June 2012 (49) May 2012 (45) April 2012 (45) March 2012 (49) February 2012 (56) January 2012 (44) December 2011 (35) November 2011 (47) October 2011 (47) September 2011 (55) August 2011 (55) July 2011 (39) June 2011 (35) May 2011 (39) April 2011 (35) March 2011 (38) February 2011 (40) January 2011 (42) December 2010 (38) November 2010 (37) October 2010 (41) September 2010 (34) August 2010 (35) July 2010 (49) June 2010 (38) May 2010 (45) April 2010 (35) March 2010 (36) February 2010 (31) January 2010 (38) December 2009 (40) November 2009 (36) October 2009 (39) September 2009 (53) August 2009 (68) July 2009 (75) June 2009 (73) May 2009 (76) April 2009 (81) March 2009 (61) February 2009 (24) 
Categories
 Select Category Celebrity Grubbers  (18) Discussion  (19) Featured Restaurant  (50) First Impressions  (50) Food for Thought  (6) Food News  (903) From the Editor  (66) GG Contests  (120) GG Videos  (104) GrubGrade Site Update  (12) Hitting the Road  (48) Homemade  (45) In My Pantry  (12) Jealous  (17) Observations  (56) Polls  (38) RememBear This  (24) Reviews  (506)    Breakfast  (75)    Burgers  (66)    Chicken  (92)    Desserts  (39)    Drinks  (16)    Fries/Rings/Sides  (27)    Hot Dogs  (8)    Mexican  (37)    Pizza  (19)    Salads  (17)    Sandwiches  (121)    Seafood  (18)    Snacks  (91)    Soup  (1)    Wraps  (12) Uncategorized  (9) 
 GrubGrade on Twitter 

 #HowToKeepARelationshipWithMe http://t.co/Zg5Wekvx 2 hours ago Rudy&apos;s: Breakfast Tacos http://t.co/FUGwMbW2 2 hours ago Kolache Factory http://t.co/tUaayh7c 2 hours ago 
 
Recent Comments

 stevenp on Review: Cantina Bell Menu from Taco Bell Raiders757 on KFC Introduces New KFC Bites Matt T on A Look at Family Meal in Frederick, Maryland Alex on Son of Baconator Joins the Wendy’s Menu 
 
 
 
Check Us Out On...

 GrubGrade on Facebook GrubGrade on Tumblr GrubGrade on Twitter The GrubGrade Channel 
 
Other Blogs

 EJ Eats Food Junk Freezer Burns On Second Scoop Option Pitch&amp;Waffle Crisp Rodzilla Reviews San Diego Sugar Serious Eats Snack Snoop So Good Blog The Impulsive Buy Would I Buy It Again? Yum Yucky 
 
Meta

 Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.org 
 
 
 
 GrubGrade ©2007 - 2012 All Rights Reserved. Using WordPress 3.4 Engine
 Entries and Comments .

 Prosumer ver. 1.9 design by WP GPL 

 
 Page optimized by WP Minify WordPress Plugin 

 Featuring Recent Posts WordPress Widget development by YD
	</body>
</document>
