<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001512" url="http://www.answerbag.com/q_view/1276254" time="2012-07-12-17:16" support="2" score="0.012168299170059137" bingtitle="Can you eat food once you chop the mould off, or is it safer to ..." webtitle="Can you eat food once you chop the mould off, or is it safer to just throw it away? | Answerbag">
			<query id="000345" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="001098" bing-rank="133"/>
	<description>Sometimes he finishes the whole can; sometimes he refuses to eat, forcing me to throw the leftover food away. Has been to a fast food restaurant and got a cold burger from ...</description>
	<body>
		Ask a Question or Create a Poll 
 Home Categories Questions Forums Blog NEW! 
 
 Arts Autos&amp;Motorcycles Business Computers Diet&amp;Fitness Education Electronics Entertainment Environmentalism Fashion&amp;Beauty Finance Food&amp;Dining Games Health Hobbies Home&amp;Garden Kids Legal Life&amp;Society Pets&amp;Pet Care Real Estate Recreation&amp;Sports Relationship Advice Religion Science Social Sciences Transportation Travel&amp;Places Answerbag Outside the Bag 
 
 Home / Questions / Food And Dining / Cooking&amp;Recipes / Food Safety 
 
by Sunshine1 on February 12th, 2009
 
Question

Help answer this question below.
 
Can you eat food once you chop the mould off, or is it safer to
just throw it away?
 Share your answer here... Want to attach an image to your answer? Click here. 
 
Only upload an image if you have the rights to it,
and ensure that it complies with our terms of use .
 
 Like Report 
 Share: Facebook Twitter Other Sort answers by: Greatness / Likes Date submitted 
Answers. 10 helpful answers below. 
 
 
by Spicy Hot on February 12th, 2009
 
 It is only safe on a few things.


Molds are used to make certain kinds of cheeses and can be on the surface of cheese or be developed internally. Blue veined cheese such as Roquefort, blue, Gorgonzola, and Stilton are created by the introduction of P. roqueforti or Penicillium roqueforti spores. Cheeses such as Brie and Camembert have white surface molds. Other cheeses have both an internal and a surface mold. The molds used to manufacture these cheeses are safe to eat.


Meats - Some salamis -- San Francisco, Italian, and Eastern European types -- have a characteristic thin, white mold coating which is safe to consume; however, they shouldn’t show any other mold. Dry-cured country hams normally have surface mold that must be scrubbed off before cooking.


Fruits and vegetables, firm
(such as cabbage, bell peppers, carrots, etc.) Cut off at least 1 inch around and below the mold spot (keep the knife out of the mold itself so it will not cross-contaminate other parts of the produce). 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by Lori K still ignores stalkers and trolls on February 12th, 2009
 
 Depends. Cheese gets moldy during aging. Removing it is perfectly safe. Salt cured meats also acquire mold. It&apos;s usually removed with a stiff brush prior to cooking. I&apos;m sure there are other foods like that. 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by Galeanda on February 13th, 2009
 
 There are some foods you might be able to trim the mold away, like cheese, but most foods are not safe. The mold&apos;roots&apos;go deeper than just what you see, so yu have to cut away a LOT of the item. 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by Shanel with an S on February 12th, 2009
 
 i heard you can cut it off and still eat it (something like bread) but just to be safe i&apos;d throw it away. 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by jjdecker on March 15th, 2009
 
 grandma would just cut the mold off, i would throw it away! 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by hugh750 on February 12th, 2009
 
 i would just throw it out, why risk getting sick. 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by WilAtHart is DONE on February 12th, 2009
 
 it depends how much is on the food. if i find mold on bread in just one or two places, i chop it off...but if its like covering, chiao!!! =] 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by Whitehair on February 12th, 2009
 
 The only food safe to eat and being still delicious after you have cut off the mold is real cheese ( grown cheese !). The most dangerous to eat is moldy bread. When you see a tiny spot, it is present in the entire bread. 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by Beany on February 12th, 2009
 
 It&apos;ll be fine, just chop it off.
Bread is a bit dodgy as the mold spreads fast, but if it obviously hasn&apos;t got to the rest it should be okay. Cheese is class, it could have thick hairy mould on and you could just give it a shave and then eat it 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by GuitarPlayer92 on February 12th, 2009
 
 I would throw it away. Something tells me there could still be mold residue on there or something. 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
 Share your answer... Want to attach an image to your answer? Click here. 
 
Only upload an image if you have the rights to it,
and ensure that it complies with our terms of use .
 
Did this answer your question? If not, then ask a new question or create a poll . 
 
More Questions. Additional questions in this category. 

 
 What are the dangers of used canola oil? 
by Answerbag Staff on May 15th, 2011
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 What Is the Best Temperature to Grill Salmon? 
by Answerbag Staff on May 12th, 2011
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 Is it okay to cook canned foods in their can? 
by Answerbag Staff on May 4th, 2011
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 Have you ever eaten an entire jar of peanut butter in half an hour? 
by Lucius50 on May 9th, 2012
 
 | 2 people like this
 
 If a tomato has DNA and a chicken has DNA and veggies and spices have DNA....Does curry? 
by barradarcy on June 15th, 2012
 
 | 1 person likes this
 More Food safety See only professionally researched Food safety questions 
 
You&apos;re reading Can you eat food once you chop the mould off, or is it safer to just throw it away?
 
Follow us on Facebook!
 
Related Ads
 
Related Questions

 
 if food goes out of date and grows mould/bacteria, then when it is cooked or boiled the mould dies and surely its ok to eat isnt it? 
 
 Do you throw away food after its expiration date? Canned food? Dry Goods? What if it&apos;s been frozen? Do you smell it/check it first, or do you just toss it after the date on the package? 
 
 How long does&quot;wet food&quot;(canned cat food) stay fresh after opening? I feed my cat 1/2 teaspoon twice a day and refrigerate the rest. Sometimes he finishes the whole can; sometimes he refuses to eat, forcing me to throw the leftover food away. 
 
 Has been to a fast food restaurant and got a cold burger from after spending a lot of money just to have to throw it away because it was ice cold and unfit to eat 
 
 I nearly didnt sleep or eat for 2 days and now when i try to eat i have a stomach ache or i even throw up the food i just ate. What is this, a stomach flu or what? and how can i get better? 
 
 
Professionally Researched
 
 
 Is celebrex safer than vioxx? 
 
 Can you throw away or burn us currency? 
 
 Can you throw away computer monitors? 
 
 Can you throw your computer away in the garbage? 
 
 Can I ship food with Fedex and UPS? 
 
 
ANSWERBAG BUZZ
 Can you cut mold off bread Bell pepper mold safe to eat Cut mold off bread Can you cut mold off of bread Eat bread if cut away mold 
 About Us About Answerbag Sitemap Professionally Researched Questions   Legal Privacy Policy Terms of Use Disclaimer Ad Choices   Follow Us on Facebook 
 Answerbag.com 
Your favorite Q&amp;A site is on Facebook! Become a fan to connect with the ever-growing community of Answerbaggers, share your thoughts and find out what Answerbag&apos;s up to next!

 Latest Tweet 
 Follow Answerbag on Twitter! 
 
 
Answerbag

 AB4Adults Answerbag UK
	</body>
</document>
