<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001948" url="http://www.weightwatchers.ca/util/art/index_art.aspx?art_id=19941&amp;tabnum=1&amp;sc=3&amp;subnav=health%2520ideas" time="2012-07-12-17:51" support="4" score="0.002253649408105105" bingtitle="Java Joy" webtitle="Java Joy">
			<query id="000243" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="001466" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="001497" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="001371" bing-rank="220"/>
	<description>Nowadays, it seems that every corner deli, fast-food restaurant, and even ... Advocates favour the increase that the drink causes in your metabolism. One cup of coffee ...</description>
	<body>
		WeightWatchers.ca 
 Find a Meeting Help Log In 
 Search Entire Site Plan Information Articles Message Boards Help About Us For Go 
 How Weight Watchers Works Food&amp;Recipes Fitness&amp;Health Success Stories Community Shop 
 
 Workout Ideas Health&amp;Wellness Science Centre 
 
 
 
 
 
 
About Weight Watchers
 
 Our approach What you’ll eat Meetings Online The science of weight loss Success Stories 
 
 Free E-mail Newsletter 
 Our free e-mail newsletter highlights recipes, Success Stories, helpful tips and more!
 Sign up for free now 
 
 
 Java Joy 
 
 
 Article By: Leigh Newman Print Email 
 
 
 
 Desc 
 
 According to the Coffee Association of Canada, over 63% of Canadians over the age of 18 drink coffee daily, making coffee the number one drink for adults in the country. The trick is to stick with coffee, not a milkshake in disguise. 


 
 
Remember when a cup of hot fresh coffee tasted like a cup of hot fresh tar? Nowadays, it seems that every corner deli, fast-food restaurant, and even office has a pot of delectable, rich-tasting java either simmering on the burner or chilled over ice. According to the Coffee Association of Canada, over 63% of Canadians over the age of 18 drink coffee daily, making coffee the number one drink for adults in the country. But for those of us watching our waistlines, never fear, the calories in one cup of coffee only total—drum roll, please—zero.

Calories in coffee come from creamers, milk, sugar, flavoured sweeteners and flavoured creamers. Depending on how much you pour into your coffee, that, diet-friendly drink can turn into a serious enemy. The situation only intensifies when you enter the coffee bar. Tim Horton&apos;s 16-ounce Iced Cappucino has about 457 calories and 23 grams of fat. Second Cup&apos;s 16-ounce Iced Crème Brulee Ristretto? 439 calories and 21 grams of fat. Starbuck&apos;s Cafe White Chocolate Mocha prepared with 2% milk? 440 calories.

The trick is to stick with coffee, not a milkshake in disguise. Order a plain cup with skim milk and sugar substitute. If you&apos;re a fan of Tim Horton&apos;s coffee, try swapping out the 18% cream for 1% milk the next time you order one of their famous iced cappuccinos. Or, if you&apos;re the mood for a little sophistication, try an Americano, a thicker, espresso-based coffee that totals around 15 calories. Flavoured coffees are also an option. Van Houtte makes chocolate, hazelnut vanilla, and Irish crème (www.vanhoutte.com) blends that taste like deserts, but come in at—drum roll again, please—zero calories!

Other major pitfalls are the croissants, cookies, and scones that invariably show up next to coffee. A bagel is a healthy, low-fat choice, if you&apos;ve planned on eating. If you haven&apos;t, work on eliminating the temptation of an extra, unwanted meal. For example, if the office regularly sets out doughnuts by the coffee machine, consider buying your morning cup on the way to work.

These simple rules should help you enjoy coffee while sticking to your weight-loss goals. But watch out for the talking heads. Just about every diet-mogul in the world has something to say about coffee. Advocates favour the increase that the drink causes in your metabolism. One cup of coffee contains about 100 mg of caffeine. After drinking a cup, a person&apos;s resting metabolic rate increases by as much as 10%, which may help burn up a calories, but may also push your heart and nerves into overdrive.

Low-carb pundits concerned with blood sugar and insulin level advise against the drink completely. According to the Canadian Diabetes Association, drinking caffeine in large amounts such as coffee over a short period of time has been shown to raise blood sugar. Caffeine does this by enhancing the effect of two hormones (adrenaline and glucagons), which can impede your body&apos;s ability to process fat.

The best solution seems to be moderation. If you&apos;re a regular drinker and you quit coffee cold turkey, you&apos;re gong to feel exhausted, which may lead you to compensate with sweets. If you drink too much, you&apos;ll end up edgy and irritable—feelings you may already be struggling with as you watch your weight. In short, drink no more than four cups a day, and try to space them evenly throughout the day to avoid mood swings.

Here are a few drinks to help you enjoy the approaching fall months. So whip out that blender or set the kettle on boil and get ready to enjoy a satisfying treat that will keep you moving on with your weight-loss goals.

 Frappacino To Go 

 Ingredients 

 1 cup of strongly brewed coffee such as French or Dark Italian Roast, chilled Your favourite variety of no-calorie sweetener 2-4 Tablespoons of light or regular powdered creamer Dash of Cinnamon Nonfat Whipped Topping 1/2 Cup of Crushed Ice 

Blend all except topping in a blender. Pour in glass. Add topping and extra dash of cinnamon.

 Summer Coffee Soda 

 Ingredients 

 1/2 cup of Chilled Brewed Coffee 1/2 cup of Cola Soda (diet or lo-calorie) Lemon slice Sugar free sweetener to taste. 

Combine and Consume.

 Fall Flavour 

 Ingredients 

 1 Cup of Hot Brewed Coffee 2 Tablespoons of Non-Dairy Creamer 1 Teaspoon of Pumpkin Pie Spices 2-3 Packets of no-calorie Sweetener 

Mix creamer with pumpkin pie spices and sweetener. Add to coffee and stir.


 NEXT STEPS 

Interested in some fresh and exciting coffee concoctions that won&apos;t cost you your entire Weekly Points Allowance? Check out the winners in the beverage category of our SPLENDA* Sweet Recipe Creations Contest .

 
Recent Articles
 
 Your activity overview Your activity overview About PointsPlus® 2012 
 View all 
  

 



 About Us | Press Room | Site Map | Contact Us | Help | Affiliate Program | Troubleshooting 
 Terms&amp;Conditions | Privacy |For subscribers only: Subscription Agreement 

 WEIGHT WATCHERS is the registered trademark of Weight Watchers International, Inc. PointsPlus is a trademark of
Weight Watchers International, Inc. Trademarks used under license by Weight Watchers Canada Ltd. and WeightWatchers.ca Limited.
© 2012 Weight Watchers International, Inc. © 2012 WeightWatchers.com, Inc. All rights reserved. 



 International Sites
	</body>
</document>
