<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001922" url="http://studyofeconomics.wordpress.com/" time="2012-07-12-17:49" support="1" score="0.0005125502755722973" bingtitle="Study of Economics" webtitle="Study of Economics">
			<query id="000086" bing-rank="224"/>
	<description>For example, a modern fast food restaurant can be staffed by a handful of ... A well-trained worker can load the soda dispenser with an empty cup and press a button ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to content Follow: RSS 
 Study of Economics 
 Links to books and texts on praxeology and economics 
 Home Books About 
 February 28, 2012 
 I Want to be a Consumer, a Poem by Patrick Barrington 
 
Henry Hazlitt, in his Failure of the“New Economics” , quotes this poem, which can be viewed as a critique of Keynesian economics. Hazlitt writes (p. 146 in PDF file):
 
The natural consequences of the Keynesian economic philosophy were vividly portrayed by Patrick Barrington (two years before the particular rationalization that apeared in the General Theory ) in his poem in Punch [Issue of April 25, 1934]:
 
I Want to be a Consumer

“And what do you mean to be?”
The kind old Bishop said
As he took the boy on his ample knee
And patted his curly head.
“We should all of us choose a calling
To help Society’s plan;
Then what do you mean to be, my boy,
When you grow to be a man?”

“I want to be a Consumer,”
The bright-haired lad replied
As he gazed up into the Bishop’s face
In innocence open-eyed.
“I’ve never had aims of a selfish sort,
For that, as I know, is wrong.
I want to be a Consumer, Sir,
And help the world along.

“I want to be a Consumer
And work both night and day,
For that is the thing that’s needed most,
I’ve heard Economists say,
I won’t just be a Producer,
Like Bobby and James and John;
I want to be a Consumer, Sir,
And help the nation on.”

“But what do you want to be?”
The Bishop said again,
“For we all of us have to work,”said he,
“As must, I think, be plain.
Are you thinking of studying medicine
Or taking a Bar exam?”
“Why, no!”the bright-haired lad replied
As he helped himself to jam.

“I want to be a Consumer
And live in a useful way;
For that is the thing that’s needed most,
I’ve heard Economists say.
There are too many people working
And too many things are made.
I want to be a Consumer, Sir,
And help to further Trade.

“I want to be a Consumer
And do my duty well;
For that is the thing that’s needed most,
I’ve heard Economists tell.
I’ve made up my mind,”the lad was heard,
As he lit a cigar, to say;
“I want to be a Consumer, Sir,
And I want to begin today.”
 Leave a Comment January 24, 2012 
 Value is subjective 
 
“The value of an article does not depend on its essential nature but on the estimation of men, even if that estimation be foolish.”
 
—Diego de Covarrubias y Leiva (1512-1577), quoted in The School of Salamanca , by Marjorie Grice-Hutchinson.
 
 Leave a Comment December 20, 2011 
 Frank Shostak: What is Wrong With Econometrics? 
 
 [This article was published at Mises.org on April 17, 2002.] 

A recent academic study by economists Karl Case, John Quigley, and Robert Shiller of consumer-spending behavior in the U.S. and 13 other developed nations indicates that the wealth effect from housing is twice as great on consumer spending as comparable changes in stock-market wealth. In the U.S., for example, they found that a 10-percent gain in housing prices would provoke an average 0.62-percent increase in consumption, while a similar jump in stock-market wealth only elicited about a 0.3-percent to 0.2-percent increase in spending ( Barron’s , April 15, 2002).

What enabled these economists to derive these answers is econometric modeling.

In the natural sciences, a laboratory experiment can isolate various elements and their movements. There is no equivalent in the discipline of economics. The employment of econometrics and econometric model-building is an attempt to produce a laboratory where controlled experiments can be conducted.

The idea of having such a laboratory is very appealing to economists and politicians. Once the model is built and endorsed as a good replica of the economy, politicians can evaluate the outcomes of various policies. This, it is argued, enhances the efficiency of government policies and thus leads to a better and more prosperous economy. It is also suggested that the model can serve as a referee in assessing the validity of various economic ideas. The other purpose of a model is to provide an indication regarding the future.

By means of mathematical and statistical methods, an econometrician establishes functional relationships between various economic variables. For example, personal consumer outlays are related to personal disposable income and interest rates, while fixed capital spending is explained by the past stock of capital, interest rates, and economic activity. A collection of such various estimated relations—i.e., equations—constitutes an econometric model.

A comparison of the goodness of fit of the dynamic simulation versus the actual data is an important criterion in assessing the reliability of a model. (In a static simulation, the equations of the model are solved using actual lagged variables. In a dynamic simulation, the equations are solved by employing calculated from the model-lagged variables). The final test of the model is its response to a policy variable change, such as an increase in taxes or a rise in government outlays. By means of a qualitative assessment, a model builder decides whether the response is reasonable or not. Once the model is successfully constructed, it is ready to be used.

Despite the aura of importance and mysterious wisdom that econometric modeling projects, it is nevertheless an empty vessel. The econometric modeling procedure employs an untenable methodology: it tries to capture human behavior by means of mathematical and statistical methods.

 Is the mathematical method valid in economics? 

By applying mathematics, mainstream economics is attempting to follow in the footsteps of natural sciences. In the natural sciences, the employment of mathematics enables scientists to formulate the essential nature of objects. In short, by means of a mathematical formula, the response of objects to a particular stimulus in a given condition is captured. Consequently, within these given conditions, the same response will be obtained time and again.

The same approach, however, is not valid in economics. For economics is supposed to deal with human beings and not objects. According to Mises,
 
The experience with which the sciences of human action have to deal is always an experience of complex phenomena. No laboratory experiments can be performed with regard to human action.[1]
 
The main characteristic or nature of human beings is that they are rational animals. They use their minds to sustain their lives and well-being. The usage of the mind, however, is not set to follow some kind of automatic procedure, but rather every individual employs his mind in accordance with his own circumstances. This makes it impossible to capture human nature by means of mathematical formulae, as is done in the natural sciences.

In short, people have the freedom of choice to change their minds and pursue actions that are contrary to what was observed in the past. As a result of the unique nature of human beings, analyses in economics can only be qualitative.

Furthermore, to pursue quantitative analysis implies the possibility of the assignment of numbers, which can be subjected to all of the operations of arithmetic. To accomplish this, it is necessary to define an objective fixed unit. Such an objective unit, however, doesn’t exist in the realm of human valuations. On this Mises wrote,“There are, in the field of economics, no constant relations, and consequently no measurement is possible.”[2]

There are no constant standards for measuring the minds, the values, and the ideas of men. Valuation is the means by which a conscious purposeful individual assesses the given facts of reality. In other words once an individual establishes what the facts are, he then assesses which out of these established facts are the most suitable to attain his various ends.

Individual goals or ends set the standard for valuing the facts of reality. For instance, if the goal of an individual is to improve his health, then he would establish which goods will benefit his health and which will not. Among those that will benefit him, some will be more effective than others. There is no way, however, to quantify this effectiveness. All that one could do is rank these goods in accordance with perceived effectiveness.

The use of mathematics in economics poses another serious problem. The employment of mathematical functions implies that human actions are set in motion by various factors. However, this is an erroneous way of thinking. For instance, contrary to the mathematical way of thinking, individual outlays on goods are not“caused”by real income as such. In his own context, every individual decides how much of a given amount of income will be used for consumption and how much for savings. While it is true that people respond to changes in their incomes, the response is not automatic, and it cannot be captured by a mathematical formula. For instance, an increase in an individual’s income doesn’t automatically imply that his consumption expenditure will follow suit. In other words, every individual assesses the increase in income against the goals he wants to achieve. Thus he might decide that it is more beneficial for him to raise his savings rather than raise his consumption.

 The validity of probability theory in economics 

While mathematics is the key tool of econometric methods, the foundation of econometrics is probability theory. What is probability? The probability of an event is the proportion of times the event occurs out of a large number of trials. For instance, the probability of obtaining heads when a coin is tossed is 50 percent. This does not mean that when a coin is tossed 10 times, five heads are always obtained. However, if the experiment is repeated a large number of times, then it is likely that 50 percent will be obtained. The greater the number of throws, the nearer the approximation is likely to be.

Alternatively, say it has been established that in a particular area the probability of wooden houses catching fire is .01. This means that on the basis of experience, on average, 1 percent of wooden houses will catch fire. This does not mean that this year or the following year the percentage of houses catching fire will be exactly 1 percent. The percentage might be 1 percent each year or not. Over time, however, the average of these percentages will be 1 percent.

This information, in turn, can be converted into the cost of fire damages thereby establishing the case for insuring against the risk of fire. Owners of wooden houses might decide to pool their risk, i.e., spread the risk by setting up a fund. In other words, every owner of a wooden house will contribute according to a certain proportion to the total amount of money that is required in order to cover the damages of those owners whose houses will be damaged by the fire. Note that insurance against the fire risk can only take place because we know its probability distribution and because there are enough owners of wooden houses to spread the cost of fire damage among them so that the premium will not be excessive. In this regard, these owners of wooden houses are all members of a particular group or class that will be affected in a similar way by a fire. We know that, on average, 1 percent of the members of this group will be affected by fire. However, we don’t know exactly who it will be. The important thing for insurance is that members of a group must be homogeneous as far as a particular event is concerned.

In economics, however, we don’t deal with homogeneous cases. Each observation is a unique, nonrepeatable event caused by a particular individual response. Consequently, no probability distribution can be established. Again, probability distribution rests on the assumption that we are dealing with a nonparticular, and so repeatable, event. Let us take for instance entrepreneurial activities. If these activities were repeatable with known probability distributions, then we would not need entrepreneurs. After all, an entrepreneur is an individual who arranges his activities toward finding out consumers’ future requirements. People’s requirements, however, are never constant with respect to a particular good. The assumption that econometrics makes–that probability distribution exists and can be quantified–leads to absurd results. For it describes, not a world of human beings who exercise their minds in making choices, but machines.

Human activities, however, cannot be analyzed in the same way that one would analyze objects. To make sense of historical data, one must scrutinize them not by means of statistical methods but by means of trying to grasp and understand how they emerged.

 Continue reading at Mises.org. 
 Leave a Comment November 28, 2011 
 Gold vs. Paper 
 
By Ludwig von Mises

 [This article was published on Mises.org on 28th September 2009. It was originally published in the Freeman, July 13, 1953 ( download PDF ).] 

Most people take it for granted that the world will never return to the gold standard. The gold standard, they say, is as obsolete as the horse and buggy. The system of government-issued fiat money provides the treasury with the funds required for an open-handed spending policy that benefits everybody; it forces prices and wages up and the rate of interest down and thereby creates prosperity. It is a system that is here to stay.

Now whatever virtues one may ascribe — undeservedly — to the modern variety of the greenback standard, there is one thing that it certainly cannot achieve. It can never become a permanent, lasting system of monetary management. It can work only as long as people are not aware of the fact that the government plans to keep it.

 The Alleged Blessings of Inflation 

The alleged advantages that the champions of fiat money expect from the operation of the system they advocate are temporary only. An injection of a definite quantity of new money into the nation’s economy starts a boom as it enhances prices. But once this new money has exhausted all its price-raising potentialities and all prices and wages are adjusted to the increased quantity of money in circulation, the stimulation it provided to business ceases.

Thus even if we neglect dealing with the undesired and undesirable consequences and social costs of such inflationary measures and, for the sake of argument, even if we accept all that the harbingers of“expansionism”advance in favor of inflation, we must realize that the alleged blessings of these policies are shortlived. If one wants to perpetuate them, it is necessary to go on and on increasing the quantity of money in circulation and expanding credit at an ever-accelerated pace. But even then the ideal of the expansionists and inflationists, viz., an everlasting boom not upset by any reverse, could not materialize.

A fiat-money inflation can be carried on only as long as the masses do not become aware of the fact that the government is committed to such a policy. Once the common man finds out that the quantity of circulating money will be increased more and more, and that consequently its purchasing power will continually drop and prices will rise to ever higher peaks, he begins to realize that the money in his pocket is melting away.

Then he adopts the conduct previously practiced only by those smeared as profiteers; he“flees into real values.”He buys commodities, not for the sake of enjoying them, but in order to avoid the losses involved in holding cash. The knell of the inflated monetary system sounds. We have only to recall the many historical precedents beginning with the Continental currency of the War of Independence.

 Continue reading at Mises.org… 
 Leave a Comment October 24, 2011 
 The Genius of Carl Menger, by F. A. Hayek 
 
 This article, written by F. A. Hayek, was published at Mises.org on 30th September 2011. 

 [Introduction to Carl Menger&apos;s Principles of Economics (1934)] 

The history of economics is full of tales of forgotten forerunners, men whose work had no effect and was only rediscovered after their main ideas had been made popular by others, of remarkable coincidences of simultaneous discoveries, and of the peculiar fate of individual books. But there must be few instances, in economics or any other branch of knowledge, where the works of an author who revolutionised the body of an already well-developed science and who has been generally recognised to have done so, have remained so littleknown as those of Carl Menger. It is difficult to think of a parallel case where a work such as the Grundsätze has exercised a lasting and persistent influence but has yet, as a result of purely accidental circumstances, had so extremely restricted a circulation.

There can be no doubt among competent historians that if, during the last sixty years, the Austrian School has occupied an almost unique position in the development of economic science, this is entirely due to the foundations laid by this one man. The reputation of the School in the outside world and the development of its system at important points were due to the efforts of his brilliant followers, Eugen von Böhm-Bawerk and Friedrich von Wieser. But it is not unduly to detract from the merits of these writers to say that its fundamental ideas belong fully and wholly to Carl Menger. If he had not found these principles he might have remained comparatively unknown, might even have shared the fate of the many brilliant men who anticipated him and were forgotten, and almost certainly would for a long time have remained little known outside the countries of the German tongue. But what is common to the members of the Austrian School, what constitutes their peculiarity and provided the foundations for their later contributions is their acceptance of the teaching of Carl Menger.

The independent and practically simultaneous discovery of the principle of marginal utility by William Stanley Jevons, Carl Menger, and Léon Walras is too well known to require retelling. The year 1871, in which both Jevons’ Theory of Political Economy and Menger’s Grundsätze appeared, is now generally and with justice regarded as the beginning of the modern period in the development of economics. Jevons had outlined his fundamental ideas nine years earlier in a lecture (published in 1866) which, however, attracted little attention, and Walras began to publish his contribution only in 1874, but the complete independence of the work of the three founders is quite certain. And indeed, although their central positions, the point in their system to which they and their contemporaries naturally attached the greatest importance, are the same, their work is so clearly distinct in general character and background that the most interesting problem is really how so different routes should have led to such similar results.

To understand the intellectual background of the work of Carl Menger, a few words on the general position of economics at that time are required. Although the quarter of a century between about 1848, the date of J.S. Mill’s Principles , and the emergence of the new school saw in many ways the greatest triumphs of the classical political economy in the applied fields, its foundations, particularly its theory of value, had become more and more discredited. Perhaps the systematic exposition in J.S. Mill’s Principles itself, in spite or because of his complacent satisfaction about the perfected state of the theory of value, together with his later retractions on other essential points of the doctrine, did as much as anything else to show the deficiencies of the classical system. In any case, critical attacks and attempts at reconstruction multiplied in most countries.

Nowhere, however, had the decline of the classical school of economists been more rapid and complete than in Germany. Under the onslaughts of the Historical School not only were the classical doctrines completely abandoned — they had never taken very firm root in that part of the world — but any attempt at theoretical analysis came to be regarded with deep distrust. This was partly due to methodological considerations. But even more it was due to an intense dislike of the practical conclusions of the classical English School — which stood in the way of the reforming zeal of the new group which prided itself on the name of the“ethical school.”In England the progress of economic theory only stagnated. In Germany a second generation of historical economists grew up who had not only never become really acquainted with the one well-developed system of theory that existed, but had also learnt to regard theoretical speculations of any sort as useless if not positively harmful.

The doctrines of the classical school were probably too much discredited to provide a possible basis of reconstruction for those who were still interested in problems of theory. But there were elements in the writings of the German economists of the first half of the century which contained the germs for a possible new development.[2] One of the reasons why the classical doctrines had never firmly established themselves in Germany was that German economists had always remained conscious of certain contradictions inherent in any cost or labor theory of value. Owing, perhaps, partly to the influence of Condillac and other French and Italian authors of the eighteenth century a tradition had been kept alive which refused to separate value entirely from utility. From the early years of the century into the‘fifties and‘sixties a succession of writers, of whom Hermann was probably the outstanding and most influential figure (the wholly successful Gossen remaining unnoticed), tried to combine the ideas of utility and scarcity into an explanation of value, often coming very near to the solution provided by Menger. It is to these speculations, which to the more practical minds of the contemporary English economists must have appeared useless excursions into philosophy, that Menger owed most. A glance through the extensive footnotes in his Grundsätze , or the author’s index which has been added to the present edition, will show how extraordinarily wide a knowledge he possessed of these German authors and also of the French and Italian writers, and how small a role the writers of the classical English school plays in comparison.

But while Menger probably surpassed all his fellow-founders of the marginal utility doctrine in the width of his knowledge of the literature — and only from a passionate book collector inspired by the example of the encyclopaedic Roscher could one expect a similar knowledge at the early age the Grundsätze was written — there are curious gaps in the list of authors to whom he refers which go far to explain the difference of his approach from that of Jevons and Walras.[3] Particularly significant is his apparent ignorance, at the time when he wrote the Grundsätze , of the work of Cournot, to whom all the other founders of modern economics, Walras, Marshall, and very possibly Jevons,[4] seem to have been directly or indirectly indebted. Even more surprising, however, is the fact that at that time Menger does not seem to have known the work of von Thünen, which one would have expected him to find particularly congenial. While it can be said, therefore, that he worked in an atmosphere distinctly favourable to an analysis on utility lines, he had nothing so definite on which to build a modern theory of price as his fellows in the same field, all of whom came under the influence of Cournot, to which must be added, in the case of Walras, that of Dupuit[5] and, in the case of Marshall, that of von Thünen.

 Continue reading. Footnotes are in the original article at Mises.org. 
 Leave a Comment September 7, 2011 
 The unintended consequences of the minimum wage 
 
Art Carden writes about the minimum wage and“the forgotten man” :
 
Popular treatments of the minimum wage point to Wanda Washerwoman and declare the policy a success because she now earns higher wages than she used to. If we focus solely on Wanda and ignore how the policy affects Helen Housekeeper and David Dishwasher, we aren’t telling the complete story and will likely enact policies that oppress the poor.
 
In other words, the minimum wage can help some people, but at the same time, it can hurt others. Those who are hurt by it are usually forgotten by the supporters of the minimum wage laws. This is a good example of the importance of looking on both seen and unseen effects .

Carden also makes interesting point when he says that “the workers who now earn higher wages might be worse off, too” . He explains:
 
First, higher wages can be made up for on other margins because there is a lot more to a labor contract than wages. Wanda has higher wages, but she might end up working in a less attractive environment (no AC, perhaps, or less-than-diligent floor workplace maintenance, or less safety equipment, or fewer bathroom breaks, or…) and her schedule is less flexible. Perhaps she has to put up with more sexual harassment (overt or covert). If she doesn’t like this, there might three other people who applied for her job who are willing to put up with it.
 Leave a Comment August 22, 2011 
 Human Action quotes–Chapters I-IV 
 
Assorted quotes from Mises’s Human Action, from Introduction and Chapters I–IV.

 Introduction 

 Praxeology – Theory of Human Action 
 On Criticism 
 Economics as a Theoretical Science 

 Chapter I 

Section 1. Purposeful Action and Animal Reaction
 Praxeology – the Science of Human Action 

Section 2. The Prerequisites of Human Action
 The Prerequisites of Human Action 
 On Praxeology 

Section 4. Rationality and Irrationality; Subjectivism and Objectivity of Praxeological Research
 The Object of Praxeology 

 Chapter II 

Section 1. Praxeology and History
 On Praxeology 

Section 3. The A Priori and Reality
 The A Priori and Reality 

Section 4. The Principle of Methodological Individualism
 The Principle of Methodological Individualism 

Section 5. The Principle of Methodological Singularism
 The Principle of Methodological Singularism 

 Chapter IV. 

Section 1. End and Means
 Subject of Economics 

Section 2. The Scale of Value
 Scale of Values 
 Judgment of Ends 
 Value is not in things 
 Leave a Comment «Older Entries 
 
Categories

 Articles (14) Books (5) Comments (7) Economy (1) Quotes (26) Uncategorized (1) 
 
Recent Posts

 I Want to be a Consumer, a Poem by Patrick Barrington Value is subjective Frank Shostak: What is Wrong With Econometrics? Gold vs. Paper The Genius of Carl Menger, by F. A. Hayek The unintended consequences of the minimum wage Human Action quotes–Chapters I-IV Who is responsible for inflation? 
 
Archives

 February 2012  (1) January 2012  (1) December 2011  (1) November 2011  (1) October 2011  (1) September 2011  (1) August 2011  (1) July 2011  (1) June 2011  (1) May 2011  (1) April 2011  (2) March 2011  (1) February 2011  (3) January 2011  (4) December 2010  (8) October 2010  (2) September 2010  (5) August 2010  (4) July 2010  (4) June 2010  (4) 
 
Tags
 Action Action and Reason Articles Austrian Economics Austrian School of Economics Basic Economics Calculated Risk Blog Carl Menger Criticism Definition of Economics Economics Economics for Real People Economic Theory Eugen von Böhm-Bawerk Frédéric Bastiat Gene Callahan Henry Hazlitt Human Action Inflation Late Scholastics Ludwig von Mises Means and Ends Methodological Individualism Methodological Singularism Milton Friedman Minimum Wage Mises.org Object of Praxeology Praxeology Praxeology vs. Psychology QE2 Quantitative Easing Quotes Recession Review of Human Action Robert P. Murphy Scope of Praxeology State Study Guide to Human Action Study of Economics Subjective value The Freeman The Mises Review US Economy US Unemployment 
Links

 Consulting by R.P.Murphy Economic Policy Journal Mises Institute–Literature 
 
 
Subscribe to RSS Feed

 RSS - Posts 
 
 Study of Economics Blog at WordPress.com .
 Theme: Titan . 
 Blog at WordPress.com . | Theme: Titan by The Theme Foundry .
 Follow 
 Follow“Study of Economics” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com Add your thoughts here... (optional) Post to or Cancel
	</body>
</document>
