<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001001" url="http://www.ble272.org/RULE_archive.htm" time="2012-07-12-16:24" support="19" score="0.027236807616284546" bingtitle="1997 Norac Rules Study Guide - Safari" webtitle="1997 Norac Rules Study Guide">
			<query id="000794" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="001422" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="001391" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="001170" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000262" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000387" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000105" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000951" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000294" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000355" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="000920" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="000542" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000168" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="001516" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000417" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000448" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="001297" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000042" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="001108" bing-rank="190"/>
	<description>Prior to passing a fast food restaurant. 2. Prior to arriving at ... also have a line 13 indicating the Bulletin Order number ... If a fixed signal is absent from the place where ...</description>
	<body>
		2009 Norac Rules Study Guide Archive 
 Definitions: 
  Home Signal 
   1. A fixed signal governing the entrance to an automatic block.
 2. A fixed signal governing the entrance to an interlocking or controlled
 3. A signal from your wife/girlfriend that it is okay to come home.
 4. A fixed signal governing the approach to an interlocking signal. 
 Bolt-lock Switch: 
1. A hand-operated switch equipped with a pipe connected locking device
that is operated by unscrewing a bolt before the switch is thrown.
2. A hand operated switch that is unlocked by turning a bolt on the
switch mechanism.
3. A remotely controlled switch that is operated by a complex system
of bolts and levers designed to test the mechanical aptitude of the employee.
4. A hand-operated switch equipped with a pipe connected locking device
that is designed to shunt the signal system before the switch points are
operated. 

 Rule A Required Books: 
 Employees must maintain and have on them 
while on duty a copy of the following:
 1. The Operating Rules, Timetable, and Air Brake Instructions if their 
duties are affected by them, the Safety Rules of their department, and the 
Hazardous Materials instructions if they are involved in the shipment of 
Hazardous materials.
2. A copy of the latest crossword puzzle.
3. A copy of the CFR 49.
4. All of the above. 
 Rule C, Required Examinations: 
 Employees whose job requires them to be qualified on the Operating Rules and 
Timetable must:
 1. Pass the required exams.
2. Memorize all the Operating Rules and Timetable Special Instructions.
3. Memorize only those Operating Rules and Timetable Instructions that are on 
the test. 
4. Memorize the&quot;Rule of the Day&quot;. 
 
 Employees will be given a written exam and must obtain a score of at 
least:
 1. 23%
2. 50%
3. 75%
4. 85% 
 When reporting 
for the examination employees must:
 1. Wear steel toes work boots and safety glasses.
2. Bring their keys to the examination.
3. Bring a white envelope with the appropriate amount of cash for the examiner.
4. Present their Operating Rules book, Timetable and other instructions for 
inspection.
  
Employees who fail this examination:
 1. Will be dismissed from service.
2. Will have to take a second examination within thirty (30) days.
3. Will be required to stay after class to take a reexamination.
4. Will lose their craft seniority.
 
 Employees who fail the second examination:
 1. Will be terminated.
2. Will be publicly ridiculed by the examiner.
3. Will not be qualified to perform service.
4. Will be promoted to management. 
 When an employee passes a physical characteristics examination:
 1. The employee should go out an get drunk.
2. The employee should run home and tell mommy.
3. The territory on which the employee is qualified must be shown on the&quot;Qualification for Service&quot;page of the employee&apos;s Timetable, if provided.
4. None of the above. 
 Rule D 
Employee Conduct: 
 While on 
duty employees must devote themselves exclusively:
 1. Picking up girls on the concourse.
2. Playing cards in the employee lounge.
3. Getting out of a middle trip.
4. The Company&apos;s service.

 They must render every assistance in their power in: 
1. Picking up girls on the concourse.
2. Helping other employees skip their middle trip.
3. Carrying out the rules and special instructions and properly report any 
violation to the proper official.
4. Helping little old ladies across busy intersections.  
 To remain in service, employees must:
 1. Refrain from conduct that adversely affects the performance of their 
duties, other employees, or the public.
2. Refrain from conduct that benefits the company if it embarrasses their 
supervisors.
3. Refrain from conduct that would bring credit upon the company if they 
don&apos;t get overtime rate.
4. Look out for themselves first and not worry about other employees, 
especially ones with less seniority.

 Acts of insubordination, hostility, or willful disregard of the 
Company&apos;s interest:
 1. Are prohibited.
2. Are good for at least three hours overtime.
3. Will require carrying a pen the next time the employee picks up their 
mail.
4. Will be cheered by other employees. 
 Rule E, Prohibited behavior: 
 Which of the following behaviors are prohibited while on duty or
on company property: 
1. Doing a good job.
2. Gambling, fighting or participating in any illegal immoral, or unauthorized
activity.
3. Failing to operate a train on time.
4. Operating safely if it costs the company money or interferes with
the on time performance of a train. 
   Which of the following behaviors are prohibited when required
to perform service: 
1. Sleeping or assuming the attitude of sleep.
2. Having or using electronic devices not related to their duties,
unless authorized by the railroad.
3. Card playing or reading other than Company instructions.
4. Solicitation of gratuities from patrons.
5. All of the above.
 
Rule F, Reporting 
Unusual Conditions: 
 Derailments, collisions, storms, high 
water, fires, obstructions to tracks, and any other condition which could 
result in death or injury, damage to property or disruption of railroad 
operations:
 1. Must be reported to the Dispatcher as soon as convenient.
2. Must be reported to the Dispatcher by the quickest means of 
communication.
3. Must be reported on the conductor&apos;s 1021 form.
4. Can be ignored if the unusual occurrence does not involve the crew&apos;s 
train. 

 Rule L, Protecting Company Affairs and Property: 
 The divulging of the Company&apos;s 
business affairs to other than those authorized to receive such information:
 1. Is encouraged.
2. Is guaranteed under the First Amendment.
3. Is prohibited.
4. Is protected under the state&apos;s Whistle Blower Law. 

 Company property must:
 1. Be sold on ebay.
2. Be protected.
3. Be stolen then sold back to the Company.
4 Be stolen then sold at a Flea Market or Train Show.. 
 The abuse, misuse, defacing, deliberately damaging 
or destroying of Company property, tools, or equipment is:
 1. Encouraged.
2. Not a concern if done by management personell.
3. Prohibited.
4. Can be a lot of fun. 
 Employees must key 
switch keys:
 1. In secure places and not allow unqualified or unauthorized persons to use 
or gain possession of these keys.
2. And steal all they can get and sell them at train shows.
3. And start a collection to display on their den wall.
4. And melt them down into ingots.

 The unauthorized possession, removal, or disposal of any material from 
railroad property or property served by the railroad:
 1. Is okay if it is done by management.
2. Is prohibited.
3. Is okay if the profits from it&apos;s sale is shared with management.
4. Is frowned upon but generally ignored. 
 Unauthorized persons must not:
 1. Be allowed on Company property or equipment at any time.
2. Run trains on Main Tracks.
3. Collect tickets unless they are in full uniform.
4. Take promotion to management. 
 Rule N, Complying with rules, Orders,
and Instructions: 
 Employees on duty on any division or
railroad must:
 1. Comply with the rules of their home
division or railroad.
2. Be very, very careful.
3. Be personally supervised by management of that
division or railroad.
4. Comply with the orders and instructions
of that division or railroad, unless otherwise directed.
 
Rule Q, Hours of Service: 
 Employees subject to the Hours of Service
Act must:
 1. Carry a copy of the Hours of Service
Act with them at all times.
2. Familiarize themselves with the Act
and comply with it&apos;s requirements.
3. Not exceed the maximum hours permitted
by law unless authorized by the Dispatcher.
4. #2 and #3. 
 An employees who is called to report
for duty before his legal rest has expired:
 1. Can work the maximum hours permitted
by law if he wants.
2. Can refuse to work.
3. Must report that fact to the person
ordering him to report.
4. Can only work a maximum of two hours. 
 Train and engine crews must notify the
appropriate Dispatcher or other designated supervisor:
 1. When they are tired and want to go
home.
2. When they want to go to lunch.
3. Three (3) hours before their legal rest
expires unless they will be able to complete their assignment before their
legal work period expires.
4. Before they expire. 
 Rule R, Injuries on Railroad Property:

 Initial medical assistance:
 1. Is inconvenient and will be delayed as necessary.
2. Is expensive for the Company so the injured person must take themselves to a 
free standing medical facility.
3. Will be covered by the injured person&apos;s private medical insurance.
4. Should be afforded to all persons injured on railroad property.

 A report of such occurrences must be made:
 1. Before the employ involved goes off duty.
2. Before the bill is received from the medical facility involved.
3. Promptly to the designated officer followed by a full written report on the 
prescribed form.
4. Need not be made if the injury is not life threatening. 
 When persons are injured by appliances on engines or 
cars, or by tools or machinery, such equipment:
 1. Must be destroyed on location.
2. Must be placed back in service as soon as the blood and tissue are removed.
3. Must be immediately inspected and removed from service if defective.
4. Must be painted red to remind users to be careful around such equipment. 
 Rule U, Reporting Medical Conditions: 

 Employees must notify the company medical 
officer of:
 1. Any condition not already on record with the railroad.
2. Any medical problem that might affect the employee&apos;s ability to go to work.
3. Any condition that might cause incontinence.
4. No matter what condition your condition is in.
5. Numbers 1 and 2. 

 This notification must be made:
 1. Before reporting for work.
2. Before getting up in the morning.
3. Immediately upon finishing your tour of duty.
4. Immediately upon the employee receiving knowledge of the condition. 

 Rule 1 General Orders, Bulletin 
Orders, Division Notices: 
 When reporting for duty, employees whose duties are affected by General 
Orders, Bulletin Orders, and Division Notices must:
 1. Familiarize themselves with the employee&apos;s parking facilities.
2. Familiarize themselves with the quickest way out of the parking lot.
3. Familiarize themselves with, and must comply with, those instructions 
pertaining to any portions of the territory on which they are qualified and 
ordered to operate.
4. Make sure they have enough money to buy lunch or bring their lunch with 
them when reporting for duty.

 At locations specified in the Timetable employees reporting for duty 
must examine the Bulletin Board:
 1. Then they can go back home.
2. Endorse their paychecks and go to the bank.
3. Leave for breakfast.
4. Sign the employee&apos;s register 
 An 
employee must contact the Dispatcher if:
 1. He does not have a copy of the current information affecting the 
movement of his train or he reports for duty at a location where no 
employee&apos;s register is located.
2. He is confused about where he is.
3. He has less than twelve hour to work.
4. He forgot his lunch.

 The Dispatcher must inform the employee:
 1. Of the best places to get breakfast.
2. Which stations his train can pass without stopping.
3. Of all information affecting the movement of his train.
4. Of the hours the Dispatcher has left to work that shift.  
 When a Bulletin Order or Division Notice 
is issued after the summary:
 1. The engineer is not responsible for it&apos;s content.
2. A designated employee assigned to the Dispatcher&apos;s office must ensure 
that such information is properly posted at each Bulletin Board location.
3. The Conductor must contact the Dispatcher to learn it&apos;s affect on his 
train.
4. The engineer can blame the conductor for not informing the engineer of 
the contents of the Bulletin Order or Division Notice. 
 Rule 13, Hand Signals:

 Hand signals must be given:
 1. From a point somewhere on railroad property.
2. From a point where they may be plainly seen, in a manner that can be 
understood and in sufficiently ahead of time to permit the train to comply.. 
 3. From the point of the move.
4. From a point where the crewmen can stay comfortable. 
 Movement must be stopped:
 1. When it is time for lunch.
2. When the crewmen&apos;s arms get tired. 
 3. When there is doubt concerning the meaning of the signal or for whom the 
signal is intended.
4. The signal disappears from view.  
 5. 3 and 4. 
 Any 
object waved violently by anyone on or near the track:
 1. Means it is time to check you out-of-service insurance.
2. Means it is time to close the cab windows to avoid being struck by a thrown 
object.
3. Is a signal to stop.
4. All of the above. 
 If 
a train has one unit:
 1. It is terribly under powered.
2. Signals to the engineer must be given according to the way the unit is 
headed.
3. Signals are given according to the way the crewman is facing.
4. Signals cannot be given except be radio. 
 If a train has more than one 
engine and they are faced in opposite directions:
 1. No signals can be given by hand.
2. The crewman is certain to be confused.
3. No movement will be made until the Conductor has an understanding with his 
crew.
4. The train is terribly over powered and one engine must be removed from the 
consist. 
 Rule 16; Blue signal protection of workers: 
 Blue Signal rules provide for the protection of:
 1. Railroad workmen who work on, under, or between equipment.
2. All railroad employees.
3. Only employees represented by a collective bargaining unit.
4. The railroad from frivolous lawsuits. 
 Train and engine service employees are excluded from Blue Signal
protection:
 1. Because nobody cares if they get hurt.
2. They never leave the safety and warmth of the train.
3. They do not need protection since they are always asleep.
4. Except when assigned to perform work on equipment that is not part
of the movement that they have been called to operate. 
 Once a Blue Signal is displayed:
 1. Equipment must not be coupled to or moved
2. Other equipment must not be placed on the same track so as to reduce
or block the view of a Blue Signal.
3. Equipment must not pass a displayed Blue Signal.
4. All of the above 
 An employee, under the direction of the employee in charge of the
workmen may reposition equipment in an engine servicing track area or car
shop repair area when:
 1. Employees have been informed of the move.
2. Blue Signal have been removed from the equipment to be repositioned
or coupled.
3. Employee receives permission from the Yardmaster.
4. #1 and #2. 
 Blue Signals may only be removed by:
 1. A person of the same group or craft that displayed them after 
all the workmen are clear.
2. The workmen moving the equipment.
3. The Yardmaster or his representative.
4. Anyone who wants the equipment moved. 
 When equipment to be worked on is on a track other than a main track
or controlled siding workmen must:
 1. Attach a Blue Signal to the controlling engine(s) at a location
where it will be clearly visible to an employee at the controls of that
engine.
2. Line each hand operated switch providing access to the track against
movement to the track and lock each switch with an effective locking device.
3. Display a Blue Signal at each hand operated switch effected.
4. All of the above.
5. None of the above. 
 A derail locked in a derailing position with an effective locking
device:
 1. Is not a substitute for a switch with an effective locking device.
2. May substitute for the hand operated switch requirement.
3. Must be used in addition to the hand operated switch requirement.
4. Must be placed on both sides of the equipment to be protected. 
 If the equipment to be protected is on a main track or controlled
siding:
 1. Display a Blue Signal at each end of the equipment.
2. Hang a Blue Signal from the employee&apos;s belt so that they will be
protected wherever they work.
3. Attach a Blue Signal to the controlling engine(s) at a location
where it will be clearly visible to an employee at the controls of that
engine.
4. 1 and 3. 
 When emergency work is to be done on rolling equipment and no Blue
Signal is available:
 1. The conductor must be notified.
2. The engineer must be given a Form D.
3. The engineer must be notified.
4. A blue flag must be used under all conditions. 
 When an engineer is notified of work being done on his train, he
must:
 1. Apply the brakes and stay in the locomotive until all work is 
completed..
2. Apply the brakes, put the reverser in neutral, and leave the field
generator or control switch open.
3. Shut the engines down.
4. Observe the work being done.

 The engineer must maintain this protection until:
 1. He is relieved or has to relieve himself.
2. He gets tired and falls asleep.
3. The employee who requested the it that the protection is no longer
needed notifies him.
4. None of the above.

 Rule 19 Horn Failure: 
 If the engine whistles or horns fail 
enroute, the engineer must take the following actions:
 1. Notify the Dispatcher as soon as practical and ring the bell 
continuously, if equipped.
2. Approach public crossings at grade prepared to stop.
3. Reduce speed to not exceeding 30 mph while approaching locations where 
employees are known to be working.
4. Reduce speed at other locations where warranted by the prevailing 
conditions.
5. All of the above. 
 Rule 19b(2) Approaching locations where roadway workers may be at work 
on tracks, bridges, and other points: 
 The engineer must sound the horn as 
follows:
 1. o o o o = four short whistles.
2. - - - - = four long whistles.
3. - - o - = two longs, a short and a long.
4. o o - o = Two shorts \, a long and a short. 
 Rule 20 
Engine bell: 
 If a train is 
equipped with a bell, it must be sounded:
1. Continuously.
2. When the engine is about to move and when running through tunnels, 
approaching public crossings at grade or locations where Roadway Workers 
may be at work on tracks, bridges, and other points.
3. When passing a train on an adjacent track or in an emergency.
4 Numbers 2 and 3. 
 Rule 21, Communicating Signal appliances: 
 &quot;---&quot; 
1. When running, stop at once.
2. When running, start jogging.
3. When running, stop at the next station.
4. When running, back up at once. 
 &quot;---&quot; 
1. When standing, proceed.
2. When running, back up.
3. When standing, apply or release brakes.
4. When standing, call the Dispatcher. 
 &quot;00&quot; 
1. When standing, back up.
2. When running, stop at the next station.
3. When standing, start.
4. When running, back up. 
 &quot;000&quot; 
1. When running, back up.
2. When standing, start.
3. When running, stop at once.
4. When standing, back up. When running, stop at the next passenger
station. 
 &quot;0000&quot; 
1. When standing, brakes have applied and released on rear car, brake
test complete.
2. When standing, brakes have applied on the head car; brakeman is
too lazy to walk to the rear of the train.
3. When standing, brake test is complete even though no one has checked
the operation of the brakes.
4. When standing, the brakes are working, &quot;trust us&quot;. 
 &quot;0&quot; 
1. Train crewman has hit the communicating buzzer instead of the door
button.
2. Incomplete signal to proceed.
3. Incomplete signal to back up.
4. When spotting, switching, or making up trains, prepare to stop. 
 Rule 22, Engine Lights:

 The headlight facing the direction of movement on every train and 
engine must:
 1. Be dimmed when running though tunnels.
2. Be turn on only when another train is approaching in the opposite 
direction.
3. Be displayed brightly by day and night.
4. Be aimed upward above the trees. 
 The headlight must be dimmed:
 1. When standing or passing through yards where other engines are 
working.
2. When approaching a station where a Form D is to be received.
3. When approaching Junctions or terminals.
4. When standing or moving on a main track at meeting points or when 
standing or approaching another train in multiple track territory.
5. All of the above. 
 When 
approaching or passing over a crossing:
 1. The headlight must be dimmed.
2. The headlight must not be dimmed.
3. The headlight may be dimmed.
4. The headlight must be turned on and off rapidly to warn motorists 
of the approaching train. 
 If all 
headlight bulbs fail enroute the engineer must:
 1. Stop the train immediately and not move it until the headlights are 
fixed.
2. Illuminate all external lights and notify the Dispatcher.
3. Ring the bell continuously.
4. Sound the engine whistle or horn frequently.
5. Numbers 2, 3, and 4. 
 Auxiliary Lights:

Engines that operate over crossings at speeds greater than 20 MPH:
 1. Must be equipped with speed control.
2. Must be equipped with Epic Brakes.
3. Must be coupled to a train.
4. Must be equipped with auxiliary lights.

 Auxiliary lights consist of:
 1. Flashing strobe likes mounted on the cab roof.
2. A high intensity flashlight carried by the engineer.
3. Two ditch lights, two crossing lights, or one oscillating light.
4. Two lights which move in such a way as to blind motorist on both sides of the 
crossing.

 Auxiliary lights are considered operative when:
 1. They illuminate after the engine horn and/or bell is sounded or the 
auxiliary light switch is activated.
2. They illuminate after the engine has passed the crossing.
3. They are aimed so as to blind oncoming engineers.
4. All of the above.

 Auxiliary lights must be operational:
 1. Before the engine arrives at the first grade crossing.
2. When the engine goes in for it&apos;s 92 day inspection.
3. Whenever the mechanical department gets around to it.
4. Before the engine leaves it&apos;s initial terminal. 
 Rule 24, Markers: 
 Passenger trains, lite engines, and engines 
operating on the rear of a train must:
 1. Be running at all times.
2. Be equipped with an illuminating marker or rear headlight on low beam at 
all times.
3. Must have a conductor on the rear end dropping fusees every half mile.
4. Must be in constant communications with other trains to avoid a 
collision. 
 Trains other than 
passenger trains:
 1. Do not need a lighted marker at any time. 
2. Must be equipped with a lighted marker from one hour before sunset to 
one hour after sunrise.
3. Must be equipped with a lighted marker when visibility is so restricted 
that the end silhouette of a box car cannot be seen from one half mile on 
straight track.
4. Numbers 2 and 3. 
 During periods 
other than described above:
 1. No marker is required.
2. Trains must be operated very carefully.
3. A reflector, flag, or extinguished marker may be used.
4. The Dispatcher must be notified so that he may put a block on behind the 
train.

 When an illuminating marker is required en route:
 1. It must be tested one half hour before use so as not to drain the 
battery.
2. It must be tested before it leaves it&apos;s initial terminal.
3. It need not be tested if it was tested at the factory.
4. It must be tested during it&apos;s 92 day inspection. 
 If the marker fails en route:
 1. The train must stop and not move until the marker is fixed and the 
Dispatcher notified.
2. The train can continue to the next point where the marker can be 
repaired. The Dispatcher must be notified as soon as practical.
3. The train can continue to it&apos;s final destination. Nothing further is 
required.
4. All of the above. 
 Rule 30 
Tampering with Appliances and other equipment 
 Employees are prohibited from:
 1. Taking the day off when the weather is good.
2. Taking the day off when the weather is bad.
3. Breaking seals on interlocking appliances and other equipment or 
altering, nullifying or in any manner restricting or interfering with the 
normal function of any device or equipment on engines, cars, or other 
railroad property, except when specifically authorized to do so.
4. Picking up girls on the concourse. 
 In the case of failure or where seals are 
found to be tampered with, broken, missing, or authorized to be removed:
 1. A report must be made to the Dispatcher, Yardmaster, or enginehouse 
Foreman in charge of the territory where the defect is discovered.
2. The engine cannot be moved until the defect is corrected.
3. The engineer will be blamed.
4. The engineer will blame the mechanical person who signed the daily 
inspection report. 
 Rule 70 
Inspection before departure: 
 Conductors and engineers must know that the cars and engines in the 
train:
 1. Have the proper number of wheels.
2. Have the proper reporting marks.
3. Have been inspected.
4. Have flanged wheels. 
 At points 
where cars that are to be picked up have not been inspected by a car 
inspector:
 1. Train crews cannot pick up the cars until inspected by a car 
inspector.
2. Trains crews cannot couple the cars onto the hind end of the train.
3. Train crews must determine that they are safe for movement.
4. Trains crews must call the Dispatcher for instructions.

 Crew members must insure that:
 1. They have had lunch before inspecting the cars.
2. They have adequate waste and car oil prior to inspecting cars.
3. They are well rested before inspecting the cars.
4. Required brake tests are performed on all cars and engines. 
 Freight cars that are picked up en route 
that are safe for movement and placarded with bad order cards:
 1. May not be moved without permission of the Yardmaster.
2. May not be moved until repaired.
3. May be forwarded to the point where repairs will be made.
4. May be forwarded to the customer before repairs are made. 
 All crew members must be:
 1. Informed of the presence of a defective car in the train and any 
movement restrictions shown on the bad order card.
2. Kept as far away from a bad order car as possible.
3. Qualified to repair a bad order car before movement.
4. Well fed before moving a bad order car because it can take a long 
time to get to a point where repairs can be made.  
 Rule 72 Inspection of moving trains: 
 Employees must observe passing trains for:
 1. Sleeping engineers.
2. Defects and display of headlights, markers, and auxiliary lights.
3. The first three cars then they don&apos;t have to observe the train any more.
4. As long as they want.

 The improper display of headlights, markers, and auxiliary lights must:
 1. Be reported to the train and the Dispatcher.
2. Be reported to the newspapers.
3. Be reported at the final terminal.
4. Be reported when signing up for the next work day. 
 If attention is called to a dangerous 
condition, the train: 
 1. Can continue to the next point where repairs can be made.
2. Can continue if the Conductor feels the defects are not life 
threatening.
3. Can continue if the speed of the train is reduced to 30 mph.
4. Must be promptly stopped consistent with good train handling techniques, 
and inspection made and the Dispatcher notified. 
 Crew members must:
 1. Frequently observe both sides of their train while moving looking 
for hand signals and other indications of defects in their train and track.
2. Get a good night&apos;s sleep before reporting for duty.
3. Observe all major holidays.
4. Bring enough cold beverages to last the entire trip. 
 When practical crew members on moving 
trains:
 1. Must stop for lunch.
2. Must Be well rested.
3. Must have a comfortable seat.
4. Must be in a position to inspect passing trains. 
 Rule 90, Delay of trains:

 Employees must not: 
 1. Jump off tall buildings while on company property.
2. Pass gas in public.
3. Date the Conductor.
4. Unnecessarily delay trains. 

 Employees who know of a condition that will delay a train or prevent it 
from making Normal Speed:
 1. Must remove or correct that condition.
2. Must stop all trains until the condition is resolved.
3. Must contact the employee in charge of the condition.
4. Must advise the Dispatcher. 

 When a train is delayed:
 1. The crew must determine the cause as soon as the safety of their 
train will permit.
2. The crew must send the brakeman for coffee.
3. The crew must have lunch.
4. The crew must take a power nap.
 
The Dispatcher or Operator must be notified of the delay: 
1. When the crew returns from lunch.
2. When the train reaches it final terminal.
3. When the Conductor submits his 1021 form.
4. As soon as practical. 

 Rule 91, Starting a Train: 

 A train must not start until:
1. The engineer has finished his lunch.
2. The engineer receives verbal authority from the Dispatcher.
3. The Conductor has given or authorized the proper hand signal, communicating 
signal, or permission by voice authority.
4. All of the above. 

 Rule 94, Responsibilities
of Employees: Signals and Restrictions: 
 
Employees qualified on the operating rules and located on the leading
engine or car must: 
1. Be on the lookout for bars and restaurants along side the track.
2. May sleep as long as the engineer promises to stay awake.
3. Be on the lookout for signals affecting the movement of their train.
4. Not do the daily crossword puzzle if the train is moving.
 
Employees qualified on the operating rules and located on the leading
engine or car must: 
1. Communicate to each other in a clear manner their lunch order.
2. Must communicate to each other in a clear manner their plans for the weekend.
3. Must communicate to each other in a clear manner the latest sports scores.
4. Must communicate to each other in a clear manner the name of each signal
as soon as it becomes clearly visible.
 

 After the name of each signal has been communicated: 
1. The employee may go back to sleep.
2. The employee may continue reading the paper.
3. The employee may return to his crossword puzzle.
4. The employee must observe it until passed. 

 Any change in the signal: 
1. Can be ignored if the signal&apos;s original aspect was clearly seen and communicated
to others in the cab or leading car.
2. Can be ignored if the preceding signal was a signal to proceed.
3. Must be communicated in the required manner.
4. Must be communicated in the required manner only if it is a Stop signal.
 

 When a train reaches a point 2 miles from a temporary speed restriction: 
1. Employees qualified on physical characteristics and located on the leading
engine or car must immediately communicate with the engineer and confirm
the requirements of the restriction.
2. Employees qualified on physical characteristics and located on the leading 
engine or car must immediately communicate with the engineer and then jump
off the leading engine or cars.
3. Employees qualified on physical characteristics and located on the leading 
engine or car must immediately communicate with the engineer screaming. &quot;Danger,
Danger, Danger&quot;.
4. Employees qualified on physical characteristics and located on the
leading engine or car must immediately communicate with the engineer then
fall back to sleep. 

 If a train is not operated in accordance with the requirements of a
signal indication or speed restriction: 
1. Qualified employees on the leading engine or car must jump for their lives.
2. Qualified employees on the leading engine or car must communicate with
the engineer immediately and if necessary, stop the train.
3. Qualified employees on the leading engine or car can ignore the problem
if the engineer is senior to them.
4. Qualified employees on the leading engine or car can ignore the
problem if the engineer is, or was, a member of management.
 

 Calling Signals on Push Pull Trains without cab signals for the
direction of movement in territory where the speed limits exceeds 30 MPH: 
 
When a wayside signal affecting the movement of the train displays
an Approach, Medium Approach, Slow Approach, Restricting, or Stop and Proceed
aspect: 
1. The engineer can ignore the signal if he passed the NORAC rules test within
the previous nine months.
2. The engineer must communicate the signal to the Dispatcher so he can display
a more favorable aspect.
3. The engineer must communicate to a road Foreman the name and location
of each signal.
4. The engineer must communicate to a qualified employee on the engine or
train the name and location of each signal as soon as the signal becomes
clearly visible.
 

 When in multiple track territory: 
1. The trainmen can become confused.
2. The engineer can become confused.
3. Everyone can become confused.
4. The engineer must include the track number.
 

 The qualified employee:
 1. Can ignore the engineer.
2. Must repeat the signal information in Spanish to exercise his language
skills.
3. Must repeat the signal information to the engineer.
4. Can ignore the engineer if he is busy with a passenger.
 

 If the qualified employee fails to repeat the required signal information: 
1. The engineer must &quot;dump&quot; the train.
2. The engineer must call the Dispatcher and complain about the qualified
employee.
3. The railroad must initiate termination proceedings against the qualified
employee.
4. The engineer must determine the reason at the next station stop.
 

 If the engineer fails to properly control the speed of the train: 
1. The qualified employee must save himself by jumping off the train.
2. The railroad must initiate termination proceedings against the engineer.
3. The qualified employee must notify the Dispatcher immediately and complain
about the engineer.
4. The qualified employee must immediately communicate with the engineer
and, if necessary, stop the train. 

 The next signal, when more favorable: 
1. Can be ignored.
2. Must also be communicated by the engineer.
3. Can be ignored if the last signal was a signal to proceed.
4. All of the above. 
 Rule 100 
Coupling or switching passenger equipment or occupied camp cars: 

 A stop must be made:
 1. Prior to passing a fast food restaurant.
2. Prior to arriving at the signup location.
3. Prior to coupling passenger equipment.
4. To rest before continuing work if the crew has been on duty more than 1 
hour.

 All coupling must be made:
 1. At a speed not exceeding 20 mph.
2. At a speed not exceeding Medium speed.
3. At a speed not exceeding Full speed.
4. At a speed not exceeding 4 mph. 

 Equipment with spear-type couplers must 
be coupled at a speed not to exceed:
 1. Ramming speed. 
 2. Full speed. 
 3. Medium speed. 
 4. 2 mph. 

 Passenger equipment with continuous 
buffer plates:
 1. Should not be used for a buffet diner.
2. Should not be coupled to a locomotive. 
 3. Should not be coupled to freight cars. 
 4. Should not be coupled to freight cars with coupler release levers 
with a center projecting arm. 

 When switching passenger equipment or occupied camp cars:
 1. The crew must be very, very careful.
2. The crew must make sure all occupants have their seat belts fastened.
3. The crew must make sure all air hoses are uncoupled.
4. The engine and cars must not be detached until the equipment is stopped.

 Curtains and electric jumpers:
 1. Must be connected before the cars are separated.
2. Must be disconnected before the cars are separated.
3. Must be connected to the cars before the cars are separated.
4. All of the above. 

 Rule 101, Coupling, Shoving, or Switching Cars: 

 When coupling, shoving, or switching cars, precaution must be taken: 
1. To assure that the crew does not become tired.
2. To assure that all cars are lined up in ascending numerical order.
3. To prevent damage or fouling other tracks
4. To assure that as little work as possible is actually accomplished. 

 Employees must insure that :
 1. They have had sufficient rest before making the move.
2. They are well fed.
3. That there is sufficient room in the track to hold the cars.
4. That they have communicated their intentions to their Union 
representative. so
he can prepare their defense. 

 Rule 101, Coupling, shoving, or switching cars: 
 When coupling, shoving, or switching cars: 
1. Be very, very careful.
2. Precautions must be taken to avoid damage and fouling other tracks.
3. Employees must confirm that there is sufficient room in the track
to hold the cars.
4. #2 and #3. 
 Rule 108 Unattended engine: 
 An engine must not be left unattended:
 1. Ever.
2. Unless the air and hand brakes are applied.
3. The reverser is removed (or locked in the neutral position) from all 
control stands on all units of the engine.
4. The controls, switches, and circuit breakers are positioned so 
that traction power cannot be developed.
5. All of the above. 
 Rule 109, Hand brakes: 
 On cars or drafts of cars left standing:
 1. A sufficient number of hand brakes
must be applied on cars to make them secure when left standing on any track.
2. If necessary, car wheels must be blocked.
3. All hand brakes must be applied.
4. Numbers 1 and 2. 
 When hand brakes are used to control
movement:
 1. It must be determined that these brakes
are working properly.
2. The hand brake must be on the leading
end of the movement.
3. A minimum of two hand brakes must be
used to control the movement of more than one car.
4. Hand brakes cannot be used to control
the movement of cars without an engine coupled to them. 
 Rule 116, Operating train from other
than leading end: 
 When an engineer operates the train
from other than the leading end of the movement:
 1. He must be sure he has out of service
insurance.
2. He must go very, very slowly.
3. A crew member must be stationed on
the leading end of the movement.
4. An engineer cannot operate a train
from other than the leading end. 
 The crew member on the leading end of
the movement:
 1. Must be qualified on the physical characteristics
of the territory involved.
2. Does not have to be qualified on the
physical characteristics of the territory involved if the engineer is so
qualified.
3. Must be sure he has out of service
insurance.
4. Must be sure he has had sufficient
rest. 
 During the movement:
 1. The crewman must stay inside the equipment
to take advantage of the air conditioning/heat whenever possible.
2. Hand signals, communicating signal,
or radio communications must be maintained with the engineer.
3. The engineer is allowed to take short
naps as long as the crewman on the leading end stays awake.
4. A crewman has to walk ahead of the
train to protect against opposing moves. 
 If signals from the crew member cannot
be received by the engineer:
 1. The engineer should speed up so as
to get closer to the crewman on the leading end of the movement.
2. The engineer may continue as long as
the conductor says, &quot;trust me&quot;.
3. The engineer must stop the movement
when he gets nervous.
4. The movement must be stopped immediately. 
 Should conditions require, the employee
on the leading end must:
 1. Be prepared to jump from the train.
2. Be prepared to call for help.
3. Be prepared to have lunch if the movement
takes too long.
4. Operate the engine whistle or horn,
if available, as well as the emergency brake valve. 
 The speed of the train should not exceed:
 1. Restricted Speed.
2. 20 mph.
3. 30 mph.
4. Track speed. 
 This rule (116) does not apply:
 1. If the crew doesn&apos;t want it to.
2. If the Dispatcher says so.
3. If the crew is in a hurry to complete
the move.
4. When switching, making up trains in
the yard, or when the movement is proceeded by a crew member. 

 Protection against other trains is not required when discharging
across a main track or controlled siding when: 
1. The crew sees that no opposing trains are in sight.
2. The stop is made during daylight hours.
3. A delay would be incurred by such protection.
4. The specific station is designated in the Timetable as one where
scheduled trains normally receive and discharge passengers across a track
between the train and the station platform. 
 Trains operating on tracks across which passengers are normally received
and discharged must approach such stations: 
1. At restricted speed until they occupy the station.
2. Prepared to stop until the engineer has determined that no passenger
train is occupying the station.
3. At track speed,
4. At a speed not to exceed 30 mph until the engineer determines that
no train is occupying the station. 
 The engineer can determine that no passenger train is occupying the
station by: 
1. Telepathy.
2. Visual observation or verbal confirmation from the Dispatcher.
3. Hand signal from the Trainmaster.
4. Observing the signal at the end of the station platform. 
 If a passenger train is occupying the station the approaching train: 
1. Can proceed into the station at Restricted Speed.
2. Must not occupy the station unless permission is received from the
crew of the train occupying the station.
3. The engineer must dump the air.
4. 2 and 3. 
 When a train is approaching, the station platform must not: 
1. Be occupied by passengers preparing to board the approaching train.
2. Be occupied by trains operating on an out-of-service track adjacent
to the platform.
3. Be occupied by track cars operating on an in-service or out-of-service
track adjacent to the platform.
4. 2 and 3. 
 Rule 121, Intervening tracks at a station platform: 
 When a passenger train is receiving or discharging passengers on
the side toward a station platform: 
1. The crew need not protect against trains passing between the train
and the station.
2. Dispatchers must advise opposing trains of that fact.
3. Trains must pass between it and the platform at slow speed.
4. Trains must not pass between it and the station platform. 
 A passenger train routed to a track that will result in a station
stop for receiving and discharging passengers across a main track or controlled
siding must: 
1. Protect passengers against opposing traffic according to rule 99a.
2. Stop immediately and obtain assurance from the dispatcher that protection
on the track adjacent station platform has been provided.
3. Bypass the station stop.
4. Stop and request a route to the other track. 
 Trains routed to a track that will result in a station stop across
a main track or controlled siding do not have to stop if: 
1. They don’t want to.
2. The engineer can see that no trains or track cars interfere with
the station stop.
3. Written or verbal assurance of protection has previously been provided
or the track adjacent to the station platform is out of service.
4. The train is late or a delay would be incurred by stopping. 
 The Dispatcher must not give permission to discharge across a main
track or controlled siding until: 
1. It has been determined that no train is approaching the station
on the track to be protected.
2. All trains involved have been advised as to how to proceed to insure
passenger safety.
3. Signals governing entrance to that track are placed at stop and
blocking devices applied.
4. All the above. 
 Protection against other trains is not required when discharging
across a main track or controlled siding when: 
1. The crew sees that no opposing trains are in sight.
2. The stop is made during daylight hours.
3. A delay would be incurred by such protection.
4. The specific station is designated in the Timetable as one where
scheduled trains normally receive and discharge passengers across a track
between the train and the station platform. 
 Trains operating on tracks across which passengers are normally received
and discharged must approach such stations: 
1. At restricted speed until they occupy the station.
2. Prepared to stop until the engineer has determined that no passenger
train is occupying the station.
3. At track speed,
4. At a speed not to exceed 30 mph until the engineer determines that
no train is occupying the station. 
 The engineer can determine that no passenger train is occupying the
station by: 
1. Telepathy.
2. Visual observation or verbal confirmation from the Dispatcher.
3. Hand signal from the Trainmaster.
4. Observing the signal at the end of the station platform. 
 If a passenger train is occupying the station the approaching train: 
1. Can proceed into the station at Restricted Speed.
2. Must not occupy the station unless permission is received from the
crew of the train occupying the station.
3. The engineer must dump the air.
4. 2 and 3. 
 When a train is approaching, the station platform must not: 
1. Be occupied by passengers preparing to board the approaching train.
2. Be occupied by trains operating on an out-of-service track adjacent
to the platform.
3. Be occupied by track cars operating on an in-service or out-of-service
track adjacent to the platform.
4. 2 and 3. 
 At these stations: 
1. Trains, other than passenger trains, must not block access to the
station platform.
2. Trains, other than passenger trains, can block access to the platform
if the track they are on is out-of-service.
3. Can block access to the platform during daylight hours only.
4. 2 and 3. 
 Rule 122 unscheduled stops: 
 Trains 
must not make unscheduled stops to receive or discharge passengers or 
employees:
 1. Without permission of the Conductor.
2. Without permission of the passengers or employees.
3. Unless Simon says:
4. Without authorization from the Dispatcher. 
 Rule 123, Failure of the Deadman or 
Alerter 
feature en route: 
 If the 
Deadman or Alerter feature fails en route:
 1. The engineer will be promptly taken out of service. .
2. An employee instructed on how to stop the train will take position in 
the operating control compartment with the engineer.
3. The train must be stopped until the Deadman or Alerter feature is fixed.
4. The Deadman/Alerter feature must be fixed during the engine&apos;s 92 day 
inspection.

 When the engine reaches it&apos;s next turnaround point, undergoes it&apos;s next 
calendar day inspection:
 1. The Deadman/Alerter shall be repaired.
2. The failed Deadman/ Alerter shall be covered with Duck Tape. 
 3. The engineer will be promptly taken out of service. 
 4. Someone will have to wake up the Machinist. 
 This rule does not apply:
 1. If there are no mechanical forces on duty.
2. If the mechanical forces are at a safety meeting.
3. If the mechanical forces are out of Duck Tape.
4. On tracks other than main tracks or controlled sidings. 
 Rule 124, Maximum Authorized Speed: 
 Trains must not be operated:
 1. In excess of the speed of sound.
2. Before the engineer has had his nap..
3. Before lunch.
4. In excess of the maximum authorized speed.

 Rule 133, 
removing a track from service: 
 The Dispatcher must not issue a Form D, 
line 4 authority until:
 1. Determine that the affected track is
clear of movements that are not part of the work group.
2. Controlled signals leading to the track
are in Stop position.
3. Blocking devices are applied to the
controls of switches and signals leading to the affected track.
4. All of the above. 
 The Form D, line 4 must be addressed
to:
 1. The employee requesting the use of
the track and the operators controlling entrance to the track.
2. The employee requesting use of the
track and the Chief Dispatcher.
3. The employee requesting use of the
track and all trains operating over the Division.
4. The employee requesting the track only. 
 A whole mile post, a station or other
physical characteristic, and a track barricade or flagman at a designated
location:
 1. Are used to define each end of the
out-of-service limits.
2. Are put across the track to stop a
train.
3. Are things you see along the tracks.
4. Are clues that you work for a railroad. 
 ABS, CSS, DCS, and interlocking rules:
 1. Apply within the out-of-service track.
2. Do not apply within the out-of-service
limits.
3. Must be taken out of service by Form
D, line 13.
4. Apply depending on the reason for the
track being out of service. 
 All movements within the out-of-service
track:
 1. Must proceed at restricted speed.
2. Must proceed at slow speed, prepared
to stop short of obstructions.
3. Must proceed not exceeding 30 mph.
4. Must proceed at yard speed not exceeding
15 mph, prepared to stop short of obstructions. 
 The employee in charge of the out-of-service
limits:
 1. Is very important.
2. Should have out-of-service insurance.
3. Can leave the area once the work has
started.
4. Is the employee named in Form D, line 4 
 In territory where non-signaled DCS rules 
apply in both directions, the employee in charge of the out-of-service 
limits:
 1. May authorize trains to operate within the out-of-service limits at Normal Speed not exceeding 30 mph.
2. May authorize trains to operate within the out-of-service limits at 
Restricted Speed.
3. May authorize trains to operate within the out-of-service limits at 
Medium Speed.
4. May authorize trains to operate within the out-of-service limits at 
Parade Speed not exceeding 45 mph.

 Before the in charge of the out-of-service limits may authorize trains 
to operate at Normal Speed not exceeding 30 mph:
 1. The track must be clear and safe to operate at the authorized speed&apos;
2. All affected switches must be secured in the normal position.
3. All Roadway Workers must be notified
4. All of the above. 
 Trains given 
authorization to operate within the out-of-service limits at Normal Speed 
not exceeding 30 mph must:
 1. Not stop anywhere in the out-of-service limits.
2. Not exceed Restricted Speed.
3. Not reverse direction without permission of the employee in charge.
4. Must not stop for lunch before leaving the out-of-service limits. 
 After obtaining permission of the employee
named in Form D, line 4 and the employee in charge of the out-of-service 
limits has shown or read him the Form D, Line 4:
 1. The Chief Dispatcher can allow additional
equipment into the out-of-service limits.
2. The Trainmaster can allow additional
equipment into the out-of-service limits.
3. The employee in charge of the additional equipment can move additional
equipment into the out-of-service limits.
4. The Dispatcher can allow additional
equipment into the out-of-service limits. 
 When the out-of-service limits are published
by Bulletin Order:
 1. The Form D must also have a line 13
indicating the Bulletin Order number and line.
2. A new Form D has to be issued for each
piece of equipment allowed into the out-of-service limits.
3. Additional equipment can travel freely
into and out of the out-of-service limits.
4. The delivery or reading of the Form D, Line 4 is not required. 
 When a track is returned to service,
the employee in charge of the out-of-service limits must:
 1. Notify the Dispatcher of any restrictions
necessary for the safe passage of trains.
2. Ascertain that all track cars and trains
are clear of the track and notify the Dispatcher or Operator that they
are clear unless the equipment is authorized by the Dispatcher
to occupy the track after it is returned to service.
3. Pick up all his tools.
4. Promptly leave the area.
5. 1 and 2. 
 If the movement to the out-of-service 
limits will involve passing a stop signal:
 1. The person in charge of the additional equipment can pass the stop 
signal at his discretion.
2. The person in charge of the out-of-service track can give permission for 
the additional equipment o pass the stop signal.
3. The Dispatcher or Operator may authorize movement in accordance with 
Rule 241.
4. The additional equipment must not enter the out-of-service limits. 
 When a train is authorized by the Dispatcher
to occupy a track after it has been returned to service:
 1. The permission must include direction
if governed by rule 251.
2. The permission must include direction
if governed by DCS rules.
3. The permission must include direction if governed
by rule 261.
4. Does not have to include direction
unless the crew requests it. 
 Rule 135, Protection by stop signs
when in service track is obstructed for maintenance: 
 Working Limits:
 1. The area between the start of the Approach
sign and the Stop Sign.
2. The area designated by Form D, Line
5 or Bulletin Order, which must be identified by a whole mile post, station,
or other physical characteristic location.
3. The area within the limits of a block.
4. The area where employees are working. 
 When a Form D, line 5 is issued to obstruct
a track, it must be addressed to:
 1. The employee requesting to obstruct
the track except when the Working Limits is published by Bulletin Order.
2. Trains approaching their final terminal.
3. Form Ds do not have to be issued if
the Working Limits is published in the Bulletin Order.
4. The employee requesting to obstruct
the track and trains approaching the obstructed track. 
 When the Restricted Area is published
by Bulletin Order:
 1. The employee wishing to obstruct the
track does not need a Form D, line 5.
2. The Form D, Line 5 issued to approaching trains
is not required.
3. The Form D, line five must include
the times noted in the Bulletin Order.
4. 1 and 2. 
 The approach to the Working Limits must
be indicated by:
 1. An Approach Working Limits Sign.
2. An Approach Sign.
3. A Stop Sign.
4. A Distant Signal Marker. 
 The Working Limits must be indicated
by:
 1. A Stop Sign.
2. An Approach Sign.
3. A Stop Sign and a Working Limits Resume
Speed Sign.
4. A flagman with the proper flagging
equipment. 
 If the Working Limits are not obstructed: 
1. No signs need be placed.
2. A Form D, line 5 need not be issued.
3. A Working Limits Speed Limit Sign may
be substituted for the Stop Sign.
4. A Form D, line 13 must be issued indicated
that fact. 
 The Dispatcher cannot issue a Form D,
line 5 to obstruct the track until:
 1. He has had coffee.
2. He has been notified by the Chief Dispatcher
that the work has begun.
3. Until he been notified by the employee
in charge that the track is obstructed.
4. Until the affected track is clear of movements that are not part of 
the work group and the employee in charge has notified
him that the signs have been properly placed 
 The employee in charge must not authorize
a train to enter the Working Limits until:
 1. The &quot;Roadway Workers&quot; have had lunch.
2. The track through the Working Limits
is not obstructed and the &quot;Roadway Workers&quot; have been notified.
3. The track through the Working Limits
is not obstructed by anything bigger than the train.
4. The track through the Working Limits
is back in service. 
 Trains operating through the Working
Limits must:
 1. Not exceed 45 mph unless authorized
by the employee in charge to proceed at a higher or lower speed.
2. Not exceed Restricted Speed unless
authorized to operate at a higher speed.
3. Not exceed 30 mph unless authorized
by the employee in charge to operate at a higher or lower speed.
4. Not proceed without a hand signal from
the employee in charge. 
 Work trains and track cars may enter
and leave the Working Limits:
 1. While the Working Limits are obstructed
and must travel at Restricted Speed. Permission of the employee in charge
is required.
2. Only when the Working Limits are not
obstructed and must travel at Restricted Speed. Permission of the employee
in charge is not required.
3. Only before the Stop Sign and Working
Limits Resume Speed signs are properly placed.
4. Trains and track cars cannot enter
the Working Limits once the Stop Sign and Working Limits Resume Speed Signs
are placed. 
 Trains in the Working Limits when the 
Bulletin Order Item becomes effective:
 1. Must leave the Working Limits immediately.
2. May continue at Normal Speed throughout the Working Limits.
3. Must immediately reduce speed to Restricted Speed until the entire train 
has left the Working Limits.
4. Must immediately stop and contact the Dispatcher for further 
instructions.
 
Rule 136, Emergency Stops: Protection: 
 When a train is moving and an emergency application of the brakes
occurs, the train crew must: 
1. Initiate an emergency radio transmission and protect all adjacent
main tracks and controlled sidings.
2. Initiate an emergency radio transmission and protect against following
movements only.
3. Initiate an emergency radio transmission stating that the train
is in emergency giving the time and date.
4. When the train stops, reset the air and continue to the final terminal. 
 After the train stops following an emergency application: 
1. The entire train must be examined and a car count completed.
2. The entire train must be examined for derailed cars, shifted loads,
or other conditions affecting train movement.
3. The entire train must be examined for bad brake valves.
4. The crew must reset the air and continue to the final terminal. 

 A train operating in the same direction as a train in emergency must: 
1. Operate at slow speed from two (2) miles before the reported location
until reaching the head end of the train in emergency.
2. Operate at slow speed from one (1) mile before the reported location
until reaching the head end of the train in emergency.
3. Operate at restricted speed from two (2) miles before the reported
location until reaching the head end of the train in emergency.
4. Operate at restricted speed from (1) mile before the reported location
until reaching the head end of the train in emergency. 
 A train operating in the opposite direction as a train in emergency
must: 
1. Operate at slow speed from the head end of the train in emergency
until two (2) miles beyond the rear of that train.
2. Operate at restricted speed from the head end of the train in emergency
until two (2) miles beyond the rear of that train.
3. Operate at slow speed from the head end of the train in emergency
until one (1) mile beyond the rear of that train.
4. Operate at restricted speed from the head end of the train in emergency
until one (1) mile to the rear of that train. 
 A radio transmission from a train in emergency should include: 
1. Time and date.
2. Time, date, and Conductor’s name.
3. Train, engine, track, and milepost numbers.
4. Any hazardous materials in the train. 
 Until the Dispatcher or operators know there is no obstruction on
adjacent tracks: 
1. He must not go to lunch.
2. He cannot be relieved.
3. He cannot take his pension.
4. He must not permit trains to enter the block on adjacent tracks
without notifying them of the situation. 
 Rule 141, Inaccessible Track: 
 Roadway workers may establish Working 
Limits no controlled by the Dispatcher or Operator :
1. By standing on the track and not moving when a train approaches.
2. By making the track inaccessible at each possible point of entry by 
securing a switch or derail with an effective locking device..
3. Lining securing a remotely controlled switch to prevent access to the 
working limits.
4. A disconnected rail or flagman to hold trains and equipment clear of the 
working limits.
5. Numbers 2, 3, and 4. 
 Rule 160, issuing a Form D: 
 All Form D’s are issued by:
 1. Trainmaster.
2. Division Superintendent.
3. Train Dispatcher.
4. Yard Master. 
 The Form D number, when issued on New
Jersey Transit, must be preceded by:
 1. &quot;NJT&quot;.
2. &quot;T&quot;.
3. &quot;NJ RAIL&quot;.
4. &quot;N&quot;. 
 Rule 161, Completing Form D properly: 
 Information on a Form D must be:
 1. Written in crayon.
2. Legible and without erasure or alteration.
3. Written in ink.
4. Indelible. 
 Only authorized abbreviations:
 1. May be used when spelling the Dispatcher&apos;s
name.
2. May be used in radio communications.
3. May be used when ordering lunch.
4. May be used in Form D’s. 
 To separate numbers or locations listed
in a series on a Form D you must use:
 1. Hyphens.
2. Parenthesis.
3. Commas.
4. Semi-colons. 
 Applicable Form D line numbers must
be:
 1. Crossed out.
2. Underlined.
3. Erased.
4. Circled. 
 Employees must review the entire Form
D for:
 1. Typographical errors.
2. Misspelling.
3. Jelly stains.
4. Additional information. 
 Operators must:
 1. Keep an office copy of each Form D.
2. Throw their copy away after 24 hours.
3. Return their copy of the Form D to
the Chief Dispatcher.
4. Return their copy of the Form D to
the Trainmaster. 
 Rule 162, Addresses: 
 Form D’s are addressed to:
 1. The Dispatcher, operator, and Conductor
involved.
2. Those who are to execute them.
3. Conductors and Engineers only.
4. Track and signal supervisors only. 
 Form D’s for trains must be addressed
to:
 1. The Dispatcher and Conductor.
2. The Conductor and Engineer only.
3. The Conductor, Engineer, and Pilot,
if any.
4. All members of the train crew. 
 Scheduled trains will be identified
by:
 1. The engine number.
2. The engine number and the number of
the last car on the train.
3. The abbreviation &quot;No.&quot; plus the schedule
number and the engine number.
4. The engineer&apos;s employee number. 
 In a Form D, extra trains will be identified:
 1. By the Conductor&apos;s name.
2. By the railroad&apos;s name.
3. By the train number and direction.
4. By the word &quot;extra&quot; and the engine
number. 
 Blanket addresses on Form D’s:
 1. May not be used.
2. May be used but not very often.
3. May be used with the Chief Dispatcher&apos;s
permission.
4. May be used, such as &quot;Eastward Trains&quot;. 
 Form D’s for a track car must be addressed
to:
 1. Foreman, driver, or pilot.
2. Track car number only.
3. Driver only.
4. None of the above. 
 If more than one track car is to operate
on the same Form D authority:
 1. All track cars must be addressed.
2. All track car drivers must be addressed.
3. The number of additional pieces must
be specified.
4. Only the lead track car must be addressed. 
 Rule 164, Examination before delivery: 
 Copies of Form D’s made with pressure
sensitive or carbon paper:
 1. Cannot be transmitted electronically.
2. Cannot be transmitted by radio or telephone
3. Must be examined for legibility before
delivery.
4. Must be examined for neat penmanship
before delivery. 
 Rule 168, Errors discovered 
 If an error in a Form D is discovered
before &quot;Time Effective&quot; is given:
 1. The error must be corrected on the
Form D.
2. The Dispatcher must be sure the error
is noted and understood.
3. The Dispatcher must direct the receiving
employees to destroy their copies
.4. The employee&apos;s copies must be tortured,
maimed, and then eaten. 
 If an error is discovered after the
&quot;Time Effective&quot; has been given:
 1. The Form D must be canceled.
2. The error must be corrected and a new
&quot;Time Effective&quot; must be given.
3. The Form D is good as long as the error
does not affect the movement of trains.
4. The Dispatcher is to be tortured, maimed,
and then eaten. 
 Rule 169, Additions to Form D: 
 Once a Form D has been given a &quot;Time
Effective&quot;, additions to Form Ds:
 1. Can be made as long as a new &quot;Time
Effective&quot; is given.
2. Must not be made after the &quot;Time Effective&quot;
has been given.
3. Can be made with the Trainmaster’s
permission.
4. Can only contain Form D cancellation
information, track is clear information, occupying DCS territory, and additional
line 2 authorities 
 Rule 170, Delivery at an Interlocking
or Controlled Point: 
 The last interlocking signal governing
a train&apos;s movement must be placed in the stop position, a blocking device
applied and not removed: 
1. When a Form D is to be received at an
interlocking.
2. When two (2) trains request a Form
D for the same purpose.
3. When the Dispatcher is confused.
4. None of the above. 
 The blocking device can be removed from
the interlocking signal when:
 1. A Form D is delivered.
2. The engineer acknowledges that he is
to receive a Form D.
3. When the Dispatcher is no longer confused.
4. #1 and #2. 
 Blocking devices are not required:
 1. When the Dispatcher doesn&apos;t want to
apply them.
2. At locations where the crews are required
to inquire about Form D’s prior to departure.
3. At locations where the crew regularly
stop for stations.
4. At locations where the crew regularly
stops after work. 
 Rule 171, Physical delivery to a
moving train: 
 When a Form D is to be delivered to
a moving train:
 1. The train must stop.
2. The train must not exceed thirty (30)
MPH.
3. The train may do track speed.
4. The train may not exceed the speed
mentioned on line nine (9) of the Form D. 
 If delivery to a moving train is not
effected:
 1. The train can continue and the Form
D is transmitted electronically to the crew.
2. The train can continue but the Form
D is canceled.
3. The train can continue but must pick
up the Form D at the next interlocking or Controlled Point.
4. The train must be stopped. 
 Rule 172, Delivery to a train that
will have restricted movement in the immediate vicinity: 
 Unless the engineer has been informed
of a Form D restriction that is within three (3) miles of the Form D delivery
point:
 1. The train must proceed at restricted
speed when picking up the Form D.
2. The train must not exceed medium speed
when picking up the Form D.
3. The train must stop to pick up the
Form D and a signal to proceed not given until the engineer is fully advised
of the situation.
4. The engineer must dump the air. 
 Rule 173, Delivery to a relieving
conductor or engineer: 
 When a Conductor or Engineer is relieved,
all Form D’s not fulfilled or canceled:
 1. Must be returned to the Dispatcher.
2. Must be delivered to the relieving
Conductor or Engineer who must compare the Form D’s and instructions.
3. Must be destroyed.
4. Must be re-transmitted. 
 When the relieving crew cannot communicate
with the crew to be relieved, they must:
 1. Assume the Form D’s were never sent.
2. Call the previous crew at home to receive
the Form D’s.
3. The previous crew must remain until
the relieving crew arrives.
4. Contact the Dispatcher for all information
affecting the movement of their train before proceeding. 
 Rule 174, receiving a Form D at a
TBS: 
 Trains approaching a temporary block
station:
 1. Must be prepared to stop and must not
pass it without receiving a Form D.
2. May proceed on verbal permission or
a green flag.
3. Must stop and the Conductor or engineer
call the Dispatcher for a Form D.
4. None of the above. 
 At a TBS where hand operated switches
are in service:
 1. Trains may foul the switches if they
are within the limits of the TBS.
2. Trains may not foul the switches unless
they are within the limits of the TBS.
3. Trains may not foul the switches without
a signal to proceed from the operator.
4. Trains may foul the switches to get
to the operator&apos;s position. 
 If a train passes the last holding point
(Interlocking, block station or controlled point) while the TBS is open
and reaches it after its scheduled closing time:
 1. The train must remain at the TBS until
it reopens.
2. The TBS must remain open until all
trains are by.
3. The Conductor must walk to the nearest
station for a Form D.
4. The train must approach the TBS prepared
to stop and must not pass it without verbal permission of the Dispatcher. 
 When an operator at a temporary block
station has no Form D issued by the Dispatcher for a train:
 1. The train must not proceed.
2. The Dispatcher must be called and a
Form D issued.
3. The train may proceed on verbal permission
if the operator knows the block is clear.
4. The operator may issue an unnumbered
Form D with the address and date portion completed, indicating &quot;NONE on
the delivery portion and the &quot;Time Effective&quot; and sign his last name instead
of the Dispatcher&apos;s. 
 Rule 175, Speed restrictions 
 Speed restrictions must be listed
 1. In alphabetical order.
2. By descending order of speed.
3. By ascending order of speed.
4. In sequential order. 
 If speed signs cannot be displayed immediately:
 1. The speed restriction must be considered
void.
2. The Dispatcher must not use portions
of a mile unless used in conjunction with a physical characteristic location.
3. The Dispatcher must not issue the Form
D.
4. The Dispatcher must use a station location. 
 Rule 176, Effective period of a Form
D: 
 Form Ds are in effect:
 1. Until fulfilled or until canceled.
2. Until midnight on the date of issue.
3. Until canceled by Form D, line 13.
4. Until the time indicated on line four
(4). 
 Rule 177, Canceling Form D’s: 
 A Form D may be canceled on the same
form:
 1. When the Dispatcher contacts the addressees
involved stating the Form D number, date, cancellation time and date and
his initials and recording it on the appropriate section of the Form D.
2. By using the Conductor&apos;s punch where
indicated.
3. By throwing it out the cab window.
4. All the above in numerical order. 
 When Canceling a Form D, the addressee
must:
 1. Repeat the Form D number, date, and
cancellation information to the Dispatcher.
2. Throw the Form D out of the cab window.
3. Repeat the cancellation information
to his crew.
4. 1 and 3.

 Rule 242, Absent or Imperfectly Displayed 
Signals: 
 If a fixed signal is absent from the place where it 
is usually shown:
 1. The movement may proceed according to the last signal seen.
2. The movement must proceed at Restricted speed.
3. The movement must be governed by the most restrictive indication that can be 
given by that signal.
4. The movement has to stop and the Dispatcher notified without delay to the 
train. 

 Imperfectly displayed signals must be:
 1. Ignored if they display better that Stop.
2. Must be reported to the Dispatcher or Operator as soon as practical without 
delay to the train.
3. 1 and 2.
4. All of the above. 

 Imperfectly displayed signals must be:
 1. Ignored because they are imperfect.
2. Regarded as the most restrictive indication that can be given by that signal.
3. Regarded as a Stop signal and the movement must be stopped until the 
Conductor walks to the next signal which is perfectly displayed.
4. Regarded as a Stop signal. 

 If the imperfectly displayed signal is a color light 
signal, position light signal, color position light signal, or a semaphore 
signal: 
1. It can be ignored.
2. It must be considered a Stop signal and the Dispatcher must be contacted for 
permission to proceed.
3. It must be considered a stop and proceed in all instances.
4. If only one indication is possible the indication will govern. 

 If more than one indication is possible for an 
imperfectly displayed signal that are more favorable than Stop and Proceed:
 1. All possibilities must be explored.
2. The dispatched must be consulted as to which indication governs the move.
3. The crew must flip a coin to determine which indication governs.
4. Trains may proceed as though a Restricting Signal were displayed. 

 Rule 244, Signal requiring Stop: 
 A train approaching a fixed signal requiring a stop Must:
 1. Call the Dispatcher for permission to approach the signal requiring 
a stop.
2. Stop before the rear of the train passes the signal requiring a stop.
3. Stop for lunch.
4. Stop before any part of the movement passes the signal. 

 Rule 245, Unexpected signal changes: 

 When a train, operating on a signal indication more favorable than 
approach encounters a Stop Signal, Stop and Proceed, or Restricting, that 
train must:
 1. Continue according to the last indication passed.
2. Comply with the signal consistent with good train handling, notifying 
the Dispatcher.
3. Dump the train immediately.
4. Have a heart attack and die. 

 Opposing movements in Rule 261 Territory: 

 Before giving permission for an opposing movement The Dispatcher
must: 
1. Be well rested.
2. Issue a Form D, line 8 to the disabled train.
3. Must issue a Form D, line 9 to the disabled train.
4. Must issue a Form D, line 2 to the disabled train. 
 After issuing a From D, line 8 to the disabled train the Dispatcher: 
1. Can go to lunch.
2. Can be relieved to relieve himself.
3. Must issue a Form D, line 9 to the assisting train.
4. Must issue a Form D, line 13 to the assisting train. 
 For an opposing movement to assist a train: 
1. ABS rules are in effect.
2. ABS rules are not in effect.
3. ABS anti-lock systems are in effect.
4. ABS anti-lock systems are cut out.
 
Opposing movements in Rule 251 Territory: 
 Before giving authorization for a train to assist a disabled train
in Rule 251 territory the Dispatcher must: 
1. Have lunch.
2. Be relieved.
3. Issue a Form D, line 8 to the disabled train.
4. Issue a Form D, line 9 to the disabled train. 

 After issuing a Form D, line 8 to the disabled train the Dispatcher
must :
1. Issue a Form D; line 2 to the assisting train.
2. Issue a Form D, line 8 to the assisting train.
3. Go to lunch.
4. Issue a Form D, line 13 to the assisting train. 
 The Form D issued to the assisting train must: 
1. Be hand written on Parchment.
2. Authorize the assisting train to operate to the whole milepost or
station at least 2 miles prior to the disabled train.
3. Contain a line 9 to operate from the whole milepost or station to
the disabled train.
4. 2 and 3. 
 For the portion of the movement govern by Form D, line 9: 
1. DCS rules apply.
2. DCS rules do not apply.
3. DCS rules are in effect for the first portion of the movement governed
by Form D, line 9.
4. DCS RULES!

 Opposing movements where on tracks where DCS rules are in effect
in both directions: 
 
Before a Dispatcher can permit an opposing move to assist a train
in DCS territory, the Dispatcher must: 
1. Ask permission from the Chief Dispatcher.
2. Issue a Form D, line 8 the disabled train, cancel the disabled train’s
form D, line 2 and inform the crewmember of the disabled train that an
opposing movement will be authorized.
3. Issue Form D; line 8 to the assisting train.
4. Pray that no one will screw up. 
 The Dispatcher must issue Form D, line 2 to authorize the assisting
train to: 
1. Stop and eat.
2. Leave their train on the main.
3. Operate to the whole milepost or station at least 2 miles prior
to the disabled train
4. Operate against the direction of traffic in rule 261 territory. 
 The Dispatcher must also issue a Form D, line 9 to the assisting
train to: 1. Operate from the point mentioned in the Form D, line 2
to the disabled train. 2. To authorize the assisting train to couple to
the disabled train.
3. To authorize the assisting train to operate against the current
of traffic in 251 territory.
4. None of the above. 
 DCS rules do not apply: 
1. To the portion of the movement governed by Form D, line 2.
2. To the portion of the movement governed by Form D, line 9.
3. To any portion of the movement.
4. DCS rules apply to all movement governed by the Form D.
 
Following movement where DCS rules are in effect: 
 Before a Dispatcher can authorize a following movement to assist
a disabled train, he must: 
1. Inform a crewmember of the disabled train that a following movement
will be authorized.
2. Issue a Form D, line 2 to the assisting train to operate to the
whole milepost or station at least 2 miles prior to the disabled train.
3. Issue line 9 to the assisting train to operate from the whole milepost
or station to the disabled train.
4. All of the above. 

 DSC rules: 
1. Apply to the entire movement.
2. Do not apply to the entire movement.
3. Apply the line 2 portion of the Form D.
4. Do not apply the line 9 portion of the form D. 
 To provide flag protection against an assisting train an employee
equipped with flagging equipment must: 
1. Proceed to the nearest 7-11 and pig out on Slurpies and Chilidogs.
2. Proceed in the proper direction, display a lighted fusee when the
train is seen or heard approaching and remain at that location until the
assisting train arrives or until the employee is recalled.
3. Proceed to the nearest pay phone and call his girlfriend/boyfriend
and tell them about the neat accident about to happen.
4. Disappear into the woods for a short period of recreation. 
 If the disabled train is within&amp;frac14; mile of an interlocking
where the assisting train will begin it’s opposing move or the assisting
train is operated by the engineer of the disabled train: 
1. All the rules for opposing movement to assist a disabled train stated
above do not apply.
2. Only Form D, line 9 is needed.
3. Only Form D, line 2 is needed.
4. A disabled train cannot be assisted because there is not enough
room between it and the interlocking or control point. 
 When the assisting train has received a proper signal at an interlocking
or control point or verbal permission per rule 241, it must proceed at: 
1. Track speed.
2. Ramming speed.
3. Escape velocity.
4. Restricted speed.
 
Rule 138, Highway crossing warning: 
 Activating/reactivating Crossing Warning 

  Which of the following indicate the start of a crossing gate
circuit: 
1. A yellow sign or post with the letters &quot;CC&quot;.
2. Yellow joint bars.
3. Yellow strip painted on the inside and outside of the head, web,
and base both rails.
4. All the above. 

 On tracks other than main tracks or controlled sidings, movement
over this point will: 
1. Cause the train to derail.
2. Cause an accident at the crossing.
3. Activate an alarm, which will automatically summon police and fire
units.
4. Activate the automatic crossing warning. 
 On a main track or controlled siding, movement over this point will: 
1. Cause death and destruction.
2. Cause termination of the engineer and crew.
3. Activate a water cannon to stop the pedestrian traffic.
4. Reactivate the operation of automatic crossing warning that has
been interrupted because of a train’s delay or stop. 
 Two steps, which will avoid unnecessary operation of automatic crossing
warning, are: 
1. The Lindy and the Foxtrot.
2. Sending a flagman to protect the crossing and being very, very careful.
3. Engine and cars must not be allowed to stand longer than necessary
and switches must not be left open or unlocked within the operating limits
of such protection.
4. Deactivating the crossing protection and refusing to pass over the
crossing with the train. 
 If automatic crossing protection is not operating properly: 
1. The engineer must refuse to pass over the crossing until the protection
is fixed.
2. Employees must immediately notify the Dispatcher who will issue
a Form D, line 12 to all affected trains.
3. Employees must immediately notify the Dispatcher who will call police
to provide protection.
4. All of the above. 
 If Automatic crossing warning devices are not working properly trains
must: 
1. Never occupy the crossing.
2. Approach the crossing prepared to stop, not occupy the crossing
until protection is provided by on-ground personnel, and proceed not exceeding
15 mph until the head end clears.
3. Approach the crossing prepared to stop then accelerates rapidly
if no cross traffic is seen.
4. Approach the crossing prepared to stop, have a qualified employee
lay across the road to stop traffic, then proceed not exceeding 15 mph
avoiding the prone employee. 
 When automatic crossing warning devices are not operating properly,
on-ground protection is not needed: 
1.When the crew sees that no cross traffic is in sight.
2. The crew sees that cross traffic has stopped to allow the train
to proceed.
3. The crossing is equipped with gates and the crew sees that they
are in the horizontal position and the crossing lights are flashing.
4. The crossing is equipped with passive protection and that protection
is working properly. 
 The only personnel relied upon to provide on-ground protection are: 
1. A member of the crew, a policeman, or an employee with a reflective
vest and proper flagging equipment.
2. An employee of the company, policeman, or the local rail nut who
came to help.
3. An officer of the company, policeman, or a helpful pedestrian.
4. Any one willing to stand in front of enraged motorists. 
 When equipment is standing and obscures highway traffic’s view: 
1. It is a good thing.
2. An employee must be ready to call an ambulance.
3. An employee must protect the highway traffic against movement on
adjacent tracks.
4. An employee must carry a camera to record the accident. 
 Equipment stored on tracks close to a public crossing must: 
1. Be low to the ground so that drivers can see over it.
2. Be stored at least&amp;frac14; mile from the crossing.
3. If space permits, must not stick out onto the crossing in a way
that would obstruct traffic.
4. Be placed so as to permit a clear view for highway traffic using
the crossing, at least 300 feet if space permits. 
 When cars not headed by an engine are to be moved over a highway
crossing not protected by automatic crossing warning devices, or a designated
employee: 
1. A Company of National Guard soldiers must be called.
2. Barriers must be placed on the crossing to stop vehicular traffic.
3. A caboose or other suitable platform must be provided for the crew.
4. A member of the crew with proper flagging equipment must provide
protection against highway traffic by giving stop signals to pedestrian
and highway traffic until the leading end of the train is through the crossing. 
 Conditions that require special procedures when fouling a public
crossing are: 
1. When a train passes entirely over a crossing and then makes a reverse
move.
2. When a train approaches a crossing at Restricted Speed.
3. When a train stops then starts again within 0.6 miles from a crossing
with an interrupt system and starts again.
4. All of the above. 
 More conditions, which require special procedures when fouling a
public crossing, are: 
1. When a train passes a warning device activation or reactivation
point or performed switching within 1.2 miles of the crossing.
2. When the crew is on overtime.
3. When the crew stops short of the crossing to buy a few beers.
4. 2 and 3. 
 If automatic crossing warning is not operating: 
1. The train is not allowed to occupy the crossing and the Dispatcher
must be notified.
2. The train is not allowed to occupy the crossing until the crew is
on overtime.
3. The crew must stop for a couple of beers to build up their courage
for the dash across the highway.
4. The movement must not be made until protection is provided by on-ground
personnel. 
 When crossing warning devices are operated manually no movement may
be made until: 
1. Protection is provided by on-ground personnel, protection has been
reestablished for at least 20 seconds, or gates, where equipped, are in
the horizontal position and crossing lights are flashing.
2. No Highway traffic can be seen in either direction.
3. Police have arrived to provide protection.
4. Crossing devices cannot be manually controlled. That’s why they
are called automatic warning protection. 
 When crossing protection is interrupted manually or is manually operated: 
1. The crew can leave the crossing on manual if another employee is
left in charge.
2. The crew can leave the crossing on manual if a policeman is there
to direct traffic.
3. The crew must restore the automatic crossing warning protection
unless the Chief Dispatcher authorizes otherwise.
4. It must be restored to normal after movement is complete. 
 At crossings where the apparatus interrupts automatic protection
on adjacent tracks: 
1. The employee must remain at the crossing to reestablish automatic
protection to normal when a train is approaching on an adjacent track.
2. The employee can leave the crossing as each approaching train must
provide it’s own protection.
3. The Dispatcher must issue a Form D, line 12 to all trains that the
crossing protection has been interrupted.
4. Police or Signal Department protection must be provided for trains
on crossing where the automatic protection has been interrupted. 
 Rule 140, Foul time: 

 Foul time may be issued only by:
 1. The Conductor of the train in the track segment involved.
2. Bulletin Order or Form D, Line 2.
3. The Dispatcher or Operator when authorized by the Dispatcher.
4. The foreman of the crew working in the track segment involved. 

 Before issuing foul time:
 1. The Conductor must determine that his train is clear of the track 
 segment involved.
2. The Dispatcher must determine that no trains have been authorized to 
 occupy the track segment to be fouled.
3. The Foreman must determine that all his men are ready to work quickly.
4. All of the above. 

 In signaled territory the dispatcher must insure that:
 1. Stop signals have been displayed and blocking devices have been 
 applied..
2. He has had a nutritious breakfast.
3. The crew requesting foul time is not in the Interlocking limits.
4. He has Out-of-Service insurance. 

 When trains are to be held at a TBS where blocking devices cannot 
 be applied:
 1. The Dispatcher must get permission from the block operator before 
 allowing Foul Time.
2. The Dispatcher must issue a Form D, Line 13 instructing the Operator 
 to hold trains clear of the affected track.
3. The Engineer of the train to be held must stop at the Interlocking 
 closest to the TBS.
4. The Block Operator must build a signal fire on the track to be 
 affected. 

 Permission to Foul must include the following information:
 1. The trains to be held out of the affected track segment.
2. The title and name of employee receiving foul time.
3. Track designation and track limits (Between/at).
4. Time limits.
5. 2, 3, and 4. 

 The person receiving foul time must:
 1. Have all the workers ready to complete the work quickly.
2. Must have Out-Of-Service insurance.
3. Must repeat the permission and the Dispatcher must then confirm it 
 before foul time becomes effective.
4. The Dispatcher must check with the Chief Dispatcher for permission to 
 give foul time. 

 Once protection has been provided:
 1. It must be maintained until the Dispatcher is relived of duty.
2. It must be maintained until the crew working has finished their work.
3. It must be maintained until lunch time.
4. It must be maintained until the employee who was granted the foul time 
 has released the foul time. 

 Rule 244, Signal requiring Stop: 

 A train approaching a fixed signal requiring a stop Must:
 1. Call the Dispatcher for permission to approach the signal requiring 
a stop.
2. Stop before the rear of the train passes the signal requiring a stop.
3. Stop for lunch.
4. Stop before any part of the movement passes the signal. 

 Rule 245, Unexpected signal changes: 

 When a train, operating on a signal indication more favorable than 
approach encounters a Stop Signal, Stop and Proceed, or Restricting, that 
train must:
 1. Continue according to the last indication passed.
2. Comply with the signal consistent with good train handling, notifying 
the Dispatcher.
3. Dump the train immediately.
4. Have a heart attack and die. 

 Rule 
 300, Operating in Speed Enforcement Territory:
 
Unless authorized by the Timetable or Dispatcher,
trains operating in SES Territory:
 1. Must have the SES equipment 
cut out.
2. Must be equipped with a working toilet.
3. Must be equipped with the necessary onboard devices to communicate
with the Speed Enforcement System.
4. Must have an employee on the leading end to watch for speed changes.
 
A Departure test of the equipment must 
 be performed and the system must be known to be operational:
 1. Within 48 hours of entering SES Territory.
2. Within 12 hours prior to entering SES Territory.
3. Within 6 hours of entering SES Territory.
4. Prior to entering SES Territory.
 
Rule 301, Operating from non-equipped 
 Unit or Equipped Unit with SES Cut Out:
 
The movement of a train not equipped SES 
 apparatus in SES Territory:
 1. Is prohibited except when authorized by Timetable or the Dispatcher.
2. Is prohibited at all times.
3. Is prohibited unless the engineer has not been trained on SES equipment.
4. Is prohibited unless the Mechanical Department says so.
 
Authorized non-equipped movements or equipped units with the SES cut out 
 must:
 1. Proceed at Restricted Speed unless authorized to operate at higher 
 speeds by Form D, Line 13.
2. Proceed prepared to stop at all signals regardless of the aspect displayed.
3. Be governed by fixed signal indication an, if applicable, Cab Signal
 System rules.
4. None of the above. 

 Rule 302, Conformity between Speed Enforcement
System, Speed Restrictions, and Fixed Signals:
 

 If the Speed Enforcement System authorizes 
 a speed greater than the speed indicated by the fixed wayside signals or 
fails to enforce a speed restriction:
 1. The engineer must stop the train until the system is fixed.
2. The engineer must operate at Restricted Speed until the SES and the 
fixed signals conform.
3. The engineer will be confused.
4. The engineer must operate at the speed indicated by the fixed signal
 and published speed restrictions.
 

 When operating in CSS/SES Territory, the 
 speed displayed by the SDU:
 1. Cannot be believed.
2. Will be displayed as green frogs dancing on a light blue background.
3. Will be ten MPH higher than the actual speed restriction.
4. Will be the most restrictive speed authorized, based on the information 
 conveyed by the fixed signal and speed restrictions on the affected track.
 

 When operating in CSS/SES Territory with 
 operative SES apparatus, engineers are relieved:
 1. To relieve themselves.
2. From all responsibility for the safety of the train.
3. From operating on schedule.
4. From the requirements of Rules 552 and 555(3).
 
Rule 303, Movement with inoperative 
 Speed Enforcement System:
 
The movement of a train equipped with SES
apparatus not in operative condition:
 1. Is prohibited.
2. Is prohibited except when the failure occurs enroute or when authorized 
 by Rule or the Dispatcher to cut out the SES.
3. Is prohibited except when the failure 
 occurs enroute or when authorized by Conductor to cut out the SES.
4. Is 
prohibited except when the failure occurs enroute or when authorized by anybody
to cut out the SES.
 

 The onboard SES apparatus will be considered 
 as having failed when:
 1. The SES status indicator on the SDU is dark.
2. The SES failed light on the SDU is illuminated Red.
3. The speed authorized by the SDU exceeds the maximum authorized speed.
4. When the engineer gets tired of looking at the SDU.
5. Numbers 1,2, and 3.
 
Other conditions where the SES is considered 
 failed include:
 1. There is damage to the onboard SES apparatus.
2. The audible indicator continues to sound even though the speed change 
 was acknowledged and the speed of the train was reduced to the speed required 
 by the SES.
3. The audible indicator fails to sound when the speed changes to a more 
 restrictive authorized speed.
4. The blinking indicator located in the upper left hand corner of the 
SDU is not blinking.
5. When the engineer gets tired of looking at the SDU.
6. Numbers 1,2,3, and 4.
 
If the SES fails, the engineer must:
 1. Notify the Conductor and Dispatcher of the failure and attempt
to reset the system.
2. Stop the train until the SES system resets.
3. Reverse direction and return to the initial terminal.
4. Contact his union representative immediately.
 
If the engineer is unable to reset the 
 SES System he must:
 1. Cut out the SES and consider the failed apparatus as inoperative.
2. Take the rest of the day off.
3. Stop the train and wait to be rescued by a following train.
4. Notify the passengers that they will be late arriving at their final
 destination.
 
If the engineer is unable to reset the SES the Dispatcher:
 1. Can forget about that train and concentrate on getting other trains 
 over the road.
2. Can go for coffee.
3. Must inform the mechanical and signal departments and the dispatcher
 of connecting districts, divisions, or railroads.
4. Call his supervisor for advice.
 
Rule 304, CSS failure in SES/CSS Territory:
 
If there is an enroute failure of the
CSS and the CSS is cut out:
 1. The train can continue using SES.
2. The SES must also be cut out.
3. The train needs a Form D, Line 13 to continue.
4. The train can continue at slow speed until the CSS is fixed.
 
Failure to cut out the SES after a CSS
 failure:
 1. Will result in disciplinary action against the engineer.
2. Will result in the engineer being late for breakfast.
3. Will result in an enforced stop at all fixed signal locations.
4. All of the above.
 
Rule 304, Stop Acknowledgment:

 In SES Territory, a train must come to
 a complete stop:
 1. Within 5 feet of a signal displaying a Stop Signal, Restricting,,
 or Stop and Proceed Signal.
2. Within 500 feet of a signal displaying
 a Stop Signal, Restricting,, or Stop and Proceed Signal.
3. When a signal displaying a Stop Signal, 
Restricting,, or Stop and Proceed Signal is first seen.
4. When the engineer gets tired.
 
The train brakes:
 1. Must be in release with the throttle in the first notch.
2. Must be in &quot;Application&quot; and the throttle in idle.
3. Must be in &quot;Suppression&quot; with the engineer idle.
4. Must be in &quot;Suppression&quot; with the throttle in idle.
 
The engineer must advise the Dispatcher:
 1. When he has five hours left to work.
2. When he is hungry.
3. When he is stopped at a Stop Signal.
4. All of the above.
 
The Dispatcher, after complying with the
 requirements of Rule 241:
 1. Must communicate to the engineer the time when he can go to lunch.
2. Must communicate to the engineer the password for the day and the correct
 time.
3. Must communicate to the engineer the correct &quot;Stop Release Code&quot; for 
that location.
4. Must communicate to the engineer his sincere wishes for a pleasant day,. 

 After receiving the &quot;Stop Release Code&quot;
 from the Dispatcher, the engineer:
 1. Must push the &quot;Acknowledging Button&quot; on the SDU and proceed at Restricted
 Speed until the SDU displays a more favorable indication.
2. Must enter a &quot;*&quot; , the number &quot;8&quot; followed by the six digit &quot;Release 
Code&quot;.
3. After the correct code sequence is entered, enter the &quot;#&quot; sign.
4. 2 and 3.
5. None of the above.
 
If all the above stuff is done correctly,
 the engineer:
 1. Will receive an &quot;Atta Boy&quot; from the Dispatcher.
2. Will receive a &quot;Release from Stop&quot; display on the SDU enabling the engineer
 to pass the Stop Signal.
3. Will be more confused than he was when he started the trip.
4. Will understand that the people who design this junk are not our friends.
 
After &quot;Stop Acknowledgment&quot; is displayed
 on the SDU the train:
 1. May proceed at Normal Speed.
2. May proceed at Slow Speed.
3. May proceed at Medium Speed.
4. May proceed at Restricted Speed.
 
Rule 306, Dispatcher&apos;s responsibility
 for Recording Movements:
 
Dispatchers must record on the Record
of Train Movements:
 1. The time he goes to lunch.
2. The time he comes to work.
3. The time he has left to pension.
4. The movement of all trains operating with inoperative SES or that are
 not equipped.
 
Rule 307, Temporary Speed Restrictions
 and Out of Service Transponders:
 
Temporary speed restriction transponders:
 1. Must never be used.
2. Must never be used without the permission of the Deputy General Manager
 - Transportation.
3. May be installed in conjunction with temporary speed restrictions in 
SES Territory.
4. All of the above.
 
If temporary speed restriction transponders
 are not in place in SES Territory:
 1. Trains do not have to comply with the temporary speed restriction.
2. This information must be added on Form D, Line 13 or the Bulletin Order
 establishing the temporary speed restriction.
3. This information must be verbally relayed to the engineer before the 
train departs its initial terminal.
4. None of the above.
 
Track out of service transponders may
be placed in conjunction with the out of service limits of a track removed
from service in accordance with Rule 133:
 1. Never.
2. Sometimes.
3. Whenever possible.
4. Always. 

 Rule 308, Reverse movements - Direction:
 
When operating under Rule 116 (Operating
 from other than the leading end&quot; using locomotives types SW1500, GP40-2
and GP40-2B:
 1. The SES must be left cut in to prevent a penalty brake application.
2. The SES must be cut out to prevent a penalty brake application.
3. The SES must be constantly moved from cut in to cut out to prevent a 
penalty brake application.
4. All of the above. 

 A reverse movement within the same block:
 1. Must never be made.
2. Can be made without cutting out the SES.
3. Must be made with the reverser in forward.
4. Cannot be made in SES Territory.
 
When operating under Rule 116 on an electric
 locomotive:
 1. The controller must be in the forward position
2. The controller must be in the neutral position.
3. The controller must be in the reverse position.
4. The controller must be removed.
 
Rule 309 ABS Failure:

 During an ABS failure:
 1. The SES must be cut out, DCS rule are in effect.
2. The SES must be cut in, DCS Rules are in effect.
3. The SES must be cut out Form 19 rules are in effect.
4. The SES must be cut in, Form 19 rules are in effect.
 
Rule 310, SES Release Code:
 
At all locations where a train leaves
SES Territory or enters non-SES Territory:
 1. A flagman is on duty to notify the engineer that he is leaving SES
 Territory.
2. A member of management is on duty to notify the engineer that he is
leaving SES Territory.
3. A transponder is located to automatically change the SES to inactive.
4. Once in SES Territory, the train may never leave.
 
In the event that this feature fails and
 the SES remains active:
 1. The engineer must contact the Dispatcher and advise him of the failure.
2. The Dispatcher must issue a release code to the engineer.
3. The engineer must enter the release code using the SDU keypad to make 
the SES light amber (inactive.
4. All of the above.
5. None of the above.
 
Employees are prohibited from entering 
the SES Release Code:
 1. While the train is in motion.
2. When the HEP is down.
3. Without cutting out the SES apparatus.
4. While operating in SES Territory. 

 Rule 311, Work trains Operating in SES
Territory:
 
Work trains operating in working limits 
that require forward and backward movements or where work would be impeded 
by stopping at all signal locations:
 1. May request permission from the employee in charge of the track to 
cut out the SES.
2. May request permission from the Project Trainmaster to cut out the SES.
3. May request permission from the Dispatcher to cut out the SES.
4. None of the above. 

 Rule 403, Operating in both directions in DCS territory: 

 A train authorized by Form D, line 2 to operate in both directions: 
1. Must report to the Dispatcher before he changes direction within the limits
of the Form D.
2. Must mark the time on his Form D each time he reverses direction.
3. Has exclusive occupancy of the track and may operate in either direction.
4. Is in deep trouble because operating in both direction requires two Form
Ds. 

 Once a train has been issued a Form D, line 2 for movement in both directions,
the Dispatcher: 
1. Can allow other trains into the limits of the Form D with permission of
the train crew who &quot;owns&quot; the Form D authority.
2. Can allow track equipment into the limits of the Form D, line 2 with permission
of the crew that &quot;owns&quot; the Form D authority.
3. Must not authorize other movements into the line 2 limits.
4. Must not authorize the train to leave the limits of the Form D authority 
until the Form D, line 4 is canceled. 

 Once a Form D, line 2 has been issued for movement in both directions: 
1. The Form D authority is good for the calendar day.
2. The Form D authority is good until midnight after it is issued.
3. The Form D authority is good until canceled.
4. The Form D authority is good until the movement is complete. 

 Switches within the limits of the Form D, line 2 authority: 
1. Can be left open after the crew is finished with the Form D authority
2. Can be left open but must be locked in the normal position before the
Form D, line 2 is canceled.
3. Must be restored to the normal position after each use.
4. Must not be used without permission of the Dispatcher. 

 Rule 405, Reporting to Dispatcher or Operator: 

 The crew of a train must that ensure that the Dispatcher or Operator 
is promptly notified: 
1. When it is time to go home.
2. When it is lunch time.
3. When entering DCS territory or clearing the limits of their specific direction
line 2 authority except at interlockings, control points, or TBS.
4. When entering DCS territory at a Bridge or tunnel. 

 Trains may report clear of DCS territory or intermediate points only 
after the employee has determined that the rear car: 
1. Has derailed.
2. Has caught fire.
3. Is still coupled to the train.
4. Has cleared. 

 Rule 505, Clearing a block, Switches restored to 
normal: 

 When a train clears a block at 
a hand-operated switch or crossover and the switches have been restored to the 
normal position:
 1. It must be reported clear to the Yardmaster..
2. It must be reported clear to the Dispatcher.
3. It must be reported clear to the switch tender who will report it to the 
Yardmaster.
4. It need not be reported clear if the switch is connected to the signal 
system. 
 When hand-operated switches has been 
restored to normal, even thought the train has not been reported clear of the 
block:
 1. The train may reenter the block on signal indication from a member of the 
crew.
2. The train may reenter the block to complete a switching move.
3. The train may reenter the block if the switches are properly lined for the 
movement.
4. The train must not again enter that block without permission of the 
Dispatcher. 
 Rule 551, Testing the cab signal apparatus 
 Cab signal equipment on the leading end of the first engine or control
car must be tested and found operational: 
1. Within 24 hours before the engine or control car leaves it&apos;s initial terminal.
2. Once a week or if a defect has been reported.
3. Once a month.
4. When the engine is shopped. 
 If test equipment is not available at a point where an intermediate
unit becomes a lead unit: 
1. The intermediate unit cannot be used.
2. Speed is restricted to thirty (30) MPH.
3. The unit must be tested at the initial terminal.
4. The Dispatcher must be notified and equipped territory not entered. 
 When the cab signal equipment is de-energized after the departure
test has been made: 
1. The equipment must be scrapped.
2. The equipment cannot leave the next station.
3. The equipment must be tested again prior to entering equipped
territory.
4. The engineer will be taken out of service. 
 Engines dispatched from terminal point in CSS territory must: 
1. Continue to operate only in CSS territory.
2. Have the cab signal apparatus energized for the entire trip.
3. De-energize the cab signal apparatus when leaving CSS territory.
4. Be tested again before re-entering CSS territory. 
 If the audible indicator fails to sound before departing the initial
terminal: 
1. The Dispatcher must be notified and the equipment must not enter
equipped territory.
2. The engine cannot leave the initial terminal.
3. The shop must fix the cab signal equipment.
4. The engineer must report the defect at the terminating station. 
 When necessary to operate an equipped unit or end that has not been
given a departure test: 
1, The unit may operate at normal speed, wayside signals govern.
2. The cab signals must be considered inoperative, rule 554 in effect.
3. The cab signals must be tested before proceeding.
4. A crew member, qualified on the territory, must remain in the cab
with the engineer. 
 Cab Signal, Automatic Train Stop, or Speed Control Failure on 
equipment used in turnaround service: 
 A train that has experienced 
a cab signal, automatic train stop, or speed control failure may be 
dispatched from a turnaround point:
 1. Never.
2. If the Dispatcher is in a good mood.
3. The equipment is used in turnaround service between it&apos;s originating 
terminal and the turnaround point and the equipment received a satisfactory 
cab signal test within the previous 24 hours, and no mechanical forces are 
at the turnaround point to repair the equipment.
4. None of the above.

 The crew of the equipment must:
 1. Seek advise from their psychic advisor before leaving the turnaround 
point.
2. Go for lunch.
3. Not leave the turnaround point until the equipment is fixed and a 
satisfactory cab signal test is received.
4. Notify the Dispatcher of the failure before leaving the turnaround 
point. 
 Rule 553, Cab signal changes between fixed signals 
 When a cab signal changes to Restricting between fixed signals: 
1. The engineer must dump the train.
2. The engineer must dump the train and run back through the cars yelling:
EMERGENCY, EMERGENCY, EMERGENCY!
3. The engineer must immediately reduce speed to Medium speed.
4. The engineer must take action at once to reduce to Restricted speed. 
 If an interlocking signal requires Medium or Limited Speed and the
cab signal changes to a more favorable aspect: 
1. The cab signal system has failed.
2. The engineer can ignore the cab signal since the more restrictive
indication applies.
3. Speed must not be increased until the train has run it&apos;s length.
4. Speed can be increased as soon as the more the cab signal indication
changes. 
 If the cab signal changes from a Restricting to a more favorable
aspect: 
1. Speed cannot be increased until the cab signal conforms to two wayside
signal.
2. Speed can be increased as soon as the cab signal indication changes.
3. Speed cannot be increased until the train has run it&apos;s length or
500 feet, whichever is greater.
4. Speed cannot be increased until the cab signal conforms to the next
wayside signal. 
 If the cab signal changes from Clear to Approach Medium between fixed
signals: 
1. Trains must immediately reduce speed to Restricting as there is
no Approach Medium cab signal aspect.
2. Trains must immediately reduce speed to Limited Speed and further
reduce to Medium Speed if the next signal displays an aspect requiring
Medium Speed.
3. Trains must immediately reduce speed to Medium Speed.
4. Trains may continue at Normal Speed until the cab signal changes
to Approach. 
 If the cab signal does not conform the fixed signal at the entrance
to a block and the fixed signal is more restrictive: 
1. The cab signal will govern movement through the entire block.
2. The fixed signal will govern movement until the cab signal conforms.
3. The fixed signal will govern movement through the entire block.
4. The cab signal is considered failed and the Dispatcher must be notified. 
 Rule 552, Conformity between cab signals and fixed signals 

 Being interconnected with the fixed signal system, the cab signal must
conform with the fixed signal system: 
1. Within ten (10) seconds after the train enters the block.
2. Within five (5) seconds after the train enters the block.
3. Within three (3) seconds after the train enters the block.
4. Within three (3) seconds prior to the train entering the block. 

 When cab signal and fixed signal do not conform: 
1. The more restrictive signal indication will govern and the Dispatcher notified
as soon as possible.
2. The cab signal will govern and the Dispatcher notified when the train
arrives at it&apos;s destination.
3. The train crew must be notified.
4. The engineer must panic. 

 Rule 555, Criteria for determining cab signal apparatus failure 

 The cab signals will be considered as having failed when: 
1. The audible indicator fails to sound when the cab signal changes to a
more restrictive aspect.
2. The audible indicator continues to sound after a cab signal change has
been acknowledged and acted upon.
3. The cab signal fails to conform at two (2) fixed signals in succession.
4. All the above. 

 If a cab signal displaying &quot;restricting&quot; fails to conform to a fixed 
signal of &quot;approach&quot; or better or damage occurs to any part of the cab signal
apparatus: 
1. The engineer must panic.
2. The cab signal apparatus has failed.
3. The train must be stopped.
4. The train must be reduced to restricted speed. 

 When approaching a fixed signal displaying approach or better in CSS
territory without fixed automatic signals, the cab signal displays Restricting
and fails to conform after passing the fixed signal: 
1. The engineer will become confused.
2. The engineer must consider the cab signals failed.
3. The engineer must consider the wisdom of eliminating wayside signals.
4. The engineer will take his pension. 

 When approaching a fixed signal displaying stop and proceed, Restricting, 
or a Stop Signal and the cab signal displays an aspect more favorable than 
approach: 
1. The engineer must immediately stop the train and not move until the cab
signals are repaired.
2. The engineer must curse the mechanical department.
3. The engineer must call the conductor up to the cab to witness the crash.
4. The engineer must consider the cab signals failed. 

 The criteria for determining a failed cab signal do not apply: 
1. When the engineer is asleep.
2. The engineer passes the signal and doesn&apos;t comply.
3. No management is on board the train.
4. The fixed signal is imperfectly displayed. 

 Rule 608, Delay in an Interlocking: 
 If a train has passed an Interlocking signal and is 
delayed:
 1. It may proceed according to the last signal indication received.
2. It may proceed at normal speed if the track ahead is known to be clear.
3. It Must proceed at Restricted Speed.
4. None of the above. 
 If the track is seen to 
be clear to the next signal and the next signal indicates proceed:
 1. The train may operated in accordance with the last signal indication 
received.
2. The train may operate at Medium speed.
3. The train may operate at normal speed.
4. The train may operate at a speed required to make up time.

 When a train is delay while operating in cab signal territory:
 1. It may operate at Restricted Speed until it travels 500 feet of one train 
length, then proceed according to cab signal indication.
2. It may operate in accordance with cab signal indication.
3. It may operate at Restricted Speed until the entire train passes a more 
favorable signal.
4. All of the above. 
 Rule 609, Interlocking or Controlled Point changes to Stop: 

 If an interlocking aspect permitting a train to proceed changes to
Stop before it is reached: 
1. The engineer must dump the train.
2. The engineer must call his Local Chairman and ask what to do.
3. The engineer must notify the Dispatcher immediately screaming &quot;Train Wreck,
Train Wreck,
Train Wreck&quot;.
4. The stop must be made as soon as same train handling will permit.

 Rule 612, Reversing Direction within an Interlocking:
 
To reverse direction within an interlocking the train must:
 1. Have the proper interlocking signal or permission of the Dispatcher
or Operator.
2. Be completely within the limits of the interlocking.
3. Get permission prior to entering the interlocking.
4. All of the above. 

 Rule 705, Radio Transmission and Reception Procedures:
 
Before Transmitting on a radio the employee must:
 1. Be able to speak fluently in Spanish.
2. Must make sure his radio has batteries.
3. Shout loudly into the microphone.
4. Listen to ensure that the channel on which he intends to transmit is not
in use.
 
 All transmissions must be repeated by the employee receiving them except:
 1. Those that make no sense.
2. Those that only affect the movement of one train.
3. Transmissions used in yard service or do not contain information, instructions,
or advice that could affect the safety of a railroad operation.
4. Numbers 1 and 2.
 

 Employees must insure that:
 1. All radios on the railroad are set to the same channel.
2. Radio contact has been made with the proper persons.
3. They are properly rested before transmitting.
4. Their radios are not use to chock wheels on passenger cars. 

 Except for emergency communications, any radio transmission that is
not fully understood:
 1. Can be acted upon if it is partially understood.
2. Shall not be acted upon.
3. Must be repeated three time to make sure everyone understands it.
4. Must be written down and discussed by the crew in a job briefing.
 

 An Employee receiving a radio call:
 1. Must acknowledge the call immediately unless doing so would interfere
with safety.
2. Must acknowledge the call immediately even if doing so would interfere
with safety.
3. Must write down the message then repeat it back to the sender.
4. Must immediately act upon it as it is being received. 

 Rule 709, Prohibited Transmissions:
 
Employees must not knowingly transmit:
 1. Any false distress communication.
2. Any unnecessary, irrelevant, or unidentified communication.
3. Any obscene, indecent, or profane remark.
4. All of the above.

 Rule 710, Radio identification in the yard:

 When positive identification is achieved in connection with switching, 
classification, and similar operations wholly within a yard, fixed or 
mobile units may use:
 1. Obscene gestures.
2. Written messages.
3. Cell phones.
4. Short identification after the initial transmission and acknowledgement.

 Such messages must include:
 1. The lunch order.
2. Obscene language.
3. Engine or unit number.
4. Girlfriend&apos;s telephone numbers.

 If positive exchange of communications continues without substantial 
interruption, positive identification must be repeated:
 1. once a day.
2. Every four hours.
3. Every hour.
4. Every 15 minutes.
 
Rule 712, Signal Indications: 

 Dispatchers or Operators 
must not advise:
 1. Other employees on matter concerning money.
2. Aspect, name, or indication of any fixed signal.
3. Which crew will get off duty first.
4. When to brush your teeth. 

 Crew members may use the radio:
 1. To order pizza.
2. To call home.
3. To call their bookie.
4. communicate a fixed signal to other members of the crew.

 Except as noted in Rule 241, radio communications may not be used:
 1. Notify the Dispatcher of an emergency.
2. Advise the engineer of the distance of a movement.
3. To convey instructions that would have the effect of overriding the 
indication of a fixed signal.
4. Report a mechanical defect. 

 Rule 958, Visibility Compromised:

 If anything distracts attention from a constant lookout ahead
or if weather conditions make observation of signals in any way doubtful: 
 1. The engineer should speed up to get clear of the problems quickly.
2. Engine service employees must at once regulate the speed of their train
to ensure safety.
3. Engine Service employees will be late for lunch.
4. All of the above. 
 Return to the&quot;Unofficial Hoboken Division 
Engineer&apos;s Web Site
	</body>
</document>
