<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001043" url="http://www.chacha.com/question/how-much-does-a-16-oz-cup-of-soda-cost" time="2012-07-12-16:27" support="1" score="0.0006332595796020049" bingtitle="How much does a 16 oz cup of soda cost? | ChaCha" webtitle="How much does a 16 oz cup of soda cost? | ChaCha">
			<query id="001025" bing-rank="159"/>
	<description>What kind of crime is it if you throw a cup of soda at a Fast Food restaurant? ... At the dinner table, what do you gravitate towards? Sauces- I ...</description>
	<body>
		About ChaCha 
 
 ChaCha 

 Questions Categories 
 Entertainment 
 Art&amp;Design Celebrities Events Games Humor Literature Movie Showings Movies Music Song Lyrics TV&amp;Radio Theater 
 Sports 
 Baseball Basketball Football Golf Hockey Motorsports Olympics Scores Soccer Tennis 
 Culture 
 Christianity Cultures&amp;Groups Demographics Education Family Historic Figures History Islam Judaism Mormonism Mythology&amp;Folklore Name Etymology Relationships&amp;Dating Religion&amp;Spirituality 
 Politics 
 Campaigns&amp;Elections Law Military Political Figures State&amp;Local Gov. U.S. Government Wars&amp;Conflicts World Governments 
 Lifestyle 
 Bars&amp;Nightlife Dining Out Food&amp;Drink GLBT Green Living Home&amp;Garden Pets Recreation Shopping Style&amp;Beauty 
 Lookup 
 Definitions Mail&amp;Shipping Non-Famous People Puzzles Translations Weather&amp;Time White Pages Yellow Pages 
 SciTech 
 Animals&amp;Plants Astronomy Automotive Biology Chemistry Computers Consumer Electronics Earth Sciences Internet Math Physics Science 
 Business Health Travel 
 Galleries Quizzes 
 Sign In 
 Please enable JavaScript in your browser to immerse yourself in our rich user experience. 
 X 
 
 
How much does a 16 oz cup of soda cost? 

In: Lifestyle › Food&amp;Drink 
 
Rate This Answer
 
A 16 ounce Cup of Soda is normally just under $2, in the $1.89 range on average from convenience stores. Thanks! 
 Answered

 by Clavel R. - 740 days ago at 3:42pm on Jul 02 2010 
Related Questions for Food&amp;Drink 

 
 How many calories are in a 32 oz cup of soda? 

An 8 oz cup of soda-pop has 105 calories so a 3...

in Diet&amp;Nutrition | 12 hr 18 min ago via sms text 
 
 How many cups of sugar is in 1 can of sunkist orange soda? 

1 can of Sunkist soda has 52 grams of sugar. I ...

in Diet&amp;Nutrition | 2 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 If you put a cup with soda and ice in the fridge, will the ice melt? 

If you put it in the Fridge most likely over ti...

in Food&amp;Drink | 3 days ago via Android app 
 
 What band did the song Soda in The Water Cup? 

Attila is the band that does the song&quot;Soda in ...

in Music | 4 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 How much does it cost to make a cup of soda? 

A soda mix bottle makes about 33 cans of soda, ...

in Shopping | 7 days ago via sms text 
 
 Why does soda fizzle when you pour it into a cup of ice? 

Any gas that is in&quot;solution&quot;in a liquid, like...

in Science | 18 days ago via web 
 
 Why do sodas foam up when you poor them in to a cup? 

Soda foams because the dissolved carbon dioxide...

in Food&amp;Drink | 22 days ago via Android app 
 
 How many cups are in 2 cans of a can of soda? 

There are 12 ounces in a standard can of soda, ...

in Diet&amp;Nutrition | 24 days ago via sms text 
 
 Is it true that if you put a tooth in a cup of soda it will decay over night? 

Adults who drink three or more sodas a day have...

in Science | 32 days ago via Android app 
 
 How many calories are in one cup of AW cream soda? 

In 8 fl ounces there are 120 calories. Text Cha...

in Diet&amp;Nutrition | 46 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 How much more caffeine does a cup of coffee have than a 12 oz soda? 

The amount of caffeine in an average cup of cof...

in Diet&amp;Nutrition | 57 days ago via iPhone app 
 
 How many cups are in a pound of baking soda? 

While cups are a measure of volume and pounds a...

in Diet&amp;Nutrition | 57 days ago via sms text 
 
 See All Questions ▶   
Related Galleries for Food&amp;Drink 

 
 
 
 Healthy Smoothie Recipes 
 Viewed 14 times 
 
 
 
 Delectable State Fair Foods 
 Viewed 91 times 
 
 
 
 Healthy BBQ Burgers 
 Viewed 182 times 
 
 
 
 Summer Foods: Skip That, Savor This 
 Viewed 826 times 
 
 
 
 How to Prevent Food Poisoning at a BBQ 
 Viewed 28 times 
 
 
 
 Best Late-Night Snacks 
 Viewed 2898 times 
 
 See All Galleries ▶ 
Related Quizzes for Food&amp;Drink 

 
 
 
 Which Late Night Snacks Won&apos;t Make You Fat? 
 
 
 
 Are You Getting Enough Vitamin D? 
 
 
 
 Should You Go on a Detox Diet? 
 
 
 
 Do You Scream For Ice Cream? 
 
 
 
 Which Girl Scout Cookie Are You? 
 Viewed 61974 times 
 
 
 
 Are You Ruining Your Teeth? 
 
 See All Quizzes ▶ 
Share This Page:

 Facebook Tweet Email 
 Advertisement 
Top Trends in Food&amp;Drink 

 Fish» Fruits» Tequila» Pepsi» Vegan» Lemon» Gluten» Yogurt» Pickles» Gatorade» 
 
Top Trends in Lifestyle 

 Puppies» Makeup» Restaurant» Fishing» Kittens» Fast Food» liquor» McDonalds» Pizza» Coke» 
 
Top Trends

 Love» 100 Floors» Say in Spanish» Boy» Facebook» Illegal» Website» Area Code» Hurt» Cancer» 
 Advertisement Home › Categories › Lifestyle › Food&amp;Drink 
Text Your Question

* ChaCha does not charge for its service.
Message and Data Rates May Apply.
If you need help, text HELP to 242-242 .
To cancel your service, text STOP to 242-242 .
 
ChaCha Mobile Apps
 
 ChaCha for iPhone ChaCha for iPad ChaCha for Android 
 
Connect

 Become a ChaCha Fan on Facebook Follow ChaCha on Twitter Follow ChaCha on Pinterest Follow ChaCha on Google+ Follow ChaCha on Apple Follow ChaCha on Android 

 About Contact FAQs 
 
Services

 Questions&amp;Answers Become a Guide Work for ChaCha 

 Advertise With Us ChaCha Mobile Affiliate Program 
 
©Copyright 2006-2012 ChaCha Search, Inc.–Experimental Use, All Rights Reserved, May Be Covered by US or Foreign Patents or Patents Pending. Copyright Notice | Terms of Use | Privacy
	</body>
</document>
