<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001683" url="http://www.flipdog.com/jobs/kansas-city/compass-bank/" time="2012-07-12-17:27" support="1" score="0.0017269299734389847" bingtitle="Kansas City Compass Bank Jobs &amp; Employment - FlipDog Job Search" webtitle="Kansas City Compass Bank JobsEmployment - FlipDog Job Search">
			<query id="001448" bing-rank="125"/>
	<description>Job Purpose: Serves fast food restaurant customers by directing ... internal and external guests (ex., general cashier ... General ledger Financial reporting Month-end ...</description>
	<body>
		Kansas City Compass Bank Jobs

Sort by: Date | Relevance 
 
 Kansas City/Independence MO   Kansas City KS   Kansas City MO   
 
 
 Financial Advisor BMO Harris Bank (Kansas City/Independence, Missouri) 

BMO Harris Bank is seeking a Finanacial Advisor to work in our Kansas City, MO location. To explore this great career opportunity, please visit our website and apply at: Click here to Apply Established in 1817 as Bank of Montreal, BMO Financial Group (TSX, NYSE: BMO) is a highly diversified financial services organization. With total assets of $477 billion as of October 31, 2011, and more than 47,...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Wed 23rd May
 
 Part Time Money Room Clerk A - Kansas City, MO Brink’s Inc. (Kansas City/Independence, Missouri) 

Job ID: 2352 Position Description: Brink’s U.S., a division of Brink’s, Incorporated, is the premier provider of armored car transportation, ATM servicing, currency and coin processing, document destruction and other value added services to financial institutions, retailers and other commercial and government entities. The company has a proud history of providing growth and advancement opportuniti...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Mon 4th June
 
 Personal Banker - Briarcliff ( M&amp;I Location ) BMO Harris Bank (Kansas City/Independence, Missouri) 

BMO Harris Bank is seeking a Personal Banker - Briarcliff ( M&amp;I Location ) to work in our Kansas City, MO location. To explore this great career opportunity, visit our website at: Click here to Apply At our company, we have been helping our customers and communities for over 125 years. In July 2011, our parent company BMO Financial Group acquired Marshall&amp;Ilsley Corporation (M&amp;I;). Over the nex...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Mon 11th June
 
 Part-Time Supervisor Carter&apos;s/OshKosh B&apos;Gosh (Kansas City, Kansas) 

Carter’s and OshKosh B’Gosh are two of the oldest, largest and most recognized branded marketers of baby and young children’s apparel in the U.S. Based on the belief that childhood is a celebration, our brands are all about creating products for children that are distinguished by quality and creative art and color. We strive to be a great Company to do business with, to have as a neighbor and to w...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Thu 21st June
 
 Sales Representative / Account Manager Evo Merchant Services (Kansas City/Independence, Missouri) 

Our organization is looking for local reps in this area to establish our brand and products. For the last 20 years, we have grown to a $22 billion dollar sales organization and one of the best in our industry simply because we have some of the most talented sales professionals in America. As we continue to take our brand nationwide, we need your sales talent to build a valuable portfolio in your a...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Mon 25th June
 
 Sales Centex Payments (Kansas City/Independence, Missouri) 

Centex Payments is looking for Dynamic Sales Representatives that can run confirmed, pre-set appointments. We offer an excellent commission plan that includes a $3,000.00 JUMP START BONUS, cell phone and gas allowances along with medical, dental and vision insurance. As an employee of Centex you can expect to earn $800.00 - $2,000.00 weekly. $100.00 Bonus Paid on First Sale! Position Requirements:...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Mon 25th June
 
 Data Analyst Adaptive Solutions Group (Kansas City/Independence, Missouri) 

ADAPTIVE SOLUTIONS GROUP IS LOOKING FOR 3 IMMEDIATE DATA ANALYSTS FOR PERMANENT, FULL TIME OPPORTUNITIES IN KC. 401K AND PENSION PLANS, COMPREHENSIVE INSURANCE PLANS, TUITION REIMBURSEMENTS AND A TON OF GROWTH POTENTIAL. SEND RESUMES AND REFERRALS TO avoss@adaptivesg.com FOR DETAILS!!! Statisical Analysis, Data Packaging and Delivery, Data Research and Reporting and Business Objects as it relates ...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Tue 26th June
 
 Treasury Sales Executive The Lewis Group (St. Louis, Missouri) 

Are you ready to work for a bank that has invested in itself, so they can invest in YOU?? Do you have experience working with Cash/Treasury Services in a sales capacity? Would you be interested in working for one of the most admired, respected and dependable banks in the country? While other banks have been in a holding pattern, our client, a Mega Regional Top “A” rated bank has been investing mil...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Wed 27th June
 
 Retail Banking Specialist - Kansas City, MO Beal Bank (Overland Park, Kansas) 

Beal Bank Retail Banking Specialist Kansas City, MO 　 Are you looking for a non-traditional banking opportunity? Beal Bank, one of the most successful privately owned banks in the nation, is growing and seeking a Retail Branch Specialist for our retail branch located in Kansas City (Overland Park), MO. We are a wholesale bank with a focus on deposits and related services. Our branch product lines ...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Mon 2nd July
 
 Credit Specialist Heubel Material Handling (Kansas City/Independence, Missouri) 

Heubel Material Handling, Inc. provides the best narrow aisle material handling equipment in the Central and Central-Southern United States. Heubel is a team of highly professional people who have dedicated themselves to providing top quality service to customers. We are searching for the right individual to join our growing company. Immediate opportunity for CREDIT SPECIALIST Position Summary: Th...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Tue 3rd July
 
 Store Manager - Levi’s® Outlet Store - Kansas City, KS LeviStrauss&amp;Co. (Kansas City, Kansas) 

The purpose of this position is to direct and lead superior retail strategies and execute store operation functions to deliver financial growth and sustained brand equity. Meet or exceed established store sales and performance goals daily Model sales performance for retail associates Coach employees, ensuring that all associates are fully trained on product knowledge Reconcile daily cash receipts ...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted 3 days ago
 
 Sr. Credit Analyst Citizens Bank&amp;Trust (Kansas City/Independence, Missouri) 

Responsiveness, Competency&amp;Clarity are necessary to deliver the Citizens Experience as Senior Credit Analyst. You will be responsible for assisting the Commercial Lending staff by; spreading and analyzing financial statement, including performance ratios, performing credit underwriting and analysis of loan relationships, mentoring credit trainees, presenting to loan committee, assisting in admin...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted 3 days ago
 
 Sales / Customer Service - Part Time / Full Time - Entry Level / Summer Work Vector Marketing Corporation (Kansas City/Independence, Missouri) 

Want to work full or part time with a company that gives you the opportunity to make money while gaining professional skills? Looking for something other than your typical retail or administrative job? Need to bulk up both your resume and your bank account this summer? You should apply to work with us. We’re Vector Marketing, and for the last 30 years, we’ve been successfully taking people with li...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted 2 days ago
 
 Sales / Customer Service - Part Time / Full Time - Entry Level / Summer Work Vector Marketing Corporation (Kansas City/Independence, Missouri) 

Want to work full or part time with a company that gives you the opportunity to make money while gaining professional skills? Looking for something other than your typical retail or administrative job? Need to bulk up both your resume and your bank account this summer? You should apply to work with us. We’re Vector Marketing, and for the last 30 years, we’ve been successfully taking people with li...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted 2 days ago
 
 Insurance Agent Rodney D. Young Insurance (Kansas City/Independence, Missouri) 

Current Openings: Full-TimeCSR&apos;s and P&amp;C;Licensed Agents Current Opening Location: Kansas City, MO Job Description: Quoting, issuing and endorsing auto insurance policies, greeting and servicing customer’s auto insurance needs, answering incoming calls, receive payments, make bank deposits, general office duties. Requirements: Proficient skills in the following areas: Communication Organization Se...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted 2 days ago
 
 Money Room Clerk F - Kansas City, MO Brink’s Inc. (Kansas City/Independence, Missouri) 

Job ID: 2512 Position Description: Brink’s U.S., a division of Brink’s, Incorporated, is the premier provider of armored car transportation, ATM servicing, currency and coin processing, document destruction and other value added services to financial institutions, retailers and other commercial and government entities. The company has a proud history of providing growth and advancement opportuniti...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted 2 days ago
 
 Cage Cashier, Part-Time Ameristar Casinos, Inc. (Kansas City/Independence, Missouri) 

-Candidates must be able to work nights as well as weekends. - Provide an outlet of sales and redemption of coin and chips for internal and external guests (ex., general cashier, main bank, fill bank and jackpot/fill window). - Adhere to established department and property policies and procedures regarding guest service standards. - Assure the securing of company funds, provide accurate and courte...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Wed 27th June
 
 Cage Cashier Ameristar Casinos, Inc. (Kansas City/Independence, Missouri) 

Candidates must be able to work nights as well as weekends Provide an outlet of sales and redemption of coin and chips for internal and external guests (ex., general cashier, main bank, fill bank and jackpot/fill window) Adhere to established department and property policies and procedures regarding guest service standards Assure the securing of company funds, provide accurate and courteous guest ...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted 3 days ago
 
 Staff Accountant Accounting Principals (Kansas City/Independence, Missouri) 

Immediate Opening for a Staff Accountant Extraordinary People. Exciting Possibilities. Great Opportunity for an Accounting Professional In a highly competitive world, there&apos;s one thing that sets a company apart-it?s talent people. At Accounting Principals we bring their expertise, enthusiasm and creativity to work every day to make us the place to work and employer of choice We&apos;re committed to mak...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Yesterday
 
 Full-Time And Part-Time Teller Positions Available! UMB Financial Corporation (Kansas City/Independence, Missouri) 

Are you looking for a career in customer service? Do you have experience in sales? Do you have cash handling experience? If you answered YES to all of these questions UMB Bank is looking for you! UMB has immediate openings for part-time and full-time Tellers and Retail Specialists throughout the Kansas City area. We are seeking customer-focused individuals with a minimum of 6 months cash handling ...
 Full job description at Monster 
 
Posted Yesterday
 
 
 1 2 3 Next 20 Kansas City Compass Bank Jobs 
 
Kansas City Job Search Tip

Major employers in Kansas include Learjet, Sprint, Goodyear Tire and Rubber Company, Applebee&apos;s, Koch Industries and the Department of Defense. The highest paid professionals in Kansas are Anesthesiologists, Doctors and Surgeons, and Air Traffic Controllers. According to America&apos;s Career InfoNet, the most job openings in Kansas are for Cashiers, Retail Salespeople, and Food Service Workers.

 Kansas at a Glance: 

 
Unemployment Rate: 4.7%
 
2005 Per Capita Income: $32,836
 
Largest Cities: Wichita, Overland Park, Kansas City, Topeka, Olathe
 
Minimum Hourly Wage: $2.65

Here are some jobs to look at:
 Radiation Therapist Jobs , Radiation Therapist Jobs by State 
 Technical Writer Jobs , Technical Writer Jobs by State 
 Tour Guide Jobs , Tour Guide Jobs by State 
 Delivery Driver Jobs , Delivery Driver Jobs by State 
 Strategic Account Manager Jobs , Strategic Account Manager Jobs by State 

Find more Kansas Jobs on Monster.com.

Learn how to write a resume , find relevant examples of resumes , read through resume help , and then create your resume .

Search through Kansas jobs by city on Flipdog!
 
 
Related Cities
 
 Jefferson City Compass Bank Jobs 
 Kansas City/Independence Compass Bank Jobs 
 Northeastern Missouri Compass Bank Jobs 
 Quincy Compass Bank Jobs 
 Southeastern Missouri Compass Bank Jobs 
 Springfield/Joplin Compass Bank Jobs 
 St Louis Compass Bank Jobs 
 More Related Cities… 
 
Job Categories
 
 Accounting Jobs In Kansas City 
 Construction Jobs In Kansas City 
 Education Jobs In Kansas City 
 Engineering Jobs In Kansas City 
 Finance Jobs In Kansas City 
 Government Jobs In Kansas City 
 Healthcare Jobs In Kansas City 
 Marketing Jobs In Kansas City 
 Nursing Jobs In Kansas City 
 Real Estate Jobs In Kansas City 
 Retail Jobs In Kansas City 
 Sales Jobs In Kansas City 
 Security Jobs In Kansas City 
 Teaching Jobs In Kansas City 
 More Job Categories… 
 
Create a FREE Monster account!

 Build a searchable resume and let employers find you Sign up for a JobAgent and have jobs emailed to you Get expert career advice 
 
 Services from Monster.com 

Career Resources
 
 Career Advice Sample Resumes&amp;Cover Letters Salary Comparison Calculator Entry-level Jobs&amp;Internships Scholarship Search Online Degrees&amp;Continuing Education 
 
Monster for Employers
 
 
 Post Jobs 

Post jobs in minutes and get immediate results
 
 Search Resumes 

Search by Zip Code, Title, Industry and Keyword
 
 
Share this Page
 URL: 
Share this page with friends on:
 
 Del.icio.us Digg Facebook Netscape StumbleUpon Reddit 
 
 
 Job Search Home Jobs by Category Jobs by Title Jobs by Company Most Popular Job Searches Search Tips Job Posting 
 
Get these results in RSS   
 
 Job Seekers: Search Jobs Post Your Resume Create a Free Account Find Career Advice Sign-up for Job Alerts 

 Employers: Monster Hiring Solutions Post Jobs Search Resumes 

 The Monster Network: Scholarship Search Financial Aid Internships Online Degree Search More Monster Sites 
 
 About FlipDog Jobs by State New Jobs Privacy Terms of Service  Copyright©2012 FlipDog. All Rights Reserved. 
 Keywords Location 
Powered by  
 
 Advanced Search Recent Searches Search Tips 
 
 You are here: Home Missouri Jobs Kansas City Jobs Kansas City Compass Bank Jobs
	</body>
</document>
