<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001789" url="http://www.newyorkemployeehandbook.com/NY_Restaurant_Handbook.html" time="2012-07-12-17:34" support="12" score="0.0433024352647399" bingtitle="Instant Customized New York Restaurant - NY Fast Food Restaurant ..." webtitle="Instant Customized New York Restaurant - NY Fast Food Restaurant Employee Handbook, Policy Manual">
			<query id="001215" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="001198" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="001218" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="001207" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001214" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="001191" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000178" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000427" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="001180" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="001369" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="001495" bing-rank="166"/>
			<query id="000898" bing-rank="176"/>
	<description>... New York Restaurant Employee Handbook - Fast Food Restaurant ... change to keep your Employee Handbook and policies ... At Will Employment &amp; Receipt of Employee Handbook ...</description>
	<body>
		NY Restaurant Employee Handbook   Attorney Written New York Employee Handbook&amp;Forms in Minutes
 1-888-396-2682 
 Your Subtitle text 
 Home - Employee Handbook NY Restaurant Handbook Custom Employee Handbook 
 
 Instant Customized New York Restaurant Employee Handbook 
 NY Restaurant Employee Handbook, Updated When Laws Change For Lawsuit Protection Current and Compliant with NY and Federal Employment Laws as of:
 
       New York Restaurant Employee Handbook 
                         
 Easy For You to Edit For Your Restaurant Available by Immediate Download Drafted by a New York Business Attorney    Includes Legal Wording for Lawsuit Protection
 
 
               
 Let us write your employee handbook for you.   
            

 
 
 
  
NY Restaurant Employee Handbook With Free Add-ons 
 
         Policy Updates 
  F ree for one Year!
 
 Personalized Free 
 With Your Name
and Your Logo 
  Restaurant Employee Handbook 
 Restaurant Employee Handbook Spanish 
   10 HR&amp;Legal
Employment Forms 
   $99 95 
  
 
  
NY Restaurant Employee Handbook Features&amp;Benefits
  
 

    Fast 
       D ownload this Complete NY Restaurant Employee Handbook in English and Spanish, Ready to go
      with instant lawsuit protection. Available by immediate Download, Email, or CD. 

 
     Easy to Use 
      Policies are already done for you. No blanks to fill in. Easy guidelines tell you which policies apply to your
      business. 

 
    Easy to Edit - MS Word Format 
      I t&apos;s easy to change anything with the click of the mouse. This NY Restaurant Employee Handbook is
      completely customizable.       
  
 
     Up-To-Date When You Order
       Employee Handbooks get out-dated because employment laws change.  We monitor New York and federal
      employment laws and make changes to the NY Employee Handbook as laws change so it is current and
      compliant when you order.
 
  

      Policy Updates Keep Your NY Employee Handbook Up-To-Date For You 
        When the federal government or New York makes a change in an employment law that effects policies in
      this Employee Handbook, you get a new policy from an attorney, emailed to you keeping your NY
      Employee Handbook up-to-date as laws change, 1 year free. We&apos;ll continue to update your Handbook for 
      you for only $2 per month after the first year. This can be the last Employee Handbook you will ever
      need . 
                               
 

 
 
 
   Employee Guidelines 
      Clearly communicates employment &quot;Rules of the Road&quot; and standards you want employees to follow.  
 

    Legal Compliance 
       This NY Restaurant Employee Handbook complies with New York and federal employment policies for your
      legal protection. Easy guidelines tell you which policies apply to your business so you don&apos;t have to figure
      out which laws you have to follow. 


    Lawsuit Protection 
     This NY Restaurant Employee Handbook is drafted by a New York business-employment attorney who
     has been protecting businesses like yours since 1973. Employee Handbooks are legal document that can be
     used as a guide to determine if you violated employment laws. Employee Handbooks can also be used to
     help an win a lawsuit against you. This New York Employee Handbook is designed to help protect you from
     employee lawsuits.
 

            
 
 
    
     About Your Free Add-Ons 
    
 
                   
                
      10 HR and Legal Employee Forms 
       Proper documentation is crucial in protecting and managing your business.
      If you don’t keep good records, how will you prove you are compliant?

 
       Free Customization 
         If you want, we will insert your company name and logo on the cover and throughout the policies
     for you FREE. Just email your logo to us.

          
       Policy Update Club Membership - first year FREE   
      When the federal government or New York makes a change in the law effecting one of these
   policies, we email a new policy to you within days, to keep your NY Employee Handbook and
     policies up-to-date and compliant .   


      Ongoing Policy Updates Maintenance Plan 
      This can be the last Employee Handbook you will ever need. After your first year of free
    updates, you can continue to get your New York Employee Handbook updated and maintained
   for you to keep your handbook current and compliant. Only $2 a month. 

 
  
NY and Federal Compliant Employee Policies 
 
 
 Easy guidelines tell you which policies apply to your business according to NY and federal employment laws.    These policy areas are offered so that you have policies that you need, already written for you. K eep the policies you want, delete the rest.           Related policy areas are combined into one policy for your convenience and easy reading.  
 
      
                 
   
 You Get the Same Quality and Expertise that These Major Companies Trusted 
 
 

 
 
 
  
 NY Restaurant Employee Handbook with Employment Forms Add-ons
    
 
 
Policy Updates 
 English&amp;Spanish
Free for one Year! 

 Personalized Free 
 with Your Name
and Your Logo 
             Restaurant Employee Handbooks English&amp;Spanish Easy tips to: reduce employee turnover&amp; lower training costs 
  37 HR&amp;Legal
Employment Forms 
 
 
        $149.95
 

 
 
 
  
Restaurant Employment Forms Details
  
 37 Hire to Fire Employment Forms 
 
 
 
 Hiring and Pre-Employment Forms 
 
 
 Employee
Handbook +10 Forms
 Employee
Handbook
+ 37 Hire to Fire Forms Employment Application with At Will Acknowledgment 
 Employment Application with At Will Acknowledgment and
Arbitration Provision 
 Confidentiality Agreement 
 
 Authorization for Reference Check&amp;Release of Liability 
 
 Reference Checklist 
 Drug&amp;Alcohol Testing Consent and Release 
 
 Driver’s License&amp; Criminal Background Check Authorization 
 
 Credit Checks - Credit Report Forms 
 Federal Fair Credit Reporting Act requires these forms to be used where credit information is sought in making employment decisions. 
 
 Authorization to Obtain Consumer Credit Report 
 
 Initial Credit Report Disclosure 
 
 Credit Report: Pre-Adverse Action Notice 
 
 Credit Report: Adverse Action Notice 
 
 New Employee Letter, Forms, Agreements 
 New Hire Checklist 
 At Will Employment Agreement 
 
 I-9 
 
 
 Non-Solicitation Agreement 
Pr events ex-employees from soliciting business from customers, suppliers, employees. 
 
 Non-Compete Agreement 
 
 Job Offer Letter 
 
 
 Employee Records and Forms 
 Employee Handbook Receipt&amp;At Will Employment Acknowledgment 
 Employee Evaluation with Employment At Will Notice 
 
 HIPAA Release 
 
 Warning&amp;Disciplinary Action Report with Employment At Will Notice 
 Leave Request - Non-FMLA 
 
 FMLA - Leave Request 
 
 E mployee Conflict of Interest Statement 
 Employee&apos;s Ideas and Suggestions Submission 
 
 Property Receipt Form 
 Change of Personal Information Report 
 
 
                                                     Work Schedule and Payroll Forms 
 Weekly Work Schedule–To Post - Microsoft Excel 
 Payroll Form: Weekly Employee Time Record - Excel 
 
 Payroll Form: Monthly Employee Time Record - Excel 
 Overtime Authorization 
 
 
 Firing, Termination and Exit Forms 
 Notice of Employee&apos;s Failure to Return to Work 
 
 Property Return 
 Exit Interview 
 
 Termination of Employment Report 
 
 
 
 
 $99 95 $149 95 Compare New York Employee Handbook Packages 
 
    
 
 

  
 NY Restaurant Employee Handbook with Business Protection
    
   
   
  
 

U.S. D.O.T.&amp;
Federal
Contractors
Policies
+ much more 

 

 $199 95 Restaurant Employee Handbooks English&amp;Spanish 
 4 Steps to Prevent Disputes&amp;Lawsuits 
 
 Easy-to-understand
laws for businesses

 37 Hr and Legal Forms 
 
 
 
     
   Restaurant Employee Handbook For New York        You Select the Attorney Drafted Handbook Just For Your State

     Up-to-Date and Compliant with Your State and Federal Laws

     Customized For You With Your Company Name and Logo
        
    Spanish Employee Handbook for Your State is included free

 

 
     37 Hire to Fire Employment Forms 
             

     Makes documentation and record-keeping easy

      Provides proof of compliance 
             
                                 



 
 
     Hire and Retain The Best Employees Manual   

       Helpful tips to retain employees, reduce turnover&amp;lower training
    costs 

    How to prepare for the interview to set the stage for success.

    How to interview job applicants to quickly weed out the wrong candidates.

     How to interview job applicants over the telephone to save time &amp;money.

     Why hiring the right employees reduces employee turnover &amp;training costs.

     How to ask the right questions to help you choose the right employees.

     How clues from interviewing applicants can be vital in protecting you.

    Why the decision to hire someone effects your staff and your customers.

     How proper training reduces job turnover and increases productivity.

    How keeping valued employees helps grow your business.            
 

         
   
   
 
 
     Employment Laws for the Workplace   

    Easy to understand overview of business laws for the business
    owner. 
 
     How At Will Employment protects your right to hire and fire employees.

     How Employment Discrimination laws give employees the right to sue you.

    How employee behavior can lead to a Sexual Harassment lawsuit against you

     How your questions  &amp;actions can result in age discrimination claims.

      Why compliance with FLSA will protect you against huge penalties and fees.

     Why not accommodating Disabled employees can jeopardize your business.

     How state&amp;federal FMLA requirements determine laws you have to follow.

     Why you need to know the requirements of Drug-Free Workplace testing.

    How Employee Privacy limits employer&apos;s rights.
           
     How Immigration laws control your workforce and documentation you need.

     How Military Service employee rights effects employee scheduling and jobs.

     How improper Termination of an employee can be expensive and dangerous.

    How EPLI limits your financial damages in an employment lawsuit.   
 
  

       Trademarks   

     Trademarks… 

     What Are They?

     Registration

     The Process of Making Your Mark &quot;Official&quot;

     Rules of the Road

     Proper Trademark Usage

     ®or TM and never a Noun or Verb!

     Disclaimer

 

 
 
          Prevent Employee Disputes&amp;Lawsuits   
     4 Things You Can Do To Right Now to: 
 
     Prevent or Resolve Employee Disputes

     Avoid Lawsuits 
                                  
 
   
                U.S. Dept. of Transportation Drug-Free Policy   

      For Employers with employees operating commercial motor
   vehicles regulated by the U.S. Department of Transportation 
            


   
      Federal Contractors Drug-Free Policy   

    For employers having a contract with the federal government
     worth $100,000 or more 



         Policy Updates 
     

    Free Policy Updates - one year free 
 
     The main reason Employee Handbooks get outdated is that your
    state and federal employment laws change.

       You get new Policy Updates emailed to you when your state or
      federal laws change, to keep your Employee Handbook up-to-date
      and compliant for 1 Year Free. 
           


        Maintenance Plan   (Ongoing after the free Policy Updates) 
    
   You can continue to have us keep your Employee Handbook
    updated and maintained for you for only pennies a day.

     This can be the last Employee Handbook you will ever need .  


    
   New York Restaurant Employee Handbook with Business Protection      
 $199 95  
  Compare NY Employee Handbook Package 

   
 
  Object reference not set to an instance of an object. 

 
  
 NY Restaurant Employee Handbook Business Protection Details 
 
                

              
   

         Employment Laws for the Workplace Manual 
                         
         Easy-to-understand information about the laws affecting your business. 
 
 At Will Employment, Foundation of Modern Employment Practices,  Fair Labor Standards Act, Sexual Harassment, Disabled Employees,    Age Discrimination in Employment Act, Family and Medical Leave Act, Drug-Free Workplace Act, Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act, Employee Polygraph Protection Act, Employee Privacy, Immigration and Alien Employment, Uniformed Services Employment and Reemployment Act, COBRA, Employment Practices Liability Insurance, Good Employment Practices. 
 

           
            Updates and Maintenance - First Year FREE 

         When the federal government or New York makes changes in employment laws that effects policies in this
        NY Restaurant Employee Handbook, you get new policies from an attorney, emailed to you to keep your
        NY Restaurant Employee Handbook up-to-date as laws change, 1 year free. This Maintenance Plan
        continues to keep your Handbook up-to-date and complaint for only $2 per month and no effort on your
        part.
 
                       
                  NY Restaurant Employee Handbook Business Protection               $199 95    
 Compare NY Restaurant Employee Handbook Packages         
                                                                      



 
    Let Us Do Everything For You ... for only $200 more 

 
   
   Custom Restaurant Employee Handbook     $399   
   
  We write your Employee Handbook - Made For You.

   We Custom Design Your Complete Restaurant Employee
   Handbook Just For Your Business. Read more 
 
 
 
  
 



 

 
   Cash Control: 
 
 
Locks, Keys, Safe Combinations, Security Codes and Passwords, Safe Access, Deposits, Cash Register Policies, Deposits,
Accountability, Customer Refunds, Tip Policy and more.

 
 
   Security and Safety: 
 
 
Opening and Closing Procedures, Damaged Products, Product Delivery Security,
Non-Employee Access, Employee Parking, Robbery Procedure and more.
  
 
   Customer Relations and Service: 
 
 
 
Customer Service, Customer Complaints, Alcoholic Beverages, Publicity and more.
   
 
 
   


 
  Sanitation: 
 
 
Equipment Washing, Sanitizing Procedures, Employee Hand Washing Procedure,
Limitation on Use of Hand Gels, Pest Control and more.
 
 
 
   Food Safety: 
 
 
Food Safety Certification, Poisonous 
or Toxic Materials, Food Recalls, Tampering, Food Security, Food Terrorism, Maintaining Food Temperatures and more .


 
 
   List of Restaurant Policy Areas Covered 
 
 
 

 
   Employment Practices
 
 
 
At Will Employment, HIPAA, ADA, FLSA, FMLA, USERRA, ADEA, OSHA, EEOC 
Sexual Harassment, Drug Free Workplace, COBRA, Discrimination, Minors&amp;more.

 
 
   Employee Obligations and Behavior: 
 
 
Work Related Injuries, Conflicts of Interest, Employee Discipline, Workplace Monitoring,
Confidentiality, Social Networking, Computer/Internet, Workplace Violence, Dress Code and more.

 
 
 Employee Benefits: 
 
 
Family&amp;Medical Leave, Vacations, Holidays, 
Workers Compensation, Sick Leave, Maternity, Military Leave, Bereavement Leave, Domestic Violence Leave, Crime Victims Leave, and more.

 
 
   Hiring and Terminating Employees:   
 
 
Welcome Message, Acknowledgment of
At Will Employment&amp;Receipt of Employee
Handbook, Company Expectations,
Termination&amp;Exiting Employment,
Exit Interview and more.

 
 
 Record-Keeping:  
 
 
Employment Records, Government Inspections, Recording Time Worked,
Works Made For Hire, Employee Review of Personnel Files and more.

 
 
 Compensation:  
 
 
Wage Garnishment, Pay Periods, Work Schedules, Overtime, Errors in Paycheck, Employer Withholding, Deductions and Offsets from Paycheck and more.

 
 


 

  
 
   
   &quot; My lawyer recommended that I get an updated Employee Handbook.    
   This one hit the nail on the head. 
 
     It&apos;s very professionally written, tailored for my state and gives me 
    the type of protection that I need. I&apos;m very satisfied. &quot; 

      Lin, Focus Your Plan, Inc. 
 

   
                  
 Compare New York Restaurant Employee Handbook Packages:
  

 
 NY Restaurant Employee Handbook
Business Protection Packages
AT A Glance 
 Economy 

 Deluxe
 
 Premium
 
 New York Restaurant Employee Handbook NY and Federal Compliant Policies Free Customization with your company name and logo inserted for you New York Restaurant Employee Handbook in Spanish
 (valued separately for $99.95) 10 Human Resource Forms
 (valued separately for $49.95 ) Policy Updates
 (sold separately for $29.95) 37 Hire to Fire Employment Forms
 includes 10 HR Forms   (sold separately for $99.95) Employment Laws for the Workplace Manual
 (sold separately for $59.95) 
 
 Hire and Retain the Best Employees Manual
 (sold separately for $24.95) 
   U.S. Department of Transportation
Drug Free Workplace Policy 
 
 Federal Contractors Drug-Free Workplace Policy 
 
 Ongoing Maintenance Plan Available ($2 per month) 
 $99.95
 
 $149.95 
 
 $199.95 
 
 

 
   Customer Testimonials | Frequently Asked Questions |   Terms and Conditions | Privacy Policy FingerTip Manuals®, FingerTip Law®, and At Your FingerTip®are registered Trademarks of FingerTip Enterprises, LLC.
Triangle of Liability, We Put Employee Handbooks...At Your FingerTip, Our Expertise is Your Peace of Mind,
Your Own Human Resource Department...At Your FingerTip, Turn-Key Employee Handbook and Video Employee Handbook 
are Trademarks of FingerTip Enterprises, LLC. 
Fortune 500 is a trademark of Time Inc.
FingerTip Enterprises, LLC does business as FingerTipManuals.com 
All intellectual property is protected under the laws of the United States of America, Florida and other states.

 Content copyright | FingerTip Manuals | All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
