<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001687" url="http://dinehere.ca/white-rock/cosmos-greek-restaurant" time="2012-07-12-17:27" support="6" score="0.008556595868625911" bingtitle="Cosmos Greek Restaurant | White Rock - Dine Here | Restaurant ..." webtitle="Cosmos Greek Restaurant | White Rock">
			<query id="000078" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000091" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="000590" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000079" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="000081" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="000066" bing-rank="161"/>
	<description>The last 3 times we had asked for window seats to enjoy ... I had bought an italian soda, from a gelato store right ... and was again this afternoon when we arrived near 5:30 P.M..</description>
	<body>
		Home &gt;&gt; Metro Vancouver Login or Register 
 Metro Vancouver Bowen Island Burnaby Coquitlam Delta Langley Maple Ridge New Westminster North Vancouver 

 Pitt Meadows Port Coquitlam Port Moody Richmond Surrey Vancouver West Vancouver White Rock 

 Abbotsford Brampton Burlington Calgary Chilliwack Duncan Edmonton Halifax Hamilton Kamloops Kelowna Kitchener Ladysmith 

 London Mission Mississauga Montreal Nanaimo Niagara Falls Oakville Oshawa Ottawa Parksville Saskatoon Scarborough Squamish 

 St. Catharines Tofino Toronto Vaughan Waterloo Welland Whistler Whitby Windsor 

 Greater Victoria Sidney Sooke Victoria 
 Do a search below using the city or postal code search box if your city is not listed above. 
 
 Follow us on Facebook and Twitter 

 Get dining news including restaurant closures and qualify for giveaways.
 Search: Location: Locations Locations: 
 Vancouver Burnaby Coquitlam Maple Ridge White Rock Pitt Meadows Richmond North Vancouver New Westminster West Vancouver Port Moody Bowen Island Surrey Langley Delta Port Coquitlam     
 Tip: To view neighbourhoods, click on a city above or change the default location to a specific city (top left of website). Cuisines Cuisines: 
 Afghan Cambodian European International Pakistani Soup African Canadian Family Irish Pasta Southern American Caribbean Fast food Israeli Persian Southwestern Asian Chicken Filipino Italian Peruvian Spanish Australian Chilean Fish&amp;chips Izakaya Pho Steaks Austrian Chinese French Jamaican Pita Sushi Bagels Coffee Fusion Japanese Pizza Swiss Bakery Contemporary Game Juice Polish Szechuan Bar Continental Gelato Korean Portuguese Taiwanese Barbeque Creole German Kosher Poutine Tapas Belgian Crepes Greek Latin American Pub Tea house Bistro Cuban Halal Lebanese Ramen Tex-Mex Brazilian Deli Hawaiian Malaysian Regional Thai Brewery Dessert Healthy Mediterranean Romanian Tibetan British Dim sum Hot dogs Mexican Russian Tunisian Bubble tea Diner Hot pot Middle Eastern Salad Turkish Burgers Doughnuts Hungarian Mongolian Sandwiches Ukrainian Cafe Dutch Ice cream Moroccan Seafood Vegetarian Cafeteria Eastern European Indian Organic Shanghainese Vietnamese Cajun Eclectic Indigenous Pacific northwest Singaporean Wine bar California Ethiopian Indonesian Pacific rim     
 Options Price: $ ($15 or less) $$ ($15 - $30) $$$ ($30 - $45) $$$$ ($45 or more) Features: 
 Ocean Wise View Dinner Banquet Wheelchair accessible Patio Lunch Delivery Live entertainment All day breakfast Breakfast Takeout Romantic Catering Weekend brunch Cheap eats Television Late night Buffet Fine dining 
 Sort: A-Z Popularity Rating - Food - Service - Value - Ambiance Z-A # Reviews Created Updated Min: 0 Reviews 1 Reviews 2 Reviews 3 Reviews 5 Reviews 10 Reviews 15 Reviews 20 Reviews 25 Reviews Results: 10 20 50 Offer: None Deals -- Group buys -- Coupons Order online Reserve online Gift cards Status: Open Opening soon Renovation Closed Fast food 
 Food Service Value Ambiance Reviews 25 
   Add to favourites Add to try 
 White Rock › Greek 

Cosmos Greek Restaurant
 14871 Marine Drive 
 White Rock , BC V4B1C2 Tel: (604) 531-3511 
Fax: (604) 531-3936
 Neighbourhood: North Bluff West 
 Cuisine: Greek Price: $$ ($15 - $30) Reservations: Accepted Service: Takeout Meals: Lunch , Dinner Features: Patio , View , Live entertainment 
White Rock&apos;s oldest Greek restaurant, located on Marine Drive. Featuring weekend entertainment a heated outdoor patio and ocean views.
 

 Web site Facebook Inspection reports 
 
 Submit review Upload image Edit restaurant 
 
 Reviews Images Tips 
 
Reviews
 Displaying 1 - 20 of 25 Reviews Found Sort: Useful | Helpful | Reviews | Date anniversary dinner By nino of WhiteRock, BC (1 Review) Submitted Tuesday, July 3, 2012 - 12:03am [Dine in] 
My husband and I had made reservations here for our anniversary. We were seated promptly by the friendly hostess. Our server had recommended a nice red wine for us which was perfect. It was a busy night and the food did take a bit to be served but we had ordered appetizers (kalamari and saganaki) which were delish!
My husband ordered rack of lamb, he loved it, it was cooked perfectly and marinated just enough. I had the moussaka which was by far the best I &apos;ve had,. Our server was so kind as to bring us an anniversary dessert platter and two flaming sambucas on the house. We were pleasantly surprised. Its a shame the review below was so unhappy. We will definitely be going again!
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 6 / 12 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Very, very disappointing.....as usual. By L and R of white rock b.c. (1 Review) Submitted Friday, June 22, 2012 - 7:38pm [Dine in] 
My husband&amp;I have been long time residents of White Rock&amp;many years ago we used to love Cosmos. However, it is nothing like it used to be. We have been in many times over the years&amp;each time is more&amp;more disappointing. We went two weeks ago with some family that had not been there for some time&amp;really wanted to go. We did not wish to go there but we also wanted our family to be happy. So we went&amp;had a very average meal. At that time we were happy to see that another server from another restaurant had become an employee of Cosmos&amp;were very please as she is fabulous. So tonight we decided that we would give Cosmos another chance. Unfortunately, she was not our server, but that was ok. We wish we had never given Cosmos another chance. It was terrible. I have never written anything online EVER before but this is absolutely warranted. We both ordered the steak&amp;lobster dinners. My husbands steak was cooked as per his request but he noted that the lobster&amp;rest of his meal was lousy. I ordered a medium rare steak&amp;mine came well-done. At this time there was 6 tables with people at them&amp;5 or 6 servers. The server did offer to replace my steak, however, by the time she came back, my husband had already almost finished&amp;our dinner had already been spoiled. The server said she would talk to her manager&amp;have her sort out the issue for the bill. The server also told us that she is extremely frustrated as this steak issue happens often by the kitchen staff. She did apologize profusely, however it is NOT her fault. It is a management issue. Due to the fact that it is not the servers fault we tipped her our usual generous percentage. She did contact the manager regarding our bill&amp;the manager was only willing to take off $10 for the steak portion my meal. Our bill was $105.00 with tip. I hope it was worth saving the rest of the cost of meal as they have lost a good paying customer for good. We were also one of the loyal customers that come for dinner in the slow winter months. We will never return as there are many other options in White Rock these days.
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 9 / 20 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 
&lt; More reviews below advertisement &gt;
 Portions tend towards &apos;enormous&apos; By cjwright79 of White Rock (17 Reviews) Submitted Thursday, May 17, 2012 - 6:37pm [Dine in] 
I really like Cosmos but the thing is, whenever I go there my appetite doesn&apos;t quite match up the extremely generous portion sizes. The one time I got a three course meal (soup, an entree, dessert, and coffee) I went out to the parking lot afterwards and nearly puked because I was so full. That said, the food -is- really good, the prices are very reasonable, and the staff are friendly and good at what they do. So... what am I saying exactly? -- should I fault them for serving so much food? That&apos;s silly. They are a great operation and I&apos;ll be back again and again, but I definitely need to bring a fierce appetite next time to match their portion sizes. I definitely recommend their dolmades, avgolemono soup, and baklava.
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 9 / 18 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Rush, Rushing, Rushed!!! By Desirtainaia of WHITE ROCK BC (1 Review) Submitted Monday, May 14, 2012 - 4:20pm [Dine in] 
We went to Cosmos to celebrate Mother&apos;s Day and a family birthday. We had a reservation for 4pm and when we were seated at the table the waitress told us that we had to be done by 6:15pm because the table was triple booked. We didn&apos;t know that our reservation was for a set amount of time and that definitely wasn&apos;t explained to us when we booked or we would never have gone there. This was the first time that any of us had experienced a waitress telling us that we had to &quot;eat and go&quot;. The whole concept of going out for a relaxing meal was gone. It was so rushed that we weren&apos;t even offered tea or coffee and the staff were lined up with their buckets waiting for us to get up so they could clear our table. There was no option to stay and chat over a few drinks. We were basically kicked out. The crazy part is that there were several side-by-side tables that were empty the whole time, yet the staff were rushing us. It&apos;s ironic that they were by no means fast at getting us our drinks or food and they didn&apos;t even greet us for several minutes when we arrived. We complained to the manager who was absolutely rude. She just left my husband and I standing there while she disappeared into the back. It was honestly the worst service we have ever experienced!
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 8 / 14 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Great service By helandy7 of Surrey ,B.C. (1 Review) Submitted Monday, May 21, 2012 - 12:25pm [Dine in] 
On May 18th, 2012 at 7PM we had reservations for 3 and were immediately seated.

&quot;NEIL&quot; was our OUTSTANDING waiter for the night and we ordered pre-meal drinks and an appetizer, which were served with very little waiting. He took our meal orders shortly thereafter and the timing was perfect when the main course arrived. Meals were hot, nicely prepared and excellent value. &quot;NEIL&quot; kept in touch with us throughout the evening and looked after us very well. We all had the $25.00 inclusive, I ordered the roast Lamb.
I had read the negative reviews on-line prior to making our reservations however thought we would try the restaurant because we had good experiences on our prior visits - we had been there approximately 1 year previous. I can say that we were not disappointed and would recommend this place to anyone.

Andy
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 6 / 18 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Way overpriced for the quality of the food and service. By DK of Surrey, BC (2 Reviews) Submitted Saturday, July 23, 2011 - 9:41am [Dine in] 
The building decor has potential, but that is about it. The food was disappointing, the special coffee was terrible, and for the high price of the entree, there should have been a Greek salad included. The server not at all personable, therefore, we will not return to this restaurant again.
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 29 / 50 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 
&lt; More reviews below advertisement &gt;
 Not Couple Friendly By white-rock-fan of white rock area (1 Review) Submitted Thursday, June 30, 2011 - 9:52am [Dine in] 
The last 3 times we had asked for window seats to enjoy the view and was told no even though all window seats were available . We are a couple so maybe window seats are not for couples . My view is first come first serve .
Server was friendly and dedicated . Food was so so . Not a pleasant experience overall .
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 27 / 47 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Reliable Greek food on the beach By FoodMan99 of Surrey , B.C. (57 Reviews) Submitted Thursday, February 24, 2011 - 3:31pm [Dine in] 
I love Greek but I stick to the basics. The beef Souvlaki was good, the potatoes were amazing but the bread was a bit tough. Dessert portions are small but tasty. The atmosphere is friendly, and there is outdoor seating on the beach for summer and a fireplace inside for colder times. I know better Greek places DT, but in the White Rock/Surrey area, Cosmos is reliable.
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 18 / 136 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Solid food, friendly service By Kujibo of West Vancouver (127 Reviews) Submitted Sunday, July 22, 2007 - 3:00am [Dine in] 
Eaten here several times over the years. My family eats here somewhat regular and like it quite a bit and are friendly with the staff. Never seems to be a dissapointing experience.

Food has been good. I found their greek salad a bit bland (I like lots of dressing) but that&apos;s probably a personal thing. Everything else I&apos;ve had is great though. Prices start at about $15 for a Kalamari dinner with most items hovering just under $20. Not the cheapest greek but not too expensive either.

We last dined on a Friday night and they had a lot of servers working, so service was pretty fast. Even with a full restaurant food came pretty fast. Service seems quite personable, when it&apos;s less busy many of the staff seem to be mingling with customers in a friendly way.

On a Friday night the place was lively and festive. It&apos;s a fairly large restaurant. Lots of lively conversation, I don&apos;t think they even bother trying to play music as it would be too loud. A belly dancer appeared for a few songs though.

Overall it seems to be one of the most popular spots on Marine drive and deservedly so.
 
 Food Service Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 6 / 9 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Good meal near the boardwalk. By epicurious of Burnaby, BC (507 Reviews) Submitted Tuesday, January 22, 2008 - 12:18pm [Dine in] 
The moussaka is a must try. It&apos;s been a while since I&apos;ve been here, but all I can think about at the mere mention of White Rock is the moussaka Cosmos serves up!

It&apos;s a great restaurant to dine, especially during the summer time sitting out in the patio.

I would definitely eat here again the next chance I get.
 
 Food Service Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 4 / 9 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Credit Card Debt? Search and compare every credit card in Canada and find the best one to suit your needs at Credit Card Search.
 Meh. By charchar of Vancouver (5 Reviews) Submitted Tuesday, November 9, 2010 - 9:22pm [Dine in] 
Decided to have dinner here with my friend from out of town during the summer. We arrived at the doorway and stood there for about 3 minutes waiting for someone to acknowledge we were there. A couple of servers or hostess saw us standing there but nobody came over... so another minute or two of that and we walked a few feet closer to the counter. Still no one said anything to us. Finally my friend stopped a waitress and asked if we could be seated. The waitress said &quot;Oh sorry! Didn&apos;t know you were going to eat here.&quot; We were like.. okay.. ahaha..I mean.. come on, we were awkwardly standing there for about 5-6 minutes with you guys walking by us and nobody stopped to think Hmmm, I wonder why those two girls are standing there, maybe I should ask them??
I let that go, and we happily sat down at a table outside on the patio, since it was a warm night and the sunset was too beautiful to resist! We put in our drink order, and a few minutes later ordered our entrees. I noticed that the patrons near our table looked really bored and it seemed like they&apos;ve been waiting a while for their food. The man certainly didn&apos;t look too impressed, so I&apos;m guessing that the service was slow that night.

Food: Our food came about half an hour after our drinks. (Sucks for the other customers, because their food came probably 10 minutes after ours did even though we were seated after them). The only thing I didn&apos;t like was the squid. Honestly, I&apos;ve had better calamari at White Spot. I expected that it would be on an amazing-level since we&apos;re actually at a Greek restaurant.. but the batter wasn&apos;t crispy at all and it was bland. I&apos;d order from Opa Souvlaki over this, any day. (fast service, and tasty calamari for half the price!)

Service and ambiance: Our yummy drinks, girl&apos;s heart-to-heart, and our seating in the open patio and warm summer night made up for the non-existant service. I don&apos;t remember the server coming back to check up on us on her own free will. My friend asked to have an extra shot of rum in her drink and the server nodded Yes! Sure! Well.. 10 minutes later no-nothing. Friend had to wave her down again, first attempt failed. Second attempt of waving finally got the server&apos;s attention, and only 5 more minutes my friend had to wait to get her alcohol fix. Yay! With that said.. we really did enjoy our time there though. The music was a nice touch, the belly-dancing was pretty entertaining.. and the washrooms were very nicely decorated and clean.
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 14 / 24 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Great Greek Food on the Strip By sunshine52 of White Rock (1 Review) Submitted Friday, July 16, 2010 - 2:21pm [Dine in] 
Was in White Rock beach recently and I usually go with my girl friends to Charlie Don&apos;t Surf or the sushi place close to the pier, but my friends and I decided to try the Greek restaurant Cosmos.

We were pleasantly surprised to find such a beautiful patio that we were able to sit out on. We had great weather and our server was very friendly. Our drinks came very fast and our appy&apos;s did too.

The main courses didn&apos;t take too long and when they came, the food was outstanding. Our server came back many times to check up on us.

Overall, it was a great experience and I am looking forward to going to the beach again to visit Cosmos again.
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 7 / 12 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Praise for Cosmo&apos;s By ilovefoodsomuch of Vancouver (1 Review) Submitted Wednesday, December 1, 2010 - 4:22pm [Dine in] 
I actually adored this restaurant, We walked in and we were literally seated right away, the hostess was so gracious and welcoming I felt right at home. We sat down and looked over the menu and then the server came over and took our drinks menu. We got to seat right by the fire place and it was extremely cozy and warm. Our drinks came in no time at all. After we had decided what we wanted we ordered the calamari. I have eaten a lot of kalamari in my life, and this was by far the best. It was so fresh and the crispy outside was a dream. After finishing the kalamari and wanting more. We made up our minds about what we were going to eat for our main entree&apos;s. My friend decided to get the classic chicken souvlaki, and I decided to go with the kileftiko which is the roast lamb shoulder.

We waited for 15 minutes and then the food came out ready to eat. By far the best greek entree I have ever eaten. It was cooked to perfection exactly the way I wanted it to be cooked. And the portion size was massive, I literally couldn&apos;t eat all of it, there was just way too much food. All in all I loved this restaurant
great food, great service, just an amazing time. I would defintily go back any time, I&apos;d even bring my family back too. This restaurant definitely made an impression on me.
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 15 / 35 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Old Standby By TheDuke of White Rock (31 Reviews) Submitted Thursday, June 19, 2008 - 9:09pm [Dine in] 
A very good&quot;Old Standby&quot;kind of restaurant.
Nother super as far as ambiance, food, or service.....BUT...
one can at least rely on getting a good standard of fare.

Kalamari and Souvlaki are the most ordered amongst our group.

The Greek Salad is O.K. but not the most memorable of dishes.

Service is always pretty good...and was again this afternoon when we arrived near 5:30 P.M..

Yes--- this is getting to be a regular&quot;Haunt&quot;for my wife and I as well as friends.
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 5 / 9 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Reliable Greek Food on the Beach By Eat-All-Joo-Want of Langley (21 Reviews) Submitted Saturday, June 13, 2009 - 6:03am [Dine in] 
A reliable Greek restaurant with pretty good food and fair pricing. Service can be pretty inconsistent at time. During our multiple visits, my Wife and I will get outstanding attention by our server but other times we&apos;re less than impressed by their attention to detail.

Food is pretty good overall. You won&apos;t get 5 star eating but you get a decent meal. This is a good place to dine during the warmer months, especially when you sit outside to partake the cool breeze from the sea. Even the ambiance is cozy with plenty of plants, decor and reminders of sunny days on the Mediterranean sea.

I do have ONE WARNING. If you&apos;re a straight male, like me, beware of the male belly dancers that frequents the premises on specific days. The last thing I want is some guy&apos;s ass jiggling in my face, while I eat my Souvlaki.

Despite my minor quibbles, Cosmo&apos;s a pretty good place and worth the time on the White Rock Strip.
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 6 / 9 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 I go often By HeartOfSilver of Surrey (15 Reviews) Submitted Tuesday, January 22, 2008 - 11:38am [Dine in] 
I really love this restaurant. The food is reasonably priced, and it is really what I want when I crave greek food.

The ambiance is really nice, and I enjoyed the last time I was there because a bellydancer came up to my group and we all tried dancing with her! That doesn&apos;t happen all the time, but I suggest going on a night when there is a woman there for a bit of fun.

I have never had a bad meal there, I especially love their flavoured potatoes and rice!
 
 Food Service Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 9 / 13 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Try ANY other restaurant on the strip but this one! By fivestar of Coquitlam (2 Reviews) Submitted Wednesday, May 13, 2009 - 12:41pm [Dine in] 
Planned Mother&apos;s Day dinner here this year at my Mother&apos;s request (she wanted to be close to home). We made reservations 3 weeks in advance for the Saturday...not the Sunday...thinking it wouldn&apos;t be as busy and the service and food would be better....WRONG!
We waited to be seated yet the restaurant was empty (it was 4:00 pm). When we were seated, it was off in the furthest corner away from the bar and kithchen, by an open door and it was FREEZING. My mother is 75 and was shivering. When asked if they could close the door to the patio they did.....for 10 minutes. I guess they could care less if most of the retired older folks in White Rock get a pneumonia in their establishment. There were no smiles or friendly greetings from the staff. It took about 15 minutes for someone to take our drink order and another 10 mintues for those to arrive. We placed our food orders, stupidly thinking that this greek restaurant was like most and pita and tzatziki would be placed on the table to nibble on. Again...WRONG. We waited for our food for about 45 minutes. Most of us had the roast lamb which was mid quality and chemical laden flavour. My Mother however had the halibut which came to the table cold with the sauce having turned to a lovely gelatin consistency and half a broccoli TREE as a vegetable. I&apos;ve NEVER seen a greek restaurant serve as little greek salad as this one nor have I seen greek salad consisting mostly of cucumber slices. It was pretty awful. The server actually asked my Mother if she&apos;d like hers reheated or was it fine. At this point my sister and I spoke up and said&quot;This is our Mother&apos;s Day dinner and we&apos;d like it to be nice for our Mother so please remake the dish properly&quot;. She grumpily took the dish away and brought a new one.....TWENTY FIVE minutes later! No apologies, nothing. Drink refills were few and far between. I can&apos;t figure out for the life of me what kept the serving staff from doing a fantastic job at our table when the restaurant was EMPTY. I complained again to the server about how long it had taken to remake the halibut and she defended herself by saying that she had no control over the kitchen staff. I was shocked! to say the least. I have never come across an establishment with such low standards of service and food but advertised as excellent dining. Are the positive reviews on here from people who never get the chance to eat out? I have no other explanation. This place is a rip off with horrible service and very bad staff attitudes. Skip it and hit Moby Dicks for some excellent fish and chips. If you want Greek then leave the strip in search of quality food and people who actually work for their money and tips and servers who actually smile...not bring misery and attitude to your expensive dining experience.
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 8 / 15 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Had a great time and food was very tasty By billiez of surrey (1 Review) Submitted Friday, March 6, 2009 - 7:25am [Dine in] 
I had gone to Cosmos on a Saturday night without reservations. It was very busy, but the hostess did her best to find us a table. We did have to wait a bit, but at least we got a good table.
I really liked the interior of the restaurant, it had a traditional yet modern feel to it, with different pictures, objects, artifacts etc.

Our waitress came after a few minutes and took our orders, she seemed friendly enough and had good knowledge of the menu. We ordered some appies, kalamari was excellent and so were the prawns in the tomato sauce. Our dinner did take a while, but we weren&apos;t in a hurry and we worked on our appies. The roast lamb was splendid, it melted in my mouth, my boyfriend had souvlaki which he said was also very good, although the salad had a few too many onions for my liking. They had bellydancers a male and female which was really fun. They came to our table and got the birthday boy to dance. Overall enjoyed this restaurant, will definitely go again!
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 5 / 8 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 Good greek food, nice atmosphere! By Jennie78 of Surrey, BC (2 Reviews) Submitted Thursday, December 11, 2008 - 5:05pm [Dine in] 
Went for dinner on Friday night to Cosmos Greek Restaurant. We made reservations, we were seated right away, sat near the cozy fireplace. The waitress came right away to get drink orders. We received very good service, we were never looking for the waitress. Which was a nice change! I had ordered the lamb shoulder (kleftiko). It was fabulous! Sooo tender and flavorful! I thoroughly enjoyed it. My friends all had souvlaki, they said it was very good. We decided to split two desserts between the four of us. The dessert that stood out was the Bougatsa, it was amazing!... very very good!!
We had a good experience and enjoyable evening there and look forward to going back.
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 5 / 9 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 May not be the best, but pretty close By AlphaOne of White Rock (5 Reviews) Submitted Thursday, December 11, 2008 - 1:25am [Dine in] 
Good, solid food. The Lamb Kleftiko just melts in my mouth. Souvlakis are also well recommended. Very friendly service. Pleasant surroundings with a good view of the Semiahmoo Bay. Parking on and across the street may be a bit tough to find on weekend evenings in summer. But this does not discourage me.
 
 Food Service Value Ambiance 
 Was this review helpful?
 4 / 8 users found this review helpful. Yes No 
 Report 
 
 1 2 next › last » 
 
Images
 Displaying 1 - 2 of 2 Images Found 
Tips
 Displaying 1 Foursquare Tips 
 Jean-Pierre D. : Exohico here is AMAZING. little pricey but def worth it if you get the chance. 1 year 34 weeks ago 
   Map and directions 
 Vancouver Entertainment Book 
 Up to $26 off when you buy the new 2012 Vancouver Entertainment Book. Free Shipping. 
Nearby Restaurants
 
 1. West Beach Bar and Grill (77 m) 2. Gelateria Italia and Coffee Shop (85 m) 3. Bistro Elis (91 m) 4. Fresh Slice (124 m) 5. White Mountain Homemade Ice Cream (128 m) 6. Boathouse Restaurant, The (143 m) 7. Wings Tap&amp;Grill (172 m) 8. Pearl Urban Bistro (197 m) 9. Le Vol Au Vent (199 m) 10. Cones Creamery (209 m) 
   
 Restaurants Opening Soon New Restaurants Updated Restaurants 

 Support Review Guide FAQ News 

 Socialize Facebook Twitter Google + 

 Corporate Contact Advertise 
 Copyright©2004-2011
	</body>
</document>
