<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001754" url="http://www.sooperarticles.com/technology-articles/software-articles/how-has-epos-software-developed-599915.html" time="2012-07-12-17:32" support="2" score="0.0012305653396466768" bingtitle="How Has EPOS Software Developed - Submit Articles - Free Ezine ..." webtitle="How Has EPOS Software Developed">
			<query id="000740" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="001390" bing-rank="191"/>
	<description>In a fast food restaurant for example, tickets had to be printed ... If the receipt paper jammed it also meant it could ... Discovery - The Modern Concept of Atomic Number ...</description>
	<body>
		Sooper Articles 
Sooper Articles
 Your Best Article Source.. Titles Contents Authors Welcome, Guest 
 Submit Articles Sooper Authors Top Articles Blog Register Login Widgets RSS Feeds FAQ Contact 
 Find us on Facebook Follow us on Twitter 
Article Categories
 Art&amp;Entertainment Automotive Business Careers Communications Education Finance Food&amp;Drinks Gaming Health&amp;Fitness Hobbies Home and Family Home Improvement Internet Law News&amp;Society Pets Real Estate Relationship Self Improvement Shopping Spirituality Sports Technology 
 Advancements Artificial Intelligence Biotechnology Computer Architecture Computer Forensics Data Recovery Data Storage Databases Gadgets&amp;Gizmos Hardware Intranet IT Trainings Laptops Malware Mobile Computing Networks Office Automation Operating System Programming Research Security Software Support&amp;Services Tech Updates 
 Travel Writing Subscribe to Latest Articles 
Enter your email address:

 
 Useful Links For Authors 
 Author Guidelines Article Writing Tips Why Submit Articles 
 
 Home Technology Articles Software Articles How Has EPOS Software Developed 
 
How Has EPOS Software Developed
 By Richard A Jackson on August 23, 2011 
 0 
When going about our daily shopping, whether that be in a supermarket or a shopping centre it is easy to take for granted all the process and procedures that are going on behind the scenes. One such process is the use of EPOS software used in conjunction with modern touch screen tills. I&apos;m not sure many of us have ever really stopped to ponder its evolution and we forget all too quickly the irksome and slow tills of the past. Here is an overview of how EPOS software has developed and evolved to become an integral part of the retail environment.
 
A Time Before EPOS Software 
 
Many of us born after the 80&apos;s are not likely to remember the old fashioned, mechanical, heavy tills. However for many they were common place, found in shops ranging from department stores through to corner shops. Relying purely on a receipt being printed to tally up the days takings caused issues and they were also flawed in several other ways. In a fast food restaurant for example, tickets had to be printed and lined up at the grill station, tickets that could be easily lost. If the receipt paper jammed it also meant it could be difficult to add up the days takings. Not to mention card transactions, stock control and many other operations that EPOS software does effortlessly on modern technical hardware. A solution to this problem was needed...

 Early EPOS Software 

The solution came in the form of microprocessor development. As computers started to become more sophisticated and smaller in size they could be made into the size of a till. In fact one of the first organisations to use a simple but none the less working EPOS software based computer was McDonalds, the well know fast food outlet. Their till used EPOS software to allow them to send and queue up orders directly to the kitchen area. As time went on early Apple and Atari machines where used until Microsoft Windows based software was developed and became the standard OS, along with Unix and Linux.

 Modern EPOS Software Solutions 

Once the ball got rolling many different EPOS software solutions started springing up, tailored to different customer facing environments. Modern EPOS software is even featured on till systems that can be operated by the customer, via self-service tills. Modern EPOS software implementations offer a much wider field of customer data to be captured which covers everything from special offers through to stock information and accounts data storage.

It&apos;s interesting to learn how EPOS software goes unnoticed much of the time and we take for granted till systems. It&apos;ll also be interesting to see how EPOS software continues to develop over the coming years.
 For more information regarding EPOS software , contact BCP - EPOS software specialists 

 
Rate this Article
 
 Currently 0/5 1 2 3 4 5 

 How Has EPOS Software Developed Not Rated Yet 
 Contact Author Email this Article Comments(0) Bookmark Print Republish Article Report Article 

 Richard A Jackson has published 42 articles. Article submitted on August 23, 2011 . Word count: 459
 
Related Articles From Software Category
 Advantage of Using Spa And Salon Management Software For Your Biz The Role of Live Help Software in Making Sales For Your Company Youtube to Mp4 Converter For Mac Convert Youtube Videos to Mp4 on Mac OS X Snow Leopard And Lion What is it About After Sales Service That Bothers Most? Nidesoft Video Converter Software Free Version Download 
More Articles From Technology Category
 New Age Green Datacenter Solutions Spammers Use Excel to Cloak Malware Tips on How to Choose The Right Multimedia Speakers For a Great Sound Experience Mud Map Your Way out of Any Tough Situation - 4x4 Off Road GPS Maps Australia Maxx MQ 606 price 
 Article Keywords: EPOS software, till software, bcp software, retail software
 
Post a Comment on this Article
 Note: We read and moderate all comments before they visible on article page. Your email address will not be published. Fields marked with asteric are required. Name: * Email: * Website: Comments: * Type the characters you see in the picture below. * 
   Submit Articles | Blog | Author Guidelines | Mobile | Widgets | FAQ | Advertise | Resources | Privacy Policy | Terms of Services | Contact Copyright©2012 Sooper Articles - Free Articles . All Rights Reserved. Powered by: ISolution
	</body>
</document>
