<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001304" url="http://tag.wonderhowto.com/make-homemade-frozen-yogurt-without-an-ice-cream-maker/" time="2012-07-12-16:48" support="2" score="0.0012363601368318197" bingtitle="Make homemade frozen yogurt without an ice cream maker" webtitle="Make Homemade Frozen Yogurt Without an Ice Cream MakerWonder How To">
			<query id="000082" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="000086" bing-rank="197"/>
	<description>How To Eat Healthy at a Fast Food Restaurant. Whether you&apos;re eating ... Ingredients 2 1/2 cups flour 1 teaspoon baking soda ... And if you love cars and cookies, this video will ...</description>
	<body>
		WonderHowTo Login | Signup   Worlds: 
 Minecraft Smartphones Hacks, Mods&amp;Circuitry Photoshop Fear Of Lightning More Worlds » 
 Explore All Worlds How-To » How-To Topics » Make homemade frozen » Make homemade frozen yogurt » Make Homemade Frozen Yogurt Without an Ice Cream Maker 
 Make Homemade Frozen Yogurt Without an Ice Cream Maker 
 How to Make homemade frozen yogurt without an ice cream maker Frozen yogurt is delicious but it can be expensive to buy. Luckily in this how-to video we show you how to make frozen yogurt at home. You don&apos;t need a fancy ice cream maker for his recipe. Grab your favorite yogurt, a plastic bag, and your favorite toppings. Chill the yogurt in the plastic bag, attach a pastry tip and dispense into a bowl. Enjoy... 0 dessert-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make homemade frozen yogurt without an ice cream maker 
 How to Make ice cream Everyone loves ice cream, no matter what age they are. So why not try making a little homemade ice cream instead of hitting up Ben&amp;Jerry&apos;s? You&apos;ll enjoy it, and most of all, you&apos;re kids will love it. With this recipe and an ice cream maker, you can create your own sundaes, shakes and ice cream cones at home.

You Will Need
* 1 qt. half and half
* 1 c. granulated sugar
* Pinch of salt
* 2 vanilla... 0 dessert-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make ice cream 
 How to Make old world homemade strawberry ice cream Ever yearn for the days of homemade ice cream served up at old world ice cream parlors in a real glass cup with a non-plastic spoon? Don&apos;t settle for the mass-produced stuff in the frozen aisle and learn how to make your own ice cream instead.

In this home made strawberry ice cream video, Rita shows you how to make a simple strawberry ice cream in 20 minutes flat using a home ice cream maker. We ... 0 dessert-recipes »How-To 
 How to Make old world homemade strawberry ice cream 
 How to Make healthy after school snacks your kids will love When kids get home from school they go straight for the snacks, don&apos;t they? So, why not have some healthier options available, rather than fatty chips and cookies? Now, we know kids don&apos;t always like what&apos;s good for them, so check out this tutorial and start making snacks that are delicious AND healthy! Your kids won&apos;t even know how good for them these snacks are because they are so tasty!

Step 1... 0 parenting »How-To 
 How to Make healthy after school snacks your kids will love 
 How to Spend Less on Dairy Products Dairy products are becoming increasingly expensive in some countries or regions. Rather than foregoing having them in your well-rounded diet, there are some good ways to cut the costs on dairy and still enjoy it in your daily fare. Prefer stronger flavoured cheese. Cheese that has a stronger flavour goes further. For example, choose Parmesan or Pecorino cheese and grate lesser amounts of these typ... 0 cheese »How-To 
 How to Spend Less on Dairy Products 
 How to Go Canoe Camping While camping from a canoe is similar to car camping, it also shares many similarities with backpacking . This article will provide the information that you need to make your first trip successful. Select a river. When choosing a river, it&apos;s a good idea to find one that has a reputation as a good camping river. Many rivers are unsuitable for camping as the flood plains tend to be uneven and have h... 0 camp »How-To 
 How to Go Canoe Camping 
 How to Eat Healthy at a Fast Food Restaurant Whether you&apos;re eating on-the-go, on a budget, or with friends who couldn&apos;t care less about their diets , you&apos;ll probably end up eating at a fast food restaurant despite your best efforts to avoid them. They&apos;re everywhere, they&apos;re cheap, and they&apos;re convenient -- so what&apos;s a dieter to do? Take the following steps to minimize the impact of fast food on your diet. Read the nutrition pamphlet . If the... 0 nutrition »How-To 
 How to Eat Healthy at a Fast Food Restaurant 
 How to Care for a Pet Rat Mice too boring for you? Maybe you should try having a pet rat. They make great pets! They&apos;re sweet, smart, friendly, social, and active--as well as very entertaining--and you can learn how to take care of them through the following instructions. Get your pet rats . Getting at least two of the same gender (unless they are spayed/neutered) is STRONGLY recommended, and most good breeders/stores/resc... 0 pet-rodents »How-To 
 How to Care for a Pet Rat 
 How to Make Jam In today&apos;s world of all-night supermarkets and ready-made everything, it&apos;s easy to forget that jam didn&apos;t always come from the store. Homemade jam tastes fresher than store-bought stuff and it makes a great (and increasingly rare) gift . Ingredients Fruit or fruit juice according to the pectin package insert. **This demonstration uses 5 3/4 cups of crushed strawberries, equivalent to about 4 pints... 0 jelly-jam-preserves »How-To 
 How to Make Jam 
 Previous Next 
 Community 
 McPhiL commented on How to Obtain a blood sample through venipuncture i downloaded the plugin but still cant view videos how come? Austin Sirkin commented on APPLY WITHIN to JOIN OUR SERVER Sorry about that, the server machine was rebooted from the other end. It&apos;s back up now. =) Sa&apos;adi Rahman published How to Record Videos by Digital SLRs Siddak Bakshi published How to Revive a Dead Hard Drive Siddak Bakshi published LED Faucet Light Siddak Bakshi published How to Charge an Ipod/Iphone with Fruits 
 Arts 
 Arts&amp;Crafts Beauty&amp;Style Dance Fine Art Music&amp;Instruments 
 Science&amp;Tech 
 Autos, Motorcycles&amp;Planes Computers&amp;Programming Disaster Preparation Education Electronics Film&amp;Theater Software Weapons 
 Lifestyle 
 Alcohol Business&amp;Money Dating&amp;Relationships Diet&amp;Health Family Fitness Food Home&amp;Garden Hosting&amp;Entertaining Language Motivation&amp;Self Help Outdoor Recreation Pets&amp;Animals Pranks&amp;Cons Spirituality Sports Travel 
 Gaming 
 Gambling Games Hobbies&amp;Toys Magic&amp;Parlor Tricks Video Games 
 
 
 About Us Privacy Policy Terms&amp;Conditions
	</body>
</document>
