<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001623" url="http://www.mammothcavehotel.com/mc-dining" time="2012-07-12-17:24" support="1" score="0.0006581806672318969" bingtitle="Dining &amp; Shopping at Mammoth Cave Hotel, Mammoth Cave, Kentucky" webtitle="Dining&amp;Shopping at Mammoth Cave Hotel, Mammoth Cave, Kentucky">
			<query id="000711" bing-rank="19"/>
	<description>Mammoth Cave National Park ... Lake Coffee Shop: Stop by for a cup of coffee and one of our homemade desserts. TrogloBITES: Our on-site fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Mammoth Cave National Park Mammoth Cave Hotel Online Reservations Dining&amp;Shopping Meetings&amp;Retreats Travel Tips&amp;FAQ History Articles Employment Opportunities Special Offers Photo Gallery Local Resources Forever Resorts Locations News&amp;Media Resources Contact Us Home   
 Stay up on vacation specials&amp;travel news at Forever Resorts. First Name
 Last Name
 Email
 Zip Code
 Forever Resorts does not send unsolicited email.
 Please review our online privacy policy . 
 
This is such a beautiful place. We loved spending time together as a family during the cave tour.

 Recent Guest 
Mammoth Cave National Park

 
 
 
Dining&amp;Shopping
 
 Dining 

No hotel is complete without a good restaurant and Mammoth Cave Hotel offers you three of them! Enjoy southern hospitality at its finest while local chefs prepare popular entrees and homemade desserts.

 Travertine Restaurant : Featuring popular local dishes in a casual atmosphere.

 The Crystal Lake Coffee Shop : Stop by for a cup of coffee and one of our homemade desserts.

 TrogloBITES : Our on-site fast food restaurant, delivers burgers, fries and sodas in a jiffy.

 
 
Come one or come all, no appetite is too big or too small at the Travertine Restaurant. The restaurant is open daily from 7:00 a.m. to 7:30 p.m.

 Gifts&amp;Souvenirs 
Mammoth Cave Hotel, winner of the prestigious 
2003 Kentucky Crafted Retailer of the Year Award, is proud to support Kentucky artisans and craftspeople and promote craft entrepreneurs and traditions.

The Kentucky Home Gift Shop features beautiful gifts and works of art. The Cave Company features souvenirs, cave memorabilia, t-shirts, postcards, books&amp;snacks.

The Gift Stores is open daily from 8:00 a.m. to 7:30 p.m.

 Convenience Store 

Mammoth Cave Hotel also offers guests and Park visitors a service center and convenience store located on Mammoth Cave Parkway, near the National Park Service campground. The Caver&apos;s Camp Store features auto supplies, groceries, picnic foods, showers and a self-service laundry facility with an adjacent full-service U.S. Post Office.
 

   
 
 
    Home Page    |    Our Environmental Policy    |    Contact Us    |    Property Policies    
 
Forever Resorts is an authorized concessioner of the National Park Service and operates under special permits with state agencies, and the USDA Forest Service. Forever Resorts is a committed Equal Employment Opportunity Service Provider.

©2012 Forever Resorts. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
