<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001747" url="http://www.packworld.com/machinery/converting-machinery/festive-cup-stars-carls-jr-restaurants" time="2012-07-12-17:31" support="17" score="0.019495873877713774" bingtitle="Festive cup stars at Carl&apos;s Jr. restaurants | Packaging World" webtitle="Festive cup stars at Carls Jr. restaurants | Packaging World">
			<query id="001341" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="001466" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000204" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="000214" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000660" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000666" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000305" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000680" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000192" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000217" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001339" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000213" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="001320" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000429" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000211" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000180" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000212" bing-rank="247"/>
	<description>» Tropicana Europe: Air conveying/filling/accumulating/labeling/tray packing on aseptic ... On-demand Webinar: Bottom Line Benefits of Thermal Inkjet Printing »</description>
	<body>
		Skip to main content 
 Subscribe Magazine 
 Magazine info About Contact us Advertise Media kit 
 Newsletters Conferences 
 The Automation Conference Sustainable Packaging Symposium Calendar of Events 
 Contract Packaging 
 Contract Packaging Magazine info Subscribe to Contract Packaging Latest Articles 
 Education 
 Webinars Packager&apos;s Playbooks Packaging Education Alliance Packaging Schools IoPP Latest Articles Associations 
 Leadership iPad/Mobile Contact us 
 Packaging news, trends&amp;innovations 
 Package Design 
 Graphic Structural Sustainability Retail Ready Private Label Rigid Containers Flexible Packaging Closures Labels Protective 
 Machinery 
 Controls Bagging&amp;F/F/S Fill/Cap Convey Code/Mark Cartoning Labeling Case/Tray Palletize/Wrap Vision/Inspection Blister/Clamshell 
 Videos 
 Beverage Roundtable Package Design Videos Private Label Smackdown Off the Shelf Video Pack Expo Las Vegas 2011 
 Case Studies 
 Food Beverage Health Personal Care Consumer Products Flexible Rigid Carton/Box Blister/Clamshell Controls 
 INNOVATION GALLERIES 
 Flexible Packaging Labeling 
 
 
 
 Post jobs free View jobs 
 
 
Trending
 
 Digital printing QR codes In-pack pasteurization Package Development Playbook 
   Flexible packaging project in the works? Download this free, 84-page Flexible Packaging Playbook jam-packed with strategies for success, best practices, and pitfalls to avoid.  Learn more  » Glenroy invites you to download this playbook.
 
Related Sponsored Links
 Video Compact case packer and sealer for folding cartons White Paper Case study and package evaluation of the Fres-co #10 can replacement Video A cool alternative to traditional hot melt can double your mileage Video Ultrasonic sealing technology that reduces materials, maintenance, and energy Video SmartCycle® films, a packaging solution with sustainability in mind Video Tour the latest thermal-transfer date coding system 
Recommended Reading
 Machine Product Brief Compact sheeter Machine Product Brief Plastic pallet molding system Machine Case Study Boston Scientific boxes savings by producing shippers on demand 
Festive cup stars at Carl&apos;s Jr. restaurants
 Article | June 1, 1995 
Festive cup stars at Carl&apos;s Jr. restaurants
 A converting process expands into cups,creating a festive holiday promotion for Print Email Share FILED IN:  Machinery  &gt; Converting machinery     Enlarge Carl Karcher Enterprises Anaheim CA became the first to use a beverage cup made by a multi-patented converting process. Beginning last Thanksgiving and continuing through the &apos;94 holiday season some 650 of its Carl&apos;s Jr. West coast fast food restaurant outlets sold one million 32-oz beverages in cups formed by Dopaco (Downington PA) using Graphic Packaging&apos;s (Wayne PA) Com-posiCup(TM) process. &quot;We wanted a festive cup with a foil look&quot; says Linda Larsen manager of sales promotion for the fast food chain. &quot;We&apos;ve never sold beverages in a paper cup as elaborate as this one. Dopaco gave us the opportunity to market a beautiful cup using Graphic Packaging&apos;s process with little incremental costs. We&apos;re always looking for a way to differentiate ourselves in this competitive marketplace and ComposiCup certainly fills the bill. It looks fantastic.&quot; The cup features an array of star shapes sizes and colors with the words &quot;Star Season&quot; in two places. The Carl&apos;s Jr. name is repeated near the base of the cup though in small lettering. From the inside out the material used for the Carl&apos;s Jr. cup includes 75-ga low-density polyethylene laminated to a 16-pt SBS board that incorporates extra-long fibers with a high moisture content to prevent cracking during cupforming. GP uses 0.75 mils of LDPE to laminate the boardstock to metal/lacquer/seven-color reverse-print by gravure/1-mil LDPE. The lacquer applied at an eighth printing station provides a good tack for the metallization. By burying graphics beneath the outer LDPE layer the print is protected from abrasion and scuffing that can occur during shipping and storage. Graphic Packaging slits the 44 1/2&quot;-wide webs of printed metallized laminated material into individual cup blanks. Blanks are shipped to Dopaco where existing equipment forms the cups. Of course this container isn&apos;t a typical &quot;package&quot; but the process derives from GP&apos;s Composipac(TM) method previously used for folding cartons and flexible packaging. The ComposiCup process can work with canister forming equipment for applications including ice cream snacks drinks and soups.
 
 Companies in this article: SUPPLIER: 
 » Graphic Packaging Corporation 
 
Comments(0)
 
Add new comment
 Your name Subject Comment * By submitting this form, you accept the Mollom privacy policy . 
SPECIAL REPORT

10 TIPS

ON SUSTAINABILITY
 Sign up to receive timely updates from our editors and download this special report from Greener Package Editor Anne Marie Mohan. 

 

 
Newsletters
 Don’t miss intelligence crucial to your job and business! Click on any newsletter to view a sample. Enter your email address below to sign up! GENERAL INTEREST 
 New Issue Alert 

Packaging World Magazine
 
 eClip 

Breaking packaging news
 
 Packaging Insights 

Pertinent packaging issues
 PACKAGE DESIGN/
DEVELOPMENT 
 Greener Package 

Sustainable packaging
 
 Package Development 
 
 Shelf Impact 

Package design strategies
 SPECIAL INTEREST 
 Healthcare Packaging 
 
 Contract Packaging 
 PACKAGING MACHINERY 
 Automation Strategies 

Machine automation
 
 Automation Catalyst 

Igniting ideas to solve automation challenges
 
 Machine
Automation Insights 
 
 On the Edge 

Keith Campbell speaks out!
 
 New Machines 

New packaging machines
 PLAYBOOK STRATEGIES 
 Playbook Strategies for Flexible Packaging 
 
 Labeling
Playbook Strategies 
 
 Primary Packaging Line Playbook Strategies 
 
 End-of-Line Playbook Strategies 
 
 Package Identification
Playbook Strategies 
 PACK EXPO 
 Spotlight on PACK EXPO 
 
 Live from PACK EXPO 
 Each newsletter ranges in frequency from once per month to a few times per month at most. 

 
Search form
 
Design Videos
 » Beverage Roundtable: When (not) to use... O-I, makers of pure, beautiful, sustainable glass packaging, is proud to sponsor GlassIsLife.com SEE ALL VIDEOS » 
PACKAGING WORLD SHOWCASE

Going to the show?

Get your pre-show planner!
 Sign up to receive this FREE pre-show planner for North America&apos;s largest packaging exposition, PACK EXPO International, Oct. 28-31. (Published September 2012) Select your country United States Canada Afghanistan Åland Islands Albania Algeria American Samoa Andorra Angola Anguilla Antarctica Antigua and Barbuda Argentina Armenia Aruba Australia Austria Azerbaijan Bahamas Bahrain Bangladesh Barbados Belarus Belgium Belize Benin Bermuda Bhutan Bolivia Bosnia and Herzegovina Botswana Bouvet Island Brazil British Indian Ocean Territory Brunei Darussalam Bulgaria Burkina Faso Burundi Cambodia Cameroon Cape Verde Cayman Islands Central African Republic Chad Chile China Christmas Island Cocos (Keeling) Islands Colombia Comoros Congo Congo, The Democratic Republic of The Cook Islands Costa Rica Cote D&apos;ivoire Croatia Cuba Cyprus Czech Republic Denmark Djibouti Dominica Dominican Republic Ecuador Egypt El Salvador Equatorial Guinea Eritrea Estonia Ethiopia Falkland Islands (Malvinas) Faroe Islands Fiji Finland France French Guiana French Polynesia French Southern Territories Gabon Gambia Georgia Germany Ghana Gibraltar Greece Greenland Grenada Guadeloupe Guam Guatemala Guernsey Guinea Guinea-bissau Guyana Haiti Heard Island and Mcdonald Islands Holy See (Vatican City State) Honduras Hong Kong Hungary Iceland India Indonesia Iran, Islamic Republic of Iraq Ireland Isle of Man Israel Italy Jamaica Japan Jersey Jordan Kazakhstan Kenya Kiribati Korea, Democratic People&apos;s Republic of Korea, Republic of Kuwait Kyrgyzstan Lao People&apos;s Democratic Republic Latvia Lebanon Lesotho Liberia Libyan Arab Jamahiriya Liechtenstein Lithuania Luxembourg Macao Macedonia, The Former Yugoslav Republic of Madagascar Malawi Malaysia Maldives Mali Malta Marshall Islands Martinique Mauritania Mauritius Mayotte Mexico Micronesia, Federated States of Moldova, Republic of Monaco Mongolia Montenegro Montserrat Morocco Mozambique Myanmar Namibia Nauru Nepal Netherlands Netherlands Antilles New Caledonia New Zealand Nicaragua Niger Nigeria Niue Norfolk Island Northern Mariana Islands Norway Oman Pakistan Palau Palestinian Territory, Occupied Panama Papua New Guinea Paraguay Peru Philippines Pitcairn Poland Portugal Puerto Rico Qatar Reunion Romania Russian Federation Rwanda Saint Helena Saint Kitts and Nevis Saint Lucia Saint Pierre and Miquelon Saint Vincent and The Grenadines Samoa San Marino Sao Tome and Principe Saudi Arabia Senegal Serbia Seychelles Sierra Leone Singapore Slovakia Slovenia Solomon Islands Somalia South Africa South Georgia and The South Sandwich Islands Spain Sri Lanka Sudan Suriname Svalbard and Jan Mayen Swaziland Sweden Switzerland Syrian Arab Republic Taiwan, Province of China Tajikistan Tanzania, United Republic of Thailand Timor-leste Togo Tokelau Tonga Trinidad and Tobago Tunisia Turkey Turkmenistan Turks and Caicos Islands Tuvalu Uganda Ukraine United Arab Emirates United Kingdom United States Minor Outlying Islands Uruguay Uzbekistan Vanuatu Venezuela Viet Nam Virgin Islands, British Virgin Islands, U.S. Wallis and Futuna Western Sahara Yemen Zambia Zimbabwe 
Supplier Directory
 Compare machines and materials from different manufacturers: 
 Cartoning machines Labeling machines Case/tray loading/multipacking Form/fill/seal machines All packaging machinery Packaging converters—rigid&amp;flexible 
 EVALUATE MORE THAN 17,000 PRODUCTS » 
Magazines
 
 
 
Most popular
 Article Package Case Study » Tropicana&apos;s bold shift to PET Article Feature Article » Sustainability helps advance molded fiber packaging Article Primer » Flexible packaging specification guidelines Article Feature Article » Variety-pack box reveals four 22-oz glass bottles inside 
 Videos Webinars White Papers 
 » New palletizer doubles production » Kliklok Cartoning -- Innovation in Action » Edna Valley Vineyard: Accumulation table for wine bottling line » Marking and verification system VIEW MORE VIDEOS » » On-Demand Webcast: Real-time Ethernet for Machine Control » On-demand Webinar: Advanced Hot-Melt Adhesives » On-demand Webinar: Walmart&apos;s North American Retail Ready Packaging Evolution » On-demand Webinar: The Value of Specification Management VIEW MORE WEBINARS » » Robots automatically show rapid return on investment » Ensuring RFID&apos;s Bottom Line Payoff » The case for outsourcing a packaging line to a machinery supplier » White paper discusses advances in roll-fed extended content labeling View more white papers » 
Magazine
 
 Subscribe Advertise About 
 
Conferences
 
 The Automation Conference Sustainable Packaging Symposium 
 
Stay in Touch
 
 Newsletters RSS 
 
 Facebook LinkedIn Twitter 
 
Education
 
 Packaging Education Alliance Packaging Playbooks Packaging Schools 
 
Other Summit Media Group Websites
 
 PW Marketplace Directory GreenerPackage.com HealthcarePackaging.com AutomationWorld.com 
 Home | Advertise | About | RSS | Privacy | Terms of use | © Copyright 2012 Summit Media Group, Inc. | Reprint, re-use or license articles from this Web site | Login OM Base Theme 2012 | V7.x-2.x | Daniel Honrade
	</body>
</document>
