<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001519" url="http://forumserver.twoplustwo.com/30/business-finance-investing/about-how-much-do-fast-food-franchise-owners-make-213489/index2.html" time="2012-07-12-17:17" support="1" score="0.0065448532247384126" bingtitle="About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make? - Page 2 ..." webtitle="About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make? - Page 2 - Business, Finances and Investing Forum">
			<query id="001034" bing-rank="124"/>
	<description>I take out 1200 to pay down my note, and 750/wk in admin expenses ... Re: About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make?</description>
	<body>
		2+2 Shortcuts Hand Converter 2+2 Store 2+2 Magazine 2+2 Blogs 2+2 Pokercast 
 
 Non–US players
GET FIVE 2+2 books FREE!
see our poker bonus 
 
 2+2 Forums Expand   Collapse 
 Two Plus Two Best of 2+2 2+2 Magazine Forum 2+2 Bonus Program 2+2 Pokercast 2+2 Videos Marketplace Commercial Marketplace Classified Listings About the Forums 
 General Poker Beginners Questions Poker Goals&amp;Challenges Books and Publications Poker Theory News, Views, and Gossip Poker Headlines Televised Poker Brick and Mortar Mortar and Brick Home Poker Poker Legislation Fight for Poker Rights (PPA) That&apos;s What She Said Beats, Brags, and Variance 
 Videos Poker Video Directory CardRunners.com DragTheBar.com PokerVIP.com LeggoPoker.com PokerStrategy.com 
 Coaching/ Training Coaching Advice Cash Games Poker Coaches Tournament / SNG Poker Coaches CardRunners PokerStrategy.com 
 Sponsored Support RPM Poker Lock Poker Carbon Poker Draft Day 
 Limit Hold&apos;em High Stakes Limit Medium Stakes Limit Small Stakes Limit Micro Stakes Limit Mid-High Short-handed Small Stakes Shorthanded Limit––&gt;NL Heads Up Limit 
 No Limit Hold&apos;em High Stakes NL Medium Stakes NL Small Stakes NL Micro Stakes NL Medium-High Full Ring Small Full Ring Micro Full Ring Heads Up NL Live Low-stakes NL 
 Tournament Poker STT Strategy Heads Up SNG High Stakes MTT Midstakes MTT Small Stakes MTT MTTSNG MTT Community MTTc - Live Tournament Results 
 Other Poker High Stakes PLO Small Stakes PLO Omaha/8 Stud Draw and Other Poker 
 General Gambling Backgammon Probability Psychology Sports Betting Other Gambling Games Entertainment Betting 
 Internet Poker Internet Poker Internet Bonuses Affiliates/RakeBack Software 
 2+2 Communities Other Other Topics The Lounge EDF Las Vegas Lifestyle BBV4Life The Studio 
 Sports&amp;Games Sporting Events Wrestling Golf Pool, Snooker, and Billiards Chess Video Games Puzzles and Other Games 
 Other Topics Politics Business, Finance, and Investing Travel Science, Math, and Philosophy History Religion, God, and Theology Health and Fitness Student Life Laughs or Links! Computer Technical Help Programming 
 International Deutsch Français Español 2+2.ру 

 Other Links Two Plus Two Poker Books Authors Book Translations Abbreviations Feedback Advertising Info Privacy Notice Terms and Conditions Forum Archives 
 

 
   Two Plus Two Poker Forums &gt; Other Topics &gt; Business, Finance, and Investing About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make? 
 
 User Name Remember Me? Password 
 
 
 Register FAQ Today&apos;s Posts Search Video Directory TwoPlusTwo.com 
 

 Business, Finance, and Investing Making money, investing in markets, and running businesses 

 
 Search Forums Show Threads   Show Posts Advanced Search 
 
 Home Magazine Featured Blogs Order Books Pokercast Bonus Program Feedback Terms&amp;Conditions 
 
 Go to Page... 
 
 
 Page 2 of 8 &lt; 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 &gt; Last » 
 

   Thread Tools Display Modes 
 
 05-28-2008, 02:10 PM  # 16 Mandor_TFL grinder  
 Join Date: Dec 2006 Posts: 577 Re: About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make? I bought two poorly run Subway franchises and turned them around. Sales growth of 20 percent year over year for both. Money is still around to be printed if your willing to work for it. Currently my only problems are with Subway corporate itself and its unwillingness to help franchisee&apos;s ( a gotcha kind of inspection system is now in place, causing franchisee&apos;s to worry about inspections rather than sales )


A busy location can pull in 10-20% gross profit. A slower location might do 0-10% though. The key to these type of restaurants is to have a strong enough location that your sales can reduce your labor cost percentage. Busy stores may require more employee hours but they will be more productive.


Last week breakdown at my busy store

Sales 15,000 ( this is 50% more than subway nation wide avg )
Royalties Adv 12.5% ( always 12.5 per dollar sold)
Elec 225/wk
Gas 20/wk
Trash 50/wk
Labor 3,400/wk ( not including my time )
Food and Drink cost 34% ( this varies between 32-36% depending on sales and food prices )
Maintence 125/wk ( varies but averages to be 500 a month
Rent 500/wk ( mine is normal but low for how good a location it is )

So I pulled in 3500/wk in profit. I take out 1200 to pay down my note, and 750/wk in admin expenses ( paying self ). If i was debt free and did not draw any income from the store I would be making about 150k a year at this volume.


My slower store though only does 5500/wk in sales but its labor is still 1800/wk. Notice that insane labor percentage. You can only cut labor so much. Having busy hours all the time is the key to a profitable franchise. If it was my only store I would only need maybe 1000/wk in labor. But I would be working 60+ hours a week in the store for about 800 bucks a week. So buying a slower store is buying yourself a job. After maintence and Subway forced upgrades the location barely makes any money. I can probably make another year of sales gains at the location before I hit a wall. Then I plan on selling it off. Its not worth the work for value gained.   
 
 05-28-2008, 02:38 PM  # 17 heater Carpal \&apos;Tunnel  
 Join Date: Feb 2006 Location: Happy Easter! Posts: 7,637 Re: About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make? Quote: 
 Originally Posted by ImsaKidd Probably like 30-40k/year. 
 A guy I went to school with is a director of operations or something for Arby&apos;s in SW Michigan. He said their average store in that area grosses around 1.5 mil a year. They&apos;re profiting much more than 30-40k a year.

I know an area supervisor for Papa John&apos;s. Their best store did 1.2 mil last year and profited around 180k. Their worst store did less than half that and made close to nothing.   
 
 05-28-2008, 03:36 PM  # 18 guids banned  
 Join Date: Oct 2005 Posts: 16,997 Re: About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make? Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Yowserrrs The best idea for starting a new restaurant business is to sample local specialties then bring those ideas to new towns with similar demographics and where you still have reasonable access to the same ingriedients. You&apos;ll make a ****load more than opening a ****ty MCD. 
 There are tons of statistics to refute this, and its simply wrong.   
 
 05-28-2008, 03:59 PM  # 19 CrushinFelt Pooh-Bah  
 Join Date: Aug 2006 Posts: 4,651 Re: About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make? Quote: 
 Food and Drink cost 34% ( this varies between 32-36% depending on sales and food prices ) 
 What are the laregst items in this category?   
 
 05-28-2008, 04:01 PM  # 20 Yowserrrs Pooh-Bah  
 Join Date: Nov 2007 Posts: 5,348 Re: About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make? Quote: 
 Originally Posted by guids There are tons of statistics to refute this, and its simply wrong. 
 So many in fact that you couldnt even list one in your post...thanks for your valuable contribution.   
 
 05-28-2008, 04:05 PM  # 21 Mandor_TFL grinder  
 Join Date: Dec 2006 Posts: 577 Re: About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make? Quote: 
 Originally Posted by CrushinFelt What are the laregst items in this category? 
 Cheese and meats are the most expensive items. Veggies are so cheap we do not charge extra for requesting extra lettuce for instance. But cheese is about 10 cents a slice so that would add up quick. If a footlong costs about 1.70 in food about 1.20-1.30 of that is in the meat and cheese.



Too bad people do not like salads much, selling veggie salads for 5 bucks a pop would have insanely low food cost.   
 
 05-28-2008, 04:10 PM  # 22 Mandor_TFL grinder  
 Join Date: Dec 2006 Posts: 577 Re: About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make? Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Yowserrrs The best idea for starting a new restaurant business is to sample local specialties then bring those ideas to new towns with similar demographics and where you still have reasonable access to the same ingriedients. You&apos;ll make a ****load more than opening a ****ty MCD. 
 Finding reasonable access to ingredients is not as easy as it sounds. Finding consistent suppliers at a reasonable price for ingredients is one of the reasons for being with a franchise. Having to call and yell at your supplier yourself about how terrible todays tomatoes are works a lot better when it is 1000 people all working together.


In general large franchises save tons on buying food in bulk and passing the savings on to franchisees. Of course the royalty fee&apos;s take this all back. It does however help mitigate that 6-8% going out the door to your corporate overlords.   
 
 05-28-2008, 04:41 PM  # 23 maxtower Pooh-Bah  
  
 Join Date: Sep 2005 Posts: 4,975 Re: About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make? Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Mandor_TFL I bought two poorly run Subway franchises and turned them around. Sales growth of 20 percent year over year for both. Money is still around to be printed if your willing to work for it. Currently my only problems are with Subway corporate itself and its unwillingness to help franchisee&apos;s ( a gotcha kind of inspection system is now in place, causing franchisee&apos;s to worry about inspections rather than sales ) 
 I would be interested in hearing more about this. How did you increase sales? What other improvements did you make? How did you find the Subways for sale? How much did they cost (in terms of profits)?   
 
 05-28-2008, 04:49 PM  # 24 Yowserrrs Pooh-Bah  
 Join Date: Nov 2007 Posts: 5,348 Re: About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make? Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Mandor_TFL Finding reasonable access to ingredients is not as easy as it sounds. Finding consistent suppliers at a reasonable price for ingredients is one of the reasons for being with a franchise. Having to call and yell at your supplier yourself about how terrible todays tomatoes are works a lot better when it is 1000 people all working together.


In general large franchises save tons on buying food in bulk and passing the savings on to franchisees. Of course the royalty fee&apos;s take this all back. It does however help mitigate that 6-8% going out the door to your corporate overlords. 
 Absolutely. Its basically similar to how an index fund is shopped to mom and pop. Conservative investors look at an index fund as allowing them to be involved in the market without having to take on the level of risk associated with holding just a few names while also minimizing trading costs at the same time.

Franchises function in a similar way. You get a known successful brand and product. You dont need to worry about a number of the risk factors associated with indepedent businesses. However the biggest risk factor, location, is just as relevant. The downside is there is intense competition and the thread of new entrants is very high. So even if you were lucky enough to be in top 0.5% who actually hit a home run instead of just earning a decent middle class living, you are always vulnerable to franchisees coming to town and opening in your neighborhood.

Obv the model I&apos;m suggesting is riskier but when youre the first and only in your town to offer a hot product, the returns can be enormous. Yes you dont get things handed to you like you do in a franchisee program, but with hard work and good decision making, it is the far superior option.   
 
 05-28-2008, 05:10 PM  # 25 Mandor_TFL grinder  
 Join Date: Dec 2006 Posts: 577 Re: About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make? Quote: 
 Originally Posted by maxtower I would be interested in hearing more about this. How did you increase sales? What other improvements did you make? How did you find the Subways for sale? How much did they cost (in terms of profits)? 
 
Increased sales by treating my employees better, and firing bad ones. The previous owner was very absentee and did nothing. Fixed operations to be more focused on customer service. Did minor promotions involving giving away free subs. Free drives in customers much better than dollar off coupons. Let them eat a free sandwich and if they come back once a week, you end up making an extra 400 dollars in sales for that sandwich that cost u a buck.


A lot of repairs were needed which were let slide by the previous ownership. So I fixed them which helped to increase sales.

Subway.com has a list of subway&apos;s for sale. Some areas have been built up long ago and the franchisee&apos;s are ready to move on. If every subway is new near you then the only ones for sale are the ones with bad locations. Most places in the USA are built out, and are not building new Subways.


The previous owner was a motivated seller ( divorce ). He charged what the busy store did in profits * 4. The slow store he threw in for free basically, as it made no money.


I do not necessarily recommend Subway due to the corporate structure. It is still privately owned by 1 guy, who does as he pleases more or less. He is a smart guy. But he contracted out his inspection and development to local area managers. The local guys oversee 100-300 stores, and are next to unaccountable. So if you have a good local guy it works great, but some suck. I alas got a sucky one though I did not know it at the time.   
 
 05-28-2008, 05:15 PM  # 26 onlinebeginner Pooh-Bah  
 Join Date: Dec 2006 Posts: 4,892 Re: About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make? Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Yowserrrs So many in fact that you couldnt even list one in your post...thanks for your valuable contribution. 
 hahah you couldn&apos;t even respond to me with an example... so ignorant hypocritical and stubborn it is unbelievable   
 
 05-28-2008, 05:35 PM  # 27 Yowserrrs Pooh-Bah  
 Join Date: Nov 2007 Posts: 5,348 Re: About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make? Quote: 
 Originally Posted by onlinebeginner hahah you couldn&apos;t even respond to me with an example... so ignorant hypocritical and stubborn it is unbelievable 
 Sorry I confused you with someone else....Yes Id be glad to give you a real one, just let me know what means you have to open it and lets contract the 10% finders fee because otherwise Im wasting my time.   
 
 05-28-2008, 07:02 PM  # 28 S2000Maniac journeyman  
 Join Date: Feb 2008 Posts: 363 Re: About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make? a guy in my town did a presentation in our accounting class.

he owns the 4 mickey D&apos;s in town.

He said the average mcdonalds owner makes 500k profit a year.   
 
 05-28-2008, 07:30 PM  # 29 Mandor_TFL grinder  
 Join Date: Dec 2006 Posts: 577 Re: About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make? Quote: 
 Originally Posted by S2000Maniac a guy in my town did a presentation in our accounting class.

he owns the 4 mickey D&apos;s in town.

He said the average mcdonalds owner makes 500k profit a year. 
 
I heard the opposite from a former McD franchisee. Well to be paraphrase him he said that McD franchisee&apos;s made most of their money from the value of the business rather than making oodles of money. Seeing as how much labor must eat into their profits I was inclined to believe him. That being said very busy McD&apos;s certainly could make that much. One of the great benefits if you run a business right is when you got to sell it you can sell it for a very significant profit.   
 
 05-28-2008, 07:39 PM  # 30 ArturiusX Carpal \&apos;Tunnel  
  
 Join Date: Sep 2004 Posts: 19,115 Re: About How Much Do Fast Food Franchise Owners Make? Quote: 
 Originally Posted by code7654321 Everyone is health conscious nowadays. 
 I lol&apos;ed   
 

 
 Page 2 of 8 &lt; 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 &gt; Last » 
 

 Tweet         

 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
 
 Thread Tools Show Printable Version Email this Page 
 
 Display Modes Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 
 Posting Rules You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On HTML code is Off Trackbacks are Off Pingbacks are Off Refbacks are Off Forum Rules 
 
 
 


 All times are GMT -4. The time now is 11:17 AM . 
 
 
 
 
 Contact Us - Two Plus Two Publishing LLC - Privacy Statement - Top 

 Powered by vBulletin®
Copyright©2000 - 2012, Jelsoft Enterprises Ltd.
Content Relevant URLs by vBSEO 3.6.0©2011, Crawlability, Inc. Copyright 2008-2010, Two Plus Two Interactive
	</body>
</document>
