<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001493" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/hot-some-extra-money-doing-nothing-380038.html" time="2012-07-12-17:16" support="17" score="0.02577597221629625" bingtitle="Hot -To Make Some Extra Money Doing Nothing - Yahoo! Voices ..." webtitle="Hot -To Make Some Extra Money Doing Nothing - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="001196" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="001231" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000756" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="001243" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="001389" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000780" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="001420" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000397" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="001432" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="001435" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000772" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="001200" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="001416" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="001227" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000770" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="001247" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="001385" bing-rank="95"/>
	<description>... more likely to spend it if you go to a fast food restaurant and ... You take that receipt to a cashier and they give you the money. ... Hint: longer : the longer you keep the money ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 
 
Hot -To Make Some Extra Money Doing Nothing

Save Your Change Make Some Money
 Rob Church , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
Jun 11, 2007 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: Talking About Money Old Coins Coin Grading Machining 
 Flag Close Post a comment Introduction 
People say that making some extra little cash, around $10 in two weeks, requires work. I am here to tell you that it does not require any work at all. The only work it requires is bending down and picking something up every once in a while.

Let me tell you what I am talking about. I am talking about saving coins. It is a very simple thing to do. I know from experience.

 Steps 

Here is how I make about $20 in three weeks.

When you go out and buy something and they give you change, coins, put it in your pocket. Do not put it in an ash tray in the car or something like that, because you are more likely to spend it if you go to a fast food restaurant and they have a drive through. The reason I say that you need to put the coins in your pocket is because you will go inside your house with the coins in your pocket. Anther thing that you need to know is that you do not take the coins out of your pocket right when you walk in the door.

What you need is something in your room to put the coins in, so when you go to your room you take the coins out of your pocket and put them into that container or whatever. If you keep following these steps your money will increase. It will help if you put the container somewhere that might get covered up with clothes or something.

People these days have busy schedules, and most of the time you get ready to go somewhere at the last minute. In this case you run out of the house leaving the change in the room, because you were in a rush and did not think about it or your mind was set on something that made you forget about it.

There is something that I do that most people may find stupid, but it will help you make more money. If you ever see just a penny lying on the ground anywhere, pick it up and put it into the container you have in your room. All the pennies you get from other places, that one penny helps to reach another dollar. You may not have a full dollar with the extra coins after you count it out and those extra pennies that you pick up on the side walk anywhere will help that reach another full dollar. I pick up any change I see.

You will be amazed how fast the money will accumulate over time.

What I do is take my change to Food Lion and stick it in the machine they have. This machine counts all of your coins. It then prints out a receipt that tells you how much you had. You take that receipt to a cashier and they give you the money. The only bad thing about this machine is that it charges you 8.9 cents for every dollar you put in. I believe the machine is called Coin Star.

 Hint 
Hint: longer : the longer you keep the money in the container without taking it to Coin Star the more you will make.
 
Published by Rob Church 

Born in Marrietta, Georgia in 1989. Lived in Atlanta until I was in the middle of 1rst grade. In the middle of First grade we moved to Ringgold, Georgia. I have lived there since. I was a student at Geor...  View profile 
 
 10 Tips on Getting Your Family Involved in Saving Money 10 Tips on Getting Your Family Involved in Saving Money Make Money Blogging! Ads all over the internet claim you can make a lot of money through a blog. What is a blog? How can you make money with one? Read more about making money through blogging! How to Make Money Using Your Blog Everyone owns blogs, and now you can monetize your blog and make money Make Money Online Monetizing Blogs: I Cracked the Code This amazing tutorial will show you how easy it is to make money from blogs; this is like walking around with a blank cheque from Adsense! American Values Investments Wants to Help You Make Money American Values Investment is putting the theory to the test that you can actually make money and not need to give you conscience a long shower every night. 

 How to Make Money with WowPTP.org How to Make Money with WorldWide... How to Make Money with ImageFly.... 
 
 Saving Money: Trick Yourself into Saving Instead of Spending Saving Money when You&apos;re Already Broke Tips on Saving Money While Grocery Shopping 8 Ways to Save Money Just by Taking a Shower 51 Surefire Ways to Make Money Online Money: How to Make the Best of It Nothing but a Number 
 
 
 
 Takeaways Did You Know 
 
 Introduction Steps Hint 
 The longer you follow the steps without taking your coins to Coin Star at Food Lion, the more money you will make by doing basically nothing. 
13 Comments
 Post a Comment 
 Claire Grey 11/3/2008 
Wow, very good idea!
 DJ 729 8/25/2008 
this sucks im trying to make over $200 in just a week but ur tellin me u made only $20 dollars in 3 weeks that bogus. this suck really hard
 Paul Diamond Blow 8/17/2008 
Some good tips here... and to think I used to throw my spare change away in the garbage. Thanks!
 Brian Hanson 2/25/2008 
Insted of using Coinstar why not bring it to the bank for free?
 Harry 1/2/2008 
Saving change definetely helps. It really adds up. This also acts as an example to various things in Life.
 chuck 11/9/2007 
i keep my change all the time last year i took it to a bank and i had 100.00extra for christmas now this year so far i have over 50.00 dollors al;l ready i keep it all the time in my home made bank i made out of a coffee can and taped the lid shut so i cant get into it i love to keep my chang ,and all the pennys to they add up quick.thanks your frend chuck
 Jesus 11/1/2007 
Wait... that&apos;s not making money... that&apos;s saving change.

You&apos;re a fag.
 Tiffany Blue 9/25/2007 

you can use that change to open a savings account with a high APY, check out my article on &quot;online banks&quot; for some good banks to choose from!
 SAC 9/17/2007 
Want to really add up change?
Try doing it in Canada where we use one and two dollar coins (no more 1 and 2 dollar bills and haven&apos;t been in several years).
My wife has saved as much a thousand (Yes, one THOUSAND)dollars at a time in about a year or so.
Managed to buy a used car and a dishwasher with pocket change.

 Richie 9/7/2007 
You can make $10 couple day if you really wanted by joining some GPT websites where you do offers and surveys. It&apos;s easy to make $30 a month by doing $1.00 daily surveys on 1 website. Check out more information at http://www.gptwebsites.com

... deffinately count out your own change
 
 Displaying Comments «Prev 1 2 Next» 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Shine and Lifestyles Network. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
