<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0001665" url="http://ssilveri.edublogs.org/ap-literature/week-8-2011-the-outsiders/" time="2012-07-12-17:26" support="1" score="0.0017234442207019378" bingtitle="Week 8 (2011): The Outsiders" webtitle="Week 8 (2011):  The Outsiders">
			<query id="000257" bing-rank="175"/>
	<description>... how the essays and The Outsiders confirm or ... A person who works as a janitor or a cashier at a fast food restaurant ... In fact, they have to dress down in order to ...</description>
	<body>
		In Session: Sentiments from Silveri&apos;s Class 

Engaging in Critical Conversations that Matter Most
 
 Home “With All Deliberate Speed” AP Language 
 (Spring 2012) Week #7: Their Eyes Were Watching Gatsby (Spring 2012) Week #9: Lady Zora (Spring 2012) Week 1: All Other Nights (Spring 2012) Week 3: O.G. Edgar Allan Poe (Spring 2012) Week 5: GSHGT Practice AP Language Final Exam (Fall 2011) Week 1 (2011): We Shall Remain Week 7 (2011): A Letter to Your Children Week 2 (2011): An Issue of Race Week 3 (2011): Reliability of Primary Sources Week 4 (2011): American Propaganda Week 5 (2011): A Great and Mighty Walk Week 6 (2011): Between Heaven and Hell Week 8 (2011): Inconvenient Consumption Week 9 (Fall 2011): Going Global Week 10 (Fall 2011): The Crucible, Part I Week 12 (Fall 2011): The Crucible, Part II Week 13 (Fall 2011): The Crucible, Part III Week 14 (Fall 2011): A Declaration Week 15 (Fall 2011): The Ultimate Appeal 
 AP Language Instructions AP Literature 
 (Spring 2011) Week #9: Ellison’s Invisible Man (Spring 2012) Senior Exit Portfolio Guidelines (Spring 2012) Week #4: Letter to Self… (Spring 2012) Week #7: Hamlet (Spring 2012) Week 1: Intro to the International Novel (Spring 2012) Week 3: Theoretically Speaking… (Spring 2012) Week 5: AP Lit Exam Prep International Novel Presentation Guidelines Week 1 (2011): A Lesson Before Dying Week 2 (2011): Epic Beowulf Week 3 (2011): The Canterbury Tales Week 4 (2011): College Readiness Week 5 (2011): Identity Contruction Week 6 (2011): Elements of Fiction Week 7 (2011): Personal Development Plan Week 8 (2011): The Outsiders Week 9 (Fall 2011): The End of Poverty? Week 10 (Fall 2011): Dichotomies Week 12 (Fall 2011): The Country Road Week 13 (Fall 2011): Ethereal Experience Week 14 (Fall 2011): Beloved Week 15 (Fall 2011): Beloved, Part II AP Lit Fall 2011: Final Exam 
 AP Literature Instructions AP Literature Learning Extensions In Memoriam: Whitney Houston Letter to My Babies Parent Portal Recommendation Letter Etiquette About 
 Contact 
 Poetry 180 (Library of Congress) 
 Our Poetry Gallery 
 RSS 
 
 
Become a Classroom Sponsor
 Donation 

 Classroom Supplies Learning Journeys Technology 

 
Pages

 “With All Deliberate Speed” About 
 Contact 
 AP Language 
 (Spring 2012) Week #7: Their Eyes Were Watching Gatsby (Spring 2012) Week #9: Lady Zora (Spring 2012) Week 1: All Other Nights (Spring 2012) Week 3: O.G. Edgar Allan Poe (Spring 2012) Week 5: GSHGT Practice AP Language Final Exam (Fall 2011) Week 1 (2011): We Shall Remain Week 10 (Fall 2011): The Crucible, Part I Week 12 (Fall 2011): The Crucible, Part II Week 13 (Fall 2011): The Crucible, Part III Week 14 (Fall 2011): A Declaration Week 15 (Fall 2011): The Ultimate Appeal Week 2 (2011): An Issue of Race Week 3 (2011): Reliability of Primary Sources Week 4 (2011): American Propaganda Week 5 (2011): A Great and Mighty Walk Week 6 (2011): Between Heaven and Hell Week 7 (2011): A Letter to Your Children Week 8 (2011): Inconvenient Consumption Week 9 (Fall 2011): Going Global 
 AP Language Instructions AP Literature 
 (Spring 2011) Week #9: Ellison’s Invisible Man (Spring 2012) Senior Exit Portfolio Guidelines (Spring 2012) Week #4: Letter to Self… (Spring 2012) Week #7: Hamlet (Spring 2012) Week 1: Intro to the International Novel (Spring 2012) Week 3: Theoretically Speaking… (Spring 2012) Week 5: AP Lit Exam Prep AP Lit Fall 2011: Final Exam International Novel Presentation Guidelines Week 1 (2011): A Lesson Before Dying Week 10 (Fall 2011): Dichotomies Week 12 (Fall 2011): The Country Road Week 13 (Fall 2011): Ethereal Experience Week 14 (Fall 2011): Beloved Week 15 (Fall 2011): Beloved, Part II Week 2 (2011): Epic Beowulf Week 3 (2011): The Canterbury Tales Week 4 (2011): College Readiness Week 5 (2011): Identity Contruction Week 6 (2011): Elements of Fiction Week 7 (2011): Personal Development Plan Week 8 (2011): The Outsiders Week 9 (Fall 2011): The End of Poverty? 
 AP Literature Instructions AP Literature Learning Extensions In Memoriam: Whitney Houston Letter to My Babies Parent Portal Poetry 180 (Library of Congress) 
 Our Poetry Gallery 
 Recommendation Letter Etiquette 
 
Links of Interest

 African American History (Biography Channel) Asian American Heritage (PBS: Ancestors in the Americas) CNN College Board&apos;s AP Central Digital Citizenship Internet Safety Edublogs Help and Support Edublogs.org Free Documentaries “The Truth is Free” Glossary of Literary&amp;Rhetorical Terms (Rutgers Univ.) Hispanic Heritage Learn Out Loud (Free Audio&amp;Video Downloads) Library of Congress (LOC) Mrs. Silveri&apos;s Teacher Site (Hosted by SchoolDesk) National English Honor Society (Servant Scholars Chapter) NCTE (National Council of Teachers of English) New York Times Number 2 (Free Test Prep and College Planning Tool) OER Commons (Free-to-Use Teaching and Learning Content from Around the World) Online Etymology Dictionary PBS Project Gutenburg (36,000 free ebooks) Purdue University Online Writing Lab Shmoop Literature Analysis and Test Prep Silveri Service Learning Academy The History Channel The Onion TIME Magazine Univ. of Penn Library (40,000+ free ebooks) USA Test Prep (GSHGT and Amer. Lit. EOCT prep) Vocab Ahead (SAT Vocabulary) Xtranormal: 3-D Movie Maker Make your own movie in 3 minutes 
 
Stay Thirsty (...for knowledge)

 Silveri&apos;s AP English: Collaboration Station 
 
 
Week 8 (2011): The Outsiders
 
Greetings, My AP Babies!

This week, you’ll need to consider S.E. Hinton’s The Outsiders using the literary analysis techniques we’ve been discussing in class and in your Bedford text .

 

_________________________________________________________

Your tasks:

 Take a look at Robert Frost’s “Nothing Gold Can Stay.” Consider the following questions in your analysis: 

 What is Frost trying to say? Is this supposed to be a sad poem?  Why or why not? How do the words of this poem relate to what you’ve seen of the characters thus far?  How do they relate to your own life as a teenager? 

 Next, read one of the essays discussing class differences in America and share your thoughts about it in 3-4 sentence maximum.  Be sure to list the author and title of the essay you’re critiquing at the end of your response.  Basically, cite your source. PBS, People Like Us 

 Finally, consider how the essays and The Outsiders confirm or reject your theories about class differences in America.  Be sure to consider how the following social issues affect the characters’behavior:  poverty, child abuse, educational disparities, and grief. *Note:  this part requires additional outside research… Now, you’ll need to respond in one coherent analysis.  To do this effectively, you’ll also need to synthesize your sources.  Be sure to tell us where you got your information by citing your sources appropriately. 

That’s it!  Your original response post is due by 10:00pm, Wednesday, October 5th. Your response to at least two of your classmates’ posts is due by 10:00pm, Sunday, October 9th .

As always, I’m here if you need me.”Stay Gold…”

Love,  :)

Mrs. S
 
 119 Comments 
 
119 Comments so far↓

 
 Jasmine Evans // Oct 24, 2011 at 5:04 pm 
 
1)I believe that Frost is saying that everything must come to an end. “Good things don’t last forever” is what Frost makes me think of. Make the best of the situation!

2)I don’t think it was meant to be sad, I just think it was meant to show how life is and always will be, you cant change your situation only make the best of it before it comes to a end

3)I think the poem relates to Ponyboy, Johnny and Dally, because they have a strong friendship that no one can come between, their like family! The poem relates to me because I have experienced many trials and tribulations. I just let whatever I go through make stronger as a person and that’s what makes me me!

Title: “Pride, prejudice and the not-so-subtle politics of the working class” Author: Katherine Boo
 http://www.pbs.org/peoplelikeus/resources/essays1.html 
I totally agree with this essay! In the essay, Katherine explains how people are judged based on the uniform they were. A person who works as a janitor or a cashier at a fast food restaurant gets less respect than a person who has a blue-collar job. In this essay I learned that the low status workers don’t get to choose how they look. In fact, they have to dress down in order to move up.

What I have found in The Outsiders and the essay has given me evidence that my theories about class differences are very much true. What you are classified as by the world really impacts you your behavior. Most of the people who are classified as being in the lower class are more likely to behave in bad way and do things that aren’t so good. They are acting out because they are in poverty which they probably don’t even know ( I learned that from Mrs.Silveri)
 http://www.pbs.org/peoplelikeus/resources/essays7.html 
 http://www.alternativeright.com/main/blogs/untimely-observations/social-classes-the-american-middle-class 
 Reply 
 Oshia // Oct 24, 2011 at 5:25 pm 
 
Frost is trying to that how precious life is, how brief it remains before it fades. Everything worthwhile, is gold for a moment, until its time is over
No, I don’t think this poem is supposed to be sad but t to teach us about life and how thing or people are in your life for a season.
The poem relates to the characters Ponyboy, Johnny and Dally because they have a unbreakable friendship. The poem relates to me because I have experienced many tribulations in my life, but instead being miserable and depressed. I took the time to learn from those incidences a. They have made me become a better person.
“Pride, prejudice and the not-so-subtle politics of the working class”
 http://www.pbs.org/peoplelikeus/resources/essays1.html 
In the essay, Katherine discusses uniforms and how they identify you and your social class. For example, if you were seen wearing a janitor’s uniform or a blue-collar uniform you would get less respect or get looked down because they know your lower class. But if you were wearing a doctor’s jacket or any kind of medical coat, you would be viewed highly. In fact, they have to dress down in order to move up. I agree with this essay.
The essays and The Outsiders recognizes the social classes of America are very different. Why should people judge on where a person comes from?
 Reply 
 shayla // Nov 2, 2011 at 9:29 pm 
 
1. I think Frost is trying to say that everything that grows must die, adn everything that’s good must end. It’s like the circle of life.
2. I don’t think its supposed to be a sad poem, but it can come off sad to many people. Those people probably havent accepted death yet, and the fact that everything dies.
3. Well in the movie it seems like everything the characters recieve that is good comes to a quick end. Besides a few people I know dying, this hasnt really beeen a factor in my life.

I chose to read the essay“http://www.pbs.org/peoplelikeus/resources/essays1.html”I have this discussion topic with so many people from my school it’s crazy. It is so true that people assume things about you by how you dress. When you see someone with a mechanics outfit on, you automatically assume he’s nto making $$$ . Boys try to argue with me that rich people sag to, but I just argue back that they already have money. Get your money first before you try to copy what they do.

The essays and the movie The Outsiders completely accept my theories about poverty and social classes, etc. My theory was that even people with money in a higher social class can stilla ct as if they are living in poverty. An example would be the Socs. They had moneym yet they still fought the Greasers as if they lived in the same community. I also had a theory that child abuse happens more in poverty, which turned out to be true.

 http://www.ehow.com/about_6793581_child-abuse-poverty.html 

 http://www.pbs.org/peoplelikeus/resources/essays1.html 

”My mind”
 Reply 
 Charise K. Clay // Nov 8, 2011 at 6:37 pm 
 
1. Frost is basically saying that nothing perfect can stays perfect; there is always something to mess it up. Everything and everyone starts off good until something taints them.
2. This is supposed to be a sad poem. He is making up see how we destroy everything. We just can’t leave things be.
3. It shows how your environment can shape you. Johnny probably would have been the way he was or have done the things he did, if he had parental guidance at home. He truly was a product of his environment. I have picked up some traits from my parents; some are good as well as bad.
• “The Dark Side of Camp”
-This essay made me realize someone is always going to have something to say about everything you do. No one thinks the same. You can’t please everyone, just work on trying to please yourself. http://www.pbs.org/peoplelikeus/resources/essays2.html 
• The essays and the movie are a direct correlation. The essay is saying that somebody is always going to criticize you. The Soc’s didn’t like the Greasers. They believed they were disgusting and ill mannered. The greasers thought they were fine people but the Soc’s didn’t. They grew up on to totally different sides of the tracks. They couldn’t even respect one another as people because of their social class. Like Henry Fielding said,’’ Neither great poverty nor great riches will hear reason.” http://www.brainyquote.com/quotes/keywords/poverty_9.html 
 Reply 
 Vicorie Brown // Nov 11, 2011 at 9:45 am 
 
1.What is Frost trying to say? I believe Frost was trying to say was that even though something can be so inicent and pure, it eventually loses that“golden”look. Nothing stays perfect!
2.Is this supposed to be a sad poem? Why or why not? No, the poem is just food for thought. I took it as being ensightful.
3.How do the words of this poem relate to what you’ve seen of the characters thus far? I visualize a friend from middle school who such a scholar and care only about work and honors and completely changed into a“tart”in high school. Nothing stays“golden!”How do they relate to your own life as a teenager?
I still trying to stay golden so not much to my life.
 http://www.pbs.org/peoplelikeus/resources/essays3.html 
This essay really made me think of the word“bougy.”People of the elite class put so much thought into the simplest things such as weddings. It was also mentioned how the children who grow up to be apart of the elite, have spent their childhood trying to impress adults in their lives rather than trying to rebel. Children around me seem to be incapable of turning a negative into a positive. The behaviors deplayed in The Outsiders comfirm my theories because the greasers had bad living conditions but they let it affect their entire life. Their situations made it extremely difficult for any of them to remain“golden.”
 Reply 
 
 Laura Augustave // Jan 3, 2012 at 10:37 pm 
 
@Vicorie, you really got me on the middle school“tart”! I can really feel your emotions about that middle school student. There’s kids that are smart as they days are long, but end up into a position where it doesn’t come out right, and feel like they can’t get out of it, but if they were really smart, they should use their brains and intelligence to get out of thise types of“tarts”situations.
 Reply 
 
 Jenni Meshele // Nov 25, 2011 at 4:40 pm 
 
1)My interpretation of Robert Frost’s poem is things have to change. We all know change is a part of life and I just feel as if his poem is a rebuttal to the saying “stay golden”. I think he uses nature to support his theory. I feel that he’s saying when something is new it’s golden. It’ll be hard to hold on to because it won’t last that long. Eventually it will change. Another way this comes off is as “good things don’t last forever”.
2)I don’t think it’s sad or meant to be sad. It’s the truth, most of the time the truth hurts; in turn it sets you free. This poem should be joyous because it shows u things must move forward.
3)I think compared to the poem the gold is the friendship between pony boy, Johnny, and Dally. All the stuff that goes on around them makes it harder for them. The poem isn’t sad but the movie ending is, they both express that nothing gold can stay. In the end of the movie the golden thing, this was their friendship, had to come to an end due to the death of Johnny and Dally.
•It seems as if most people don’t like talking about social class unless there in the wealthy class. This essay is like the chart Mrs. Silveri showed us about how you can which social class a person fits in by the way they act as well as their actions. It also states that if you feel no need to explain your actions or alter the way you act then you are dealing with someone in your social class. http://www.pbs.org/peoplelikeus/resources/essays6.html 
•Again that chart is the perfect source to see figure out why people act the way they do. The outsiders show a great example of how general poverty affects different races as well. Most people feel like African Americans are mainly the ones who act that way. In all actuality its where you come from.
 Reply 
 Kendralyn :p // Nov 26, 2011 at 7:30 pm 
 
1) When I read this poem I instantly thought about fall. I think Frost is trying to say is that everything about fall is beautiful. Other seasons are nice too but fall makes everything colorful and other seasons can’t do that.

2) No I don’t think this poem is sad. Life shouldn’t sad.The seasons shouldn’t change anyones moods.

3) This poem is saying that good things don’t last forever. For example johnny was the character that told a story. He taught all the greasers lesson. And after he died they all changed their lives around.
 Reply 
 LaDarius Fletcher // Dec 15, 2011 at 10:13 pm 
 
1. I think that Frost is trying to say everything that’s good must end. He means you have to go through the good times and bad times so you can fully experienced both side of it. It’s simlar to the circle of life.
2. I don’t think its supposed to be a sad poem. Some people probably havent accepted death yet, and the fact that everything dies.
3. Well in the movie it seems like everything the characters recieve that is good comes to a quick end. Lately in my life I’ve witnessed alot of good things happen to me or someone around and its gone before you know it. I learned you have to enjoy the good things while you can.

I chose to read the essay “http://www.pbs.org/peoplelikeus/resources/essays1.html ” I have this discussion topic with so many people from my school it’s crazy. It is so true that people assume things about you by how you dress. When you see someone with a mechanics outfit on, you automatically assume he’s nto making $$$ . Boys try to argue with me that rich people sag to, but I just argue back that they already have money. Get your money first before you try to copy what they do.

The essays and the movie The Outsiders completely accept my theories about poverty and social classes, etc. My theory was that even people with money in a higher social class can stilla ct as if they are living in poverty. An example would be the Socs. They had moneym yet they still fought the Greasers as if they lived in the same community. I also had a theory that child abuse happens more in poverty, which turned out to be true.

 http://www.pbs.org/peoplelikeus/resources/essays2.html 
 Reply 
 Sydney Beatty- Schofield // Dec 15, 2011 at 11:59 pm 
 
1. In my opinion I think Frost is trying to say nothing good last forever. All good things must come to a end. Everything loses the golden look sonner and later.

2. This was not meant to be a sad poem. It just shows how life is. I believe it shows you how things and/or people stay in your life for just a season.

Title: “Pride, prejudice and the not-so-subtle politics of the working class” Author: Katherine Boo
 http://www.pbs.org/peoplelikeus/resources/essays1.html 
I totally agree with this essay! In the essay, Katherine explains how people are judged based on the uniform they wear. A person who works as a janitor or a cashier at a fast food restaurant recieve less respect than a person who has a blue-collar job. In this essay I learned that the low status workers don’t get to choose how they look. In fact, they have to dress down in order to move up.

What I have found in The Outsiders and the essay help me come to the conclusion that my theories about class differences are very much true. What you are classified as by the world really impacts you your behavior. Most of the people who are classified as being in the lower class are more likely to behave in bad way and do things that aren’t so good. There actions show and reflect there poverty level
 Reply 
 Sydney Beatty- Schofield // Dec 16, 2011 at 12:02 am 
 
I apologize I forgot to type 3

3. This poem relates to Ponyboy, Johnny and Dally because there friendship is unbreakable, nothing can tear them apart. This relates to me because everything that has gone on and that will go on i have realized that at the end of the day it will make me a stronger person
 Reply 
 
 Laura Augustave // Jan 3, 2012 at 10:33 pm 
 
@Sydney, I totally agree with you on that. Katherine outlined the facts about others judging others, but didnt think one second to actually judge a book by its cover. There’s many out there that are very stuck up and feel as if they are more eager than others. I believe that they are truly blessed and well favored, but many are not lucky like they are. Instead of judging and pointing fingers, they should have the heart to help to become better instead of leaving them under.
 Reply 
 
 Stratiesha Mahone // Dec 18, 2011 at 11:07 pm 
 
1) What Robert Frost is saying is that as a child everything is “gold”; perfect, but its hard to maintain that perfection. Also that you never know how its going to turn out or the obstacles that you may have along the way.

2) This poem is graceful, sad, but also uplifting. It’s sad, because of the way things play out, but then again no one said that it was going to be easy or good or bad.

3) This poem and the movie have told me that sometimes in life you’ll literally kill for the ones you love. Also that sometimes you will make mistakes but able to overcome them, is what really matters in the end. In this novel a lot of sacrifices were made and I can apply that to the sacrifices that we make everyday. If we don’t make them, then I’m sure our parents have made lots of them for us and their kids.

Why doesn’t this world respect all llegal professions. Just because they are made a certain way doesn’t mean they are any less then you. They just have a different occupation, they have to make a living too right. That doesn’t mean that they are any less of person. Wouldn’t you rather them working them living off of your taxes?
“Working Poor” Barbara Ehrenreich

 http://www.pbs.org/peoplelikeus/resources/essays7.html 

My theory is that people judge everyone. But of course I follow the moto, never judge a books by its cover. That same person that you think is poor or not doing anything with their life, may be that same person that will become the next top inventor. Or could even be the reason why you receive food stamps,if you do. people never sometimes really take the initiative to get to know a person that isn’t like them or don’t fall into the same category as them. In the article I read it was comparing two boys, both had the same education and the same IQ’s but being that one boys parent was a lawyer and the other boys parent was a custodial assistant that their parents jobs would determine theirs. Despite their similarities, the difference in the circumstances to which they were born makes it 27 times more likely that the boy with the lawyer parent will get a job that by time he is in late 40s will pay him an income in the top tenth of all incomes in this country. The boy with the parent that is a custodial assistant had about one chance in eight of earning even a median income. Which means your social class could be determined and affected by many people and many things. People just have to make the right choices and choose whats best for them. Because just because my mother may be a manager at Mcdonalds, Doesn’t mean that I cant become a lawyer.
 Reply 
 Amanda Johnson (mandi) // Jan 3, 2012 at 8:01 pm 
 
1. That in the beginning all things new have the potential to be great things and the hope that they bring is what makes them precious and valued. However as time passes some of these things go through the trials of their own personal lives. Some are lost, some give up, some make it and some just don’t. Basically, what I think he means is nothing, including the good things last forever.

2. Not so much as a sad poem, but as a revelation poem. Its purpose is to reveal a deep truth that many people don’t learn until tragedy strikes or a disaster occurs.

3. That even though the common misconception in the movie was that all “Greasers” were just white trash, bums, thugs, jerks, uneducated, and worthless, but in actuality Johnny and Ponyboy were good kids in bad situations pushed to behave and act a certain way. I feel that the poem relates to me because I’m sure that when I was younger the people who cared about me had big dreams and great expectations for who I would one day become and I’m sure they still have great expectations for me but they more than likely morphed to accommodate my goals and personality.

4. In the essay I read my head was spinning the whole time I was reading it. I understood what the author meant in his essay, but I don’t what it had to do with the title: The Rise of the Educated Class. ( http://www.pbs.org/peoplelikeus/resources/essays3.html ) What I got from the essay was the status quo of people who have higher and then marry within their class. Just comparisons and stories of people whose marriages were significant enough to make it into the New York Times. What I think would have made the essay relate more to the title would be highlighting how these certain individuals beat the statistic and earned degrees that most poverty ridden individuals don’t even think about obtaining.

5.What I have learned from the film, “The Outsiders” and the essay is that people are a lot like animals in the way that we caste off into different groups. Only our system depends on looks or socioeconomic status. “The greasers” were identified as having grease in their hair and they wore jeans, t-shirts, and leather jackets. The preppy boys wore sweaters, slacks and dress shoes. Also a peaceful relationship between a prep girl and a greaser was thought then to be unacceptable. In the essay, The Rise of the Educated Class, most of the couples went to the same school or Ivy League schools. And their parents were of the same class of jobs; after their children were married they grew up to follow in their parents footsteps. It seems to me that until people can learn to live with each other’s differences, we will forever be classed off and isolated.
 Reply 
 Jeffrey Wallace(THE Rhetorician) // Jan 3, 2012 at 8:20 pm 
 
1) I believe Frost is actually saying live your life like its golden because you never know whats going to happen. When you’re born you’re born pure and innocent, but as you get older you become sinful, and tainted by the world but you musnt let that stop you from enjoying your life because everything must at one point must grow old and die.
2) I dont think it was intended to be a sad poem. The author Robert Frost was writing about how we humans taint things, just can not ever leave things alone. I think if we lived in an utopian societ, Mr. Frost poem would be titled Everything stays Gold ecause, in Utopia there are no problems, but out here in the real world there are so therefore, Nothing stays gold.
3)i think it relates not only to dally, Johnny, and Pony boy, but it also includes the (what i like to call the preps), It relates to both of the groups because it shows how on either side of the social ladder we all can still have our flaws, and strengths. And the type of envioroment that we live in depicts wether we going to do something with our strengths. With the Greasers, they had a typical bad boy persona because they really didnt have a male father figure to show them how to be a real man so they potrayed, what they thought a man was. As far as the“preps”it relates to them be cause they are the“golden’members but they are very tainted”i mean they are capable of murder.
4) I agree with this article, if a janitor walks into a 5 star restaurant with his work clothes on he will indeed be looked down upon and probably not even seated. Where as a fortunae 500 man walk into that same restaurant with his“uniform”and he will be respected very well. One thing that the author failed to mention that even in the blue collar jobs (or jobs of the lower class) there still seems to be competetition for the TYPE of uniform worn.
 Reply 
 Jeffrey Wallace(THE Rhetorician) // Jan 3, 2012 at 8:24 pm 
 
this definitely confirms my views on class diferences, or lack there of. To me there are really no difference to from the wealthy to the poor other than the amount of money that each has. if you grow up in a loving enviroment, sorrounding by positivity and tranquility, youll be a person of peace, or if you are constantly surrounded by things like war, hate, and unrest well, that will become you (unless you change it). and i think this goes for both the wealthy class and the poor class.
 Reply 
 Laura Augustave // Jan 3, 2012 at 10:27 pm 
 
1.) What Frost was saying that it’s the circle of life, make sure you live to the fullest before it all comes to the end of your life’s journey.

2.) I really don’t think that it’s a sad poem, it might be sad to others, but its basically telling the truth about life and the way it is. Those people probably haven’t accepted death yet, and the fact that everything dies for its own being.

3.) It shows how life can make you become a different person. You can either become a good person for the best, or a bad person for the worst. When Johnny talks about staying “Gold” I feel like the meaning pertains that sometimes you will make mistakes but you are willing to be able to overcome them, that what really matters before the end.

 http://www.pbs.org/peoplelikeus/resources/essays7.html 

In the essay, Katherine explains how people are judged based on the uniform that employees wear. In this essay I learned that the low status workers don’t get to choose how they look. But I believe that those people that you think is poor or not doing anything with their life, may be that same person that will become the next top inventor for the new generation.

The Outsiders and the essay help me come to the conclusion that my theories about class differences are very much true. There are actions that show and reflect their poverty level. I believe a person’s surroundings has a greater influence than we give credit to. I’ve always believed people of low class would be looked upon differently than someone working in a high paying job. They were looked down upon. They weren’t working in blue-collar jobs, they struggled to take care of the family. The mentality of your class is still apparent.
 Reply 
 Ladii Tink // Jan 5, 2012 at 12:54 pm 
 
I feel that Frost is trying to say that how precious life is, how brief it remains before it fades. Everything worthwhile, is gold for a moment, until its time is over
No, I don’t think this poem is supposed to be sad but t to teach us about life and how thing or people are in your life for a season.
The poem relates to the characters Ponyboy, Johnny and Dally because they have a unbreakable friendship. The poem relates to me because I have experienced many tribulations in my life, but instead being miserable and depressed. I took the time to learn from those incidences a. They have made me become a better person.
“Pride, prejudice and the not-so-subtle politics of the working class”
 http://www.pbs.org/peoplelikeus/resources/essays2.html 
• The essays and the movie are a direct correlation. The essay is saying that somebody is always going to criticize you. The Soc’s didn’t like the Greasers. They believed they were disgusting and ill mannered. The greasers thought they were fine people but the Soc’s didn’t. They grew up on to totally different sides of the tracks. I feel that the essays confirm what I feel about class rooms in America. We all learn differently but it seems the more white people there are in a certain environment they somewhat get special treatment. Opposed to the kids in Africa who get whatever they can get because of the economy or situations they are in. America is in a a place where no matter what you have to have money to get what’s best but you can also get what’s best by the teachers you have. The outsiders seem to have their own way of coping with what was going on in the world them because no one challenged them or marked them as a brand of people. Who wouldn’t be as good as the next because they didn’t work as hard as they do. ” Poor Whites are the one group that even the most touchy-feeling liberals seem to feel fully licensed to mock without remorse” To me this says if it were blacks wed be in the same boat as them except their poor and some blacks were not. Its just a high crazy that we all have to fix or live with. They couldn’t even respect one another as people because of their social class. Like Henry Fielding said,’’ Neither great poverty nor great riches will hear reason.”
My theory is that people judge everyone. But of course I follow the motto, never judge a books by its cover. That same person that you think is poor or not doing anything with their life, may be that same person that will become the next President. Or could even be the reason why you have a roof over your head. People sometimes really take the initiative to get to know a person that isn’t like them or don’t fall into the same category as them. In the article I read it was comparing two boys, both had the same education and the same IQ’s but being that one boys parent was a lawyer and the other boys parent was a custodial assistant that their parents jobs would determine theirs. Despite their similarities, the difference in the circumstances to which they were born makes it 30times more likely that the boy with the lawyer parent will get a job that by time he is in late 40s will pay him an income in the top tenth of all incomes in this country. The boy with the parent that is a custodial assistant had about one chance in eight of earning even a median income. Which means your social class could be determined and affected by many people and many things. People just have to make the right choices and choose whats best for them. Just because my mother works at the airport doesn’t mean I can’t become a doctor. I believe that it all depends on the effort you put into yourself. You have to believe in yourself even if no one else does.
 Reply 
 Keya Denson // Jan 18, 2012 at 6:56 pm 
 
I belive Robert Frost was trying to say that every good thing has to come to an end. I don’t believe this poem was meant to be sad. I think it was for a life lesson,to teach us everything not going to always be here or be the same. The poem can relate to “The Outsiders” because Johnny and Ponyboy were bestfreiends. Johnny, Ponyboy’s gold, dies. I can relate to the poem because I have lost people in mhy life who I was very close with. I’ve been in various of situations were I’ve lost the things that were very special to me.

The “Pride,prejudice and the not-so-subtle politics of the working class” Katherine Boo
In the essay, Katherine explains how people are judged based apon the uniform they were. People who work for a blue-collar job gets more respect than someone who works as a janitor or a cashier at Burger King. The low status workers don’t get to choose how they look. In fact, they have to dress down inorder to move up. I agree with this essay.
 http://www.pbs.org/peoplelikeus/resources/essays1.html 
The essay and The Outsiders confirms my theory. I’ve always believed people of low class would be looked upon differntly than someone working in a high paying job. This causing them to behave violently.The outsiders were lower class people. They were looked down upon. They weren’t working in blue-collar jobs, they struggled to take care of the family. In “The Outsiders” they were killing and fighting because they were being mistreated and picked on.
 http://www.alternativeright.com/main/blogs/zeitgeist/social-classes-the-upper-class-in-america/ 

 http://www.alternativeright.com/main/blogs/zeitgeist/social-classes-the-lower-class/ 

 http://www.alternativeright.com/main/blogs/zeitgeist/social-classes-the-working-class/ 

 http://www.alternativeright.com/main/blogs/untimely-observations/social-classes-the-american-middle-class/ 
 Reply 
 ←Older Comments 
Leave a Comment (Cancel) 
 
 Name 

 Mail 

 Website 

 

 
 
 Anti-spam word: (Required) * 
 To prove you&apos;re a person (not a spam script), type the security word shown in the picture. 
 
 
 
 
 “We learn more by looking for the answer to a question and not finding it than we do from learning the answer itself.” ~Lloyd Alexander 
From the Peanut Gallery…

 The Power of Vulnerability The New Negro Rise of the Planet of the Apes The Makings of a Manifesto Traces of Slavery by Another Name… 
 
Wiki

 National History Day 2012: Georgia Unsung Project 

 
 
©2012 In Session: Sentiments from Silveri&apos;s Class— Sitemap — Cutline by Chris Pearson 
Hosted by Edublogs.org 

 
 
 
 
 Edublogs Home Help and Support The Edublogger Community Get A Blog! 
 Log in
	</body>
</document>
