<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002477" url="http://www.squidoo.com/JelloShots" time="2012-07-12-18:32" support="3" score="0.0030999477892402543" bingtitle="How to Make Great Jello Shots - Squidoo : Welcome to Squidoo" webtitle="How to Make Great Jello Shots">
			<query id="000774" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000523" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="001138" bing-rank="185"/>
	<description>A fun alternative to the traditional shot cups is ... -You can easily pick up at a fast food restaurant if you&apos;re in a ... jello shot - or vodka jelly as us bloody brits put ...</description>
	<body>
		Log In Explore Topics Join Us 
 Go 
 Squidoo 
 Close Home » Food&amp;Cooking » Recipes » Other Recipes 
How to Make Great Jello Shots
 
 20 Comments 
 How do you like it? Which do you prefer? Jello Shot Recipes Guestbook 
 
 
 76 Like 

 Like 76 Pin It 
 
 Ranked #196 in Food&amp;Cooking ,
 #4,329 overall
 
Squishy, Colorful, and Yummy Jello Shots
 Jello shots, jello shooters, or Vodka Jelly (to the Brits) are the most fun shots invented yet to date. Jello shots are a summer party necessity, but there is no season and no party that wouldn&apos;t be improved by adding them.

Jello shots immediately bring a little life to the party. You cannot have a boring party with jello shots. It is not possible.

So, go ahead people...slurp your jello shot, suck it out with your tongue. Have a good time. Life&apos;s short.
Photo by TMAB2003 used under CC 2.0
 
Jiggelo: Inventive Gelatin Shots for Creative Imbibers
 
 Jelly Shot Test Kitchen: Jell-ing Classic Cocktails-One Drink at a Time 

 by: Michelle Palm

 Amazon Price: $9.65 (as of 07/12/2012) 


Remember your first Jell-O shot-and how naughty it felt to add booze to Bill Cosby&apos;s favorite food group? Well times have changed, and so have those wiggly, jiggly shots you used to slam back with glee. All the rage with the postcollege party set, today&apos;s gelatin shots are still cool and fruity, but with a hip and sophisticated edge that sets them miles apart from those plain old liquid drinks.
 
How&apos;s it done?
 Basically what you want to do is prepare jello as usual...boil water (the amount listed on your box) and stir in your powder until fully dissolved. Then add your cold water/liquor, and refrigerate.

The key to making great jello shots is how much liquor and how much cold water. If you use no cold water, then the shot will likely be too strong, so you&apos;ll want to use some cold water with the liquor.

The recipe must be done correctly for the gelatin to set. If too much liquid is added, you&apos;ll just be left with colored liquid. You must decifer how much alcohol to add, and then leave that much water out. Perhaps you want to combine the liquor and cold water in a measuring cup first and make sure the total amount combined is what the box asks for for the cold water portion.

I would suggest:
30 Proof - 15% Alcohol - 1 Part Liq. 3 Parts Water
40 Proof - 20% Alcohol - 1 Part Liq. 4 Parts Water
50 Proof - 25% Alcohol - 1 Part Liq. 5 Parts Water
80 Proof - 40% Alcohol - 1 Part Liq. 8 Parts Water
90 Proof - 45% Alcohol - 1 Part Liq. 9 Parts Water
100 Proof - 50% Alcohol - 1 Part Liq. 10 Parts Water
150 Proof - 75% Alcohol - 1 Part Liq. 15 Parts Water
190 Proof - 95% Alcohol - 1 Part Liq. 20 Parts Water
 
Lime Jello
 How can you not have fun when green jello is involved? Try one of these in your next batch of lime jello shots. 
 Bacardi Vanilla Coconut Rum Tequila Apple Puckers Rootbeer Schnaps and raspberry Vodka
(supposedly tastes like bottle-cap candies) Tequila and Triple Sec Vodka 
 
Gelatin Shot Books
 Have a handy guide nearby... 
Tips for Great Jello Shots

Ah, the magic of gelatin !

 Let the jello cool before adding the alcohol. At high temperatures, the alcohol is evaporated out leaving you with non-alcoholic jello shots...which probably won&apos;t go over well. Alcohol boils at 173º F. Use a turkey baster to fill the cups. It is quick, clean&amp;easy. According to Jellophile , fresh or frozen pineapple, kiwi fruit, figs, mangoes, guava or papaya, or fresh ginger will prevent gelatin from setting. All contain an enzyme that keeps gelatin from setting. All are fine, however, if cooked or canned. 
 
Jello Shot Auctions
 
How do you like it?
 a%3A5%3A%7Bs%3A7%3A%22options%22%3Bs%3A373%3A%2214b3f382e5bacc06f6c2926912374dd9%2CI+use+a+toothpick%2C9f1c2974d187cae161a98de807d35d78%2CI+use+my+finger%2C9f7fb9140c7df1fb76b09fd5f221921a%2CAll+tongue+%21%2C79428f7118b57d346883a978d44a855c%2CIn+paper+cups+-+use+tongue+then+pop+it+inside+out+to+finish+it+off%2C3b4466d60fe3959b822dfc3728f44774%2COther+%28which+I+will+describe+in+the+comments+section%29%2C749019770edcc05e4b50348d3a7105e4%2CSyringe%22%3Bs%3A6%3A%22period%22%3Bs%3A2%3A%2260%22%3Bs%3A8%3A%22question%22%3Bs%3A27%3A%22How+do+you+take+your+jello%3F%22%3Bs%3A9%3A%22stripHTML%22%3Bs%3A2%3A%22no%22%3Bs%3A10%3A%22showPhotos%22%3Bs%3A3%3A%22yes%22%3B%7D Loading poll. Please Wait... 
Thanks for voting! Now invite your friends to vote.

 Tweet it | Share on Facebook 
 
 Share this poll 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious Email 
 
 
Pineapple Jello
 Try these with pineapple jello: 
 Malibu Coconut Rum - Pina Colada! Pineapple Malibu Coco Lopez Parrot Bay Rum Blue hawaiian maui and vodka Tropical Maui 
 
Jello Shot Cups

Paper or plastic?
 The question of paper or plastic is one of personal preference. You can also get syringe to fill with the jello shot mix.

 Paper
PROS: 
-You can easily unfold it, crumple it, whatever you need to get out every last bit of jello.
-You can easily pick up at a fast food restaurant if you&apos;re in a pinch.
 CONS: 
-You can&apos;t get lids which enable you to stack them,
-They may be difficult to work with when filled with liquid.
-You have the potential of the liquid seeping through folds before setting (though this rarely happens).

 Plastic:
PROS: 
-You can get lids enabling you to stack them in the fridge to take less room.
-They are smooth on the inside, so often you can use your tongue around the sides to get jello to slide out easily.
 CONS: 
-If jello doesn&apos;t pop out, it is harder to get your tongue to the bottom. 
Orange Jello
 Try these with orange jello (also try making the jello in an orange peel): 
 Vanilla Vodka - orange creamsicle ! Peach Schnapps Grand Marnier Brandy Amaretto Irish Whiskey Midori and Vodka Orange Vodka 
 
Jello Shot Cake

Yummy!
 Make your own Jello Shot Cake to top off the evening (or picnic!). Jello Shot Cake Recipe | Recipezaar Jello Shot Cake Recipe | Recipezaar - Strawberry Jell-O gelatin dessert cake. This cake is made with a cake mix, jello and your favorite liquors... 
How to Make Jello Shots

Video Clips
 So you&apos;re more audio-visual and can&apos;t bear to read these instructions on how to make jello shots? Watch an instructional video clip by self-proclaimed jello shot masters - keep in mind that they all have their own style and methods. Go with your gut. 
Which do you prefer?
 a%3A5%3A%7Bs%3A7%3A%22options%22%3Bs%3A228%3A%22c2df49db819e2a3b6650c0d21086407e%2CIn+a+paper+cup%2C18477d5493e02e2afb3f9c1f334b166a%2CIn+a+plastic+cup%2Ca6a97bdf736555f9219e089d951720da%2CIn+a+citrus+peel+%2C95a3c6108389ac2955ab02ec8d76dc1b%2CIn+syringes+%2C8641660db7dc517a2948cf1fcc325d77%2C%22%3Bs%3A6%3A%22period%22%3Bs%3A2%3A%2260%22%3Bs%3A8%3A%22question%22%3Bs%3A52%3A%22How+do+you+prefer+to+serve+%28or+receive%29+jello+shots%3F%22%3Bs%3A9%3A%22stripHTML%22%3Bs%3A2%3A%22no%22%3Bs%3A10%3A%22showPhotos%22%3Bs%3A3%3A%22yes%22%3B%7D Loading poll. Please Wait... 
Thanks for voting! Now invite your friends to vote.

 Tweet it | Share on Facebook 
 
 Share this poll 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious Email 
 
 
Strawberry Jello

 Bacardi Grand Melon Jagermeister Banana Rum Light Rum 
 
Watermelon Jello
 And with your Watermelon flavored jello: 
 Watermelon Bacardi Midori melon liqueur Malibu coconut rum Watermelon pucker Watermelon vodka 
 
Other Combinations

 Cranberry Jello and Vodka with a slice of lime stuffed in Peach Jello and Peach Schnapps
Peach Jello and bourbon Mixed Fruit jello and dark rum
Mixed Fruit jello and wilderberry schnapps Green apple jello and sour apple pucker Strawberry banana jello and Blue Hawaiian maui Pineapple jello and cranberry jello with Malibu Rum Cherry jello and orange jello with Captain Morgan Lemon jello and lime jello with Irish Whiskey 
 
Jello T-Shirts for Guys
 
Cherry Jello or Black Cherry Jello

 Cherry Jello and Fire Ball Cherry Jello and Cherry Brandy Black Cherry Jello and Amaretto Black Cherry Jello and Southern Comfort and drop a cherry into the cup Cherry Jello and Smirnoff watermelon vodka 
 
Grape Jello
 Try these with grape jello: 
 Blackberry brandy Vodka 
 
Jello Shot Recipes

Vote for Your Favorite Jello Shot

Looking for a Jello Shot to mimic another drink you love? Check out these recipes and vote for your favorites:
 
1
 Vote Up Vote Down 
 Drink Recipe: Daiquiri Jello Shots 

Drink recipe for mixing &apos;Daiquiri Jello Shots&apos; 1 point 
 
2
 Vote Up Vote Down 
 Drink Recipe: Rum and Coke Jello Shots 

Drink recipe for &apos;Rum and Coke Jello Shots&apos; 1 point 
 
3
 Vote Up Vote Down 
 Drink Recipe: Creamsicle Jello Shots 

Drink recipe for &apos;Creamsicle Jello Shots&apos; 1 point 
 
4
 Vote Up Vote Down 
 Drink Recipe: Mai-Tai Jello Shots 

Drink recipe for &apos;Mai-Tai Jello Shots&apos; 0 points 
 
5
 Vote Up Vote Down 
 Drink Recipe: Margarita Jello Shots 

Drink recipe for &apos;Margarita Jello Shots&apos; 0 points 
 
6
 Vote Up Vote Down 
 Drink Recipe: Beer Jello Shots 

Drink recipe for &apos;Beer Jello Shots&apos; 0 points 
 
7
 Vote Up Vote Down 
 Drink Recipe: Fuzzy Navel Jello Shots 

Drink recipe for mixing &apos;Fuzzy Navel Jello Shots&apos; 0 points 
 
8
 Vote Up Vote Down 
 Drink Recipe: Green Margarita Jello Shots 

Drink recipe for &apos;Green Margarita Jello Shots&apos; 0 points 
 
9
 Vote Up Vote Down 
 Drink Recipe: Caribbean Blue Jello Shots 

Drink recipe for &apos;Caribbean Blue Jello Shots&apos; 0 points 
 
10
 Vote Up Vote Down 
 Drink Recipe: Red Wine Jello shots 

Drink recipe for &apos;Red Wine Jello shots&apos; 0 points 
 
11
 Vote Up Vote Down 
 Drink Recipe: Purple Passion Jello Shots 

Drink recipe for &apos;Purple Passion Jello Shots&apos; 0 points 
 
12
 Vote Up Vote Down 
 Drink Recipe: Red Hot Cinnamon Jello Shots 

Drink recipe for &apos;Red Hot Cinnamon Jello Shots&apos; 0 points 
 
13
 Vote Up Vote Down 
 Drink Recipe: Irish Whiskey Sour Jello Shots 

Drink recipe for &apos;Irish Whiskey Sour Jello Shots&apos; 0 points 
 
14
 Vote Up Vote Down 
 Drink Recipe: Dragon&apos;s Fire Jello Shots 

Drink recipe for &apos;Dragon&apos;s Fire Jello Shots&apos; 0 points 
 
15
 Vote Up Vote Down 
 Drink Recipe: Jolly Rancher Jello Shots 

Drink recipe for &apos;Jolly Rancher Jello Shots&apos; 0 points 
 
16
 Vote Up Vote Down 
 Drink Recipe: Chocolate Covered Cherry Jello Shots 

Drink recipe for &apos;Chocolate Covered Cherry&apos; 0 points 
 
17
 Vote Up Vote Down 
 Drink Recipe: Green Apple and Butter Jello Shots 

Drink recipe for &apos;Green Apple and Butter&apos; 0 points 
 
 Share this list 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious Email 
 
 
Raspberry Jello
 Try these with raspberry jello: 
 Banana Rum Raspberry Schnapps 
 
Jello Shot Accessories

on eBay
 
Guestbook

(you don&apos;t have to be a member to leave a message)

Any tips for us? comments? questions?
 submit 
 Reply enjoyecigs Apr 28, 2012 @ 2:42 pm | delete awesome idea! thaks for this lens.....def doing some for our next get together! Reply WorldWide101 Mar 23, 2012 @ 7:19 pm | delete Looking cool!
Thnx for share the recipes Reply DANCINGCOWGIRLDESIGN Dec 1, 2011 @ 4:19 am | delete Yummy Yummy! Send samples. Reply cocktailsexaminer Jul 12, 2011 @ 1:45 pm | delete Very informative! Great information - I love Jello shots! Reply HelanaRirosknee May 1, 2011 @ 9:43 pm | delete one could get in a lot of trouble trying all of these shots, good job ! Reply Apr 1, 2011 @ 6:30 am | delete Nice Squidoo. Very enjoyable to read. Chris Reply Deadlego Mar 29, 2011 @ 11:18 am | delete I have just lensrolled from your lens to my finest.vodka.ever.com lens about zubrowka. i&apos;ve never had a jello shot - or vodka jelly as us bloody brits put it apparantly! but love the lens and am definately going to try some now. Reply RobGrawberger Jan 2, 2011 @ 10:40 pm | delete These are always a blast at any of our functions..... nice to have some new recipe ideas Great Lens!!! Reply howdoyouspellstupid Oct 23, 2010 @ 2:20 am | delete Good to know! I&apos;m turning 21 soon, so maybe I&apos;ll try one! (Don&apos;t worry, I won&apos;t abuse my jell-o-shots-making powers!) Thanks! Nice lens. Reply Sep 30, 2010 @ 4:54 am | delete I&apos;m going to pass your lens address onto my young co-worker. Saturday night and jello shots dominate her vocabulary every monday morning :) Reply Pastiche Aug 23, 2010 @ 9:01 am | delete I have never enjoyed a jello shot - I think I&apos;ll make these for the holidays this year, along with a batch of Boilo, the champagne of coal cracker country. Reply Mythological Apr 11, 2010 @ 3:39 pm | delete Jello shot syringes look a little gross. Good recipes and good lens! Reply Information-Guru Apr 13, 2009 @ 4:28 am | delete Well laid out squidoo, I like it!

Have a look at mine http://www.marios-bar.com/jello.html Reply Jello Shot Freak Dec 8, 2008 @ 1:21 am | in reply to Jello Shot Freak | delete Links are here, by the way:

Jello Shot Recipe - http://jelloshotrecipe.blogspot.com/
5 Tips On Taking Jello Shot Out - http://jelloshotrecipe.blogspot.com/2008/11/5-tips-on-jello-shot-recipe-consuming.html
Amaretto Jello - http://jelloshotrecipe.blogspot.com/2008/12/amaretto-jello-shot-recipe.html Reply Jello Shot Freak Dec 5, 2008 @ 8:30 am | delete Great info! This jello shot recipe topic is really interesting and popular, as I see.

I would add couple of articles from Jello Shot Recipe Blog

5 Tips On Taking Jello Shot Out :)))

And also a very special Amaretto shot - Orange Jell-O Amaretto

Enjoy! Reply mosdiva Sep 30, 2008 @ 7:54 pm | delete Great lens! In particular the &quot;How it&apos;s done&quot; Reply WhiteBison Jul 30, 2008 @ 4:09 pm | delete I haven&apos;t had one of these since...well, it&apos;s been a while. Nice work! Reply mulberry May 28, 2008 @ 7:28 pm | delete Jello shots...sounds wonderfully fruity! Reply DAD1104 May 27, 2008 @ 10:34 am | delete But don&apos;t forget the probablity that your friends may have a problem with Gluten (beer etc.)Check my site dad1104 Reply enslavedbyfaeries May 26, 2008 @ 11:50 am | delete Great idea for a lens, love it (and the jell-o shots)! 5*&apos;s for some great recipe combinations and a lot of fun.:) Reply amandaquerque Mar 30, 2008 @ 7:10 pm | delete What a fun lens! Thank you for adding it to the BIG LENSES group! Reply riff999 Mar 16, 2008 @ 3:06 pm | delete What a great idea for a lens. Can&apos;t wait to put together a Cherry Jello with watermelon vodka. Sounds yummy.
~Jane Reply Music-Resource Mar 11, 2008 @ 6:24 pm | delete Hi Kab, Fun Jello Shots lens. Fun and yummy :) ~Music Resource~ Reply thomasz Feb 13, 2008 @ 8:56 pm | delete Interesting lens. Nice info. Reply Donna_Fallon Feb 10, 2008 @ 1:46 pm | delete Hiya
5 stars Lens!,Check out my lens on belly fat.
Post Feedback :)
Donna Reply Skelkeys Jan 13, 2008 @ 2:50 pm | delete How to make a jello shot Has some info on jello shots, and a ton of listing games. Reply Aika Jan 9, 2008 @ 10:14 am | delete perfect for parties! bookmarked! :) Reply Dec 20, 2007 @ 8:24 am | delete There&apos;s always room for jello shots, great lens! Please visit my lens for some great ebooks! Reply minky Oct 9, 2007 @ 3:24 am | delete Great lens and interesting content. Reply tplus Sep 24, 2007 @ 10:49 am | delete Congratulations! You are #8 at Who Has the Most Lenses?! I&apos;ve picked this lens to be featured alongside your name. Come check out your competition! Load More 
 Show All 
 Share this Guestbook 
 Stumbleupon Facebook MySpace Twitter Digg Delicious RSS Email 
 
 
 76 Like 
 
 by kab 
 
 I live; I write; I disregard warning labels. I&apos;m a jack of all trades - ace of only ten or eleven. Kab&apos;s 10 Newest Lenses more » 

 309 featured lenses Winner of 33 trophies ! Top lens» What to Do With Your Old Soda Cans This lens» Won purple star 
 Feeling creative? Create a Lens! 
Explore related pages

 Funny Alcoholic Drinks and Cocktail Recipes Funny Alcoholic Drinks and Cocktail Recipes Easter Cocktails Easter Cocktails Margaritas .....It&apos;s 5 O&apos;clock Somewhere Margaritas .....It&apos;s 5 O&apos;clock Somewhere Classic Cocktails With A Twist Classic Cocktails With A Twist Adult Halloween Punch Recipes Adult Halloween Punch Recipes 10 Great Drink Recipes for St Patrick&apos;s Day 10 Great Drink Recipes for St Patrick&apos;s Day 
Jello Shots Recipe Book 
 Could not locate item B005K8HS4I. Please try again.Sorry, there are no results available from Amazon. 
EZ InjectTM Jello Syringes 
 
 50 Pack EZ-InjectTM Jello Shot Syringes (Medium 1.5oz) 

 Amazon Price: $32.95 (as of 07/12/2012) 

 
Twist Shot Jello Shooter Glasses 
 
 Twist&apos;n Shot Jello Shot Cups 

 Amazon Price: $8.00 (as of 07/12/2012) 

 
Related Tags

 Jello other-recipes alcohol alcoholic drink recipes drinks gelatin how to make jello shots jell-o jell-o shot jell-o shots jello jello shots jelly liquor mixed drinks recipes rum shooter shots kab more... 
 
 TOS Originality Pact About Us SquidooHQ Charity Report Abuse Feedback&amp;Bugs 
 Copyright©2012,
 Squidoo, LLC and respective copyright owners This page and all the pages on Squidoo generate income for lensmasters and charities based on affiliate relationships with our partners, including Amazon, Google, eBay and others. Have fun. 
Want our Newsletter?
 Sign up! Notify me by email when new comments are added. 
 Enter Your Name to post as a vistor
 or Login 
 E-mail Address:   Post Comment Cancel
	</body>
</document>
