<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002426" url="http://vrnewport.com/area-listings.asp" time="2012-07-12-18:21" support="4" score="0.004910400058108322" bingtitle="VR Business Brokers in California | Buy or Sell a Business in ..." webtitle="VR Business Brokers in California | Buy or Sell a Business in Orange 
County">
			<query id="000089" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000081" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000068" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000078" bing-rank="169"/>
	<description>... Wire Closer, 26&quot; UV Coater, Reinforce Tape Dispenser. ... 16 yrs Chinese fast food restaurant; 2 owners operate + 2 full time ... SUPPLIES, PET CARE, FOOD, GREETING CARDS, SODA ...</description>
	<body>
		Home | Contact Us 
 Click on a listing to see details
 Click on a column heading to sort by that column (click again to sort in reverse order) 

 Industry 
       Location Hide Descriptions Listing Price Down Payment Gross Sales Owner Benefit Total Assets 
 
 41480048 - Green Products Manufacturer 
Northern California Undisclosed   5,000 2,000   Manufacturing (Other Manufacturing): This unique buisness opportunity stems from a succesful inventor who developed a patented energy saving product but lacks teh business savvy to take it to the next level. Unlike many products that have yet to be tested in the marketplace, this product has many satisfied customers and targets a sizable niche. There is only one competitive product that is a proprietary design, and costs over three times as much. The ideal buyer is a person that has a broad business experience and knows how to bring a product to market. It could also be a compoany that offers compolementary green products with an established retail distribution system. The bulk of the value is in the patent. 
 2508101913 - Aircraft parts new and aftermarket 
Orange County 4,900,000 4,900,000 4,765,522 2,014,441 12,800,000 Aviation (Aviation): The company is a leader and trusted provider of new and aftermarket parts for commercial, corporate and military aircraft. They have the skill and ability to source parts new and used for most all aircraft and have direct relationships with major OEMS. Over the years the company has acquired a large inventory of parts ($12,800,000) stored in its 7,400 sq ft building, ready for immediate shipment. Has about 33,000-++ part line items listed in their computer system, plus another 30,000 that can be sourced from manufactures, OEMS or others. Their customers are generally global and order the needed items after searching various subscription websites (which this business is a member) or the company’s website. Generally sales are all PART NUMBER driven and most orders are processed from email or directly from the websites. The competitive advantage of this company is their skill and knowledge in the acquisition of inventory. Gross margins can be extremely high when parts are in short supply. Only four employees  (including the owner) generated nearly five million in sales in 2011.Needs buyer industry experience who at a mimimun can understand the current wholesale value of the parts currently owned by the company.  All sales are invoiced and easily verified. Current owner has taken this oportunity as far as he desires. New owners with professional management skills could take this business to a much higher level. 41141017 - Statewide Trucking/Logistics Company 
South San Francisco and Los Angeles 4,800,000 4,800,000 4,500,000 900,000   Transportation Services (Delivery): This is a substantial trucking business with operations in San Francisco and Los Angeles. This company has an outstanding operations platform with significant opportunities to expand the business. 01982204 - LIQUOR,140K SALE WITH PROPERTY, HELP RUN 
HEARTLAND OF LOS ANGELES 2,500,000 2,500,000 1,680,000 420,000   Liquor Stores (Liquor Stores): 

 HIGH VOLUME LIQUOR WITH RENTAL INCOME. 
 MOSTLY HELP RUN 
 STILL HAS ROOM FOR GROWTH IN SALES AND NET 
 VERY STABLE CLIENTELE 
 SELLS MOSTLY LIQUOR AND WINE 
 CURRENTLY RECEIVE 4,500 COMMISSION FROM LOTTERY (MONTHLY) WHICH MEANS HEAVY FOOT TRAFFIC.&quot;LOTS OF CLIENTS&quot; 
 THIS LIQUOR AND PROPERTY IS ABLE TO RECEIVE SBA LOAN FOR A QUALIFIED BUYER. 
 HAS GREAT BOOKS AND RECORDS TO PROVE THE SALES. 


THIS TYPE OF HIGH VOLUME LIQUOR WITH PROPERTY DOESN’T COME OUT ON THE MARKET TO OFTEN. THIS IS A LIFE DREAM TO HAVE A BUSINESS NETS 35K A MONTH AND OWN HIS OWN PROPERTY WITH RENTAL TO HAND DOWN FOR GENERATIONS. DOES NOT HAVE CHECK CASHING OR WESTERN UNION ETC. 41191003 - Sheet Metal Manufacturing 
Anaheim, CAlifornia 2,500,000 2,500,000 3,100,000 888,810 1,900,000 Manufacturing (Fabrication/Welding): The company is a job shop for precision sheet metal and CNC milling/lathe work. They have a diversified customer base and the potential of increasing production. The company has a reputation for high quality workmanship and on-time delivery.The sales have been strong for many years and with the slowing of the economy the sales profit dropped somewhat. However, the company has picked up some new accounts and the existing customer base is increasing their demand for orders.There is a shop manager that wants to continue work in the business He does most of the bidding and knows how to operate and program all machines.The company is in the process of the ISO 9000 certification. If the new owner is an engineer they could pursue the aerospace industry. The owner is expecting to close his year end with strong sales.

 01982032 - MARKET + PROPERTY HAS LIQUOR LICENSE 
CULVER CITY 2,000,000 2,000,000 1,200,000 180,000   Liquor Stores (Package Store w/Grocery): 

 FREE STANDING BUILDING 
 BRAND NEW WALK-IN COOLERS WERE INSTALLED 
 TOP NOTCH CONDITION 
 NO CONDITION ON THE LICENSE FOR THE CURRENT OWNER 
 SBA PRE-APPROVED FOR THE BUSINESS 
 VERY FAMOUS AREA, NEAR BY FOX HILL MALL 
 MIX DEMOGRAPHICS 


HAS ALL BOOKS AND RECORDS TO SUBSTANTIATE THE NUMBERS AND RECEIVE SBA LOAN FOR THE PROPERTY AND BUSINESS, DEPENDING ON THE QUALIFIED BUYER. MUST SEE BUSINESS!!!!! 41191208 - VERY Popular Bar w Live Music, Land, Rental Unit 
Southern California / Inland Empire 1,700,000 1,700,000 763,540 165,700 1,280,000 Cocktail Lounges/Taverns/Bars (Taverns w/Entertainment or Dance): The Business A real roadhouse in southern California!


 Very profitable full bar - 15,000&quot;pours&quot;per month! 
 Complete bar type food menu 
 Type 47 liquor license 
 Approximately 4,000sf - stage for live music, DJ booth, full wood dance floor, pool tables, 14 large screen HDTV’s 


Widely known, popular, very loyal clientele! The Property The price includes the bar/restaurant situated on a 40,128 sf parcel of property


 Easy freeway access 
 Plenty of onsite and free street parking 
 Very large - unused patio space. 


 Rental Property The property includes a 1,200 sf SFR - 3 BR, 2 BA currently rented to an employee for $ 775/mo. Market rent much higher! Very complete and accurate financial and business records.  01982112 - Gas Station + Property, C-store, 3-Bay Garage 
Anaheim 1,700,000 1,700,000 5,400,000 5,400,000   Gas Stations (Gas&amp;Market&amp;Repair): 

 Shell Service Station, Lot size 24,000 Sq. F or 0,55 acres 
 Building size 1,770 Sq. F with three garage bay service station, sublet month to month $4,000 
 Smog check with equipment 
 Convenience store with ATM, Lottery, Propane sales, refrigerators, 2 restrooms. Sales $15,000 
 Fuel volume December 2011: 150,367 Gallons, January 2012: 167,254 Gallons 
 Payroll: $8212; Insurance: $807; Utilities: $1700; Property taxes: $650; Telephone: $108 
 Environmental report 2008. 

 01982158 - Office Buillding Currently Occupied by School 
Cerritos 1,695,000 678,000 Sale of Assets 1,695,000 Land&amp;Commercial Property (Office Building): 

 Cerritos rare free standing school or office building. 
 12,628 sf lot, 4,092 sf building with 17 parking spaces. 
 Currently doing business as a school (K-12th grade licensed), 12 classrooms. 
 Business is available separately $600,000. (I-20 Certified, netting 200k/yr) 

 01982129 - Commercial, Wholesale, Trade Print&amp;Bindery 
Los Angeles&amp;Orange County 1,390,000 1,390,000 2,900,000 560,000   Printing Services (Commercial Printing): 

 Commercial&amp;Wholesale Printer. 
 Centrally located between LA/OC. 
 COG 47% 
 Pre Press Equipment: Pre Press System, Kodak Trend Setter. 
 Printing Equipment: Heidelberg Press 5C 28x40, HP Digital Press 12x18.Vehicles: 2 Folk Lift. 
 Finish/Binder: Polar Cutter 115 45&quot;, Die Cutter, 2 MBO Folder 23&quot;,35&quot;, Duplo Collector, 2 BGC-USP Heavy duty Punch Hole,GBC Coil Inserter, JBI Wire Closer, 26&quot;UV Coater, Reinforce Tape Dispenser. 
 Employees: 12 Full Time, 15 Part Time 
 includes: 3 Heidelberg Press Op., Accounting/Purchaser, Graphic Designer, Sales,Folder, Cutter, Die Cutter and Stitcher Op. 

 41191205 - Manufacturer of patented purification systems 
Inland Empire 1,140,000 1,140,000 1,164,386 285,171 1,001,000 Manufacturing (Proprietary Shop): Business established for 18 years. Seller purchased new building in May 1994 in upscale industrial area. The Seller owns 12,600 square foot building and will write lease for new owner. Company has diverse customer base for commercial, medical and builders They are a manufacturer of patented water and air purification systems.. Company exports approximately 15 percent of business to overseas companies. The 6 patents are included in sales price.Seller will carry a substancial note, if the Buyer has a good credit history. 41141018 - Granite/Marble Fabricator in San Francisco 
San Francisco 1,099,000 1,099,000 2,800,000 700,000   Contractor Services (Construction/installation): earnings exceed $700,000 per year. This granite fabrication business is fully staffed and turnkey. Company has very strong name recognition with a 10+ year successful track record. Owner is motivated and is ready to retire. This business does high quality residential and commercial work. The customer list is comprised of a who’s who of San Francisco. They have more work than they can handle!! 41480051 - Parking Lot Equipment Manufacturer 
Silicon Valley 1,000,000 1,000,000 1,500,000 374,000   Manufacturing (Electronic): This company manufactures and sells Parking Access and Revenue Control Systems (PARCS). They design and build parking equipment to meet any performance specification. All equipment is produced in the USA. The principal founders are involved hands-on with every aspect of manufacturing operation. They oversee and direct all research, design, engineering, cost-analysis, fabrication, assembly, delivery, installation, training and service. They design the software that operates all the equipment including remote troubleshooting and system diagnostics. Sellers are willing to stay on for an extended period for the new owners. The ideal buyer is someone who understands the parking industry with sufficient funds to grow the business. Technology companies related to the parking control industry with general management and business growth abilities is the ideal buyer for this business.

 41191204 - Hydroponic distrib/retailer w/online store 
Los Angeles, CA 1,000,000 1,000,000 1,800,000 300,000 195,000 Distribution/Wholesale (Chemical Product): Rapidly growing Niche Distributor/retailer of hydroponic gardening products and commercial pesticides. Xlnt online store with over 3000 products. Since its inception 3+ years ago the company has shown steady growth in an unlimited market. 2011 gross was over $1.4 million with $243,000 profit. 2012 numbers already have it on pace to do around $1.8 million gross and over $300,000 discretionary earnings. Customer base includes general building contractors, commercial greenhouse growers, qualified pesticide applicators, lumber yards, and hobbiest.  Hydroponics is a method of gardening which does not require soil, either through the use of misters or another substrate such as expanded clay, coco coir, or lava rocks. Living Lettuce, for example, is grown hydroponically in chambers with misters with the nutrient solution applied directly to the root zone, and sold&quot;alive&quot;at farmers markets. 41141032 - Internet Streaming, Broadcast, Video-Audio Studio 
San Francisco North Bay 999,999 999,999 999,999 999,999   Messenger Services (Messenger Service): This is a state-of-the-art video and music and video recording studio located in Southern Marin County. Hundreds of thousands of dollars have been spent on tenant improvements and equipment. The studio offers live internet streaming capabilities. The location is fantastic. The studio has accommodated very well known actors and musicians over the years. ’live internet streaming capabilities.’ 01981943 - TUTTI FRUTTI WITH HUGE VOLUME INSIDE MALL 
Los Angeles County 980,000 980,000 662,000 297,000   Miscellaneous Food Service (Ice Cream/Yogurt): * 100% ABSENTEE OWNER 
 * High Volume 
 * No Royalty 
 * 7 Self Serve Machines 
 * Unique layout - very inviting entrance design 
 * Long lease in a busy mall 
 * No Worries about competition / weather!!! 


 Food Cost: 19%, Utilities: $850/mo. 

 41141000 - Wine, Spirits&amp;Fine Food Retailer 
San Francisco 975,000 975,000 722,771 526,672   Liquor Stores (Liquor Stores): This fine food and liquor store is located in one of San Francisco’s most affluent neighborhoods. This business has been established for over 100 years and has had only 3 owners! The location is absolutely outstanding. The current owner has been running the business since 1971 and works only 12 hours/week. The owner’s earnings consistently exceed $450k/year. There is very little competition in the area with the main competitor scheduled to close its operations within the year as its location will be redeveloped into condominiums. This business has excellent name recognition and a history of substantial and stable profitability. The owner has recently renovated the entire facility. This is a turnkey opportunity 01982149 - LIQUOR STORE HIGH VOLUME EMPLOYEE RUN 
COMPTON 975,000 975,000 1,620,000 240,000   Liquor Stores (Liquor Stores): 

 HIGH VOLUME LIQUOR 
 EMPLOYEE RUN 
 CORNER LOCATION 
 AVERAGE MONTHLY SALES 135,000 / NET PROFIT 20,000 


THIS HIGH VOLUME LIQUOR SELLS MOSTLY LIQUOR AND WINE. NO CHECK CASHING. EASY OPERATION AND ABLE TO RECEIVE SBA LOAN FOR A QUALIFIED BUYER!!!THIS LIQUOR IS A GOLD MINE FOR ANYONE WHO WANTS TO MAKE MONEY. VERY RARE TO COME ON THE MARKET!!! 2508101898 - Offset and Digital Printing 
Santa Ana-- Irvine 950,000 475,000 1,015,174 352,781   Printing Services (Commercial Printing): Offers full color commercial printing and wholesale printing in all Orange County and surronding areas. Cheap color printing with focus on catalog printing, calendar printing. short run or long run color printing. Fast and quick turn around time. This business was established by the current owner in 1984. Open Monday though Friday9-5. Seller owns the building and give new owner a good lease. Excellent equipment including 6 color Komori 28”and 4 color Ryobi 3404 Ditial press. Complete list to follow. Sales peaked prior to Great Ressession at about $1.5 million and are now bouncing back. Most all sales are through brokers and most all come through emails etc. Very little contact with the public saves a great deal of time.  01982191 - Commercial Property with Auto Body&amp;Repair 
Ontario 845,000 845,000 Sale of Assets 845,000 Land&amp;Commercial Property (Industrial Building): Commercial Property on Major Street in Ontario that includes Body Shop &amp;Auto Repair, Both are on Month to Month lease, Price Includes Paint Booth, Frame Machine, 3 Hoists (2 in ground&amp;1 above), 2 Compressors, Needs new motivated owner to promote. Excellent opportunity to make money, Lot size (26,340 SF), Building (5,825) Two Buildings, 5 Bays. 25071755 - Niche Sign Manufacturing 
Riverside County 800,000 800,000 968,007 290,633 210,000 Manufacturing (Signs): This is a not your ordinary sign company .   In an industry crowded with competition, this business is a stand out. Competing with just a few true competitors in its marketplace and utilizing its state-of-the-art in-house manufacturing capabilities in a facility well-suited to its needs, this company focuses on public works projects such as schools, universities, hospitals, government buildings, airports and military installations and uses its manufacturing capabilities to produce ADA compliant Braille signage using photopolymer, acrylic and a sand etched product. The company also produces architectural signage for way-finding, building identification and site signs and has completed numerous private sector projects requiring ADA compliant signage. Producing ADA compliant signage is a niche with some significant barriers to entry.  A significant part of revenues is derived from the installation of the finished signs and requires that the business has a California C61 contractor’s license or a General Contractor’s license. The current owner is willing to continue as the contacting licensee under California’s RME or RMO provisions until an unlicensed new owner obtains a license of his/her own or makes other provisions for licensing. 2508101917 - Market/Deli/Liquor 
Coastal Oange County 799,000 799,000 1,005,976 292,806   Markets (Deli Market): Extremely rare opportunity to acquire a Market/ Liquor/ Deli established over 80 years ago in a small seaside community. Average home price exceed $2MM and this business is the only convenient nearby place to buy food items, liquor, beer, wine and deli items. Purveyor to the boat owners and yachts in the area as well as thousands to tourists walking by everyday. For at least the last seven years, the business has been 100% help run as the owners live out of state and are focused on much larger scale businesses. Still sales have exceeded $1MM a year.  Realistic opportunity for professional hands on operator to double volume. Needs merchandising and the right inventory, such as higher end wines, craft beers and sprits, organic groceries, etc.  Could add wine tasting. Promote the deli with larger varity of salads, sandwiches and hot prepared foods. Huge margins loacation not price sensitive and customers expect to pay more. Ten year lease with options possible for qualified entrepreneur at very favorable rental rate. New state of the POS System 6/12 , new store front doors and glass, currently installing hood and grill for hamburgers, etc. Buyer needs to have mimiunm$500K cash with experience to be considered.  01982174 - Pizza/Sports Bar Hi Volume! 
El Monte 750,000 350,000 1,080,000 275,000   Fast Foods-Primarily Take-Out (Pizza - Beer&amp;Wine): 

 Franchise Pizza/sports bar. Hi volume and net! 
 Same owner 38 years! Generations of families have been coming here for years. 
 Excellent reputation in the area for best tasting pizza. 
 Very busy during football season where many customers come to watch their favorite teams available on several television. 
 Free standing building with its own parking lot. 
 Major Expenses Monthly: food cost (33%)-30,000, labor-17,000, electric-1500, gas-750, water-125, trash-250, ins-300 

 41191210 - XLNT Fitness center for sale, 20,000 sq. ft. 
Low Desert 750,000 750,000 698,391 174,999 755,000 Health, Fitness&amp;Nutrition (Health Clubs): Brand name fitness center. Well established. Owner Operated adjusted earnings $175,000. Excellent staff. Well established classes. First class facility. Great reputation. Over $1,000,000 invested. Top of the line equipment. Solid client base on automatic electronic transfers for monthly fees.  41191212 - XNLT Sign Mfg. $280,000 net 
Greater Los Angeles 725,000 250,000 1,182,357 280,458 7,000 Manufacturing (Signs): Excellent sign franchise with amazing growth. 2011 gross was $1.2 Million with Adjusted earnings of $280,000. On track to exceed that in 2012. Over $300,000 invested. Franchise training as well as seller training available. Fun business with great potential for continued growth. High profit margin. Fully trained staff. Terms based on buyer qualifying for SBA loan. 01982088 - Hispanic Market High Volume Hi Net 
Mission Viejo 700,000 700,000 2,400,000 336,000   Markets (Supermarkets w/Beer or Wine): 

 Hispanic market, hi volume and net. Store sells meat, produce and grocery; and they just recently received their beer and wine license and are now selling beer and wine. This will increase their sales above the current volume. 
 Professionally designed and built by experts in the market industry catering to the Spanish speaking clientele. 
 Has WIC and Food Stamps and a complete kitchen with hood and grill to serve any kind of hot food. 
 Beautiful store set up with only the top of the line equipment. Business shows well. 
 Located in large shopping center with ample parking in a very pleasant and safe area. 
 Major Expenses: Rent- 11.492, labor-20,000, utility-2000, advertsing-3000,supplies-2000, banking fees-800, insurance-500 
 Gross profit 35% overall 

 01982239 - Full Service Car Wash located in Pomona busy area 
Pomona well mixed commercial,business and residential 700,000 700,000 Sale of Assets 700,000 Car Wash (Car Wash): 

 Full Service Car Wash located in a busy industrial,commercial and residential area 
 Purchase price includes property and business 
 Offer will be subject to lender approval 
 Lot size 31,500 sf, building 3,600 sf.   

 01982228 - Jeans Manufacturer for sale LA has brand. 
Los Angeles 690,000 690,000 2,800,000 235,000 500,000 Manufacturing (Clothing): 

 Made in USA, Denim Jeans, Popular Company Brand&amp;Private Labels 
 Large capacity production Highest Quality and Craftsmanship
 
 Current Sales to Many Major Chains and Stores Nationwide 
 Located in LA strong labor pool 
 Established (11 years) 
 Seller to assure smooth transition to new buyer, training&amp;transition period 
 In-House Design, Production, inside sales&amp;sales Reps 
 Company needs Marketing&amp;Sales minded buyer 
 Capital is needed for more marketing and partnership is also available. 

 01981993 - MEDICAL SPA- LASER HAIR REMOVAL 
LOS ANGELES 650,000 650,000 1,028,000 250,000 300,000 Medical/Dental/Optical (Medical/Dental/Optician): 

 Medical Spa, Laser Hair Removal, Botox, Skin Care, Etc. 
 3000 Active Accounts seeing about 50 clients per day. 
 2 New Laser hair removal machines $200,000. 
 Staff: 1 PT MD, 7 PT RN, 3 Employees. 
 Gross Sales Jan - July 2011 $600,000; Net $200,000. 
 $100,000 (Approx) Credit to Buyer for Pre-Paid Packages Sold. 
 4 laser rooms and 4 consultant rooms. 
 Net profit is based on owner / Doctor being there 10 hrs/week 

 41140997 - Established Gourmet Food Manufacturer - $238,000 i 
San Francisco Bay Area 649,000 649,000 1,204,364 226,169 350,000 Manufacturing (Food Products): Price at $649,000 this long established USDA/FDA Approved Food Manufacturer produces a line of gourmet products under their own brand for national distribution to hospitality and healthcare foodservice companies. The company also partners with several upscale, retail clients seeking to please their own discerning Bay Area customers.

Known for its product innovation, the Company will provide new product scale-up services to Fortune 100 food companies in concert with nationally known food product developers and marketers.

Founded in 1985, the company offers a unique depth of food sophistication resulting from a combination of high-end chef skills and experience, plus a deep knowledge of frozen food technology, food safety systems, and quality controls normally found only among much larger manufacturers.

Its state-of-the-art manufacturing plant is located on the San Francisco peninsula. The plant has over 6,000 square feet of manufacturing and warehouse space. A U.S. Department of Agriculture inspection approval has broadened the scope of production to include meat and poultry processing.

It is also FDA-inspected and all production is under a HAACP (Hazard Analysis and Critical Control Point) program.

Management is open to an outright acquisition where it would transition out of the business within an agreed-upon time period. During the transition time, the new owner(s) would be guided through the various aspects of complexity, specifically, U.S. government regulations. 

The company’s greatest asset is its staff; great attention is paid to their training and retention. This combined experience and long term‘group memory’will provide a valued resource of expertise for the new owner’s continuing success. 01982157 - I-20 K-12 School in Cerritos 
Cerritos 600,000 600,000 600,000 200,000   Educational/Schools (Learning&amp;Tutorial): 

 I-20 K-12 Learning center located in Cerritos. 
 2 story free standing school has 12 classrooms, office and 17 parking spaces. 
 Successful academic program for 17 years offer tutoring,college exam prep. 
 Owner will sell the property separately (4,092sf building + 12,628 sf lot) for $1,695,000. 

 01982215 - Thai Restaurant Upscale, Seller Training! 
Tustin 560,000 560,000 1,032,000 240,000   Restaurants (Chinese/Thai Rest. Beer&amp;Wine): 

 100% Absentee Run 
 Gross Sales $1,032,000 /annually, Net Profits $240,000/annually 
 Prim location Classic design in upscale area sounding shops 
 Upscale high volume high profit Thai Restaurant 
 Turn-Key operation and no prior experience is required 
 Anchor stores: AMC Theater, Whole Food Market, TJ Maxx, Michael’s, Costco, Target, Lowes, Best Buy 
 COG 23~26% 







 41141021 - Innovative Green Construction Products Retailer 
Alameda County 549,000 549,000 1,600,000 250,000   Contractor Services (Contractor Service): This business is a leader in the field with an outstanding location. Business is trending up 30% in 2012. The retail showroom is immaculate and well designed. From paint, to counters, cabinets, flooring and tile, this company offers a full line of high quality and well conceived green construction products. The owners have spent a great amount of time and effort in establishing a solid operations platform that can be readily duplicated. While many competitors were washed out when the economy collapsed, this company stayed profitable throughout and is now showing very robust growth. This is a great time to take this business to the next level. 41191207 - Auto Tinting, Audio/Video&amp;Security Installation 
San Gabriel Valley 545,000 545,000 664,021 267,978   Automotive Aftermarket (Automotive Aftermarket): Revenues derived from a combination of both automotive and commercial window tinting, a broad spectrum of 12 volt automotive installations, auto electronics and auto and truck accessories. 01982232 - Beer Bar with Property 
Baldwin Park 520,000 520,000 156,000 36,000 450,000 Cocktail Lounges/Taverns/Bars (Beer Bars or Taverns): 

 Beer bar with property. Same owner 35 years. Free standing building with parking 
 Located in industrial area, many businesses all around. 
 No competition in the area. Possible conversion to 48 cocktail bar after the sale as there are few residential in the area. 
 Major Expenses: pouring cost (30%)-3500, labor-3800, utility-800, ins-250 
 Lot size approximately 8700 sq ft 

 01982092 - Franchise Yogurt Shop in Shopping Center 
Corona 495,000 495,000 500,000 144,000   Fast Foods-Primarily Take-Out (Smoothie/Kiosk): 

 LOCATED IN SHOPPING CENTER WITH 24HR FITNESS CENTER, RESTAURANTS, IT’S A GRIND COFFEE SHOP, ETC. 
 P.O.S. SYSTEM 
 100% HELP RUN 
 ROYALTY FEE 8% 
 FRANCHISE TRANSFER FEE-$10% 
 FOOD COST-31% 
 ELECTRIC-$1000 
 CREDIT CARD FEE-$600 
 LAUNDRY-$100 
 ALARM-$35 
 PAYROLL TAX-$700 
 W.C.-$150 
 PHONE&amp;INTERNET-$130 
 PURITY WATER-$22 
 MUSIC-$52 

 01982096 - BUSY ASIAN FUSION RESTAURANT WITH ENTERTAINMENT 
BRENTWOOD 490,000 490,000 1,875,000 250,000 300,000 Restaurants (Chinese/Thai Rest. Beer&amp;Wine): 

 FRANCHISE CHINESE FOOD, BEER&amp;WINE, 3 PATIOS, LIVE COMEDY! 
 PRIME LOCATION IN THE HEART OF BRENTWOOD WITH UNDERGROUND PARKING. 
 FRANCHISE ROYALTY IS 4% ONLY. NO TRANSFER FEE. SELLER TRAINING. 
 NEW PATIO DESIGNED TO HOST LIVE COMEDY UNDER THE STARS! 
 FULL MANAGEMENT AND STAFF ACCOUNTS FOR HUGE PAYROLL. NET PROFIT IS ESTIMATED WITH OWNER OPERATOR REDUCING MANAGEMENT&amp;PAYROLL. 
 BUSINESS IS CURRENTLY RUN ABSENTEE OWNER. EXPENSES ARE RUNNING HIGH DUE TO ABSENTEE OWNER. 
 DELIVERY ACCOUNTS FOR 25% OF REVENUES. DRIVERS ARE EMPLOYEES. 
 ONGOING FRANCHISE AGREEMENT. NO RENEWAL FEES.
 

 01982103 - DRY CLEANERS, LONG ESTABLISHED, HIGH END! 
Beverly Hills 479,000 160,000 576,000 161,000   Cleaning Operations (Dry Cleaners (w/Plant)): SEMI ABSENTEE OWNER, 18 years old dry cleaners in the heart of Beverly Hills. Located in a high-end strip center with other complimentary businesses and with parking on street level and under ground. Currently has 5th generation perc machine which is good till 2020.
 
 
 
 
 Manager’s Salary is about $34k per year and a full time owner can add that to the profit. 
 No Soil Test Needed 
 Brand new POS system in place 
 01982102 - Structural Steel Contractor - Great Company 
L.A. County 460,000 460,000 925,000 200,000 100,000 Contractor Services (Other Contractors): 30 year old company bids on jobs then builds and installs custom steel for commercial buildings. Sales are up for 2012. Owner will train and assist in licensing.
Equipment includes:1971 C-60 tractor&amp;32’-0&quot;flatbed trailer.
2001 model 8042 skytrack reach forklift.
2002 model 40’TB40 snorkle boom lift.
2 - one ton utility truck field wedling rigs.
1 -1999 dodge one ton stake bed delivery- utility truck  
3 - 8,000 lb shop forklifts.
1 - stud welding machine&amp;1- P50 piranah iron worker machine
2 - portable Miller welding machines 302 trailblazer
1 - towable lincoln Classic 3 portable welding machine
2 - shop mig welders&amp;5- field ready portable welding machines
7 - LN 25 heavy duty wire feed field&amp;shop welding machines
Miltiple torch sets, multiple welding power sources, lots hand tools, grinders ect........ 01982230 - Nail and Foot Spa, High Volume, Employee Run 
Near Glendale and La Cresenta 460,000 460,000 1,200,000 216,000   Hair&amp;Beauty Services (Nails&amp;Facial Only): 

 Employee run 
 High volume Nail spa 
 established for a long time. 
 can prove the numbers. 


Must see and appreciate this business. rare to come on the market 41190835 - Information Technology - System Support Business 
San Gabriel Valley / Southern California 450,000 337,500 479,600 154,900 60,000 Computers (Programming/consulting): 
The business provides full range of Information Technology design, installation and support services, including: acquisition of hardware and software, network design and installation, installation and maintenance of video surveillance and phone systems, voice and data cabling and technology related project management. They also provide locally staffed - full enterprise and desktop support. The business also generates substantial revenue from providing the hardware associated with their installation and service businesses. Several clients have entered into maintenance support contracts, generating approximately $ 6,400 in monthly recurring revenue.In business for 10 years, they have developed a reputation for providing an exceptional level of technical support and service.The business has developed several other IT related niche services, including:Installation and support of internet based video surveillance/security systems and telephone systems. 
 
This business appears well positioned to benefit from current market conditions where larger firms seeking to reduce costs decide to outsource their existing IT operations.
 41480035 - Auto Window Tinting and Detailing 
Silicon Valley 450,000 450,000 495,000 205,000   Automotive Aftermarket (Automotive Aftermarket): Overview: Well established specialist shop for auto detailing, window tinting, gold plating and auto glass window replacement and repair located within easy access to Highway. It is efficiently managed and enjoys a strong track record of repeat business from its B2B and B2C customer base including retail, government and corporate accounts with big name auto dealerships in the Silicon Valley. Very profitable with proven long-term track record and growth potential. Direct auto experience is not necessary but the ideal buyer must be passionate about cars with strong managerial, sales and marketing background and a good eye for detail and quality control. Facilities: Large shop with excellent street frontage visibility. Approximately 2,400 Sq. ft. for 7-8 vehicles inside and a parking area outside for 10-11 vehicles. Favorable lease terms transferable to new owner. Market Outlook: This business was started by the current owner about 30 years ago and today it has an excellent reputation for high quality service, on time delivery and pick up and life time nationwide guarantee for auto window tinting. Over the years, this company has won many awards for excellent‘detailing’work. The team of experienced full time staff is cross trained to repair, tint and detail auto windows for all types of automobiles to the highest standards. This company has also been nominated‘Best Car Detailing’in a popular local poll. The Competition: The other competitors in the area cannot match this company’s track record for service, lifetime nationwide guarantees, longevity, and consistent business from repeat customers and referrals Growth/Expansion: With the right buyer, this company is well positioned for growth and expansion. Recommendations by the owner to increase sales include more programs for pick-ups and deliveries, increasing the gold plating of  emblems/logos business, higher frequency of visits to body shops, mining existing data base of customers through email contact or other social media. 41480054 - Wholesale Paper&amp;Office Supplies 
San Francisco 450,000 450,000 5,750,000 178,000   Office Supply/Business Stationery (Office Supply/Business Stnry): Successful and well established 60 year old wholesale paper and office Supplies Company trading under the same name since 1952. Six decades of successful management has established this company as a premier reputable company. The current owner, an ex-banker acquired this company more than 22 years ago and has made this into a thriving, stable and profitable business delivering a consistent 6 figure cash flow. This company has multi-million dollar contractual agreements with the Department of General Service, Sacramento for the next 3 years to supply paper products and toners statewide. The owner does not carry any paper or toner inventory. Over the years he has successfully modeled a financial cash flow management system based on‘just in time’delivery that focus on maximizing the timing of the delivery and invoicing to ensure collection in a timely manner. The Owner will coach the buyer on this proven cash management process to ensure a seamless transition. The seller is willing to remain with the new owner for as long as needed and is selling to transition towards retirement. The Company generates 90 percentage of its revenue from the wholesale paper and toner supply division and with the 3 years contract in place, is less reliant on the office supplies division. In addition to the owner, there is a part-time Office Manager who contributes to the successful operation of this Company. Very little contact with the public saves a great deal of time. The ideal buyer could be a husband and wife team or family members with management and operation experience. This is an opportunity to acquire a long time successful company with a strong stable sales revenue and profit base and proven business model to allow the new owner to continue to create value and build wealth. There are many opportunities to develop the office supplies division with increased sales and marketing to grow revenue and profitability. Organized and turnkey this is a solidly profitable business with steady cash flow. Complete with a good lease, furniture, fixtures and equipment.
 41480054 - Wholesale Paper&amp;Office Supplies 
San Francisco 450,000 450,000 5,750,000 178,000   Distribution/Wholesale (Paper Goods): Successful and well established 60 year old wholesale paper and office Supplies Company trading under the same name since 1952. Six decades of successful management has established this company as a premier reputable company. The current owner, an ex-banker acquired this company more than 22 years ago and has made this into a thriving, stable and profitable business delivering a consistent 6 figure cash flow. This company has multi-million dollar contractual agreements with the Department of General Service, Sacramento for the next 3 years to supply paper products and toners statewide. The owner does not carry any paper or toner inventory. Over the years he has successfully modeled a financial cash flow management system based on‘just in time’delivery that focus on maximizing the timing of the delivery and invoicing to ensure collection in a timely manner. The Owner will coach the buyer on this proven cash management process to ensure a seamless transition. The seller is willing to remain with the new owner for as long as needed and is selling to transition towards retirement. The Company generates 90 percentage of its revenue from the wholesale paper and toner supply division and with the 3 years contract in place, is less reliant on the office supplies division. In addition to the owner, there is a part-time Office Manager who contributes to the successful operation of this Company. Very little contact with the public saves a great deal of time. The ideal buyer could be a husband and wife team or family members with management and operation experience. This is an opportunity to acquire a long time successful company with a strong stable sales revenue and profit base and proven business model to allow the new owner to continue to create value and build wealth. There are many opportunities to develop the office supplies division with increased sales and marketing to grow revenue and profitability. Organized and turnkey this is a solidly profitable business with steady cash flow. Complete with a good lease, furniture, fixtures and equipment.
[!--[endif]--&gt; 01981887 - BOBA FRANCHISE,FULLERTON,BUSY,EMPLOYEE RUN 
NORTH ORANGE COUNTY, FULLERTON AREA 450,000 450,000 456,000 120,000   Miscellaneous Food Service (Ice Cream/Yogurt): 

 VERY POPULAR BOBA LOCA FRANCHISE IN FULLERTON 
 100% EMPLOYEE RUN 
 CURRENT OWNER HAS BEEN RUNNING FOR OVER 7 YEARS 
 CURRENTLY UPGRADED THE INTERIOR 
 VERY BUSY LOCATION 
 LOW RENT AND LONG LEASE 


IF YOU LIVE IN FULLERTON AREA, YOU’VE PROBABLY HAVE VISITED THIS BOBA LOCA!! EASY OPERATION, GREAT INVESTMENT OPPORTUNITY. 01982144 - DRY CLEANERS SINCE 1971, NEW EQUIPMENT&amp;TESTING 
HUNTINGTON BEACH 425,000 425,000 280,000 120,000 150,000 Cleaning Operations (Dry Cleaners (w/Plant)): 

 3 YEARS NEW HYDROCARBON CLEANING SYSTEM LOOKS&amp;RUNS LIKE NEW 
 PHASE I PERFORMED 6 YEARS AGO WITH CLEAN RESULTS 
 NO ADVERTISING, NO COUPONS, NO MARKETING, NO DISCOUNTS 
 2 EMPLOYEES PERFORM BULK OF LABOR - USUALLY OFF AT 3:00 PM 
 TYPICAL EXPENSES: Electric $600, Gas $375, Water Included NNN, Telephone $100, Supplies $800, Hangers $750, Insurance $200, Worker’s Comp $200 
 GREAT OPPORTUNITY FOR THRIVING NEIGHBORHOOD CLEANERS. SERIOUS UPSIDE POTENTIAL FOR MORE ACTIVE OWNER WILLING TO DO SOME MARKETING 
 FAMILY RUN, HUSBAND, WIFE AND SON WORK WITH 2 EMPLOYEES 

 41191202 - High income Fast Food Franchise 
Orange County, CA 410,000 410,000 700,158 136,181 350,000 Fast Foods-Primarily Take-Out (Sandwich Shops): Established high income Fast Food Franchise in upscale shopping center with wellknown anchor tenants in an affluent neighburhood of mixed residential and commercial properties. Dining destination for surrounding high rise office buildings. Great Franchise and easy operation with healthy, fresh and tasty menu from quality ingredients. Great books and records supporting profitable track records. SBA loan approved. 2508101909 - Hi volume screenprinting 
North Orange County 400,000 400,000 807,445 101,035   Printing Services (Commercial&amp;Graphic Arts): Company has been established for seven years and has state of the art equipment such as 12-color automatic presses ideal for multiple color screen prints and designs. It has grown From a simple single screen-printing shop to a large and professional firm. Can meet the complex demands of the retail industry and is a prominent player in the wholesale industry as well. Shop is 9,300 sq ft industrial building and seller values equipment at $300,000. Up to 12 full time employees and part time available as needed. Best years prior to the Great Recession was $1,300,000. 25080000 - Popular So Cal Pizza Franchise 
South Orange County 399,000 399,000 600,000 140,000   Fast Foods-Primarily Take-Out (Pizza): This opportunity is a VERY popular pizza restaurant franchise in one of the best locations in ALL of California. This chain has shown continued growth, expansion and gains in POPULARITY, This location caters to an upscale community and has NEW growth and construction planned for the future bringing more and more potential customers to the area. This sale also includes development rights for three (3) additional neighboring areas so its PERFECT for future expansion of more units as well. Call me for more info and specifics, hurry this one will go fast!!!!!!!! (949) 679-9697 01982206 - FF HAMBURGER WITH PROPERTY, DRIVE THRU, LA AREA. 
LOS ANGELES, NEAR BY LONG BEACH AREA 399,000 399,000 204,000 108,000 350,000 Fast Foods-Primarily Take-Out (Hamburger): 

 FREE STANDING BUILDING 
 DRIVE THRU 
 NO TO MINIMAL COMPETITION 
 SURROUNDED BY APARTMENTS AND HOMES 
 CURRENTLY FAMILY RUN 


THIS BUSINESS IS SOLD WITH THE REAL PROPERTY. HAS SO MUCH POTENTIAL TO GROW TO INCREASE SALES AND NET PROFIT. THE LIST PRICE IS UNDER MARKET VALUE FOR BUSINESS AND PROPERTY. MUST SEE BUSINESS AND REAL PROPERTY. PS: THE REAL PROPERTY AND BIZ IS UNDER VALUE, WILL BE ABLE TO RECEIVE SBA LOAN FOR THE QUALIFIED BUYER. GREAT OPPORTUNITY TO PURCHASE FREE STANDING BUILDING AND BIZ AS A COMBO. WILL NOT BE ON THE MARKET TOO LONG FOR $399,000 INCLUDING THE PROPERTY AND BUSINESS. 01982216 - Thai Restaurant Upscale Busy Location 
Irvine 385,000 385,000 762,000 120,000   Restaurants (Chinese/Thai Rest. Beer&amp;Wine): 

 Employee Run in Irvine upscale neighborhood  
 Net Profits $120,000/annually 
 Prim location busy Lunch and Dinner 
 High volume high profits Thai Restaurant 
 Millions homes, condos and apartments are surrounding 
 Turn-Key operation and no prior experience is required 
 Anchor stores: Albertsons, Banks, Gas station, Starbucks coffee, restaurants... 
 COG 23~26% 

 01981929 - Sports Bar near University 
Long Beach 375,000 200,000 1,366,000 84,000   Cocktail Lounges/Taverns/Bars (Lounges w/Entertainment or Dance): 

 Hi volume sports bar with full liquor, live entertainment license, catering permit to serve liquor offsite like weddings.and 1000 sq ft outside patio permitted to serve alcohol and smoke. 
 Located in walking distance to the University with 35,000 students and faculty. Has 9-47&quot;televisions plus many more smaller televisions to see just about any sporting event happening. 
 Beautiful bar! Original build out cost close to $1,000,000. Has complete kitchen with hood and grill. 
 Affluent area close to the water. 60% beverage&amp;40%food sales 
 Major Expenses: Rent-14,735, food and beverage-33%, utilities-2500, sales tax-11,100, labor- 31,000, credit card fees-2100,insurance-2000 

 01982143 - #1 Franchise Fast Food, Incld Build.&amp;Drive Thru 
Riverside County 350,000 350,000 382,000 40,000 400,000 Fast Foods-Primarily Take-Out (Fast Food - Primarily Take Out): This Franchise fast food is ranked #1 in Market Share for their field. With over 3700 stores in place. The price include the building with a 30 years land lease in place. Imagine you can have 30 years very low lease amount!!! Also you get to write off most of your investment in depreciation!!! The trend has been up for the last 2 years and there is an opportunity to change the concept if you like.


 Very well design and setup for concept change 
 Includes the building and a drive-thru 
 30 years land lease in place 

 41191206 - National Fast Food Franchise 
Orange County 350,000 350,000 985,331 88,841 200,000 Fast Foods-Primarily Take-Out (Hamburger): National Fast Food Franchise in Orange County located in a free standing building with drive through on a high traffic street with high visibility&amp;easy access. Densely populated neighburhood of mixed residential and office buildings. Elaborate menu made from premium ingredients with no additives. There is a REBATE of $ 220,00 0 For remodeling from the asking price of $ 350,000 that would make this store almost like new!SBA loan eligible. 01982210 - DONUT,EMPLOYEE RUN, BOOKS AND RECORDS TO PROVE 
NORTH ORANGE COUNTY NEAR FULLERTON AND BUENA PARK 350,000 350,000 504,000 96,000   Miscellaneous Food Service (Donut/Bagel Shop): 

 EMPLOYEE RUN 
 HAS EXCELLENT BOOKS AND RECORDS 
 DEMANDING AREA AND EXCELLENT LOCATION 
 INVESTED OVER 400,000 PLUS FOR BUILD OUT. 


THIS LOCATION AND BUSINESS IS GREAT FOR E-2 VISA OR L-1 STATUS FROM QUALIFIED COUNTRIES. THIS NORTH ORANGE COUNTY, NEAR FULLERTON AND BUENA PARK AREA. THIS BUSINESS IS WELL KNOW AMONG THE COMMUNITY AND NONE LIKE OTHER DONUT SHOP. THIS PLACE IS NICE !!!!!! 01982193 - 100% Full Service Through Hand Car Wash 
L. A. county, Near Torrance 350,000 350,000 300,000 96,000   Car Wash (Car Wash): 

 IT’S UNBELIEVABLE BUT TRUE, A NEW HAND CAR WASH IN TORRANCE. 
 100,000 cars pass by every day, per owners 
 Surrounded with businesses and office buildings, lot of untapped marketing. 
 Current advertisements at Vons, Albertsons and money mailer only 
 Typical exp. Rent $7000. labor $6000. property tax $425. other exp. $2500 
 Right now doing an avg. of $800 a day at $13 per car. Room to expand to at least 150 cars a day. (future projections) 
 Opportunity to increase inside sales by offering automobile related products. like car mats, fresheners etc. 

 41191213 - pharmacy retail 
street 350,000 350,000 1,200,000 115,000   Professional Services (Professional Services): pharmacy retail store in Arcadia, los angeles county for sale. Owner retirement. Good Location. Renewed Lease. Owner can stay to help. Please contact Steve Wang for the details. 2508101915 - Dance Studio 
Orange County 350,000 175,000 240,000 114,000   Professional Services (Personnel Service): Highly successful Ballroom Dance&amp;Studio offering private, group lessons with competitions and live performances. Has a highly improved leasehold and some of the best sound equipment available. Hundreds of thousands invested in improvements and equipment. Housed in a three thousand square feet storefront, with exceptional lease terms. (Current rent is $2,500 month). Has a capacity for 120 people.

Location has plenty of parking and central location is convenient for Los Angeles and Orange County clients. Instructors are independent contractors making this business simple to operate with low fixed overhead. Offers Zambia and Pilate s classes in the mornings and can be used a meeting/ event center.

Has the best Karaoke and sound equipment west of Las Vegas. Draws customers from all over So California. Submit offers!

 41191218 - Pharmacy retail store 
Shipping Mall 350,000 350,000 1,056,000 18,000 25,000 Pharmacy/Drugstores (Pharmacy/Drugstore): 30 years established pharmacy retail store is now available to you, once a life time opportunity. the seller is retiring and motivated to sell. Great location with new lease. Absentee onwer and one full time manager who will stay with the new owner. Please call agent for details!  41141012 - Gourmet/Organic Market w Great Local 
San Francisco Peninsula 340,000 340,000 650,000 150,000   Markets (Fruits, Produce Store/Market): No expense was spared in the build out of this market. The location is outstanding, and the clientele is very upscale. This is a turnkey opportunity with tremendous upside. This business is priced for a very quick sale as the owner needs to focus on their other significant business interests. Owner currently spends about 15 hours a week overseeing this operation. 41191215 - Major Fast Food Franchise 
Los Angeles County 335,000 335,000 493,725 91,025 300,000 Fast Foods-Primarily Take-Out (Chicken&amp;Ribs): National Fast Food Franchise in Los Angeles County located near by two major free ways and in populated area. Great visibility easy access and fingre licking products made fresh from quality ingridients. Reasonable rent, 5+5 % royalty and advertising fees, $ 5000 transfer fee. 41191216 - National Fast Food Franchise 
Los Angeles County 335,000 335,000 510,729 96,861 300,000 Fast Foods-Primarily Take-Out (Chicken&amp;Ribs): National Fast Food Franchise in Los Angeles County located in populated area with drive through. Great visibility easy access and fingre licking products made fresh from quality ingridients. Reasonable rent, 5+5 % royalty and advertising fees, $ 5000 transfer fee. 41141019 - Leading SF Carpet/Flooring Retailer and Installer 
San Francisco 329,000 329,000 1,900,000 240,000   Contractor Services (Construction/installation): This is a 26 year old business that built its reputation selling and installing carpet and vinyl. It also offers cabinets, molding imported from China, and household fixtures. Unlike most of its competitors, the company carries a large inventory, including first quality remnants, which allows for immediate product delivery. This model has created loyal customers who need to get the job done without waiting for supplies to be delivered. Lowe’s Home Improvement recently opened across the street. This has reinvigorated the neighborhood with the company experiencing greater traffic and sales.
     
     This is a Cash-and-Carry business with 20 years remaining on its lease. Priced at 329,000 with annual adjusted earnings exceeding 240,000, this is an exceptional opportunity! The company has a strong customer base and excellent reputation.
     
     Over the last several years, company sales have ranged from 1,,900,000 to 2,900,000. Sales are tracking significantly upward for 2012. The majority of company revenues are generated by carpet sales which are broken down in to the following categories: 1.) high-margin installation and product sales to Real Estate Management Companies, Homeowners and Apartment owners, 2) wholesale to established commercial and residential contractors 3) cash and carry customers many of which have known the company and are repeat customers. 01982155 - Chinese Fast Food - Very Busy! 
ANAHEIM 320,000 320,000 468,000 96,000   Fast Foods-Primarily Take-Out (Chinese or Thai): 

 Owner operating for 6 yrs with steam table 
 Located at major shopping center  
 1 owner works from 9:30am-2pm, 1 owner works only on Monday 
 Nice employees, easy management 


 Perfect for a couple to run with stable sales. 
 
 41141013 - Auto Retailer and Consignor 
San Francisco - Southeast Bay Area 320,000 320,000 4,500,000 160,000   Auto/Motorcycle Dealers (Used Dealer): Very well established auto dealer and auto consignment business with a great location. Owner does not work weekends. There are substantial opportunities to grow the business.Owner earns over $160,000 per year.

 01982172 - Russian Market, Seller Financing, Short Owner Hrs 
Los Angeles 300,000 150,000 1,080,000 144,000   Markets (Ethnic Food Store): 30 years established market in a prime high traffic location. They sell different kinds of produce, non perishable goods, with full deli and catering services.
	</body>
</document>
