<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002782" url="http://www.diabetesnet.com/food-diabetes/carb-counting/fast-food-carb-counts" time="2012-07-12-18:50" support="1" score="0.00103939994078767" bingtitle="Fast Food Carb Counts | Diabetesnet.com" webtitle="Fast Food Carb Counts | Diabetesnet.com">
			<query id="001515" bing-rank="64"/>
	<description>Fast Food Carb Counts ... Numbers to Know; Low Blood Sugars. Symptoms; Prevention; Treatment; More Treatment Tips</description>
	<body>
		Home About Us Contact Us 
 Diabetesnet.com 
 SHOP WITH US ABOUT DIABETES DIABETES CONTROL FOOD&amp;DIABETES DIABETES TECHNOLOGY DIABETES TOOLS DIABETES RESOURCES DIABETES PRESENTATIONS DIABETES BOOKS FORUMS NEWS/POPULAR 

 Home About Us Contact Us 
 Home › FOOD&amp;DIABETES › Carb Counting › Fast Food Carb Counts 
Fast Food Carb Counts
 
These chain restaurant sites provide a nutrition analysis of their menu items to help you plan and balance fast food meals, whether you are dieting, controlling your blood sugar or eating healthy. We hope this information will help you make better decisions about balance, variety and moderation in your diet, and improve your overall control.

 Arby&apos;s Papa John&apos;s Blimpie s Pizza Hut Boston Market Quiznos Burger King Schlotzsky&apos;s Carl&apos;s Junior Soup Plantation&amp;Sweet Tomatoes Dominos Starbucks Kentucky Fried Chicken Subway Little Caesars Taco Bell McDonalds Wendy&apos;s 
 Thu, 12/16/2010 - 11:13 

 
 Carb Counting Food&amp;Diabetes 
 
Great Books on Carb Counting
 
 
 SEARCH:
 SITE STORE
 
 SHOP WITH US ABOUT DIABETES 
 Newly Diagnosed 
 Risk/Diagnosis Types of Diabetes Diabetes Care 
 Talking To Your Docto 
 Blood Sugar Testing 
 HbA1c 
 Diet and Nutrition Plans Insulins Diabetes Medications Healthcare Team Motivation 
 People&amp;Diabetes 
 Women&amp;Diabetes Men&amp;Diabetes Children&amp;Diabetes Air Travel&amp;Diabetes 
 Types of Diabetes 
 What Type? Type 1 Diabetes Type 1.5 Type 2 
 The Apple Figure&amp;Insulin Sensitivity 
 Prediabetes Syndrome X Polycystic Ovary Disease Gestational Diabetes Hemochromatosis Cystic Fibrosis 
 Insulin 
 Long-Acting Insulins Insulin Basics Rapid Insulins 
 Humalog and Heat User&apos;s Reports on Humalog 
 Basal Insulins 
 Levemir - Dose Splitting 
 Insulin Action Time 
 Action Time of Humalog and Novolog Duration of Insulin Action 
 Insulin Sensitivity Insulin Delivery 
 Inhaled Insulin Insulcheck Insulin Pens 
 Pendiq Timesulin 
 Oral Insulin Transdermal Insulin Delivery 
 
 Diabetes Medications 
 Symlin Incretins 
 DPP-4 Inhibitors GLP-1 Agonist 
 Sulfonylureas Metformin Precose and Glyset Actos and Avandia Prandin and Starlix 
 Diabetes Complications 
 Frozen Shoulder Why Are Only Certain Organs Damaged? Eye Complications 
 Eye Changes Causes of Damage Background Retinopathy Preproliferative Retinopathy Proliferative Retinopathy Macular Edema Cataracts Amsler Test 
 Foot Complications Skin Complications Heart Complications Kidney Disease 
 Stages and Reversal 
 Diabetic Neuropathy Celiac Disease Dupuytren&apos;s Contracture 
 
 DIABETES CONTROL 
 Record Keeping Rules For Control 
 Carb Factors Correction Factor Bolus on Board Basal/Bolus Balance Numbers to Know 
 Low Blood Sugars 
 Symptoms Prevention Treatment More Treatment Tips Hypoglycemia Unawareness Emotion Control 
 High Blood Sugars 
 Symptoms Prevention Treatment 
 Exercise and Diabetes 
 ExCarbs for Exercise Taking the&quot;Ex&quot;Out of Exercise 
 Alternative Therapies Insulin Control Secrets 
 FOOD&amp;DIABETES 
 Carb Counting 
 What Are Carbs? What Are Grams of Carbs? The 500 Rule Insulin Reaction Guides How To Count Carbohydrates 
 Food Labels The Carb Challenge 
 How Many Carbs Do You Need? Fast Food Carb Counts 
 Glycemic Index 
 4th Dimension of Management 
 Satiety Index Weight Control Cyber Kitchen 
 All Recipes Judith Jones-Ambrosini Cyber Kitchen 1-10 
 A Fun Lentil Meal The Restaurant Detective A Summer Grill Menu Harvest Lunch - A Picnic Menu A Sweet Thanksgiving Holiday Gift Ideas Winter In The Pantry The Fiber Of Tuscany Diet Defenses In The Fat Fight Spring Into Vegetarianism 
 Cyber Kitchen 11-20 
 Food and War Stories Exercise, A Functional Cure A Very Berry Summer Palate Pleasing Pastas Good, Practical Weeknight Cooking for the Non-Cook Better Living Through Sandwiches Cookies&amp;Summer Exercise A Potent Elixir For All Seasons Yoga For Enhanced Diabetes Care Oranges and Olives for the Holiday Season 
 Cyber Kitchen 21-30 
 All About Philosophy And Fish Soup A big fat greek wedding feast, on a diabetic diet Reality Sandwiches and a Dessert Party Allium Sativum (Garlic), Prickly Thistle (Artichokes), and Jicama A healthy, delicious and festive Latino menu A Cooking Class For The Odd Couple Less In More Out Organic Living The Carbohydrate Conspiracy Catching Up On Control 
 Cyber Kitchen 31-40 
 Yet Another Level A Celebration Feast For HbA1c Morning Glories Frozen Favorites Life Is Good Diabetes and Happiness Catapulted To Diabetes Advocacy A Diabetes Library Perennial Holiday Favorites Sometimes it&apos;s a Bumpy Ride 
 Cyber Kitchen 41-50 
 Positive Influences - Good Taste Diabetes And The Five Tibetans Diabetes in the Garden Diabetes --- Take A Hike! Diabetes Care For Ordinary People Moving to Diabetes Tech Town Super Foods The Almost Perfect Life with Diabetes Dreams and CGM&apos;s The Sisterhood of Diabetes 
 Cyber Kitchen 51-60 
 Just In Case.... Freedom of Choice A Breath of Spring Daily Double Diet Watch: Diabetes and Celiac Diabetes and Extremes Diabetes Made Me Do It Splurging and Losing Creating a Type 2 Lifestyle There&apos;s Always More To Learn The Influence of Activity 
 Climbing Stairs and Wild Salmon: A Common Bond? World Diabetes Day and Pulses A Tonic for the Diabetes Doldrums Can Someone Please Tell Me Whatís Going On? Get Your Bones Ready to Go Outdoors What&apos;s Cooking? The Energy of Diabetes Apple Cider Vinegar 
 
 DIABETES TECHNOLOGY 
 Insulin Pumps 
 Current Pumps 
 Pump Comparison OneTouch Ping Paradigm Revel 
 mySentry Remote 
 Deltec Cozmo Accu-Chek Spirit Insulet Omnipod 
 Insulet and J&amp;J 
 Minimed X22 Series Dana Diabecare II Nipro Large BoB 
 Future Pumps 
 Cellnovo Debiotech Jewel Pump Solo MicroPump Tandem t:slim 
 t:slim Available 
 Valeritas V-Go 
 Patch Pumps Pump Life 
 Heart And Soul Of An Insulin Pump Pump Preparation 
 Sterile Technique Insulin&amp;Dressings Site Sterilization Infusion Sets Choices Insert The Infusion Set Infusion Sites Prevent Infections Infusion Set and Reservoir Prep Safety Loop 
 Pump Problems 
 O-Ring Leaks Tunneling Bubbles Hub Leaks Sweating Bleeding Infections Clogs 
 Pump Accessories 
 Pump Insulin Duration Older Pumps 
 Animas 1200 Series Animas 2020 Compare Older Pumps 
 
 Infusion Sets Meters&amp;Monitors 
 Continuous Monitors 
 Compare Current Monitors Dexcom 
 Dexcom Partners with Roche Dexcom and Tandem Partnership 
 Freestyle Navigator MiniMed Guardian CGM Head to Head Comparison Looking Beyond the Numbers 
 Blood Glucose Meters 
 Contour USB Meter Meter Accuracy Problems Talking Blood Glucose Meters iBGStar 
 Future Meters&amp;Monitors 
 Orsense Glucoday S Hypomon by AIMEDICS Kumetrix Lightouch Medical Photonic Glucose Sensor Scout DS by Veralight Animas System ArithMed GmbH Glysens NIR Diagnostics Optiscan SMSI Sensys Medical Sentek Solianis Monitoring AG Sontra Spectrx Visual Pathways 
 Blood Glucose Test Strips Improving Meters Infrared Technology Radiowave Technology Other Monitors 
 SenseWear Monitor 
 
 Diabetes Software Blue Skying 
 Super Bolus Smart Insulin Pen 
 
 DIABETES TOOLS DIABETES RESOURCES 
 Insurance&amp;Diabetes Diabetes Links Diabetes Companies Diabetes Associations Diabetes Publications Clinical Trials 
 Corengi 
 Diabetes Conferences Diabetes Assistance 
 DIABETES PRESENTATIONS DIABETES BOOKS FORUMS NEWS/POPULAR 
   
Newsletter
 
Sign up for the Diabetesnet.com newsletter.
 
 Name: Email:   
 
Site Terms
 Meters&amp;Monitors Pump Problems Low Blood Sugars Future Monitors books Insulin Pumps Current Pumps Complications Cyber Kitchen Carb Counting Controlling Diabetes Continuous Monitors Diabetes Resources Types Newly Diagnosed Technology Pump Life Insulin Food&amp;Diabetes Information     
 Shop | Info | Control | Nutrition | Tech | Tools | Resources | Forum | Newsletter 

To learn more about the Diabetes Mall, please visit our About Us page.
If you have comments or wish to help with this site, please contact us .
Visit our Advertising or Links pages to put your site on the Diabetes Mall.
 Ver 40.0 ©2010, Diabetes Services, Inc., serving you on the net since May, 1994
	</body>
</document>
