<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002326" url="http://www.bestcookinggames.com/" time="2012-07-12-18:15" support="47" score="0.11073317609329428" bingtitle="Fun Cooking Games - Pizza and Food games" webtitle="Fun Cooking Games - Pizza and Food games">
			<query id="000349" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000453" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="001367" bing-rank="198"/>
			<query id="001144" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="000050" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="000401" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000036" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000117" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="000557" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="001112" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="000970" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="001187" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="000946" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="001050" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001185" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000447" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="000046" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="001189" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="001175" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="001034" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000124" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="000559" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="001156" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="001259" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="001049" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="000061" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="000892" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000460" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="001165" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="001160" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="001136" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000555" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="000118" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="001363" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="000547" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="001158" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="001102" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000392" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="000955" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="000054" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="001058" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="001279" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="000109" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="000907" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="000561" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000554" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000359" bing-rank="210"/>
	<description>Fast Food Cashier 14. Top That Restaurant Game 15. Patty Panic Spongebob Game ... Lea got a job as a waitress at the new fast food restaurant in her hometown, help her ...</description>
	<body>
		Home | Members | Tell a Friend | Links 
 Find Games: 
 All Dress Up Games   |   Cooking ·  Cooking Games ·  Cake Decorating ·  Restaurant Games ·  Fast Food ·  Waitress Games ·  Burger Shop ·  Pizza Games ·  Ice Cream ·  
 Members Username: 
Password: 
 
 Lost your password? You have only couple of credit(s) left before you must log in or register . 
 New Games Popular 
 
 New Dress Up Games 
 01.   Juicy Server 
 02.   Memorize and Service 
 03.   Sandwich Making 
 04.   Hungry Giants 
 05.   Crazy Cup Cakes 
 06.   Stabilize the Food 
 07.   Stabilize the Food 
 08.   How to Make Madeleine Castles 
 09.   Scooby Stall 
 10.   Scooby Stall 
 11.   How to Make Oat and Raisin Cookies 
 12.   Chocolate Rum Pots 
 13.   Village Bistro 
 14.   How to Make Easter Humpty Biscuits 
 15.   How to make Banana Lollies 
 16.   Luigi Kitchen Soup 
 17.   Roadside Fastfood 
 
 Popular Games 
 01.   Cooking food 
 02.   Sue Cooking 
 03.   Birthday cake 
 04.   Become a Bartender 
 05.   Cake Bakery Game 
 06.   Cream cake Game - Bake and dec... 
 07.   Create a Cake 
 08.   Fast cooking 
 09.   Disney Restaurant 
 10.   Disney Restaurant 
 11.   Fast Food Cashier 
 12.   Holly Hobbie Muffin Maker 
 13.   Spongebob Burger Game 
 14.   Breakfast Game 
 15.   Top That Restaurant Game 
 16.   Patty Panic Spongebob Game 
 17.   Pizza 
 18.   Busy Burger Game 
 Site Statistics Registered Users: 50076
 Total Games: 5877
 Views Today: 256142135
 Total Views: 256142117

There are 1265 users online:
 0 Members , 1265 Guests. Top Players 01.   AiNoKaikoroku - 5331
 02.   sephybaby - 4455
 03.   miss_fabolous97 - 4158
 04.   Sakuralinh - 3264
 05.   Mondstein - 3202
 06.   HessieNae - 3120
 07.   nicole990248 - 2914
 08.   ducky3gal - 2848
 09.   valval - 2411
 10.   alliemae - 2168
 Cool Links 
Dolls and Stars
 01.   Stardoll Celebs 
 
New Roiworld
 01.   Roiworld 
 
Dress Up
 01.   Create a DressUp 
 02.   Happy Dress Up 
 03.   Good Dressup 
 04.   New Dress Up Girls 
 05.   Free Dressing Up 
 06.   Girls Dressup 
 
Bratz Dolls
 01.   Bratz Dolls 
 02.   Dress Up Toys 
 03.   Bratz 
 04.   Bratz Games 
 More Cool Links» 
 
Largest cooking games site for girls. This place is full with coolest free food , pizza games and burger games. You can become a waitress in cafeteria , bake a birthday cake or simply grill some burgers . Whatever you do, you will have a lot of fun cooking food in our virtual kitchen.
 Cooking Games BBQ Challenge 
 
 BBQ Challenge 
 Cranberry Smoothie 
 
 Learn to make cranberry smoothies in this fun interactive cooking game, put the ingredients from the recipe in the mall and mix them together to creat... 
 Cooking Championship 
 
 Get ready for the chef cooking championship, practice some great recipes in this game. Follow the instructions to match your opponents speed as you cr... 

 More Cooking Games» Recently Played Games 
 Sandwich Making 
476.5 minutes ago
 Arrange the ingredients in the same order (from left to right) which is shown in the customer’s request. Pizza Shop 
476.9 minutes ago
 Come and make pizzas according to the instructions and have fun. Cooking School 
477 minutes ago
 Enroll at classes in cooking school and learn all new recipes. Learn how to be a chef by taking cooking classes and entering competitions with your me... Cheese Omelette 
477.3 minutes ago
 Learn to prepare the best cheese omelette, beat the eggs and add the cheese at the right time to create a delicious fluffy breakfast. Follow the recip... 
 Cooking Games Games Festive Turkey Stuffing 
 
 Follow the recipe to make this delicious turkey stuffing. A tradition for the American holiday Thanksgiving, this dish features a combination of bread... 
 Speedy Sushi Chef 
 
 Its time to learn how to prepare sushi, you will be going through all the instructions 1 by 1 until you complete the sushi rolls. Once you have comple... 
 Stuffed Mushrooms 
 
 Try out this delicious recipe for stuffed mushrooms, a great appetizer that will feed your guests and show off your cooking skills. Follow the instruc... 
 More Cooking Games Games» Cake Decorating Games Spooky Cake Decorating 
 
 When the monsters and ghouls come out to play on Halloween, they also enjoy a sweet treat to begin their night of haunting. Create a beautiful spooky ... 
 Halloween Wedding Cake 
 
 Ghouls and bats decorate this tiered beautiful haunted wedding cake for a special couple&apos;s wedding on Hallow&apos;s Eve. Create a fantastically d... 
 Perfect Cupcake Decorating 
 
 Design the perfect cupcake in this fun cake decorating game, choose your favorite frosting, toppings, and flavor for the dream dessert. Cupcakes are c... 
 More Cake Decorating Games» Restaurant Games Games Sushi Mania 
 
 In Japan, everyone is crazy about their sushi, and it is actually a very easy dish to prepare. Put together the rice, seaweed, and raw fish to create ... 
 Sushi Chef 
 
 In this game you will be cooking your sushi specials for your customers, when a customer comes into your restaurant you should take their order then c... 
 Juice Bar 
 
 Working at a juice bar can be tough work, your customers are in a hurry and are very picky about their fresh juice beverages. Do the job right and ser... 
 More Restaurant Games Games» Fast Food Games Big City Diner 
 
 Your new job as a waitress at this drive in diner. Suzie and her chef serve up good times, smiles and great meals at this fast paced, fun, American di... 
 Popcorn Booth 
 
 See what it&apos;s like to work at a popcorn booth and serve hasty customers on the way to watch a movie. Fill the orders quickly to earn money and ha... 
 Quick Serve 
 
 Working at a fast food counter is a test of your skill and reflexes, remember the order your customers give and place the right in front of them. But ... 
 More Fast Food Games» Waitress Games Games Fast Food Resto 
 
 Lea got a job as a waitress at the new fast food restaurant in her hometown, help her make some money and keep her customers happy with the service by... 
 Japanese Restaurant 
 
 Lee just got a job at a hot new Japanese Restaurant, help her keep her waitress job by fulfilling all the duties, she has a 5 day trial period so don&amp;... 
 Italian Restaurant 
 
 You got a summer job as a waitress in an Italian restaurant. Fulfill your duties as a waitress, seat the customers, take their orders, and deliver the... 
 More Waitress Games Games» Burger Shop Games Belle&apos;s Burger 
 
 Welcome to Belle&apos;s Burger, may I take your order? Assemble the burger orders according to the customer&apos;s demands, some may want cheese to ma... 
 Busy Burger 
 
 In this game you will be able to help this girl to make hamburgers and French fries. The customers can be very insistent in a fast food restaurant and... 
 Burger Shack 
 
 Welcome to the Burger Shack, a delicious hamburger grill on the beach. Order anything from our menu including hamburgers, cheeseburgers with lettuce a... 
 More Burger Shop Games» Pizza Games Games Making a Pizza 
 
 This game is full of steak cutting, ingredient chopping, dough pounding fun. Get through each of the unique cooking challenges to win this pizza game.... 
 Deep Dish Pizza 
 
 Learn how to cook a delicious Chicago-style deep dish pizza that can be a great dinner for your whole family. Start off with the dough and bake it in ... 
 New York Pizza 
 
 Everyone knows that you can find the best slice of pizza in New York City. The thin crust New York style pizza, is something the best chef wishes to c... 
 More Pizza Games Games» Ice Cream Games Making Ice Cream 
 
 Learn to make ice cream from scratch in this fun cooking game. Beat together the eggs and milk and add your favorite flavors to create your perfect ic... 
 How To Make Banana Split 
 
 Are you ready to lean how to cook a delicious desert? The desert on the menu today is a super yummy banana split! It is your job to make these all day... 
 Ice Cream Parlor 
 
 Welcome to the town&apos;s new biggest and best ice cream parlor. You have been invited to come work at this magical place for the day, serving some o... 
 More Ice Cream Games» 
 Www Vip Jatt   |   Mobhot Net   |   Bossmovi   |   Www 3gp King Dot Com   |   Jatnat Com   |   Www Feesbook Com   |   Www Hotmobi Net In   |   Jattemob Com   |   Www Jat Com   |   Wwwmrjaat Com   |   Www Booss Com   |   Wapwap Mobi Com   |   Mobcup In   |   Mr Jatt Com Home   |   Www Boss Mobie Com   |   Www Fanzstar Com   |   Hot Jatt Com   |   Www Ms Jatt Com   |   3 Gp Kinges   |   Www Mobihotin Fo Com   |   
 Home - Submit - RSS - Copyright Disputes - Privacy Policy - Sitemap Copyright©2005-2012 Best Cooking Games.
	</body>
</document>
