<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002135" url="http://www.theshadeexperts.com/product.php?pid=244" time="2012-07-12-18:02" support="1" score="0.0020772848313558865" bingtitle="The Shade Experts Offering Top Quality Italian Offset Patio ..." webtitle="The Shade Experts Offering Top Quality Italian Offset Patio Umbrellas Worldwide!">
			<query id="001267" bing-rank="80"/>
	<description>Two types of permanent installation and a selection of ... cafes, pubs, breweries and even fast food restaurant chains. ... even the largest umbrella folds up above the table ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Offset Umbrellas Centerpost Umbrellas Products Gallery About Contact Blog 
 Installations Referrals Shade Gallery About The Shade Experts Shows&amp;Exhibitions Advertising Vulcano Offset Umbrella Stromboli Offset Umbrella Basic Offset Umbrella Patio Offset Umbrella Poker Offset Umbrella Double Offset Umbrella Giant Large Umbrellas Market Umbrellas Prestige Strong Wind Telescopic Gazebos Pergolas Request a Catalogue 
 View Our Installations Designer and Specifier Sign In REGISTER      Lost Password? 
Centerpost Patio Umbrellas
 
 
 

 View more Installations Product Specifications 
 Printable Brochure Canopy Colors Assembly Instructions Options Available 
 
Giant Large Umbrellas
 The Uhlmann Giant Umbrellas are manufactured with the highest grade materials in three shapes, and over 90 standard sizes. Adjacent square or rectangular umbrellas can be linked with rain gutters to cover extremely large areas. 

 
 Optional accessories include side panels, infrared heating and lighting and screen-printing your logo on roof panels or valances. Two types of permanent installation and a selection of portable bases assure easy and safe operation. The Uhlmann Giant Umbrellas have been made in Germany for twenty years. Their s uperb design, expert engineering and German precision in manufacturing make them the choice of European customers who demand top quality, reliability, strength, safety and value. They provide stylish protection from the elements to a wide range of customers from exclusive hotels, restaurants, resorts, country clubs and private residences to municipalities, cafes, pubs, breweries and even fast food restaurant chains. 
 Giant Commercial Umbrellas T, TL, TL-X for Weather and Shade 
 
 Our Large patio umbrellas and our giant restaurant umbrellas are manufactured with the highest grade materials in three shapes, and over 90 standard sizes. Adjacent square or rectangular umbrellas can be linked with rain gutters to cover extremely large areas. Our“Strong Wind”umbrellas are strongest on the market. We use two types of material in 46 colors in our creative canopy designs, and offer a selection of 9 colors to powder-coat the mast. Optional accessories include side panels, infrared heating and lighting and screen-printing your logo on roof panels or valances. Two types of permanent installation and a selection of portable bases assure easy and safe operation. The Uhlmann Giant Umbrellashave been made in Germany for over twenty years. Their superb design, expert engineering and German precision in manufacturing made them the choice of European customers who demand top quality, reliability, strength, safety and value. We provide stylish protection from the elements to a wide range of customers from exclusive hotels, restaurants, resorts, country clubs and private residences to municipalities, cafes, pubs, breweries and even fast food restaurant chains.
 
 You get what you paid for!
 -Powder coated white aluminum profiles that resists peeling, chipping, rusting and oxidation, therefore remain maintenance free and permanently appealing. -All of the Type T, TL/TLx and Tx giant umbrellas are manufactured with 8, 10 or 12 exceptionally strong roof supporting arms. The longer roofing arms are reinforced inside for increased rigidity.
-All joints are manufactured from high grade steel. -All reinforcing arms are individually replaceable. -Each support ring is welded to the main flange. -The bottom supporting disk is welded to the main pole. -The telescopic part is high density plastic bearing, and guided to prevent rotation or twisting. -Through the use of adjustable main arms, it is possible to alter the tension of the roof covering material and to remove it easily from the frame. -When the umbrella is lowered the canopy can&apos;t get cut between the arms.
 -The Uhlmann telescopic giant umbrella design, with cranked lever operation, is exceptionally strong to ensure high wind stability and durability. -A maintenance free gear box (built into the mast) rotates the special spindle lift which is moving the telescoping part. -For the Type TL/TLx models the slider is connected to the telescope with 2 stainless steel wires. The telescope and the slider are moving together, enabling the very easy operation of the umbrella. -The telescopic system is designed with a special spindle lift, so even the largest umbrella folds up above the table without disturbing its content.          -The drive crank handle locks the spindles automatically in every opening/closing position, to prevent accidental opening or closing of the giant umbrella, - an important safety consideration. -The cranking handle is removable for safety and esthetic reasons. Offset Umbrella | Centerpost Umbrella | Products | Gallery | About | Contact | Associate Sites USA Offices: 3101 Fairlane Farms Rd, Suite 3,
Wellington, FL, 33414
Tel : 561 422 3200 Fax : 561 422 3217
Email: info@theshadeexperts.com
	</body>
</document>
