<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002203" url="http://www.yelp.com/biz/the-varsity-atlanta-2" time="2012-07-12-18:06" support="11" score="0.05542381883369578" bingtitle="The Varsity - Midtown - Atlanta, GA" webtitle="The Varsity - Midtown - Atlanta, GA">
			<query id="000783" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000813" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000790" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="000793" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000808" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000113" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000801" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="000227" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000802" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="000814" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="000251" bing-rank="22"/>
	<description>Food: The only thing healthy about this place is the exit door. Menu options include ... Atmosphere is expected---it&apos;s still just a fast food restaurant, with burgers and ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Search Form Skip to Navigation Skip to Page Content 

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 Log In Sign Up for Yelp Friends&apos; Activity 0 Loading... 
 Yelp is using Facebook to personalize your experience. What is this? Not you?
 Log out of Facebook Don&apos;t want to be connected?
 How to turn this off 
 
 Yelp 
 Real people. Real reviews. ® 
 
 Search for (e.g. taco, cheap dinner, Max&apos;s) 

 Near (Address, Neighborhood , City, State or Zip) 
 Search 
 Welcome About Me Write a Review Find Reviews Find Friends Messaging Talk 

 Member Search 
   
The Varsity
 512 reviews Rating Details 
 Category: Restaurants Fast Food Fast Food   [Edit] 
 61 North Ave NW 
 Atlanta , GA 30308 
Neighborhood: Midtown
 (404) 881-1706 http://www.thevarsity.com 
 
 Add Photos Nearest Transit Station: 
North Avenue

Civic Center
 Hours: 
Mon-Sun 6:30 am - 10:30 pm
 Good for Groups: Yes
 Accepts Credit Cards: Yes
 Parking: Private Lot
 Attire: Casual
 Price Range: $ 
 Good for Kids: Yes
 Takes Reservations: No
 Delivery: No
 Take-out: Yes
 Waiter Service: No
 Outdoor Seating: Yes
 Wi-Fi: No
 Good For: Lunch, Dinner
 Alcohol: No
 Drive-Thru: Yes
 Noise Level: Loud
 Ambience: Casual
 Has TV: Yes
 Caters: Yes
 Wheelchair Accessible: Yes
 First to Review John L. 
 Edit Business Info Work Here? Unlock This Business Page 
 Send to Friend Bookmark Send to Phone Write a Review 
512 reviews for The Varsity
 Reviews Matching: Search Reviews 
Review Highlights  
 
 &quot;I love the atmosphere and I love their onion rings .&quot; In 189 reviews &quot;The frosted orange was definitely my favorite though.&quot; In 83 reviews &quot;It has a lot of history and the hot dogs are awesome.&quot; In 74 reviews &quot;My favorites were the Onion Rings and the fried Peach Pie .&quot; In 11 reviews &quot;It&apos;s also the World largest drive in restaurant.&quot; In 17 reviews &quot;It&apos;s an institution and amazing to see it in action.&quot; In 49 reviews &quot;...fact that when you order, they&apos;ll ask you, &quot; What&apos;ll ya have.&quot; In 47 reviews &quot;I also enjoy their chili dogs and chili burgers .&quot; In 9 reviews 
 Show more review highlights   Loading... Sort by: Yelp Sort | Date | Rating | Elites&apos; | Facebook Friends&apos; 
Facebook Friends


 
From Reviewers You&apos;re Following 


 
Reviews from Your Friends


 
511 reviews in English

 
Review from Tiffany N. 
 
 20 friends 154 reviews 

 Tiffany N. 
 
West Covina, CA
 7/7/2012 1 Check-in Here 
i am so glad i got to try this place out. it was so packed BUT so worth it! i ordered a slaw dog&amp;a chili cheese dog. omgawhh DELISH. we also got onion rings and chili cheese fries. my mom got a double cheeseburger&amp;a side salad.

everything was really good.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jennifer D. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 10 friends 39 reviews 

 Jennifer D. 
 
Rome, GA
 7/9/2012 1 Check-in Here 
Not much to add that hasn&apos;t been Yelped before, but after a recent stop here, I was forced to admit to myself that the old place just ain&apos;t the same as when I was a kid. Actually, the food and restaurant itself IS exactly the same, so maybe what works for a 12-year-old just doesn&apos;t &quot;pass mustard&quot; with a grown-up. Sorry, I had to. Really, I did.

I ordered the two chili dogs, onion rings, and frosted orange that have comprised my Varisty order forever and ever. One dog really would have been fine, and I&apos;m glad I split the onion rings. Let&apos;s just acknowledge that children have stomachs of steel, and if you really try to eat that much on your own, you&apos;re going to have some Bubblegut about twenty minutes later.

The food *is* delicious - nobody does greasy dogs and onion rings better, and the frosted orange is STILL a revelation. The dogs are simple and perfect - still the best buns I&apos;ve ever tasted, and the chili is the perfect level of spicy without being overbearing. The onion rings are seasoned to perfection, but (and I never thought I&apos;d say this about anything, ever) they&apos;re just too darn greasy for me to rave about the way I used to. They&apos;re meant for sharing, because otherwise you&apos;re better off just asking the folks who work there to cut to the chase and stab you directly in the heart.  The frosted orange is absolutely scrumptious, and unlike anything you can get anywhere else. It&apos;s like a Dreamsicle and orange sherbet and fresh orange juice and a vanilla milkshake had a crazy food orgy, and this is their spawn. It&apos;s a party in a cup, y&apos;all.

So why only three stars? The prices have gone up because the Varsity is increasingly impressed with itself. Our combined three chili dogs, one order of onion rings, small Coke and small frosted orange was over $20. Consider that&apos;s what you pay AFTER waiting in line at least 20 minutes on a non-busy afternoon, and it&apos;s more trouble than it&apos;s worth anymore. Still, if anyone asks me to go back, I&apos;ll always cave!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from David D. 
 
 20 friends 22 reviews 

 David D. 
 
Brooklyn, NY
 7/6/2012 
&quot;What&apos;ll ya have, what&apos;ll ya have?&quot;

Dysentery and the diabeetus.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (2) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Geert G. 
 
 0 friends 5 reviews 

 Geert G. 
 
Geel, Antwerpen
 Belgium 7/10/2012 1 photo 1 Check-in Here 
The biggest drive-in in the world. Pure nostalgia. The chilli dog is good als well als the rings, burgers are realy below average. A step back in time !
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Nikki L. 
 
 1 friend 2 reviews 

 Nikki L. 
 
Atlanta, GA
 7/8/2012 
I love the food!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Austin T. 
 
 0 friends 391 reviews 

 Austin T. 
 
Austin, TX
 Updated - 7/7/2012 
It&apos;s the varsity
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
1 Previous Review:

 6/21/2009 
We&apos;re huge fans of this heart stopping hamburger hot dog joint. It&apos;s a treat not an everyday meal.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Mychael W. 
 
 12 friends 31 reviews 

 Mychael W. 
 
Atlanta, GA
 6/11/2012 
Let me first say that I moved to Atlanta after living in Chicago for 3 years. I was spoiled by the amazing dogs up there, so when I heard that there was a &quot;classic&quot; drive in selling &quot;amazing&quot; hot dogs that I just &quot;had to try&quot; I was excited.  I also saw it on Man Vs Food on Travel Channel, so it was on my list when I moved here.

I ordered 2 chili cheese dogs, onion rings, and a drink.  The onion rings were a little salty, but they had a great flavor.  They were some of the best I&apos;ve ever had actually.  Then came the dogs...  I bit into the average frank with the dark brown, greasy chili sauce and was so disappointed! It tasted exactly like I went to Walmart, bought a pack of Oscar Mayer franks, some Great Value bread, and some Hormel chili, and allowed my 13 year old to make it for me.  Nothing special about the flavor of the dog, nothing appetizing about the look of the chili, and the bun wasn&apos;t too soft.  I have a rule at my house with my children that they must take 2 bites of any new food.  With that, I took my second bite and deposited the remaining 1 1/2 hot dogs in the garbage.

I am also big in giving second chances, unfortunately.  The next time I went I ordered 2 double cheeseburgers.  They were dry, the bread was stale, and I almost didn&apos;t finish them.  The only reason I did was that I had gone with a group of co-workers and didn&apos;t want to be a party pooper.  I will definitely not be back!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ryan D. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 238 friends 111 reviews 

 Ryan D. 
 
Sinking Spring, PA
 6/12/2012 
While in town for a wedding, my family decided to stop in to The Varsity for a quick lunch. The atmosphere is quite electric with all of the noise and commotion all around. The distant &quot;What&apos;ll ya have&quot; screams could be heard all around like a siren&apos;s song.

Okay, enough of the poetic crap, let&apos;s talk about what we are really here for, the FOOD. I ordered the chili cheese dog/chili cheeseburger combo with fries. The chili cheese dog was amazing, the burger not so much. There fries were also subpar at best. They were just limp and barely room temperature.

The onion rings on the other hand, were probably the best onion rings I&apos;ve ever had. If I didn&apos;t live several hundred miles away, I would be visiting The Varsity weekly for the onion rings alone.

Besides the food, the service was acceptable. We got the new guy, who was having trouble with the register and wasn&apos;t comfortable enough to scream their signature catch phrase at us. I understand the pressures of being new, but it was still a little bit of a let down that such a big piece of the puzzle was missing from my experience.

Overall, a great place to visit while in Atlanta, and whenever I&apos;m back in town, I will do my best to visit.

I also wrote about my visit here: http://www.appetiteforin… . A more causal take on The Varsity with pictures I took while visiting and a video of &quot;What&apos;ll ya have&quot; in action.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from love lv f. 
 
 0 friends 38 reviews 

 love lv f. 
 
Henderson, NV
 7/6/2012 
This is an institution I had to experience.
My family grabbed lunch here in between the aquarium and World of Coca Cola.
Big place that takes you back in time. We heard &quot;Whatta you have&quot; and placed our order.
2 chili dogs&amp;onion rings, Slaw dog and onion rings, 2 naked and fries.
The slaw didn&apos;t have much flavor but the hot dog itself did and the bun was ok.
The onion rings however were some of the best I had! Reminded me of the ones I ordered as a kid at the local burger stand.
My dad, who&apos;s favorite fast food is a hot dog, said his was just ok. He grew up on James Coney Island Dogs and swears they are the best.
My one daughter liked hers so much, she ordered a 2nd one.
The place is eclectic with not much change in decor since they probably opened in 1928. cool vibe. My daughters also thought it was very cool to sit in the school desks to eat.
Fun experience, with decent food that you should try when in Atlanta.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Mina B. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 12 friends 57 reviews 

 Mina B. 
 
Arlington, VA
 6/8/2012 1 photo 1 Check-in Here 
Truly a gem. I rarely if ever eat a hot dog so when I do, it&apos;d better be good in some way, shape or form. I don&apos;t know if the ones at the Varsity are actually as good as my all time favorite, a Chicago-style, &quot;dragged through the garden&quot; Vienna beef hot dog, but the Varsity&apos;s are distinctive thanks to the delicious beef chili and mustard topping. That they&apos;re nested in soft, top-cut buns is a huge plus, allowing them to sit nicely on the plate without falling over and everywhere.

I also tried the chili cheeseburger, which was meh by comparison. Really, don&apos;t bother with anything but their dogs. If you&apos;re not into chili, you can get a slaw dog. Definitely score the home-cut fries and onion rings, and gulp them down with a frosted orange. The unsweetened iced tea  (Gasp! I&apos;m one of those heinous people not-from-the-South who&apos;d dare to order such a thing in Atlanta, though I suspect it was at least a Coke product) was icy and strong.

We sat in the ESPN room, which was set up like a classroom--high school desks and all. Too bad they were airing a very boring women&apos;s softball game but I really didn&apos;t care, as I was too involved with the food and people watching, always an amusing enough pursuit.

I don&apos;t understand the haters and criticisms here; the Varsity is a freakin&apos; classic American drive-in--the real deal--are you expecting tofu and quinoa? Personally, I wouldn&apos;t be a regular but I do love its history and that they&apos;re not so over the top with the tourist kitsch one often sees in such &quot;landmarks. Their &quot;gift shop&quot; is so homespun, it may as well be a vendor stand at the ballpark, which seems poignantly fitting. So stay away if your sensibilities are offended by fat, gluten, carbs and cholesterol. Definitely stay away if you&apos;re not a kid or kid-at-heart--you&apos;re missing the point--leave more onion rings for the rest of us.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Robert P. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 3 friends 55 reviews 

 Robert P. 
 
Fulton, GA
 5/26/2012 
Being hyped as the place you have to go to once in Atlanta, and living here 5 years, I decided it was time to go. The layout can be confusing as there are no real lines, simply walk up and order.

We got a few chilli and chilli slaw dogs, rings and their orange drink. Wait time was low and no real problems ordering.

The food was not impressive. I don&apos;t mind &quot;greasy food&quot; if it tastes good. However as other reviewers mentioned it appeared that my food may have been cooked a long time ago. The buns were dry and had a bit of a crust. The flavor of the chilli dogs just didn&apos;t live up. The orange drink, not sure what it is exactly, was tasty.

I have had much better chilli dogs elsewhere in Atlanta, which is sad considering this is the Varsity. I also did not feel well for quite some time after eating here.

Might be fun to check out if you are in Atlanta, but I won&apos;t be going back.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Andrew W. 
 
 10 friends 82 reviews 

 Andrew W. 
 
Arcadia, CA
 5/30/2012 
So I visited the vaunted Varsity while in Atlanta.

There really isn&apos;t much special about this place besides the questionable historic value of the place itself. The food is all greasy and decent, but being from Southern California I judge all fast food places by the In-n-Out measuring stick and The Varsity doesn&apos;t reach very high.

Also, is the chocolate milk here really so special as to merit costing $1.50 for a half-pint carton? I didn&apos;t think so.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jim C. 
 
 8 friends 67 reviews 

 Jim C. 
 
Belmont, NC
 6/10/2012 
It&apos;s just fast food, and it&apos;s kind of... sad that The Varsity is selling itself out as a cultural icon (it was better before there was a a gift shop, if you know what I mean).
Still, I&apos;ll take two chili-cheese dogs, fries or rings, a PC, and a fried apple pie any day of the week! The food&apos;s as good as it ever was, even though I can&apos;t eat it as often as I used to. I age, but The Varsity doesn&apos;t.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Don T. 
 
 8 friends 90 reviews 

 Don T. 
 
Glendora, CA
 6/25/2012 1 photo 
Nice retro decor, but they sell a small burger for a big price.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Brandy L. 
 
 526 friends 252 reviews 

 Brandy L. 
 
Brentwood, CA
 6/30/2012 1 Check-in Here 
What ya have what ya have chile dog pullleeeze&amp;a frosty Orange with a chili dog ! Yum! :) The largest drive thru in the world doesnt disappoint!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Edward M. 
 
 0 friends 4 reviews 

 Edward M. 
 
Alpharetta, GA
 6/27/2012 
This place suck!!!!

No stars!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Walter C. 
 
 1 friend 4 reviews 

 Walter C. 
 
Knoxville, TN
 6/29/2012 1 Check-in Here 
A classic. It&apos;s a greasy spoon type of place.  Don&apos;t expect too much from the food.  Go for the experience and atmosphere.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Kevin W. 
 
 1 friend 1 review 

 Kevin W. 
 
Costa Mesa, CA
 6/18/2012 1 Check-in Here 
Food is okay.  Visibly stale.  Onion rings are different.  Kind of expensive for chili dogs.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Don P. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 2 friends 53 reviews 

 Don P. 
 
Woodstock, GA
 5/6/2012 2 Check-ins Here 
The Varsity is a Legend with a capitol &quot;L&quot; in Atlanta.

The phrase &quot;Whadda ya have, Whadda ya have&quot; is widely recognized and pretty much always brings a smile to folks that recognize it.

The Varsity gets five solid stars for the nostalgia and fond memories it evokes in the tens of thousands of people that have eaten there over the last several decades.

The current three star rating is an average of the past three visits I&apos;ve made to the place. This is the mother ship location downtown, not one of the satellite spots.

Good Health Department score and you always see staff cleaning throughout the place. Floors are constantly being swept and tables wiped. Condiment and napkin stations are replenished often and the restrooms are also kept clean.

Unfortunately, the food is an issue. Well, not if you&apos;re expecting sandwiches with bread so soggy from grease that they literally fall apart as you try to pick them up. Or onion rings served limp and greasy. I&apos;m from the South and like grease as much as the next redneck. In fact, &quot;fried&quot; is it&apos;s own category of food.  The Varsity has always had an unofficial slogan (aka comment said with a smile whenever the Varsity is mentioned) of  &quot;Whadda ya have, Whadda ya have?  Grease burger, please!&quot; And while the burgers, whether a basic chili-cheese or a glorified burger have always been a tad on the greasy side, the most recent visits were above and beyond the normal grease-burger status.

The cleanliness and friendly staff got it two stars and the peach pie and Large F.O. (that&apos;s Frosted Orange to you non-Varsity folks) bumped it to three. Our son attends Georgia Tech, so we have no choice but continue dining at the Varsity occasionally.

Hopefully, my next review of it will be much more positive!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Mike G. 
 
 0 friends 43 reviews 

 Mike G. 
 
Naperville, IL
 5/9/2012 1 Check-in Here 
I went to this place while in town for business.  I had to go, it&apos;s been there for a long, long time.

It&apos;s unique and is a throwback to the old diner days.  The lines moved very, very quickly.

I got the two chili dog special and the orange drink.

The dogs are a popular order it seems and I think mine were wrapped and ready for service two hours before I got to the counter.

Dry, nothing special.  The orange drink is also something not very special.

Overall, after reading the reviews on Yelp before going, I had the right expectations . . .   and the Varsity delivered.

It&apos;s a place to visit and go once for sure, but I can check it off my list of dining places to attend when I go to Atlanta.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ramon L. 
 
 14 friends 16 reviews 

 Ramon L. 
 
Birmingham, AL
 6/19/2012 
Great atmosphere and great tradition. The food is ok at best. Onions rings and signature orange drink are the Best menu items.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Karen N. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 210 friends 236 reviews 

 Karen N. 
 
Houston, TX
 4/24/2012 1 photo 1 Check-in Here 
Ok.  This place is a landmark (and tourist death trap).  I get it.  I&apos;m sure it&apos;s one of those places that your pappy took you to and you&apos;ve ordered the same thing since you were five.  You&apos;ve got fond memories of it.  Once again, I get that.

Well I don&apos;t like it.  I saw it on tv with that blonde haired Fieri who says things like, &quot;that&apos;s all she wrote,&quot; and. &quot;that&apos;s money&quot; and wears loud shirts.  I typically am ok with the places he goes to but i can&apos;t stand him and find myself oddly jealous of him.  When I didn&apos;t stop into the Varsity the last time I was in town, I vowed that I would this time.

I found everything I had to be worse than the food you order at a concession stand at a high school baseball game.  And that&apos;s being nice.  The onion rings were so greasy I only bit into them.  The chili cheese dog... well... the chili.. can you call it chili?  I had high hopes for the slaw dog until the taste came along.  Bland and boring.  Just like the actual hot dog.

The redeemer was the Varsity made orange drink.  I did like that.  One extra star for the orange drank!

So I guess nostalgia?  Don&apos;t hate me, Atlanta.
 
 Listed in: Georgia on My Mind. 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (2) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Tunicia W. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 49 friends 35 reviews 

 Tunicia W. 
 
Atlanta, GA
 5/4/2012 1 Check-in Here 
I&apos;m an Atlanta native, so my feelings for The Varsity have never changed.

I will tell you, there is nothing like the original location on North Avenue. They eventually did spin offs in the burbs and they are about to open one in the Airport, which I think is neat because you should have Atlanta native restuarants there. Just sayin.

Anyhoo, if you cannot stomach grease, don&apos;t come here. Most of the people that wrote negative reviews of The Varsity obviously said they don&apos;t like greasy things. And thats fine, but I don&apos;t understand what you were looking for when you come to a joint that sells chili dogs, onion rings and fried pies. I&apos;m just saying.

Whenever I visit the Varsity, I make certain that I always order a chili dog, onion rings and a frosted orange. Oh sweet baby Jesus that drink....maaaan just order it, you will not be disappointed. I can&apos;t ever eat up the onion rings because they give you a lot in one order.

This place is not for the bougie foodie person, but more for the one that has a Food bucket list for each place they visit. This is one of them.

PS you should order your food carside like the old days, it&apos;s actually still pretty cool.
 
 Listed in: Must eat in the ATL 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Matthew D. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 43 friends 74 reviews 

 Matthew D. 
 
Alpharetta, GA
 4/23/2012 
I am reviewing The Varsity as non-native, current resident of Georgia.  I have lived in seven major cities across the US and each place has it&apos;s landmark/institution/tourist favorite spot and that is what this place is.  If expectations are properly maintained and you enjoy for what it is you will enjoy yourself and check it off your culinary bucket list for the ATL.

Now to fully experience this place three items must be consumed: The chili dog, onion rings and the orange drink.  I suggest pulling into one of the designated spots and having the food brought out to you like the good old days.

The food will not wow you and that really isn&apos;t the point.  You go so you can say you have been and that is it.  Take a picture, move on and eat a salad for dinner.

To Recap:

The Good:  A must stop if you have never been.  Eat in your car and drink in the nostalgia, just don&apos;t spill it on the leather, man.

The Bad:  The food isn&apos;t the point, so if you go expecting to be wowed, you will be let down.

The Band This Restaurant Most Resembles:  Bob Dylan.  A classic even with that voice.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Michael C. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 62 friends 77 reviews 

 Michael C. 
 
Honolulu, HI
 3/28/2012 
The Varsity is one of those places that defy all my logic for what I like in a restaurant in favor of delicious gluttony for stuffing my face with copious amounts of oh-so-tasty, addicting crap for food.

Every time I come here, I feel like a heroin junkie, bug-eyed and drooling with the thought of being able to get my first fix in months.

Now I&apos;ll preface this by saying:

1)  I hate crowds.  I hate crowded restaurants.  I hate long lines.

2)  I hate places crowded by obnoxious Travel Channel tourists crammed together and wandering cluelessly like a herd of zombie cattle packed into a pen, taking pictures of everything in sight.

3)  I hate places where parking is near impossible and I feel like I have to knifefight someone for a space.

4)  I hate low-quality crap for food.

Yet, for some reason I love this place with the kind of love that makes a man fly 5000 miles dreaming of eating five pounds of onion rings.  Every time I even pass through Atlanta, I make it a point to go to The Varsity, and this is not an easy nor convenient thing, living in Honolulu.  I wander around that parking lot, ready to gank someone for a spot to park in.   I get in that damned line and stand there for what seems like half an hour every time, enduring annoying babble and cameras and tourist paraphernalia everywhere.  I shout my order across the counter, then spend the next ten minutes looking for a table just to feed on.

So I have a theory that The Varsity stuffs their food full of crack.  It&apos;s the only reason i can think of as to why I would violate all my rules for picking restaurants to return to over and over and over again.  I feel like a crack ho every time I come here, knowing that I&apos;m going to get smacked around but yet still willing to put up with it, for something that I know is terrible but is oh so good.

You love it, but you hate it at the same time.  It&apos;s a vicious cycle of destruction.

I order six cheeseburgers, four hot dogs of some sort, half of the stuff covered in chili and cheese, pimento this or that, slaw everywhere, and four orders of onion rings, fries, fried pies, frosted orange -- and **then** I let my companion order.  When someone finds me a few hours later passed out in an alleyway with a half-eaten pimento cheeseburger in hand, I know I&apos;ve hit rock bottom.  Delicious, wonderful rock bottom.

Don&apos;t come here expecting a transcendental experience.  Don&apos;t come here expecting high quality burgers and hot dogs.  These things, The Varsity are not.

The Varsity IS a place that draws upon of decades upon decades of great tradition; a tradition of feeding mindless slaw dog zombies like myself, a tradition of calling a craving for squashed-flat pimento cheeseburgers from 1/4 the planet away; a tradition of turning regular people into addicts that - from the moment you pull into the parking lot, all the time you&apos;re standing in line bug eyed and drooling, you wish you had a double-bladed chainsaw mounted on a shotgun just so you could clear the place out quickly for your fix.

P.S. - Best Onion Rings I&apos;ve ever had.  5/5
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny (4) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from kevin t. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 110 friends 203 reviews 

 kevin t. 
 
Amsterdam, Noord-Holland
 Netherlands 4/11/2012 1 Check-in Here 
The Varsity is a must visit for downtown Atlanta. Yes, it is a novelty from the past when fast food was a new thing.   Forget the diet.  Forget the cholesterol.  Forget the fat.  Order up, find a place to consume and enjoy.

Been coming here since I was a kid. My Dad came here when he was a kid.

Forget the hamburgers.   The real deal here are the hotdogs.   Best bet are the chili dogs.  Get a side of finely chopped onions to pile on top.  Pair that with an order of Onion Rings and a Coca-cola...and you are all set.  Not a &quot;fast food&quot; person here, but will relent when it comes to those decadent Onion rings.  They are the best Onion rings in the world.  Like all the other food...they are meant to be eaten right away...hot/warm.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Kirk H. 
 
 0 friends 30 reviews 

 Kirk H. 
 
Frankfort, KY
 5/14/2012 
I have seen some reviews that disparage the Varsity&apos;s chili.  I like the chili!  Meaty and mildly spiced, it complements the dog. I had a chili-slaw dog. Delicious!  The onion rings are good, french fries are usually soggy.  The cheeseburgers are smashed, bun and all, so they don&apos;t look that great.  My teenage daughter had a grilled cheese and loved it.  Highlight of the visit was the fried peach pie.
This location is VERY easily accessed from I-75. Just take exit 249D.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ben V. 
 
 4 friends 41 reviews 

 Ben V. 
 
Alto, MI
 4/9/2012 1 Check-in Here 
I&apos;ve read quite a few of the reviews for this place and they&apos;re all pretty much right. The people who rate it poorly because it&apos;s not quality food are right. It&apos;s not. It&apos;s hotdogs, hamburgers, fries, onion rings, etc.  Since when has any of that stuff been considered &quot;quality?&quot;  You don&apos;t go to a place like The Varsity thinking you&apos;re going to get grass-fed, cage-free, hormone-free, organic food.

So let&apos;s rate this place based on what it is. A very busy half landmark, half tourist stop that serves crappy (as in bad for you) food. Have I ever had a better hotdog? Probably. Fries? Yes. Onion rings? Hmm, maybe not. They were pretty good. The frozen orange drink was delicious and not something that&apos;s readily available other places. My wife also tried the pimento burger and we both thought it was scrumptious (she shared one bite).

What makes this place great is that they bring all of these things together into one place. My favorite hotdog place at home only serves hotdogs and chips.  The Varsity has done a good job at offering a number of options just as quickly.

They seemed to handle the large crowd very efficiently as well. We stopped on a Saturday evening on our way home from spring break. It was quite busy there since a lot of others had the same idea. I only waited in line for 5 minutes and we had no trouble finding a table.

So for how busy they are, the type of food they&apos;re serving and how it tasted? I give them 4 stars.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Megan W. 
 
 9 friends 49 reviews 

 Megan W. 
 
Richmond, VA
 5/8/2012 
Their burgers are flat and may not look that appealing, but they do taste good as far as burgers go.  Also their food is very greasy.

The atmosphere is awesome.  It&apos;s like eating at a 50&apos;s diner.  This place is a legend in Atlanta.  If you&apos;re ever in town, you should at least stop by and check this place out.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Josh A. 
 
 90 friends 488 reviews 

 Josh A. 
 
Goose Creek, SC
 5/23/2012 1 Check-in Here 
Chocolate shake was amazing.  Had the Heavy Dog, paid for it later.  It was good for the time being though!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jules S. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 598 friends 380 reviews 

 Jules S. 
 
Haleiwa, HI
 4/30/2012 1 photo 3 Check-ins Here 
Just OK food. It&apos;s a must go for a first timer to A-town though. Glad I went and finally experienced The Varsity. Service is kinda in your face at times but it&apos;s part of the experience at The Varsity. Oh, you can skip the Varsity Orange, too. I love orange soda...the V.O. is nothing special.  Just get a Coke and a chili dog.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (7) Funny (4) Cool (5) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Hot Tub J. 
 
 9 friends 29 reviews 

 Hot Tub J. 
 
Dallas, TX
 6/1/2012 
Lookit, anyone selling a quarter of a million hot dogs an hour may have a cold dog or 3 sitting in the window, OK? Just ask for some HOT fries, rings or dogs when ya order from the little old biddy hens cackling &quot;whaddle Ya Have?&quot; When you get close to their register. I get it and hope you do too! Go Varsity!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Irwin F. 
 
 1 friend 31 reviews 

 Irwin F. 
 
Winchester, MA
 3/9/2012 
I&apos;m a sucker for places I see on the Food Network or Travel Channel, so I had to experience The Varsity first hand.  It has a really cool atmosphere and the staff is very friendly.

Overall, the food is OK.  I mean, it&apos;s basically fast food burgers and hot dogs.  The onion rings were absolutely fantastic though.

Definitely a place to visit if you&apos;re in the neighborhood (just make sure to lock your car).
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Daniel C. 
 
 1 friend 34 reviews 

 Daniel C. 
 
Concord, CA
 4/7/2012 
A fun place to grab some quick eats if you don&apos;t mind the grease.  There was a crowd inside at 230pm with no clear lines in sight.  I asked a police officer standing guard where to line up and he said anywhere sir.  Lucky I found a sign that said express line along the wall.   5 mins later I walked out with a chili dig, chili burger, onion rings, and the Varsity orange koolaid.  Rings were awesome and crispy - much bigger than I expected.  Didn&apos;t care too much for the burger and the chili dog was OK.

Worth going at least once for the experience.  Sort of like waiting at 3am for dogs at Pinks in L.A.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Terry J. 
 
 10 friends 105 reviews 

 Terry J. 
 
Reston, VA
 3/1/2012 1 Check-in Here 
Chili slaw dog, rings, fries and an FO.

Need I say more?

As of the folks from Chicago, or Detroit, or NYC who don&apos;t get it:  well you don&apos;t get it.  We don&apos;t get some of your ^%$# either.

As for me - If I am in Atlanta I am making a trip to the Varsity.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Richard R. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 256 friends 224 reviews 

 Richard R. 
 
Dacula, GA
 1/5/2012 
Let&apos;s be honest here... the Varsity has terrible food that I&apos;m not sure is food at all.

Every out of town guest that comes to my home wants to go to the Varsity and some are even weird enough to actually like it!!! I think the real appeal for many of the regulars may be the memories of college days gone by, hanging out during and after games and fun childhood experiences. There is really something to be said about how a place makes you feel, because it can stick with you for a lifetime.

My favorite part of coming to the Varsity is watching first timers reaction to what they HEARD was great food... LOL!!! The facial expression of most people after taking one bite would be part of my highlight reel for life&apos;s funniest moments.  I know it may sound wrong, but I enjoy coming just to talk about how bad it is. There is always some Superfan there trapped in their own I LOVE THE VARSITY commercial. Not once have I been to the Varsity and failed to meet someone who has been coming there for 20 or more years faithfully. It really does have a Cult following.

I can honestly say I am fond of a place where I think the food is aweful. Get the frosted orange drink for sure, the onion rings to help speed up any triple bypass surgeries in your future and add chilli to whatever meat you get for a wonderful experience guessing if it is actually beef or something else!!! I don&apos;t know if  I will ever like the food, but I sure do enjoy the experience.
 
 Listed in: 38 THINGS TO DO WITH YOUR KIDS… 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (4) Funny (15) Cool (4) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from David O. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 34 friends 561 reviews 

 David O. 
 
Nashville, TN
 3/3/2012 1 Check-in Here 
If you&apos;ve been around since 1928, I guess you have the right to be a greasy spoon.

The place was really hopping, clearly gaining popularity from its reputation.

Service is speedy, even with the enormous number of people there.

In the end, don&apos;t stop in for the food. (Though the Onion Rings /are/ delicious) Stopping in is an experience worth having.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Lura M. 
 
 3 friends 40 reviews 

 Lura M. 
 
Atlanta, GA
 5/18/2012 
I have lived in Atlanta for 4 years and finally got around to going to the Varsity! I first heard about this restaurant on Man VS. Food. I conveniently rode the Marta train down to the North Ave Station, and easily walked the 2 blocks over. The parking lots was beyond full on a Monday Lunch rush! There are lots of options to choose from; I picked the cheese dogs and onion rings with an orange drink. The coolest part of this restaurant is that there are several rooms to pick a seat in. I picked the room with school desks and the big screen TV to watch ESPN! The onion rings were crisp and the orange drink was extra fresh. If you are in the area, it is definitely must visit!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Marc F. 
 
 5 friends 27 reviews 

 Marc F. 
 
Auburn, AL
 1/29/2012 1 Check-in Here 
I&apos;m not really sure what the hype is about this place.

The food is extremely unhealthy and that not exciting or even high quality.  The building makes up for some of the weaknesses in the food.  And every time I&apos;ve been here, all of the employees&apos; &quot;What&apos;ll yah have?&quot; has been as enthusiastic as a man asking for a prostate exam.

All in all, I guess this place is a landmark, not much more can be said.  Might as well stop by once.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ray O. 
 
 1 friend 31 reviews 

 Ray O. 
 
Los Angeles, CA
 1/6/2012 
Does The Varsity serve gourmet cuisine?  Absolutely not.  Does The Varsity cloak itself in pretentious decor?  Absolutely not.  Does The Varsity pander to the ultra-organic, macrobiotic, I&apos;m-too-cool-to-eat-anything-that-hasn&apos;t-been-­approved-by-my-food-sensitivity-coach crowd?  Absolutely not.  What you see is what you get at The Varsity.  It&apos;s an Atlanta landmark with high-calorie, low-nutritional value food that tastes great, costs little, and gets served with a smile.  Would you rather have that or some haughty, overpriced brasserie where everyone has a stick up her/his ass?

&quot;What&apos;ll Ya Have?&quot;
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (6) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
 Read more reviews for this business: German (1) 1 to 40 of 511 ( 53 Filtered )

 |   
 Page: 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 ... 
 Write a Review View Larger Map/Directions 
Browse Nearby:
 
 Restaurants | Nightlife | Shopping | Movies | All 
 
Deals Nearby
 
 $10 for $20 Deal Broadway Cafe Atlanta, GA $25 for $30 Deal Mamma Mia Pizzeria Atlanta, GA 
 
People Who Viewed This Also Viewed...
 
 The Vortex Bar&amp;Grill  489 reviews &quot;I love their burgers and sweet potato fries.&quot; The Varsity  18 reviews &quot;You must eat here if you enter the Atlanta city limits.&quot; Gladys Knight&apos;s Signature Chicken&amp;Waffles  416 reviews &quot;My favorite dish is&quot;Midnight Train&amp;Fried Corn.&quot; Fat Matt&apos;s Rib Shack  556 reviews &quot;Their rum baked beans are also delicious.&quot; World of Coca Cola  340 reviews &quot;You can try Coca Cola products from around the world.&quot; 
 
Related Lists
 More» 
 I&apos;m gaining weight just reading… 
When I get hungry now, instead of eating- I just read these reviews!
 Burgers, Baby! 
Delicious Atlanta hamburgers, bacon burgers, cheese burgers and everything in between.
 Best Classic Cheeseburger (not… 
Best place to get a classic meat and cheese cheeseburger, the kind you order at the walk-up counter, typically…
 ATL Fast Food 
I reviewed more fast food chains than I thought.  Chick-fil-A and McDonald&apos;s are my favorites.  When I&apos;m…
 Dining in the ATL 
Who doesn&apos;t love going out for dinner?! Here are places I&apos;ve been to in and around the city.
 TV Shows (ATL) 
Places to eat recommended by shows like &quot;Man vs Food&quot;, &quot;Food Paradise&quot;, etc.
 Must eat in the ATL 
Seeing as that I am one of the 5 people still living here that were born and raised here, I am always asked…
 Eating for One 
Places that are friendly for people eating alone!  Getting a table for one is depressing, so these are great…
 
 
People Viewed This After Searching For...
 
 Varsity Drive In Of Ga Atlanta Hot Dogs Atlanta Diners Drive Ins And Dives Atlanta 
 
About

 About Yelp Yelp Blog Press Investor Relations Terms of Service Privacy Policy 
 
Help

 FAQ Advertise Content Guidelines Contact Yelp Business Support Developers 
 
More

 Careers Yelp Mobile The Weekly Yelp Yelp Apparel RSS Top Searches 
 
Countries

 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany 

 Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom 
 
Language

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 
 
 Atlanta Business Listings # A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z | Newly Added | Talk Archive 

 Site Map | Atlanta | Austin | Boston | Chicago | Dallas | Denver | Detroit | Honolulu | Houston | Los Angeles | Miami | Minneapolis | New York | Philadelphia | Portland | Sacramento | San Diego | San Francisco | San Jose | Seattle | Washington, DC | More Cities 

Copyright©2004-2012 Yelp Inc. Yelp logo and related marks are registered trademarks of Yelp. All rights reserved.
 
 Email Address Step 1 of 2 Zip Code 
 
Hey , you can use Facebook to make signing up for Yelp even faster . Yes, use Facebook to sign up 
 Already have an account? Log In Now 
 Email Address Password Zip Code Birthdate (Optional) --- Jan Feb Mar Apr May Jun Jul Aug Sep Oct Nov Dec --- 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 --- 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 2000 1999 1998 1997 1996 1995 1994 1993 1992 1991 1990 1989 1988 1987 1986 1985 1984 1983 1982 1981 1980 1979 1978 1977 1976 1975 1974 1973 1972 1971 1970 1969 1968 1967 1966 1965 1964 1963 1962 1961 1960 1959 1958 1957 1956 1955 1954 1953 1952 1951 1950 1949 1948 1947 1946 1945 1944 1943 1942 1941 1940 1939 1938 1937 1936 1935 1934 1933 1932 1931 1930 1929 1928 1927 1926 1925 1924 1923 1922 1921 1920 1919 1918 1917 1916 1915 1914 1913 1912 1911 1910 1909 1908 1907 1906 1905 1904 1903 1902 1901 Country 
 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom United States 
 
 United States Change 
 
By clicking the button below, you agree to the Yelp Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .
 
 
 Cancel Sign Up 
 
 Use Facebook to sign up faster! 
 Already have an account? Log In Now 
 First Name Last Name Email Address Password City / Town: Zip Code Birthdate (Optional) --- Jan Feb Mar Apr May Jun Jul Aug Sep Oct Nov Dec --- 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 --- 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 2000 1999 1998 1997 1996 1995 1994 1993 1992 1991 1990 1989 1988 1987 1986 1985 1984 1983 1982 1981 1980 1979 1978 1977 1976 1975 1974 1973 1972 1971 1970 1969 1968 1967 1966 1965 1964 1963 1962 1961 1960 1959 1958 1957 1956 1955 1954 1953 1952 1951 1950 1949 1948 1947 1946 1945 1944 1943 1942 1941 1940 1939 1938 1937 1936 1935 1934 1933 1932 1931 1930 1929 1928 1927 1926 1925 1924 1923 1922 1921 1920 1919 1918 1917 1916 1915 1914 1913 1912 1911 1910 1909 1908 1907 1906 1905 1904 1903 1902 1901 Gender (Optional) Male Female Country 
 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom United States 
 
 United States Change 
 
By clicking the button below, you agree to the Yelp Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .
 
 
 Cancel Sign Up 
 No account yet? Create an Account 
 Email Password 
 
 Cancel Log In 
 
Add a Profile Picture

More people will read your reviews and you will be one step closer to the Yelp Elite Squad if you have a profile picture.
 Import Facebook Photo You don&apos;t have Flash installed, Facebook Connect requires the latest version of Flash
	</body>
</document>
