<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002839" url="http://www.stltoday.com/news/local/metro/recent-st-louis-county-job-cut-goes-against-a-two/article_ece0430b-cbf8-5baa-ae52-e4936cbacde5.html" time="2012-07-12-18:54" support="1" score="0.005905809298774881" bingtitle="Recent St. Louis County job cut goes against a two-decade trend of ..." webtitle="Recent St. Louis County job cut goes against a two-decade trend of adding jobs">
			<query id="001411" bing-rank="250"/>
	<description>He said major changes in ... dead in Franklin County trailer; Missouri House takes another swing at workers&apos; comp effort; Charges filed in death of man at St. Louis fast-food ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Today&apos;s Post-Dispatch Suburban Journals St. Louis&apos; Best Bridal STLHighschoolsports Ladue News Feast ShopSTL Mobile 

 Login | Register | Subscriber Services 
 weather 
 Search 
 
 Search Stories Search Web Search Classifieds Search Local Directory 
 
 Recent St. Louis County job cut goes against a two-decade trend of adding jobs 
 
 Home 
 Weather Obits Opinion Columns Traffic Lottery Multimedia Newsletters Apps Contests Archives Photo Reprints Chats E-Edition 
 News 
 Opinion Blogs Metro Illinois St. Charles Obits Nation Politics Crime Education Religion Galleries Videos Databases Forums 
 Business 
 Stock quotes St. Louis stocks Calendar Press releases Blogs Public Salaries Galleries Twitter 
 Sports 
 Cards Rams Blues Mizzou Illini SLU High School Golf Racing More sports Blogs Forums Galleries Videos Chats Timelines 
 Entertainment 
 Calendar Music Dining Movies Movie Times TV Arts Books Celebs Comics/Games Horoscopes Blogs Forums 
 Health 
 Live Well Golden Age Health Services Directory Health Calendar Medical Ads 
 Life&amp;Style 
 Food Feast Magazine Home&amp;Garden Health&amp;Fitness Fashion Travel Pets Moms and Dads Blogs Galleries Videos St. Louis&apos; Best Bridal 
 Suburban News 
 AFFTON CHESTERFIELD COLLINSVILLE EDWARDSVILLE GRANITE CITY O&apos;FALLON MO ST. CHARLES ST. PETERS WILDWOOD MORE TOWNS... BLOGGER NETWORK 
 Classifieds 
 Business Opportunities Notices Travel Tickets/Events Pets Estate Sales Garage/Yard Sales Bargain Box Merchandise Place an Ad 
 Find n Save 
 Get It Local Directory Coupons Newspaper Ads Circulars Special Sections P-D Store Today&apos;s Deal Today&apos;s Deal Blog 
 Homes 
 Place an Ad Search Homes Mortgage Guide Agent Directory Your Next Home New Home Folio What Did It Sell For 
 Autos 
 New Used Certified Research Services Dealer Specials Reviews 
 Jobs 
 Salary Wizard Cost of Living Wizard Post a Resume Search Jobs Employers Post a Job Work at the P-D or SJ 
 
 HOT TOPICS 
 ESPY AWARDS $500 GAS GIVEAWAY ALL-STAR CARDINALS WASHINGTON AVE. STL SPORTS TOP 10 JUNE&apos;S MUG SHOTS OLYMPICS 
 
 CLICK TO ENTER: Only 2 days left! Enter for your chance to win a $50, $250 or $500 gift card from QT 
 Home /  News /  Local /  Metro 
Recent St. Louis County job cut goes against a two-decade trend of adding jobs
 Share | 
 Story Discussion Image (2) 
 Recent St. Louis County job cut goes against a two-decade trend of adding jobs 
 BY PAUL HAMPEL • phampel@post-dispatch.com &gt; 314-727-6234 stltoday.com |Posted: Sunday, March 4, 2012 12:05 am | ( Loading… ) comments. 
 Font Size: Default font size Larger font size 

 Loading… 
 
 
Related Stories

 Related: Budget cuts trim 26 jobs in St. Louis County Related: After difficult prelude, St. Louis County Council approves budget 
 
 CLAYTON • The layoff of 27 St. Louis County government employees in January caused consternation among county officials, particularly County Council members. But the firings bucked a trend of a steady rise in county jobs over the last two decades.

Since 1990, the county has added 455 jobs.

Meanwhile, the population of the unincorporated area of the county in that period has dropped to 319,698 from 382,543. St. Louis County government is the prime provider of services in the incorporated area. (The overall population of St. Louis County was nearly unchanged in that period — 993,508 in 1990 and 998,954 now.)

Meanwhile, the private sector has in many cases reduced work forces because of computer-driven increases in productivity.

County officials assert that there are good reasons for an increased workforce.

Of the 455 new jobs, 384 have gone to the county Police Department. It has 1,051 slots now, up from 667 in 1990. Overall, the county has 4,301 jobs, up from 3,846 in 1990.

Of the police hires, about 230 were to fill the county&apos;s growing list of municipal contracts. The county has 71 service agreements with area municipalities, which pick up the tab for the salaries and benefits of county officers and other staff who perform such jobs as routine patrols and filing crime reports.

&quot;We are able, in most cases, to offer a relative bargain to municipalities,&quot; County Police Chief Tim Fitch said in a recent interview.

And he said he expects the department to soon sign up a few more municipalities.

&quot;We know there is some pent-up demand for our services,&quot; Fitch said. &quot;I think that, after the April elections, you&apos;ll see more municipalities moving toward contracting with us for law enforcement.&quot;

Fitch declined to identify the potential clients. &quot;Let&apos;s just say that we&apos;ve got about six (municipalities) in the bullpen right now, warming up,&quot; he said.

The county offers what Fitch calls a &quot;cafeteria style&quot; selection of services that range from filing reports, which it does for Ballwin and Clayton, to handling all patrols and administrative work, which it performs for such cities as Fenton, Wildwood, Jennings and the villages of Hanley Hills and Twin Oaks.

Fitch said his department can save municipalities money in part because it buys equipment in bulk and already has supervisors and administrative staff in place.

Fenton began contracting with the county in 1995. Mayor Dennis Hancock estimates that the city&apos;s deal with the county saves the municipality more than $500,000 a year.

&quot;Essentially, it&apos;s the same as having our own police force,&quot; Hancock said. &quot;The county department is very well organized and professional. And this setup gives us the flexibility that, if an officer doesn&apos;t work out for whatever reason — not necessarily a bad officer, but maybe just a bad fit — it&apos;s the county&apos;s problem to deal with it, not ours.&quot;

But the municipal contracts do not explain about 150 additional county police jobs since 1990.

Those 150 officers and civilian staff receive an estimated $67,416 a year in pay and benefits — costs borne by county taxpayers. About 70 of those employees are police officers whose hiring had at one time been funded by various federal grants. When the grants ran out, typically after three years, the county kept the officers on the force.

Fitch, who joined the department in 1983 and became its chief in 2009, said hanging on to those hires helped the county bring its ratio of officers-to-residents in line with the national average of about two for every 1,000.

By comparison, the city of St. Louis has 1,401 officers and 319,294 residents, or 4.4 officers for every thousand residents.

(Looking at the last two decades, city of St. Louis employment peaked in 2000, with more than 7,800 employees. As the economy dipped, the city shed jobs — about one of every eight. This fiscal year, the city has just over 6,800 in its budget. Comparisons of city and county employment numbers are difficult, because the county total does not include government employees of county municipalities.)

DROP IN CRIME RATE

Fitch credits extra cops on the street for the drop in the county&apos;s rate of violent crimes to 25.7 for every 1,000 residents last year from 36.9 for every 1,000 in 1990.

&quot;One of the biggest complaints we heard when I started on this force was that people never saw the police out in their neighborhoods,&quot; Fitch said. &quot;And it&apos;s an established fact that with more police officers, you have a higher incarceration rate and lower violent crime.&quot;

Apart from the police hires, other county departments have added 71 new jobs since 1990.

The county&apos;s director of operations, Garry Earls, said that a drop in the county&apos;s unincorporated population and the rise in productivity due to computer and Internet advances do not translate into a reciprocal drop in the number of county employees.

&quot;Only about 20 percent of our workforce is dedicated to providing unincorporated services,&quot; Earls said. &quot;Most of what we offer are countywide services — everything from the police department, to the courts, to revenue to the dog folks.&quot;

Earls said most of those new positions went to the county Justice Center, which houses the jail and the circuit court.

&quot;Those areas have both gotten much busier for us over the years,&quot; he said. &quot;When the jail opened (in 1998), it had 800 prisoners. It now has 1,200. And with more prisoners you need more staff.&quot;

He said major changes in records requirements for the courts system have resulted in increased employment there.

&quot;Family courts have also changed dramatically,&quot; he said. &quot;We used to just lock kids up. Today, we serve about eight times as many kids as we did in 1990, but in what you might call an outpatient basis, which requires additional juvenile officers.&quot;

Earls said that technology has increased demand for services even as it has enhanced efficiency.

&quot;Many of those advances have not reduced requirements for staff but rather increased them because of the expectations of the public,&quot; he said. &quot;For example, in 1990, if you wanted real estate information you had to find someone and have them do that search. Today, you can do it yourself online.

&quot;But somebody&apos;s got to load that data and keep it current. Technology has allowed us to expand our mission but not to cut employees.&quot;

David Hunn of the Post-Dispatch contributed to this report.
 
 Copyright 2012 stltoday.com. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 
Posted in Metro , Govt-and-politics on Sunday, March 4, 2012 12:05 am Updated: 2:37 pm. | Tags: St. Louis County , Bill Fitch , Garry Earls , Paul Hampel ,
 
 Print Email 
 
Sponsored Links
 
top stories

 Drought deepens across St. Louis area Teen girls accused of beating disabled Missouri man, posting video on Facebook St. Louis man charged with robbery of Florissant Salvation Army worker St. Louis city and county police investigate rash of morning store break-ins 2 men found fatally shot in one St. Louis block hours apart Report: Penn State officials concealed sex abuse A-B InBev selling $7.5 billion in bonds for Grupo Modelo purchase Commerce&apos;s 2Q profit up more than 7 percent 
 
most popular
 
 Facebook Most Read 
 
 Canadian chef Anthony Sedlak dies at age 29 Setting the record straight: Top 10 moments in St. Louis sports history St. Louis woman sentenced for performing sex acts on dog Trade talk surrounds San Diego closer Street 2 suspects still at large after St. Louis police kill man during home invasion Tony&apos;s twists keep Cards&apos; All-Stars on their toes Votto wants Cards, Reds to &apos;turn the page&apos; Woman from St. Louis area electrocuted while swimming at Lake of the Ozarks Gordon: One glaring need holds back Cardinals Young couple buys landmark Stuart Castle in Eureka Couple killed in motorcycle crash in St. Louis County identified Bernie Bytes: Cardinals midseason awards Will success kill Washington Avenue? 
 

 St. Louis Coupons: Get fantastic deals—up to 80% off—sent to your e-mail.
 Sign up today! PPG Porter Paints® Stores - Only $30 for $60 towards PPG Porter paints, stains, primers,&amp;more at PPG Porter Paints® Stores! 
 DEALS, OFFERS AND EVENTS 
 
 Want beautiful nails? 

Call today for special price on full set.
 
 Webkinz Pet of The Month! 

July Webkinz pet of the month: Puckerfish.
2404 Highway 94 So…
 
 New Dog Agility Classes Starting August 6th 

6 week Intro-to-Agility classes starting Monday August 6th at 8:00pm
 
 15% off new first time customers 


 
 Want to throw your computer out of the window? 

DON&apos;T !!
 
Sections

 Home Page News Obituaries Business Sports Entertainment Health Life&amp;Style Photos Jobs Autos Homes Directory Classifieds 
 
Services

 Subscriber Services Advertise on Our Site Email Newsletters RSS E-Edition Mobile Site Events Calendar Newspapers in Education Archives Contact Us Terms of Service Privacy / About Our Ads Copyright Corrections 
 
 St. Louis Apartments St. Louis Attorneys St. Louis Auto Dealers St. Louis Auto Parts St. Louis Auto Repair St. Louis Beauty Salons St. Louis Car Rental St. Louis Dentists St. Louis Doctors St. Louis Flowers St. Louis Hotels St. Louis Insurance St. Louis Loans St. Louis Mortgages St. Louis Movers St. Louis Pizza St. Louis Realtors St. Louis Restaurants St. Louis Storage St. Louis Tax Preparation St. Louis Travel Featured More... 
 
Marketplace

 Local Directory The List Classifieds Jobs Rides STL Homes ShopSTL Newspaper Ads STL Coupons DineSTL Post-Dispatch Store STLshopper St. Louis&apos; Best Bridal 
 
STLtoday Network

 St. Louis Post-Dispatch Suburban Journals Ladue News St. Louis&apos; Best Bridal Feast Go! STL Health and Fitness STL Moms and Dads STL High School Sports MySTLtoday.com 
 
©Copyright 2012, stltoday.com , 900 N. Tucker Blvd. St. Louis, MO | Terms of Service and Privacy Policy
	</body>
</document>
