<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002547" url="http://www.freesamplesite.com/ydf/showthread.php/195365-test-tube-make-up/page5" time="2012-07-12-18:36" support="1" score="0.0014964748280716976" bingtitle="test tube make up??? - Page 5 - Welcome to Your Daily Freebies ..." webtitle="test tube make up??? - Page 5">
			<query id="001272" bing-rank="55"/>
	<description>... the forum that you want to visit from the selection ... But it is bad business to charge your credit card way ... Fast Food &amp; Restaurant Coupons; Drug Store &amp; Pharmacy Coupons</description>
	<body>
		Register Help Remember Me? 
 
 Home Forum 
 FAQ Calendar Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 

 
 Blogs What&apos;s New? 
 
 Advanced Search 
 
 Forum YDF Freebies - Discounts - Deals Freebies - Discounts - Deals test tube make up??? 
 
 If this is your first visit, be sure to
 check out the FAQ by clicking the
 link above. You may have to register before you can post: click the register link above to proceed. To start viewing messages,
 select the forum that you want to visit from the selection below. 
 + Reply to Thread Page 5 of 16 First 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 15 ... Last 
 Jump to page: 
 Results 41 to 50 of 156 
Thread: test tube make up??? 
 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Search Thread 
 
   Advanced Search 
 
 
 02-06-2007,  06:51 PM #41 Jakibro 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Dec 2006 Location FL Posts 1,578 
received#2,missed one
 Received it,it&apos;s great, great samples , some full size.Once you give your credit card info they will bill you before they send out automatically...I can&apos;t wait for the next one Reply With Quote 02-07-2007,  03:35 PM #42 lovemyfreebies 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Aug 2006 Posts 452 Everyone who is still getting these, do you still feel it&apos;s a great deal? Before I sign up I just want to be sure that the quality/quantity is still good after a few shipments. Thanks! Reply With Quote 02-07-2007,  05:05 PM #43 zoemama 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 1/2007 Join Date Sep 2005 Posts 944 anybody notice they raised the price? Wasn&apos;t it $25 before plus shipping? Reply With Quote 02-17-2007,  09:49 AM #44 APunkAdicts 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Dec 2006 Location Kyle, Texas Posts 1,463 The price did go up.

I signed up for it, they took my nearly $40 for it, and then they sent me an e-mail saying it would be at least 4 - 6 weeks before it will be shipped.

I just e-mailed them back and asked for a refund. I would think the products are worth the money, BUT I don&apos;t think it is right for them to take my money up to 6 weeks before they are even going to ship it.

Anyone else think that is unfair or am I wrong? I shop online all the time and if things are backordered, I don&apos;t get charged until it is shipped. Reply With Quote 02-17-2007,  10:39 AM #45 vegasmom04 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Feb 2007 Posts 1,546 I agree with you on them charging and then it taking long to ship. Fortunately I am a pretty patient person as I had ordered my test tube back on January 21 and when I called the second time which was this week to say I still hadn&apos;t received it yet, the girl in customer service said they have such a huge backlog and it should ship finally next week. I have heard so many good things about this program which is why I am anxious to receive it Reply With Quote 02-17-2007,  11:38 AM #46 DocsWife 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Dec 2001 Location Maryland Posts 895 Originally Posted by APunkAdicts The price did go up.

I signed up for it, they took my nearly $40 for it, and then they sent me an e-mail saying it would be at least 4 - 6 weeks before it will be shipped.

I just e-mailed them back and asked for a refund. I would think the products are worth the money, BUT I don&apos;t think it is right for them to take my money up to 6 weeks before they are even going to ship it.

Anyone else think that is unfair or am I wrong? I shop online all the time and if things are backordered, I don&apos;t get charged until it is shipped. I wonder, will the price go up for the individuals that signed up the original offer? anybody know? Reply With Quote 02-17-2007,  01:12 PM #47 misslilly 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 chat Join Date May 2006 Location Blue Ridge Mtns&amp;Ca Posts 2,365 i agree, they should not charge you , until it is shipped. Reply With Quote 02-23-2007,  02:25 PM #48 jcluc 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Sep 2003 Location Lafayette, IN Posts 147 
new tube listed:)
 Just looked at the site and there are new products listed for those enrolled in the program...

 http://www.newbeauty.com/testtube.aspx 

Just called them and they said they expect to ship in April or May... I was hoping for earlier... Last edited by jcluc; 02-23-2007 at 02:38 PM . Reason: more info Reply With Quote 02-23-2007,  02:32 PM #49 Mom2M&amp;A 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Oct 2006 Posts 31 I also ordered mine back in January and my credit card was charged and I still haven&apos;t received anything. I emailed them twice and called once, but no one returned my messages. I was getting ready to file a dispute with my credit card company when I saw the other threads. I will give them another week or so. But it is bad business to charge your credit card way before an item ships! My credit card was charged over a month ago!!! I hope they get their stuff organized over there, because this really does sounf like a fun program. Reply With Quote 02-23-2007,  03:42 PM #50 anneinsand 
 View Profile View Forum Posts View Blog Entries View Articles 
 Registered User Join Date Oct 2006 Posts 6 Hey everyone,
I signed up for the test tube back in January as well and didn&apos;t receive anything. But then on February 9th I received this email:

Thank you for your recent TestTube order. Due to the overwhelming order response, we are currently experiencing a backlog of orders and expect to be sending your TestTube within the next four to six weeks. Because of this delay, we have included a special gift certificate valued at $25 on purchases of $50 or more for ANY product you would like to purchase through spaLook.com.

it goes on to give me my code and tells me that when they ship it they will send me my fedex tracking number.

Maybe everyone that is missing their tube got this and it went into spam? I am anxiously awaiting mine!! Reply With Quote
	</body>
</document>
