<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002476" url="http://www.ciao.co.uk/sr/q-restaurants+dundee" time="2012-07-12-18:32" support="4" score="0.005334197961617817" bingtitle="Restaurants Dundee - Prices, Offers &amp; Tests of Restaurants Dundee" webtitle="Restaurants Dundee - Prices, Offers&amp;Tests of Restaurants Dundee">
			<query id="000572" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000769" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001334" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="000518" bing-rank="131"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant, Take-away - Address: 157 Dundee Street, ... more</description>
	<body>
		Join Ciao | Login | Help | Mobile 
 
 Browse by category 
 Appliances 

 Books 

 Cameras 

 Cars 

 Computers 

 Electronics 

 DVDs 

 Music 

 Phones 

 Travel 

 More 
 
Ciao - for people with opinions

 
 Latest reviews Write a review 
 
 Latest questions Latest videos 
 
 
 
 ALL RESULTS Shopping Offers Reviews FILTER BY CATEGORY 
 Travel (20) 
 Europe (20) 
 United Kingdom (19) 
 Edinburgh (13) 
 Edinburgh Restaurants (13) 
 Other Destinations in United Kingdom (6) 
 United Kingdom Restaurants (6) 
 
 Ireland (1) 
 Other Destinations in Ireland (1) 
 Ireland Restaurants (1) 
 
 
 
 
 ALL RESULTS &gt; Shopping &gt; Results for &quot;Restaurants Dundee&quot; 
Shopping»
 
 
 Results on ciao.co.uk Results in online shops Special Offers 
 

 1 - 20 of 20 results for &quot;Restaurants Dundee&quot; sort by: Popularity | Price | Rating | Date 
 
 
 Hungry Horse Restaurant , The Marmalade Pot, Dundee 
British Restaurant (On Ciao since: 08/2004)


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (4) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Other Destinations in United Kingdom &gt; United Kingdom Restaurants 
 
 Nosey Parkers Restaurant &amp;Bistro, Dundee 
 Restaurant (On Ciao since: 02/2012)


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (1) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Other Destinations in United Kingdom &gt; United Kingdom Restaurants 
 
 Rancho Pancho Wellbank, Dundee 
Mexican Restaurant (On Ciao since: 02/2012)


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (2) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Other Destinations in United Kingdom &gt; United Kingdom Restaurants 
 
 Burger King, Kingstown, Dundee 
Fast Food Restaurant (On Ciao since: 12/2000)


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (1) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Other Destinations in United Kingdom &gt; United Kingdom Restaurants 
 
 Da Vinci, Dundee 
Pizzeria (On Ciao since: 10/2005)


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (1) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Other Destinations in United Kingdom &gt; United Kingdom Restaurants 
 
 Marble Slab Creamery, Dundee 
Ice-Cream Parlour (On Ciao since: 09/2010)


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Other Destinations in United Kingdom &gt; United Kingdom Restaurants 
 
 Quick Bite Diner, Lifford 
 
 Restaurant - Address: St Johnston, Dundee , Lifford (On Ciao ... more 
 Restaurant - Address: St Johnston, Dundee , Lifford (On Ciao since: 04/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; Ireland &gt; Other Destinations in Ireland &gt; Ireland Restaurants 
 
 Guru Balti Restaurant , 9 Dundee Street, Edinburgh 
 
Indian Restaurant - Address: 9 Dundee Street, Edinburgh EH11 ... more 
 Indian Restaurant - Address: 9 Dundee Street, Edinburgh EH11 1DL (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Edinburgh &gt; Edinburgh Restaurants 
 
 Pizza Hut, 130 Dundee Street, Edinburgh 
 
Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: 130 Dundee Street, ... more 
 Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: 130 Dundee Street, Edinburgh EH11 1AF (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Edinburgh &gt; Edinburgh Restaurants 
 
 Pizza Hut, 2 Dundee Street, Edinburgh 
 
Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: 2 Dundee Street, ... more 
 Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: 2 Dundee Street, Edinburgh EH11 1AF (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Edinburgh &gt; Edinburgh Restaurants 
 
 O&apos;Briens Irish Sandwich Bar Dundee , Edinburgh 
 
Sandwich Bar - Address: 78 Cowgate, Edinburgh EH2 2LR (On Ciao since: ... more 
 Sandwich Bar - Address: 78 Cowgate, Edinburgh EH2 2LR (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Edinburgh &gt; Edinburgh Restaurants 
 
 Old Orleans, Edinburgh 
 
American Restaurant - Address: Dundee Street, Edinburgh EH11 ... more 
 American Restaurant - Address: Dundee Street, Edinburgh EH11 1AL (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Edinburgh &gt; Edinburgh Restaurants 
 
 Wing Sing Inn, Edinburgh 
 
Chinese Restaurant - Address: 147-149 Dundee Street, ... more 
 Chinese Restaurant - Address: 147-149 Dundee Street, Edinburgh (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Edinburgh &gt; Edinburgh Restaurants 
 
 Taj Express, Edinburgh 
 
Indian Restaurant - Address: 161 Dundee Street, Edinburgh ... more 
 Indian Restaurant - Address: 161 Dundee Street, Edinburgh EH11 1BY (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Edinburgh &gt; Edinburgh Restaurants 
 
 Piatto Verde, Edinburgh 
 
Italian Restaurant - Address: 7 Dundee Terrace, Edinburgh ... more 
 Italian Restaurant - Address: 7 Dundee Terrace, Edinburgh EH11 1DL (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Edinburgh &gt; Edinburgh Restaurants 
 
 Spicy Bite, Edinburgh 
 
Falafel/Kebab Restaurant - Address: 119 Dundee Street, ... more 
 Falafel/Kebab Restaurant - Address: 119 Dundee Street, Edinburgh EH11 1AX (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Edinburgh &gt; Edinburgh Restaurants 
 
 Hack Shack, Edinburgh 
 
Internet Cafe - Address: 153 Dundee Street, Edinburgh EH11 1BP (On ... more 
 Internet Cafe - Address: 153 Dundee Street, Edinburgh EH11 1BP (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Edinburgh &gt; Edinburgh Restaurants 
 
 Agnellos Sandwich Deli Bar, Edinburgh 
 
Sandwich Bar - Address: 177 Dundee Street, Edinburgh EH11 1BY (On ... more 
 Sandwich Bar - Address: 177 Dundee Street, Edinburgh EH11 1BY (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Edinburgh &gt; Edinburgh Restaurants 
 
 Fountain News, Edinburgh 
 
Fast Food Restaurant , Take-away - Address: 157 Dundee Street, ... more 
 Fast Food Restaurant , Take-away - Address: 157 Dundee Street, Edinburgh EH11 1BY (On Ciao since: 03/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Edinburgh &gt; Edinburgh Restaurants 
 
 Old Orleans, Unit 7, Fountain Park Leisure Complex, 130/7 Dundee 
Old Orleans, Unit 7, Fountain Park Leisure Complex, 130/7 Dundee Street, Edinburgh, EH11 1AF, Edinburgh
 
 
American Restaurant - Address: Unit 7, Fountain Park Leisure ... more 
 American Restaurant - Address: Unit 7, Fountain Park Leisure Complex, 130/7 Dundee Street, Edinburgh, EH11 1AF (On Ciao since: 08/2007)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Edinburgh &gt; Edinburgh Restaurants 
 
 
(*) Reviews by Ciao members
 
 1 




 
Offers»

 1 - 6 of 6 results for&quot;Restaurants Dundee&quot; sorted by: Popularity | Price 

 
 Shaftesbury Lodge, Dundee 
Shaftesbury Lodge, Dundee 
 
 
Located in the West End of Dundee , the Shaftesbury Lodge is a 5-minute taxi journey from Dundee city centre. Local restaurants can be...... more 
 Located in the West End of Dundee , the Shaftesbury Lodge is a 5-minute taxi journey from Dundee city centre. Local restaurants can be reached after 5 minutes walk and free Wi-Fi is available throughout.
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  refer to website 
 Availability :  Price is per double room per night and may vary depending on date booked... £ 58.00 Visit Shop  &gt; booking.com 
 The Hotel Broughty Ferry, Dundee 
The Hotel Broughty Ferry, Dundee 
 
 
The Broughty Ferry is a family-run hotel located in the old fishing village of Broughty Ferry. It offers luxury rooms, a leisure complex and an award-winning...... more 
 The Broughty Ferry is a family-run hotel located in the old fishing village of Broughty Ferry. It offers luxury rooms, a leisure complex and an award-winning restaurant and free Wi-Fi.
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  refer to website 
 Availability :  Price is per double room per night and may vary depending on date booked... £ 78.00 Visit Shop  &gt; booking.com 
 BEST WESTERN QUEENS HOTEL, DUNDEE 
BEST WESTERN QUEENS HOTEL, DUNDEE 
 
 
HOTELYEAR BUILT 1879 YEAR REMODELED 2006ADDITIONAL PROPERTY DESCRIPTION RELAX LIKE ROYALTY AT BEST WESTERN QUEENS HOTEL. BUILT IN 1878,...... more 
 HOTELYEAR BUILT 1879 YEAR REMODELED 2006ADDITIONAL PROPERTY DESCRIPTION RELAX LIKE ROYALTY AT BEST WESTERN QUEENS HOTEL. BUILT IN 1878, DUNDEE S MOST PRESTIGIOUS PRIVATELY OWNED HOTEL HAS ALL THE HALLMARKS OF A QUALITY RESIDENCE, WITH A FANTASTIC LOCATION TO MATCH. IDEALLY SITUATED FOR GOLF, WITH ST. ANDREWS AND CARNOUSTIE NEARBY, YOU LL HAVE YOUR PICK OF PARKLAND COURSES AS WELL AS COASTAL LINKS ROUNDS ADDING A CHALLENGE TO YOUR CHARM FILLED BREAK. MINUTES FROM THE SHOPPING CENTRE, UNIVERSITY, THEATRE AND BUSTLING WEST END BARS AND RESTAURANT S OF THIS SCOTTISH HAVEN, OUR OWN NOSEY PARKERS IS WELL WORTH A...WELL, NOSEY. IMPRESSIVE CONFERENCE AND BANQUETING FACILITIES MAKE WORKING AWAY A HASSLE FREE EXERCISE, WHILE MAJOR AND NOT SO WELL KNOWN TOWNS AND CITIES ARE NEARBY FOR BUSINESS AND LEISURE OUTINGS WITH A DIFFERENCE.
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  refer to website 
 Availability :  Price is per double room per night and may vary depending on date booked... £ 64.16 Visit Shop  &gt; hotels.com 
 Dundee Resort and Golf Club, West Bay 
 Dundee Resort and Golf Club, West Bay
 
 
Location. Located in West Bay, Dundee Resort and Golf Club is on a lake. Features.This West Bay property has a private beach. Dining options at...... more 
 Location. Located in West Bay, Dundee Resort and Golf Club is on a lake. Features.This West Bay property has a private beach. Dining options at Dundee Resort and Golf Club include 2 restaurants and a bar/lounge. Recreational amenities include a golf course. Also located on site are an outdoor pool, an indoor pool, a fitness facility, and tennis courts. This 3.5 star property offers small meeting rooms, secretarial services, and audio visual equipment. Complimentary wireless Internet access is available in public areas. This West Bay property has event space consisting of banquet facilities, conference/meeting rooms, and a ballroom. Business services and wedding services are available. Guest parking is complimentary. Additional property amenities include laundry facilities. This is a smoke free property. Guestrooms. There are 98 guestrooms at Dundee Resort and Golf Club. Balconies offer lake views. Bathrooms feature shower/tub combinations, complimentary toiletries, and hair dryers. In addition to complimentary wireless Internet access, guestrooms offer direct dial phones. Televisions have satellite channels. Air conditioned rooms also include coffee/tea makers, blackout drapes/curtains, irons/ironing boards, and clock radios. Housekeeping is available. Guestrooms are all non smoking. Notifications and Fees:The following fees and deposits are charged by the property at time of service, check in, or check out. Pets: C$ 25,00 per stay The above list may not be comprehensive. Fees and deposits may not include tax and are subject to change.
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  refer to website 
 Availability :  Price is per double room per night and may vary depending on date booked... £ 65.55 Visit Shop  &gt; hotels.com 
 PARK HOTEL MONTROSE, Angus 
PARK HOTEL MONTROSE, Angus
 
 
PARK HOTEL IS AN EXCELLENT BASE FOR EXPLORING THE ANGUSGLENS AND ALL THEY HAVE TO OFFER CASTLES INCLUDINGGLAMIS AND DUNNOTAR ARE A LITTLE OVER HALF AN...... more 
 PARK HOTEL IS AN EXCELLENT BASE FOR EXPLORING THE ANGUSGLENS AND ALL THEY HAVE TO OFFER CASTLES INCLUDINGGLAMIS AND DUNNOTAR ARE A LITTLE OVER HALF AN HOUR AWAYAND FOR GOLFERS THE MONTROSE LINKS THE FIFTH OLDEST GOLFCOURSE IN THE WORLD IS A LEISURELY FIVE MINUTE STROLL AWAY WHETHER YOU ARE ORGANIZING A MEETING CONFERENCE OR WEDDING THE PARK HOTEL IS FULLY DEDICATED TO PROVIDING A VENUETHAT ACCOMMODATES YOUR EVERY REQUIREMENT THERE ARE THREEMEETING AND CONFERENCE ROOMS OFFERING FACILITIES FOR 2 TO150 DELEGATES ABERDEEN AND DUNDEE ARE BOTH WITHIN A 1 HOURDRIVE EACH OF OUR ROOMS HAS A TELEVISION HAIRDRYER IRON AND IRONING BOARD WELCOME TRAY AND A TROUSER PRESSPROVIDED AS STANDARD WIRELESS INTERNET ACCESS IS AVAILABLEHOTEL WIDE FOR A SMALL FEE OUR WELCOMING BAR AND RESTAURANT ALWAYS PROVIDE A RELAXEDATMOSPHERE WHERE YOU CAN ENJOY A VARIED SELECTION OF DISHESTO TEMPT YOUR PALATE THROUGHOUT THE DAY
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  refer to website 
 Availability :  Price is per double room per night and may vary depending on date booked... £ 99.82 Visit Shop  &gt; hotels.com 
 THE ALBANY HOTEL ST ANDREWS, ST ANDREWS FIFE 
THE ALBANY HOTEL ST ANDREWS, ST ANDREWS FIFE
 
 
THE ALBANY IS SET IN AN ELEGANT GEORGIAN TERRACED HOUSE SYMPATHETICALLY CONVERTED TO RETAIN MANY OF ITS ORIGINALFEATURES AND OFFERS A REWARDING 3 STAR SMALL...... more 
 THE ALBANY IS SET IN AN ELEGANT GEORGIAN TERRACED HOUSE SYMPATHETICALLY CONVERTED TO RETAIN MANY OF ITS ORIGINALFEATURES AND OFFERS A REWARDING 3 STAR SMALL INFORMALHOTEL EXPERIENCE IN ST ANDREWS IT IS LOCATED ON NORTHSTREET A VERY QUIET YET VERY CENTRAL STREET IN THE HEARTOF THE HISTORIC TOWN CLOSE TO GREAT AMENITIES BARS RESTAURANTS AND CAFES AND NIGHTSPOTS STAFF WILL BEPLEASED TO RECOMMEND DINING OPPORTUNITIES THE ALBANYOFFERS EXCELLENT HOSPITALITY AND ITS INTIMATE SIZE ALLOWSFOR VERY HIGH STANDARDS OF ACCOMMODATION AND SERVICE AND AWARM AND CARING ATTITUDE TOWARDS GUESTS GREAT GOLF COURSESARE AVAILABLE WITHIN WALKING DISTANCE OF THE HOTEL AND STAFFWILL BE DELIGHTED TO HELP ARRANGE GOLF THEATRE ANDSIGHTSEEING TOURS CONTINENTAL BUFFET AND FULL SCOTTISHCOOKED BREAKFASTS ARE SERVED IN THE PLEASANT RESTAURANT WITHPATIO DOORS OPENING OUT ONTO DELIGHTFUL LANDSCAPED GARDENS THE ALBANY IS ONE OF THE FEW HOTELS IN THE CENTRE OF STANDREWS WITH A DELIGHTFUL SPLIT LEVEL AND LANDSCAPED BEERGARDEN AND PATIO THE RESIDENTS BAR AND LOUNGE ISCOMFORTABLY FURNISHED WITH AN INVITING LOG FIRE AND LOTS OFBOOKS TO BROWSE THE HOTEL OFFERS 22 ENSUITE ROOMS INDIVIDUALLY DECORATEDAND RECENTLY REFURBISHED AND WELL APPOINTED WITH ALL MODERNAMENITIES INCLUDING CONTROLLABLE CENTRAL HEATING TROUSERPRESS FREE WIFI ACCESS AND INTERNATIONAL DIRECT DIALTELEPHONE FLUFFY TOWELS AND EXTRA BEDDING ARE OFFERED ASSTANDARD ST ANDREWS POSSIBLY THE LEADING GOLFINGDESTINATION IN THE WORLD IS SET IN A SUPERB COASTALLOCATION WITH MILES OF GOLDEN SANDS YET IT IS SOCONVENIENT FOR EDINBURGH DUNDEE AND INDEED ALL SCOTTISHMAJOR TOWNS AND CITIES IT IS ARCHITECTURALLY VERYINTERESTING WITH FEATURE GARDENS A HISTORIC FEEL AND AFAMOUS UNIVERSITY CASTLE AND CATHEDRAL COME AND SPENDSOME TIME WITH US AT THE ALBANY HOTEL AND GET A REAL FLAVOURFOR EVERYTHING ST ANDREWS HAS TO OFFER.
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  refer to website 
 Availability :  Price is per double room per night and may vary depending on date booked... £ 138.50 Visit Shop  &gt; hotels.com 
 
(*) Reviews by Ciao members


 
Related tags for Restaurants Dundee»
 dundee united dundee scotland travel dundee crocodile dundee dundee dundee uni dundee, or restaurants the restaurant dundee university 
Reviews»

 
 Park your backside for a lovely meal 

 Advantages: Fantastic food, well cooked, brilliantly presented, very polite and friendly staff, quiet.
 Disadvantages: no facilities for children


...None of your beeswax! Valentines Day: A soppy, unromantic excuse for a million and ten places to cash in on your fear of not showing the one you love that you love them. That?s generally my view on it and up to the date it had been made clear I don?t care for it to my partner of 8 months. Then I noticed the nearer we got to the date he was actually yearning for a little bit of romance on the day. Being quite a romantic sop, I decided to throw my hatred for the day out the window and surprise him. I snuck into his house with some presents (which almost caused him to have a heart attack when he came home to find his doors unlocked) and booked a table at a lovely little restaurant called ?Nosey Parkers?. Picking your nose Nosey Parkers is situated in the Queens Hotel in Dundee at the...

 ryanando 
 01.01.1970 Read review 
Ciao members have rated this review on average very helpful 
Review of Nosey Parkers Restaurant &amp;Bistro, Dundee 
 
 The Bell Tree, Dundee 

 Advantages: Great service, food and surroundings
 Disadvantages: None


...On a recent trip to Inverness, we stayed over one night in Dundee at one of the Premier Inns there. The Bell Tree pub/restaurant is next door to the Premier Inn and we decided to pay a visit.

 The Bell Tree 

Situated on the A92 to Arbroath, The Bell Tree is a modern dining venue built in the Chef&amp;Brewer style which advertises a comfortable, relaxed atmosphere. Previous to our visit here, I had no experience of a Chef&amp;Brewer pub restaurant, but from the outside it certainly looked inviting enough, a large cosy-looking stone building with wooden tables and chairs set outside.

The setting is ideal, on the outskirts of Broughty Ferry and set away from the busy road and near a residential area, but also adjoining the Premier Inn and a handful of small retail outlets opposite, ensuring that this pub restaurant receives plenty...

 JEFFJEN 
 01.01.1970 Read review 
Ciao members have rated this review on average very helpful 
Review of The Bell Tree Pub/ Restaurant 
 
 An Absolute Gem of a Restaurant! 

 Advantages: price, selection, atmosphere, quality of food, service, family friendly
 Disadvantages: you might not know it existed!


...The Mint Restaurant - Essential Information

16 Academy Street 
Coatbridge
Lanarkshire
ML5 3AU

01236 441191
www.navantaverns.com

The Mint Restaurant is part of the Navan Tavern Group of restaurants. This group offers two restaurants in Glasgow, one in Motherwell (my home town) and The Mint. The Mint is located up a side street from the main shopping area of Coatbridge. Street parking is available. It is very easy to find if you know your way around Coatbridge. The exterior of the restaurant is homely and welcoming.

The Mint is a family run establishment and they claim to offer home cooked food in a stylish and relaxed environment. The restaurants has a function room upstairs which offers tribute evenings and meals. They also cover weddings and other events. The main restaurant is accessed via a ramp and the inside...

 angelboouk123 
 01.01.1970 Read review 
Ciao members have rated this review on average very helpful 
Review of Mint Restaurant &amp;Bar, Coatbridge 
 
 
 About Us - 
 Jobs
 - 
 Advertise with Us
 - 
 Press
 - 
 Become a Partner
 - Ciao Quality Seal Ciao Deutschland - Ciao France - Ciao Italia - Ciao España - Ciao Nederland - Ciao Sverige Site Index - Ciao Charts - Most searched products - Data Protection 
 ©2012 Shopping Guide GmbH
	</body>
</document>
