<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002946" url="http://www.wlbt.com/Global/story.asp?S=14459609" time="2012-07-12-19:02" support="1" score="0.00178904406412167" bingtitle="Statement from SSGT Jason Rogers&apos; Company Commander - WLBT.com ..." webtitle="Statement from SSGT Jason Rogers&apos; Company Commander - WLBT.com - Jackson, MS">
			<query id="001177" bing-rank="234"/>
	<description>Four arrested for credit card fraud and identity theft ... Jackson fast food restaurant armed robbery ... Rogers not taken the point man position in order ...</description>
	<body>
		WLBT.com - Jackson, MSStatement from SSGT Jason Rogers&apos; Company Commander
 SITE SEARCH WEB SEARCH BY 
 
 St. Jude Dream Home Video Landing Page Decision 2012 Jackson Gas Prices Editorials America Now Medical Matters Sign up for Alerts Contact Us 
 
 Decision 2012 Editorials MDOT Traffic Cams Wednesday&apos;s Child Look Around Mississippi Most Wanted Sign up for Alerts 
 
 Alfa Insurance Skycams How to Program a Weather Radio Sign up for Alerts 
 
 Olympic Zone Sign up for Alerts 
 
 MedNOW Medical Matters Sign up for Alerts 
 
 Taking Back Our Neighborhoods 
 
 Main Summer Back to School Entertainment Money Home/Family Health Food Pets Tech Travel Beauty&amp;Style Auto Tax Guide VideoBytes Press Releases 
 
 SkyCopter 3 Community Our Team The Morning Team Midday Mississippi Sign up for Alerts Contact Us Closed Captioning This TV Network 
 
 WLBT Community St. Jude Dream Home SkyCopter 3 Our Team The Morning Team Midday Mississippi Contact Us Fresh from the Flame 
 
 
 Email 
 Share | 
 Print 
 
Statement from SSGT Jason Rogers&apos; Company Commander
 Posted: Saturday, April 16, 2011 3:08 PM EST Updated: Saturday, April 16, 2011 10:03 PM EST 
 
 Most Popular Stories Most Read More&gt;&gt; 
 
 PD: Father punched man who attempted to meet daughter 

 PD: Father punched man who attempted to meet daughter 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 10:34 PM EDT 2012-07-12 02:34:44 GMT A 42-year-old Monterey man got a bloody nose when he tried to meet a 12-year-old girl that he met on Facebook. More &gt;&gt; A 42-year-old Monterey man got a bloody nose when he tried to meet a 12-year-old girl whom he met on Facebook, according to police. More &gt;&gt; 
 Police identify 3 shooting victims 

 Police identify 3 shooting victims 
 Updated: Wednesday, July 11 2012 9:44 PM EDT 2012-07-12 01:44:43 GMT Jackson police have identified three people shot while sitting in an SUV at 947 Robinson Street Tuesday night. More &gt;&gt; Jackson police have identified three people shot while sitting in an SUV at 947 Robinson Street Tuesday night. More &gt;&gt; 
 Parents arrested, girl allegedly forced to live in chicken coop 

 Parents arrested, girl allegedly forced to live in chicken coop 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 6:53 PM EDT 2012-07-10 22:53:55 GMT The parents accused of keeping their teen daughter in a chicken coop have been arrested. More &gt;&gt; The parents accused of keeping their teen daughter in a chicken coop have been arrested. More &gt;&gt; 
 Good Samaritan fatal crash results in multiple lawsuits 

 Good Samaritan fatal crash results in multiple lawsuits 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 11:05 PM EDT 2012-07-11 03:05:14 GMT The aftermath of an accident that killed one twin sister and left the other critically injured is headed to federal court. A wrongful death lawsuit was expected in the case, but now there are legal filings More &gt;&gt; The aftermath of an accident that killed one twin sister and left the other critically injured is headed to federal court. A wrongful death lawsuit was expected in the case, but now there are legal filings against lawyers, a Hinds County Constable and the father of the deceased woman&apos;s child. More &gt;&gt; 
 Man takes baby to meet with prostitute 

 Man takes baby to meet with prostitute 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 9:48 AM EDT 2012-07-10 13:48:25 GMT A man in Tuscaloosa may be charged with child endangerment after taking along his nine month old son during a meeting with a prostitute. More &gt;&gt; A man in Tuscaloosa may be charged with child endangerment after taking along his nine month old son during a meeting with a prostitute. More &gt;&gt; 

 
 Sponsored Information More&gt;&gt; 
 
 sponsored information: 

 Personal Injury Attorney 

 Personal Injury Attorney 
 
 
 STATEMENT FROM SSGT JASON ROGERS&apos;COMPANY COMMANDER 

SSgt Rogers exemplified the term Marine. He was a true mentor to the Marines that he led, he was slow to yell, quick to correct, and happy to praise.

Young Marines respected him; his magnetic personality and smile put young men at ease in tough situations.

I am grateful to have known him and I know that I will never forget what he did for my Marines.

On the day prior to SSgt Rogers going out on the next operation, I pulled him in my office and told him &quot;your job is to look out for the well being of your Marines, protect them like a pit bull.&quot; On that day a situation arose where he did just that.

Two of his Marines were severely wounded while clearing a compound. One of SSgt Rogers&apos;Marines struck a pressure plate IED.

SSgt Rogers immediately recognized the gravity of the situation and rushed to the aid of his injured Marines. He rushed to their aid and arrived to find that they had sustained very serious wounds and would surely die if he didn&apos;t do something.

SSgt Rogers was a rock solid example in a traumatic situation, directing the Marines to stay calm and keep focused, while he continued to ensure that the Marines tending to the casualties were responsive and coherent.

SSgt Rogers ordered the Marines to keep the casualties responding with oral communication. Even after this group of Marines had already experienced one mass casualty situation that day, SSgt Rogers was able to provide the combat tested leadership that kept their focus on the task at hand.

Recognizing that his wounded Marines would require stretchers to be moved and that his Marines would soon die if they didn&apos;t receive higher level care, SSgt Rogers wasted no time and assigned the remaining engineers to assist the Corpsman in preparing the two wounded Marines for evacuation.

Without regard for his own life and focused solely on getting his Marines to safety, he charged across 20 meters of uncleared, IED laden terrain in order to retrieve two litters from his nearby vehicle. He unhesitatingly crossed the 20 meter IED laden area in order to make his way back to his Marines.

Once he returned, he instructed the remaining engineers to prepare the casualties for evacuation.

Fueled by a tenacious desire to evacuate his Marines to safety, SSgt Rogers once again without hesitation or regard for his own life, placed himself between the enemy&apos;s devices and his Marines by using a Vallon metal detector to sweep a lane for their evacuation.

As he cleared the lane that he had traversed twice previously, he picked up a metallic signature with his metal detector. As SSgt Rogers went to confirm the IED, it detonated, and he succumbed to his wounds instantly.

Through his heroic actions and ferocious desire to save the lives of his critically wounded Marines, he paid the ultimate price and ensured that every last Marine came out of the compound alive.

Had SSgt Rogers not taken the point man position in order to provide freedom of movement to the litter bearers, the lead litter team would most certainly have struck the IED and led to the lost lives of most if not all of the engineer squad.

SSgt Rogers is a hero in the truest sense of the word. I can&apos;t tell you how proud I am to say that I knew him and I will tell my children and grand children of the Marine who guarded the lives of his Marines with ferociousness tenacity.

On the day he left I told him to protect his Marines like a pit bull and he did just that.


Capt John Shubeck D Company
Commander/ RCT-8 Engineer
1st CEB, 2d MarDiv (FWD)
DSN: 3586023
VOSIP: 3578074
 
 
Explore WLBT.com
 Home Local News Decision 2011 Gas Prices America Now Point of View Sound Off News Most Read Local News Skycopter 3 Most Wanted Look Around Mississippi 3 On Your Side Wednesday’s Child Taking Back our Neighborhoods Red Blue Review Medical Matters Weather Local Weather Alfa Insurance Skycams How to Program a Weather Radio Interactive Radar 4-Day Pollen Forecast Sports Sports National Sports Mississippi Sports Friday Nite Lites Video Latest Videos Most Watched Video Center Contact Us Contact Us Sign Up for Email Alerts Our Team Birthday Club All content©Copyright 2000 - 2012 WorldNow and WLBT, a Raycom Media Station .
All Rights Reserved. For more information on this site, please read our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service .
	</body>
</document>
