<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002826" url="http://search.blossom.com/nquery/226/type0/compact2/p1?key=taste" time="2012-07-12-18:54" support="3" score="0.00255342076053044" bingtitle="Consumer Complaint Search Results - Blossom Software: Hosted and ..." webtitle="Consumer Complaint Search Results">
			<query id="000654" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="001446" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="000648" bing-rank="224"/>
	<description>Children even are turning to condiments to add these ... More What Does A Doctor Order At A Fast Food Restaurant? http://www ... the care there is good, BUT they pad the bill ...</description>
	<body>
		Results 1-100 of 785 containing &quot;taste&quot; sorted by [ Relevance / Date ] These phrases also occur:
 bad taste 
 state tastes different 
 sour taste 
 taste buds 
 bitter taste 
 Taste Test Finds Best Wings for NFL Playoff Season 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com...st-finds-best-wings-for-nfl-playoff-season.html 
 [Score: 402, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -2, Age: -7]
 Taste Test Finds Best Wings for NFL Playoff Season Consumer Reports crowns Bell&amp;Evans best overall for taste quality
 More Frozen Pizzas Fare Well In Taste Tests 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com.../12/frozen-pizzas-fare-well-in-taste-tests.html 
 [Score: 357, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -2, Age: -7]
Frozen Pizzas Fare Well In Taste Tests DiGiorno, Amy s and Home Run Inn win Consumer Reports recommendations
 More Coke Suit: Vitaminwater Advertising Leaves a Bitter Taste 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com...minwater-advertising-leaves-a-bitter-taste.html 
 [Score: 355, Weight: 0, Hits: 4, Size: -2, Age: -6]
Coke Suit: Vitaminwater Advertising Leaves a Bitter Taste Plaintiff says supposed health drink is nothing but fortified sugar water
 More Would Fructose By Any Other Name Taste As Sweet? 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com...-fructose-by-any-other-name-taste-as-sweet.html 
 [Score: 329, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -2, Age: 0]
There&apos;s been a series of controversial TV commercials circulating over the past couple of years. It speaks about how safe high-fructose corn syrup (HFCS) i
 23 Complaints and Reviews about Zicam 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/rx/zicam.html 
 [Score: 120, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -6, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Zicam
...I filed a complaint about loss of taste and smell due to Zicam nasal spray, but have heard nothing....
...I lost my sense of smell and taste for three months....
 More 212 Complaints and Reviews about Nabisco | Page 6 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/nabisco.html?page=6 
 [Score: 110, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -8, Age: 0]
I am very upset with the texture and taste of these round saltine crackers. I want my light, traditional saltines that are square! I don&apos;t want these dry and hard ... (Page 6)
...Now they have a strange taste, different texture, and so hard they can hardly be crumbled into soup/chili....
 More Survey Sees Opening for &apos;Enhanced&apos; Milk 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com...1/02/survey-sees-opening-for-enhanced-milk.html 
 [Score: 107, Weight: 0, Hits: 5, Size: -2, Age: -7]
Survey Sees Opening for &apos;Enhanced&apos; Milk. Consumers tested displayed a preference for the taste of more nutritious milk.
...CONSUMERS TESTED DISPLAYED A PREFERENCE FOR THE TASTE OF MORE NUTRITIOUS MILK...
 More 212 Complaints and Reviews about Nabisco | Page 7 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/nabisco.html?page=7 
 [Score: 106, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -8, Age: 0]
...They smelled and tasted like a paint product....
 More More Restaurant-Style Foods Offered For Home 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com...re-restaurant-style-foods-offered-for-home.html 
 [Score: 104, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -2, Age: -3]
Food marketers are emphasizing restaurant-style taste 
...MARKETERS PUSH DINING OUT TASTE ON EAT AT HOME BUDGET...
 More 368 Complaints and Reviews about Crest Toothpaste | Page 10 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/cosmetics/crest.html?page=10 
 [Score: 100, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
I experienced a tingling/drooling sensation on my lower lip and inside of my cheek along with white stringy, slimy stuff forming near the gum line and the lower bottom teeth. ... (Page 10)
...This stuff leaves a bad taste, burns and numbs in the inside of my mouth and tongue, and worst of all, has increased the sensitivity of my teeth....
...I did experience many symptoms reported by other consumers at first: tissue shedding inside my mouth around the gum, lip and cheek areas; constantly peeling and raw lips which I had to continually moisten with Vaseline; raw tip of tongue; occasional metallic taste ; and raw burning throat....
 More 368 Complaints and Reviews about Crest Toothpaste | Page 7 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/cosmetics/crest.html?page=7 
 [Score: 100, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
...I can&apos;t taste very much and it hurts to eat or drink....
...I still have no ability to taste and my tongue is still red, but it hurts less....
 More 368 Complaints and Reviews about Crest Toothpaste | Page 9 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/cosmetics/crest.html?page=9 
 [Score: 94, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
...My mouth had this nasty taste in it and I kept brushing my teeth and rinsing with mouthwash in an attempt to get rid of it. It didn&apos;t work....
...The slimy feeling went away, the stringy mucous stopped forming, my tongue felt more normal and the awful taste in my mouth dissipated. ...
 More 209 Complaints and Reviews about Nabisco 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/nabisco.html 
 [Score: 93, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -8, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Nabisco
...They also do not have the same taste. ...
...I have been eating and enjoying Premium Saltine Crackers ever since I can remember (I am 54) and now you go and change them into round crackers that don&apos;t taste the same, and go all stale by the time you reach the bottom of the bag!...
 More 368 Complaints and Reviews about Crest Toothpaste | Page 8 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/cosmetics/crest.html?page=8 
 [Score: 92, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
...The mouthwash made my tongue feel like I burned it. I could not taste my breakfast and it hurts until before dinner....
...I switched mouthwash to Crest Pro-Health Complete Rinse and I used it on the first night I bought it. The next morning, I couldn&apos;t &quot; taste &quot; anything-no spicy foods, nothing....
 More 211 Complaints and Reviews about Nabisco | Page 5 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/nabisco.html?page=5 
 [Score: 92, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Nabisco (Page 5)
...Well, the worst thing happened. I took a bite of the desert and nearly choked from the toxic like taste. ...
...It tasted like I was eating paint. ...
 More 368 Complaints and Reviews about Crest Toothpaste | Page 6 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/cosmetics/crest.html?page=6 
 [Score: 90, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
...I opened a new tube of Crest Scope Extra Whitening toothpaste and noticed that it left a minty taste that seemed to stay for a very long time with a tingle to my tongue....
...After a week, I have now got a constant tingling in my tongue, no taste sensitivity and my tissue on the inside of my lower lip is starting to peel....
 More Study: Low-Fat Dairy Foods Reduce Stroke Risk 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com...udy-low-fat-dairy-foods-reduce-stroke-risk.html 
 [Score: 90, Weight: 0, Hits: 2, Size: -2, Age: -1]
There&apos;s no question that full-fat yogurt, milk and cheese taste better than the low-fat varieties but a new study confirms that eating low-fat dairy f
...04/20/2012 | There&apos;s no question that full-fat yogurt, milk and cheese taste better than the low-fat varieties but a new study confirms that eating low-fat dairy foods reduces the risk of stroke....
 212 Complaints and Reviews about Nabisco | Page 8 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/nabisco.html?page=8 
 [Score: 88, Weight: 0, Hits: 1, Size: -2, Age: 0]
 368 Complaints and Reviews about Crest Toothpaste 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/cosmetics/crest.html 
 [Score: 87, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -12, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Crest MultiCare Toothpaste
...The taste buds are all red, irritated and numb....
...I&apos;ve used Crest before and would get awful canker sores, but figured since this kind tasted mild, I wouldn&apos;t have a problem....
 More 207 Complaints and Reviews about Kroger | Page 6 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/supermarkets/kroger.html?page=6 
 [Score: 87, Weight: 0, Hits: 2, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Today, I bought two brownie pops from Kroger. I ate one pop while at work. As I started to bite into the brownie, it had a funny taste. So I ... (Page 6)
...We baked it and tried to eat. The first bite tasted horrible, and I stopped eating....
 207 Complaints and Reviews about Kroger | Page 7 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/supermarkets/kroger.html?page=7 
 [Score: 86, Weight: 0, Hits: 1, Size: -12, Age: 0]
 211 Complaints and Reviews about Nabisco | Page 3 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/nabisco.html?page=3 
 [Score: 86, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Nabisco (Page 3)
...Premium crackers: We bought 4 boxes of the saltines, and they were terrible - they tasted like soap....
...These round things are nowhere near the originals in taste, feel, or anything else....
 More 368 Complaints and Reviews about Crest Toothpaste | Page 2 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/cosmetics/crest.html?page=2 
 [Score: 85, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -12, Age: 0]
...I can&apos;t seem to taste anything and my sense of smell is way, way down....
...I took another look in a magnifying mirror today, because I was getting worried about tongue cancer and my taste buds are swollen and red down the middle and I have a white coat on the back of my tongue....
 More 273 Complaints and Reviews about Nutrisystem | Page 8 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/nutrition/nutrisystem.htm?page=8 
 [Score: 85, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Come on, people. It clearly states on Nutrisystem&apos;s website that you will be charged the difference of the non-discounted meal plan when you cancel before receiving two consecutive auto deliveries. ... (Page 8)
...Ordered Nutrisystem because of the commercials on TV. The first meal of roast beef was horrible, the roast looked like a block of wood and tasted about as bad....
...Cereal is ok but such a small amount, most of the snacks are soy and taste horrible, like eating cardboard....
 More 211 Complaints and Reviews about Nabisco | Page 4 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/nabisco.html?page=4 
 [Score: 85, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Nabisco (Page 4)
...They tasted the same. I know it didn&apos;t come from the cabinet they were in. I cannot smell anything of the sort anywhere in our house....
...These round ones taste stale and even though I have only bought Premium Saltines my whole adult life (as they were the only kind my parents bought), I will not be buying these again....
 More Is It Worth the Extra Money? 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/news04/2010/09/cr_taste_test.html 
 [Score: 84, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -2, Age: -9]
...CONSUMER REPORTSLATEST TASTE TESTS FIND SOME STORE BRANDS AT LEAST AS GOOD AS NATIONAL BRANDS...
...09/09/2010 | When it comes to taste, store brand products can compete with their name-brand counterparts and save shoppers more than a thousand dollars a year on grocery bills, according to a new Consumer Reports study. ...
 More 368 Complaints and Reviews about Crest Toothpaste | Page 11 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/cosmetics/crest.html?page=11 
 [Score: 82, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
...Lot #81692, exp. 5/10. Shortly after I began using it I developed a dry, numb tongue and noticed that my sense of taste was off....
...I am afraid of lasting affects. My food is almost tasteless. ...
 More 368 Complaints and Reviews about Crest Toothpaste | Page 5 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/cosmetics/crest.html?page=5 
 [Score: 82, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
...I haven&apos;t been able to taste anything in the paste 3 days and my tongue feels sore and swollen....
...Sores on the tongue. Loss of taste. ...
 More Study: Water With Meals Promotes Better Food Choices 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com...er-with-meals-promotes-better-food-choices.html 
 [Score: 80, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -2, Age: 0]
Most weight-loss programs focus on what we eat. Two researchers, T. Bettina Cornwell of the University of Oregon and Anna R. McAlister of Michigan State Un
...It&apos;s not so much the calories in the beverages, it&apos;s how they play with your taste buds....
...INFLUENCING TASTE PREFERENCE...
 More Which Is Better, Store Brand or Name Brand? 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/news04/2010/03/brand_comparison.html 
 [Score: 79, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -2, Age: -11]
... TASTE TEST...
...Not only can some consumers not tell the difference between a store brand and a nationally advertised brand, sometimes they might even prefer it. In 2005 a double-blind nationwide taste by Meyers Research found that participants preferred the taste of private-label products over advertised brands by a margin of 51 percent to 49 percent....
 More What&apos;s On Your Mind? LAPD, Dish Network, Best Buy, Zicam 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com...your-mind-lapd-dish-network-best-buy-zicam.html 
 [Score: 79, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -2, Age: -4]
...NO TASTE OR SMELL...
...&quot;It worked pretty good but after three days I noticed I could no longer smell or taste anything....
 More 368 Complaints and Reviews about Crest Toothpaste | Page 3 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/cosmetics/crest.html?page=3 
 [Score: 79, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -12, Age: 0]
...Spicy food did not taste spicy, and that includes red cayenne peppers....
...It limited what I could eat because many foods burned it more and I lost the sense of taste for bland foods....
 More Black Chamber Of Commerce Opposes Menthol Cigarette Ban 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com...-of-commerce-opposes-menthol-cigarette-ban.html 
 [Score: 78, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -2, Age: -8]
Now that the Food and Drug Administration has authority over tobacco products, the agency is considering whether it should ban cigarettes containing ment
...CLAIMS ACTION TARGETS &apos;TASTE PREFERENCE OF AFRICAN-AMERICANS&apos;...
...&quot;It is no secret that menthol cigarettes provide a distinctive taste that is preferred by many African Americans,&quot; NBCC President Harry Alford said....
 More 368 Complaints and Reviews about Crest Toothpaste | Page 4 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/cosmetics/crest.html?page=4 
 [Score: 78, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
...I could not taste anything for a couple days....
...I have had a metallic taste in mouth which does seem to be getting better; but the whole situation has been scary and painful....
 More 29 Complaints and Reviews about Fire Safe Cigarettes 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/health/fire_safe_cigarettes.html 
 [Score: 78, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -8, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Fire Safe Cigarettes
...I just learned that Pennsylvania does not require cigarettes to contain the additive, and New Yorkers are buying cigarettes from PA, because they are all noticing the difference in the taste and sore throats....
...Same bad taste, constantly went out, and when relit, almost set my hair on fair the flame ignites so big....
 More 211 Complaints and Reviews about Nabisco | Page 2 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/nabisco.html?page=2 
 [Score: 77, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Nabisco (Page 2)
...I just tried the new round crackers, very disappointed, taste and the consistency is different, taste is flat, not as crispy, and as a single person, having them all in one bag means I will be throwing half away as I will not use them up before they are stale....
...Somehow, I was hoping they would still taste the same....
 More Energy Drinks Work, But Not The Way You Think 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/news04/2009/04/energy_drinks_health.html 
 [Score: 77, Weight: 0, Hits: 5, Size: -2, Age: -16]
... TASTE RECEPTORS IMPROVE ATHLETIC PERFORMANCE IN UNUSUAL WAYS...
...Nor does the sugary taste solve the riddle, as artificial sweeteners do not boost performance even when they are indistinguishable from real sugars....
 More Study: Adding Collectible Toy To Healthy Meals Make Them Desirable 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com...e-toy-to-healthy-meals-make-them-desirable.html 
 [Score: 77, Weight: 0, Hits: 2, Size: -2, Age: -4]
Adding Collectible Toy To Healthy Meals Make Them Desirable
...A TOY MAKES IT TASTE BETTER...
...&quot;The study tells us that the inclusion of a collectible toy influences the children&apos;s perceptions of how the food is going to taste, and whether they will like it,&quot; said Cornwell, a professor of marketing in the University of Oregon Lundquist College of Business....
 273 Complaints and Reviews about Nutrisystem | Page 7 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/nutrition/nutrisystem.htm?page=7 
 [Score: 77, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Nutrisystem (Page 7)
...And especially so when it doesn&apos;t work that well and their food tastes like cardboard with watery tomato sauce on it! ...
...The meal are very hard to eat, all smell and taste the same....
 More Study: By Three Years Old, Kids Know They Like Fat, Salt, Sugar 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com...ars-old-kids-know-they-like-fat-salt-sugar.html 
 [Score: 76, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -2, Age: -7]
Study: By Three Years Old, Kids Know They Like Fat, Salt, Sugar Researchers urge parents to not wait to introduce their toddlers to healthy foods
...In a study of preschoolers ages 3 to 5, involving two separate experiments, researchers found salt, sugar and fat are what kids most prefer - and that these children already could equate their taste preferences to brand-name fast-food and soda products. ...
...Children even are turning to condiments to add these flavors - and with them calories - to be sure that the foods they eat match their taste preferences....
 More 35 Complaints and Reviews about Quaker Oats 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/quaker_oats.html 
 [Score: 75, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Quaker Oats
...A few years ago, I ate some Quaker instant grits that &quot; tasted funny&quot;....
...We would like to share some of our products for you to taste and enjoy....
 More 26 Complaints and Reviews about Reiman Publications 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/misc/reiman_publications.html 
 [Score: 75, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -6, Age: 0]
Consumer Complaints about Reiman Publications
...I enjoy the Taste of Home magazine but will have to cancel so they will get the idea....
...I received an unsolicited sample Magazine ( Taste of Home) a couple of weeks ago from this company, along with an order form....
 More Adults Consume Too Much Sodium, CDC Finds 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/news04/2010/07/cdc_sodium.html 
 [Score: 75, Weight: 0, Hits: 2, Size: -2, Age: -10]
...SALTY TASTE ?...
...Many of these foods, such as breads and cookies, may not even taste salty....
 Chromium-6 In Your Water? Ask 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/news04/2011/01/chromium-6-in-your-water-ask.html 
 [Score: 73, Weight: 0, Hits: 2, Size: -2, Age: -7]
If you want to know whether there is chromium-6 in your tap water, an expert says you have to ask.
...ODORLESS AND TASTELESS ...
...Chromium is an inorganic metallic element that is odorless and tasteless. ...
 212 Complaints and Reviews about Mr. Coffee 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/homeowners/mr_coffee.html 
 [Score: 73, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -8, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Mr. Coffee
...The thermos on some Mr. Coffee models has a nasty habit of exploding, some models manage to impart a taste of burning plastic to the coffee and others just plain quit working....
...Lately, the coffee tasted funny, so I decided to clean the machine....
 More 212 Complaints and Reviews about Mr. Coffee | Page 3 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/homeowners/mr_coffee.html?page=3 
 [Score: 73, Weight: 0, Hits: 6, Size: -8, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Mr. Coffee (Page 3)
...The thermos on some Mr. Coffee models has a nasty habit of exploding, some models manage to impart a taste of burning plastic to the coffee and others just plain quit working....
...Then we made coffee. The coffee tasted like chemical, a bad chemical taste. ...
 More 193 Complaints and Reviews about Royal Caribbean Cruise Lines | Page 5 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/travel/royal_caribbean.htm?page=5 
 [Score: 72, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -12, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Royal Caribbean Cruise Lines (Page 5)
...The quality of the food seemed to be okay, but the preparation and taste was just bland....
...The milk that they provided was boxed milk with Chinese writing on it, and it had an objectionable taste to it. If you wanted cereal to taste halfway decent, you had to go around and collect a bunch of the coffee creamers that were made of half-and-half and use it for your cereal, or any of the other food that normally you would put...
 More 145 Complaints and Reviews about Bumble Bee Tuna | Page 3 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/bumble_bee.html?page=3 
 [Score: 72, Weight: 0, Hits: 4, Size: -8, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Bumble Bee Tuna (Page 3)
...We could barely eat the product. It has a strong fishy taste to it. Can Code is **; Bar Code 0 866253 1; and Expiry date is on October 2013....
...But the taste is what got me. It did not taste salty, and instead it was bland and had some other weird flavor I could not ever associate with a memory of what tuna should taste like....
 More 212 Complaints and Reviews about Mr. Coffee | Page 2 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/homeowners/mr_coffee.html?page=2 
 [Score: 71, Weight: 0, Hits: 6, Size: -8, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Mr. Coffee (Page 2)
...The thermos on some Mr. Coffee models has a nasty habit of exploding, some models manage to impart a taste of burning plastic to the coffee and others just plain quit working....
...The coffee tastes great in it, but we are senior citizens and the thermal carafe is just too hard to use....
 More Quorn Foods Sued For Not Disclosing Potential Allergic Reactions 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/news04/2009/09/quorn_cspi.html 
 [Score: 71, Weight: 0, Hits: 1, Size: -2, Age: -14]
...VAT-GROWN MOLD TASTES LIKE CHICKEN BUT ALLEGEDLY MAKES SOME VIOLENTLY ILL...
 204 Complaints and Reviews about Starbucks | Page 6 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/starbucks.html?page=6 
 [Score: 71, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
After numerous complaints to Starbucks about an incident that occurred at the Indian Harbour Beach, Florida store, it&apos;s quite apparent that Starbucks does not care how customers are treated. Foul ... (Page 6)
...Sadly, there is only one other coffee shop in my building, but I&apos;m vowing never to return to this Starbucks after numerous times of paying $2.38 for a cup of coffee that tastes like hot water with a dollop of leftover coffee&amp;milk. ...
...They offered to exchange my drink (which I had to do because it tasted horrible), but how can they run out of syrup at the beginning of the day?...
 More 212 Complaints and Reviews about Mr. Coffee | Page 4 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/homeowners/mr_coffee.html?page=4 
 [Score: 71, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -8, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Mr. Coffee (Page 4)
...The thermos on some Mr. Coffee models has a nasty habit of exploding, some models manage to impart a taste of burning plastic to the coffee and others just plain quit working....
...The coffee also tasted like burnt plastic....
 More 74 Complaints and Reviews about Trader Joe&apos;s | Page 2 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/supermarkets/trader_joe.html?page=2 
 [Score: 70, Weight: 0, Hits: 5, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Trader Joe&apos;s (Page 2)
...As I was chugging it, I felt as if I had swallowed a foreign object (possibly plastic and it tasted soapy)....
...About 3 days ago, I noticed that everything I ate tasted like the proverbial bitter pill&apos;....
 More 273 Complaints and Reviews about Nutrisystem | Page 3 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/nutrition/nutrisystem.htm?page=3 
 [Score: 70, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -12, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Nutrisystem (Page 3)
...I have the same complaints as other people about the food, it all tastes the same and is awful....
...Yes, what I ate tasted pretty terrible, but my main complaint is that all the cereals and many of the bars were not sealed in their packaging well and were stale....
 More 52 Complaints and Reviews about Lipton Tea 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/lipton_tea.html 
 [Score: 70, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -8, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Lipton Tea
...For the last several months we have found the tea to be tasteless and not as full-bodied as it used to be. We generally buy 2-3 100 count boxes a month plus 3-4 boxes of the cold brew bags too....
...The tea is dull-tasting. One box tastes fine and the other box tastes dull....
 More 273 Complaints and Reviews about Nutrisystem | Page 6 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/nutrition/nutrisystem.htm?page=6 
 [Score: 70, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -14, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Nutrisystem (Page 6)
...I tried to eat it, but the taste was revolting....
...The meals were gross, tasted terrible, and caused me gas and stomach distress....
 More 273 Complaints and Reviews about Nutrisystem | Page 2 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/nutrition/nutrisystem.htm?page=2 
 [Score: 70, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Nutrisystem (Page 2)
...But that&apos;s my taste buds. I&apos;ve chosen to flex my meals....
...If you sign up for automatic delivery, and then decide after the first shipment the food tastes horrible (which it does) they will charge you $54 to cancel since you promised to accept a second order from them....
 More Kids Cough Medicine Recalled Over Dosing Issue 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/news04/2008/01/cough_medicine.html 
 [Score: 70, Weight: 0, Hits: 1, Size: -2, Age: -22]
...A TASTE OF HONEY...
 10 Complaints and Reviews about Welch Foods 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/welch_foods.html 
 [Score: 69, Weight: 0, Hits: 5, Size: -4, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Welch Foods
...The six pack has a &quot;best by June 1, 12&quot; date on it and the code is LT11F02 03 07. The juice tastes very plastic like and nasty....
...It had the worst chemical taste. I then smelled it and it smelled like pesticide....
 More 18 Complaints and Reviews about Heinz Foods 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/heinz.html 
 [Score: 69, Weight: 0, Hits: 4, Size: -6, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Heinz Foods
...The beans did not have a good taste ; they are not thick, more like soupy....
...even taste the baked flavor of brown sugar....
 More 20 Complaints and Reviews about Gatorade 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/gatorade.html 
 [Score: 69, Weight: 0, Hits: 5, Size: -6, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Gatorade
...I bought it from the local gas station, brought it home and took a big drink of it. After probably swallowing some, I spit out some slimy dark green/blue crap and it left a bad taste in my mouth....
...We bought a 12 pack of Gatorade Perform02 Cool Blue from WalMart in Ephrata WA. My son drank over half of the bottle before questioning the taste and discovering the hopefully foreign material....
 More 40 Complaints and Reviews about Denny&apos;s Restaurants 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/dennys.html 
 [Score: 69, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Denny&apos;s Restaurants
...I stayed in there and let them continue to disrespect me and my witness, with poor service and taste of food, and professionally misconduct customers&apos; rights, who are paying to be fed by Denny&apos;s....
...My meal tasted like a TV dinner and my poor husband&apos;s steak was so dry and gross looking....
 More 526 Complaints and Reviews about HFA Inhalers | Page 9 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/health/hfa_inhalers.html?page=9 
 [Score: 69, Weight: 0, Hits: 5, Size: -12, Age: 0]
I am losing hair from ProAir inhaler HFA. (Page 9)
...HFA propelled albuterol inhalers may taste and feel different than the CFC propelled albuterol inhalers....
...my asthma was under control for years before the switch from cfc to hfa inhailers.upon my first use of the new inhailer i became dizzy and my lungs felt sore like someone pulled a rake acrosss them the feeling lasted for 2 days. they also have a horrible taste and no matter how hard i inhale when using it and believe me when you...
 More 168 Complaints and Reviews about Gevalia Coffee | Page 6 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/online/gevalia_coffee.html?page=6 
 [Score: 69, Weight: 0, Hits: 4, Size: -6, Age: 0]
Gevalia scams us, customers and does not honor gift cards! I ordered a $100 gift card two years ago. The card explicitly stated there was no expiration date and that ... (Page 6)
...The coffee tasted funny. I tried bottled water, tap water, and filtered water, but nothing helped....
...i tried to order online in responce to an advertisement. each of four times it said failed. so i called, only to be told they do not accept debit cards. well, they sure got my money for the stuff. 4 times the $18.65! their product leaves a bad taste in my mouth.and ive NEVER tried it. caveat coffee emptor!...
 More 204 Complaints and Reviews about Starbucks | Page 4 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/starbucks.html?page=4 
 [Score: 69, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Starbucks (Page 4)
...They taste bland and the cups are 3/4 filled....
...My husband&apos;s tasted like old burnt coffee that had been sitting for hours!...
 More 273 Complaints and Reviews about Nutrisystem | Page 4 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/nutrition/nutrisystem.htm?page=4 
 [Score: 69, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Nutrisystem (Page 4)
...The food tastes better, much better!...
...I lost over $300 which, if I was not misled, I could have used to actually help lose weight without sacrificing taste. ...
 More Mushrooms Can Be Diet Staple, Not Just Pizza Topping 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com...-can-be-diet-staple-not-just-pizza-topping.html 
 [Score: 68, Weight: 0, Hits: 2, Size: -2, Age: -7]
Mushrooms Can Be Diet Staple, Not Just Pizza Topping The Mushroom Council hopes consumers will (re)discover the dirt-dwelling veggie
...They pick up and complement subtle flavors, adding taste without weighing down the dish with calories, fat, cholesterol or sodium....
...Mushrooms are rich in umami (the 5th taste known for its savory, brothy, rich or meaty taste sensation), which counterbalances saltiness and allows for less salt to be used in a dish without compromising taste. ...
 Northeast Grocery Chain Recalls Ground Beef Products 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com...grocery-chain-recalls-ground-beef-products.html 
 [Score: 68, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -2, Age: 0]
Hannaford, a Scarborough, Maine-based grocery chain, is recalling an undetermined amount of fresh ground beef products that may be contaminated with a stra
...&quot;80% Taste of Inspirations Angus Ground Beef&quot;...
...&quot;85% Taste of Inspirations Angus Ground Beef&quot;...
 More 867 Complaints and Reviews about GE Refrigerators | Page 12 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/homeowners/ge_refrigerators.htm?page=12 
 [Score: 68, Weight: 0, Hits: 5, Size: -10, Age: 0]
We purchased a new french door style stainless refrigerator and in less than 3 weeks, the compressor started making loud noises. The repairman came out and told us that our ... (Page 12)
...About six months ago the water that was coming out of the filtered water dispenser started to taste bad....
...I changed the filter, it still tasted bad and then I realized the fridge was leaking....
 More 161 Complaints and Reviews about Dollar General | Page 5 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/retail/dollar_general.html?page=5 
 [Score: 68, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Dollar General (Page 5)
...Bought charcoal at Dollar General that made my steaks and veggies to taste like CREOSOTE....
...The taste left was a bitter oil product taste. we allowed the charcoal to burn down as indicated on the side of the package etc....
 More Fruit and Vegetable Diet May Help You Stop Smoking 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com...d-vegetable-diet-may-help-you-stop-smoking.html 
 [Score: 68, Weight: 0, Hits: 2, Size: -2, Age: 0]
Reluctant smokers spend millions each year on smoking cessation programs and products, but maybe all that&apos;s needed is diet rich in fruit and vegetables, al
...And unlike some foods which are known to enhance the taste of tobacco, such as meats, caffeinated beverages and alcohol, fruits and vegetables do not enhance the taste of tobacco....
...In fact, Haibach says foods like fruit and vegetables may actually worsen the taste of cigarettes....
 168 Complaints and Reviews about Gevalia Coffee | Page 3 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/online/gevalia_coffee.html?page=3 
 [Score: 68, Weight: 0, Hits: 6, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Gevalia Coffee (Page 3)
...Initially, we ordered from Gevalia to get the free coffee pot but once we tasted the coffee, we were hooked....
...Received free samples. Every sample was identical: tasteless. ...
 More 42 Complaints and Reviews about Brita Water Filters 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/homeowners/brita_water_filters.html 
 [Score: 67, Weight: 0, Hits: 5, Size: -8, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Brita Water Filters
...The water tastes awful, as if it&apos;s not filtering at all....
...It just taste like faucet water. I would like to know if you could send me a new replacement filter....
 More 25 Complaints and Reviews about Albertsons 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/supermarkets/albertsons.html 
 [Score: 67, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -8, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Albertsons Supermarkets
...(these are my husbands favorite cookies and always buys them from this store), when we got home my husband and I and our daughter ate some of the cookies and all of us noticed that the taste was different from other times, they tasted STALE....
...Since my husband always buys them and we eat them we know when the cookies are fresh and taste good compared to this batch that tasted arwful....
 More 13 Complaints and Reviews about Frito Lay 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/frito_lay.html 
 [Score: 67, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -4, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Frito Lay
...It was like a plain chip. So where is the onion taste ?...
...The cookies taste like someone poured after shave in them....
 More 144 Complaints and Reviews about Bumble Bee Tuna 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/bumble_bee.html 
 [Score: 67, Weight: 0, Hits: 6, Size: -8, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Bumble Bee Tuna
...I made a sandwich, which tasted just fine; however, several hours later, I developed a stomach ache (nothing else) and have had it now for the past two weeks!...
...It is mushy, doesn&apos;t even taste like any kind of tuna I had years ago....
 More 10 Complaints and Reviews about Taco Bell 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/taco_bell.html 
 [Score: 67, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -4, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Taco Bell
...As I drove off, I took a sip of the ice tea, and my drink tasted like sewer water, what rotten water would taste like....
...She said that she was going to go and taste the tea....
 More 10 Complaints and Reviews about Medifast 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/nutrition/medifast.html 
 [Score: 67, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -4, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Medifast
...The food is an acquired taste, but I have been able to find little tricks that make it very enjoyable....
...I am not a picky eater. I eat diet foods, foods with no taste, foods low in sugar, etc. all the time, so I wasn&apos;t worried about this food until I actually ate it. Needless to say, I called them and immediately asked for a reimbursement....
 More Suit: Safeway&apos;s Kona Coffee Is Mostly Not From Kona 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com...feways-kona-coffee-is-mostly-not-from-kona.html 
 [Score: 67, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -2, Age: -4]
Safeway advertises its Safeway Select Kona Blend coffee &quot;as if Kona beans are the major portion of the Kona Blend,&quot; but they actually contain &quot;only a very
...A dedicated purchaser of the disputed coffee since 2006, Ms. Thurston took as gospel Safeway&apos;s assertion that she would &quot;revel in the unmatched taste of savory beans from Hawaii&apos;s big island&quot; when, in fact, she was reveling mostly in the taste of savory beans from elsewhere....
...Still tastes good....
 More What Does A Doctor Order At A Fast Food Restaurant? 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com...s-a-doctor-order-at-a-fast-food-restaurant.html 
 [Score: 67, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -2, Age: -2]
Tips for ordering at a fast food restaurant
...Cheese can add an additional 100 calories or more per serving, as does mayonnaise and, often, you won&apos;t miss the taste when ordering the plainer versions....
...The dressing is a cup of vinegar (pure apple cider is best), black pepper, stevia/splenda to taste, dash of lemon juice if prefered, 3 tbsps. water....
 More 397 Complaints and Reviews about Canidae Pet Foods | Page 10 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/pets/canidae.html?page=10 
 [Score: 67, Weight: 0, Hits: 4, Size: -14, Age: 0]
I have been trying to get dog food (large bag of Canidae All Life Stage formula) for my dog for over a couple of weeks. No one else handles it ... (Page 10)
...I found a great food Taste of the Wild Venison and Bison and all of my guys have improved and the runs are gone and their coats are great....
...They even stopped picking at their food and now are playing and happy guys I have no clue what I will do if Taste of the Wild changes its formula , my guys will even eat it dry not something they would do with canidae....
 More 1,206 Complaints and Reviews about Nutro Pet Foods | Page 8 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/pets/nutro.html?page=8 
 [Score: 67, Weight: 0, Hits: 4, Size: -12, Age: 0]
Nutro Natural Choice company testing: As per my prior post, I sent a sample of dry Grain-Free Venison to Nutro after it made our Welsh Corgi sick. Nutro rep Katy ... (Page 8)
...Since the bags of Nutro I recently purchased (which made my cats sick) have highlighted on the bag &quot;Improved Taste- New Look&quot; and they do list &quot;natural flavoring&quot;, this may actually be related to what is harming our pets....
...I reminded her the package says &quot;Improved taste &quot;&amp;both she&amp;another Nutro phone rep previously confirmed the formula changed with additional chicken meal....
 More 225 Complaints and Reviews about Wal-Mart - Dangerous Products, Conditions | Page 5 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/retail/walmart_hazards.html?page=5 
 [Score: 67, Weight: 0, Hits: 7, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Wal-Mart - Dangerous Products, Conditions (Page 5)
...We thought it was the weather. I finally tasted the water today myself....
...I tasted this water at 9:15 am today and it tasted dry and not so good....
 More 168 Complaints and Reviews about Gevalia Coffee | Page 5 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/online/gevalia_coffee.html?page=5 
 [Score: 67, Weight: 0, Hits: 5, Size: -8, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Gevalia Coffee (Page 5)
...The taste of this coffee is the only thing even remotely similar to the coffee that we have had in Paris....
...The taste of it just brings a bliss and excitement to the world of coffee drinking, and for me to get this goodness back is just so amazing....
 More 567 Complaints and Reviews about McDonalds | Page 4 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/mcd.html?page=4 
 [Score: 67, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -12, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about McDonalds (Page 4)
...The chips was terrible that had a bad after taste, the tomato&apos;s was mushy and old the lettuce was brown and look if it was a few days old and the patty&apos;s was disgusting....
...Now that I knew where the smell was coming from, I paid a bit more attention to the taste of the sandwich and this time I could taste the same sourness I was smelling....
 More 15 Complaints and Reviews about Philip Morris USA 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/misc/philip_morris.html 
 [Score: 67, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -4, Age: 0]
Consumer Complaints about Philip Morris USA
...Nasty amber one and the taste was stronger than what I am used to, not sure if it&apos;s the tobacco blend or the new filter....
...When I bought my first pack of cigarettes here, I noticed they tasted bad....
 More 74 Complaints and Reviews about Trader Joe&apos;s | Page 3 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/supermarkets/trader_joe.html?page=3 
 [Score: 67, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -4, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Trader Joe&apos;s (Page 3)
...The two from 080806 have a horrible chemical/metal like after taste, you can&apos;t even eat them, the taste/flavor of whatever it is, is very distinct....
...As long as I&apos;ve eaten these (one every morning) I&apos;ve never experienced this strange taste ???? ...
 More 160 Complaints and Reviews about Dollar General | Page 3 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/retail/dollar_general.html?page=3 
 [Score: 67, Weight: 0, Hits: 2, Size: -12, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Dollar General (Page 3)
...Most of the time, these chemicals can go undetected to the palate, but more often than not, you can taste the awful detergents, chemicals, etc in the food, and I feel that even if there is not an overtly bad taste, there is still an excess of unwanted and unhealthy chemicals in the food and we are ingesting them....
...Most of the time, these chemicals can go undetected to the palate, but more often than not, you can taste the awful detergents, chemicals, etc in the food, and I feel that even if there is not an overtly bad taste, there is still an excess of unwanted and unhealthy chemicals in the food and we are ingesting them....
 Complaints Board - Consumer Complaints, Reviews, Information | Foam Coffee Cup is Not Good for Coffee? 
 http://www.complaintsboard.com/articles/foam-coffee-cup-is-not-good-for-coffee.html 
 [Score: 67, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -6, Age: 0]
...Finally, using foam for cups do not alter the taste of coffee....
...There are actually no documented studies that show whether foam coffee cups affect the taste of coffee....
 More Complaints Board - Consumer Complaints, Reviews, Information | Unique Gift Ideas - Food Gifts That Offer Flavor And Help A Low Sodium Diet 
 http://www.complaintsboard.com...at-offer-flavor-and-help-a-low-sodium-diet.html 
 [Score: 67, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -6, Age: 0]
...Olive oils are flavorful, heart healthy, and every country or state tastes different....
...The more variety the better. If possible, get a variety or an assortment of the food gift so there is something for every taste. ...
 More 225 Complaints and Reviews about Wal-Mart - Dangerous Products, Conditions | Page 2 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/retail/walmart_hazards.html?page=2 
 [Score: 66, Weight: 0, Hits: 4, Size: -12, Age: 0]
Wal-Mart - Dangerous Products, Conditions (Page 2)
...It still had an odd smell, so I tasted it and it was rancid!...
...It was the 3rd package and opened it, horrible chemical taste and smell....
 More 35 Complaints and Reviews about Quaker Oats | Page 2 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/quaker_oats.html?page=2 
 [Score: 66, Weight: 0, Hits: 2, Size: -2, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Quaker Oats (Page 2)
...Quaker apparently changed the formula or something as the taste has changed....
...The last two boxes I purchased do not taste right....
 270 Complaints and Reviews about Farberware | Page 2 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/homeowners/farberware.html?page=2 
 [Score: 66, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -8, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Farberware (Page 2)
...Even after washing them several times in a dishwasher, the smell and foul taste are still there....
...You can taste it for several hours later....
 More 34 Complaints and Reviews about Chipotle 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/chipotle.html 
 [Score: 66, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Chipotle
...Does he not think someone wouldn&apos;t taste the unwanted food topping?...
...I&apos;m not one who typically likes to dine out so I usually get food to go and take it home with me, expecting it to taste just as good as it would have been in the restaurant....
 More 8 Complaints and Reviews about Baskin-Robbins 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/baskin_robbins.html 
 [Score: 66, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -4, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Baskin-Robbins
...I then tasted the drink which tasted like rotten mangos....
...Kim then put the drink on the counter stating that she did not want the drink because of the horrible taste that with the same drink she had not experienced in the past....
 More 235 Complaints and Reviews about Black&amp;Decker Coffee Maker 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/homeowners/blackdecker_coffee.html 
 [Score: 66, Weight: 0, Hits: 4, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Black&amp;Decker Coffee Maker
...What&apos;s worse, the chemical and plastic taste/smell is stronger now....
...I cannot get rid of the &apos;new plastic&apos; taste. ...
 More 147 Complaints and Reviews about Burger King | Page 4 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/burgerking.html?page=4 
 [Score: 66, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -8, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Burger King (Page 4)
...When she saw that I was watching what she was doing, she threw them away and asked me if I wanted onion rings to which I said no. She prepared some new fries but you could taste the old oil in them....
...There were no flame broiled marks or taste. ...
 More 3 Complaints and Reviews about Cabela&apos;s World&apos;s Foremost Outfitter 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/retail/cabelas-world-foremost-outfitter.html 
 [Score: 66, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -2, Age: 0]
Cabela&apos;s Reviews and Complaints - Real Consumer Experiences Help You Save Time and Avoid Scams.
...As I continued to carve, I cut a bite to taste for myself and was not able to swallow....
...It tasted like it sat in a brine tub for three days....
 More 159 Complaints and Reviews about Natural Balance Pet Foods | Page 3 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/pets/natural_balance.html?page=3 
 [Score: 66, Weight: 0, Hits: 3, Size: -10, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Natural Balance Pet Foods (Page 3)
...I&apos;m glad I read these reviews. I am searching for another food for our shelter animals since I have the same issues with both Purina ProPlan chix and rice for cats and Taste of the Wild Parrie....
...We fed Taste of the Wild for lunch and dinner, and she&apos;s already more energetic and has shown no sign of stomach upset. ...
 More 39 Complaints and Reviews about Kellogg&apos;s | Page 2 
 http://www.consumeraffairs.com/food/kelloggs.html?page=2 
 [Score: 65, Weight: 0, Hits: 2, Size: -4, Age: 0]
Consumer complaints about Kellogg&apos;s (Page 2)
...Kellogg is always happy to hear from consumers like you and eager to show you how our brands can satisfy your taste preferences and...
...Our food scientists have been working hard to reduce or replace the hydrogenated oils from our brands while retaining the taste and textures consumers love....
 
 Some similar pages were removed.
 Click here to search again without removing any pages. 
 Search results generated by Blossom. 
 [Next 100] 
 
   Copyright Blossom Software, All rights reserved
	</body>
</document>
