<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002055" url="http://ncgogreen.myncblogs.com/2009/08/07/green-fast-food/" time="2012-07-12-17:57" support="1" score="0.0019772781075757554" bingtitle="Green Fast Food | N.C. Go Green" webtitle="Green Fast Food|N.C. Go Green">
			<query id="000405" bing-rank="116"/>
	<description>She says, “85% of our waste is either recycled in the blue or composted in the green. ... It’s that mindset that these Bay area restaurants are banking on to take a bite ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Getting Started: Go Green Green 101: Going Green Guides Videos 
 
 Green Fast Food 
 Posted by admin August 7, 2009 
[vms=7695]

BERKELEY, Calif.—Amanda West is the woman behind one of Berkeley’s newest restaurants, Amanda’s Feel Good Fast Food.

It’s a twist on the conventional burgers and fries joint.

Using all natural beef for the burgers, baking the fries instead of frying them and freshly made sodas with organic agave nectar.

 The focus is on healthy foods to feed your stomach, and eco-friendly business practices to nourish your soul.

“Every decision we make in this community is about creating a healthy community and that’s from a healthy menu, and that’s also from a healthy environment,”says West.

Which is why West takes special pride in her trash room.

She says,“85% of our waste is either recycled in the blue or composted in the green.  This is the trash, little trash bin, and in the corner is the grease that’s recycled.”

Everything they sell is compostable and while all this may sound expensive amanda has a recipe to keep costs down.

“We’re focused on keeping a pretty simple menu and just doing lunch and dinner and just getting as many people though the door as we can,”says Amanda.

Amanda’s is just one of several Bay Area restaurants delivering healthy organic food in an eco-friendly restaurant.

Sellar’s Market in San Francisco uses the same business model.

“It’s a good alternative and it’s just as cheap as McDonalds and so it’s not like you’re paying more for going green which I think is really helpful,”says customer Mary Taloff.

It’s that mindset that these Bay area restaurants are banking on to take a bite out of the traditional fast food market.

Amanda West hopes to expand her restaurant beyond Berkeley in the future.
 Uncategorized 
 If you enjoyed this post, please consider leaving a comment or subscribe to the feed and get future articles delivered to your feed reader or email. 
 
Comments

No comments yet.

Sorry, the comment form is closed at this time.
 Subscribe to RSS 


 
Search
 
Archives

 December 2010 November 2010 August 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 
 
Categories

 air chapel hill climate conservation durham energy environment green greenway Raleigh recycle transit Uncategorized water 
 
 
Recent Comments


 
 
Archives
 Select Month December 2010 (1) November 2010 (1) August 2010 (1) May 2010 (9) April 2010 (1) March 2010 (17) February 2010 (28) January 2010 (30) December 2009 (9) November 2009 (10) October 2009 (5) September 2009 (16) August 2009 (36) July 2009 (14) June 2009 (12) May 2009 (9) April 2009 (36) March 2009 (24) February 2009 (16) January 2009 (16) December 2008 (19) November 2008 (30) October 2008 (33) September 2008 (25) August 2008 (30) July 2008 (39) June 2008 (14) May 2008 (15) April 2008 (32) March 2008 (17) February 2008 (11) January 2008 (9) December 2007 (6) November 2007 (6) 
 
 
Categories
 Select Category air chapel hill climate conservation durham energy environment green greenway Raleigh recycle transit Uncategorized water 
 
Powered by Wordpress | WP Premium theme by WP Remix 
Copyright 2007. N.C. Go Green. All rights reserved

 Subscribe to RSS Home Getting Started: Go Green Green 101: Going Green Guides Videos
	</body>
</document>
