<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002361" url="http://weightloss.about.com/od/diningout/qt/wendys.htm" time="2012-07-12-18:17" support="3" score="0.009310539998424634" bingtitle="Wendys - Most Healthy Fast Food Choices at Wendys" webtitle="Wendys - Most Healthy Fast Food Choices at Wendys">
			<query id="000901" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="000624" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000594" bing-rank="191"/>
	<description>Wendy&apos;s is a fast food restaurant popular for burgers and a soft-serve dairy dessert, the Frosty. Wendy&apos;s offers a few filling, diet-friendly items, such ...</description>
	<body>
		Health 
 Weight Loss Search 
 Weight Loss Healthy Eating&amp;Diet Fitness Motivation 

 Share 
 
 Discuss in my forum 
 
 Fast Food Quick Guide: Wendy&apos;s 

What Are the Most Healthy Fast Food Choices at Wendy&apos;s?

From Jennifer R. Scott , former About.com Guide

Updated July 14, 2009

About.com Health&apos;s Disease and Condition content is reviewed by our Medical Review Board 
 See More About: 
 healthy fast food choices eating out on a diet counting calories 
 Wendy&apos;s is a fast food restaurant popular for burgers and a soft-serve dairy dessert, the Frosty. Wendy&apos;s offers a few filling, diet-friendly items, such as a grilled chicken salad or small beef and bean chili for around 200 calories. But beware those fat-laden specialty burgers -- some pack in close to a thousand calories! This quick guide will help you identify the most healthy fast food choices at Wendy&apos;s.

Good Choices:

 fresh fruit bowl with yogurt - 220 calories fresh fruit bowl - 130 calories side salad - 35 calories broccoli and cheese potato - 330 calories Caesar chicken salad (no dressing or toppings) - 190 calories taco salad (no sour cream, chips, or salsa) - 360 calories small chili - 220 calories kids meal fries - 280 calories ham and cheese kids meal sandwich - 240 calories 


Less Preferable Choices:

 The Baconator - 840 calories Class Triple with Cheese - 970 calories blue cheese salad dressing - 260 calories Homestyle Chicken Strips (3) - 410 calories Premium Fish Filet Sandwich - 450 calories Honey BBQ Boneless Wings - 580 calories Frosty Float - 380 calories Classic Single with Everything - 420 calories Sweet and Spicy Asian Boneless Wings - 550 calories Crispy Chicken Sandwich - 380 calories 

I found all of the calorie counts for these menu items using About.com&apos;s Calorie Count . You can find many more listings for Wendy&apos;s menu items there, plus you can search for any other restaurants and types of foods, all for free.

 More Fast Food Quick Guides 

 
More Fast Food Quick Guides

 Arby&apos;s Quick Guide Taco Bell Sonic Drive-In 
 Related Articles 
 Fast Food - 500 Calorie or Less Fast Food Choices Atlanta Bread Company - Healthy Choices at Atlanta Bread Company Chickfila - Healthy Choices at Chickfila Restaurants Healthy Choices at Ruby Tuesday - What are the Most Healthy Choices at Ruby... Quiznos Subs - Healthy Choices at Quiznos Subs 
 Explore Weight Loss Must Reads 
 3 Best Weight Loss Tips Find the Best Diet For You Exercise for Weight Loss 10 Things to Stop Doing Get Diet Support from Family and Friends 
 Most Popular 
 Caloric Intake Is Loose Skin an Issue? Feel Fat? Stop Making These Portion Size Mistakes Know Your Danger Zones Losing Weight 
 See More About: 
 healthy fast food choices eating out on a diet counting calories 
 By Category 
 Weight Loss Basics Count Calories Exercise for Weight Loss Healthy Eating About Diets Nutrition Emotional Eating Eating Out Obesity&amp;Health Children&amp;Teens Weight Loss Surgery Glossary 
 Weight Loss 
 About.com Health Weight Loss 
 
 Most Popular Latest Articles RSS 
 Also from About.com: 
 Calorie Count - Nutrition Database 
 
 Advertise on About.com Our Story News&amp;Events Work at About SiteMap All Topics Reprints Help 

 Write for About User Agreement Ethics Policy Patent Info. Privacy Policy Your Ad Choices 
 
©2012 About.com. All rights reserved.

A part of The New York Times Company .
 We comply with the HONcode standard
for trustworthy health information: verify here .
	</body>
</document>
