<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002514" url="http://blogs.miaminewtimes.com/shortorder/food_facts/" time="2012-07-12-18:34" support="4" score="0.02410711270530417" bingtitle="&quot;Food Facts&quot; Archives - Miami Restaurants and Dining - Short Order" webtitle="&quot;Food Facts&quot; Archives - Miami Restaurants and Dining - Short Order">
			<query id="001163" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000632" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000440" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="000626" bing-rank="236"/>
	<description>... for maybe the baked beans), as do all of the condiments ... Give her a few minutes and she&apos;ll tell you why ... Fed&apos;s Primal Zin Wine Dinner; Salty American Fast Food; Restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Blogs 
 Entire Site Articles&amp;Blogs Restaurants Places Events Music Images Ads Bars Best Of Movies 
 News Home Riptide Strouse Luke&apos;s Gospel Letters Special Reports Archives Search New Times Flipbook Weekly Newsletter Get Mobile Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads New Times Web Awards Music Home Crossfade Concert Calendar Bars and Clubs Brew at the Zoo Submit an Event Music Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurants Home Short Order Find a Restaurant Menus Iron Fork Happy Hours Dining Deals Dining Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurant Ads Arts Home Cultist Visual Arts Theater Welcome to the Future Skrawberry Jam Artopia Arts Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Film Home Showtimes Cultist Film Film Poll 2011 Film Newsletter Get Mobile Free Stuff Best Of Home 2012 2011 2010 2009 Readers&apos; Poll 2012 Best Of Newsletter Get Mobile Best Of Ads Promotions Home Promotional Events Street Team Free Stuff On Sale Promotions Newsletter Get Mobile Deals Post an Ad Jobs Real Estate Advertiser Index Deals Deals Newsletter Virtual Job Fair 
Top

blog

Stories
 
 
 First Bites 

 Bloom&apos;s Upscale Fusion Street Food 

By Laine Doss
 
 Miami Spice 

 Miami Spice at Gotham Steak Hakkasan, Scarpetta 

By Laine Doss
 
 Holidays 

 Bastille Day at Brand New Fabien&apos;s Bistro 

By Lee Klein
 
 Best of Miami 

 Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants 

By Laine Doss
 
 First Bites 

 Iron Side Cafe: Fresh New Lunch Spot 

By Lee Klein
 
 Gastronomic Gatherings 

 Fairchild Makes Mangoes Exciting This Weekend 

By Laine Doss
 
 Chef on the Small Screen 

 Eat St. to Film Food Trucks in Miami 

By Laine Doss
 
 Food Charity 

 Taste of the Nation Celebrates 25th Anniversary 

By Laine Doss
 
 Neighborhood Joints 

 Shack Shack In Coral Gables Opening Soon 

By Laine Doss
 
 News 

 Zeke&apos;s Reincarnated: Rio Station 

By Hannah Sentenac
 
   Food Facts 
 Mosquito Season Is Here: Tame Bites With Vinegar, Meat Tenderizer, and Tea 
 By Laine Doss Thu., May 31 2012 at 8:53 AM Categories: Food Facts 
 Pin It 
 
 Did it get you? Here&apos;s how to stop the maddening itch. 
 Mosquito season is here. Fueled by the heavy rains last week, eggs are hatching at an alarming rate, causing the little monsters to swarm south Florida, making life difficult for everyone who wants to enjoy a cool drink on their porch after a long day.

Mosquitoes aren&apos;t just annoying, they&apos;re carriers of some nasty diseases like West Nile virus, malaria, and dengue fever, according to the Mayo Clinic .

What to do if one of those nasty bloodsucking insects takes a bite? Although there are dozens of chemical-based remedies at the drug store, your kitchen has a host of remedies that are just as effective, a lot cheaper, and better for you and the environment. Next time a mosquito gets you, try one of these home remedies:
 More &gt;&gt; Write Comment Email to Friend Food Facts 
 Miami&apos;s Best Macaroni and Cheese Dishes: Truffles, Lobster, Even Broccoli 
 By Laine Doss Mon., Jan. 9 2012 at 8:56 AM Categories: Best of Miami , Food Facts 
 Pin It 
 
 Food Network Macaroni and cheese: childhood favorite elevated to cult status. 
​ Macaroni and cheese. What began as an inexpensive school cafeteria lunch for most of us has turned into an adult&apos;s obsession: the search for the ultimate dish of firm noodles engulfed in creamy béchamel sauce and topped with a layer of golden-brown cheese.

Though the classic mac &apos;n&apos; cheese consists of elbow noodles and cheddar or American cheese sauce, there are so many variations -- topped with breadcrumbs, baked into individual mini casseroles, made with upscale ingredients such as truffle oil and lobster. Frankly, we love them all.

Here&apos;s a list of our top ten favorite mac &apos;n&apos; cheese dishes, from classic to epic. All have one thing in common: bubbling, cheesy goodness that warms both heart and stomach.
 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 CheeseMe , Prime One Twelve , Red The Steakhouse Write Comment Email to Friend Food Facts 
 Seven Billion and Counting: Dade&apos;s Farms Disappear, Hunger Grows 
 By David Minsky Mon., Oct. 31 2011 at 1:02 PM Categories: Food Facts , Food Industry , Food News 
 Pin It 
 
 via .:[ Melissa ]:.&apos;s Flickr (CC) 
​ The world&apos;s population reaches seven billion today, according to the United Nations. That has led to a lot of hand wringing about how we feed future populations around the world.

But what we really need to worry about is right here.

In both Miami-Dade and the rest of Florida, the population has increased while the amount of farmland has shrunk in the last decade. The number of folks living in the county jumped 10 percent to 2,496,435 while approximately 30,000 acres of farmland was lost due to real-estate development and the Everglades Restoration Act, which reduced farmland by at least 10,000 acres, said Debbie Brady, director of member services for the Dade County Farm Bureau.
 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 Miami-Dade farms Write Comment Email to Friend Food Facts 
 Pig 05049 Follows Piggly-Wiggly Right Into Your Shopping Cart 
 By Christina Staalstrom Fri., Sep. 30 2011 at 4:26 PM Categories: Food Facts 
 Pin It 
 
 From Pig 05049 by Chrstien Meindertsma Deep-fried pig nose. 
​ Generally speaking, being vegetarian is a choice. I am all for those who forgo meat for health reasons or just for the sake of feeling healthier and leaner. But keep me away from fashion-conscious tree huggers who look at us carnivores with disdain, while stomping around in leather shoes and chomping on Twizzlers touting, &quot;I don&apos;t eat meat because of the way animals are slaughtered&quot;.

This gets you to the top of my pet peeve list. True, there are many vegetarians who truly follow this mantra and don&apos;t wear any fur or leather, however, when was the last time you checked the ingredient statement on your daily dose of candy?

Christien Meindertsma recently published a three-year project called Pig 05049 researching all products made from a single pig. The result -- a whopping 185 items. Seemingly &quot;innocent&apos; things like chewing gum, marshmallows, store-bought bread and Jell-O contain porcine strands -- pig by-products. Pig protein, bone fat and hoofs. If the idea of eating piggly wiggly&apos;s hoofs turns you off, keep reading for a quick appetite suppressant.
 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 Christina Meinderstema , Pig 05049 Write Comment Email to Friend Food Facts 
 Ketchup: Way More Than You Need To Know About It 
 By Lee Klein Fri., Sep. 2 2011 at 8:44 AM Categories: Food Facts 
 Pin It 
 
 Lee Klein Ketchup didn&apos;t start out with tomatoes. 
​ Labor Day weekend brings hamburgers, hot dogs, barbecued chicken, cole slaw, some baked beans, chips and salsa (and perhaps guacamole), ice cream, beer, lemonade ... well, we can go on quite awhile with this list. Every one of these foods has a fascinating history (except for maybe the baked beans), as do all of the condiments used -- like, say, ketchup, which 97% of American kitchens are stocked with. Each one of us, in fact, consumes on average three bottles of the stuff a year.

Did you know that, like wines, there are good and bad ketchup years determined by the tomato harvest? Neither did I, but now that I do, I think it&apos;s high time someone introduced vintage ketchup with the year printed on the label.

Even though you&apos;re all very familiar with ketchup, there&apos;s probably a whole lot you don&apos;t know about it.
 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 Heinz Tomato Ketchup Write Comment Email to Friend Food Entrepreneur 
 Beekeeper Marcie Davis&apos;s Honey Mustard Miracle 
 By Laine Doss Mon., Jul. 18 2011 at 3:05 PM Categories: Food Entrepreneur , Food Facts 
 Pin It 
 
 all photos Laine Doss Forager bees coming home after collecting nectar 
​ Marcie Davis sells her local honey at the weekly Coconut Grove organic market and online . Wearing a bee necklace, she displays her wares with the smile of a mom showing what her child made in art class - local honey, bees&apos; wax candles in the shape of little hives, soaps. Give her a few minutes and she&apos;ll tell you why bees are so important and why she feels so strongly about her hives.
&quot;One third of all your food is dependent on honey bees&quot;, Davis says. Even digging into a steak you can thank bees, in part, since livestock eat grass, grain and other plant life.
 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 Coconut Grove Organic Market , Marcie Davis Write Comment Email to Friend Food Facts 
 Winnie the Pooh is Out Today: 10 Things You Didn&apos;t Know About Honey 
 By Mandy Baca Fri., Jul. 15 2011 at 11:00 AM Categories: Food Facts , Musings 
 Pin It 
 
 
​ Perhaps I could borrow some honey. (Pooh&apos;s stomach growls.) Just a taste. A small lick I should think. 

Have you seen the promos for the new Winnie the Pooh movie out today? It&apos;s so utterly nostalgic, (dare I even say cute?) capturing even the hearts of grown men.

Focusing on Pooh, he&apos;s the king of honey. You could also say that he&apos;s one BIG foodie. (Have you seen his belly? The true sign of a food connoisseur.) I could definitely hang with him.

Hell, I&apos;m sure he&apos;d know all the tricks of the trade -- type of bees that make the best honey, the best tasting honey and how to store the procured honey (I bet he&apos;d say pots).
 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 Mieli Thun , Winnie the Pooh Write Comment Email to Friend Food Facts 
 Video: Shrimp, Tang, and Urine: Ten Crazy Astronaut Food Facts 
 By Laine Doss Fri., Jul. 8 2011 at 9:20 AM Categories: Food Facts 
 Pin It 
 

 


 Astronauts chowing down at zero gravity 
​ According to NASA , the last space shuttle launch of STS-135 will take place at 11:26 this morning (be sure to turn on the TV). Just as space flight has evolved, so has the astronaut&apos;s diet of what used to be Tang and tubes of ham salad and cheddar cheese. In honor of the brave folks about to be shot into space, we bring you ten crazy astronaut food facts:





 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 astronauts , space food , space shuttle , STS-135 Write Comment Email to Friend Food Facts 
 Ten Things About Deep-Frying You Really Should Know 
 By Lee Klein Tue., Jun. 28 2011 at 8:39 AM Categories: Food Facts 
 Pin It 
 
 Lee Klein 
​ Great article about deep-frying in this month&apos;s Food Arts by Chris Young (co-author of Modernist Cuisine:The Art and Science of Cooking and head of The Fat Duck Experimental Kitchen for five years). Assuming you already know the basics of frying (the oil should be clean and hot, the food very dry), here are ten things that you may not have thought about:

10. Those bubbles you see in the oil after placing food in the fryer represents the evaporation of moisture -- the heat, in other words, is being used to vaporize water rather than to increase the temperature of the food. In fact, these bubbles actually serve to cool the surface of the food, so while the temperature of the fryer may be 400F, the effective cooking temperature is only 200F. Once the water is evaporated, the heat then goes towards browning the surface of the food.
 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 Chris Young , Food Arts Write Comment Email to Friend Food Facts 
 Pasta is the World&apos;s Favorite Food, Better than Italian... Steak, Pizza and Chicken 
 By Alexandra Leon Tue., Jun. 21 2011 at 9:34 AM Categories: Food Facts 
 Pin It 
 
 
 ​If you&apos;re like us, there are just too many different types of food to pick just one favorite. That&apos;s why we take friends to restaurants. We pretend to be social as their food shifts from their plates onto ours.

Yet, it seems that decision isn&apos;t so difficult for everyone. Last week, NGO Oxfam released the results of a survey , determining that there is indeed a resounding favorite. Over 15,000 people in 17 different countries were asked to give their top three food choices. Although there were variations between country, global results greatly resembled those of the US and UK.

So what food is so delicious, and so universal that it spans the world from Australia to Spain to Tanzania?

The answer would be pasta.
 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 Oxfam Write Comment Email to Friend &lt;&lt;Previous Stories 
Now Trending


 
Sign up for free stuff, news info&amp;more!
 
Slide shows » 

 Closer Look: Villa Azur Closer Look: Josh&apos;s Delicatessen&amp;Appetizing Rock &apos;n&apos; Roll Beer-B-Que 2012 at Seminole Hard Rock Hotel&amp;Casino More Slideshows&gt;&gt; 
 
 Restaurants 
 
 
Our pizza is simply an honest diversity of all-nat
 View Ad | View Site 
8oz Burger Bar
 View Ad | View Site 
The Corner
 View Ad | View Site 
Bagel Express
 View Ad | View Site 
 More &gt;&gt; 
Twitter Feed
 
 Follow short_order on Twitter 
 More Twitter &gt;&gt; 
Headlines from our Partners
 

 Summer Gold: Susser Talks Mangoes; London Burger King Installs a Damien Hirst Painting Boulud Hosting &quot;To Live and Dine in Miami&quot;; Balloo&apos;s Summer Additions at Sugarcane &quot;That Glow On The Beach&quot;: The 1950s Restaurants of 22nd Street Whiskey Joe&apos;s Set to Booze on Key Biscayne Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants; Watch an Ad For the Second Cheapest Wine Out There 
 
Links

Choice Eats

 All Purpose Dark ...And The Eggs Be A Wok Star
	</body>
</document>
