<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002349" url="http://www.linkedin.com/in/tedhclark" time="2012-07-12-18:16" support="5" score="0.00895000701599825" bingtitle="Ted Clark | LinkedIn" webtitle="Ted Clark | LinkedIn">
			<query id="000025" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000028" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="000016" bing-rank="219"/>
			<query id="000223" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="001446" bing-rank="75"/>
	<description>Product marketing management expertise with national fast-food restaurant chain and ... Food Products: Refrigerated Horseradish and Garlic, sauces and condiments</description>
	<body>
		Join Today Sign In 
 
 Ted Clark 

Category Sales Manager at The Neil Jones Food Company
 Location Dallas/Fort Worth Area Industry Food&amp;Beverages 
 Join LinkedIn and access Ted Clark’s full profile. 
 
As a LinkedIn member, you&apos;ll join 150 million other professionals who are sharing connections, ideas, and opportunities. And it&apos;s free! You&apos;ll also be able to:

 See who you and Ted Clark know in common Get introduced to Ted Clark Contact Ted Clark directly 
 
 View Full Profile 
 
Ted Clark&apos;s Overview
 Current 
 Category Sales Manager at The Neil Jones Food Company 
 Past 
 West Coast Division Sales Manager at Mill Creek Brands Director of Foodservice and Government Sales at The Sqwincher Corporation Regional Vice President at Tulkoff Food Products, Inc 
 
 National Accounts Manager at Mann&apos;s Company Manufacturer Representative at Wallace Systems National Accounts Manager at Portion Pac Inc/H.J. Heinz of North America National Distributor Group Sales Manager at Portion Pac Inc. Regional Sales Manager at Portion Pac Inc. Corporate Product Manager at Long John Silver&apos;s Inc. Field Marketing Manager at Long John Silver&apos;s Inc. Media Planner at Bloom Advertising Agency 

 see less 
 
 see all 
 Education 
 The University of Texas at Austin Baylor University - Hankamer School of Business 
 Recommendations 
 2 people have recommended Ted
 Connections 
 500+ connections
 
Ted Clark&apos;s Summary
 
Food and beverage sales professional specializing in government, military, schools, hospitals, colleges/universities and concessions sales channels. Product marketing management expertise with national fast-food restaurant chain and advertising media planning/buying with a leading national advertising agency.
 
Specialties

Food and Beverage Sales Management, New Business Development, Broker Manager, Strategic Marketing, Competitive Pricing, National Regional Key Accounts, Corporate Distribution Accounts, Military, Group Purchasing Organizations, C-Stores, Healthcare, Colleges/Universities/K-12 Schools
 
Ted Clark&apos;s Experience
 
 Category Sales Manager 

 The Neil Jones Food Company 
 
Privately Held; 1001-5000 employees;
Food Production industry

 August 2011 – Present (1 year) Dallas/Fort Worth Area 

Sales plan development and overseeing of broker market execution for the operational, environmentally green-friendly pouch packaging of processed California tomatoes/sauces to state of Texas customers. Initiating product sales strategies and tactics targeted to Military, Correctional and Regional Chain restaurants.
 
 West Coast Division Sales Manager 

 Mill Creek Brands 
 


 September 2010 – August 2011 (1 year) 

Direct sales activities for the MillCreek Brand bakery mix product line for the Western half of the United States targeting commercial foodservice accounts including Restaurant Chains, Colleges/Universities, Hospitals/Healthcare, Business and Industry, Correctional Facilities and other Government agencies. Parent company name is American Manufacturing and Packaging (AMP Corp).
 
 Director of Foodservice and Government Sales 

 The Sqwincher Corporation 
 


 July 2008 – June 2010 (2 years) 

Beverage Products: Electrolyte-based powders, concentrates and ready-to drink beverages

Launched a new Government and Military sales plan that boosted revenue levels by 20% in 2009 and outperformed the other Company business segments
Hired a leading Military consultant to best leverage international sales to achieve this revenue growth
Introduced Sqwincher to the Foodservice segment and established new National supplier agreements with the leading foodservice purchasing groups including Sysco Corporate and UniPro Foodservice
Penetrated new accounts and achieved new sales with high volume accounts including the US Army Central Command, Department of Homeland Security/Border Patrol and the Farner Bocken Company which supplies the new electrolyte freezer pops to 2,800 convenience stores in 15 states
 
 Regional Vice President 

 Tulkoff Food Products, Inc 
 


 November 2005 – June 2008 (2 years 8 months) 

Food Products: Refrigerated Horseradish and Garlic, sauces and condiments

Managed sales activities with 15 Foodservice broker firms representing 1/3rd of total company revenue of $30 million dollars
Launched a new private label SKU program with a leading foodservice distributor group, Independent Marketing Alliance, and closed a new contract with a key IMA distributor member, Reinhart Foodservice, which brought in significant new annual business of $500,000 to Tulkoff&apos;s existing $30 million revenue baseline
Signed new sales contracts with Tulkoff&apos;s leading national restaurant customers: Applebee&apos;s and Landry&apos;s
Established a new sales and marketing plan geared to the College/University end user markets seating new sauce products, i.e. Chipotle Chili Aioli, into cafeteria buffet-style serving operations

Ted Clark (cont&apos;d)
 
 National Accounts Manager 

 Mann&apos;s Company 
 


 January 2005 – November 2005 (11 months) 

Food Products: Frozen prepared soups and pastas
Maintained sales responsibility and new product development projects with national and regional multi-unit restaurant chains including Chili&apos;s, Hardee&apos;s and 7-Eleven
Coordinated and launched a new Frozen Tortilla soup to Consolidated Restaurant Operations, parent company of the El Chico Mexican dining chain
 
 Manufacturer Representative 

 Wallace Systems 
 


 June 2003 – December 2004 (1 year 7 months) 

Products: Digital Camera Surveillance and Enterprise-level software
Pioneered multi-unit restaurant account sales activities for Digital Witness and earned prime vendor status with the Luby&apos;s Cafeterias and M-Crowd Inc. taking revenue from zero to $250,000 in 2004
 
 National Accounts Manager 

 Portion Pac Inc/H.J. Heinz of North America 
 


 January 2002 – June 2003 (1 year 6 months) 

Food Products: Portion control condiments, sauces and dressings
Performed Midwest and Southwest U.S. sales activities focusing on eight accounts including Sonic, Whataburger, Hardee&apos;s, Braum&apos;s, Pizza Inn, Schlotsky&apos;s, Mazzio&apos;s and Texas Dairy Queen
Territory sales increased by 8%, totaling $30MM dollars outpacing overall company growth by 6%
 
 National Distributor Group Sales Manager 

 Portion Pac Inc. 
 


 January 1996 – December 2001 (6 years) 

Managed national foodservice purchasing group sales focusing on six accounts including Performance Food Group, Independent Marketing Alliance, UniPro and U.S. Foodservice totaling $60 million
Achieved a 42% sales increase during year 2000 and earned Portion Pac&apos;s top sales recognition, the Timeless Performance Award
Launched two private label product introductions, totaling 60 SKUs, for the Performance Food Group and Independent Marketing Alliance customer accounts
 
 Regional Sales Manager 

 Portion Pac Inc. 
 


 October 1992 – January 1996 (3 years 4 months) 

Managed ten foodservice and two convenience store/vending broker firms totaling $25 million in company sales
 
 Corporate Product Manager 

 Long John Silver&apos;s Inc. 
 


 November 1986 – September 1992 (5 years 11 months) 

Marketing responsibility for 1/3 of serving menu totaling $27MM dollars
Developed, consumer researched, market tested and launched a broiled and baked seafood menu to 1,500 system wide stores
 
 Field Marketing Manager 

 Long John Silver&apos;s Inc. 
 


 July 1985 – October 1986 (1 year 4 months) 

Executed Corporate and local store marketing, media and merchandising plans for 250 Southwest stores.
 
 Media Planner 

 Bloom Advertising Agency 
 


 May 1983 – June 1985 (2 years 2 months) 

Developed and executed multi-million dollar media plans and buying for key clients including Anheuser Busch/Earth Grains.
 
Ted Clark&apos;s Education
 
The University of Texas at Austin

 MA , Advertising (program hours completed) 

 1982 – 1983 



 Activities and Societies: Teaching Assistant, Marketing Department, Red McCombs School of Business
 
Baylor University - Hankamer School of Business

 BBA , Marketing/Statistics 

 1977 – 1981 



 Activities and Societies: Sigma Chi
 
Ted Clark&apos;s Additional Information
 Groups and Associations: 
 American Marketing Association, Dallas-Fort Worth Chapter Baylor University Alumni Association CPG Supergroup! - FMCG Professionals in Food, Beverage, Luxury, Household, Foodservice&amp;Retail Food Service Professionals Network FoodBev Network High Powered Food, Beverage&amp;Hospitality - Foodservice&amp;Retail Executive Networking Jobs Highland Park High School Alumni Association, Dallas, TX Hook &apos;em Horns Fans International Foodservice Manufacturers Association (IFMA) NO Budget Marketing National Association of Sales Executives Private Label and Contract Manufacturing Restaurant R&amp;D Sigma Chi Network Texas Exes/University of Texas at Austin The Purchasing Conference for Chain Restaurant Executives USGA Watermark CIM 
 
Contact Ted for:
 
 career opportunities job inquiries expertise requests business deals reference requests getting back in touch 
 
View Ted Clark’s full profile to...
 
 See who you and Ted Clark know in common Get introduced to Ted Clark Contact Ted Clark directly 

 View Full Profile 

Not the Ted Clark you were looking for? View more» 
 
Name Search:
 
 Search for people you know from over 150 million professionals already on LinkedIn.
 
 First Name Last Name 

 

Example: Ted Clark 
 
 Viewers of this profile also viewed... 
 
 Valari Szall 
 Regional Sales Manager at Fair Oaks... Steve Kellam 
 Southwest Region Business Manager at... Ian Davis 
 Director of Sales, CPG, Foodservice,... Steve Hundt 
 Director of National Accounts at The... Tim Michael 
 Regional Sales Manager Kathy Menger 
 Sales Consultant at ARAMARK Greg Nichols 
 Regional/Divsional Foodservice Sales... Janice Dyer 
 Non-Commercial Sales Manager at McCain... Scott Woodard 
 Director, National Accounts Sales and... TIM WEIR 
 National Sales Manager Foodservice at... 
 
 Find a different Ted Clark: 
 
 
 Ted Clark , Experienced Senior Corporate Science and Technology Recruiter

Greater Seattle Area
 
 Ted Clark , Technology and Project Management Professional

Toronto, Canada Area
 
 Ted Clark , Experienced Private Equity Investor and Advisor, Philanthropist

Greater Boston Area
 
 Ted Clark , VP of Operations at Clark Construction Consulting Services, Inc

Washington D.C. Metro Area
 
 Ted Clark , --

Greater Seattle Area
 

 More professionals named Ted Clark » 
 
LinkedIn member directory - Browse members by country 

 a b c d e f g h i j k l m n o p q r s t u v w x y z more 
 
By using this site, you agree to LinkedIn&apos;s terms of use . Commercial use of this site without express authorization is prohibited.

LinkedIn Corporation©2011

 User Agreement Privacy Policy Copyright Policy
	</body>
</document>
