<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002036" url="http://www.southafricafares.com/6.1%20JNB.htm" time="2012-07-12-17:56" support="3" score="0.001449734972278609" bingtitle="JNB info - South Africa Fares" webtitle="JNB info">
			<query id="000699" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="000738" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="000734" bing-rank="204"/>
	<description>... of Johannesburg toward Kempton Park. CLICK HERE FOR ROAD MAP Number of ... coffee shop, juice bar and a fast food restaurant. ... CAR PARKING: There are several car ...</description>
	<body>
		GETTING
 THERE 
 The routes&amp;carriers 
 Seat Plans 
 Airports 
 
 INSURANCE
 Benefits and cost 

 LINKS 
 Lappies Letters&amp;other South African
stories

 Safaris and more 

 About us 

 Home
 
 

 
       JOHANNESBURG AIRPORT 
    
 B ACK TO AIRPORTS 

 Location: The airport is located 22km east
 of Johannesburg toward Kempton Park. CLICK
 HERE FOR ROAD MAP 

Number of terminals: 6. A new Domestic Terminal is due to open by
 December 2003.   CLICK HERE
 FOR A MAP SHOWING LOCATION OF TERMINALS 
International arrivals will fly into the INTERNATIONAL
 ARRIVALS TERMINAL   . Travellers flying to other destinations
 within South Africa will have to proceed to  DOMESTIC DEPARTURES. 
Travellers leaving from Johannesburg International Airport do so from INTERNATIONAL DEPARTURES.  
 
TRANSFER BETWEEN TERMINALS: A free shuttle bus service departs
 every six minutes between all terminals and the car parks. 

INFORMATION AND HELP DESKS: Airport information desks are located
 in all terminals. Info Africa and the South African Tourism Board both have
 information desks in Terminal 2. For flight arrival and departure times (tel: (0)11 921
 6262). 

AIRPORT FACILITIES: Money and communications: ATMs, a full
 service bank and bureau de change facilities can be found in the International Arrivals
 and Departures halls. A post office is located between Terminals 2 and 3, and mobile
 telephone rental is also available. Shopping: The airport has a wide variety of
 shops, including a duty-free shop, florists, jewellers, pharmacy, sunglasses shop, sports
 shop, sweet shop, clothing accessories shop and a bookshop/newsagents. Eating and
 drinking: There are plenty of places to eat and drink. Food outlets include a coffee
 shop, juice bar and a fast food restaurant. Other facilities: There is a medical
 clinic in Domestic Arrivals (Terminal 4). 

DISABLED FACILITIES: Disabled parking spaces are available in the
 airport car parks and give direct access to the terminals. The free shuttle service which
 serves the remote car parking area can accommodate disabled passengers in wheelchairs.
 Disabled passengers can park in reserved spaces by displaying a disabled sticker; those
 without a disabled pass should contact the ACSA-JIA Help Desk (tel: (0)11 921 6262)
 for assistance. The airport has lifts (two of them are equipped with Braille) and ramps
 throughout the terminals. 

CONFERENCE AND BUSINESS FACILITIES: A fully-equipped, ten room
 conference facility (tel: (0)11 390 1330) is located in the Domestic Arrivals hall in
 Terminal 3; facilities include fax, telephone and secretarial services. 

CAR HIRE: Car hire companies including Avis , Budget , Europcar and Hertz are located in Domestic Arrivals. A Golf Cart service which can
 accommodate disabled passengers operates between the terminals and the car hire areas. 

CAR PARKING: There are several car parks offering short- and
 long-term parking. A free shuttle bus service departs every six minutes between the
 furthest car parks and the terminals. Passengers can pay for parking at &apos;pay on foot&apos;
 machines before they return to their car. 

DRIVING DIRECTIONS: From Johannesburg, take the R24 to the airport;
 from Pretoria, take the R21. 

PUBLIC TRANSPORT: A variety of approved public transport operators
 provide services between Johannesburg, Pretoria and their surrounding suburbs. For more
 information on public transport contact the information desk in Domestic Arrivals (tel:
 (0)11 921 6262). 

 

 

 

 

 

   
   

 
 OR CONTACT A SPECIALIST AT SOUTH TRAVEL INC - Tel (403)277-6884 or email info@southtravel.ca
	</body>
</document>
