<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002680" url="http://in.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20090323003430AA1nEFp" time="2012-07-12-18:44" support="1" score="0.00012502565028111784" bingtitle="Does oily food make acne worse? - Yahoo! Answers India" webtitle="Does oily food make acne worse? - Yahoo! Answers India">
			<query id="000150" bing-rank="233"/>
	<description>When you go to a fast food restaurant and get a burger or any other finger food, let it sit on a napkin for a minute or two to absorb the grease.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! India Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Health &gt; Diseases&amp;Conditions &gt; Skin Conditions &gt; Resolved Question 
 masterof... Member since: 17 March 2009 Total points: 895 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Does oily food make acne worse?
 Someone told me that eating oily food/ fried food makes causes acne. Can food really affect skin health? 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 by WhachooS... Member since: 11 February 2009 Total points: 12,365 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 Absolutely, but I think it&apos;s a little more complicated than that. Eat your lunch and dinner with 50% vegetables. Don&apos;t eat inflammatory foods like potatoes (french fries!) or tomatoes (ketchup!) or spicy things, so your skin will be less inflamed. Things will probably get better. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: would be nice if you could include more examples of inflammatory foods 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (6)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by sean C Member since: 13 January 2009 Total points: 4,632 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 From experience, I can tell you it definitely does. If I even picked up a pizza, then washed my hands (thoroughly), any left over residue would cause me to break out. The oil (from the burger fryer or deep fryer) gets absorbed into you skin, then when you touch your face, you push the oil from your hands into your pores. My advice (and this was seconded by my dermatologist), use a fork as much as possible and wash with dishsoap (she recommended using AJAX grapefruit dishsoap---&gt;not the orange scent, it contains different chemicals&lt;---, just put a travel size amount in one of those tiny Germ X bottles you see at the Wal-Mart check-out and wash up after eating). I&apos;ve been doing this for a couple of years now and it has really helped. When you go to a fast food restaurant and get a burger or any other finger food, let it sit on a napkin for a minute or two to absorb the grease. At night, use Witch Hazel astringent to wash your face (after using natural soap such as dove), it&apos;s good for your skin and can stop break-out before they start. I haven&apos;t had a break-out in almost two years, except when I went to Carl&apos;s Junior, but I actually expected that. Obviously, different people will tell you different things, but I had to learn the hard way. Keep your hands and face clean. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Dee Member since: 21 July 2008 Total points: 5,988 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 No, that is false. Food does no make you break out or cause acne. However; good vitamins and oils such as fish oils like omegas make the skin healthier.

*edit* I can tell you this much, acne is a condition in the pores...the oil glands. Not by getting burger grease on your face! Thats called having dirty hands and pusing bacteria in the pores! 
Source(s):
 I am a licensed esthetician, I do skin care for a living. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Jeniv the Brit Member since: 21 May 2006 Total points: 24,012 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Contrary to what some people think, foods have little effect on acne. Acne also isn&apos;t caused by dirt. In fact, scrubbing the skin too hard or cleansing with harsh soaps or chemicals irritates the skin and can make acne worse. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Chance D Member since: 04 June 2008 Total points: 2,261 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 interesting, ive never heard that
maybe...... 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 by hntraut Member since: 18 March 2006 Total points: 265 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 NO. 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 by delhiwalah.com forms, paper work Member since: 12 March 2009 Total points: 2,097 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Yes 
 3 years ago Report Abuse 
 
 
Discover Questions in Skin Conditions 

 Painful lump near armpit... What could it be? VERY SCARED? How do i get rid of my acne ? ive tried everything? Please help me cure my acne? My acne is just starting? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 
 
Related Questions

 does eating greasy and oily foods cause you to get acne/pimples?? Does water flush oily food from the body and prevent acne… will eating oily foods make my skin oily? Does eating oily foods can cause oily face? What are the best home remedies for acne that you have tried? 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Health 
 Diseases&amp;Conditions 
 Allergies Cancer Diabetes Heart Diseases Infectious Diseases Other - Diseases Respiratory Diseases Skin Conditions STDs 
 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Sponsor Results
 Provenance Skin Care Exclusive Botanical Skin Solutions www.passion4health.com Oily Or Acne Bargain Prices. Smart Deals. Explore Oily Or Acne ! BizRate.com Oily Or Acne Looking For The Best Deals, Eh? Save On Oily Or Acne ! Shopzilla.com See your message here... 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any user content on Yahoo! Answers. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2009 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines
	</body>
</document>
