<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002421" url="http://www.jail.org/pennsylvania/phila_698058_news_archives.htm" time="2012-07-12-18:21" support="1" score="0.000851786602125126" bingtitle="Phila Jail and Crime News Archives" webtitle="Phila 698058 News Archives Jail and Crime Reports">
			<query id="001437" bing-rank="158"/>
	<description>... two dogs found starving and buried in trash ... pleaded ... a suburban Philadelphia fast-food restaurant. The Bucks County ... American-Statesman Read more about the change ...</description>
	<body>
		Jails in Phila 698058 News Archives, Pennsylvania 
 Correctional Facilities and Public Records in Phila 698058 News Archives, PA 
 
 
 Home Phila 698058 News Archives Report A Crime Latest News Directory Crime Statistics Background Checks Videos 
 

 
 
 

 
 Write an Open Letter to an inmate 
 Click here to write and publish it. 
 
 Phila 698058 News Archives PA Directory 
 Pennsylvania State Prisons 
 
 
 Latest Related News in Phila 698058 News Archives 
 
 
 
 Get Alerted When A Crime Occurs
In Phila 698058 News Archives Or Anywhere Near You ! 
 
 
Ask A Question About Jails in Pennsylvania
 Type in your Question: 
 E.G. Do I Need a Criminal Lawyer? Add question details Details 
 Would you like to be notified by email when an answer is posted ? Your Email Address 
 Your Name or Nickname 
 1 x 1 = ? 
 This Question will be displayed live on Jail.org. 
 Mugshot and Inmate Directory 

 To find a mugshot, or an Inmate, click on the first letter of his Last Name. 
 A - B - C - D - E - F - G - H - I - J - K - L - M - N - O - P - Q - R - S - T - U - V - W - X - Y - Z - 
 Latest Q&amp;As; 


 Q: How can I find out how long someone will be in prison? 

 by Perri Post Answer Report Abuse 
 
 Type in your answer: 
 E.G. Do I Need a Criminal Lawyer? Your Email Address 
 Your Name or Nickname 
 8 x 2 = ? Notify me of new answers 
 This reply will be displayed live on this page 
 Q: i was denied visitation for 180 days due to coming up hot for herion,never in my life did it,i am on fentanyal patch and other meds,went got two letters from my dr stating that is why i am showing up for herion cause it is a opiod,got lists of meds from pharmacy,what can i do (Washington 2915404 News Archives PA)

 by pam Post Answer Report Abuse 
 
 Type in your answer: 
 E.G. Do I Need a Criminal Lawyer? Your Email Address 
 Your Name or Nickname 
 6 x 2 = ? Notify me of new answers 
 This reply will be displayed live on this page 
 Q: i would like to find out how many charges my cousins has and how to find ot where i go to see about seeing his case when he goes to court (East Stroudsburg PA)

 by dawn Post Answer Report Abuse 
 
 Type in your answer: 
 E.G. Do I Need a Criminal Lawyer? Your Email Address 
 Your Name or Nickname 
 7 x 2 = ? Notify me of new answers 
 This reply will be displayed live on this page 
 A: Pennsylvania has a website that you can use to view a persons court docket which will contain a small transcript of his court proceedings to date. Visit: http://ujsportal.pacourts.us/DocketSheets/CP.aspx You can search by name if you do not know the docket # of the case. 

 by PowderPA 
 

 Q: how to find what someone was arrested for (Mercersburg PA)

 by chris Post Answer Report Abuse 
 
 Type in your answer: 
 E.G. Do I Need a Criminal Lawyer? Your Email Address 
 Your Name or Nickname 
 7 x 1 = ? Notify me of new answers 
 This reply will be displayed live on this page 
 Browse By City 
 Abbottstown Abington Akron Albion Alburtis Aldan Aliquippa Allegheny Allentown Allison Park Allport Altoona Ambler Ambridge Annville Apollo Archbald Ardmore Ashley Aston Athens Auburn Avis Avoca Avondale Baden Bally Bangor Beaver Beaver Falls Beaver Meadows Beaverdale Bedford Belle Vernon Bellefonte Bellwood Bendersville Bensalem Benton Berlin Bernville Berwick Bethlehem Biglerville Birdsboro Blairsville Bloomsburg Blossburg Blue Bell Boyers Boyertown Braddock Bradford Breinigsville Bridgeport Bristol Brockway Brookhaven Brookville Broomall Brownstown Brownsville Bryn Athyn Buckingham Burgettstown Butler California Callery Cambridge Springs Camp Hill Campbelltown Canonsburg Canton Carbondale Carlisle Carmichaels Carnegie Catawissa Center Valley Chalfont Chambersburg Charleroi Chester Chester Springs Cheswick Chinchilla Clairton Clarion Clarks Summit Claysburg Claysville Clearfield Clifton Heights Clinton Clymer Coal Township Coaldale Coatesville Cochranton Cochranville Collegeville Columbia Confluence Conneaut Lake Connellsville Conshohocken Conyngham Coopersburg Coplay Coraopolis Corry Coudersport Covington Township Cranberry Township Crescent Cresson Cressona Crum Lynne Curwensville Dallas Dalton Danville Darby Delmont Denver Derry Dickson City Donora Douglassville Dover Downingtown Doylestown Drexel Hill Drums Du Bois Duncannon Duncansville Dunmore Dupont Dushore East Earl East Freedom East Mc Keesport East Pittsburgh East Stroudsburg Easton Ebensburg Edinboro Edwardsville Eldred Elizabeth Elizabethtown Elkins Park Ellwood City Elysburg Emlenton Emmaus Enola Ephrata Erie Essington Etters Evans City Everett Exeter Exton Fairchance Fairfield Fairless Hills Farrell Fayetteville Feasterville Trevose Fleetwood Folcroft Folsom Ford City Fort Washington Fountain Hill Frackville Franconia Franklin Freeland Freemansburg Freeport Gaines Galeton Garnet Valley Gettysburg Gibson Gibsonia Gilbertsville Girard Girardville Glassport Glen Campbell Glenshaw Glenside Gouldsboro Greencastle Greensburg Greenville Grove City Halifax Hamburg Hanover Hanover Township Harding Harmony Harrisburg Harrisville Harveys Lake Hatboro Haverford Havertown Hawley Hazleton Hellertown Hermitage Highspire Hiller Hilltown Hollidaysburg Homer City Homestead Honesdale Hop Bottom Horsham Houston Houtzdale Hughesville Hummelstown Huntingdon Indiana Industry Inkerman Irwin Jamestown Jamison Jeannette Jenkintown Jersey Shore Jessup Jim Thorpe Johnsonburg Johnstown Jonestown Kelayres Kennedy Kennett Square Kingston Kittanning Knox Knoxville Koppel Kulpmont Kutztown Lafayette Hill Lake City Lake Harmony Lampeter Lancaster Langhorne Lansdale Lansdowne Lansford Latrobe Lawrenceville Lebanon Leechburg Leesport Lehigh Valley Lehighton Lemoyne Levittown Lewisburg Ligonier Lititz Littlestown Llewellyn Lock Haven Loretto Loysville Lykens Macungie Mahanoy City Manheim Manor Mansfield Mar Lin Marcus Hook Marienville Marietta Mars Martinsburg Mary D Masontown Matamoras Mayfield Mc Connellsburg Mc Donald Mc Elhattan Mc Kees Rocks Mc Sherrystown Mcadoo Mckeesport Meadville Mechanicsburg Media Mehoopany Mercer Mercersburg Meyersdale Middleburg Middletown Midland Mifflinburg Mifflintown Milbourne Milford Mill Hall Millersburg Millersville Millvale Millville Milton Minersville Mohnton Monaca Monessen Monongahela Monroeville Montgomery Montoursville Montrose Moosic Morgan Morgantown Morrisville Morton Moscow Mount Carmel Mount Holly Springs Mount Jewett Mount Joy Mount Lebanon Mount Union Mount Wolf Mountain Top Muncy Nanticoke Nanty Glo Narberth Natrona Heights Nazareth Nelson Nescopeck Nesquehoning New Berlin New Bethlehem New Bloomfield New Brighton New Castle New Cumberland New Freedom New Holland New Hope New Kensington New Ringgold New Stanton Newmanstown Newport Newtown Square Newville Norristown North Apollo North East North Versailles North Wales Northampton Northern Cambria Northumberland Norwood Oakdale Oakmont Oil City Old Forge Oley Olyphant Orangeville Osceola Osceola Mills Oxford Palmerton Parkesburg Peckville Pennsburg Perkasie Petersburg Pgh Phila Philadelphia Philipsburg Phoenixville Pine Grove Pipersville Pittsburgh Pittston Plains Plumsteadville Plumsteadvlle Plymouth Plymouth Meeting Point Marion Port Allegany Port Carbon Portage Pottstown Pottsville Presto Prospect Punxsutawney Quakertown Quarryville Reading Rehrersburg Renovo Reynoldsville Richboro Ridgway Ridley Park Rimersburg Riverside Robesonia Rochester Rockwood Rome Roseto Royersford Rural Valley Saegertown Saint Clair Saint Marys Salix Sarver Saxonburg Saxton Sayre Schaefferstown Schuylkill Haven Schwenksville Scott Township Scranton Selinsgrove Sellersville Sewickley Shamokin Dam Sharon Sharon Hill Sharpsville Shavertown Sheffield Shermans Dale Shinglehouse Shippensburg Shippenville Shippingport Shohola Sidman Skippack Slippery Rock Slovan Smethport Smithfield Smock Solebury Somerset Souderton South Fork South Mountain South Park Southampton Spring Church Spring City Spring Grove Spring House Springdale Springfield State College Steelton Stevens Stewartstown Stockertown Stroudsburg Summit Hill Sunbury Susquehanna Swarthmore Sweet Valley Swiftwater Sybertsville Tamaqua Tarentum Tatamy Taylor Telford Thornton Throop Tidioute Tionesta Titusville Towanda Tower City Transfer Tremont Trevorton Trevose Troy Tunkhannock Turtle Creek Tyrone Uniontown Upper Black Eddy Upper Darby Valencia Valley View Vandergrift Verona Wallingford Walnutport Wampum Warminster Warren Warrington Washington Watsontown Wattsburg Waymart Wayne Waynesboro Waynesburg Wellsboro Wernersville West Chester West Hazleton West Middlesex West Mifflin West Newton West Pittston Westfield Wexford White Haven White Oak Whitehall Wiconisco Wilburton Wilkes Barre Williamsburg Williamsport Williamstown Wilmerding Windber Woodlyn Worthington Wrightsville Wyoming Wyomissing Yardley Yeagertown York York Springs Youngsville Zelienople 
 Browse By County in Pennsylvania 
 Adams County Allegheny County Armstrong County Beaver County Bedford County Berks County Blair County Bradford County Bucks County Butler County Cambria County Cameron County Carbon County Centre County Chester County Clarion County Clearfield County Clinton County Columbia County Crawford County Cumberland County Dauphin County Delaware County Elk County Erie County Fayette County Forest County Franklin County Fulton County Greene County Huntingdon County Indiana County Jefferson County Juniata County Lackawanna County Lancaster County Lawrence County Lebanon County Lehigh County Luzerne County Lycoming County Mckean County Mercer County Mifflin County Monroe County Montgomery County Montour County Northampton County Northumberland County Perry County Philadelphia County Pike County Potter County Schuylkill County Snyder County Somerset County Sullivan County Susquehanna County Tioga County Union County Venango County Warren County Washington County Wayne County Westmoreland County Wyoming County York County 
 Browse By State 
 Alabama 
 Alaska 
 Arizona 
 Arkansas 
 California 
 Colorado 
 Connecticut 
 Delaware 
 District of Columbia 
 Florida 
 Georgia 
 Hawaii 
 Idaho 
 Illinois 
 Indiana 
 Iowa 
 Kansas 
 Kentucky 
 Louisiana 
 Maine 
 Maryland 
 Massachusetts 
 Michigan 
 Minnesota 
 Mississippi 
 Missouri 
 Montana 
 Nebraska 
 Nevada 
 New Hampshire 
 New Jersey 
 New Mexico 
 New York 
 North Carolina 
 North Dakota 
 Ohio 
 Oklahoma 
 Oregon 
 Pennsylvania 
 Rhode Island 
 South Carolina 
 South Dakota 
 Tennessee 
 Texas 
 Utah 
 Vermont 
 Virginia 
 Washington 
 West Virginia 
 Wisconsin 
 Wyoming 
 
 
 Phila 698058 News Archives PA Public Records and News 
 Phila 698058 News Archives Warrants Phila 698058 News Archives Wanted People Phila 698058 News Archives Recent Arrests Phila 698058 News Archives Recent Convictions Phila 698058 News Archives Recent Sentencing&amp;Judgments 
 
 
 
Crime Statistics For 
 County * , PA
 Data for Phila 698058 News Archives isn&apos;t available. 
 75 Murders in 2009 523 Rapes in 2009 7 673 Violent Crime in 2009 12 767 Burglaries in 2009 2 280 Robberies in 2009 4 795 Assaults in 2009 4 911 Auto Thefts in 2009
 * Stats for sum of available city data in County 
 
 Recent Comments 


 Lancaster County man facing theft, drug charges So...If you as a reader are doing drugs,this is where you&apos;ll end up. It is an expensive habit and you will do anything for that high.You will also loose ev(...)
 03 31, 2012 | 12:30 Report Abuse 
 
 Easton woman accused of molesting 3 boys - Allentown Morning Call Criminal background checks can only identify people with criminal convictions for child sexual abuse. However, most acts of child sexual abuse are never re(...)
 02 02, 2012 | 21:12 Report Abuse 
 
 Susquehanna County Man Dies While Working at Elk Mountain Wayne was a great person and father. He will be missed by many. (...)
 10 13, 2011 | 16:23 Report Abuse 
 
 Recent Open Letters 


 To Deondre Mcqueen, in Lawrence County Correction Whats up bro how you been? This is Brail. How everything been going for you? What eric been up to? My address is 900 agnew rd. Pittsburgh,Pa 15227(...)
 Report Abuse 
 
 To Sheridan Boothe, in Sci Frackville hey hope you see this or one of your jail buddies does and let&apos;s you know. I miss you so much I have been like a bloodhound trying to track yo butt down. L(...)
 Report Abuse 
 
 To Joshua Younh, in Sci Greene hello my old friend and lover its been so long since I last wrote u a letter but we lost contact and I started a new life I cant write to u for reasons tha(...)
 Report Abuse 
 
 To Robert Littlepage, in Armstrong County Jail Hey stink I know u tryed to get in touch with at the time my phone services didn&apos;t allow me to accept collect calls, I just wanted to u know there&apos;s not a(...)
 Report Abuse 
 
 Recent Reports 


 Jerome Kirsch, Jr. (Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania) Jerome Kirsch, Jr. breaks his probation and has a warrant for his arrest for his second PFA violation. Jerome Kirsch, Jr. has a trial scheduled for Januar(...)
 Report Abuse 
 

 Robber Holds Up OC Sturdy Savings Bank 
 Updated: 
 
 News12: Ex-state Sen. Vincent Leibell begins prison sentence 
 Updated: 
 
 Officer, Driver Hurt Following High-Speed Chase On I-79 
 Updated: 
 
 Rep. Clymer, Roebuck, Vereb, Frankel 
 Updated: 
 
 Jerry Sandusky HD VIdeo 
 Updated: 
 
 Sandusky Arrested on New Sex Abuse Charge (News) 
 Updated: 
 
 Sandusky Arrested on New Sex Abuse Charges Watch Full News 
 Updated: 
 
 Jerry Sandusky News 
 Updated: 
 
 Former UConn Football Player Held In Off-Campus Cal U. Rape Case 
 Updated: 
 
 The Obama Impeachment Is Moving Forward With Fast And Furious Swiftness ! 
 Updated: 
 
 The Engineered Collapse Of Free Society ! 
 Updated: 
 
 Why Isn&apos;t Obama In Jail For Killing The Worlds 2 Largest Oceans ? 
 Updated: 
 
 Tampa Police Arrest Suspect in the 2009 Murder of UT Student Ryan McCall 
 Updated: 
 
 Newlyweds Stole Reception Food. 
 Updated: 
 
 Richard Hughes for Judge 2009 
 Updated: 
 
 SANDUSKY FOUND GUILTY OF SEX ABUSE // BREAKING NEWS 
 Updated: 
 
 Fast And Furious Petition To Jail Obama Holder , And Napolitano ! 
 Updated: 
 
 Pennsylvania woman accused of child neglect in Fort Pierce 
 Updated: 
 
 Latest Blog Article 
 
 How to Visit an Inmate 
Visits in jail, although they may be daunting, can be hassle-free; with approval from an inmate, the right identification and a prior understanding of the proceedings, almost anyone can pay a friend o(...)
 Read The Article 
 
 
 
 
 
   

 Copyright (c) 2011 - Contact - Terms&amp;Conditions 
Please note that Jail.org is a privately owned website and is not owned, operated, or affiliated with any government agency.
	</body>
</document>
