<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002767" url="http://www.canberratimes.com.au/world/bronto-burger-off-stone-age-menu-20120303-1u9kj.html" time="2012-07-12-18:49" support="2" score="0.0021186890096035987" bingtitle="Bronto burger off Stone Age menu" webtitle="Bronto burger off Stone Age menu">
			<query id="001147" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="000585" bing-rank="61"/>
	<description>... but the chef behind its first &apos;&apos;caveman fast food&apos;&apos; restaurant ... Rugby World Cup Hub; RWC Live Scores; Latest sport ... $0 Fee Credit Card. 0% balance transfers for 6 months + $ ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to navigation Skip to content Help using this website - Accessibility statement 
 JavaScript disabled. Please enable JavaScript to use My News, My Clippings, My Comments and user settings.

 New feature Personalise your news, save articles to read later and customise settings View Demo 
 Hi there! 
 Sign-up Log in 
 Beta version 
If you have trouble accessing our login form below, you can go to our login page .
 
 12:41AM Friday Jul 13, 2012 Send news tips/photos 
 Fairfax Digital 
 Canberra Times Classifieds 
 Place An Ad Search Classifieds Place A Free Ad Trades&amp;Services Events 
 Real Estate Cars Jobs Dating Newsletters More 
 Essential Baby Stayz InvestSMART Trading Room Weatherzone More sites» 
 
 
 Canberra Times 

 World 

 ACT News National World Business Environment National Times Tech Digital Life Entertainment Life&amp;Style Travel Cars Sport 

 You are here: Home World Article 
 
Search canberratimes:
 
Search in:

 canberratimes.com.au 
 canberratimes.com.au 
 
 
Bronto burger off Stone Age menu
 Date March 4, 2012 
 Read later 
 
Copenhagen
 
 Tweet Email article Print 
 
Modern Nordic cuisine has put the Danish capital at the top of the culinary world, but the chef behind its first &apos;&apos;caveman fast food&apos;&apos; restaurant, Paleo, takes inspiration from the Stone Age to create primal gastronomy.

There will be hot dogs and pizzas on the menu, but no buns or dough. Paleo will serve meat, fish, berries and vegetables, but no starch, refined sugars or dairy products are allowed.

&apos;&apos;Bread is the devil,&apos;&apos; says Thomas Rode Andersen, 43, who has created the menu for Paleo and is head chef at the Michelin-starred Kong Hans in Copenhagen. Mr Andersen hopes his takeaway will inspire people to try a healthy alternative. The menu includes &apos;&apos;meatza&apos;&apos;, essentially a meat pizza turned upside down with a base of organic ground beef.

The so-called paleo diet has a large following in the United States.
 Advertisement 
 Guardian News&amp;Media 
 
 Tweet Email article Print Reprints&amp;permissions 
 Advertisement 
 
 Latest Video 
 
World News Video More video 
 
What lies beneath

Sharks are terrifying out in the ocean but, as this video proves, they can also surprise people while they think they&apos;re safe in their own homes.
 
 Click to play video 
 Sunset snappers hold up NY traffic 
 Click to play video 
 &apos;The supermarkets are milking us&apos; 
 Click to play video 
 Police probe billionaire&apos;s death 
 
 
 Featured advertisers Sponsored links 
Special offers Powered by Mozo 
 View these special offers by Mozo. Advertisement Advertisement 
 Business 
 
 How to calculate your tax rate 
 
 Theage.com.au Ask our small biz experts How to price website ads Online coffee success story 
 
 Jobs 
 
 Personalise your job search with MyCareer 
 
 Mycareer.com.au Sign up to the new MyCareer Don&apos;t miss the latest jobs. 1000&apos;s of jobs in Australia 
 
 Essential Baby 
 
 Sienna Miller&apos;s baby name revealed 
 
 Essentialbaby.com.au Ovulation Calculator Due Date Calculator Discuss pregnancy 
 
 Holiday Rentals 
 
 50 getaways up for grabs over 50 days! 
 
 Stayz.com.au Gold Coast getaways Holiday on the South Coast Pet-friendly rentals 
 
 Find A Babysitter 
 
 Juggling between family&amp;work? Get help now! 
 
 Findababysitter.com.au Sydney Child Care Canberra Child Care Port Macquarie Child Care 
 
Compare and Save
 
Skip to:

 Best Deals Mobile Broadband Home Loans Credit Cards Low Rate Cards Rewards Cards Savings Accts Term Deposits Loans 
 
Check out today&apos;s best deals
 
 USaver Rate Increase 
 
 NEW 5.71% bonus rate for popular USaver account 
 
 Compare rates 
 
 ANZ Online Saver 
 
 5.25% bonus rate. Until 30/11/2012 
 
 Check it out&gt;&gt;&gt; 
 
 UHomeLoan 
 
 Low 5.62% comparison rate + $500 EFTPOS gift card 
 
 Save now&gt;&gt;&gt; 
 
 Bonus Beats Headphones 
 
 On HTC One S and HTC One. RRP of $279 
 
 Free Headphones 
 
 Samsung Galaxy S3 
 
 Save 10% online, compare double data offers and more.... 
 
 Compare Online Deals 
 
Readers&apos; most viewed
 Most viewed articles on The Sydney Morning Herald 
Top 5 World articles

 How I convinced Bill to give away his billions Money and drugs: the lethal cocktail &apos;This appears to go beyond abuse to what I would consider torture&apos;: husband allegedly treated wife like a slave The curious case of the chain link, Occupy Wall Street and the killing of Sarah Fox Billionaire Tetra Pak heir&apos;s wife may have been dead for a week, police suspect 
 Most viewed articles on The Age 
Top 5 World articles

 The curious case of the chain link, Occupy Wall Street and the killing of Sarah Fox &apos;This appears to go beyond abuse to what I would consider torture&apos;: husband allegedly treated wife like a slave How I convinced Bill to give away his billions Billionaire Tetra Pak heir&apos;s wife may have been dead for a week, police suspect Money and drugs: the lethal cocktail 
 Most viewed articles on WA Today 
Top 5 World articles

 The curious case of the chain link, Occupy Wall Street and the killing of Sarah Fox &apos;I thought it was an atomic bomb&apos;: exploding train forces residents to flee Money and drugs: the lethal cocktail &apos;Weirdest job in Whitehall&apos;: UFOs, men in black and Chelsea FC Marine parasite named after Bob Marley 
 Most viewed articles on Brisbane Times 
Top 5 World articles

 Husband kept wife in chains for 10 years: police &apos;I thought it was an atomic bomb&apos;: exploding train forces residents to flee &apos;Weirdest job in Whitehall&apos;: UFOs, men in black and Chelsea FC The curious case of the chain link, Occupy Wall Street and the killing of Sarah Fox Romney booed in pitch for black vote 
 Most viewed articles on Canberra Times 
Top 5 World articles

 Billionaire Tetra Pak heir&apos;s wife may have been dead for a week, police suspect Putin sends warships to boost Syria Billionaire held after wife&apos;s body found in London home Money and drugs: the lethal cocktail Taliban reject Karzai&apos;s plea for peace talks 
 
 Canberra Times ACT News National World Environment Opinion Business Technology Digital Life Entertainment Life&amp;Style Travel Cars Sport 
 
 
Canberra Times
 Sitemap Send Us News Contact Us Advertise with Us Text Version Site Accessibility Guide 

 
Products&amp;Services
 Good Food Guide Newsletters Canberra Times Photos Canberra Times Events Trades&amp;Services Directory 

 
Connect
 Mobile Site RSS Facebook Twitter 

 
Classifieds
 Place an Ad CT Classifieds&amp;Notices Accommodation Cars Dating Jobs Property Price Data Domain Other Classifieds&amp;Notices 

 
Fairfax Media
 Member Centre Conditions of Use Privacy Policy News Store Archive Photo Sales Purchase Front Pages Fairfax Syndication Fairfax Events Fairfax Careers Press Council 
 Fairfax Media 
Our Sites

 The Sydney Morning Herald The Age MyCareer Domain Drive RSVP Essential Baby InvestSMART APM Stayz Weatherzone The Vine 

Our Partners

 Business Hair Salons Electricians Fitness Homebuilders Lawyers Mechanics Wine Wedding Wine 
 Copyright©2012 Fairfax Media
	</body>
</document>
