<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002722" url="http://www.vcarious.com/Travel-Guide/UnitedStates/California/MillValley/FoodandDrink.html" time="2012-07-12-18:47" support="3" score="0.003278253759793356" bingtitle="Mill Valley Food and Drink - Travel Guides, Photos, Videos, and ..." webtitle="Mill Valley Food and Drink">
			<query id="000233" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000250" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="000235" bing-rank="104"/>
	<description>... consultants and students crowding the tables ... This little Indian fast-food restaurant has a limited menu but it ... on the terraces to a glass of fine wine or a cocktail ...</description>
	<body>
		Hi guest !   Login  |  Sign up 
 Search:    All Photos Journals Travel Guides Hotels&amp;Atttractions   
 
 
   
 
     
 
   
 
     
 
 
 Discover Destinations and Share Your Experiences 
 
 
 
 
 
Travel Guide:

Mill Valley Food and Drink
 Find Discount Hotels: 

 North America  &gt;  United States  &gt;  California  &gt;  Mill Valley   


 
 

 Guide Sections Introduction Things to See and Do (13) Accommodations (133) Food and Drink (459) Nightlife (18) Sports, Health, and Fitness (2) 

 

 

 

 Top Contributors andrewprice03 

 
 
 
 Food and Drink 
   

 
 Cafes and Bakeries 
   

 
 Ritual Coffee Roasters (11 miles away) 

 Ritual Coffee Roasters is widely regarded to have some of the best coffee in San Francisco and certianly in the Mission district. It&apos;s not necessarily cozy but it is a center of neighborhood activity. If you drop by on a sunday afternoon you&apos;ll see the pace in full effect: hipsters, consultants and students crowding the tables, couches and bar, getting their caffiene and chatting to an indie rock... 
   
 Nomad Cafe (18 miles away) 

 This bright and socially conscious cafe is pretty small and usually packed. There are a few internet terminals, a few tables, and a few pillows for lounging while you sip your stimulants. The Nomad also has some surprisingly good food despite their lack of kitchen. The one downside? It&apos;s expensive. A delicious roasted pepper and swiss pannini will set you back about $7. 
   
 Jumpin&apos; Java (18 miles away) 

 This cafe is simple but charming. The unpretentious decor and unbelievably friendly owner and staff make it an especially pleasant place to read the paper and get your caffiene in the mornings. You may find yourself briefly becoming part of their regular clientele. There are also a few pastries in the offing and plenty of tables to do computer work at if you bring a laptop. 
   
 Au Coquelet Cafe (17 miles away) 

 This place is incredibly versatile. It&apos;s open late, has a full kitchen with some really tasty sandwiches and soups, and delicious espresso drinks. The room in the front feels sort of like a bohemian cafe with the exposed brick walls and hanging artwork. The room in the back feels like a legit diner. If you&apos;re hungry late this is a great alternative to fast food. 
   
 Restaurant 
   

 
 Ora Restaurant Bar&amp;Lounge 

 Experience Mill Valley&apos;s chic Pan-Asian restaurant and lounge - a gathering experience unlike anything in the Bay Area. Create your own happening for 4 people or 40 with small plates, a sake flight menu, waterfalls and silent films...these details create the destination that is Ora Restaurant Bar&amp;Lounge, an unforgettable dining place in the heart of the North Bay. 
   
 El Paseo 

 Welcome to El Paseo Restaurant. 

We are located in down town Mill Valley, just a 15 minute drive from Golden Gate Bridge. El Paseo has been in business for over 35 years and it is known as The Most Romantic restaurant in the San Francisco Area.

From June 1st 2006, El Paseo was renewed with skilled top teams in the kitchen as well as waiters and sommeliers.

Please take a look at the sample... 
   
 Piatti - Mill Valley 

 Piatti is a casually elegant restaurant overlooking Shelter Bay next to Mt. Tamalpais, featuring moderately priced rustic seasonal Italian cuisine. 
   
 Frantoio 

 Frantoio is a contemporary Italian restaurant with its own olive oil press. Enjoy fantastic salads, pasta, pizza and entrees in an elegant yet relaxed setting. 
   
 Piazza D&apos;Angelo 

 Piazza D&apos;Angelo is a business with a long history. Over the years, Piazza D&apos;Angelo, has become the most popular restaurant in downtown Mill Valley. They are know for wonderful Italian cuisine in a warm and friendly setting. 
   
 Chez Panisse (17 miles away) 

 This is Alice Waters&apos; famous Berkeley restaurant, often named as the birthplace of California cuisine. The idea is simple: make delicious food with what&apos;s local and what&apos;s fresh. And around Berkeley this yields amazing results. There&apos;s a fixed menu, priced depending on day of the week. Mondays are $50 and the price goes up through the week with Saturday at $85. The cafe upstairs is open for... 
   
 The Great China (17 miles away) 

 This is one of Berkeley&apos;s best Chinese restaurants. The atmosphere isn&apos;t too elegant but is perhaps authentic, and they&apos;ve got a huge menu that often incorporates ingredients from the area, especially crab. The little, two-story place tends to be packed most evenings. If you can rally up a party of 6 or more, make a reservation. Otherwise plan on waiting a while for a table if you come during... 
   
 Zachary&apos;s Pizza (18 miles away) 

 Zachary&apos;s Pizza is an East Bay institution with locations in Berkeley and Oakland. Everyone in the area knows about Zachary&apos;s and can&apos;t seem to find enough superlatives to describe it. It serves up the most incredible deep-dish pizza you&apos;ll find outside of Illinois (some would say even Chicago pizza doesn&apos;t hold a candle.) The slices are incredibly thick and the ingredients are fresh. This is... 
   
 Colucci&apos;s Cafe (18 miles away) 

 This Ethiopian restaurant is really good and atmospheric, too. The decorations inside are authentic and create a North African mood even when you&apos;re actually in Oakland and it&apos;s raining. The food is spicy, delicious, and served with injera, a traditional spongy bread. Think naan but slightly rubbery (in a good way). You use this stuff to sop up the traditional Ethiopian curries and stews. It&apos;s a... 
   
 Walzwerk (11 miles away) 

 You won’t find more authentic German food outside of Deutschland herself. Run by young German expatriates, this cozy eatery, tucked into a corner of the Mission district, has meat-and-potatoes staples like bratwurst and schnitzel. The portions are hearty, the accents are real, and the wide selection of beer is, well, German. Make reservations: this place has many fans and it’s small. 
   
 Daily Grill - San Francisco (11 miles away) 

 Located in the heart of bustling Union Square, Daily Grill is an updated version of the San Francisco grills of the past, providing generous portions of classic American dishes, such as steaks, chops, chicken pot pie, and meat loaf...a neat, friendly place where one can get crab cakes or a burger, Shrimp Louie or a T-Bone, along with martinis, single malts, microbrews and a good bottle of wine.... 
   
 Cafe Majestic - Hotel Majestic (11 miles away) 

 The Cafe Majestic is part of the Hotel Majestic, it is a boutique Hotel setting in Pacific Heights. We offer a wonderful array of Fresh and creative food in a newly remodeled casual fine dining atmosphere. Our menu is seasonal and we only use the best ingredients. All pastries, breads, and desserts are house made daily. 
   
 A. Sabella&apos;s (11 miles away) 

 A candle-lit dining room with a spectacular view is the atmosphere you&apos;ll find at A. Sabella&apos;s. The menu features fresh local seafood&amp;steaks with the exotic and contemporary flair provided by Chef Todd Hansen. 
   
 CHIAROSCURO (11 miles away) 

 CHIAROSCURO is contemporary restaurant that combines traditional values with a modern air. Inspired by the black and white films prominent during the Italian Neorealism movement of the 40s and 50s, CHIAROSCUROs clients will experience a level of service that constitutes a class of its own and an atmosphere that will express a simple yet charming air reminiscent of the subtle classy detailing... 
   
 Saul&apos;s Deli and Restaurant (17 miles away) 

 Saul&apos;s is the New York-style Jewish deli of Berkeley&apos;s &quot;gourmet ghetto&quot; and its fans can&apos;t stop raving. If you&apos;re interested in a good pastrami, corned beef, or some latkas, this is your place. It&apos;s spacious, comfortable and bright inside with large diner booths and checkered floor. There&apos;s also some great take-out options at the counter. 
   
 Brothers Korean Restaurant (11 miles away) 

 It&apos;s gotta be a pretty good restaurant that can support two locations within two blocks. Brothers specializes in Korean BBQ. It&apos;s a very participatory kind of dining. Most of the tables have grills built right in. You order some raw meats, cook them yourself at the table, and then wrap them in lettuce with any of the various and sundry supplements they bring to your table. The ambiance isn&apos;t... 
   
 Taqueria La Familia (17 miles away) 

 This little taqueria keeps the neighborhood around Shattuck and Ashby well-fed with a sizeable menu of authentic Mexican food, complete with carnitas, chile rellenos, and seasonal seafood. The decor is simple; the menu is scrawled on while boards that lean on the counter. It&apos;s not glamorous. But it is delicious and the proprietors are really friendly. 
   
 Chaat Cafe (17 miles away) 

 This little Indian fast-food restaurant has a limited menu but it&apos;s offerings are cheap and delicious. It&apos;s pretty informal: you order at the counter and then take a number to your table, but the atmosphere is surprisingly nice considering the price. They have branched out from traditional Indian cuisine and also offer Chiken Tikka Masala wraps and Tandoori Ceasar salads. 
   
 Chez TJ (28 miles away) 

 Attentive service, fresh flowers and soft music surround guests at this intimate, special occasion restaurant in downtown Mountain View. Inside a lovely Victorian villa, Chef Christopher Kostow creates a contemporary French cuisine that accentuates the vibrant, fresh flavors found naturally in high quality products. Chez TJ&apos;s menus lead guests through an exciting evening of culinary pleasure. Our... 
   
 The Cantankerous Fish (28 miles away) 

 Since opening its doors in 2003, The Cantankerous Fish has enjoyed rave reviews for its fresh cuisine, attractive presentation and attentive staff. Modern art and colorful interior give the restaurant a relaxed, vibrant feel. This is a perfect place for a romantic evening, formal business luncheon, or casual dinner.







with family or friends. We also offer patio dining. Voted Mountain... 
   
 Kingfish, San Mateo (26 miles away) 

 Kingfish provides numerous spacious banquet facilities for parties as small as 10 people to groups as large as 400 people. Kingfish can also offer live entertainment, 3 full bars, an energetic night life. Kingfish does offer Valet, and even a great Takeout menu for those who need the comfort of home without the stress of cooking. 
   
 Oliveto Café&amp;Restaurant (18 miles away) 

 On January 20 and 21, Oliveto Café&amp;Restaurant will be celebrating it&apos;s 20th anniversary. We regret to inform you that on-line reservations are not available for those days.

Oliveto Café&amp;Restaurant offers seasonal cuisine in the Northern Italian tradition, including wild game, fresh pastas, wood fired pizzas and authentic vegetable and poultry dishes.

All reservations are for the dining... 
   
 Garibaldi&apos;s on College (18 miles away) 

 Since its opening in 1997, Garibaldi&apos;s has been one of the best restaurants in the East Bay. The Mediterranean/Californian cuisine and beautiful atmosphere make it a prime destination. 
   
 Kuleto&apos;s Trattoria Burlingame (23 miles away) 

 Located just minutes from San Francisco International Airport, Kuleto&apos;s Trattoria offers contemporary Italian cuisine featuring the freshest, finest, and most distinctive ingredients available. The wood-fired pizza oven and open display kitchen is visible from nearly every seat. Seating at the exhibition kitchen encourages a casual family feel of relaxation and comfort. The lively bar area... 
   
 Nectar Wine Lounge - Burlingame (23 miles away) 

 Located in the heart Burlingame&apos;s bustling downtown, Nectar Wine Lounge, Burlingame brings together the very nectar which feeds the soul. Our 50 frequently metamorphosing wine selections by the glass span the vastness of the globe and of the palate, and our 900 selection bottle list offers something for even the most adventurous of spirit. Wines are also available for retail purchase. Executive... 
   
 Mezze (18 miles away) 

 Start planning your St. Valentine&apos;s Day Dinner. Watch for our prix fixe multi-course menu for that special evening. Our regular menu will not be offered. 
Mezze Restaurant and Bar in existence for close to seven years has attracted loyal followers from throughout the East Bay. Chef Andrew Shimer focuses on defining Mediterranean Rim Cuisine with seasonal and premium ingredients. Described in the... 
   
 Kincaid&apos;s Bayhouse - Oakland (18 miles away) 

 Located on the waterfront in historic Jack London Square, lies Kincaid&apos;s Bayhouse. Truly, today&apos;s interpretation of a traditional Fish, Chop and Steakhouse. One will find the food and beverage to be the finest available and where possible, prepared and served in the tradition of an old-time Fish and Steakhouse. Fresh fish flown in daily, prime select cuts of beef, along with signature dessert... 
   
 Cascal (28 miles away) 

 Old World taste meets New World appeal in this vibrant new restaurant concept by veteran Restaurateur, Don Durante. Serving spirited Pan-Latin cuisine, Cascal is a place to meet and linger with friends over exotic cocktails and enticing foods with bold flavors and personality. 
   
 Il Porcellino (18 miles away) 

 By serving Tuscan and Northern Italian inspired dishes, with homemade pasta and the freshest ingredients, Il Porcellino continues to be a favorite since opening in 1997. A warmly lit dining room, quaint Italian artwork and a gracious staff are all waiting to bid you a buona sera at Il Porcellino. 
   
 Jack&apos;s Bistro (18 miles away) 

 Jack&apos;s Bistro offers a unique dining experience featuring a wood-fired pizza oven and rotisserie, outdoor waterfront patio seating, nightly entertainment, two private dining rooms for parties up to fifty, and a specialty retail bakery with coffee and juice bar. This is a spectacular waterfront dining and entertainment venue. 
   
 Shiva&apos;s (28 miles away) 

 Shiva&apos;s offers classic North Indian food with a contemporary twist. It is a fresh attempt to bring to you authentic Indian cuisine in an ambiance made to leave an everlasting impression. A full service bar and a separate banquet hall make Shiva&apos;s a perfect place to host your special event. 
   
 Capellini (26 miles away) 

 Opulent décor and sumptuous food best describes the restaurant atmosphere at Ristorante Capellini. 
   
 Astaria (26 miles away) 

 Astaria (pronounced a-stair-ee-a) offers guests a fresh, innovative menu representing the ethnically diverse flavors of the Mediterranean. A passion for great food, exceptional presentation and a warm, welcoming ambiance, best describes their philosophy. The atmosphere is such that one can feel comfortable stopping in wearing shorts just as one would wearing a tuxedo for a romantic candlelit... 
   
 Citron (18 miles away) 

 Citron is one of the East Bay&apos;s most popular restaurants. Located in a small storefront on College, Chef Christopher Rossi executes a well-balanced and dazzling menu. California-American cuisine that is approachable and exciting. Enjoy first-class service, a warmly lit dining room and an extensive wine list.
Sunday - Friday Citron offers a 3, 4&amp;5 course Chef Tasting menu for $32, $40&amp;$46.... 
   
 Montclair Bistro (18 miles away) 

 The Montclair Bistro is tucked into the wooded hillside in the affluent area of the Oakland Hills. Built in 1948, the style of the building is French Provincial with much attention paid to detail-from the weather vane atop the peaked roof, the half-timbering, to the weathered bricks along the walls and pathways. Inside, discreet artwork on speckled walls in tones of soft leaf green and... 
   
 Bogies (26 miles away) 

 Bogie&apos;s is a French Continental Restaurant that has been around for about twenty years and is located in the Old San Mateo Theater. The newly remodeled restaurant serves exquisite and creative presentations in a unique environment. The Humphrey Bogart and 1940&apos;s motif gives an intimate yet old fashioned ambiance. Our new excellent chef, Jesus Sanchez provides such zesty rich flavors along with... 
   
 Cetrella Bistro&amp;Cafe (29 miles away) 

 Featured in Gourmet Magazine, this three-star European Bistro blends casual elegance with rustic charm, reminiscent of a Tuscan villa with cozy stone fireplaces and sun-lit terraces. Described as a Mediterranean dream and one of the best in the Bay Area in 2004 by food editor Michael Bauer of the San Francisco Chronicle, the Bistro features lusty, flavorful dishes inspired by the coastal... 
   
 B Restaurant (18 miles away) 

 &quot;Looking out twelve-foot-tall windows at an Edwardian street scene, and it&apos;s hard not to be impressed with B Restaurant. [It] is austere and dramatic in a style few other Oakland restaurants have dared embrace, and it&apos;s a showcase for the neighborhood Old Oakland.&quot; 
- Jonathan Kauffman, East Bay Express 
   
 Speisekammer (21 miles away) 

 Speisekammer serves up the best German cuisine this side of the pond! Cooking up original German recipes, pouring an outstanding selection of German beer and an extensive wine selection, Chef/owner Peter Kahl and his wife Cindy will provide you with an experience you&apos;ll be eager to repeat. Listen to local musicians play Thursday through Saturday. Come by and sit in the Biergarten and enjoy what&apos;s... 
   
 C&apos;era Una Volta (21 miles away) 

 Translation: Once Upon A Time.
This sun-splashed location is a hidden treasure on a quiet promenade lined with trees and cobblestones. C&apos;era Una Volta brings a Taste of Italy to the island city of Alameda. Featuring over 50 Italian wines and one of the few all Italian wine lists in Northern California, C&apos;era Una Volta serves authentic Tuscan and other Italian regional cuisine. Wine tastings and... 
   
 The Spinnaker - Sausalito (4 miles away) 

 The Spinnaker is located on the Sausalito waterfront offering panoramic views of San Francisco, Angel Island, the East Bay and Belvedere. They serve an impressive menu with fresh seafood and a fine wine selection. 
   
 Scoma&apos;s Sausalito (4 miles away) 

 Scoma&apos;s Sausalito is situated on the water in a historic landmark building overlooking San Francisco Bay. Scoma&apos;s has offered diners romantic views while serving superb fresh seafood and Italian specialties. 
   
 Gaylord India Restaurant - Sausalito (4 miles away) 

 Travelers the world over have come to identify the Gaylord name with the finest of Indian restaurants, Gaylord has been consistently rated among the top ten Indian restaurants in the world by leading critics. Come and experience Indian cuisine at its best since 1976...Dine at our new location in Sausalito,while you marvel at the twinkling lights of San Francisco,and the Bay.Enjoy a glass of wine... 
   
 Sushi Ran (4 miles away) 

 We invite you to enjoy our vibrant fusion of traditional Japanese and Pacific cuisine. Outstanding chefs, great people on the floor and in the kitchen, plus a wine and sake list unparalleled in Californiaâwe believe these are the ingredients that have made Sushi Ran one of the top-rated restaurants in the Bay Area. We are passionate about what we do, and take special delight in introducing our... 
   
 Angelino Restaurant (4 miles away) 

 Angelino restaurant specializes in bringing the taste of Southern Italy to Sausalito. Diners at Angelino Restaurant experience the flavors of authentic Italian fare. Angelino tries to capture the beauty of Italy in every bite. 
   
 Poggio (4 miles away) 

 Poggio, from the Italian translation for &apos;a special hillside place&apos;, offers seasonal Italian cuisine. The daily-changing seasonal menu features locally grown ingredients and items from the large display wood-fired rotisserie and grill and wood-roasting oven. 
   
 Cacciucco (4 miles away) 

 Nestled in the hills of Sausalito lies Cacciucco, an authentic Italian restaurant specializing in Livornese cuisine. Cacciucco offers a variety of fresh seafood and a unique selection of wild game and fresh pasta dishes daily. Chef/partner Davide Cerretini hand selects distinctly Italian ingredients to recreate the flavors and colors of his hometown. The restaurant is a fusion of modern and... 
   
 Straits Cafe - Burlingame (23 miles away) 

 Singapore for almost 200 years has been at the crossroads of Southeast Asia, where many cultures and nationalities live, work and more importantly, eat together. Singapore&apos;s cuisines logically reflect this cultural diversity. The four major culinary cultures -- Malaysian/Indonesian, Chinese, Indian and Nonya -- are in fact a blend of each other, creating a new cuisine that is unique and more... 
   
 Kincaid&apos;s Bayhouse - Burlingame (23 miles away) 

 Kincaid&apos;s translates the traditional fish, chop and steak house into contemporary terms. In a casually elegant atmosphere, the restaurant offers outstanding cuisine and impressive Bay views. 
   
 Prime on the Avenue (23 miles away) 

 For the finest dining experience, visit our newest and most attractive addition to Burlingame Avenue, in Burlingame, CA. We feature prime rib, steak, rack of lamb, seafood, poultry and more prepared by the finest culinary chefs. 

Available during the day for banquets, executive lunches, corporate seminars, private parties, bridal and baby showers, and special events. 

We offer 10% Senior... 
   
 Broadway Grill (23 miles away) 

 Locally owned and operated, The Broadway Grill answers the call from residents to open a fun and lively place to enjoy satisfying food and drink without having to spend a fortune! Our motto is Good food, nice people. We hope that you agree.

With a friendly and attentive staff and warm, stylish atmosphere, The Broadway Grill is perfect for a casual night out or a special occasion. Enjoy the... 
   
 Il Fornaio - Burlingame (23 miles away) 

 Il Fornaio means &apos;the baker&apos; in Italian. This award-winning restaurant offers an authentic and unique Italian dining experience. 
   
 Spiedo - San Mateo (26 miles away) 

 Spiedo Restaurant located in the heart of San Mateo, specializing in fine Italian cuisine and Daily Specials from the Venitian region. Using only the freshest of ingredients, Spiedo is known for our wood-fired pizzas, homemade pastas, and our fresh rotissiere. Enjoy a bottle of wine from an extensive wine list or a cocktail from our full service bar. Open for Lunch and Dinner 7 days a week.... 
   
 Roti Indian Bistro - Burlingame (23 miles away) 

 Roti is about experiencing a feast - a celebration shared with family and friends in a warm modern setting. A place where authentic and modern Indian cuisine is prepared using high quality local and organic ingredients and served in a refined style. 

With an elegant ambiance, a meticulously paired wine list, special Indian cocktails, and hiqh quality Indian cuisine, Roti Indian Bistro has been... 
   
 Navio at The Ritz-Carlton, Half Moon Bay (29 miles away) 

 Experience coastal cuisine in its truest and finest form at The Ritz-Carlton, Half Moon Bay&apos;s signature restaurant, Navio. Set within the AAA Five Diamond resort, and situated atop a dramatic ocean bluff, Navio treats its guests to Chef de Cuisine Aaron Zimmer&apos;s inspired menu from the 1,000-square foot display kitchen, which has won a variety of awards and accolades in the four years since... 
   
 Left Bank Pleasant Hill (31 miles away) 

 Pleasant Hill&apos;s Left Bank is a big, crowd-pleasing Parisian-style brasserie. The restaurant is ideal for every occasion from a casual snack on the terraces to a glass of fine wine or a cocktail at the grand mahogany bar, to a selection of fresh seafood at the oyster bar, to an elegant sit-down dining experience. Located in the new Downtown Pleasant Hill Plaza, Left Bank caters to both local and... 
   
 Nibblers Eatery&amp;Wine Bar (31 miles away) 

 NIBBLERS Eatery&amp;Wine Bar is central Contra Costa&apos;s neighborhood destination for international small plates&amp;eclectic wines. 

Casual comfort is available in our dining room and al fresco dining on our patio is an option for those seeking fresh air.

Located in the Oak Park Center, a small retail complex in residential Pleasant Hill, NIBBLERS caters to those looking for:
an intriguing dining... 
   
 Lark Creek Walnut Creek (31 miles away) 

 For 14 years the restaurants of the Lark Creek Restaurant Group have featured American wines exclusively to compliment Chef Bradley Ogden&apos;s seasonal farm-fresh American fare. Come in and savor a bottle of fine wine from our vast collection of over 200 labels. 
   
 Pasta Moon (29 miles away) 

 A popular destination in Half Moon Bay for 17 years, Pasta Moon Restaurant serves elegant Italian cuisine - in fact, easily the finest dining on the coast;
(and not the most expensive!).
You&apos;ll find a cozy setting for lunch or dinner, surrounded by old arched casement windows which once
brought light into the Burlingame Public Library, and you&apos;ll be served by an attentive and amiable staff. 
   
 A Cote (18 miles away) 

 À Côté is primarily a walk-in restaurant, a few early and late reservations are available. If no reservation is available at the hour you choose, don&apos;t be discouraged; we keep tables available for walk-in diners throughout every evening.
À Côté is a small-plates restaurant in Oakland&apos;s charming Rockridge district. Cozy tables surround large communal tables in both the main dining room and on the... 
   
 231 Ellsworth (26 miles away) 

 231 Ellsworth is considered by many to be the San Francisco Peninsula&apos;s finest restaurant. Globally inspired, Contemporary American cuisine and world-class wine list are offered in an elegant, sophisticated atmosphere. A curvaceous, intimate full bar presents light fare or dessert before or after a visit to the Downtown Cinema. 
   
 Central Park Bistro (26 miles away) 

 Central Park Bistro is a 100 seat contemporary restaurant in downtown San Mateo featuring fresh seasonal American cuisine, in the $15-$26 range. We offer a carefully chosen eclectic Wine Spectator award-winning wine list. Central Park Bistro is an affordable sophisticated, fun dining experience. Relax and unwind with a house specialty cocktail at our wonderful Martini Bar. We also have several... 
   
 Half Moon Bay Inn - Kitchen&amp;Cocktails (29 miles away) 

 Located in the newly renovated Half Moon Bay Inn, the restaurant offers a menu rooted in tradition, acknowledging the abundance of locally grown ingredients. A full bar with infused vodkas and 16 beers on tap compliments the 100 seat dining room and the European style courtyard where you can enjoy the warmth of a romantic fireplace on one of those rare foggy coast side days. 
   
 Emery Grille - Woodfin Suites Hotel (17 miles away) 

 With ingredients chosen with care from around the globe, Emery Grille is your destination to enjoy a cross-cultural epicurean encounter. Groove to the latest electro-world tunes, as you sample creations integrating the finest flavors from France, Japan, Brazil, Italy, California, and India. Savor one of our gourmet entrees such as the Pan-Seared Kobe Filet or Short Ribs. Or try one of our fresh... 
   
 Quinn&apos;s Lighthouse Restaurant&amp;Pub (18 miles away) 

 East Bay Restaurant Wins in 2006 &quot;BEST WINE LISTS IN AMERICA&quot; Competition.

Quinn&apos;s Lighthouse Restaurant was awarded the Grand Prize in the Short List Category by Restaurant Hospitality Magazine. The Judges found Quinn&apos;s List &quot;SHORT and SWEET&quot;with well choosen, food friendly selections. The list distinguished it self though &quot;DEAD ON&quot; informative Wine descriptions and an inovative Specialty... 
   
 Hunan Villa (17 miles away) 

 As you enter the doors of Hunan Villa you will immediately notice the ultra modern decor. The appetizing aromas of innovative, Chinese cuisine, presented by a professional, attentive, wait staff, entices dinners to their tables. 
   
 Bing Crosby&apos;s (31 miles away) 

 This new hot spot in Walnut Creek is a tribute to Bing Crosby and his successful career as a singer, actor, and radio personality. The restaurant provides an elegant, yet casual dining experience featuring the award-winning cuisine of Executive Chef Frank Palmer. The lunch and dinner menus combine American, French, and Asian influences. The lounge features 21 different martinis and live music... 
   
 Trader Vic&apos;s - Emeryville (17 miles away) 

 Enjoy Trader Vic&apos;s world famous cocktails and legendary Island-style cuisine overlooking the beautiful Emeryville Marina. Carefully prepared seasonal menus are constructed from fresh seafood, meats and poultry and served just the way you want them-steamed, grilled or barbequed in our Wood-Fired ovens. 
   
 The San Franciscan (31 miles away) 

 Restaurant Description Coming Soon! 
   
 Sushi Groove - Walnut Creek (31 miles away) 

 Sushi Groove Walnut Creek is nothing short of its sister restaurants in San Francisco . What started as out over 11 years ago as the quintessential sushi experience of Martel Toler and Nabiel Muslehs wildest taste buds, has now migrated east and combined forces with Operating Partners Jim and Will Tang. 
From the moment you enter into the space through the bamboo terrace, the back lit amber sea... 
   
 Pear Street Bistro (17 miles away) 

 Pear Street Bistro is a California bistro featuring rustic Italian cuisine in a modern and very trendy atmosphere. Enjoy the fun bar area which highlights a century old hand carved antique bar. The private banquet and meeting room offers accommodations for up to 30 people. 
   
 Rickey&apos;s (13 miles away) 

 American Comfort Food with an eclectic flair is Rickey&apos;s speciality. Chef Noe Martinez prides himself on presenting dishes that are as delicious to look at as they are to your taste buds. Our exciting menu choices will leave you wanting to return to try every dish. Enjoy a warm comfortable atmosphere in our craftsman style dining room dominated by a stone fireplace, or dine poolside on our patio... 
   
 Hill Top Cafe (13 miles away) 

 The Hill Top Cafe, built in 1892, overlooks Novato, the Hills and San Pablo Bay. The same team that has brought pleasure to diners for more than 27 years professionally executes an extensive menu. Go to their website for full menu details. 
   
 Boca (13 miles away) 

 Acclaimed chef George Morrone - the creative force behind Aqua, the Fifth Floor, Tartare, and the only chef to earn four stars at two different restaurants, introduces Boca - a steakhouse inspired by Morrone&apos;s Argentinean heritage.
Boca specializes in meats with Argentinean accents. A wood burning oven fires signature dishes such as empanadas, Argentinean-style house made sausages, and both... 
   
 Wildfox (13 miles away) 

 Munther and Debbie Massarweh invite you to join them at Wildfox, a rustic mesquite-fired kitchen serving American comfort food. The menu features grilled chops, aged steaks, prime rib, burgers and fish with daily chef specials. The restaurant features include a patio, fireplaces, full bar and cocktail lounge. Enjoy the extensive wine list. 
   
 AVA (4 miles away) 

 AVA is the abbreviation for American Viticultural Area, or an American grape-growing region. Like the AOCs of France and DOCs of Italy, the AVA gives clues to a wine&apos;s quality, flavor profile, and terroir. Come experience many of California&apos;s 95 AVAs on our California-only wine list featuring only family-owned wineries. Enjoy the &quot;California&quot; cuisine of Chef Dan Baker, where nearly all... 
   
 Insalata&apos;s (4 miles away) 

 Insalata&apos;s, an upscale Mediterranean venue, is located in San Anselmo, California, about twenty minutes north of the Golden Gate Bridge. Though the name may invoke images of a Mexican salad bar, it is in fact the maiden name of Executive Chef and Owner Heidi Insalata Krahling and was named such to honor her late father, Italo Insalata. Insalatas food, with its soulful, rustic style, draws... 
   
 Wolf House (29 miles away) 

 Located on the banks of the Sonoma Creek, Wolf House features an ever-changing menu of &apos;Sonoma Valley Cuisine&apos; based on the best of Northern California farms, orchards and oceans. Wolf House combines beautiful views, patio dining, fireplace and service that is warm and unpretentious to provide guests with a memorable dining experience. 
   
 Marche aux Fleurs (3 miles away) 

 The Marche aux Fleurs is the farmer&apos;s market in the south of France. We have taken this name for our restaurant because we base our cuisine on the seasons and the best the local farmer&apos;s markets have to offer. Our produce is locally farmed at the peak of ripeness, our seafood is wild and sustainable, and our meats are range-fed and antibiotic free. These ingredients comprise the selections on our... 
   
 Sam&apos;s Chowder House (29 miles away) 

 Authentic, New England style seafood, casual and inviting service with the best view on the coast offering oceanfront dining with sweeping views of the Pacific from every seat. A beautifully crafted Oyster Bar with a wide selection of tasty treats. Extensive outdoor seating and a seafood market with fresh seafood, and prepared to-go items. Accessible from Highway One, the beach or the nearby... 
   
 Barolo Restaurant - Pacifica (19 miles away) 

 Jason Yeafoli and Stephen Walker have combined their talent, experience, and friendship opening their second restaurant together. The partners opened Vignette Restaurant in San Francisco in 2004. The cuisine is simple, classic, and artful. The modern Italian menu is focused and exciting and includes house cured meats and a selection of pizzas. Menu items include: fritto misto of calamari,... 
   
 Duck Club at Lafayette Park Hotel (27 miles away) 

 The Duck Club at the Lafayette Park Hotel displays a scrumptious array of edibles in a relaxed yet elegant atmosphere. 
   
 Giardino (27 miles away) 

 Giardino is a quaint Italian trattoria serving Tuscan and northern Italian inspired dishes using seasonal ingredients, homemade pastas local and fresh seafood and meats in a charming setting. 
   
 Moss Beach Distillery (24 miles away) 

 This historic restaurant dates back to the 1920&apos;s and has been a favorite ocean view restaurant for many people worldwide. Guests marvel at the view of the Pacific Ocean while enjoying the Distillery&apos;s excellent cuisine including fabulous prime steaks and fresh seafood favorites. Relax and enjoy the ocean view from the large indoor/outdoor patio while snuggling under a cozy, warm blanket. The... 
   
 Horatio&apos;s (27 miles away) 

 Nautically themed and located in the San Leandro Marina, Horatio&apos;s offers exceptional food and service with a waterfront view. Their menu includes the freshest fish, seafood and steaks with both new and traditional preparations.
Lunch: $7 to $19
Dinner:$17 to $50 
   
 Paradiso (27 miles away) 

 Paradiso offers a contemporary atmosphere with an architectural
flair. The exhibition kitchen is a highlight. 
   
 Noonan&apos;s Bar&amp;Grill (1 miles away) 

 Noonan&apos;s Bar and Grill is an urban oasis in the heart of Marin county. They feature an 85 foot long bar stocked with over 600 individual spirits, an oak wood grill specializing in contemporary American cuisine, private banquet facilities, patio dining, and a world class wine list, plus plenty of micro brews on tap. 
   
 Left Bank Larkspur (1 miles away) 

 Left Bank is an authentic Parisian-style brasserie located in the historic Blue Rock Inn in the charming city of Larkspur. It is ideal for every occasion from a casual snack on the street-side terrace, to a glass of wine or cocktail at the lively bar, to an elegant dining experience. Executive Chef/Co-Owner Roland Passot has designed a seasonally changing, French brasserie menu of hearty, rustic... 
   
 Yankee Pier - Larkspur (1 miles away) 

 Yankee Pier Larkspur is harbored in a quaint historic landmark house built in the late 1800s. The main dining room seats 49. Outdoor seating is available on our heated patios, serving 14 on the rear patio, and 24 out front with a sandbox for the youngsters.

 Styled after New England seaside clam shacks, our upscale casual atmosphere lends itself to families and friends, young and seasoned. ... 
   
 The Melting Pot - Larkspur (1 miles away) 

 The Melting Pot is located in the historic Brick Kiln in Larkspur, CA. The Melting Pot offers an extraordinary dining experience that you won&apos;t find at any other restaurant. Here you&apos;ll discover all the ingredients to a perfect evening, including a relaxed atmosphere, private tables, attentive service, fine wines&amp;fabulous four-course fondue dinners. No matter what the occasion, from a romantic... 
   
 Picco Restaurant (1 miles away) 

 The food at Picco is designed with sharing in mind to best experience our local, seasonal, and ingredient-driven cuisine. Our wine list features an eclectic collection of bottles from the best growing regions around the globe. Located in historic downtown Larkspur California, Picco offers a full bar, private dining rooms, and cozy booths in a brick and redwood setting. Personal wines are welcome... 
   
 E&amp;O Trading Company - Larkspur (1 miles away) 

 Eastern&amp;Oriental Trading Company lives on in the creative combination of spices and ales served at our restaurant. 
   
 Lark Creek Inn (1 miles away) 

 For the past 15 years, the Lark Creek Inn has featured American wines exclusively to compliment Chef Bradley Ogden&apos;s seasonal farm-fresh American fare. Savor a bottle of fine wine from their vast collection of over 250 labels. Our patio seating is now open, so come enjoy an afternoon or evening under the Redwood trees. We are proud to be a landmark in Marin County not only for special occasions... 
   
 Hiro&apos;s - Petaluma (22 miles away) 

 Located at the center of Historic Downtown Petaluma, Hiro&apos;s Japanese Restaurant offers high quality sushi and Japanese cuisine in a comfortable and unique setting. 
   
 Willie Mays Sky Box Lounge (17 miles away) 

 Fresh quality ingredients makes fresh quality food and as far as hes concerned that theory applies to everything from his house made vinaigrettes and ice cream to his picky taste in produce. As Executive Chef of Willie Mays SkyBox Lounge he plans to offer some of the best California has to give. 

Bringing an upscale, contemporary edge to one of the East Bay&apos;s most historic venues, Willie... 
   
 Yoshi&apos;s (18 miles away) 

 Yoshi&apos;s has served Japan&apos;s best traditional dishes to Bay Area patrons since 1972. The menu highlights artfully arranged sushi, fresh grilled seafood, classic Japanese dishes, and vegetarian fare. Patrons can kick off their shoes in the traditional Japanese tatami seating or dine at tables. Expert
sushi chefs create sushi and sashimi to order either in the restaurant or in
the jazz house. Start... 
   
 Fast Food 
   

 
 Tomales Bay Foods (20 miles away) 

 Tomales Bay Foods is the home of the Cowgirl Creamery, a premier artisan cheesemaker. You can watch them create their fantastic RedHawk and Mt. Tam cheeses among others. The cheese is for sale as is a superb collection of other artisan cheese from the local area and around the world. They also offer gourmet premade sandwiches and salads, perfect for a picnic. If you are looking for local... 
   
 Gordo Taqueria (17 miles away) 

 I have lived in Mexico for over 6 years and I have searched high and low (and in the state of Michoacan where supposedly they do these things right) for a carnitas as yummy as the carnitas at Gordo. It just ain&apos;t happening in Mexico. I know, it sounds silly, but there are way better carnitas in Berkeley! So, every time I can make it to Berkeley, I make a Gordo run. Their burritos are fat. ... 
   
 Pizza Fiesta (17 miles away) 

 Owned and operated by Cantonese, this Italian eatery sports a Mexican name. It&apos;s a big cultural collage. But the pizza is fantastic. Berkeley prides itself on good pizza but most people think first of Zachary&apos;s, Blondie&apos;s and Fat Slice. While pizza fiesta doesn&apos;t have novelty-size slices or a special deep-dish recipe, they will give you a &quot;slide and a soda&quot; for $3.25, which is actually two slices... 
   
 Blondie&apos;s Pizza (11 miles away) 

 Blondie’s is a Bay Area classic with a location on famous TelegraphAve. in Berkeley, and this one in the city. Seating is very limited butthe lines are long anyway: at $3.25 for a huge, thick slice and a soda,Blondie’s is cheap and unquestionably delicious. 
   
 Other 
   

 
 Asqew Grill (11 miles away) 

 Has the feel of a small cafe but serves full meals and dessert.Reasonable prices for meat or veggie skewers that come with either asalad or choice of mashed potatoes, rice, couscous, etc all for $10.Also has great sides for cheap like corn, garlic bread, etc. Andeverything is grilled in minutes. Very fast, affordable, and tasty. Nowthey have 4 locations throughout SF. Service at the Haight... 
   

 

 
 
 Ratings for 
 
 
 good food     
 0% 
 

 5 votes 
 
 
 
 

 About VCarious  |  What People Are Saying  |  Share  |  Contribute  |  Terms  |  Site Map  |  Links  |  Contact Us 

 MIDAS Indicators for NinjaTrader  |  MIDAS Trading  |  Beauty and Fashion Blog 

 Copyright©2006-2008 by VCarious. All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
