<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002400" url="http://ezinearticles.com/?Dont-Let-Food-Eat-Your-Budget---3-Tips-For-How-to-Save-Money-on-Groceries&amp;id=2212910" time="2012-07-12-18:19" support="1" score="0.00012563510105599167" bingtitle="Don&apos;t Let Food Eat Your Budget - 3 Tips For How to Save Money on ..." webtitle="Don&apos;t Let Food Eat Your Budget - 3 Tips For How to Save Money on Groceries">
			<query id="000933" bing-rank="161"/>
	<description>... the next time you go to the store. ... Then, you need to stick to that list. Buy what you need and leave all the ... at an expensive fast-food restaurant for dinner when you ...</description>
	<body>
		Search Home » Finance » Budgeting Marie Nolan 
 Platinum Author |   22 Articles 
 Joined: September 25, 2005 Was this article helpful? 1 0 
Don&apos;t Let Food Eat Your Budget - 3 Tips For How to Save Money on Groceries

 By Marie Nolan 
 
We&apos;re facing dark financial times, and every penny counts - but you still need to eat. Here are three easy tips to save money on groceries the next time you go to the store.

 Tip 1 -- Use a List to Save Money on Groceries 

Using a list really does save you money. In fact, just making the list forces you to think about what you really need.

Then, you need to stick to that list. Buy what you need and leave all the over-priced, over-processed &quot;food&quot; on the shelves. All of those convenience items are drastically marked up, causing you to spend far too much.

 Tip 2 -- Learn When a Sale is a Sale 

When you open the Sunday papers, they are full of coupons. And then there are the days when all the grocery store flyers arrive. But when is a sale really a sale?

Buying something you don&apos;t need or probably won&apos;t use just because it&apos;s a bargain is no bargain. The same for coupons -- if you don&apos;t really need it, a huge &quot;discount&quot; costs you money -- not saves you cash.

 Tip 3 -- Use Your Freezer to Save Cold Cash 

Instead of buying frozen dinners or going the fast-food route, take a day and cook your dinners for the week. Then, freeze the food in dinner-sized portions. It sounds time-consuming, but it really isn&apos;t. The time you spend cooking saves you time during the week, when you need it most.

Freeze your dinners and all you need to do is pop it in the microwave or stove. You won&apos;t need to stop at an expensive fast-food restaurant for dinner when you&apos;re pressed for time. And there&apos;s another bonus -- you&apos;re feeding your family without extra chemicals and preservatives.
 
Save More Now

Would you like more secrets to saving money at the grocery store? Money saving grocery shopping [http://www.practicalwaystosavemoney.com/category/money-saving-grocery-shopping] is easier than you think.

Then again, there are other practical ways to save money [http://www.practicalwaystosavemoney.com] you might not have thought of. Don&apos;t you want to spend a little and save a lot?
 
Article Source: http://EzineArticles.com/?expert=Marie_Nolan 
 Did you find this article helpful? 1 0 Get Involved 0 comments Suggest a topic Article Tools Print this article E-mail to a friend EzinePublisher Report this article Cite this article Stay Informed Get notified by email when new articles are added to this category or written by this author. 
Subscribe to New Article Alerts:
 
 Finance: Budgeting 
 Marie Nolan 
 Email Address: Subscribe Budgeting Article Feed Find More Articles Search 
Similar Articles

 Understanding How to Save Money at the Grocery Store Debt Free Living - Top 10 Grocery Strategies For Saving Money at the Grocery Store Saving Money at the Grocery Store Want to Save Money and Control Your Spending? Try Starting at the Grocery Store How to Stop Spending Too Much Money at the Grocery Store Grocery Lists Are Essential to Saving Money at the Grocery Store How to Save Money at the Grocery Store How NOT to Get Ripped Off at the Grocery Store 10 Ways to Save Money at the Grocery Store How to Save Your Money at the Grocery Store 
 
Recent Articles

 5 Money Saving Tips That End Up Costing You More Best Online Deals Websites Offering Discounts 10 Money Saving Tips That Start With Not Renting Your Cable Modem Saving Money: One Day At A Time Tips for Preparing Your Budget for College How to Save Money Now and in the Future Determining Your Financial Priorities Getting Down to It: The Basics of Creating a Budget How a Divorce Can Affect Your Personal Financial Management 5 Budget Planning Tips 
 
Submitted On April 12, 2009. Viewed 97 times. Word count: 295.
 MLA Style Citation: 
Nolan, Marie &quot;Don&apos;t Let Food Eat Your Budget - 3 Tips For How to Save Money on Groceries.&quot; Don&apos;t Let Food Eat Your Budget - 3 Tips For How to Save Money on Groceries .
 12 Apr. 2009 EzineArticles.com. 12 Jul. 2012&lt; http://ezinearticles.com/?Dont-­Let-­Food-­Eat-­Your-­Budget-­-­-­3-­Tips-­For-­How-­to-­Save-­Money-­on-­Groceries&amp;id=2212910 &gt;. APA Style Citation: 
Nolan, M. (2009, April 12). Don&apos;t Let Food Eat Your Budget - 3 Tips For How to Save Money on Groceries .
 Retrieved July 12, 2012, from http://ezinearticles.com/?Dont-­Let-­Food-­Eat-­Your-­Budget-­-­-­3-­Tips-­For-­How-­to-­Save-­Money-­on-­Groceries&amp;id=2212910 Chicago Style Citation: 
Nolan, Marie &quot;Don&apos;t Let Food Eat Your Budget - 3 Tips For How to Save Money on Groceries.&quot; Don&apos;t Let Food Eat Your Budget - 3 Tips For How to Save Money on Groceries EzineArticles.com . http://ezinearticles.com/?Dont-­Let-­Food-­Eat-­Your-­Budget-­-­-­3-­Tips-­For-­How-­to-­Save-­Money-­on-­Groceries&amp;id=2212910 
 EzineArticles.com 

©2012 EzineArticles.com
All Rights Reserved Worldwide
 
 About Us FAQ Contact Us Member Benefits Privacy Policy Shop Site Map 

 Blog Training Video Library Advertising Affiliates Cartoons 
 
Authors
 
 Submit Articles Members Login Premium Membership Expert Authors Endorsements Editorial Guidelines Terms of Service 
 
Publishers

Follow Us
 
 Terms Of Service Ezines / Email Alerts Manage Subscriptions EzineArticles RSS
	</body>
</document>
