<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002456" url="http://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g298570-d966183-Reviews-Carl_s_Jr-Kuala_Lumpur_Wilayah_Persekutuan.html" time="2012-07-12-18:30" support="1" score="0.0015776001535900638" bingtitle="Carl&apos;s Jr, Kuala Lumpur - Restaurant Reviews - TripAdvisor" webtitle="Carls Jr Reviews - 38 Restaurant Reviews - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="000264" bing-rank="223"/>
	<description>Did not like the fact that there were not enough tables, and we almost had to make our order a ... Save up to 75%, Don&apos;t miss! Live support, Instant confirmation. ...</description>
	<body>
		Carl&apos;s Jr, Kuala Lumpur
 
 Home Kuala Lumpur 
 Kuala Lumpur Tourism Kuala Lumpur Hotels Kuala Lumpur Vacation Rentals Flights to Kuala Lumpur Kuala Lumpur Restaurants Things to Do in Kuala Lumpur Kuala Lumpur Travel Forum Kuala Lumpur Photos Kuala Lumpur Travel Guide 
 Hotels Flights Vacation Rentals Restaurants Things to Do Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
 Home 
 &gt; Asia &gt; Malaysia &gt; Wilayah Persekutuan &gt; Kuala Lumpur &gt; Kuala Lumpur Restaurants &gt; Carl&apos;s Jr 
 
 All 960 Kuala Lumpur Restaurants» 
Carl&apos;s Jr
 Midvalley Megamall , Kuala Lumpur , Malaysia Got a photo? 
 Add it. Ranked #91 of 960 restaurants in Kuala Lumpur 38 Reviews Price range: $10 - $15 Cuisines: Fast Food Restaurant details Update restaurant details Write a Review 
38 reviews from our community
 63% Recommend 
 Excellent 7 Very good 17 Average 7 Poor 6 Terrible 1 
 Rating summary 
 Food Service Value Atmosphere 
 38 reviews sorted by Date Rating English first Any AcidHurts KL Contributor 12 reviews “Different Standard compare to Spore...” Reviewed July 6, 2012 NEW 
My 1st try is at Vivo Spore for holiday around few years back...
So when it come to msia, went to try... well not up to my expectation...
Last year I went to Spore again... same place...same quality...
Really Need improvement...
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 11 more reviews by AcidHurts for Kuala Lumpur kimmieho Kuala Lumpur, Wilayah Persekutuan, Malaysia Contributor 18 reviews Reviews in 2 cities “american fast food” Reviewed July 2, 2012 
expensive but its burger are of good quality...try mushroom
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 16 more reviews by kimmieho for Kuala Lumpur aidrus Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia Senior Contributor 43 reviews Reviews in 19 cities 19 helpful votes “Different to other fast food restaurant” Reviewed June 13, 2012 
Like the fact that it&apos;s grilled. It taste different and I assume it&apos;s much healthier to fried chicken,etc. Hoever, its rather on the pricy side and location is limited.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 14 more reviews by aidrus for Kuala Lumpur iranadia Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia Top Contributor 68 reviews Reviews in 14 cities 9 helpful votes “love carl&apos;s jr” Reviewed May 17, 2012 via mobile 
love the burgers n fries but they already stop serving pickles at the side bar. :(
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 43 more reviews by iranadia for Kuala Lumpur shinoyuki Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia Reviewer 4 reviews “My favourite burger” Reviewed May 6, 2012 
i love Carl&apos;s Jr burger and fries! big bite portion, sink my teeth into the juicy thick meat pattie...
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 3 more reviews by shinoyuki for Kuala Lumpur edstand Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia Senior Reviewer 7 reviews Reviews in 2 cities 1 helpful vote “Burger” Reviewed May 1, 2012 
I had a burger here with someone who really liked the place. For me it was just fairly average, but fairly large burger that was quite expensive.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 5 more reviews by edstand for Kuala Lumpur oh_aaron Petaling Jaya, Malaysia Contributor 20 reviews Reviews in 11 cities 14 helpful votes “Fast food made to order... its FRESH!” Reviewed April 2, 2012 
Went to Carl&apos;s Jr last week and again enjoyed the meal there. Fast food made to order, so its not entirely that fast, you still need to wait for them to get it to you but its worth the wait. The burgers will be hot when it gets to you. Can&apos;t get any fresher than that. The fries does have... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Monagy3 Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia Contributor 11 reviews 1 helpful vote “Not so good burgers” Reviewed March 29, 2012 
The burgers used to be awesome... sadly, after some time.... the quality has gone down...
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 10 more reviews by Monagy3 for Kuala Lumpur Jeryl T Kuala Lumpur, Wilayah Persekutuan, Malaysia Senior Reviewer 7 reviews Reviews in 2 cities 3 helpful votes “Good!” Reviewed March 28, 2012 
One of the better fast food chain in town but lack the proximity. It may not be one of the cheapest but is one of the greats.
If you do not fancy extra toppings, super star is definitely value for money.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 4 more reviews by Jeryl T for Kuala Lumpur izz05 singapore Contributor 19 reviews Reviews in 4 cities 6 helpful votes “A normal burger joint” Reviewed March 18, 2012 via mobile 
We tried the burger meat at Carl jr and found that it&apos;s taste just like any fast food burger joint.nothing to cheers about
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? See 2 more reviews by izz05 for Kuala Lumpur 1-10 of 38 reviews « 1 2 ... 4 » 
Travelers who viewed Carl&apos;s Jr also viewed
 Chilis Grill&amp;Bar 197 Reviews Kuala Lumpur, Wilayah Persekutuan Songket Restaurant 166 Reviews Kuala Lumpur, Wilayah Persekutuan
	</body>
</document>
