<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002691" url="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/health/article-2074754/One-cola--hours-run-Exercise-labels-effective-calorie-counts.html?ITO=1490" time="2012-07-12-18:45" support="1" score="0.0017209704580935462" bingtitle="One can of cola = one hour&apos;s run: Exercise labels could be &apos;more ..." webtitle="One can of cola = one hour&apos;s run: Exercise labels could be &apos;more effective than calorie counts&apos; 
 | Mail Online">
			<query id="001436" bing-rank="169"/>
	<description>... caloric information to consumers on fast food restaurant menu ... someone with the truths of junk food may change ... old niece launches her own children&apos;s wear line</description>
	<body>
		Home News U.S. Sport TV&amp;Showbiz; Femail Health Science Money RightMinds Coffee Break Travel Columnists 
 
 Health Home Health Directory Health Boards Diets MyDish Recipe Finder 

 My Profile Logout Login 
 Find a Job M&amp;S;Wine Our Papers Feedback Thursday, Jul 12 2012 6PM  15°C 9PM 9°C 5-Day Forecast 
One can of cola = one hour&apos;s run: Exercise labels could be &apos;more effective than calorie counts&apos;
 
By Daily Mail Reporter 
 UPDATED: 08:24 GMT, 16 December 2011 
 
 Comments ( 40 ) Share 
 
 
 
 Warning labels that explain how much exercise is needed to run off the calories in junk food are far more effective than traditional counts, researchers say. 


 It was found that teenagers who were shown the warnings on fizzy drink cans - which stated an hour&apos;s run would be needed to get rid of the calories - were half as likely to drink them. 


 Printing a &apos;physical activity equivalent&apos; on unhealthy drinks and food could dramatically reduce their popularity, according to researchers in the American Journal of Public Health. 

 
Warning: Messages stating how much exercise is needed to work off the calories from fizzy drinks were found to work better than any other warning
 
 Health expert Dr Sarah Bleich claimed that people &apos;generally underestimate&apos; just how many calories junk food and fizzy drinks contain. 
 

 Researchers from Johns Hopkins 
University in Baltimore, USA, posted three different signs outside 
corner shops to see which was best at putting teens off the soft drinks,
which contain an average of 250 calories each. 
 
 
Fancy that drink of coke? How about an hour&apos;s jog to work it off?
 
 One asked if they knew that the 
average fizzy drink contained 250 calories, another asked if they knew 
it was equivalent to ten per cent of their recommended daily intake.
 

 A third asked &apos;Did you know that working off a bottle of fizzy 
drink or fruit juice takes about 50 minutes of running?&apos;
 

 Results showed that providing 
calorie-related information did cause sales to drop by over a third (40 
per cent), but that the physical activity equivalent was most effective,
reducing soft drink sales among teens by half. 
 

 Study author Dr Sara Bleich said: &apos;People generally underestimate the number of calories in the foods and 
beverages they consume. 


 &apos;Providing easily understandable 
caloric information-particularly in the form of a physical activity 
equivalent, such as running-may reduce calorie intake from 
sugar-sweetened beverages and increase water consumption among 
low-income adolescents. 


 &apos;Because of the health problems 
associated with junk food, it is critical to explore the most effective 
strategies for presenting caloric information to consumers on fast food 
restaurant menu boards.&apos; 

 Super sweet fizzy drinks have been blamed for a range of health conditions including obesity, heart disease and type-2 diabetes.
 

 They are most popular among teens and people from poorer backgrounds. 

 
MOST READ NEWS

 Previous 1 2 3 4 Next 
 
 Billionaire &apos;lived with Eva&apos;s dead body for four days&apos;:... Palace outrage as Australian magazine publishes intimate... Horrific moment three young tigers attack and eat young cub... &apos;The way you brutally manipulated and exploited them is pure... Doing the logo-motion: From McDonald&apos;s without its big... &apos;The girl with this phone is dead, was smiling&apos;: The... O2 hit by nationwide network failure: &apos;Millions of users&apos;... Is that what you call a greenhouse? Ivy-covered house... The human right to claim benefits: Jobless could sue for... Renter&apos;s revenge: Pictures which show the squalid aftermath... The price of financial folly: As airports and luxury flats... McDonald&apos;s force Olympics bosses to ban all other... 
   
Share this article:
 
 Facebook Twitter Google+ Messenger LinkedIn Digg it Newsvine Fark Nowpublic Reddit 

 
 
 Print article Email article 
 
Comments ( 40 )
 
Here&apos;s what other readers have said. Why not debate this issue live on our message boards. 

The comments below have not been moderated.
 
 Newest Oldest Best rated Worst rated 
   View all 
Will the packaging be large enough to print all this nutritional information on?

- John S, Bromley, 17/12/2011 21:39
 Click to rate     Rating   7 
 Report abuse 
 
Whilst I can see merit in the reasoning, like Kate below, I have reservations that it may cause as much harm as good. As a diabetic I&apos;m probably more informed on diet than non-diabetics - however even for me, it&apos;s a nightmare looking at what is good and bad, so I&apos;ve simply reverted back to a good&apos;old-fashioned&apos;balanced diet and I&apos;m fine.
Perhaps a better idea would be to bring a new style&apos;Food and Nutrition&apos;class back into the curriculum!

- Danny Adams, Lincolnshire, 16/12/2011 19:35
 Click to rate     Rating   10 
 Report abuse 
 
Perhaps we could encourage people to smoke more to suppress their unhealthy appetites.

- ANDY5759, ST. ALBANS, HERTFORDSHIRE, 16/12/2011 19:26
 Click to rate     Rating   28 
 Report abuse 
 
While I can understand the thinking behind these changes and see the good intentions of the people behind these changes, I also have a creeping feeling that these labels could cause just as much harm as good.
Young people today are bombarded with images of overweight and underweight people - They are caught between two extremes and I doubt that many people my own age could identify what a healthy person (in a clinical sense) looks like and what they did to achieve that health. 
While shocking someone with the truths of junk food may change their dietary choices, steering them towards lower and lower calorie options is not the same as steering them towards an optimally balanced diet that includes less processed foods and more nutrient-dense foods. 
Why not, in addition to printing how many calories are contained in the item and work involved in burning those calories, also add ideas for healthier options? While hardly palatable to capitalists, it would make the most sense.

- Kate, Somewhere in Minnesota, USA, 16/12/2011 14:33
 Click to rate     Rating   13 
 Report abuse 
 
I think its a great idea people would eat much less of everything if they knew exactly how many calories they where eating and how long it takes to burn off those calories!! Here in Canada the labels are so much esier to understand they say 1 tablespoon = 25 calories, or 6 crackers = 120 calories, or 17 crisps = 270 calories which is much easier to work out that the UK labels. If you have to spend half an hour working out how many calories are in each item your not going to bother

- colette, Bowmanville, Ontario, Canada, 16/12/2011 13:50
 Click to rate     Rating   6 
 Report abuse 
 
As a rule of thumb most people working pretty hard on a treadmill/cross trainer/bike will burn off 500 calories per hour. And remember its not how long you run for but the distance you go. So walk a mile jog a mile run a mile same calories burnt. Depending on your weight, in the region of 100 calories per mile. Hope that helps (Runners dont forget you get a few calories free as running elevates your metabolic rate more than a walker so for a while after you stop running you&apos;re burning extra calories. 10% or so more than a walker)

- Pete, Manchester, 16/12/2011 13:39
 Click to rate     Rating   2 
 Report abuse 
 
By that reckoning to expend the RDA of calories for a day, 2500, you would have to go for a ten hour run? Calories are expended in the natural course of things too dont forget.

- Danny, Norhampton, England, 16/12/2011 11:54
 Click to rate     Rating   34 
 Report abuse 
 
Always amazes me seeing people open cans of fizzy or Red Bull on the train in the morning. If that&apos;s what they have for breakfast I can&apos;t imagine what they have for their other meals.

- alison, southend, essex, 16/12/2011 10:23
 Click to rate     Rating   43 
 Report abuse 
 
It also depends on how well your metabolism works, I think...I mean I drink soda almost everyday, don&apos;t exercise, and I&apos;m not overweight...nor do I have any other health problems...I just don&apos;t eat alot of junk and then sit around and do nothing...obesity really has nothing to do with drinking soda, this is ridiculous...it&apos;s all the other things you do on top of that...

- Shiann, Alamogordo, USA, 16/12/2011 09:38
 Click to rate     Rating   14 
 Report abuse 
 
Hmmm, More like a 2 litre bottle of Cola (not that vile&quot;diet&quot;stuff) should give enough energy and caffeine to sit through ten minutes of Ed Miliband or Ed Ball-Lox droning on and on and on and on and on about the&quot;cuts&quot;and skoolz&apos;n&apos;ospitals and&quot;dinner ladies&quot;pensionszzzzzzzzzz....

- The Punisher, Darlington, ENGLAND, 16/12/2011 09:37
 Click to rate     Rating   12 
 Report abuse 
 
The views expressed in the contents above are those of our users and do not necessarily reflect the views of MailOnline.
 
We are no longer accepting comments on this article.
 Bing Site Web Enter search term: Search     
FEMAIL TODAY

 Duchess of Cambridge&apos;s extreme makeover: She&apos;s stuck in a beauty rut - now FEMAIL gives Kate a beauty overhaul using new virtual technology &apos;This time, Justin messed with the wrong woman&apos;: Triumphant Tulisa settles legal action against ex over sex tape leak &apos;The truth has come out&apos; You&apos;re not fooling anyone! Tulisa spends five hours having her hair dyed blonde... then tries to hide it with a wig Next time put the wig on properly Tulisa! Gorgeous by day: Kelly Brook shows off her shape in sailor bikini as she enjoys amorous day with beau Thom Evans She&apos;s nautical but nice! Playful by night: Kelly Brook narrowly misses popping out of her dress as she dances at the dinner table in Italy Who needs a dance floor? Tom Cruise&apos;s lawyer to sue National Enquirer for &apos;hundreds of millions&apos; over &apos;vicious lies&apos; Branded Tom a &apos;monster&apos; and said he &apos;humiliated his wife&apos; Single lady style statement: Katie Holmes dons tight leather trousers for dinner date Younger, sexier image for Ms Holmes Gisele Bundchen&apos;s naked ambition is laid bare in daring nude beach shoot for Vogue Paris Stripping back to basics Robert Blake launches into bizarre tirade at Piers Morgan in first interview since being sensationally acquitted of wife&apos;s murder Want a body like Denise? Richards reveals the secret behind her slim frame as she works out in weight loss shorts It&apos;s that simple! The Only Way Is Essex star Gemma Collins in hot water over hair salon tweets Not the only TOWIE star to plug for freebies She&apos;s learned her lesson! Lydia Bright teams up with Zoe Hardman to encourage the public to stay safe in the sun Been burnt before No nudity, no sex, just cuddles: How one woman is making a living from snuggling - but for 38 an hour, would you pay to hug a stranger? Soldiering on: Bikini girl Rihanna lights up a suspicious roll-up cigarette as she unwinds in Barbados after family drama Chris Hemsworth... the human stroller: Thor star carries baby India Rose around on shopping trip - and leaves pram at home Hands on dad! Woman with world&apos;s largest natural breasts claims 102ZZZ-cup assets require security to fend off admirers who &apos;chase her&apos; Annie Hawkins-Turner Big Brother 2012: Psychiatrist rushed in as &apos;depressed&apos; ex Playboy model Shievonne Robinson makes suicide remark Been &apos;crying hysterically&apos; Fleetwood Mac reuniting for tour next year, reveals Stevie Nicks Play their first shows since 2009, Stevie confirmed Grimace and bear it: Christine Bleakley looks terrified with Frank Lampard at Universal Studios Not flashing those pearly whites It&apos;s chest OR legs! Sarah Harding reveals her very thin figure in a cropped top AND low-riding shorts Didn&apos;t get the memo Raffaella Fico shows off her growing bump as she steps out after penning open letter to Mario Balotelli Maintains footballer IS the father Aunty Khloe on duty! Kourtney Kardashian&apos;s sister looks after Mason while she spends time with newborn daughter Putting in some practise? A forlorn looking Rihanna goes back to her plaited roots... after returning home for grandmother&apos;s funeral Grieving loss of beloved grandmother Dolly Makes a change from tennis whites! Maria Sharapova reveals killer legs in sheer chiffon dress at ESPY awards Caused quite a racket &apos;One doctor suggested I abort her&apos;: Against all odds one of the world&apos;s smallest surviving babies finally goes home Kenna Claire Moore is a little miracle That&apos;s one pricey push-up! The bra dripping in diamonds and gold selling for $1million Contains 750 grams of gold They&apos;re his mini mes! Liam Gallagher&apos;s sons Lennon and Gene are a chip off the old block Perfected that mean and moody scowl Fifty Shades of Grey author&apos;s saucy tale was inspired by her Latin roots, says her mother Alexandra Mitchell has praised her daughter&apos;s erotic trilogy Making the most of her bikini body: Actress Louisa Lytton shows off her slim frame on holiday Before rehearsing for latest theatre show Lesbian sex scene in ballet thriller Black Swan makes it film with most complaints Some viewers described the scene as &apos;pornographic&apos; What would Marilyn say! Karolina Kurkova flashes a bit too much as she takes centre stage in a sexy photoshoot She took it a lot further! Angelina Jolie dresses her brood in angelic white... as Maleficent sticks to the dark side in head to toe black A woman of many talents Tom Cruise and Katie Holmes&apos;s amicable divorce is &apos;a sham as actor plans to keep Suri in Scientology&apos; He has &apos;planned her indoctrination&apos; &apos;Duct tape over the camera and a $1,000 a night Presidential Suite&apos;: Inside Tom Cruise and Katie Holmes&apos;s last weekend together Efforts to hide tension &apos;Look how broken up we look&apos;: Professor Green denies split from Millie Mackintosh Said he made up lesbian rumours &apos;I just can&apos;t function in the morning&apos;: What Nick Grimshaw told BBC boss moments before being offered top breakfast slot On Chris&apos; show today Pudsey goes Stateside! Talented pooch wins over U.S. audiences with an adorable performance on Jay Leno Entranced by their show Pictured: The moment Glee star Kristin Chenoweth received emergency medical treatment following injury on set Stretchered off set A bit of me time: Jessica Alba quaffs rose wine as she enjoys some bikini time with her mother in Amalfi As the children are away... EXCLUSIVE PICS: We get it, you&apos;re engaged! Katie Waissel can&apos;t keep her hands off model fiance Celebrating poolside in Los Angeles Mr Bigger: Sex And The City heart-throb Chris Noth succumbs to the middle-aged paunch Not the trim suited Mr Big he once was You can leave your hats on! Elle Macpherson&apos;s trendy son copies her jaunty style on holiday A trendsetter in her own family THAT&apos;S how she stays so slim! Lady Gaga reveals Lindsay Lohan snacks on cucumber on big nights out Forget a kebab - its all about salad Why do the children of the rich so often turn into drug addicts? As the Rausings tragedy develops, CATHERINE OSTLER looks at how drugs are classless That will make their friends Greene with envy! Twilight beauty Ashley leads co-stars in greeting determined fans at Comic-Co Mr Bigger: Sex And The City heart-throb Chris Noth succumbs to the middle-aged paunch Not the trim suited Mr Big he once was Proud Eugenie poses in mortar board as she graduates... and she can&apos;t stop smiling Royal looked delighted at Newcastle University It takes a lot of work to look this good! Kim Kardashian heads to the gym after sharing bikini snap from sunrise shoot That&apos;s Barry&apos;s Bootcamp workout Cesc Fabregas&apos; girlfriend Daniella gets snap happy as he shows off his football skills on holiday in Sardinia Who can blame her? When in Rome: Roxanne Pallett goes for a Eastern-inspired dress at Bali spa opening Emmerdale star showed off a lot of flesh 
 
 Today&apos;s headlines Most Read 
 
 Amazing recovery of woman with tennis ball-sized brain tumour back to work weeks after op - despite doctors&apos; predictions it would take at least a year Addicted to water: Young mother whose obsession started when she was just two years old drinks up to 44 pints a day Now you can get Botox on the NHS to stop migraines The 4,500 headphones that eased my terrible tinnitus South London Healthcare becomes first NHS Trust EVER to go into administration as debts spiral out of control Why it pays to stay calm: Anxiety may age you by SIX YEARS Baldness drug Wayne Rooney took &apos;could cause permanent impotence and shrink genitals in some men&apos; Drinking coffee during pregnancy &apos;won&apos;t turn your child hyperactive&apos; &apos;Beige fat&apos; discovery could speed up development of obesity treatments Everyone over 40 should be tested for diabetes, says health watchdog Britain&apos;s first womb transplant could be carried out in just TWO YEARS Heavily pregnant teenager, 19, forced to walk FIVE MILES home from hospital in rain as contractions start... then gives birth on her bathroom floor 

 MORE HEADLINES 
 
 Addicted to water: Young mother whose obsession started when she was just two years old drinks up to 44 pints a day Terminally ill mother marries partner after mystery donor known as &apos;Mary Poppins&apos; funds lavish ceremony South London Healthcare becomes first NHS Trust EVER to go into administration as debts spiral out of control Baldness drug Wayne Rooney took &apos;could cause permanent impotence and shrink genitals in some men&apos; Losing 10lb &apos;can reduce menopause symptoms&apos; including hot flushes and night sweats High blood pressure risk in later life for teenage girls on the Pill Everyone over 40 should be tested for diabetes, says health watchdog Amazing recovery of woman with tennis ball-sized brain tumour back to work weeks after op - despite doctors&apos; predictions it would take at least a year Brain scans could detect Alzheimer&apos;s disease decades before memory problems develop Britain&apos;s first womb transplant could be carried out in just TWO YEARS Former-smokers gain up to 11lbs a year after they quit the habit Working women more likely to put on weight &apos;as they put office needs over their health&apos; MOST READ IN DETAIL 
     
DON&apos;T MISS

 Miranda Kerr pretends to be demure in long floral dress... but still flashes her cleavage and legs Showed off her runway legs No bingo wings here! Catherine Zeta-Jones shows off her toned arms in a pretty sundress as she hits the shops All that heavy lifting The perfect pairing! Christina Hendricks is the hostess with the most-ess in a plunging black dress You would have to be a mad man not to notice Can you fake the perfect cleavage? We put underwear to the test as a new bra promises to boost your assets at the tug of a string DIY Chelsea blow-dry: Can you get Kate&apos;s tumbling curls without professional help? MARIANNE POWER took up the challenge Stephen Dorff&apos;s model girlfriend is nowhere to be seen... as he&apos;s surrounded by bikini-clad babes in Ibiza Katharina Damm MIA How does a man cope when his wife wont stop breast feeding? Vicky&apos;s decision to continue with their three-year-old is inhibiting their closeness, says James She&apos;s a fan of Pink too! Singer steps out with Carey Hart and daughter Willow who is dressed head-to-toe in the girly colour Her number 1 fan THAT&apos;S how to wind down after Wimbledon! Roger Federer and wife soak up sun on luxury yacht... as Andy Murray battles rain in Britain &apos;Having sex too young ruined my love life&apos; Kristen Dugdale tells her tale of regret at losing her virginity at just 14 Curvy and proud Aubrey O&apos;Day slips into ANOTHER revealing bikini Lapping up the attention in Florida &apos;We should all be proud of her for being real&apos;: Kendra Wilkinson defends Jessica Simpson&apos;s post-baby body Can sympathise with her AMANDA PLATELL: &apos;Why I dumped the spy who loved me&apos; As Jools Oliver admits she snoops on Jamie, Amanda shares her cautionary tale Carefree Amber Heard puts on a show in strapless bustier But girlfriend Tasya fails to raise a smile amidst Johnny Depp rumours Channing Tatum confirms sequel to Magic Mike... and puts himself forward for 50 Shades of Grey movie Right choice to play Christian? Suri&apos;s smile: Katie and Tom&apos;s daughter has her spirits lifted on zoo outing with mother and grandma Kept her distracted at Central Park in New York Did Katie Holmes make secret calls to Nicole Kidman before blindsiding Tom Cruise with divorce? Claims she sought counsel from his ex Palace outrage as Australian magazine publishes intimate photographs of Prince William and Kate&apos;s island honeymoon Woman&apos;s Day cover too Leggy Jessica Biel is white hot in a short but sweet frock at the ESPY Awards Actress was a sight for sore eyes in flirty dress Ultimate girl-next-door: Freida Pinto promotes film in cutesy frocks (although only a celebrity changes three times) Diva behaviour! If it ain&apos;t broke! Emma Roberts parades her perfect pins in her favourite tiny shorts She&apos;s found a look she likes and she&apos;s sticking with it... Kim Kardashian and boyfriend Kanye West match in leather trousers and white tops Pair looked picture perfect in coordinating looks History Detectives say they have &apos;found&apos; Bob Dylans legendary electric guitar from Newport Folk Festival (though singer says hes had it all along) Catch me if you can: Kai gives Coleen and Wayne Rooney the run around on family day out in Liverpool Playing in the sunshine Fringe benefits! Anne Hathaway shows off healthier figure in classy black dress after admitting Les Miserables diet was &apos;not fun&apos; Meg Ryan displays her sinewy arms in tomboy outfit In same vein as Madonna, Sarah Jessica Parker, and Angelina Jolie It&apos;s obviously following her! A healthy and happy Sarah Harding can&apos;t keep the smile off her face She brought a bit of sun back from Ibiza Angels on wheels! Stunning Doutzen Kroes leads the Victoria&apos;s Secret models at charity spinning event So THAT&apos;S how they stay slim! He is a Sk8er Boi! Rachel Zoe puts son Skyler on wheels with his first skateboard Adorable 15-month-old tried his luck on the vehicle I do, I do, I do! Three brides, one dress and 50 years of true love Three generations from one family tell their stories Why DO so many women pretend the menopause doesn&apos;t exist? The 50-somethings don&apos;t want to own up to their age Chloe Sevigny was worried about transsexual role in Hit&amp;Miss as she poses in androgynous photoshoot Thought fans would be &apos;angry&apos; Salt in the wound: Former cocaine user Demi Lovato brands X Factor double act &apos;irresponsible&apos; over drugs rap Asked them to get off Fit for a diva! Mariah Carey puts Bahamas villa where she wed Nick Cannon on the market Luxurious house sits on the beach Big Brother housemates strip to their underwear for spray tans as they win party treats But bitching intensifies Showing off their sea legs: Kate Moss and husband Jamie Hince get playful as they jump in unison off luxury yacht in St Tropez Tom Cruise&apos;s loyal son arrives on Oblivion set to lend support amid divorce turmoil Connor, 17, jetted to Mammoth Lakes, California Tom Cruise finds release from divorce turmoil by shooting a laser gun on the set of Oblivion That&apos;s one hell of a stress relief! Zooey Deschanel holds her own against red carpet regulars Hayden Panettiere and Olivia Munn at ESPY Awards New Girl star can do glam as well as quirky Redhead bullied at school says real gingers will ALWAYS be outcasts no matter how many celebrities dye their hair because fakes &apos;don&apos;t have the gene&apos; Not afraid to show her wild side! Jennifer Hudson teams leopard print hotpants with leather top Performed at food festival She&apos;s too sexy for her shirt! Sports Illustrated model Jessica Perez rips off her vest before taking Paul Rudd for a run Blimey! By &apos;eck! Melanie Sykes gets racy and shows she&apos;s a speed demon as she leaves ITV studios on the back of a motorbike Riding pillion Dressed to frill: Rose McGowan is red hot in a ruffled dress as she hits the shops Actress showed off her trim figure Devoted aunties! Kim, Kendall and Kylie wear matching &apos;Mason loves Penelope&apos; necklaces Pendants were given to them by mother Kris Kris Jenner&apos;s marriage to Bruce in crisis after he walks in on her signing off email &apos;xoxo&apos; to ex boyfriend Todd Waterman At breaking point Katie Holmes&apos; final snub to Scientology -&apos;actress registers with Catholic church in New York&apos; Breaking free from Tom Cruise Jamie read you the riot act? Jools Oliver looks miserable as she heads home from the shops Follows her paranoia revelation Out with the old and in with the new red ride! Selma Blair buys son Arthur an updated stroller In time for his first birthday He&apos;s growing up fast! Cindy Crawford goes shopping with her 13-year-old son Presley He appears to be enjoying life as a teenager Kate Moss smoulders in femme fatale role for Salvatore Ferragamo Seen walking in heels around Berlin&apos;s gilded Russian embassy Lean in green! Hayden Panettiere shows off her slender figure in a strapless bikini Holidaying in Mexico Making a bold comeback! Dannii Minogue tweets pictures of herself in a stunning floor-length yellow lace dress Bang on trend! No more late nights, Grimmers! How nocturnal Nick Grimshaw went from friend of the stars to landing Radio 1&apos;s top job Pixie Geldof a pal Dressing down gets the kiss-off. When times are tough the &apos;lipstick effect&apos; sees women spending on clothes and cosmetics Now that&apos;s an advantage: Andy Murray has an ace time as he enjoys time off with girlfriend Kim Sears following Wimbledon Posed with fan &apos;I feel complete&apos;: Christina Milian layers low-cut tanks for hike with daughter Violet She&apos;s &apos;the love of her life&apos; &apos;You&apos;ll get divorced soon anyway!&apos; Vinny rips apart Snooki&apos;s engagement bombshell Jersey Shore cast ridicule her decision New love, new home: Giovanni Ribisi sells bachelor pad as he moves in with supermodel bride Agyness Deyn That&apos;s some love nest I&apos;m off! Chris Moyles tells listeners he is quitting his Radio 1 breakfast show Nick Grimshaw to replace self-styled Saviour of Radio 1 Clingy, needy and moody. It&apos;s Rachel who&apos;s expecting - but it&apos;s her dog who&apos;s gone all hormonal Pregnancy is having a strange effect on Maxi The best advert for her own collection! TOWIE&apos;s Lucy Mecklenburgh shines in a bedazzled bikini to launch swimwear range Totes amaze Miss Modest: Kelly Brook covers up her curves in a white vest, as boyfriend Thom Evans shows off his six-pack Picture perfect couple! Reaching new heights: Angelina Jolie shoots more of her own daring stunts as she resumes filming of Maleficent Dangling from a crane Two Cabs! John Prescott has to take taxi to and from Sir David Frost&apos;s summer party Hobbled along with a walking stick after breaking his foot World champion Ronnie O&apos;Sullivan is set to swap snooker cue for dancing shoes as he&apos;s lined up for Strictly Terminally ill mother marries partner after mystery donor known as &apos;Mary Poppins&apos; funds lavish ceremony Naomi&apos;s breast cancer has spread to her spine Amanda who? Dominic Cooper moves on from on/off lover Seyfried by kissing mystery brunette on holiday in Italy That was quick! Don&apos;t stand next to her in the pool! Jessica Alba flaunts her enviable bikini body as she continues to enjoy her Italian family holiday Family time! Legs that go on forever! Kendall Jenner accentuates her supermodel height in a mint bodycon minidress Teenager&apos;s style style Bet that hasn&apos;t got air conditioning! Melissa McCarthy smiles as she films through &apos;The Heat&apos; in a clapped-out old car On set in Boston Plenty to celebrate! Jessica Simpson takes new daughter Maxwell to 32nd birthday bash Went to The Beverly Hills Hotel Rafa Nadal swaps his tennis racket for a snorkel as he shows off his ace body on holiday in Sardinia Action-packed holiday Dakota Fanning lends teary Elizabeth Olsen a shoulder to cry on (but don&apos;t worry, it&apos;s only for a scene in their movie) How Facebook is behind a surge in plastic surgery Surgeons say internet users are repulsed by their looks in pictures on social media sites She Will Be Loved: Adam Levine sends new Victoria&apos;s Secret model girlfriend Behati Prinsloo into a spin on way back to hotel Lea Michele continues transformation into fashionista as she turns model for new Candie&apos;s campaign Retro-inspired collection &apos;Skin cancer wouldn&apos;t stop me&apos;: Tanning addict hasn&apos;t missed a day of her sunbed habit in ten years It&apos;s cost Trisha 32,000 Duchess of Cornwall gives flowers back to tearful toddler who had a change of heart after presenting posy Royal introduction for Ffion Going for gold! Michael Phelps strips down to show off his swimmer&apos;s body as he gets set for the Olympics Cover guy Forget Eden Wood! Three tiny new trash-talking pageant queens herald the return of Toddlers and Tiaras All starts tonight Addicted to water: Sasha&apos;s obsession started when she was just two years old She drinks up to 44 pints a day Is Kate Upton dating Justin Verlander? Sports Illustrated supermodel spends weekend with star Detroit Tigers pitcher Getting close They won&apos;t twist your testicles, Russell! Comedian steps out in baggy trousers as TV doctor warns tight jeans are bad for your privates Wish you were here? Tamara Ecclestone shows off in a bikini as she escapes the rainy British summer in sunny Croatia What a show off! Let&apos;s hope she&apos;d already paid for it! Lindsay Lohan smokes a cigarette wearing a green vintage dress that she had just tried on Obviously liked it! Naked ambition: Tennis star Daniela Hantuchova and NFL hunk Rob Gronkowski pose nude for ESPN&apos;s Body Issue Stripping bare Their family&apos;s still growing! World&apos;s tallest married couple welcome 9.2lb son to follow in his father&apos;s size 15 footsteps I&apos;m a big brother now! Kourtney Kardashian&apos;s son Mason bonds with dad Scott Disick after family welcome a baby girl Having some guy time It&apos;s Bitchy Spears! America&apos;s sweetheart Britney exposes her tough side in X Factor USA ad... branding contestants &apos;predictable&apos; What is she smoking? Lady Gaga enjoys a suspicious-looking pipe as she dines out in bondage outfit Spoken about her love of smoking Breast reduction in a bottle? Creams made by Ultimo bra entrepreneur claim to shrink cup size in just 8 WEEKS Wants to help burdened with bigger bosom Paying the price for 1 sunglasses: Schoolgirl&apos;s terrifying allergic reaction Laura&apos;s head, eyes and nose swelled to twice their normal size Who knew she was so political! Miley Cyrus reveals her new tattoo - a quote from President Roosevelt Eagle-eyed fans spotted new etchings Sofia Vergara wears huge &apos;engagement ring&apos; as she gets swept off her feet by Nick Loeb on 40th birthday trip Seen flashing diamond on her wedding finger The dog poo vigilante: Model causes stink after filming herself throwing excrement at woman who let her pet foul the pavement Steer clear of the granny pants in future! Chelsee Healy suffers style mishap in neon bikini with huge bottoms as she parties in Ibiza She never learns! Kristin Chenoweth rushed to hospital after being &apos;hit by scaffolding&apos; on set of TV show The Good Wife Star treated for minor injuries Bodybuilder Jodie Marsh insists she&apos;s &apos;still celibate&apos;... as she gets physical with new boyfriend Kirk Norcross Yes, they really are a couple Shaking off the shackles of Royal decorum: Kate Middleton&apos;s raunchy cousin to strip for Playboy Katrina is exotic dancer Indecent exposure: TOWIE&apos;s Cara Kilbey falls out of revealing dress... and has her bottom exposed by friend Billi Mucklow It all started so well! Don&apos;t worry Nicole, they&apos;re just mates! Lewis Hamilton parties with glamorous female friends after disastrous F1 performance He&apos;s good at one thing! 
     
ADVERTORIAL FEATURES

 BirdsEye Win 1 of 5 Royal Family Breaks with BirdsEye Clinique&apos;s 3-Step System The best things in life come in 3. Click for your chance to WIN a years supply of Cliniques 3-step system &gt; 
 
 Back to top Navigation Popular 
 
 Home News U.S. Sport TV&amp;Showbiz; Femail Health Science Money RightMinds Coffee Break Travel Columnists 
 
 Popular searches in health: Daily Mail Facebook Daily Mail Health Twitter Daily Mail Google+ Pregnancy Guide Ovulation Calculator Breast Cancer Health Directory 
 Sitemap Newsletters RSS Archive Text-based site Reader Prints Top of page 
 Daily Mail Mail on Sunday Widgets This is Network This is London This is Money 
 Metro Jobsite Mail Travel Find a property Motors Prime location Villa Holidays 
Published by Associated Newspapers Ltd

Part of the Daily Mail, The Mail on Sunday&amp;Metro Media Group
 ©Associated Newspapers Ltd Contact us Advertise with us Terms Privacy policy&amp;cookies
	</body>
</document>
