<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002120" url="http://ezinearticles.com/?What-Does-It-Look-Like?&amp;id=634986" time="2012-07-12-18:01" support="6" score="0.0066979894540128435" bingtitle="What Does It Look Like? - EzineArticles Submission - Submit Your ..." webtitle="What Does It Look Like?">
			<query id="000149" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="001456" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="000139" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001466" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="001182" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="000994" bing-rank="164"/>
	<description>Seated at the table next to me at a fast food restaurant, I couldn&apos;t help hearing the ... wipe off the tables and sweep the floor in slow times, fill in cups and napkins at ...</description>
	<body>
		Search Home » Business » Careers Employment Nan S. Russell 
 Platinum Author |   115 Articles 
 Joined: November 4, 2004 Was this article helpful? 0 0 
What Does It Look Like?

 By Nan S. Russell 
 
Seated at the table next to me at a fast food restaurant, I couldn&apos;t help hearing the lack of conversation between a young woman and a younger uniformed man, clearly employees of the establishment. &quot;You need to take pride in your work,&quot; she told him. There was no response.

&quot;I told you last week, to start taking more pride in your work, but I don&apos;t see any improvement,&quot; she stated. This one way conversation went down hill from there. He kept glancing at her with a confused look as she repeated her unvaried message. Finally, the high school employee muttered something under his breath about &quot;trying harder&quot; and the conversation ended.

I understand his confusion. What does it mean to &quot;take pride in your work?&quot; What does &quot;pride&quot; behavior look like? How will he know if he&apos;s taken enough pride to satisfy his shift leader? Since pride is not an action, the input she gave wasn&apos;t something he could apply to improve his performance.

I expect their conversations won&apos;t get any better as respective frustrations grow. Yet, conversations like these are typical in many workplace relationships. A team leader or supervisor tries to provide feedback or coach a staff member toward better performance. She thinks she&apos;s providing direction, when in fact, she&apos;s offering what a former boss of mine used to call &quot;round&quot; words. They&apos;re pumped up and nice sounding, but they don&apos;t communicate much.

Let&apos;s say you inform your child that he needs to &quot;study more&quot; after a disappointing report card. You&apos;re thinking &quot;more&quot; means an hour a day and he&apos;s thinking another ten minutes. Even if you settle on the time allotment, &quot;more&quot; is one of those round words. It doesn&apos;t tell him what you want him to do during that time. What if you told him the TV had to be off when he studied, he needed to review his homework with you before dinner each school night, and on the evening before a test, he had to be prepared to be quizzed on the chapter? You&apos;d get better results.

It&apos;s the same at work. Telling a coworker you&apos;d like to get the information &quot;earlier,&quot; or informing a staff member that she needs to &quot;improve her performance&quot; won&apos;t help you get either. Instead, paint a word picture of &quot;what it looks like.&quot; Tell your coworker you need the information at least a day ahead of the meeting, and inform the staff member she can improve her performance by reducing misspellings, responding to requests within twenty-four hours, and following up with customers without being prompted. These are actions she can &quot;see&quot; and hence, do.

When you can tell your staff, coworker, or child &quot;what it looks like&quot; to be doing the outcome you desire in specific, measurable, quantifiable, or descriptive ways, you&apos;ll discover a secret people who are winning at working use every day. They paint word pictures for themselves and others of what it looks like to be doing the something they desire. So, if they decide they want to be more successful this year, they&apos;ll have an internal picture of what that success looks like so they can achieve it.

Someone who is winning at working would coach our fast-food restaurant employee differently. Instead of telling him he needed &quot;more pride&quot; in his work, she&apos;d specifically describe behaviors she wanted him to display. She&apos;d tell him he needed to return from breaks on time, verbally greet each customer, wipe off the tables and sweep the floor in slow times, fill in cups and napkins at the end of each shift, and wear a clean, unstained uniform to work each day. Once he achieved these behaviors, she&apos;d coach him with a new set of specific &quot;what does it look like&quot; to-be-performing-well behaviors.

People who are winning at working not only offer the best of who they are to their work, but they help others do the same. They facilitate an understanding of what it looks like to be successful in their workplaces. One philosophy I found particularly useful in my twenty years in management comes from Johann Wolfgang von Goethe: &quot;Treat people as if they were what they should be, and you help them become what they are capable of becoming.&quot;

Want to help others be winning at working, or enhance your own results? Use the &quot;what does it looks like&quot; approach.

(c) 2007 Nan S. Russell. All rights reserved.
 
Sign up to receive Nan&apos;s complimentary biweekly eColumn at http://www.winningatworking.com Nan Russell has spent over twenty years in management, most recently with QVC as a Vice President. She has held leadership positions in Human Resource Development, Communication, Marketing and line Management. Nan has a B.A. from Stanford and M.A. from the University of Michigan. Currently working on her new book, Hitting Your Stride: Your Work, Your Way (Capital Books; January 2008). Visit http://www.nanrussell.com 
 
Article Source: http://EzineArticles.com/?expert=Nan_S._Russell 
 Did you find this article helpful? 0 0 Get Involved 0 comments Suggest a topic Article Tools Print this article E-mail to a friend EzinePublisher Report this article Cite this article Stay Informed Get notified by email when new articles are added to this category or written by this author. 
Subscribe to New Article Alerts:
 
 Business: Careers-Employment 
 Nan S. Russell 
 Email Address: Subscribe Careers Employment Article Feed Find More Articles Search 
Similar Articles

 Performance Management is About Achieving Results - It&apos;s That Simple! Common Reasons Why You&apos;re Failing at Work Coaching Versus Managing Mental Fitness For Confidence And Winning In Life Going for Gold - 7 Tips to Ensure Small Business Success What&apos;s a Professional Sales Manager? How to Write a Resume Guaranteed to Win Interviews Training and Development For Employees To Provide Continuous Exceptional Results Perform Better - Sell More Improving Sporting Performance Easily With Effective Psychological Coaching 
 
Recent Articles

 How Can Joining a Job Agency Help You Find The Right Career? Advantages of Outsourcing an Executive Search IT Technician Salary Information The Role of a Medical Office Assistant What Does a Medical Assistant Do? 4 Significant Requirements To Become An Electrician Snail Mail Your Way to an Interview Risk Management and Failing Cyber Security A Prescription for Success: Becoming a Pharmacy Technician Imaging All The People Living For Today: The Medical Radiation Scientist 
 
Submitted On July 06, 2007. Viewed 221 times. Word count: 733.
 MLA Style Citation: 
Russell, Nan S. &quot;What Does It Look Like?.&quot; What Does It Look Like? .
 6 Jul. 2007 EzineArticles.com. 12 Jul. 2012&lt; http://ezinearticles.com/?What-­Does-­It-­Look-­Like?&amp;id=634986 &gt;. APA Style Citation: 
Russell, N. S. (2007, July 6). What Does It Look Like? .
 Retrieved July 12, 2012, from http://ezinearticles.com/?What-­Does-­It-­Look-­Like?&amp;id=634986 Chicago Style Citation: 
Russell, Nan S. &quot;What Does It Look Like?.&quot; What Does It Look Like? EzineArticles.com . http://ezinearticles.com/?What-­Does-­It-­Look-­Like?&amp;id=634986 
 EzineArticles.com 

©2012 EzineArticles.com
All Rights Reserved Worldwide
 
 About Us FAQ Contact Us Member Benefits Privacy Policy Shop Site Map 

 Blog Training Video Library Advertising Affiliates Cartoons 
 
Authors
 
 Submit Articles Members Login Premium Membership Expert Authors Endorsements Editorial Guidelines Terms of Service 
 
Publishers

Follow Us
 
 Terms Of Service Ezines / Email Alerts Manage Subscriptions EzineArticles RSS
	</body>
</document>
