<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002843" url="http://cr4.globalspec.com/blogentry/3371/Fun-Space-Experiments-for-Kids-Unit-2" time="2012-07-12-18:54" support="7" score="0.0076864207689280786" bingtitle="CR4 - Blog Entry: Fun Space Experiments for Kids - Unit 2" webtitle="CR4 - Blog Entry: Fun Space Experiments for Kids - Unit 2">
			<query id="001263" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="000135" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="001344" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="000775" bing-rank="156"/>
			<query id="000216" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="001340" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000212" bing-rank="117"/>
	<description>To make a full, astronaut-like meal, you need a tray like you&apos;d find in a cafeteria or fast food restaurant. ... mission mars mission selection mission to mars model airplanes ...</description>
	<body>
		Tell a Friend About CR4 Engineering Toolbar Search GlobalSpec 
 
 
 Login | Register 
 

 Home | Aerospace Blog 

 
Aerospace Blog

The Aerospace Blog is the place for conversation and discussion about aeronautics, astronautics, fixed-wing aircraft, future space travel, satellites, NASA, and much more.

Search for &quot;Aerospace Blog&quot; on Google, and you&apos;ll see that this is a top result!
 

 Previous in Blog: Fun Space Experiments for Kids (Unit 1)   Next in Blog: The Hole in the Sky 
 
Comments Format:
 Indented / nested by replies 
 Flat / chronological 

 Save setting as my default 

 
 Change Mode 
 
Subscribe to Discussion:
CR4 allows you to &quot;subscribe&quot; to a discussion
so that you can be notified of new comments to
the discussion via email.

 
Rating Vote:
 Score 1 
 Score 2 
 Score 3 
 Score 4 
 Score 5 

 
 Add Vote 
 
 
 Subscribe Rate this Comments: Nested 
 

 
Fun Space Experiments for Kids - Unit 2
 Posted September 27, 2007 12:25 AM 
 by M&amp;M;_aero Pathfinder Tags: astronauts experiements food space 
 
 
Eating is an essential activity for every living organism. Here
on Earth, we humans can drive to the grocery store, visit a McDonald&apos;s drive thru,
or open the refrigerator and cupboards to choose the foods we want to eat. We
can then turn on the faucet to wash ingredients and cook meals on the stove or grill,
or in the microwave–all without fear of our food floating away. Astronauts do
not have these same conveniences and choices. So how do they eat and cook in outer
space?

Here are three experiments that kids can perform to get a
&quot;taste&quot; of life in space. For information about the history (and problems) of
eating in space, check out &quot; How to Stop Your Dinner From Floating Away &quot;, right here on CR4.

 Experiment 1: Rehydration 

Rehydration is an essential part of eating in space . If astronauts
were to transport foods in their full form, the water and packaging materials would add
weight and require more storage space. Water, of course, is limited aboard a
spacecraft. Consequently, astronauts are allowed only a certain amount of H2O
for rehydrating food items.

For this experiment, you&apos;ll need a Ziploc sandwich bag, a straw,
a package of instant pudding, powdered coffee creamer, and a syringe. First, put
approximately 1/3 of the bag of pudding mix and 1 tablespoon of coffee creamer
into the sandwich bag. The creamer makes this concoction sweeter since pudding
is made normally with milk instead of water.

Cut a small slit in one side of the sandwich bag,
approximately ¼ of the way down from the top. Now insert the straw into the
slit seal it in place with tape and zip-seal the bag. Give the bag to your
junior astronaut and have the child use the syringe to add water through the
straw. To mix the water into the powder, the child must grasp the outside of
the bag and knead the two ingredients together. Continue to add water through
the syringe and straw until the mixture is completely hydrated. Finally, have
your junior astronaut eat the pudding through the straw–just like astronauts
do.

 Experiment 2: Vacuum Sealed 

Another major concern for astronauts is the growth of bacteria
and mold on their foods. To eliminate this unappetizing problem, all foods must
be vacuum-sealed. This also minimizes the amount of packaging materials that must
be brought aboard the spacecraft. Remember: There are no dumps in outer space.
What goes up must come down.

To prepare lunch for an astronaut, you&apos;ll need a vacuum
sealer. Because some foods work better than others, you&apos;ll also need to plan your
menu.

Main Course: Astronauts do not vacuum-seal Wonder bread. Without
air, the stuff gets pretty nasty. Fortunately, tortillas stay tasty in space. Cheese
sandwiches and hotdogs wrapped in tortillas work the best. For this experiment,
wrap either a hotdog or piece of cheese in a tortilla, and then vacuum-seal this
main course. Heat the package in a microwave oven for approximately 45 seconds
at high-power. Dinner is served!

Drink: Please don&apos;t try to vacuum-seal your own drinks. Just
imagine the kind of mess that this would make! 
A good off-the-shelf option is Capri
sun pouches. They are about as close to an &quot;astronaut design&quot; as you can get.

Snack: Previously-dried foods such as dried fruit and beef
jerky work the best in the vacuum sealer.

Dessert: M&amp;M&apos;s are a favorite and colorful choice.

 Experiment 3: Full Meal 

To make a full, astronaut-like meal, you need a tray like
you&apos;d find in a cafeteria or fast food restaurant. To hold your utensils in
place, attach several magnets to the tray. Typically, astronauts eat with a metal
fork, knife, spoon and scissors. To hold your meal in place, attach strips of
Velcro to the tray and your vacuum-sealed food items. Now stick the food items
to the tray. Finally, wrap a piece of elastic or large rubber band around the
tray. Your junior astronaut can now slide things under the band (such as a
napkin) and hold them in place.

Have fun eating a full &quot;astronaut meal&quot; with your kids! But be
sure to remind them that any crumbs or spills could be life threatening if they
float away and into the equipment.

That&apos;s the end of Unit 2. Look for Unit 3 next week, right
here on CR4. And if you missed Unit 1 , don&apos;t despair. It can be found here on
CR4, too.

 CR4 Aerospace Blog 
 Reply Send to a friend 

 Interested in this topic? By joining CR4 you can &quot;subscribe&quot; to
this discussion and receive notification when new comments are added. Join CR4, The Engineer&apos;s Place for News and Discussion! 

 Previous in Blog: Fun Space Experiments for Kids (Unit 1)   Next in Blog: The Hole in the Sky 
 You might be interested in: Vacuum Bagging and Infusion Equipment , Vacuum Pumps and Vacuum Generators , Vacuum Greases and Vacuum Pump Oils 
 

 
 
 &quot;In any contest between power and patience, bet on patience.&quot; -- W.B. Prescott 
All times are displayed in US/Eastern (EDT)
 
 ( Register to change time zone )

 ©2005-2012 GlobalSpec. All rights reserved.
GlobalSpec, the GlobalSpec logo, SpecSearch, The Engineering Search Engine
and The Engineering Web are registered trademarks of GlobalSpec, Inc.
CR4 and Conference Room 4 are registered trademarks of GlobalSpec, Inc.
No portion of this site may be copied, retransmitted, reposted, duplicated or
otherwise used without the express written permission of GlobalSpec Inc.
30 Tech Valley Dr. Suite 102, East Greenbush, NY, 12061 
 
Got Something to Say?
 Ask a Question 
 Start a Discussion 

 
Search this Blog
 Aerospace Blog:
 Go 

 
Search all of CR4
 Go 

 
Recent Blog Entries
 
 Wi-Fi in the Sky? Fair Use of False Advertising? Helpful or Hype? Falling Space Junk Flying Cars: Feasible or Fancy Idea? &quot;War Flying&quot; Did Boeing Get It Right? New Strategy for Space Exploration End of an Era? Harvesting Energy in Space Microwave Warhead en Route Show all Blog Entries 
 

 
Blog Tags
 2012 920th Rescue Wing accidents aces aerodromes Aeroelasticity aerospace Aerospace Technology aerospace web sites afterburners AHS AHS RFP AIAA air shows aircraft aircraft carrier aircraft design aircraft engines aircraft interior aircraft modifications aircraft museums airframes airlines airplane airplanes airships airshows albany AlgaeLink aliens Alliant Techsystems american champion aircraft american institute for aeronautics and astronauti antique aeroplanes antique aircraft AOPA Apollo ares flight vehicle ares i-x ares test rocket armageddon artwork Asteroid astronaut astronaut food astronaut selection astronauts ATC ATK atlantis avgas aviation aviation coatings aviation fuel aviation history aviation museums aviation products aviation web sites avionics balloons battle beads beam Bigelow Aerospace biofuel bird strikes black hawk black hole Black holes blue moon Boeing Boeing 747 bombers Bristol Hercules Burt Rutan C-17 Globemaster III C-27 cabin controls CAIT cargo planes catastrophe cessna ch-47 Challenger checkride childrens experiments chinook civilian aircraft Classical Lamination Theory clouds cockpits collision columbia comets competition Composite Calculation Composite Material composite materials constellation Continental IV-1430 engine Cooking Cracked Wings creativity crux Curtis Pitts custom aircraft damage Danger dangers DBF DC-2 DC-3 defense DFCE disasters Divergence drunken EAA EAA AirVenture Oshkosh EAA AirVenture Oshkosh 2009 early aircraft designs eating eclipse Eclipse 500 Effective Rigidities ELC4 Endeavour engine damage engine restoration engines Erickson Air-Crane experiements Experimental Aircraft Associaton experiments extraterrestrial F-15 Silent Eagle F-15 Strike Eagle F-15-SE F-18 F-18 Hornet F-22 Raptor f-35 F-35 Lightning II F-35A F-35B F-35C FAA fighter plane fighters firefighting flight flight deck flight lessons flight school flight simulation flight simulators flight training florida Flutter fly flying flying wing food fuel cell fuel tank fuselage geared turbofan german aviation gliders halo hazards Health heavy lift heavy lift helicopter helicopter helicopters helmet hobbies homebuilt aircraft Huey UH1-H hyper engines Hélica ice sensing IceCube Neutrino Observatory inflatable modules International space station ISS jet engine testing jet engine tests jet engines jets joby minor johnson space center joint strike fighter JSC JSF KSC launch lift! more lift! Lockheed Martin lunar eclipse lunar landing Marcel Leyat Mars mars travel mate-demate device mayan MB-2 MDD metal meteor shower mi-26 military aircraft millitary airplanes missile missiles mission mission mars mission selection mission to mars model airplanes money monoplanes Moon NASA navy north star orbiter outer outer space photo archives photography pictures pilot pilots piper cub plane planes planet planet mars living PMM polaris Pratt&amp;Whitney Pratt&amp;Whitney engines Program propeller-driven cars propellers PW610Fs Questions R2 RAF pilots RC airplanes RC models reciprocating engines records red remote control robonaut 2 robots rockets rotorcraft rotors runway San Diego Air and Space Museum satellite satellite collision satellites SCA scourned lover SDASM service center shoot down shooting shuttle shuttle carrier aircraft shuttles sikorsky Sikorsky Aircraft SMS solar solar power solar system solo south star soviet union space space debris space discoveries space exploration space junk space program space shuttle space shuttle discovery space shuttles Space Station space suit Space tourism space war SpaceShipTwo spruce goose sputnik stealth stealth fighter steam power Strofio structural analysis STS-127 STS-129 T-38 tack welding terrorism tourism training Tranquility University of Virginia user fees vacation very light jet viewing vintage aircraft Virgin Galactic Virgin Mothership (VMS) VLJ warbird warbirds warplanes WhiteKnight WhiteKnightTwo wilbur wright Wing wing theory wings Women Soar You Soar world war II X-Prize 

 
CR4 Sections
 
 Automotive BioMech&amp;BioMed Chemical&amp;Material Science Civil Engineering Communications&amp;Electronics Education and Engineering Careers Electrical Engineering General Instrumentation Manufacturing Mechanical Engineering New Technologies&amp;Research Software&amp;Programming Sustainable Engineering 
 

 
Site Directories
 Forum Directory 
 Blog Directory 
 User Group Directory 
 RSS Feeds 
 CR4 Store 

 CR4 Rules of Conduct 
 CR4 FAQ 
 Site Glossary 

 Who&apos;s Online (167 right now) 
 Show Members
	</body>
</document>
