<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002031" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Sandusky/Burger-King_607" time="2012-07-12-17:56" support="9" score="0.018772823434647465" bingtitle="Burger King - Fast Food Restaurant Sandusky, OH 44870" webtitle="Burger King - Fast Food Restaurant  Sandusky, OH 44870">
			<query id="001285" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000187" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000719" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000437" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000188" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="001536" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000313" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000436" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="000062" bing-rank="21"/>
	<description>Burger King is a Fast Food restaurant located at 706 W Perkins ... extremely slow and the girl working the front counter ... We review a wide selection of the best New York ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Burger King
 
Average User Rating
 
5
 
Average
 
Sponsored Link


 
(419) 626-5715

 http://www.burgerking.com/ 
 OH &gt; Sandusky &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Burger King listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Burger King to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Social 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Burger King
 Burger King is a Fast Food restaurant located at 706 W Perkins Ave in Sandusky, OH 44870. Burger King has been described as an Good Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 5 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Burger King
 
 
 
All Reviews for Burger King


 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Burger King:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   0

 
Comments
 
 
Burger King Tips
 Sooooooo slow omg there slow!
 
Gerrett H. Extremely slow!!!! We sat in line for over five minutes before we even paid for our food and we still had to wait at the window to receive the food.
 
Jennie T. This is the worst burger king I&apos;ve been to. They&apos;re extremely slow and the girl working the front counter has a major attitude problem towards the customers.
 
Denny L. 
Burger King News
 McDonald&apos;s Has A &quot;Big New York&quot; Burger...In Israel They&apos;ve just rolled out a half-pound &quot;Big New York&quot; burger meant to feed hungry Israelis. According to Ynet.com the &quot;premium burger made from entrecote and prime rib&quot; replaced the McFalafel in the country&apos;s restaurants as the chain tries to ... Fast food feeds sales growth in foodservice Growth in the foodservice market for apples continues to be driven by fast-food restaurants. McDonald’s, Subway and Burger King ... Jim Allen, president of the New York Apple Association, Fishers, called the McDonald’s decision a huge ... Meet the $16 Fast Food Burger Wendy’s is on pace to replace Burger King as the No. 2 hamburger chain in the U.S ... if that meat has some fancy ingredients on top of it), consider this: New York City’s db Bistro Moderne serves a hamburger with foie gras and black ... Ryan Fichter: The king of burgers You have got to admit that Ryan Fichter, executive chef of Georgetown&apos;s upscale burger joint, Thunder Burger&amp;Bar ... And Daniel Barber at Blue Hill at Stone Barns in New York. In a large stockpot, heat the oil over medium heat and saute the onions ... TEXT-Fitch updates recovery analyses for U.S. food and restaurant cos Dec 27 - Link to Fitch Ratings&apos; Report: U.S. Food and Restaurants ... Corporation Burger King Corporation Dean Foods Company Del Monte Corporation DineEquity, Inc. Dole Food Company, Inc. Smithfield Foods, Inc. (Caryn Trokie, New York Ratings Unit ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing Burger King - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia Burger King, often abbreviated as BK, is a global chain of hamburger fast food restaurants headquartered in unincorporated Miami-Dade County, Florida, United States. BURGER KING® – HAVE IT YOUR WAY® The official home of BURGER KING®. ... BK® Chef’s Choice Burger. A flame-broiled 5.5 oz burger patty, made with USDA certified ground chuck seasoned with salt ... Hamburger - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia A hamburger (also called a hamburger sandwich or burger) is a sandwich consisting of a cooked patty of ground meat (usually beef, but occasionally pork or a ... New York Restaurants Known as the city that never sleeps, New York offers a truly spectacular range of restaurants. We review a wide selection of the best New York Restaurants covering ... Burger King | Buy KFC Menu History Main create-up: History of Burger King The predecessor to what is now the globally quick meals restaurant chain Burger King was founded in 1953 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 80° 
Fri
 
 70° - 95° 
Sat
 
 72° - 90° 
Sun
 
 73° - 90° 
 
Address
 
Burger King

706 W Perkins Ave

Sandusky, OH 
 
44870
 
Telephone
 (419) 626-5715 
Burger King
 
 Rating :  5 out of 10 based on 5 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Burger King Photos
 
 Fast Food 
 
 Local Places
 
 KFC 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Burger King 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food West Park Inn 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Dq Grill&amp;Chill 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Liberty Lanes Ltd Restaurant Lounge Bowling 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food China King 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Burger King 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Taco Bell 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Access Cash International Incorporated West 
Cuisine: ATMs ATM Network Incorporated MN 
Cuisine: ATMs ATM Systems of Ohio Incorporated 
Cuisine: ATMs Citizens First Savings Bank 
Cuisine: ATMs Citizens First Savings Bank ATM 
Cuisine: ATMs 
 

See all Sandusky ATMs 
See all Sandusky Bars and Pubs 
See all Sandusky Campgrounds 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Burger King Coupons 

 Burger King Sandusky 

 Burger King Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Sandusky Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | I | J | K L | M | N | O | P | R | S | T W 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
