<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002583" url="http://ccyee.wordpress.com/2011/08/14/taipei-free-and-easy-trip/" time="2012-07-12-18:39" support="1" score="0.001405721154604639" bingtitle="Taiwan Taipei Free And Easy Trip – Day 1 « cc yee&apos;s blog" webtitle="Taiwan Taipei Free And Easy TripDay 1cc yees blog">
			<query id="001409" bing-rank="227"/>
	<description>... Express Airport Bus ticket counter, located on the southwest side in the Arrival Passenger Reception Area. ... open daily from 7am to 12am) or Fast-food Restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		cc yee&apos;s blog 
 Just another WordPress.com site 
 Home About 
 Home &gt; Taiwan , Travel &gt;Taiwan Taipei Free And Easy Trip–Day 1 
Taiwan Taipei Free And Easy Trip–Day 1
 August 14, 2011 cc yee Leave a comment Go to comments 
 
 
Taipei Free and Easy Day 1
 
This is our first time to Taipei .  Actually we do not know much about Taipei, although there are plenty of TV program to introduce Taiwan, the problem is we seldom watch TV program.  Therefore, we have spent a lot time on internet to search for information about Taipei City , Places of Attraction&amp;their history, Transportation on Metro, Train and Bus service&amp;etc.

Taipei City is in the northern part of Taiwan island in a basin between the Yang Ming Mountains and the Central Mountains.  The largest city of Taiwan, it serves as its financial and governmental center.

 DAY 1 

Haha.. Taipei, we are coming, yeah. 

After 4 hours and 40 mins on the air (by Jestar Airway), we are arrived at Taiwan Tao Yuan International Airport Terminal I 台灣桃園國際机场 第一航厦 at 6.30pm, after Custom clearance and pick-up our luggage, we straight away proceed to the Express Airport Bus ticket counter , located on the southwest side in the Arrival Passenger Reception Area.  Public transport is very convenient and efficient in Taipei.
 
Welcome to Taiwan
 
If you landed at the Terminal II, the Express airport bus ticket counter is located on the northeast side in the Arrival Passenger Reception Area.

Adult single bus  fares vary from NT$110 to $140 depending on the bus company, bus service available every ten to fifteen minutes on each route.
 
Bus Ticket from Airport to Taipei Main Station
 
We bought ticket at NT125 each from Kuo Kuang Bus Counter to Taipei Station 台北车站 .  We already have 2 Easy-cards 悠游卡 from Taiwan Tourism Bureau , the only thing we need to do upon arriving is to top up the value.  The procedure is very simple, same as what we are doing in Singapore ( Ez-link Card ) or Hong Kong ( Octopus Card ).

 
 
Easy Card from Taiwan Tourism Bureau for Travel on MRT and Buses.
 
 
 
Taipei MRT Map
 
After about 45min bus ride, the bus stopped at outside Taipei Main Station 台北车站.  After top up our Easy-card, we took MRT from Taipei Station and alight at Chiang Kai-Shek Memorial Hall Station Exit 5 中正紀念堂站 , is only 2 stations away.  Taipei Station is the Main Station in Taipei City, it’s provide MRT, Train, High Speed Train and Bus Services.
 
Chiang Kai-Shek Memorial Hall Station - People Line up for MRT
 
 

 HOTEL 

The hotel we choose is Wing Hotel 雲鼎商務旅店 , only 3 mins walk from the Chiang Kai-Shek Memorial Hall Station .  Price is reasonable, NT1,850 per night included breakfasts.  Hotel will issue voucher each day for breakfast at 老田咖啡厅 (open daily from 7am to 12am) or Fast-food Restaurant (if you need to travel early in the morning).
 
Hotel Bedroom
 
 
 
Hotel Room
 
 
 
Big Bathtub
 
 

After check-in, it’s already 8.30pm.  We put down our luggage, after a quick shower we quickly go out to find foods, to have our first meal in Taipei.  Our first itinerary in Taipei was to visit:

 

 Shi Lin Night Market 士林夜市 

 
 
Main Road of Shilin Night Market
 
 

 MRT : Take Dansuei (Red) Line to Jian Tan Station 劍潭站 
 Location : Around Wenlin Road 文林路 and Dadong Road 大東路
 Open : 4pm to Midnight daily

 
 
Jian Tan Station
 
 
 
Shilin Night Market very Crowded
 
To really taste the flavor of Taiwanese lifestyle a trip to a night market is a must, and Shilin ranks first among all the night markets in Taipei, a“must-see”attractions oh.  It is widely regarded as having the widest range of products, the best tasting food, the biggest crowds and the most convenient transportation, just opposite the Jian Tan MRT Station .
 
Shilin Night Market, with shops selling almost everything.
 
 
 
Their Business Stall ( illegal push cart, can close shop in 3 seconds, we saw their super fast action once enforcement staff is detected by them )
 
We had our dinner in the food court, located directly across the street from the station.
 
Shilin Market Opp. Jiantan Station
 
 
 
Yummy... Eating&quot;Super&quot;Big Chicken Chop while Shopping.
 
 
 
Famous Stinky ToFu... Really very Smelly oh.
 
 

 Specialty foods and drinks includes: oyster omelets and mee sua 蚵仔煎和面线 smelly stinky tofu 臭豆腐, big chicken chop 大鸡排, lemon aiyu jelly 檸檬愛玉, fried buns 生煎包, peanut candy 花生糖, bubble tea 珍珠奶茶, snow flakes crushed ice 雪花冰 and etc.
 
White Color Bitter Gouart&quot;Ku Gua&quot;Honey Juice - Delicious, Must Try
 
 
 
Lemon Aiyu Jelly
 
 
 
Big Hot Dog
 
 
 
Famous Super Big Chicken Chop, long Q
 
 

 Link: Taipei Free and Easy Trip Day 2 

 Link: Taipei Free and Easy Trip Day 3 

 Link: Taipei Free and Easy Trip Day 4 

 Link: Taipei Free and Easy Trip Day 5 

 

Related articles

 Touring from Above and Looking for Pandas–Taipei, Taiwan (travelpod.com) Latest Taiwan Travel Info (fathomtaiwan.com) 
 
Rate this:
 
Share this:
 
 StumbleUpon Twitter Facebook LinkedIn Print Digg Reddit Email Tumblr 
 
Like this:
 Like 6 bloggers like this. 
 
 Categories: Taiwan , Travel Tags: Chiang Kai-Shek Memorial Hall Station , Easy-cards , Octopus Card , Shi Lin Night Market , Taipei 101 , Taipei Free and Easy Trip , Taipei Station , Taiwan Tao Yuan International Airport , Wing Hotel , 台灣桃園國際机场 , 士林夜市 , 悠游卡 , 中正紀念堂站 Comments (8) Trackbacks (2) Leave a comment Trackback 
 Anonymous November 18, 2011 at 6:18 AM | #1 Reply | Quote 
Very good information and pictures that will be a great help for visitors to Taipei. I have put a link on my blog to yours.

 http://fathomtaiwan.com 
 Robin January 29, 2012 at 11:32 AM | #2 Reply | Quote 
What beautiful Pictures, and a beautiful place. Thank you. I saw that you looked at my blog, and I clicked on yours. Very nice. I will read more of it. Thank you again!
 XX January 29, 2012 at 11:22 PM | #3 Reply | Quote 
Very informative. Thank you for the sharing…
 apocalypseicons January 31, 2012 at 8:01 PM | #4 Reply | Quote 
Fabulous pictures. Thanks for stopping by my blog and I am glad to discover yours. the food looks yummy!
 Anonymous February 22, 2012 at 5:15 PM | #5 Reply | Quote 
hi…i read your Taiwan tour, how’s you get the easy card? you book hotel through internet or how you get this hotel? Thank you.
 
 cc yee February 22, 2012 at 8:39 PM | #6 Reply | Quote 
Thanks for visiting.
We get the easy card from the Taiwan Tourism Bureau during their Promotion in Singapore. You can buy the Easy card from any MRT station in Taiwan. We book the hotel through internet http://www.winghotel.com.tw 
 
 Anonymous April 12, 2012 at 11:17 AM | #7 Reply | Quote 
Hi, how long did the hotel takes to reply u? thanks.
 
 cc yee April 14, 2012 at 10:32 PM | #8 Reply | Quote 
Thanks for dropping by. For my case they reply the next day. Hope you will have fun in Taiwan.
 
 

 September 24, 2011 at 2:11 PM | #1 Taipei Shilin Night Market (Part 2) 臺北(Formosa), Taiwan | Cooking Dinner For Two November 19, 2011 at 6:39 AM | #2 E-Bike 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (Address never made public) Name Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 

 Notify me of new posts via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 Taiwan Taipei Free and Easy Trip – Day 2 Michael Jackson Gallery RSS feed 
 Google Youdao Xian Guo Zhua Xia My Yahoo! newsgator Bloglines iNezha 
 
 
 
 
 
 August 2011 M T W T F S S «Jul   Sep» 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31   
 
Recent Posts

 Korea Trip Day 6 Korea Trip Day 5 Korea Trip Day 4 Korea Trip Day 3 Korea Trip Day 2 Korea Trip Day 1 Jokes–Just For Laugh Bali Free and Easy Trip–Day 4 Bali Free and Easy Trip–Day 3 Bali Free and Easy Trip–Day 2 Bali Free and Easy Trip–Day 1 Hong Kong Free And Easy Trip – Day 5 Hong Kong Free And Easy Trip – Day 4 Hong Kong Free and Easy Trip–Day 3 Hong Kong Free And Easy Trip–Day 2 Hong Kong Free And Easy Trip – Day 1 Taiwan Taipei Free And Easy Trip – Day 5 Taiwan Taipei Free And Easy Trip – Day 4 Taiwan Taipei Free And Easy Trip – Day 3 Singapore Bottle Tree Park Taiwan Taipei Free and Easy Trip – Day 2 Taiwan Taipei Free And Easy Trip–Day 1 Michael Jackson Gallery 散文– 旅游的启发 Japan Hokkaido Trip 北海道–Day 7 Japan Hokkaido Trip 北海道–Day 6 Japan Hokkaido Trip 北海道–Day 5 Japan Hokkaido Trip 北海道–Day 4 Japan Hokkaido Trip 北海道–DAY 3 Japan Hokkaido Trip 北海道–Day 2 Japan Hokkaido Trip 北海道–Day 1 Crystal– Moonstone Health Benefit of Salt Baked Chicken jokes of the day Ipoh Salt Baked Chicken Available In Singapore Mr. Lai car Awareness–Drinking Water Apa Sudah Jadi Yugi? Crystal–Lapis Lazuli One Singh Awareness–起云剂 vs. 塑化剂 How To Quit Drinking Driver With Guts Awareness–To Protect Our Planet II Crystals– Amethyst Awareness – To Protect Our Planet I Intelligent People!! Bottle Tree Sunset in Singapore Car on fire Boss 60th Birthday Party Teluk Batik Beach Picnic Medication for allergy and skin itch. Traditional Chinese Paintings Judgement Day 21 May?? Macau Free and Easy Tour Buddha Tooth Relic Temple Nice and Beautiful Flowers SNYO Classical Concert 2011. Limousine–Super Long Car 
 
Categories

 Arts (3) Bali (4) Cars (4) Chinese Post (3) Crystal (3) Environmental (5) Food (5) Health (3) Hong Kong (6) Japan (7) Jokes (7) Korea (7) Macau (2) Malay Post (1) Malaysia (4) Nature (8) Singapore (9) Social (3) Sports (1) Taiwan (5) Travel (32) Uncategorized (2) 
 
Archives

 July 2012  (1) February 2012  (1) January 2012  (1) December 2011  (3) November 2011  (6) October 2011  (3) September 2011  (3) August 2011  (8) July 2011  (5) June 2011  (14) May 2011  (19) February 2011  (1) June 2010  (4) 
 
Top Posts

 Taiwan Taipei Free And Easy Trip - Day 1 Taiwan Taipei Free And Easy Trip – Day 3 Taiwan Taipei Free And Easy Trip – Day 4 
 
 my Twitter 

 RT @ RedmondPie : Next-Gen iPhone Already Up For Pre-Order In China goo.gl/fb/HFRUf 1 hour ago DAP: Drop Sedition Act charges to prove repeal ‘genuine’. Check this news at bit.ly/NqXQ2E 1 hour ago New banknotes feature latest technology, says Bank Negara. Check this news at bit.ly/NqXMQA 2 hours ago 
 Follow @ccyee888 
Pages

 About 
 
 Email Subscription 
 
Enter your email address to subscribe to this blog and receive notifications of new posts by email.

Join 377 other followers

 

 
 
Recent Comments

 premier limos on Limousine–Super Long… Anonymous on Korea Trip Day 6 Korea Trip Day 6 « c… on Korea Trip Day 6 
 
Tags
 Angelica beach Chicken Crystal Emission Reduction Energy Healing Environment Food Gaia gemstone Ginger Global Warming Haneda International Airport Healing Health Hokkaido ipoh Ipoh Salt Baked Chicken jokes Kampung Chicken Lake Akan Lake Onneto Macau Michael Jackson Gallery minerals MJ Gallery Money plant Mount Sorak Odori Park Onsen perak Protect our Planet Quartz Save our Planet saving gaia Seoraksan National Park south korea 东京羽田机场 北海道 層雲峡峡谷 当归 札幌 生姜 盐焗鸡 马来鸡 
Blogroll

 Almanac Calendar Amnesty International Asia Setinel Channel NewsAsia Lawyers For Liberty LoyarBurok Malaysiakini Redmond Pie The Malaysian Insider Tukar Tiub WWF 
 
Meta

 Register Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.com 
 
Blog Stats

 84,881 hits 
 
Site Meter
 
Flag Counter
 Ping your blog, website, or RSS feed for Free Google pagerank checker powered by mypagerank&quot; 
SEO Monitor
 
 RSS - Posts RSS - Comments 
 
Quote&amp;History:
 Quote of the Day Quote of the Day provided by TheFreeDictionary 
 This Day in History This Day in History provided by TheFreeDictionary 
 
Live Traffic Feed
 
Flickr Photos

 
 

 

 More Photos 
 
 Top WordPress Blog at WordPress.com . Theme: INove by NeoEase . Send to Email Address Your Name Your Email Address Cancel Post was not sent - check your email addresses! Email check failed, please try again Sorry, your blog cannot share posts by email.
	</body>
</document>
