<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002415" url="http://hubpages.com/forum/topic/68116" time="2012-07-12-18:20" support="1" score="0.011410698293920237" bingtitle="What Fast Food Restaurant Has the Best French Fries" webtitle="What Fast Food Restaurant Has the Best French Fries">
			<query id="000664" bing-rank="126"/>
	<description>What Fast Food Restaurant Has the Best French Fries ... The only thing I order from the McDonalds menu is a ... I only eat certain things at those places like: Fries ...</description>
	<body>
		HubPages 
 explore 
 topics hubs answers forums 
 sign in join now 
 jump to last post 1-19 of 19 threads (37 posts) Loading... 
 All Forums  » Food and Cooking  » Restaurants and Fast Food  » Fast Food Restaurants 
 
What Fast Food Restaurant Has the Best French Fries

 76 Masata posted 16 months ago 
I am doing research for my next hub and this is what it is about so please feel free to make all your comments here thanks.
 
 reply more→ report permalink 
 92 samboiam posted 16 months ago in reply to this 
Chick-fil-A

 
 reply more→ report permalink 
 76 Masata posted 16 months ago in reply to this 
Thanks
 reply more→ report permalink 
 90 cheapsk8chick posted 16 months ago in reply to this 
McDonald&apos;s!
 reply more→ report permalink 
 76 Masata posted 16 months ago in reply to this 
lol I worked there before I like their fries too but this is not about what I like I want to hear what the world likes
 reply more→ report permalink 
 80 Tatara posted 16 months ago in reply to this 
McDonald&apos;s.
 reply more→ report permalink 
 93 KCC Big Country posted 16 months ago 
Chick-fil-a fries are good, but ONLY when they&apos;re hot. Once they cool down, they&apos;re horrible.

I think Wendy&apos;s new Natural cut sea salt fries are pretty good.

 
 reply more→ report permalink 
 76 Masata posted 16 months ago in reply to this 
Which do you like most
 reply more→ report permalink 
 93 evvy_09 posted 16 months ago 
I like Hardees natural cut fries. Though the Wendys ones look really good too, their fries used to be horrible. 
Backyard burgers had some tasty fries, but my vote goes for Hardees.
 reply more→ report permalink 
 76 Masata posted 16 months ago in reply to this 
I never ate there but I hear they have really good food. Thanks for the feed back
 reply more→ report permalink 
 95 gypsumgirl posted 16 months ago 
I think the French fries at McDonald&apos;s are, hands-down, the best of all the fast food chains.
 reply more→ report permalink 
 76 Masata posted 16 months ago in reply to this 
Thanks for your feedback
 reply more→ report permalink 
 97 rebekahELLE posted 16 months ago 
Five Guys.
 reply more→ report permalink 
 76 Masata posted 16 months ago in reply to this 
I don&apos;t think I would consider five guys fast food but thanks.
 reply more→ report permalink 
 87 ediggity posted 16 months ago 
Boardwalk fries, or Five Guys. 
 reply more→ report permalink 
 76 Masata posted 16 months ago in reply to this 
As I said I really don&apos;t think five guys could be considered fast food but thanks for the feed back
 reply more→ report permalink 
 77 Midasfx posted 16 months ago 
The only thing I order from the McDonalds menu is a the French Fries. I prefer theirs vs. BK or wendy&apos;s.
 reply more→ report permalink 
 76 Masata posted 16 months ago in reply to this 
Really why is that?
 reply more→ report permalink 
 77 Midasfx posted 16 months ago in reply to this 
just the smell of their&quot;burgers&quot;makes me sick. i feel sick if i eat anything besides the fries. I only eat certain things at those places like:

Fries~ McDonalds
Onion Rings ~ BK

some people have a sweet tooth, I have a salty tooth? lol. its across the street from my work and when im craving some salt ill go and get fries and smother them in ketchup. always get a small too. cant indulge too much.
 reply more→ report permalink 
 76 Masata posted 16 months ago in reply to this 
Lol cool, It is always fun to relive a child hood moment at least that is what I get every time I eat a McDonald&apos;s.
 reply more→ report permalink 
 78 rosiehoneywong posted 16 months ago in reply to this 
McDonald&apos;s best, I dont need to add any sauce, it still tastes good
 reply more→ report permalink 
 76 Masata posted 16 months ago in reply to this 
Cool Thanks
 reply more→ report permalink 
 
 
 
 
 86 Bellamie posted 16 months ago 
kid valley has good fries.
 reply more→ report permalink 
 76 Masata posted 16 months ago in reply to this 
I will check them out where are they located and thanks
 reply more→ report permalink 
 81 Maembe posted 16 months ago 
I like Arby&apos;s because they have curly fries.
 reply more→ report permalink 18 adrienne25 posted 16 months ago 
I agree, with lots of ketchup as well!
 reply more→ report permalink 81 theseus posted 16 months ago 
In the Philippines, the best french fries is from Jollibee. For me, at least.
 reply more→ report permalink 
 82 tritrain posted 14 months ago in reply to this 
Is ketchup in the Philippines made of banana mostly? I know it was when I was last in the PI. Very sweet flavored compared to the tomato-based version in the US.
 reply more→ report permalink 
 90 b4murray posted 14 months ago 
Wendy&apos;s or Mcdonalds, But I am not sure if Wendy&apos;s new natural cut fries are better that the original...
 reply more→ report permalink 88 eatlikenoone posted 14 months ago 
Wendy&apos;s or Culver&apos;s
 reply more→ report permalink 92 kerryg posted 14 months ago 
I hardly ever eat fast food, so I&apos;m not really sure which of the big chains I prefer, but I have to put in a good word for a local Great Plains chain called Runza. Great fries!

 http://runza.com/ 
 reply more→ report permalink 83 Disturbia posted 14 months ago 
I don&apos;t eat them but according to my kids... McDonald&apos;s!
 reply more→ report permalink 82 Matt in Jax posted 14 months ago 
Five Guys&apos; Cajun-style is my personal favorite. I&apos;ve tried Wendy&apos;s new&quot;better than McDonald&apos;s&quot;fries and I wasn&apos;t impressed.
 reply more→ report permalink 97 Stacie L posted 14 months ago 
I am not impressed with Wendys new fries either. They are too salty and just look different as far as I&apos;m concerned. i still think their other food is better than anyone else.
 reply more→ report permalink 
 82 Matt in Jax posted 14 months ago in reply to this 
Agreed on that. Burgers are awesome, but not better than everybody else.
 reply more→ report permalink 
 40 Solar Awareness posted 14 months ago 
I see that nobody has bothered to mention Nathan&apos;s Famous.. (originated in New Yawk) They are much better known for their hotdogs and I believe they have the best fries; crinkle cut with some of the potato skin left on.
 reply more→ report permalink 78 dutchman1951 posted 14 months ago 
No&quot;Fast Food&quot;place has the best, the better resturants that serve them fresh and hand cut, cooked at a proper temp, and seasoned well are the best. Fast=cheep, and cheep = average taste, thats why its fast! No good
 reply more→ report permalink 
 Post a Reply jump to first post   The post you are replying to is over two months old. Please DO NOT reply UNLESS you have truly new information to add to this conversation. Consider creating a new forum thread instead. Some errors were found: 
 
 submit cancel formatting formatting add photo close add photo back Upload Import My Photos 
Text Formatting
 [b]Bold text[/b] produces Bold text 
[u]Underlined text[/u] produces Underlined text 
[i]Italic Text[/i] produces Italic text 
[color=#ff0000]Red Text[/color] produces Red text 
[color=blue]Blue Text[/color] produces Blue text 
 
Links
 [url=http://hubpages.com/]HubPages[/url] produces HubPages 
[url]http://hubpages.com/[/url] produces http://hubpages.com 
[email]help@hubpages.com[/email] produces help@hubpages.com 
[email=help@hubpages.com]HubPages Help[/email] produces HubPages Help 
 
Images
 [img]http://x.hubpages.com/x/hubpages_120-60.gif[/img] produces: 
 
Quotes
 [quote=James]This is the text I want to quote.[/quote] 
Smilies
 :) =) :| =| :( =( :D =D :o :O ;) :/ :P :lol: :mad: :rolleyes: :cool: 
Advertising and promotional posts in the forums will be deleted and may result in the closing of your HubPages account. Signatures are also prohibited. forum rules 

Check the HubPages FAQ before asking HubPages related questions.
 
 Explain briefly why are you reporting this post Select reason... Spam Personal Attack Hate Speech Wrong Forum Category Other Choose new forum -Choose a Forum-   HubPages Community Need Help? Ask here. HubPages Tutorials and Community The Hubber&apos;s Hangout Extreme Hub Makeover The Sandpit HubChallengers Local Meetups   By Category Arts and Design Autos Books, Literature, and Writing Business and Employment Education and Science Entertainment and Media Family and Parenting Fashion and Beauty Food and Cooking Games, Toys, and Hobbies Gender and Relationships Health Holidays and Celebrations Home Personal Finance Pets and Animals Politics and Social Issues Religion and Philosophy Sports and Recreation Technology Travel&amp;Places   HubPages Official Report a Technical Problem or Bug Report an Ad Problem Report a Traffic Problem Suggest a New Feature Anything else you want to add 
You are sending a private message to the HubPages team
 
 HubPages 
 about us blog advertise faq link to this page copyright 

Copyright©2012 HubPages Inc. and respective owners. All rights reserved.

Other product and company names shown may be trademarks of their respective owners.

HubPages ® is a registered Service Mark of HubPages, Inc.

 terms of use privacy policy (0.16 sec)
 working
	</body>
</document>
