<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002713" url="http://articles.baltimoresun.com/keyword/illegal-dumping" time="2012-07-12-18:46" support="2" score="0.0018159111895800803" bingtitle="Articles about Illegal Dumping - Baltimore Sun" webtitle="Articles about Illegal Dumping - Baltimore Sun">
			<query id="001437" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="001469" bing-rank="136"/>
	<description>... the 3200 block of Doycron Court in Baltimore County ... Today, she looks out on a fast-food restaurant and low-slung shops ... illegal dumping ground for people who bring trash ...</description>
	<body>
		Advertisement Home → Collections → Illegal Dumping IN THE NEWS 
Illegal Dumping
 FIND MORE STORIES ABOUT: 
 Anne Arundel Schmoke County Officials Community Landfill |   More 
 FEATURED ARTICLES NEWS 
 A recent article about Spencer Sand&amp;Gravel Inc.&apos;s... 
 July 16, 1995 A recent article about Spencer Sand&amp;Gravel Inc.&apos;s landfill in Abingdon misstated the number of chemical drums illegally dumped on the property in 1980 that were labeled &quot;trichloroethylene.&quot; Only one of the 75 drums was so labeled, according to a Harford County Health Department inspector&apos;s report.The Sun regrets the error. ARTICLES BY DATE NEWS 
 Judge awards whistle-blower $462,500 in high-seas pollution case 
 By Candus Thomson, The Baltimore Sun | April 18, 2012 A federal judge in Baltimore has awarded $462,500 to a low-level merchant marine officer who alerted Coast Guard inspectors that his cargo ship was intentionally polluting the high seas. In his ruling Monday, U.S. District Judge Marvin Garbis also left open the possibility of giving Salvador Lopez, a former ship&apos;s engineer from the Philippines, an additional $462,500 in reward money, depending on the outcome of another portion of the case. Lopez gave Coast Guard inspectors in Baltimore a handwritten note tipping them off to the illegal dumping of oily waste and garbage during the M/V Aquarosa&apos;s first visit to the port of Baltimore in February 2011. Advertisement NEWS 
 Mount Airy * Woodbine * Taylorsville * Winfield 
 April 7, 1993 Town seeks ban on illegal dumpingThe Mount Airy Town Council has proposed a $100 fine for people who illegally dump at the town&apos;s recycling bins and composting facility behind Prospect Park.&quot; NEWS 
 Good morning, Baltimore: Need to know for Tuesday 
 The Baltimore Sun | March 27, 2012 WEATHER Today&apos;s forecast calls for sunny skies and a high temperature near 55 degrees. It is expected to be partly cloudy tonight, with a low temperature around 43 degrees. TRAFFIC Check our traffic updates for this morning&apos;s issues as you plan your commute. FROM LAST NIGHT... Teare appears before council, declines to answer questions : Anne Arundel County Police Chief Col. James E. Teare Sr. appeared Monday night before the County Council but declined to answer questions under oath about allegations of misconduct by County Executive John R. Leopold, citing the ongoing criminal investigation. NEWS 
 Stop illegal dumping Change attitudes: Is littering a reflection of what residents think of their city? 
 September 5, 1996 BALTIMORE ISN&apos;T as clean as it should be. Especially beyond the tourist-attractive realm of the Inner Harbor and downtown that gets extra attention from privately paid sanitation crews. City workers have improved a number of areas with &quot;Clean Sweep&quot; days that target some of the filthier neighborhoods. But no matter how much sanitation workers do, it&apos;s clear that until people&apos;s attitudes change it won&apos;t be enough.Attitudes deserve a lot of the blame for the extremely high amount of illegal dumping that occurs in Baltimore. NEWS 
 Illegal dumping of tires costs Baltimore $500,000 to clean up, Curran reports Year-old crackdown results in 4 convictions 
 By Neal Thompson and Neal Thompson,SUN STAFF | November 11, 1997 While a year-old crackdown on illegal tire dumping has resulted in 18 arrests and four convictions in recent months, it is costing the city $500,000 a year to clean up and dispose of the 1,200 or so tons of tires that are illegally dumped in vacant lots across Baltimore, Maryland Attorney General J. Joseph Curran Jr. said yesterday.Standing before a mound of tires illegally dumped next to an abandoned warehouse on Druid Park Drive in West Baltimore, Curran said the state&apos;s Environmental Crimes Unit and the city&apos;s Department of Public Works have recently used surveillance cameras to catch illegal dumpers in the act.In addition to being marred by used tires, other wooded or isolated parts of the city have been turned into minilandfills of trash bags, discarded furniture and other dregs, Curran said. NEWS 
 Building debris arrest made 
 By Phillip McGowan | April 22, 2007 A 44-year-old Owings Mills man was arrested and charged last week in connection with the illegal dumping of more than 100 pounds of construction debris in Upton, officials said yesterday. Tommy Ray Whitehead was arrested Wednesday while at District Court on Patapsco Avenue for another illegal dumping case, city officials said. In the most recent case, police have accused Whitehead of dumping debris in a community garden in the 1200 block of Shields Place. The Sun reported last month that a huge pile of debris - including a brown house door, insulation resembling pink cotton candy and planks of wood and bricks - was left in a grassy alleyway on Shields Place that had been converted into a community garden. NEWS 
 Columbia man, 20, charged with dumping geese 
 By MELISSA HARRIS and MELISSA HARRIS,SUN REPORTER | March 17, 2006 A 20-year-old Columbia man has been charged with illegally dumping at least two dozen snow geese near a Columbia playground this month, a spokeswoman for Howard County police said yesterday. Edward Dillon of the 9600 block of Sea Shadow faces a misdemeanor dumping charge that carries a penalty of up to $1,000 or one year in jail, plus other littering charges. Dillon declined yesterday to comment. Police spokeswoman Sherry Llewellyn said that he told police that he received the geese from his boss, and that he had cut some of them up for food. NEWS 
 Schmoke environment plans set Many steps required by state, federal law 
 By Michael A. Fletcher and Michael A. Fletcher,Evening Sun Staff | December 18, 1990 Calling cleanup of the environment &quot;one of the great challenges of the 1990s,&quot; Mayor Kurt L. Schmoke has announced some initiatives that he hopes to implement during the next two years.The proposals unveiled yesterday are the work of an mayoral environmental council established by Schmoke a year ago. The group included city planners and officials from the Baltimore Health Department and the Department of Public Works.The proposals, many of which are required by state and federal law and would require the City Council to enact legislation, include:* Giving the city the power to mandate solid-waste recycling if on-going voluntary efforts fall short of state requirements. NEWS 
 Investigation into illegal dumping site leads to arrests 
 By Matt Whittaker and Matt Whittaker,SUN STAFF | August 7, 2004 Two brothers were charged yesterday with dumping more than 100 pounds of garbage on a vacant city-owned lot that had become an illegal dumping ground over the past eight to 10 months, city officials said. John Burns Williams, 47, of the 3200 block of Doycron Court in Baltimore County and Curtis Lee Williams, 49, of the 1000 block of 43rd St. in Baltimore were charged yesterday after an investigation by the city&apos;s environmental crimes unit. The unit responded about 9:30 a.m. Tuesday to a call about the site in the 100 block of N. Calverton Road. NEWS 
 City uses cameras to combat illegal dumping 
 By Scott Calvert, The Baltimore Sun | March 26, 2012 The man insisted he didn&apos;t illegally dump the toilet by the side of the road. No, he just left it there as a favor for &quot;Moe,&quot; a homeless guy who planned to put it to use in a vacant house somewhere. &quot;That was his story,&quot; said city housing official Thomas Waugh. At least, that was the man&apos;s story after one of the city housing department&apos;s surveillance cameras caught him ditching the commode along a Southwest Baltimore street. Waugh didn&apos;t believe the excuse for a second, and even if he had, dropping off a toilet would still qualify as littering. EXPLORE 
 Police Blotter 
 January 26, 2012 Harford County sheriff&apos;s deputies and Maryland State Police report: Aberdeen Latoya Sharie Epps, 26, who has addresses in the 500 block of Plaza Court and the 300 block of Mayberry Drive, was arrested on a bench warrant Tuesday in a case in which she was charged with possession of a drug other than marijuana. There was a possible break-in Tuesday in the 400 block of Aldino Stepney Road. A drug deal occurred in front of a house Wednesday in the 1500 block of Maple Avenue. NEWS 
 Shipowner, operator fined $1.85M in pollution case 
 By Candus Thomson, The Baltimore Sun | January 25, 2012 When Coast Guard inspectors boarded a new freighter docking in Baltimore last February, a junior-level engineer from the Philippines approached and slipped them a note. &quot;I have sometheng to till you but secret,&quot; he wrote, using all capital letters. The secret — that the ship had illegally dumped oily waste and garbage into the ocean — resulted in the owners and operators of the M/V Aquarosa being fined $1.85 million in federal court Wednesday and also ordered to pay $550,000 to a foundation to help restore the Chesapeake Bay. And the whistle-blower, a seaman who supports a wife and four children on $27,000 a year, stands to earn a six-figure reward for his efforts, including gathering copies of the ship&apos;s logs and snapping hundreds of pictures of illegal onboard activities with his cell phone. NEWS 
 War vets take on Oliver community 
 By Justin Fenton | December 8, 2011 The Sun&apos;s Luke Broadwater reports this morning on an initiative that has war veterans giving back in one of Baltimore&apos;s most troubled neighborhoods : &quot;Earl Johnson&apos;s boots crunch broken glass from liquor bottles as he walks down an alley in East Baltimore&apos;s Oliver neighborhood. He is just blocks from the site of the firebombing of a family who called the police on area drug dealers and were killed for it and just yards from some of the most memorable scenes of urban decay in &quot;The Wire. NEWS 
 A daring new mission for war vets: Taking on East Baltimore&apos;s Oliver neighborhood 
 By Luke Broadwater, The Baltimore Sun | December 8, 2011 Earl Johnson&apos;s boots crunch broken glass from liquor bottles as he walks down an alley in East Baltimore&apos;s Oliver neighborhood. He is just blocks from the site of the firebombing of a family who called the police on area drug dealers and were killed for it and just yards from some of the most memorable scenes of urban decay in &quot;The Wire. &quot; At his side are Rich Blake, 32, a Marine Corps veteran, and Jeremy Johnson, 34 , a Navy veteran, who like Earl — who is no relation — are on a different kind of mission. NEWS 
 Baltimore City Council wants say on school board members 
 By Justin Fenton, The Baltimore Sun | August 15, 2011 In its last meeting before the September primary election, the Baltimore City Council unanimously passed a resolution calling on state legislators to give the council input in the selection of school board members. Councilman Bill Henry, the resolution&apos;s lead sponsor, said Monday that the council has a say in executive appointments to most city commissions and boards, and it should be involved in the selection of school board members. City school board members are appointed jointly by the governor and mayor of Baltimore. NEWS 
 Illegal dumping becoming a problem SOUTH EAST -- Sykesville * Eldersburg * Gamber 
 By Mary Gail Hare and Mary Gail Hare,Staff Writer | February 12, 1993 Illegal dumping is overloading Sykesville&apos;s sanitation workers.Unidentified dumpers are leaving bulky surprises in the trash trucks and on the grounds of the maintenance shop near Town Hall.&quot; NEWS 
 Police investigating dead snow geese 
 By MELISSA HARRIS | March 12, 2006 Howard County police have opened an investigation into the illegal dumping of about two dozen dead snow geese at a Columbia playground this month, police spokeswoman Sherry Llewellyn said Friday. Maryland Department of Natural Resources police decided not to open a similar case last week after they found no evidence of illegal hunting. Snow geese have a liberal bag limit of 15 birds per hunter per day. Hunting season ended Feb. 25. Residents found the birds March 2 in Kings Contrivance village, and their deaths were first reported in the Columbia Flier. 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 | Next 1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 | Next Index by Keyword | Index by Date | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service Please note the green-lined linked article text has been applied commercially without any involvement from our newsroom editors, reporters or any other editorial staff.
	</body>
</document>
