<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002752" url="http://www.bizbuysell.com/convenience-stores-for-sale/5/" time="2012-07-12-18:49" support="6" score="0.007440199184063495" bingtitle="Convenience Stores For Sale - BizBuySell.com" webtitle="Convenience Stores For Sale - BizBuySell.com">
			<query id="000937" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="000928" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000934" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000919" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="000933" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000925" bing-rank="176"/>
	<description>Big Truck Stop with 3200 Sq foot Store with Hot fast food Restaurant. Located on major national ... REDUCED PRICE - VERY LOW - Have to leave country $ Seller ...</description>
	<body>
		Already a BizBuySell Member?

Log In to Continue
 


Invalid log in. Check your user name and password.
 Email Address (Member ID): Password: 
 Verifying... 
 
 Forgot Your Password? 

 Note : The email address you provided matches an existing account. Please log in using this email address and your original password. If you don&apos;t recall your password, click the &apos;Forgot Your Password?&apos; link.
 
 Are you new to BizBuySell? 
 
 
BizBuySell - The Internet&apos;s Largest Business for Sale&amp;Franchise for Sale Marketplace
 
 Welcome! Sign In Register For Brokers 

 My BizBuySell BrokerWorks 
 My Listings My Watch List My Saved Searches My BizAlerts My Ad Responses My Ad Inquiries My Valuation Reports My Community Questions My Community Answers My Profile 
 Sign Out For Brokers 
 
 
 
 

 Properly valuing small, family owned businesses and larger companies. Determining which businesses offer the greatest financial return. How to value a business and negotiate the price. And much more... 

 Enter email address: 
 Please note that you can opt out of the BizBuySell Bulletin at any time. 


 Convenience Stores For Sale 
 500+ Convenience Store Businesses for Sale Found. 

Looking to buy a Convenience Store business? There&apos;s a 7-Eleven, Mini Market or other Convenience Stores to meet your needs on BizBuySell. To ensure you are seeing all potential listings, click &quot;Business Categories&quot; in the search filters below to see other categories that may contain additional Convenience Store related businesses. 
 
 
 1 ... 4 5 ... 10 
 Save this Search 
Search Saved
 Get BizAlerts Start Search Over 
Refine Your Search

 Price Range to Gross Income Range to Cash Flow Range to Business Categories City or Keyword Business Location 
 State -Search ALL of US- Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware District of Columbia Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming U.S. Territories Africa Asia/Pacific Australia/New Zealand Canada Caribbean Mexico/Central America Europe South America Hold CTRL to mutli-select 

 County Select one state above Hold CTRL to mutli-select 
 Show Only Seller Financed Listings with Disclosed Prices Show Businesses Listed 
 Anytime Last 3 Days Last 7 Days Last 30 Days 
 Home Based 
 Include Home-based Exclude Home-based Only Home-based 
 Relocatable Include Relocatable Businesses Broker Membership Exclude from Search IBBA M&amp;A Source OBBA NYABB MABIA Broker Certification Exclude from Search CBI M&amp;AMI 
 
Select Business Categories
 
RETAILING BUSINESSES - Select All 

 Apparel and Accessory Stores Automotive Dealers Bars/Taverns Blding Mat., Hardware, Garden Convenience Stores Florists Gasoline Service Stations General Merchandise Stores Home Furniture&amp;Furnishings 

 Liquor Stores Marine Dealers&amp;Equipment Miscellaneous Retail Other Eating&amp;Drinking Places Other Food Stores Pet Shops&amp;Supplies Restaurants Supermarkets Vending Machines 
 
SERVICE BUSINESSES - Select All 

 Agents&amp;Brokers Amusement&amp;Recreation Auto Repair, Parts&amp;Services Beauty Salons, Barber Shops Computer&amp;Software Services Drycleaning/Laundry Services Educational Services Engineering&amp;Accounting Svcs Finance, Banking, Loans, etc. Freight, Moving/Delivery Health, Medical&amp;Dental Hotels&amp;Other Lodging Places Landscaping&amp;Yard Services Legal Services 

 Marine Repair, Parts&amp;Services Membership Organizations Miscellaneous Repair Services Miscellaneous Services Motion Pictures Museums, Art Galleries, Zoos Other Business Services Other Personal Services Other Travel&amp;Transportation Passenger Transportation Pet Care&amp;Grooming Social Services Storage&amp;Warehousing Travel Agencies 
 
INTERNET BUSINESSES - Select All 

 Business Services (B2B) Consumer Services (B2C) Domain Name/Basic Site General Internet 

 ISP/ASP Services Software Web Design/Tech Services 
 
MANUFACTURING BUSINESSES - Select All 

 Apparel&amp;finished fabrics Chemicals&amp;Allied Products Electronic&amp;Electrical Equip. Fabricated Metal Products Food and Kindred Products Furniture and Fixtures Industrial&amp;Comm. Machinery Leather and Leather Products Lumber and Wood Products Measuring&amp;Analyzing Instr. 

 Miscellaneous Paper&amp;Allied Products Petroleum Refining Primary Metal Industries Printing, Publishing Rubber and Plastic Products Stone, Clay, Glass, Concrete Textile Mill Products Tobacco Products Transportation Equipment 
 
WHOLESALE/DIST. BUSINESSES - Select All 

 Durable Goods Nondurable Goods 
 
CONSTRUCTION BUSINESSES - Select All 

 Building Heavy Special Trades 
 
BUSINESS REAL ESTATE - Select All 

 For Lease For Sale 
 
 - Select All 

 Agriculture Communications Electric, Gas, Water, Sanitary Svcs Mining Non-classifiable Establishments 
 Cancel close 
Name Your Search
 Name: 
 cancel 
 close 
Your search has been saved
 
At any time, you may access all of your saved searches by going to My Saved Searches .

 
 
   Established Businesses for Sale Asking Price Cash Flow Location Deli, Pizza, Bakery and Convenience- Lot o... $369,000 $160,000 Hunterdon... Deli, Pizza, Bakery and Convenience Store With Tons of Potential  

 This is a deli with pizza, bakery and a convenience store. It has seating area inside and outside of the store. It s in a free standing building at the light and in a very nice neighborhood and has no competition at all. This will be a good business for an owner operator. It has lot of potential to increase deli, pizza, bakery and convenience store business. If some... Net $200K/Store/Property $590,000 $200,000 Charlottesvi... Excellent Profit Way   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Well established country store with gas and real estate for sale. Gross revenue $1.8M. The store has a lot of attractive features for a purchaser: Property is four roads way, excellent corner lot with no competition. Short operation hour: 6 days open and closes 7:00pm in the afternoon. All gasoline equipments&amp;underground tanks 2006 brand new installed. No fuel supply... Gasoline Service Station Convenience Store... $125,000 $270,340 Kent... Gasoline Service Station Convenience Store - 20573  

 Gas Station and Convenience Store with Deli sells lottery, phone cards, money orders, cigarettes and includes ATM and large walk-in cooler!! This free standing building is located on busy corner property with no lease restrictions. Owner sells 30,000 gallons of gas per month and 5 cents profit per gallon.All offers will be considered! Unbranded Gas/C-Store, NOVA, 16 islands, 3... $400,000 Prince... Unbranded, Gas/C-Store, High Volume, Major Intersection   $ Seller Financing Available 

 This very attractive unbranded gas station is located at the intersection of 2 major roads, right off the highway. Area has a high traffic count due to the highly traveled 95 South and the density of residential and commercial pockets. This high volume station pumps on average about 375,000 gallons per month. There are sixteen (16) islands with pumps on each side... High Volume Branded Gas Station - 21747 $375,000 $142,279 New Haven... High Volume Branded Gas Station - 21747  

 High volume branded gas station selling approx 100000 gallons per month on busy main road with passing traffic of approximately 45,000 cars per day. Well patronised with high inside sales. Has lottery, ATM and vacuum revenue. All credit card fees paid by the gas distributor. Attractive store with approx $2200 per day inside sales , well maintained and stocked. Very little...   Convenience Stores $200,000 - $300,000 Charleston, SC Run a BizBuySell Valuation Report to view details of this business and 1,000+ other recently for sale and sold Convenience Stores .


   7 - Corporate Run Shell Branded Stations i... $400,000 Atlanta, GA 7 Great C-Stores in Atlanta for sale   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Corporate Run Gas Stations in Metro Atlanta for sale. This is a great opportunity for any owner operator who wants to take advantage of a lease purchase option on the property. Inside Sales = 75 K /Month. Outside Gallons = 140 K Gallons/ Month Lottery Commission = $2500 / Month Rent = $8000 / Month Goodwill = $400,000.00 15 year long term NNN lease and the purchaser... Sunoco Gas Station New Port Richey!! $139,900 $137,040 New Port... New Reduced price!!   $ Seller Financing Available 

 This convenience store averages $73,000 per month in inside grocery sales. The gas station pumps an average of 65,000 gallons per month on a commission basis. You earn 5 cents commission on a cash sale and 9 cents commission on a credit card gas sale. Even if the gas company is losing money on selling gas you still get your guaranteed commission no matter what. The gas... Convenience store Denver, CO... Profitable Business For Sale  

 There are three convenience stores in three different locations for sale. Sellers are switching to different businesses and are interested to sell their businesses. Please call UPB, Amir phone 303-359-7576 for more details. Long term lease agreements with reasonable rents are available Discount Tobacco and Beer Outlet $99,900 $42,500 Maryville,... Great Investment for an Owner/Operator!  

 This discount tobacco and beer outlet has a three year sale history. Fixtures that remain with the sale are a seven front walk-in cooler, four double door display cases, various shelving, two cash registers, alarm system, office desk, laser printer/fax, and a Proview 4 channel monitoring system. Newer drive-thru window installed in 2011...making the convenience greater... Coin Laundry Lease for Sale, $92,374.00 Ne... $75,000 $92,374 Tifton, GA... Coin Laundry Lease for Sale, $92,374.00 Net Profit  

 1200 square ft Coin Laundry located in the common parking lot with Dollar Tree, Sav-a-Lot, Big Lot, King Chinese Buffet and Tractor Supply, The washing machines, dryers and steam irons are owned by the Seller. The laundry s other profit centers include Ironing, Phone Card Sales, Check Cashing and Georgia Lottery. Click on &apos;&apos;CONTACT THE SELLER}} to receive photos and ...   High Volume Gas station and C-store in Alp... $400,000 Alpharetta,... Atlanta C store For Lease  

 3200 sq High-Volume C store, 65K Inside, 130k outside, 2k lottery. Huge Potential for improvement. C-store including fuel, lottery, beer&amp;ci... $1,400,000 SC Profitable Convenience store&amp;Gas Station, Turn key ready!  

 This exceptional South Carolina based convenience store was built in 2004 and offers a new owner an incredible location on high traffic streets next to schools and a college. There is all new equipment and has a nice big porch out front to keep the sun out and was built with a country look in mind. This business for sale takes pride in their work and it shows ... Convenience Store w/Gas for Sale or Lease.... $80,000 Lenox, GA... C-Store With Gas, Owner Financing available  

 2000 square ft former Holiday Market Convenience Store with gas located on .34 acres. The gasoline is not under contract from any supplier, there are no environmental issues. Tanks and pumps are owned by the store. Inside merchandise sales are $42,000 per month, gasoline profit averages $4,645 per month. for more information and additional photos, click ( CONTACT SELLER )... On-Site Fuel Services Niche Market With Mi... $750,000 $350,000 Denver... On-Site Fuel Services Niche Market With Mini Truck Stop   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Due to owners retirement this profitable company is available for a new owner manager or as an add-on to firms already in the on-site fuel delivery, wholesale fuel distribution industry, petroleum bulk station. The company serves the construction industry, emergency power needs of facilities like Denver International Airport, hospitals and high rise complexes, as ... Gasoline Service Station&amp;C-Store - 21731 $1,100,000 $406,770 New London... Gasoline Service Station&amp;C-Store - 21731   $ Seller Financing Available 

 This un-branded gas station, with an excessively large: 10,000 sq.ft. convenience store, is located in a highly polished neighborhood in Connecticut. The store carries lotto, beer, cigarettes, vegetables&amp;fruits, bakery: bagels, cakes, pastries, muffins, croissants, etc. ( all items are baked on the premises), breakfast and lunch. The store earns $8,000 in gross sale a...   180K gallons and 75K in store sales in Sal... $1,295,000 Salem, OR... 180K gallons and 75K in store sales in Salem, OR  

 Store is doing over 180K gallons and inside sales of 75K with good margins. Entire site was completely remodeled two years ago when converted from CHEVRON. Volume has doubled in two years with ARCO&apos;s pricing policies. A great brand to compete all big box stores like COSTCO/ FRED MEYERS. SAFEWAY etc. Did I mention NO CREDIT CARD FEES . Sellers will consider financing right... C-Store With Gas, $493,518.00 Gross Profit... $1,275,000 Cordele, GA... Super Pumper C-Store Property&amp;Business for Sale  

 2370 square ft Pacecar Convenience Store w/gas operated by employees located on .66 acres at I-75, exit 101 in Cordele Georgia. This is the closest station to the exit; other businesses on this exit include McDonalds, Krystal, Pizza Hut, Taco Bell and Waffle King. The building also contains a drive through car wash, the gasoline is under contract to Pacecar but can... Business for sale in Northwest Indiana $70,000 Crown... Best top ten lottery seller in Indiana  

 The Hen is located on main street in town about 2500 sq feet big. This store is about 38 yrs old and rent is only $1835. Store is doing business of $ 350 K yearly and excellent lottery comm. is $ 53 k plus $ 15 K bonus yearly. Norwalk Full Service Major Brand Station W... $375,000 $132,000 Norwalk, CA... NORWALK 76 WITH GREAT MASTER LEASE AT LOW, LOW PRICE..  

 NORWALK FULL SERVICE MAJOR BRAND STATION WITH A SMALL MART NETTING $11,000+/Mo. After All Expenses. Pumping 65,000+ Gals/Mo. @ 22 Cts/Gal.. Profit. Mart Sales are $15,000+/-/Mo. and Back Room Labor&amp;Parts are $12,000+/Mo. Additional Income of $3,000+/-/Mo. from Propane&amp;Propel Sales. REDUCED TO $350,000 + Invent. INCLUDES L/TERM TRIPLE NET MSTR/LSE. Established Coin Laundry and Convenience s... $199,000 Denver, CO... Established Coin Laundry and Convenience store for sale Denver, C  

 This business is family owned and operated. The coin operated Laundromat has been in business for more than 15 years and the current owner added Convenience store which has been running for more than 6 years. The Convenience store sales: grocery, soda, laundry detergents, Lottery/Scratch tickets, phone cards and other things like a dollar store items. Over 3,000 square... Rent:$1750..Ask:$60k+inv.Great cash flow.E... $60,000 $60,000 Hiawasee,... LOW rent....   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Sales:$40-50k/month.Gas 30,000 gals,Lotto comm $2300/month.Great cashflow.Low rent, low investment.Must see.Call 678 637 5089.Husain A Charaniya,Great Atlanta realty C-Store in highly populated area, fantasti... $165,000 $210,000 Charleston... C-Store in highly populated area,fantastic opportunity for family  

 Here is an incredible opportunity for you to own a 2800 Sq.ft C-Store! Averages montly sale of $44000- $50,000 a month with a 35% markup and is still booming! Income from lotto is $1300.00 Located in a densely populated area. Standalone building with ample parking. Store has lotto and ATM on site. Situated just one block from the highway! Previously this store was a... 3 C-Stores and Truck Stop on Interstate Co... $937,000 WY 3 c-stores and a truck stop on major interstate corridor   $ Seller Financing Available 

 The Company comprises three convenience stores and one truck stop. Two C-stores have liquor licenses and the truck stop operates a restaurant. Three stores are branded with a major fuel brand, and the fourth store is branded with a different major fuel brand. Highlights include: * Prime retail locations * Located on Interstate highway; major national transport... Gas station/c store for Lease $115,000 Woodstock,... Oppurtunity store   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Well establised gas station for lease . Current sale for the month of june inside sale was 49,000 a month gas 33,000gallons a month .lottery32,000 a month. business constatly growin. Nice gas station for lease doing 90,000 in... $185,000 $85,000 Sullivan,... nice gas station for sale / lease  

 This is a nice store doing great volume of 90k inside and 70k gals outside. Inside mark up is minimum 25% and outside average is about 8 cents after credit card fees. over all it makes about 28-30 k per month in gross profit and with maximum expenses of 20k per month your net be standing between 7-10k per month. it is a very good deal. the rent is $6500 per month NNN... Convenience Store - Vermont , turnkey busi... $475,000 $79,000 Sharon, VT... Great business for sale   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Located in Sharon VT just off Exit 2 of I89 and alongside the White River. An ideal location and business for the outdoorsman, enjoying and supplying customers with fishing and hunting supplies and licenses, along with all the Cstore offerings, including gas/diesel/kero and propane. Open 365 days, the business caters to locals and sportsmen, with 90% of customers being... Gas Station - 20672 $250,000 $170,328 Kings... Profitable main street business Gas Station - 20672  

 This nationally-known branded gas station is located on one of the busiest roads, in Brooklyn. The adjoining road leads to a major highway, so the location stays busy, and vibrant. It pumps between 120,000 to 130,000 gallons a month. There are two different prices at the pumps, cash price and credit price, a difference of 10cents, between credit and cash. It has a huge... Branded Gas Station with Beer License for ... $19,999 Frederick,... Recently renovated, lots of room for growth  

 Gas Station is located on a very busy commuter route in Frederick County, MD.Hour of operation are 6:00 to 8:00 pm.This is great station for someone without prior experience who wants to buy a gas station. C-store Grosses $120K + annually with room for significant growth with expanded hours and addition of new products and services Pumps average 20k-25k gals per month... Gas Station and Convenience Store for Sale $91,000 $60,000 Clinton, TN... Grand Old Gas Station/c-store, Great Location..  

 Grand Old and successful Gas Station/c-store, great location on Clinton Highway, $45 to 50K inside, $3500 lottery com. with loyal clientele. Owner moving out of state and motivated to sell immediately. Please do not talk to employees. Call Ramesh on 865-253-3488. Citgo Gas Station and Convenience Store an... $399,000 San... Owner financing available. Business + property!   $ Seller Financing Available 

 This is an incredible opportunity for an owner occupied business owner. Citgo gas station with convenience store located on a signalized hard corner on HWY 123 in Seguin, TX. Property is situated on 1/2 acre with a 2400 SF building. There are 2 MPD&apos;s on the property, so 4 vehicles can pump fuel at the same time. Current owner has spend over $60k upgrading the inside... Liquor store for sale in walworth county $500,000 $80,000 East Troy,... Busy liquor store with income property for sale in downtown   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Average monthly sales around 45k lotto sales 1k. little to no competition. business has been here for over 30 years. just around corner from alpine valley. also have 3 bedroom apt which bring in around $9000 rent every year. full basement for storage. store is located in middle of downtown. real estate is also for sale in interested buyer. owner financing is avalible to... Small Neighborhood Convenience Stores for ... $129,000 $140,000 Quincy, FL... Small store for sale in north florida  

 STORE HOURS M TO S 8.30 AM TO 8.30 PM S 9.30 AM TO 8.30 PM. This convenience store averages $43,000 per month in inside grocery sales35% @$15050 lotto/lottery 55000 @coim ., $ 3250 phone card coim., $ 450 k 1 per $250 check cash fee $1000 total income $20000 rent $1609.50 uitlity $1050.00 salary $4800.00 phone/ internet $150.00 ins $250.00 totalexp... High volume gas station - $100,000 inside ... $1,325,000 Fountain... High volume gas station - $100,000 inside and 100000 gals  

 This is a nice gas station dry doing over 100k inside and 100k gals outside with 30% inside mark up. for more details please email. YOU CAN VISIT MY OTHER LISTINGS AT http://broker.bizbuysell.com/nmovania We specialize in finding gas stations for clients. We have many gas stations for sale or lease. If you are looking for a gas station, we have it and if we... Indian grocery store $70,000 Franklin,... INDIAN GROCERY IN AFFLUENT AREA  

 Store is established since 4 years, catering to indian, ethnic, pakistani, asian communitiies selling $360,000 grocery a year. add lottery, food, check cashing, money orders, money gram to increase business. must sell quickly as seller has no family help and woul;d like to retire. Bagel&amp;Deli - 21564 $249,000 $93,610 Queens... Profitable main street Bagel&amp;Deli - 21564   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Absentee run Bagel/Deli in Jackson Heights, NY. This store was renovated 2 years ago. Nice clean and steady store. Open only 6am-4pm. Generates over 12,000 per week in sales, real money maker! Contact broker Joe DiBello 631-265-7300 Country General Store for Sale in Orange C... $180,000 $75,000 Trabuco... Landmark country store for sale in orange county  

 General Store for Sale in beautiful Trabuco Canyon. Across from O&apos;Neill Campground Park. Located near Coto De Caza, Rancho Santa Margarita, Dove Canyon. Sell Beer/Wine, Lotto, Fill Propane Tanks, Groceries and Snacks and Horse Products and Feed. Good location to add deli. Established 1950. remodeled in 2001. Hiking Holy Jim Canyon nearby, we sell Adventure Passes. High Volume Branded Gas&amp;C-Store - 21514 $700,000 $200,560 Nassau... High Volume Branded Gas&amp;C-Store - 21514  

 High Volume Branded Gas&amp;C-Store. One of the best locations in Nassau County. This station is in between two major intersections just minutes off the Long Island Expressway. There is non-stop traffic generating an average of 175,000 gallons per month with an average Net Profit of .15 -.17c/gallon. The station has two canopies with 14 fueling stations. There is also a... Arco Gas, Food, Land, Seller Finance $1,550,000 Seattle... Arco gas station business with land.  

 Seattle metro area remodelled, retrofitted, pci compiant arco gas station in popular neighborhood, corner location, near freeway. for more information please contact: bill kang at 206-355-1080 or RealtyA@gmail.com Topline Market Convenience Store-NEW PRICE $69,000 Tukwila, WA... Topline Market Convenience Store-NEW PRICE  

 This a brand new convenience store in a brand new commercial building. Open only since January 2012 and already exceeding $400.00 per day in sales plus Lottery. Owner has been transferred out of state and must sell. New owner could bring in a full deli and other products. Located close by several larger businesses in a primarily residential area. A new apartment complex... Gas Station&amp;C-Store with $79k Lotto $325,000 $150,000 West... Busy Location, Great Neighborhood Store  

 Outstanding gas station, convenience store located on main road (route 20) in West Springfield, MA (Hampden County). $79k annual lottery commission, ATM machine, 34k gallons sold per month. Great c-store sales. Local General Store atmosphere with related services. Cash Cow Gas Station - 20714 $999,900 $411,420 Morris... Cash Cow Gas Station - 20714  

 Cash cow gas station on a main highway for sale. One of a kind deli including convenience store items. Up scale neighborhood. Competitive gas prices (enough room to increase revenues). Deli (Boars Head meat brand) offering sandwiches, gourmet coffees, cigarettes, lotto, and your usual convenient store items. Revenues continue to grow! #&apos;s will be documented. Semi absentee... Busy C-Store $159,950 Stayton, OR... Sales are up, price reduced, motivated seller!   $ Seller Financing Available 

 A nice family business. Clean and attractive space, well laid out, inviting to customers. Situated on a highly travelled main thoroughfare with easy ingress and egress for auto traffic and plenty of parking. Convenience Store - in Modern Office Build... $95,000 $48,000 Bronx,... Convenience Store in Modern Office Building - Bronx, N.Y.  

 Small convenience store in modern office building. Opened in 2004, renovated in 2010. Lottery and Dry Goods - no cigarettes or beer. Lottery covers rent plus. 5 Days - Short Hours - Controlled Environment. Presently operated absentee. Potential for growth. PRICE REDUCED! Opportunity to own very Pro... $229,000 Flint, MI... PRICE REDUCED! - High Profit Margin Store available   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Grab the opportunity you had been waiting for. Check out the existing convenience store + general merchandise store in Flint area. High Profit margin store located on very busy streets (main on main). Excellent Demographics and Very Good Vehicular traffic. Owner wants to sell this store so he could focus his energy @ Detroit store. Owner has excellent records of... Convenience Store/Car Wash/Garden&amp;Gift; $599,000 Northwood,... Convenience Store / Car Wash / Garden&amp;Gift  

 Moderate sized convenience store offering gas&amp;diesel sales. In store or carry out noon lunch specials with inside seating for over 30 and outdoor courtyard seating also. Excellent handmade deli sandwiches&amp;fried chicken. Car&amp;Truck wash and Garden&amp;Gift businesses included. Continual upgrades to facilities. Adjoining property available. Additional pics available... Specialty Market with Beer, Wine Sales and... $385,000 Athens, OH... Convenience Store with Beer, Wine Sales and Deli  

 Established specialty market in prime Athens, Ohio location. Locally owned, well merchandised, immaculately clean. Exceptional beer, wine, grocery, gourmet food and catering sales. 19 x 26 commercial kitchen and deli included. Excellent year over year growth with double digit comp. sales. Three year compound growth = 67%. All licenses/permits go with business. Close to... Established, turn key&amp;pride of ownership $299,990 Gardnerville... Pride of Ownership-Clean-Positive Cash Flow-Well Stocked-Turn Key   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Sierra Market is being sold as a turn key opportunity. Set up with pride of ownership in mind, the owners have set up a first class store creating a high volume, very well respected and clean store. Busy store with beer/wine/lotto/food in Ox... $250,000 Oxnard, CA... Busy convenience store with beer/winwe in Oxnard   $ Seller Financing Available 

 Business is located on a busy and growing area in the heart of Oxnard. Great business opportunity that is Profitable. SELLS beer, wine, beverages, food, as well as Lotto and ETC. Established customer base. Owner is busy in many other businesses. A lot of potential and very good opportunity for the new buyer. Convenience store specializing in beer, wi... $490,000 $140,000 Vermilion,... High gross, high profit, more than a convenience store.  

 Yearly gross income does not include $500,000 in lottery, $14,400 in rental income and $4-5,000 in ATM revenue. 2800 square foot convenience store and deli. Hugely successful and still growing fast! Excellent location on busy corner with no nearby competitors. Established for over 150 years. Plentiful parking. $110,000 in salable inventory. All fixtures and equipment... Neighborhood Grocery Store for Sale at Red... $1,100,000 $160,000 Sunbury, NC... Great Opportunity to Own Neighborhood Grocery Store  

 Sale of profitable grocery store operation. Includes land, building, equipment, goodwill, inventory, gasoline tanks, pumps and canopy. Owners want to retire and are willing to sacrifice on price. Great opportunity for owner/manager. Non-union.   
 Related Franchises View all Franchise Opportunities that match your search criteria. 
 $50,000 Capital Required 

 Allstate Insurance Agency 

 No company out there offers a faster-to-market opportunity for success like Allstate. Join one of the most recognized brands in America and become an Allstate Agency Owner. 
 
 $98,900 Capital Required 

 Kona Ice 

 EXPLOSIVE 400% GROWTH, AMAZING MARGINS, AND UNBEATABLE SUPPORT all make KONA ICE a NO BRAINER! STILL AVAILABLE IN EVERY MAJOR MARKET! 
 
 $289,900 - $386,500 Capital Required 

 Jimmy John&apos;s Gourmet Sandwich 

 Gourmet sandwich shops franchise specializing in fresh french bread subs and 7 grain wheat bread subs. 
 
 
 List your Business for Sale on BizBuySell 
 Page: 1 2 3 4 5 ... 10 
 
Browse Popular Retail Businesses
 
 Apparel Stores Auto Dealerships Bars&amp;Taverns Convenience Stores Flower Shops Food Companies 

 Furniture&amp;Home Decorating Gas Stations General Merchandise Stores Liquor Stores Marine Dealers and Services 

 Pet Shops for Sale Restaurants Retail Businesses Supermarkets Vending Machines 
 
Browse Popular Service Businesses
 
 Auto Parts Businesses Auto Repair Businesses Banks&amp;Mortgage Lenders Beauty Salons Brokerage Firms Business Services Computer&amp;Software Services Day Care Centers 

 Dry Cleaners Education Companies Entertainment and Recreation Financial Companies Health Care Companies Hotels and Motels Landscaping&amp;Gardening 

 Laundromats Medical&amp;Dental Businesses Passenger Transportation Companies Personal Services Pre-Schools Storage&amp;Warehousing Travel&amp;Transportation 
 
Browse Popular Franchises
 
 Automotive Business Opportunities Business Services Child Related Cleaning And Maintenance 

 Computer And Internet Food And Restaurant Health, Beauty, and Fitness High Capital Franchises Home Based Businesses 

 Home Services Low Cost Franchises Retail Franchises Sports And Recreation Travel And Lodging 
 
 About BizBuySell 

BizBuySell is the leading online marketplace for both finding and selling businesses available for sale. Due to our industry leading traffic, more business sellers choose BizBuySell as their marketplace of choice. That means if you are looking for new Convenience Store business opportunities, you can find the best selection of what&apos;s available right here, including C Store, Mini Market, 7-Eleven and other great Convenience Store businesses.

If you don&apos;t find what you are looking for, don&apos;t fret. Consider setting an email alert and we&apos;ll notify you each time a business matching your criteria becomes available, or better yet, try contacting a business broker with experience in the Convenience Store industry. 
Search for Convenience Store Businesses For Sale

Browse by State

 Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware District of Columbia Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming 
   x 
Be First to Know with BizAlerts
 

Get free alerts via email when new businesses are listed matching your Convenience Stores search criteria.

BizAlert Email Frequency
 Daily Alerts Summary Emails 
 Weekly Alerts 
 Realtime Alerts Individual Emails 
Save This Search
 Save Search to MyBizBuySell 
 Submit cancel 
 OK 
 Retry 
Name Your Search
 
 Name: 
 OK cancel 
 
 
 
 
 advertise terms&amp;conditions privacy policy about us contact us careers site map mobile 
 
 
 
©1996 - 2012 BizBuySell.com®   |
	</body>
</document>
