<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002337" url="http://okinawahai.com/restaurants" time="2012-07-12-18:15" support="8" score="0.033432001524270075" bingtitle="okinawa hai! | Category Archive | Restaurants" webtitle="Okinawa Hai! | Category Archive | Restaurants">
			<query id="000283" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000735" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="000673" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="001116" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="000310" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000296" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="000290" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="000363" bing-rank="228"/>
	<description>This has become our “go-to” restaurant when we want great food at good prices. The atmosphere is based off of the classics from the 50’s and 60’s, complete with [...]</description>
	<body>
		Home About FAQ Submissions Contact Us Comment Policy Hai Society 
 
 Okinawa Hai! 
 Love Living Here 
 To Eat Index School Index I’m the Map Okinawan Holidays Island Newbies 2012 Calendar 
 
 To Live 
 Cars Healthcare Making Your Home Military Life Off-Base Housing On-Base Housing Off-Island Travel PCS-ing Pets Phone&amp;Internet Spiritual Life Where To Worship Index Weather 
 To Work 
 Running a Business Work Off Base Work On Base Volunteer Opportunities 
 To Shop 
 Arts&amp;Crafts Books, Film, Music Clothing Size Charts Food For Sale Gifts&amp;Souvenirs Health&amp;Beauty For the Home Kids&amp;Maternity Men–clothes On-Base Online Women–clothes 
 To Eat 
 Cooking Local Dietary Issues Nani kore? (What’s that?!) Restaurants To Eat: by Cuisine To Eat: by Location Vegetarian 
 To Do 
 Bars&amp;Nightlife Beaches&amp;Pools Castles, Shrines&amp;Temples Date Night Daytripping Exercise&amp;Sports Hikes Indoor Activities Maps Off-Island Travel Okinawan Festivals&amp;Holidays Oki Holiday Calendar Okinawa Getaways Outdoor Activities Parks&amp;Playgrounds Photography Programs&amp;Classes US Festivals&amp;Holidays World Heritage Sites 
 To Learn 
 Japanese Language Just in Japan On Becoming Me Only On Okinawa 
 To Parent 
 Childcare&amp;Schools Kids Activities: Indoors Kids Activities: Outdoors Kids’Parties Parenting Wisdom Parks&amp;Playgrounds Pregnancy&amp;Childbirth Programs&amp;Classes 
 
 
 Archive | Restaurants
 RSS feed for this section 
 

 Cat Cafe (Neco Cafe) 

Posted on 10 July 2012. 
 
CONTRIBUTED BY ASHLEY CONNOLLY Cat Cafe 1 Cat Cafe First of all, I love cats. I have even been referred to as a crazy cat lady. So when I heard there was a café where cats just hung out with you I was amazed and had to go. If you love cats, too, then this [...]

 

 Read the full story 
 
Posted in Pets , Restaurants 2 Comments 
 
 

 Sea Garden Restaurant 

Posted on 04 July 2012. 
 
CONTRIBUTED BY LEEANN STEVENS Sea Garden View My husband and I found the perfect restaurant for our date nights. Sea Garden is right by the sea, perfect ambience and delicious food! The restaurant has indoor and outdoor seating. We preferred to sit outdoors. As the sun sets, you can see American village light up. If [...]

 

 Read the full story 
 
Posted in Date Night , Restaurants 5 Comments 
 
 

 Ramen Motonari 

Posted on 28 June 2012. 
 
CONTRIBUTED BY SARAH FORTE Here is a fun Okinawan game! Match the noodle names to the descriptions below. (The answers are at the end of the article.) A. Ramen ラーメン B. Tsukemen つけ麺 C. Soba そば D. Udon うどん 1. This kind of noodle literally means “dipping noodles.” Noodles are served with dipping soup and [...]

 

 Read the full story 
 
Posted in Restaurants 1 Comment 
 
 

 Kafuu Resort Fuchaku Condo Hotel 

Posted on 27 June 2012. 
 
CONTRIBUTED BY LISA WILLIAMS Are you looking for a resort to enjoy away from the well-beaten path? One that combines luxury, beauty and available activities for your various wants and needs? Last question: What are your feelings about gourmet food and sunsets over the aqua blue coastline of Okinawa?…I thought so! Ready for more? [...]

 

 Read the full story 
 
Posted in Okinawa Getaways , Restaurants 1 Comment 
 
 

 JiroCho Sushi 

Posted on 24 June 2012. 
 
CONTRIBUTED BY CHRIS DONG Growing up in California, I had the good fortune of going on deep sea fishing trips with my father and grandfather. Early morning drives to the port were filled with contemplative silence, father and grandfather secretly hoping to win the day’s bragging rights for most fish caught. Me, I had sushi [...]

 

 Read the full story 
 
Posted in Restaurants 2 Comments 
 
 

 CJ’s Sunset Grill 

Posted on 18 June 2012. 
 
CONTRIBUTED BY MARIE INDYK CJs Exterior When we first arrived to the island a few weeks ago, jetlagged and still scoping out our new surroundings, the familiar was a comfort. This was what we found and more at CJ’s Sunset Grill at Torii Station. CJ’s food is American style–burgers, hotdogs, pulled pork sandwiches, [...]

 

 Read the full story 
 
Posted in Restaurants 1 Comment 
 
 

 Striker’s Cafe 

Posted on 16 June 2012. 
 
CONTRIBUTED BY AMY MADDOCKS Strikers Interior Striker’s Café is a little known secret hiding inside Emery Lanes Bowling Alley on Kadena Air Base. At most bowling alleys you find the usual fast-food joints, but here, you get great food, great prices, and an entertaining atmosphere. Their menu offers burgers, sandwiches, pizza, hot dogs, soups and [...]

 

 Read the full story 
 
Posted in Restaurants 1 Comment 
 
 

 Seaside Restaurant 

Posted on 14 June 2012. 
 
CONTRIBUTED BY MELISSA RUISZ NAZARIO Seaside Sign 1 Monday and Tuesday closed. Monday and Tuesday closed. If I repeat this mantra over and over, perhaps the next time my appetite craves a meal from Seaside Ristorante, my brain will remember to check what day of the week it is BEFORE I show up to an [...]

 

 Read the full story 
 
Posted in Restaurants 6 Comments 
 
 

 Ashibiuna 

Posted on 08 June 2012. 
 
CONTRIBUTED BY KATHRYNANNE WRIGHT Ashi Entrance Deep in the green and concrete jungle of Okinawa, a small restaurant lies in it’s vast and busy city of Naha. Between a castle and it’s surrounding modern businesses, Ashibiuna Restaurant settles modestly between them, nestled in a rich garden of sand and flowers. Ashi Walkway During a rough [...]

 

 Read the full story 
 
Posted in Restaurants 0 Comments 
 
 

 Mahou Coffee 

Posted on 31 May 2012. 
 
Mahou Sign CONTRIBUTED BY CHRISTOPHER DONG Lazy. That’s what she called me… I mean, sure, I was in no position to argue the facts, lying face down, wrapped comfortably in the covers crepe-style (burrito took a bit too much effort at the time). Lazy though? Too strong, even as a passing joke. Energy-less, maybe, or [...]

 

 Read the full story 
 
Posted in Food For Sale , Restaurants 0 Comments 
 Older Entries» 
 Women and Couples Massage 
Relieves stress. Improves health. Fantastic massages. Great prices. Secret Garden Aromatherapy Salon. ADOPT while in Okinawa 
Adopt Abroad Inc., International&amp;Foster Adoptions, Homestudies. www.adopt-abroad.com US-1-888-687-3644 Advertise on Oki Hai 
Click here for information on placing your business ad on our site! 
 Comments Popular Latest 
 
 How Do I Get My Dog or Cat or Ferret or Parakeet to Okinawa?  ( 154 ) 
 Sherri : Can someone help me, I am confused at the moment. We have a rottweiler (125lbs) that we... 
 Awase Fish Market  ( 25 ) 
 David : I am thinking of moving into oceans seven that is right next to the fish market. Has... 
 Okinawa Montessori School  ( 56 ) 
 Happy Mom : MomOf SmartKids, I am a mom who has a child at the Golden Mind Achievers…as far... Liza : MomOf SmartKids I 
 Plugged in: TV, Phone and Internet  ( 51 ) 
 heather : If you live on base you can use hulu plus. Just contact them and let them know you are... 
 Baby 123 Island Style Daycare  ( 31 ) 
 Gerald : Both of my boys attend Baby 123, and have since September of 2011. The staff here is... 
 

 Should It Have Stayed or Should It Have Come? April 4, 2007 How Do I Get My Dog or Cat or Ferret or Parakeet to Okinawa? September 23, 2007 101 tips on Your Okinawa PCS with Pets! September 15, 2008 Off-Base Hair Salons May 19, 2008 What Is On-Base Housing In Okinawa Like? August 3, 2007 E-6 On-Base, E-6 Off-Base, How Do You Live? August 13, 2007 Been Pregnant or Given Birth In Okinawa? Part 1 June 30, 2007 DIY JCI (Or“The Dreaded JCI”) July 14, 2008 

 Sassy Glow July 10, 2012 Cat Cafe (Neco Cafe) July 10, 2012 Newlywed PCS, Part 10: Bumps in the Road July 8, 2012 Mt Hedo&amp;Asumui July 7, 2012 Out of the Archives: Tanabata–The Star Festival July 7, 2012 Sea Garden Restaurant July 4, 2012 Tomb of Sho Hashi July 3, 2012 Our Olympic Move, Part 2: Training July 3, 2012 
 
Local Blogs
 Local Blogs a new life in okinawa life in okinawa bags packed baking in faith black in japan click it up a notch eating okinawa enjoying life with 4 kids eric and ashley in japan genki gaijin girl goldie&apos;s garden john burgreen the loud americans me and my man in japan our gypsy camp people. love. life. scuba kim dive blog such is the life of an army wife turning japanese wandering quail road wandering weavers Get Added to our Blogroll 
Archives
 Select Month July 2012 (9) June 2012 (22) May 2012 (26) April 2012 (19) March 2012 (26) February 2012 (16) January 2012 (20) December 2011 (21) November 2011 (20) October 2011 (19) September 2011 (19) August 2011 (21) July 2011 (21) June 2011 (19) May 2011 (22) April 2011 (22) March 2011 (21) February 2011 (16) January 2011 (16) December 2010 (9) November 2010 (11) October 2010 (11) September 2010 (13) August 2010 (14) July 2010 (16) June 2010 (13) May 2010 (11) April 2010 (10) March 2010 (18) February 2010 (21) January 2010 (20) December 2009 (25) November 2009 (26) October 2009 (28) September 2009 (26) August 2009 (27) July 2009 (29) June 2009 (28) May 2009 (24) April 2009 (27) March 2009 (26) February 2009 (26) January 2009 (28) December 2008 (31) November 2008 (28) October 2008 (31) September 2008 (29) August 2008 (31) July 2008 (28) June 2008 (33) May 2008 (34) April 2008 (31) March 2008 (29) February 2008 (21) January 2008 (30) December 2007 (29) November 2007 (21) October 2007 (6) September 2007 (18) August 2007 (20) July 2007 (16) June 2007 (15) May 2007 (19) April 2007 (22) March 2007 (33) February 2007 (29) 
Categories
 Select Category Adult Programs&amp;Classes  (35) American Festivals&amp;Holidays  (13) Arts&amp;Crafts  (35) ATTRACTION CLOSED  (18) Bars&amp;Nightlife  (21) Beaches&amp;Pools  (37) Books, Film, Music  (30) Cars  (18) Castles, Shrines&amp;Temples  (21) Childcare, Preschools&amp;Schools  (48) Cooking Local  (35) Date Night  (13) Daytripping  (85) Dietary Issues  (9) Exercise&amp;Sports  (46) Food For Sale  (79) From Your Okinawa Hai Managers  (11) Gifts&amp;Souvenirs  (79) Health, Beauty&amp;Pampering  (45) Healthcare  (17) Hikes  (13) Home (shopping)  (66) Indoor Activities  (19) Japanese Language  (54) Just in Japan  (98) Kids&amp;Maternity Shopping  (48) Kids Activities: Indoors  (31) Kids Activities: Outdoors  (39) Kids Programs&amp;Classes  (20) Kids’Parties  (14) Making Your Home  (28) Maps  (8) Men (clothes shopping)  (18) Military Life  (82) Nani kore? (What’s that?!)  (19) Off-Base Housing  (37) Off-Island Travel  (56) Okinawa Getaways  (21) Okinawan Festivals&amp;Holidays  (29) On Becoming Me  (61) On-Base Housing  (25) On-Base Shopping  (6) Online Shopping  (9) Only on Okinawa  (57) OOTA  (10) Outdoor Activities  (92) Parenting Wisdom  (47) Parks&amp;Playgrounds  (31) PCS-ing  (76) Pets  (17) Phone&amp;Internet  (12) Photography  (55)    2012 Calendar  (6) Pregnancy&amp;Childbirth  (18) Restaurants  (323) Running a Business  (11) Spiritual Life  (8) Uncategorized  (10) Vegetarian  (16) Volunteer Opportunities  (21) Weather  (4) Women (clothes shopping)  (29) Work Off Base  (2) Work On Base  (5) World Heritage Sites  (7) 
Legal(ish) Disclaimer: Okinawa Hai is not military or government sanctioned. We might be here on Okinawa because of our affiliation with the US military, but our behavior here is not Government Approved. Along those lines, Okinawa Hai is not responsible for comments made by our readers, nor for any of the content on external sites that we may have links to, but if you notice that there&apos;s something wildly inappropriate or just plain wrong on a site we&apos;ve linked to, send us an email and we&apos;ll take care of it.
 
Copyright © 2007-2012 Okinawa Hai 
Site maintained by Digavise 
 Bear
	</body>
</document>
