<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002819" url="http://www.angelfire.com/wy/PurpleG/FunnyEmails.htm" time="2012-07-12-18:53" support="2" score="0.001557079682337979" bingtitle="Funny Emails" webtitle="Funny Emails">
			<query id="000395" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000238" bing-rank="235"/>
	<description>Been in a car crash? ha ha, no no no 25.Croutons or ... 56.Fast Food Restaurant: I don&apos;t really like McDonalds.... ... that you got mail from before this one?: junk ...</description>
	<body>
		Sponsored by 
 Funny Emails 

 This page was inspired by Raymond okay? He sent us 
 the funniest email I&apos;ve ever seen and I just decided to make a page to put 
 all the funny emails here
because hotmail doesn&apos;t let me keep all my emails so.... this is like a storage 
 area. Well in case you haven&apos;t noticed, this homepage I made
was kinda meant for that. Anyways... enjoy while you&apos;re here. =) 

 1.What time is it? Universal 
 Time -2900 pm 
2.Name as it appears on your birth certificate: Tinha 
3.Nicknames: Tinha 
4.Parent&apos;s names: No such name 
5.Number of candles that appeared on your last
birthday cake? Ultimate 
6.Date that you regularly blow them out: 365 days 
7.Pets: Myself 
8.Height: Dont&apos; know 
9.Eye color: Not sure 
10. Hair Color: if it is not black, then it is white, 
 otherwise it should be black 
11. Piercing: take a look yourself 
12. Tattoos: somewhere 
13. How much do you love your job: no such job 
14. Birthplace: My mom&apos;s stomach 
15. Hometown: 344 Fungwan Town 
16. Current Residence: Tinha City 
17. Had he drink Calypso Breeze?: Why ask me, ask him 
18.Been in love before? forgot 
19.Been to Africa?: yeh, many times, to see apes 
20.Been toilet-papering?: Refuse to answer 
21.Been drunk?: don&apos;t drink cheap stuff 
23. Loved somebody so much it made you cry?: Nahhhh 
24. Been in a car crash? ha ha, no no no 
25.Croutons or Bacon Bits: //\\ 
26. 2 doors or 4 (on a car): 1 sun roof, 4 wheels, 4 
 tires, no doors 
27.Sprite or 7 Up: Nestea 
28.Coffee or Coffee Ice cream: Chinese Tea 29.Blanket 
 or Stuffed Animal: Apes 
30.Dumper or Dumpee: Ace Venture 
31.WHAT&apos;S YOUR FAVORITE SALAD DRESSING: salamonna fiesta 
32.Color of socks: 7 color 
33.Number: death 
34.Why?: guess 
35.Favourite place to be kissed: my butt 
36.Movie: Fungwan, Fungwan 2 (coming up soon) 
36.Fav band: Wind&amp;Cloud, Black Panther 
37.Quote from a movie: You&apos;r mine 
38.Favorite Holiday: everyday is a holiday 
39.Foods: eatable 
40.Day of the Week: any day 
41.Song at the moment: any song 
42.TV show: Fungwan 
44.Word or Phrase: what? what you just say? 
can&apos;t hear you, say it again, my left ear is not working properly,
say it near my right year, oh, my right year is dead too, sorry. 
46.Toothpaste: don&apos;t use it 
47.Restaurant: Tinha Club 
48.Flower: Yellow and black rose 
49. Least Favorite Subject: Mongolian 
50.Alcoholic: Brandy 
51.Sport to Watch: Dragon Ball Z 
52. Type of Ice Cream: cream without ice 
53.Zoo Exhibit: Africa 
54.Sesame Street Character: Trunks 
55.Disney/Warner Bros: X-Men 
 56.Fast Food Restaurant: I 
 don&apos;t really like McDonalds.... 
 

 RANDOM QUESTIONS
57.When was your last hospital visit? 4 times in 22 
 years 
58.Favorite drink?: depends 
59.What colour is your bedroom&apos;s carpet?: Planning to 
 get one 
60.What was the name of your childhood blanket? ask 
 my mom 
61.How many times did you fail your Driver&apos;s Licence
TEST? heh heh, 100 / 10 
62.What do you think of Ouija boards?: not telling 
63.Where do you see yourself in 10 yrs?: work, $, buy 
 house, work, $, bigger house, work, house, largest house, grave. 
64.Who is the last person that you got mail from before this one?: junk 
 mails 
65. Have you ever been convicted of a crime: too many, 
 take girls to see gold fish, etc etc 
66.Which single store would you choose to max your credit card?: 
Casino Rama 
67.What do you do most often when you are bored?: repling 
 this email 
68.What words or phrases do you overuse: your welcome 
69.Name the person that you are friends with that
lives the farthest away from you?: my grandpa, in heaven 
 now 
70.Most annoying thing is: ahhhh, Teddy is online again 
71.Best thing: still alive 
72.Bedtime: any time 
73.Who will respond to this fastest?: not me 
74.Who is the person you sent this to that is least likely to respond?: 
the people I didn&apos;t send to 
75.Who are you chatting with right now?: myself 
 76.What time is it now? check 
 the clock, don&apos;t you have a clock? 
 77. Say one nice thing about the person who sent 
 this to you:
 stop sending junk mail 
 to me, you pieace of cake, yummy 

 

 Back To Main
	</body>
</document>
