<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002022" url="http://munfitnessblog.com/why-teenagers-like-eating-fast-food/" time="2012-07-12-17:56" support="21" score="0.04810314561398221" bingtitle="Why Teenagers Like Eating Fast Food? by MunFitnessBlog.com" webtitle="Why Teenagers Like Eating Fast Food? by MunFitnessBlog.com">
			<query id="000372" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000462" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="001125" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000296" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="001112" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000846" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="001443" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000360" bing-rank="188"/>
			<query id="000870" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="000859" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000861" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="000450" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000368" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000925" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="000452" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="001529" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000892" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000862" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="001121" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000924" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="001520" bing-rank="30"/>
	<description>When I was in high school and college, I went to fast food restaurant pretty often. ... Eating fast food can save more time and it is tasty too which make me full in a ...</description>
	<body>
		MunFitnessBlog.com 
 Be Strong. Be Fit. 

  
 

 
 
Why Teenagers Like Eating Fast Food?
 March 25th, 2008· 16 Comments  ·  
  
 
 

When I was in high school and college, I went to fast food restaurant pretty often. Thought it was just a trend that time, but I was wrong. Even until today, fast food remains to be a popular choice among students.

So, why make fast food restaurants really popular, years after years:


 The food is affordable. Many teenagers do not have big pocket. So, it is good to get something tasty to eat and still have some money left for a movie later. Nowadays, many fast food restaurant opens till late nights like McDonald’s . Moreover, the place is comfortable and safer to hang out during late nights. At fast food restaurants, you choose what you want . You can mix and match with plenty of choices. Coke with French fries, sundae with apple pie, salad with burger. If you don’t like to choose, most fast food restaurants have packaged value meals. Normally, managers there will not stare at you for reading there for hours if you just ordered French fries and a Coke. So, good place to have group discussion for school projects, gossip and even birthday celebration. Furthermore, most teenagers go there because they feel like it is “in”thing to do since other boys and girls are there. 

 

Fast food restaurant is a place for social activity for teenagers. Just like small kids, teens are very influenced by their peers and by the media. So, it is fun to be there, as seen in fast food TV advertisements. It is cool.

 To ask youngsters not to eat so much fast food is like asking monk to eat meat. 

It is not easy.

You can try telling them the unhealthy huge portion sizes, high calorie content, high amounts of refined starch, added sugar, high fat content, and low levels of dietary fiber, but I doubt youngsters will listen. Most teens learn about the importance of health in school but they are not yet ready to embrace responsibility and in fact not concerned about it. I knew about what vitamin A, B and C were when I was in college but I still skipped breakfast and ate only Snicker with Coke for my quick lunch. With more pocket money, beer is the next“in”thing when we thought we were old enough to be adult.

 

Teenagers are rebellious. Just like spring, the harder you press, the higher the resistance is. We all young once. We learned along the way. I hope that they all will realize the importance of health eating eventually before it is too late.

 
 
You may also like -
 How To Eat Healthy on Tight Budget? If I Can Do It, You Can Do It Too. Should Fast Food Companies Be Blamed in Causing Obesity? Do Your Parents Influence Your Eating Habit? What Color of Food Will Discourage You From Eating?  
  

   Email This Post 
 
Category: Health 

If you like this or other articles in this blog, Subscribe to MunFitnessBlog.com today . It is free.
 
 Related Posts 
 How To Stop Eating with Anti-Eating Face Mask You Don’t Want To Know How Your Food Is Prepared in Restaurant The Lazy Way To Lose Weight By Eating Fruit Top 5 Weight Loss Eating Habit Tips for Women…and Man Too 
 
Scroll down to leave a comment. I really want to know what you think.
 
Found what you were looking for? If not, try searching for it below. 
 Custom Search  
 16 responses so far↓ 
 
 chickens // Mar 26, 2008 at 12:44 AM 
 
hmmm…to be honest, I don’t think fast food is cheap lol…rm9-10 a meal? thats enough to make a big hole outta my pocket :P. I would say economic rice/chap fan is much more cheaper and healthy if compared with fast food hahaha
 
 LogicYuan // Mar 27, 2008 at 5:47 PM 
 
Have you heard of a Celebrity Chef in the name of Jamie Oliver’s quest to improve the food supplied in schools in Britain? He had a very tough time. Maybe you can do a little research and write another article on that.

Fast food are not cheap but it is still lower priced compared to other restaurants. Hawkers are still cheaper in terms of price but the quantity differs too.

I do like to go to fast food joints but I limit this venture to Once In A Blue Moon. My favourite one now is Carl’s Jr. Haha

One more thing, I heard the McD in Wangsa Maju closes one day before TAR college exams because it will be filled with students with one order and they stay there day and night. They’d rather stop the business for a day. Haha
 
 charlotte // Aug 26, 2008 at 12:38 AM 
 
Not ev1 goes fast food. Me an me m8s nvr go. its way 2 expensive and not even that nice. infact loads of me m8s frm skool just buy a salad or out frm asda healthy and cheap and nicer beat that!!!
 
 waterlily // Aug 28, 2008 at 11:05 AM 
 
fast foods is not good for our health. as we know……
lack of nutrition and can cause disease.

why don’t we just eat at home. we can save our money…and of course, safe…..and healthy
 
 Sukrat Ray // Nov 8, 2008 at 3:56 PM 
 
Lets make fast food ordering online.
 
 Lolli PoP // Nov 16, 2008 at 8:01 AM 
 
Hi.. i really liked your article.. i think it is very true and it helped me alot with my english project, because now we in school we are debating on things. And my topid is: Should people eat fast food, and im against it of course. So post more articles pls on how fast food could affect our bodies!

thanks! I also liked the 7 tips to why people eat.. i think that eating when you are bored is truly like me! lol

well keep up the good work!
 
 Fat Bastard // Nov 20, 2008 at 2:20 AM 
 
You people are all N-V-T-S NUTES. i go to McD’s and get about 5-6 Double Cheeseburgrers form the $1 menu adn scarf‘em all. For five bucks, I eat until I have to blow it all out the bottom end. My gut’s so big I can’t hardly wedge into the booth seats there anymore, but now they have 2 triple cheeseburgers for $3, so I’m going to get maybe 4 or 6 of them and try not to puke it up!
 
 Former Teen // Dec 6, 2008 at 4:21 AM 
 
I think that eating fast food is in the long run more expensive than eating at home. Besides, health concerns. Ialways liked dinners with the family and learned to cook while in my teen years, so for me there are no advantages in eating out in places like McDonald’s.
 
 Jaylah // Dec 10, 2008 at 11:20 PM 
 
I think fast food is addicting to teens and people in general because it is hard. Sometimes people don’t feel like cooking and they go through the drive thru or just sit in booths and wait at least 14 minutes to get their food. Instead of waiting an hour to eat. Sometimes all the fat is good for you. But I am a skinny person but some day all that fat and calories I ate is going to catch up with me. I your overweight don’t think your fat. Lol I seen fat. From now on in America people should just sit at the dinner table in their homes and eat a healthy meal with meat, fruits, vegetables, and bread. Once in awhile!
 
 princess syamida // Mar 4, 2009 at 9:17 AM 
 
i’m agree with you. i dictionary said thats ast food is inexpensive. in my management classes, my lecturer had been thought that fast food restaurant always use‘bundle pricing’that make it much inexpensive. it is because they combine 2 0r 3 meals in 1 set and we wll get affordable pice. in cotras, if we buy fries at KFC, burgers at McD and want to drink at Nandos.. it will cost we a lot
 
 Ms. Sophisticated // Nov 2, 2009 at 5:34 AM 
 
I like fast food because it gives me a choice between cooking and spending money. Well either way I still have to spend money but fast food is cheaper
 
 Bradley // Jan 27, 2010 at 9:53 PM 
 
I think really and honestly, when you say that”most teens learn about the importance of health in school but they are not yet ready to embrace responsibility and in fact not concerned about it.”that you are probably being a hypocrite.

When your mother explained to you why you shouldn’t do something or behave in a certain way because of certain reasons, did you listen straight away? of course not. If every one listened to their parents it would be a very boring world.

People learn the hard way. End of.
 
 douye // Mar 10, 2010 at 8:44 PM 
 
i think fast food is not good for the body, and the most funniest part is that i’m presently doing a research on why do young people eat fast food, please i need your help.
 
 kalyan keo // Jun 23, 2010 at 4:31 PM 
 
I really like your article. That is true about conception of teenager with fast food. For me, i really like fast food such sandwich and pizza, although i know that it is not good for health. Eating fast food can save more time and it is tasty too which make me full in a whole day.
 
 ScoutBoyyss // Jan 12, 2012 at 11:46 AM 
 
A lot of teenagers always mash themselves in MacDonald all the time.
I have some experience working in fast-food restaurants…
And I want to share my information…

Since I am a dude, I was force to work at the back and make burgurs.
My workplace is quite close to my school, and whenever some douchebags walk into the store and order a buruger, I just fxxxing spit on it!!

Another surprise:
We fry french fries with oil that has not been cleaned for more than 30 days.
You guys would have no clue at all if this is real or not.
But, it is true.

Try to restrain yourself from entering fastfood resturants…
It’s not good for your health!!
 
 termite // Mar 21, 2012 at 12:22 PM 
 
what i dis agree what hapens if u dont have time to cook a meal or eat“healthy”im not fat but i have fat freinds i dont juge them. yer it costs a little bit of money but maybe we like to get fast food once and a while and i bet u do to so dont be a hypercrit
 
 Leave a Comment 
 Name 

 Mail 

 Website 

 

 Notify me of future comments via e-mail 

 

 

 Notify me of new posts by email. 
 ← The New Age for Middle East Muslim Women in Olympic Games What To Wear for Yoga Classes →  
  
 
 MunFitnessBlog.com 
 About MunFitnessBlog.Com Articles Archive Ask Mun a Question Contact Mun 
 
Don&apos;t miss any post. Subscribe to MunFitnessBlog.com now. Enter your email address:

 
 

  Subscribe in a reader 

 Why Subscribe and How? Most Popular Post 
 How To Build A Body Like Ryan Reynolds 6 Reasons You Should Exercise with Cross-Trainer or Elliptical Exercise Machine Top 10 Pick Up Lines For Girls or Guys At The Gym How To Train to Get A Body Like Jessica Biel How To Build 300 Warrior&apos;s Body with Gym Workout? How To Build A Body Like Will Smith The Truth Behind “The Biggest Loser Reality Show” Which Has Never Been Told 
 Post Of The Month 
 Bruce Lee - The Legend
 Shop For Fitness Gadget Categories 
 Fitness Classes 
 Les Mills Yoga 
 Fitness Gadget/Equipment Fitness News Funny Fitness Experience Gym Going 
 California Fitness Celebrity Fitness Clark Hatch True Fitness 
 Health Motivation Nutrition Other Fitness/Sports Articles Weight Loss Weight Training 
 Abs Back Biceps Chest Forearm Legs Shoulders Triceps 
 
 Find Me On Facebook or Twitter 
 
  
 
 
Copyright (C) 2007-2012 MunFitnessBlog.com  
 
 Sitemap  
 
 Archives  
 
 Privacy
	</body>
</document>
