<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002263" url="http://californialoanfind.com/quick-cash-loan-for-5000-in-los-angeles-ca/" time="2012-07-12-18:09" support="2" score="0.0013823225968191434" bingtitle="Quick Cash Loan for $5000 in Los Angeles, Ca – California Loan Find" webtitle="Quick Cash Loan for $5000 in Los Angeles, CaCalifornia Loan Find">
			<query id="001053" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="001305" bing-rank="198"/>
	<description>On top of those two payments he needs to make an installment on a car loan for close to $600 dollars ... have to wash windows at a stop light or work in a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		ONLINE LOAN FINDER–PERSONAL LOANS–GOOD AND BAD CREDIT BORROWERS Skip to content 



 

 
 
 Home About CLF Loans Site Map Contact Terms + Privacy Sources Partners 
 
Quick Cash Loan for $5000 in Los Angeles, Ca 
 
 
Our lonesome borrow today hails from L.A. and he is need of a three-prong loan (so to speak). He needs to pay off three creditors the same week as his application, and one of those creditors is his sister, whom he has to pay back $3000 dollars. His other creditor is the landlord who wants him to clear up his arrears on his rent to the tune of $1400. On top of those two payments he needs to make an installment on a car loan for close to $ 600 dollars (actually $558 in total).

This is in some ways a dirty consolidation loan, and when I use the term“dirty consoldiation loan”and am using a lending venacular phrase coined by Carol who is one of our underwriters here at CLF . She used the term to describe an applicant that is looking to borrow high APR , high-cost money to consolidate some emergency bills that have fallen behind or through the cracks. 

The term“dirty”means that the loan is just another very high interest lending product that will take the borrower even further in to a high interest debt hole. The interest rate on a dirty consolidation (as Carol calls it), is usually in the APR range of 15% to 25%, and the runaway effect of this kind of APR is extremely damaging to any person that makes the mistake of the getting the product. It’s reallu just another predatory loan tool used by unscrupulous lenders across the United States. To be avoided at all costs.

You are not doing yourself any favors by

 Quick Cash Loan Amount :: $5000 dollars

Quick Cash Advance Speed :: Instant

Quick Cash Loan Term Length :: 3 months, or 90-100 day term

Have You Taken Out a Quick Cash Advance in the past 3 years? :: Yes

What City/Town and State do you live in? :: Los Angeles

Are you military personal (active duty)? :: Nope

Job Description :: Sales Associate at for vending machine company

Choose your credit rating from below please :: Bad to terrible

- excellent
- good
- fair
- bad
- very bad
- terrible

For your security, please don’t include the following;

- ABA or bank routing #
- SSN (social security number)
- Real Name
- Street Address
- Work Address
- Name of Employer

Have you defaulted on the loan payment recently? :: No

What do you need this loan for? :: I have two money problems. I am behind on rent and an on the verge of getting evicted, and I owe my sister a personal loan repayment too. I need to pay the landlord $1400 that I am behind on, pay back my sister the $3000 she has coming to her, and the last $600 dollars is to make a car payment.

So really I have three payments that are due by the end of the week. I’ve already been in bankruptcy once in my life and I don’t want to ever go there again. I’m 34 years old now and I have credit because my bankruptcy was over 10 years ago from my first marriage that was over when I was 23.  I just ain’t going there again. Even if I have to wash windows at a stop light or work in a fast food restaurant, I will be paying all that I owe by hook or by crook!

I don’t want to resort to stealing money or anything like that, but I’m really desperate to raise this money today. I need these pressing financial problems dealth with by the end of the day. I’m now losing sleep over these debts because I can’t let down my sister yet again, and I can’t ever be bankrupt again. It REALLY sucks being bankrupt and I have learned my lesson once and for all.

I want you to know that I am looking for a lender that will give me a second chance to get bacl on my feet again.


 

 
Below Are Some Related Loans - Borrower Requests and Approvals
 

 Cash Advance in Toronto 
In Toronto there are only a small handful of cash advance companies available in... Divorce and Bankruptcy In LA (Dennis and Sandra) 
Dennis and Sandra were married when they were 27 years old (Dennis was 28 actual... Listing Best Bad Credit Lenders - Easiest and Fastest Approval Process 
Which bad credit lenders are the best, and which Bad Credit Lenders have the eas... Loans in Santa Clara County 
We attempting to list all of the different lenders and lending products in Santa... Payday Loan Store Locations Bakersfield, Ca 
This is our all inclusive list of PDL stores, shops, and outlets in Bakersfield.... Cash Advance Payday Loan – San Gabriel, Temple City, Los Angeles 
Mr. Garcia (name changed) applied for a cash advance payday loan from his home a... Quick Cash Loans 
One of the loan categories we have not focused on at CLF is quick cash loans, an... Quick Cash Loan for $1500 in Bakersfield, Ca 
This is a loan application from Bakersfield, Ca. The applicant wants to borrow ... 



 Do 
 You Need a Personal Loan Approved Today? Use the comment form below and use FIRST NAME ONLY for you intial loan request. 

 Our 
 community of friendly folks might be able to help you! 

 Use 
 the comment box at the bottom of this page and tell us,
 
- how much you need to borrow
- what type of loan you need
- what State you live in
- how quickly you need the loan 

 Your 
 email is never made public, saved, or shared. Your privacy
is never compromised. 

 Unkind 
 words will not be published.

Thanks for visiting Californialoanfind.com ;-) 

 
Other Loan Applications

 Cash Advance Payday Loan – San Gabriel, Temple City, Los Angeles (0)
 Mr. Garcia (name changed) applied for a cash advance payday loan from his home and business in San Gabriel/Temple City. ... Payday Loan Store Locations Bakersfield, Ca (2)
 This is our all inclusive list of PDL stores, shops, and outlets in Bakersfield. Always be careful using these kinds of ... $700 Payday Loan Cash Advance Los Angeles–Hermosa Beach (0)
 This is a short form application from an applicant in Hermosa Beach (basically Los Angeles) who want&apos;s exactly $700 cash... Small Loans–200, 300, 400, 500 With Installment Repayments (2)
 Small cash loans for 200, 300, 400, 500 and up to 1000 dollars are extremely common and sought after by online borrowers... Quick Cash Loans (2)
 One of the loan categories we have not focused on at CLF is quick cash loans, and there is a reason for it. Most quick c... $10,000 Loan in Los Angeles/Altadena for Person With Bad Credit–Bill’s CC Debt (4)
 $10,000 Loan to Pay off Credit Card Debt in Los Angeles (Altadena) - The Equestrian
Bill who works in Altadena and live... Small Business Loan With Bad Credit for $30000-$10000–West Covina, Ca (3)
 This was a recent small business loan application that went through to some private lenders in Southern California. This... Unsecured Small Personal Loan in Angelino Heights, Los Angeles (Bill Payments) (0)
 This applicant and borrower needed to borrow an unsecured cash amount of $5000 - $1000o for the purpose of paying down b... $5000 No Credit Check Loan (20)
 This $5000 dollar loan request comes from an applicant who wants to pay for his girlfriends breast augmentation and he w... $3000 Personal Loan in Sherman Oaks, Los Angeles (same day) (1)
 As part of our new series on Los Angeles loans, we are presenting this loan app from the Sherman Oaks District. The appl... 
BELOW IS A LOAN CALCULATOR FOR CARRYING OUT SOME LOAN CALCULATIONS--------------------------------------------


Enter the loan amount, year of term, interest rate, and payment periods (14 for biweekly, 30 for monthly, 7 for weekly. Very helpful so you know exactly what the loan will cost you in interest payments and you will know the total COB (cost of borrowing). Loan Amount: 
 
 Interest: 
 
 Years: 
 
 Days between payments: 
30 for a Month, 7 for Week
and 14 for Bi-Weekly. Easy!
 
 
-------------------------------- NEW! --&gt; Join our Non-Profit Peer-to-Peer 
Lending Forum -------------------------------- This was written by . Posted on Saturday, May 14, 2011, at 6:14 am . Filed under Quick Cash Loans . Tagged fast cash loan , lenders , los angeles , no teletrack loan , pay rent , payday loan , Quick Cash Loans . Bookmark the permalink . Follow comments here with the RSS feed . Post a comment or leave a trackback . 
 When filling out your initial loan request, use FIRST NAME ONLY and NO PHONE NUMBERS please. This is for your privacy and security. Thank you for using Californialoanfind.com! 

8 Responses to“Quick Cash Loan for $5000 in Los Angeles, Ca”

 1 Judith Breckenridge Says:
 May 27th, 2011 at 10:20 am 
I need a $3,500–$5,000 loan asap. I am in Atwater, CA. I got myself in too deep just during the last few months. I have 3 payday loans totalling $990 (with fees) and an installment loan for $2,600 for $221.96/mo. (96% interest). Because of those, I have not been able to pay all of my monthly bills this month. I am so desperate to pay these off that I’m considering putting a“stop payment”on them but I would rather pay them off.

My scores are in the 600′s. It took me a long time to get there. I owned a home for 10 years until Dec. 2010, and prior to that I rented a house for 6 years. My bank account and phone number have been the same for 16 years, a testament to my stability.

The payday loans are due June 3; the installment loan June 18. I am desperate to resolve these loans and I would prefer a loan to pay them off. I’m afraid any lender who sees that I just took out a $2,600 loan will deny me, but 96% interest is way too high. My montly income is $2081, rent is $725. Thank you.
 2 Kristina Says:
 July 29th, 2011 at 9:09 am 
Hi I am trying to get a personal loan for the amount of 2,000. I live in Monterey Park, CA and I am looking for pay off my debts I owe to family members and on my credit. I have been looking for a bad credit personal loan online for a while now but all that I have been coming across are scams or banks who can’t approve my loan because my credit score is not so perfect. Please if you can help me in any way I would gladly appreciate it. I have messed up with my credit in the past but I’m trying to rebuild and get back on my feet.

LOAN AMOUNT: 2000-3000
PROCESS SPEED: ASAP
NEED FOR LOAN: pay off debts
LOCATION: Monterey Park, CA 91754
EMPLOYMENT: Westview Services, working with developmental disabled clients
POSITION: Vocational Specialist (Job coach)
WHEN PAID: 10TH AND 26TH of the month
CREDIT RATING: bad around 580 or so
HOW PAID: Direct deposit
GROSS AMOUNT MONTHLY: 2100
I AGREE TO PUBLICIZE MY APPLICATION WHILE KEEPING PRIVATE INFORMATION PRIVATE
EXTRA INFORMATION: I live with my Mother so I only pay 200 rent and can afford a monthly payback of 150. If you could please help me find a TRUSTED lender I would greatly appreciate it. I would like to get a loan in person so I know that everything is legitmate but if that is not possible then online is okay as long as I know I won’t be scammed. Thank you have a great day 
 3 Nancy Says:
 February 21st, 2012 at 2:43 pm 
Hello,

My name is Nancy. I live in Los Angeles CA. I need a loan of $4500.00. I would like to pay off the loan within 1-2 years. The loan is for dental procedures and braces I need to get ASAP, because of underlying tooth issues. My dentist offered me to put half down for my braces and need to pay the amount for my teeth being repaired in full, but is impossible for me to do so Id rather pay the full thing off all at once with a loan. I need this loan ASAP, because I have to start my treatments ASAP before it causes worse damage to my gums and teeth. I work in the Medical Field, and am married. Combined my husband and I make $1100.00/week and we both get paid bi-weekly. I will have no problem paying off the loan. I just started building credit 1 year and 2 months ago so my credit history is limited and is in the“fair”ranking, almost up to good. I need a Trusted Lender, with a lower apr or % because I am paying off the loan in a faster amount of time. I dont need scammers thanks!
 4 Nancy Says:
 February 21st, 2012 at 2:52 pm 
Hi my name is Nancy. I live in Los Angeles, California. I need a 4500.00 loan for dental procedures/treatments. My dentist wants half down at time of starting treatment but is impossible for me to do right now. And I need to do this ASAP so I need the money within 3 days. My husband and I make a combined 1100.00/week. We both get paid bi-weekly, we have no problem paying off a loan. I started building my credit 1 yr and 2 months ago, so my credit is Fair, close to good. I want to pay off the loan within 1-2 years with a lower apr or %. I want a trusted lender, no scammers!
 5 Howard Says:
 March 6th, 2012 at 11:58 am 
Requested Loan Amount: 3500.00
Term: 2–3 years, Monthly payments if possible.
Would like a trusted lender with lower % than a payday loan.
Process Speed: ASAP
Reason for Loan: To consolidate outstanding loans, make car payment, and purchase heating oil for the house.
Residence: New Jersey, 638 Linwood Ave, Collingswood, NJ 08108, 10 yrs
Employment: Admiral Insurance Company, Business Analyst, approx 7 yrs
Employer Address: 1255 Caldwell Road, Cherry Hill, NJ
Monthly Income: (Net) 3,341.
Pay Dates: Semi Monthly, 15th and last business day of month
 6 Ruben Says:
 May 7th, 2012 at 4:12 pm 
I need 5000 for school and debt please help!!!!
 7 Nancy Says:
 June 25th, 2012 at 3:13 pm 
I am in need of an installment loan ASAP. I understand
That this is not the smartest solution but right now I just want to
Get back on track.
I have a great job as a manager at a grocery store and
Just got behind helping out a friend in need.
The friend of course is no where to be found.
So we live and learn
I take full responsibility in my debt but do need help
Thank you for your time
 8 Darrell Says:
 July 6th, 2012 at 12:08 pm 
needs a personal loan of $8000.00
 
 
Leave a Reply
 Click here to cancel reply. 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
   ‹ New Car Loan Application for a Chevy Volt in Los Angeles Small Loans–200, 300, 400, 500 With Installment Repayments › 
The Complete List of Lending Categories for California Loan Find - Get Approved Today!
 

$

 $200-$900 Small Loans 

A

 Alhambra Loans Anaheim Loans Angel Loans Antioch Loans Auto Loan Applications 

B

 Bad Credit Loans Bad Debt Bakersfield Loans Bankruptcy Banks Bill Consolidation Loans Boat Loans Borrowing and Lending Borrowing Online Business Loans 

C

 California Loans Canada Loans Car Loans Car Title Loans Carol&apos;s Borrowing Series Cash Advance Cash Loan Chico Loans Chino Hills Loans CLF Announcements Commercial Loans Computer Loans Concord Loans Contests Credit Card Debt Relief Credit Cards Credit Repair Credit Scoring Credit Unions 
 

D

 Davis Loans Debt Consolidation Debt Management DIY 

E

 El Cajon Loans Escondido Loans Eureka Loans 

F

 Fast Loans Fast Track Loans Financial Friends Financial Stress Relief Financial Writers Free Loans Angel Loans Fremont Loans Fresno Loans 

G

 Glossary Grants 

H

 Handicapped/Retired Hanford Lenders HELOCs High Risk Loans Home Equity Loans Home Mortgage Home Refinancing Loan Huntington Beach Loans 

I

 Informational 

L

 Lawsuit Loans Loan Applications Loan Calculators Loan Find Group Loan Modifications Loan Scam Awareness Loans For Medical Bills Loans for Moving Loans for Self Employed 
 

L

 Loans for Surgery Lompoc Loans Long Beach Loans Los Angeles Loans 

M

 Madera Loans Military Loans Minority Loans Mobile Home Loans Modesto Loans Mortgage Freedom Mortgage Loans Mortgage Refinancing Motorcycle Loans 

N

 No Collateral Loans Non Profit Peer to Peer Lending Non-Conforming Loans NonProfit Debt Consolidation 

O

 Oakland Loans Oceanside Loans Office Equipment Loans Ontario Loans Overnight Loans 

P

 Palm Springs Loans Payday Loan Reviews Payday Loans Personal Information/Security Personal Loans Petaluma Loans Poor Credit Home Loan Poor Credit Rating Porterville Loans 

Q

 Quick Cash Loans 

R

 Reader Stories Redding Loans Retirement 401k 
 

R

 Reverse Mortgages Riverside Loans RV Loans 

S

 Sacramento Loans Salinas Loans San Bernardino Loans San Diego San Francisco Loans San Gabriel Loans San Jose Loans Santa Ana Loans Santa Barbara Loans Santa Clara County Santa Clarita Loans Santa Maria Loans Signature Loans Special Financing State of The Economy Stockton Loans Student Loans Subprime Loans Surgery Loans 

T

 Taxes Temecula Loans Terrible Credit 

U

 Uncategorized Unsecured Loans Updates 

V

 Ventura Loans Visalia Loans 

W

 Watsonville Loans West Covina Loans Would You Approve This Loan? 

Y

 Yuba City Loans 
 
 
 Search 
 
Recent Posts

 Loan for Moving Expenses–Los Angeles to San Francisico High Risk Applicant Loan for $10000–Los Angeles Credit Repair Loan for $5000 in San Diego Hard Money Commercial Real Estate Loan for $2 Million–Carmel Valley, San Diego, CA Excellent Credit Personal Loan With Collateral in Santa Clarita California–$10,000 Bad Credit Used Motorcycle Loan in Los Angeles for $15,000 Bad Credit RV Loan in San Francisco California–$150,000 Bad Credit Boat Loan in Santa Cruz California–$45,000 Home Equity Debt Consolidation Loan Refinance in Fairfield California Home Refinancing Loan to Pay Off Credit Card Debt–In Palm Spring California 
 
Recent Comments

 Darlene on Listing Best Bad Credit Lenders–Easiest and Fastest Approval Process Nina on $5000 Installment Loan that is Paid Back Over 2-3 Years Carol on $10,000-$15,000-$20,000 Free Angel Loan–Philanthropic Lender in Los Angeles, CA Dy on Legit Bad Credit Loans Julie on Fast Unsecured Loan With Bad Credit ($2000,$3000,$5000,$10000) Becky on Fast Unsecured Loan With Bad Credit ($2000,$3000,$5000,$10000) Brandon on $15000-$17000 Loan Request from San Bernardino, Ca–Poor Credit Borrower 
 
Categories

 $200-$900 Small Loans Angel Loans Auto Loan Applications Bad Credit Loans Bad Debt Bankruptcy Banks Bill Consolidation Loans Boat Loans Borrowing and Lending Borrowing Online Business Loans California Loans 
 Alhambra Loans Anaheim Loans Antioch Loans Bakersfield Loans Chico Loans Chino Hills Loans Concord Loans Davis Loans El Cajon Loans Escondido Loans Eureka Loans Fremont Loans Fresno Loans Hanford Lenders Huntington Beach Loans Lompoc Loans Long Beach Loans Los Angeles Loans Madera Loans Modesto Loans Oceanside Loans Ontario Loans Palm Springs Loans Petaluma Loans Porterville Loans Redding Loans Riverside Loans Sacramento Loans Salinas Loans San Bernardino Loans San Diego San Francisco Loans San Gabriel Loans San Jose Loans Santa Ana Loans Santa Barbara Loans Santa Clara County Santa Clarita Loans Santa Maria Loans Stockton Loans Temecula Loans Ventura Loans Visalia Loans Watsonville Loans West Covina Loans Yuba City Loans 
 Canada Loans Car Loans Car Title Loans Carol&apos;s Borrowing Series Cash Advance Cash Loan CLF Announcements Commercial Loans Computer Loans Contests Credit Card Debt Relief Credit Cards Credit Repair Credit Scoring Credit Unions Debt Consolidation Debt Management DIY Fast Loans Fast Track Loans Financial Friends Financial Stress Relief Financial Writers Free Loans Angel Loans Glossary Grants Handicapped/Retired HELOCs High Risk Loans Home Equity Loans Home Mortgage Home Refinancing Loan Informational Lawsuit Loans Loan Applications Loan Calculators Loan Find Group Loan Modifications Loan Scam Awareness Loans For Medical Bills Loans for Moving Loans for Self Employed Loans for Surgery Military Loans Minority Loans Mobile Home Loans Mortgage Freedom Mortgage Loans Mortgage Refinancing Motorcycle Loans No Collateral Loans Non Profit Peer to Peer Lending Non-Conforming Loans NonProfit Debt Consolidation Oakland Loans Office Equipment Loans Overnight Loans Payday Loan Reviews Payday Loans Personal Information/Security Personal Loans Poor Credit Home Loan Quick Cash Loans Reader Stories Retirement 401k Reverse Mortgages RV Loans Signature Loans Special Financing State of The Economy Student Loans Subprime Loans Surgery Loans Taxes Terrible Credit Uncategorized Unsecured Loans Updates Would You Approve This Loan? 
 
Tags
 $10000 loan $15000 loan 10000 dollar loan bad credit bad credit loan Bad Credit Loans Bad Debt Bankruptcy Banks borrowing money business loans ca california california loan California Loans california mortgage ca loans Cash Advance credit bureaus Credit Cards Credit Unions Debt Consolidation debt consolidation loan divorce fico score financial definitions free directory home loans lenders loan officer loans los angeles los angeles loans mortgages payday loan Payday Loans personal finances personal loan Personal Loans poor credit rating quick cash loan Quick Cash Loans san diego small business loan Student Loans 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 
 ©2012 ¶ Thanks, WordPress . ¶ veryplaintxt theme by Scott Allan Wallick . ¶ It&apos;s nice XHTML &amp; CSS .
	</body>
</document>
