<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002923" url="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/adam-roberts/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601.html" time="2012-07-12-19:00" support="1" score="0.0027175276507063707" bingtitle="Adam Roberts: 10 Things That You&apos;re Doing Wrong at Restaurants" webtitle="Adam Roberts: 10 Things That You&apos;re Doing Wrong at Restaurants">
			<query id="001175" bing-rank="172"/>
	<description>I&apos;ve been eating at restaurants my entire ... loves the fish, nod nicely and still order the steak. If it&apos;s a good restaurant ... it may seem rude, at first, to tell your ...</description>
	<body>
		HuffPost&apos;s QuickRead... Loading... HuffPost&apos;s QuickRead... Loading... 
 Fast Food E. Coli Food Food Informants 
 More Log in Create Account 
 Notifications 
 Profile Settings Logout 
 
 July 12, 2012
 
 
 Edition: U.S. 
 CA Canada 
  Québec 
 FR France ES Spain US United States UK United Kingdom 
 
 
 
 FRONT PAGE Politics 
 WATCH: Romney Booed Over Obamacare 42k Chris Christie Makes Fun Of Fat Jokes 1k GOP Votes To Repeal Obamacare Again 21k Brewer&apos;s Anti-Gay Benefits Stance Prompts Protest Resignation 4k Obama Leading With Single Voters 9k 
 Like 142k   Go to Politics More in Politics 
 Pollster Election 2012 Speculatron HuffPost Hill Fundrace Off The Bus Election Dashboard 
 You might also like 
 World Green Tech 
 Entertainment 
 Singer Apologizes For National Anthem Fail 1k Daniel Tosh Apologizes For Rape Joke 5k PHOTO: See Sofia&apos;s Engagement Ring! 45 7 Sites You Should Be Wasting Time On Right Now 11 Target Won&apos;t Sell Frank Ocean&apos;s Album 640 
 Like 72k   Go to Entertainment More in Entertainment 
 Celebrity TV 
 You might also like 
 Comedy Arts Books Culture Style Weird News Moviefone 
 Business 
 WATCH: Evidence Ex-Wall Street Trader May Have Taken Cyanide 2k Paul Krugman Slams Times Colleague, CNBC 3k Here Are The 16 Banks Under Investigation Over The Libor Scandal 365 Evander Holyfield&apos;s Unable To Avoid Foreclosure On $14 Million Mansion 683 Missing Banker: I &apos;Hurt The People I Was Trying To Help&apos; 428 
 Like 34k   Go to Business More in Business 
 Small Business Money 
 You might also like 
 World Tech Media Culture Sports Weird News Crime 
 Media 
 Katie Couric Speaks Out About Ann Curry&apos;s &apos;Today&apos; Ouster 397 Gallup: Confidence In TV News At New Low 4k Anderson Cooper&apos;s Coming Out Was Planned For Months 246 WATCH: Soledad O&apos;Brien Cringes At Biden&apos;s Sex Joke 332 OUCH: CNN Reporter&apos;s Ultra-Gloomy Words About Romney&apos;s NAACP Speech 1k 
 Like 46k   Go to Media More in Media 
 Eat The Press Calderone: The Backstory 
 You might also like 
 Entertainment TV Comedy Arts Books Religion Moviefone 
 Kitchen Daily 
 Beat The Heat With 15 No-Cook Meals 12 Ways To Turn Your Ugly Pie Into A Showstopper 40 Food Debate: Does Ketchup Belong On Hot Dogs? 224 Kitchen Trick: Preserve Fresh Herbs In Frozen Olive Oil Rise And Shine: 10 Mouth-Watering Eggs Benedicts 
 Like 37k   Go to Kitchen Daily More in Kitchen Daily 
 Recipes Baking Breakfast Chefs and Experts Entertaining Healthy Eating Dinner Tonight Easter Kitchen Daily Videos 
 You might also like 
 Food 
 Travel 
 PHOTOS: Guess Who Has The Worst Traffic? 406 Concordia Captain Makes Shocking Revelations 940 Boo: Now The World&apos;s Cutest Airline Spokesman 60 70-Year-Old Minister Takes 7000th Coaster Ride 53 Theme Park Sued For Barring Amputees From Coaster 78 
 Like 24k   Go to Travel More in Travel 
 Travel Video Destinations Themed Guides TSA Airlines 
 You might also like 
 Food Culture World GPS for the Soul Kitchen Daily 
 Green 
 PHOTOS: Adorable Baby Elephant Saved By Mother 353 PHOTOS: Dinosaur Sex Similar Across Species, Scientists Say 232 Waldo Canyon Fire Fully Contained 97 Young Man Mysteriously Found Dead Inside Tiger Den 75 LOOK: Why Is This Gorilla Flipping Off The Photographer? 431 
 Like 104k   Go to Green More in Green 
 Energy Climate Change Animals Green Tech Green Holiday 
 You might also like 
 Politics Food World Science Healthy Living 
 Tech 
 10 Free Programs Every Windows User Should Install Immediately 891 The Mildly Fabulous Story Of The First Photo Posted To The Internet 206 Is The U.S. Government Planning To Secret Super-Scanners? 509 WATCH: Conservative Group Calls For Boycott Of Google 1k 11 Things You Should Never Do On OkCupid 242 
 Like 54k   Go to Tech More in Tech 
 Best of TED Social Media 
 You might also like 
 Small Business Green Science New York San Francisco TechCrunch Engadget Joystiq 
 Comedy 
 Daniel Tosh Apologizes For Rape Joke 5k Comedians Defend Daniel Tosh 692 7 Sites You Should Be Wasting Time On Right Now 11 15 Dogs Receiving The Best News Ever 25 Seth Meyers Will NOT Make Big Move 117 
 Like 105k   Go to Comedy More in Comedy 
 Funny Videos Comedy Club Political Humor Original Videos Crossing The Line 
 You might also like 
 Entertainment Weird News College Arts Culture 
 ALL SECTIONS News 
 Politics World Business Small Business Money Media Sports Education Crime Weird News Good News 
 Entertainment 
 Entertainment Celebrity Culture Comedy Arts Books TV Moviefone 
 Life&amp;Style 
 Healthy Living GPS for the Soul Style Food Kitchen Daily Weddings Travel Parents Divorce Huff/Post 50 Stylelist Stylelist Home 
 Tech&amp;Science 
 Tech Science Green TechCrunch Engadget TUAW Joystiq 
 Voices 
 Women Black Voices Latino Voices Voces (en español) Gay Voices Religion College Teen Impact 
 Local 
 Chicago DC Denver Detroit Miami New York Los Angeles San Francisco Patch.com Mapquest 
 AOL 
 Daily Finance Aol Jobs Aol Autos Autoblog Aol Music Aol Video Games.com Heidi Klum Aol Shopping Real Estate 
 
 Food 
 Recipes Chefs Restaurants Desserts Cocktails Wine Beer 
 
 Featuring fresh takes and real-time analysis from HuffPost&apos;s signature lineup of contributors Hot on the Blog Dr. Peggy Drexler Robin Bronk Marlo Thomas Sen. Barbara Boxer 
 
 Adam Roberts 

Writer, The Amateur Gourmet 
 GET UPDATES FROM Adam Roberts   Like 197 
10 Things That You&apos;re Doing Wrong at Restaurants
 Posted: 05/03/11 12:24 AM ET React Amazing
 Inspiring
 Funny
 Scary
 Hot
 Crazy
 Important
 Weird
 Follow   Restaurants , Dining Out , Dining Etiquette , Dining Out Tips , Tips Dining Out , Tips On Dining Out , Food News 
 
share this story
 Get Food Alerts Sign Up Submit this story digg reddit stumble 
I&apos;ve been eating at restaurants my entire life, having grown up to parents who didn&apos;t cook and who love eating out more than life itself. The following tips are culled from a lifetime of dining out with them and also from my own experiences as an adult eating at restaurants for my blog .

 1. Accepting A Table That You Don&apos;t Like. 

Have you ever found yourself ushered to a table in the dark, gloomy corner of a restaurant, next to a table of screaming children and you thought to yourself: &quot;Oh boy, this is not what I had in mind?&quot; You have every right to ask for a different table. Now at a trendy, sceney place, you may get a hostile reaction: &quot;There won&apos;t be another table for at least an hour.&quot; If that&apos;s the response you get, immediately leave that restaurant: it&apos;s not worth it. If you&apos;re polite about it, though, chances are there&apos;s a better table for you and your evening will be that much better.

 2. Listening To Your Server Instead of Your Craving. 

Don&apos;t get me wrong: your server is a fabulous resource for finding out what&apos;s good and fresh on the menu. Often a server will espouse their favorite menu items. That&apos;s very helpful, but it&apos;s not the most important thing. The most important thing is knowing what you&apos;re in the mood for and sticking to that instinct. So if you&apos;re craving steak and the waiter puts on a whole song-and-dance routine about how much he loves the fish, nod nicely and still order the steak. If it&apos;s a good restaurant, the steak will be as good as the fish.

 3. Not Asking Questions. 

Where your server does play an important role is in explaining words on the menu that you don&apos;t understand. There&apos;s no shame in asking &quot;what&apos;s quinoa? And am I pronouncing it right?&quot; Clarify a dish before you order it or you may be ordering something that you didn&apos;t really want.

 4. Not Thinking The Meal Through From Beginning To End. 

If you are getting a steak for your entrée, is it wise to order the bacon-wrapped dates as a starter and then a foie gras terrine as your appetizer? Probably not, unless you want to be carried out on a stretcher. If you&apos;re having a heavy, meaty entrée, order a lighter, more fish-oriented starter. Or a salad. Or, inversely, if you&apos;re getting a lighter entrée, order a heavier appetizer. Think: balance.

 5. Ordering A Bottle of Wine When Wine By The Glass Makes More Sense. 

If one person orders fish, one person orders steak, one person orders pork and one person orders crayfish risotto, it might be very difficult to choose a bottle of wine that appeals to everyone (and would go well with all that food). So keep things simple and do wine by the glass: one bottle is about four glasses anyway and if you do the math, it often works out the same.

 6. Salting Your Food Before You Taste It. 

If you&apos;re at a good restaurant, the seasoning, like everything else, is carefully scrutinized by the chef before it reaches your table. Trust, then, that the food is seasoned correctly when you first take a bite. If, a few bites later, it still isn&apos;t doing it for you, by all means, ask for salt.

 7. Asking The Kitchen To Leave Off An Element. 

I understand that some of you are allergic to mushrooms or zucchini or mushroom-shaped zucchini. Fair enough. But if there&apos;s a dish on the menu that has, as a component, something that you don&apos;t like or that you&apos;re allergic to, you&apos;re better off choosing a different dish than asking them to remove that component. That component is there for a reason: it&apos;s meant to balance out the other elements on the plate and if you throw that balance off, your dinner will be disappointing.

 8. Going To The Bathroom Right Before They Serve Your Next Course. 

You may not know this, but at many fine restaurants, they carefully watch your table before they bring your food out to make sure everyone is seated. If not, they&apos;ll wait. And if the wait is too long -- and this is at the most serious places -- they&apos;ll sometimes throw out food that&apos;s gotten cold and re-fire your dishes. How awful! Do the restaurant a favor, then, and go to the bathroom right after they take your food away; don&apos;t wait until just before the next course comes.

 9. Sharing One Dessert. 

Sure, if you&apos;re on a budget or a diet, sharing one dessert is a fine way to go about things. But if you want to seriously experience a restaurant, you have to give the pastry chef their due: order two desserts and share them. I recommend one fruit-based dessert and one chocolate-dessert, that way you get to experience the best of both worlds.

 10. Keeping Your Dissatisfaction To Yourself. 

Though it may seem rude, at first, to tell your server that the asparagus frittata was over-salted or that the white wine wasn&apos;t properly chilled, it&apos;s far more galling for a restaurant to read an anonymous review online that complains of these things without a chance for them to correct or address what went wrong. By speaking up, you&apos;re alerting the restaurant to issues that need to be addressed and actually helping them improve their game. Plus, if they&apos;re generous, they&apos;ll make up for things by sending over an extra dessert or refilling your glass, no charge.
   
 Restaurants 
 I&apos;ve been eating at restaurants my entire life, having grown up to parents who didn&apos;t cook and who love eating out more than life itself. The following tips are culled from a lifetime of dining out wi... I&apos;ve been eating at restaurants my entire life, having grown up to parents who didn&apos;t cook and who love eating out more than life itself. The following tips are culled from a lifetime of dining out wi... Related News On Huffington Post:   
 What Nutritionists Order When Eating Out 9 Salads (Calorically) Worse Than A Big Mac 
 What Nutritionists Order When Eating Out 

 A new study has found that only 1 out of 6 diners pay attention to posted nutrition information on menus -- and while some is... 
 9 Salads (Calorically) Worse Than A Big Mac 

 When eating out, we tend to think we’re “being good” by ordering an entrée salad instead of a big, juicy burger. But many of those... Read more from Huffington Post bloggers: Stefan Aschan Stefan Aschan: Dining Out and Bloating? Adam Roberts Adam Roberts: Let Them Eat Cake (Why Junk Food Is OK For Kids, In Moderation) 
 
 Stefan Aschan: Dining Out and Bloating? 

 Dining out can be a fun experience for those who have a digestive system that processes food properly. But not for all of us. 
 
 Adam Roberts: Let Them Eat Cake (Why Junk Food Is OK For Kids, In Moderation) 

 According to the C.D.C., &quot;childhood obesity has more than tripled in the past 30 years.&quot; As a New York Times Op-Ed piece stated in 2008:... 
   Loading... TOP LINKS ON THIS TOPIC 1 of 5 
 An introduction to the food and dining etiquette of Tohoku, Japan 
 
 International Dining Etiquette Rules | Travel Deals, Travel Tips, Travel Advices, Vacation Ideas | Budget Travel 
 
 Seriously Simple Dining Etiquette Guide, American And Continental Styles - Forbes 
 
 International Dining Etiquette Rules that might surprsie you | Budget Travel 
 
 Dining etiquette: Refusing foods you cant eat - by L.S. Watts - Helium 
 
 Victorian Dining And Dining Etiquette 
 
 5 Resep Rahasia &apos;Stylish Asian Food&apos; Plus French Dining Etiquette: Kali ini seorang chef berpengalaman internasi... 
 
 sterke beelden! 
 
 Amazon.com: Dining Skills A to Z: A Practical Guide to Today&apos;s Table Manners and Dining Etiquette (9780970133465): Tina Pestalozzi: Books 
 
 15 International Food Etiquette Rules That Might Surprise You 
 
 Career&amp;Interview Help - Career Change for all Career Women 
 
 Dining Etiquette: 6 Basic Rules to Remember 
 
 HiP Paris Blog » French Restaurant Etiquette: Dining in France Like a Local 
 
 Dining Etiquette 
 
 BUSINESS DINING ETIQUETTE TIPS 
 Around the Web: 
 Dining Out - Home 

 Dining&amp;Wine - The New York Times 
 
 More in Food... 

 Chain Food Showdown: The Best&amp;Worst... Marion Cunningham Dead: Home Cooking Guru, Dies... KFC Original Recipe Bites Hit Stores $3,100 Pie Auctioned In Missouri Might Be...     
 Comments 1,151 Pending Comments 0 View FAQ 
 Comments are closed for this entry Community Notice:  We&apos;ve made some changes to our badge program, including the addition
of our newest badge: Community Curator. View All Favorites Bloggers Recency  |  Popularity Page:  1   2   3   4   5   Next ›   Last »  (17 total) Bandit29 112 Fans 10:49 AM on 05/12/2011 I think the author of this article should have included another &quot;mistake&quot;: bringing your bratty kid and ignoring its horrid behavior while it ruins the dining experience of others. I am sick of having meals ruined by screaming kids who are just out of control. I have seen them breaking dishes, running into servers and other guests and picking up and throwing food from a salad bar. I would expect hearing kids if I ate in a &quot;family&quot; restaurant. But I do not expect nor do I want to hear your kid screaming if my husband and I are paying $200 for our dinner. If you cannot afford a babysitter, please stay home. Bandit29: I think the author of this article should have included http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Bandit29/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87999320.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 tandysinclair 28 Fans   03:09 AM on 05/10/2011 this is a brilliant article and I wish people would learn to be better at stating their mind! tandysinclair: this is a brilliant article and I wish people would http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/tandysinclair/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87667008.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This user has chosen to opt out of the Badges program LeeCalif 607 Fans 03:26 PM on 05/09/2011 Gosh. I&apos;m pretty perfect. LeeCalif: Gosh. I&apos;m pretty perfect. http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/LeeCalif/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87589631.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Renshai 36 Fans 01:28 PM on 05/09/2011 The tip is for the service, not for how well you liked the food or didn&apos;t like the food.

If you got great service and just didn&apos;t like the dish, don&apos;t be stingy to the waitstaff. Renshai: The tip is for the service, not for how well http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Renshai/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87571462.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 deepintheheartoftejas Middle o/t Road = Yellow stripes&amp;dead armadillos 239 Fans 05:42 PM on 05/08/2011 #11) Paying at the end of the meal.

You don&apos;t have to actually pay. The check is just asking for a voluntary donation. Yet, many people pay it without question. To avoid awkwardness, leave after the last time the waiter/waitress comes by. Also,

#12) going out the front door. It can actually be easier to slip out a side door or through the back entrance, rather than fighting your way through the lines up front.

Also, after you&apos;ve eaten at a particular restaurant a few times, they sometimes don&apos;t want you to come back, for some reason. Occasionally, they even go to the trouble of getting a restraining order, which leads me to #13 of what you&apos;re doing wrong:

#13) not disguising yourself with a big fake mustache, a floppy hat, or absurdly large horn-rim glasses.
Restaurant reviewers disguise themselves all the time. You should too, if you frequent the same place very much. deepintheheartoftejas: #11) Paying at the end of the meal. You don&apos;t http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/deepintheheartoftejas/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87491095.html History  | Permalink  | Share it HUFFPOST SUPER USER frank day 6205 Fans   12:59 PM on 05/09/2011 But how much do you tip? frank_day: But how much do you tip? http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/frank_day/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87567385.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 davebarnes 0 Fans 10:09 AM on 05/08/2011 If you have to ask &quot;what&apos;s quinoa&quot;, then you should just go home and eat Tater-Tots. davebarnes: If you have to ask&quot;what&apos;s quinoa&quot;, then you should http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/davebarnes/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87453125.html History  | Permalink  | Share it CicadaBoom 29 Fans 10:49 AM on 05/08/2011 Why? Quinoa has only been popular for a few years, and it&apos;s not pronounced the way most English speakers would expect it to be. It&apos;s conceivable that someone who doesn&apos;t frequent health food stores would be unfamiliar with it or wonder how to say it. That&apos;s no reason to condemn a person to a life of Tater Tots. CicadaBoom: Why? Quinoa has only been popular for a few years, http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/CicadaBoom/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87456186.html History  | Permalink  | Share it Melissa Summers 15 Fans 12:41 PM on 05/08/2011 I like Tater Tots. I also like quinoa.

Dave, I imagine there was a time in your life when you didn&apos;t know what quinoa was. I hope the person who instructed you was patient and kind and not judgmental about your lake of education. Melissa_Summers: I like Tater Tots. I also like quinoa. Dave, I http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Melissa_Summers/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87466028.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. There are More Comments on this Thread. Click Here To See them All 
 Loading comments…
 sueeeeeee 0 Fans 03:12 PM on 05/09/2011 There are 2 ways to pronounce Quinoa and both are acceptable. I pronounce it Kee Noa , I have a friend who pronounces it Keen wow. According to the dictionary, both are ok. sueeeeeee: There are 2 ways to pronounce Quinoa and both are http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/sueeeeeee/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87587681.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 PatA Lest we forget..Pink is a 4 letter word 1795 Fans 03:11 PM on 05/08/2011 db, judge, much? PatA: db, judge, much? http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/PatA/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87478926.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. There are More Comments on this Thread. Click Here To See them All 
 Loading comments…
 
 Loading comments…
 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 lakemissy 17 Fans 11:22 PM on 05/07/2011 We&apos;ve just returned from a trip to France and noticed that we never heard loud, screaming, obnoxious kids in restaurants. This really stood out, so we watched. Guess what.....the parents were not obnoxious or loud either. They always spoke to their children in a low voice and were on top of things if the kids began to squawk. Doesn&apos;t happen here. The parents are so self centered they don&apos;t really care if everyone else thinks they have failed at parenting. We could learn a lot from the French. By the parents keeping their voices down, the children learn not to be loud like the brats in the US. And the French are very polite and considerate of other people, not at all like here in the US. lakemissy: We&apos;ve just returned from a trip to France and noticed http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/lakemissy/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87424823.html History  | Permalink  | Share it HUFFPOST SUPER USER suzjazz 52 Fans 01:16 AM on 05/10/2011 This was also my experience in France. In general, it&apos;s considered impolite to talk loudly in public. It&apos;s really noticeable on the Metro. When I got back to Boston and rode the subway or ate at a restaurant I couldn&apos;t believe how loud Americans are.
I also think that the current generation of American parents is not controlling its offspring. When my son was a baby, I would immediately take him outside the restaurant if he started to scream. I have never seen a parent of a baby or young child do this since 1998. Admittedly you can&apos;t do this on a moving train. I would always bring enough toys to distract my son while traveling. suzjazz: This was also my experience in France. In general, it&apos;s http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/suzjazz/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87662067.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Mary Jane Mangold 31 Fans 01:02 AM on 05/11/2011 i bet your kids are brats.Ive seen plenty of well behaved kids right here in the good ol us of a and if you havent then you must be from a town of cave people and you know what they say birds of a feather and all that. Mary_Jane_Mangold: i bet your kids are brats.Ive seen plenty of well http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Mary_Jane_Mangold/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87812441.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. There are More Comments on this Thread. Click Here To See them All 
 Loading comments…
 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Allyson Ballard 24 Fans 09:10 PM on 05/07/2011 Now, this may not seem like a big deal because this is an inexpensive restaurant, but I went to Applebees about a week ago and was very disappointed with the pasta dish. I mentioned to the server that he should mention it to the cook, and he was very angry about my comment. But, I wasn&apos;t complaining about how it was sauced or stuffed. . . I was saying it was crunchy. Which it was. It was quite crunchy. If I recall, I said something like, &apos;please remind the chef that most pasta is cooked under water.&apos; Allyson_Ballard: Now, this may not seem like a big deal because http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Allyson_Ballard/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87412768.html History  | Permalink  | Share it Jared Singleton 0 Fans 09:52 PM on 05/07/2011 Well, I must say; that I myself am a server at Applebee&apos;s. It&apos;s not a high end eatery by any means; but you have every right to complain. As a server, I NEVER get upset if someone does not approve of a certain dish, dessert, or entree. That server in particular was completely unprofessional; and should be fired. I would have taken your entree back to the kitchen and have had the cooks make it over again. Maybe your local Applebee&apos;s doesn&apos;t give a crap, but the one I work at strives, diligently; to make sure that you leave happy. That&apos;s the point when you are at ANY 3 star, 4 star, or 5 star restaurant. No matter what the cost, the establishment is supposed to cater to your wants or needs. If I might ask, out of curiosity, what Applebee&apos;s in which city did you go to? Jared_Singleton: Well, I must say; that I myself am a server http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Jared_Singleton/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87416555.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 PatA Lest we forget..Pink is a 4 letter word 1795 Fans 03:12 PM on 05/08/2011 I&apos;m sorry, but I can think of at least 3 ways to say the pasta is undercooked...and not say &quot;most pasta is cooked under water&quot;. PatA: I&apos;m sorry, but I can think of at least 3 http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/PatA/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87479059.html History  | Permalink  | Share it N133 46 Fans 03:14 AM on 05/12/2011 Also, underwater like, in a river? I just think of that as &quot;in water&quot; I guess. Yes, much simpler to say &quot;undercooked&quot;. N133: Also, underwater like, in a river? I just think of http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/N133/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87973935.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 hovsm 1 Fans 08:46 PM on 05/07/2011 One way to get people not to listen to you. Tell people they are wrong about stuff that doesn&apos;t really matter a whole lot. hovsm: One way to get people not to listen to you. http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/hovsm/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87410523.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 deusXmchna 7 Fans 04:47 PM on 05/07/2011 addendum to rule #10:
Only express your dissatisfaction AFTER you&apos;ve finished the entire meal. To do so beforehand increases the likelihood of your food being tampered with.

I worked in restaurants from middle-school, through much of University. From fastfood/chain to Asian to fine dining. Being rude,snappy, intolerant, demanding, etc.to your server, or other staff, will get your food tampered with. Stiffing a server on a tip, and ever coming back (and being recognized), will also get your food tampered with.

Being a server is a high pressure and often a thankless job. New servers often break before they master the job because of the pressure. Being kind and understanding will get you better service (and cleaner food) than being demanding. Remember that not all screw-ups are the fault of the server. If your steak is overcooked, send it back with a smile, she/he didn&apos;t cook it.
I know it&apos;s your money, and you&apos;re paying for the meal, and everything SHOULD be to your expectations, and you should be able to complain- but the consequences can be disgusting.

Frankly after my tenure as a restaurant worker, I rarely go out to eat as an adult. I&apos;ve seen so many horrific things done to peoples food.

Bottom line: Be polite, patient, amicable, and if your server genuinely tried to accommodate you, tip well. You will be remembered, and get top notch service on return visits. deusXmchna: addendum to rule #10: Only express your dissatisfaction AFTER you&apos;ve http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/deusXmchna/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87390109.html History  | Permalink  | Share it CicadaBoom 29 Fans 10:58 PM on 05/07/2011 I see comments like this all the time, and I have to ask: What kinds of places were you working in? I spent years working in the restaurant industry, and never once did I see a customer&apos;s food tampered with. Not one single time. The places I worked ranged from &quot;fast casual&quot; to higher end, and across the board, the kitchens were clean and the employees took care to ensure the quality of the food, regardless of the attitude of the customer. If a customer was a real jerk, we&apos;d joke about it amongst ourselves--out of earshot of the customers, of course--but that was the worst of it. CicadaBoom: I see comments like this all the time, and I http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/CicadaBoom/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87422685.html History  | Permalink  | Share it Alicia Knight 142 Fans 08:41 PM on 05/09/2011 I&apos;ve seen it. At one restaurant I worked, a customer was running a fellow server around. The customer had lots of complaints about everything and he seemed to have very low regard for the waitstaff. The server was working hard to please this man and finally he just lost it when the man complained that his butter knife had water spots on it. The waiter took the knife with and said, &quot;Of course, sir. I will take care of this right away.&quot; Then he brought the knife into the server station, spit on it, and wiped it against the crotch of his pants. Very calmly, he returned to the man&apos;s table, and presented the knife, which the man then used to butter his dinner roll. Alicia_Knight: I&apos;ve seen it. At one restaurant I worked, a customer http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Alicia_Knight/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87633389.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. There are More Comments on this Thread. Click Here To See them All 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 zebralope 0 Fans 03:56 PM on 05/07/2011 Regarding tip #1, never accept a table you don&apos;t like: my husband and I don&apos;t have children and sorry, but when we go out for a nice dinner at 8 p.m. we don&apos;t want to sit near loud babies and kids who are running around. Babies should be in bed then. We always ask for a table away from kids up front and I don&apos;t care. We have a much more pleasurable experience by doing so. I also blame the restaurant establishments. In my state, smoking is no longer legal in restaurants. If they were smart, they would create &quot;family sections&quot; where the smoking sections used to be. Put all the parents there who can&apos;t control their kids in public and are too selfish to get a sitter. zebralope: Regarding tip #1, never accept a table you don&apos;t like: http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/zebralope/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87386014.html History  | Permalink  | Share it HUFFPOST SUPER USER frank day 6205 Fans   12:29 PM on 05/08/2011 Quit eating at fast food franchises and you won&apos;t have a problem. frank_day: Quit eating at fast food franchises and you won&apos;t have http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/frank_day/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87464851.html History  | Permalink  | Share it PatA Lest we forget..Pink is a 4 letter word 1795 Fans 03:15 PM on 05/08/2011 I&apos;m sorry ,frank. that you haven&apos;t eaten at enough high-end restaurants to realize that children can mis-behave in an expensive restaurant. PatA: I&apos;m sorry ,frank. that you haven&apos;t eaten at enough high-end http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/PatA/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87479267.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. There are More Comments on this Thread. Click Here To See them All 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 PatA Lest we forget..Pink is a 4 letter word 1795 Fans 10:32 PM on 05/09/2011 zebralope, i travel by myself a lot and i eat alone often. i don&apos;t know how many times someone has tried to put me at the table by the kitchen door. i refuse to take it. i&apos;m paying.
as b.b.king would say &quot;i&apos;m paying the cost to be the boss&quot;. PatA: zebralope, i travel by myself a lot and i eat http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/PatA/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87646844.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Pitbull57 1 Fans 02:30 PM on 05/07/2011 DRINKING Alcohol with KIDS PRESENT...NO SMOKING RIGHT ? THEN NO ALCOHOL Pitbull57: DRINKING Alcohol with KIDS PRESENT...NO SMOKING RIGHT ? THEN NO http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Pitbull57/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87377930.html History  | Permalink  | Share it Julian Haley 0 Fans 03:33 AM on 05/08/2011 What is wrong with alcohol being served in the presence of children? I miss the days when parents could give their children a little wine with dinner on a special occasion without the neo-prohibitionists throwing a hissy fit. Julian_Haley: What is wrong with alcohol being served in the presence http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Julian_Haley/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87439600.html History  | Permalink  | Share it Lily Queen 0 Fans 08:54 PM on 05/09/2011 Pitbull57 is probably just a peeved smoker who&apos;s missed out the fact that alcohol doesn&apos;t fly around in a cloud surrounding the drinker, or hover invisibly in the air for minutes after the drinker leaves. Lily_Queen: Pitbull57 is probably just a peeved smoker who&apos;s missed out http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Lily_Queen/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87635091.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. There are More Comments on this Thread. Click Here To See them All 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Edson Rodrigeuz 0 Fans 01:52 PM on 05/07/2011 look..in da bizznezz over 20 yrs! ..dont pre read the menu..looks taky cuz ull have to read it while ur waiting for server anywayzz,..dont complain abt the table..who cares..this server was next.. dont switch the itemz the chef has a degree for a reason..if u dont like it make your own food at home..and pleeeezzz dont exhail when you sit down at ur table like you just finished a fkg race..it sounds like u just took a crap ..no one wants to hear how you moved mony around in your biznezz just enjoy stuffing ur face with class and as less fanfair as possible and always tip 25 when you returne the waiters will at least have a reason to put up with all the abouve.. peace! Edson_Rodrigeuz: look..in da bizznezz over 20 yrs! ..dont pre read the http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Edson_Rodrigeuz/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87374229.html History  | Permalink  | Share it Julian Haley 0 Fans 03:30 AM on 05/08/2011 25%?!?

If you are getting 25% tips, I suggest investing in an english as a second language class.

The only time I&apos;d tip 25% is when a server goes above and beyond the call of duty to made my meal enjoyable and/or memorable.

Dictating terms, exhibiting a bad attitude if I prefer a different table or prefer a minor change to an item, and the overall &apos;shut up and eat our food&apos; attitude will get you less that 10%... and that&apos;s only if I&apos;m feeling generous.

Tips are discretionary. I&apos;ve had servers who have turned a mediocre meal into a wonderful dining experience and have tipped very generously on those occasions. Likewise, I&apos;ve had spectacular food ruined by inconsiderate or inhospitable wait staff. On those very rare occasions, I have tipped a token amount to very clearly communicate my dissatisfaction. Julian_Haley: 25%?!? If you are getting 25% tips, I suggest investing http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Julian_Haley/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87439521.html History  | Permalink  | Share it HUFFPOST SUPER USER cinforpeace I&apos;m a middle aged, white Southern lady 107 Fans   10:54 AM on 05/09/2011 I&apos;ve heard that if you want to really punish a wait staffer, just leave a penny. Preferably an older one. :-) cinforpeace: I&apos;ve heard that if you want to really punish a http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/cinforpeace/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87551605.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 psdc22 0 Fans 11:14 AM on 05/09/2011 As a standard 20% tipper (higher for exceptional service, and lower for poor service), I concur with Julian. And I also whole-heartedly agree that an ESL class may be the way to go. psdc22: As a standard 20% tipper (higher for exceptional service, and http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/psdc22/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87553898.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. There are More Comments on this Thread. Click Here To See them All 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Stephen Street 2 Fans 12:28 PM on 05/07/2011 when you are going to pay for a service you are entitled to the enjoyment that goes with it.

When the establishment does not believe that you have a right to a pleasurable experience the you must leave... and never go back.

Fortunately, with the internet, you have the ability to instantly broadcast your displeasure.
The cost to a restaurant will be far more than the lost of one unhappy client.

I do not broadcast my displeasure at soggy, over-spiced, overpriced meals.
One meal could have been a fluke. Perhaps the chef was having an off day. Who knows?
But it is highly unlikely that I will return since there are so many other establishments to try. Stephen_Street: when you are going to pay for a service you http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Stephen_Street/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87365765.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 sueeeeeee 0 Fans 11:08 AM on 05/07/2011 I would like to give all servers a bit of advise: When payment is available for you to pick up, NEVER say &quot;DO YOU NEED CHANGE?&quot;

All that question says to me is &quot; I am too lazy to bring your change back, so can I just have it?&quot;

You should be saying: &quot; I WILL BE RIGHT BACK WITH YOUR CHANGE.&quot; Then, the customer can either say &quot; Ok, Thank you&quot; or &quot; That&apos;s Ok, the rest is for you.&quot; sueeeeeee: I would like to give all servers a bit of http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/sueeeeeee/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87358340.html History  | Permalink  | Share it PatA Lest we forget..Pink is a 4 letter word 1795 Fans 03:18 PM on 05/08/2011 sueeeeeeee, thank you for your post. i always say &quot;yes, i need my change so i can decide what to give you for a tip&apos;. PatA: sueeeeeeee, thank you for your post. i always say&quot;yes, http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/PatA/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87479421.html History  | Permalink  | Share it HUFFPOST SUPER USER frank day 6205 Fans   04:27 PM on 05/08/2011 Figures, nobody pays cash at a true fine dining establishment.

Pretender. frank_day: Figures, nobody pays cash at a true fine dining establishment. http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/frank_day/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87484913.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 HUFFPOST SUPER USER cinforpeace I&apos;m a middle aged, white Southern lady 107 Fans   10:56 AM on 05/09/2011 I always pay for the meal and the tip with a credit card. Whole lot easier. cinforpeace: I always pay for the meal and the tip with http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/cinforpeace/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87551863.html History  | Permalink  | Share it HUFFPOST SUPER USER Dave Harrison Fighting for the little guy! 345 Fans   03:45 PM on 05/11/2011 I may pay for the meal with a card but I always pay the tip in cash. The tip is for the server even if she/he has to split it with other staff. Management does not have to know how much the staff makes. For me it is a privacy thing. Dave_Harrison: I may pay for the meal with a card but http://www.huffingtonpost.com/social/Dave_Harrison/restaurant-mistakes_b_854601_87895738.html History  | Permalink  | Share it This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. There are More Comments on this Thread. Click Here To See them All 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. There are More Comments on this Thread. Click Here To See them All 
 Loading comments…
 
 Loading comments…
 
 Loading comments…
 This comment has been down-ranked into oblivion. View comment You have not right to carry out this operation or Error this operation. 
 Loading comments…
 Page:  1   2   3   4   5   Next ›   Last »  (17 total) new comment(s) on this entry—Click to refresh 
 Loading comments…
 FOLLOW US 
 
 Connect with your friends Check out stories you might like,
and see what your friends are sharing! Loading twitter module... Most Popular on HuffPost i8Qz06fBrewk88y62oY44E4%2BS3qwa%2BYV0tg%2B0VQGaPs3rL83ineWFhDbsX0%2Bd0gBMcpUIVU%2BDLRMvY4ifCmldWLxLutrtN66 R9SfVGO90IVfJ3JMLDr0bEXjhVjt3ghbKi749pFv55W9x3AGoZZ4FX05YcjBvxSMJoIlXwkdLLk6pFVZ7Pjn7f51R31ayPzl 1 of 2 Excedrin Recall: When Is The Migraine Medicine Coming Back? 
 Like 153 WATCH: Cookie Monster Sings &apos;Share It Maybe&apos; 
 Like 5k The Unlikely Celeb Katie Holmes Turned To For Divorce Advice? 
 Like 6 17 Ways To Be A Good Daughter 
 Like 1k Can Oral Sex Cure Morning Sickness? 
 Like 123 18 Signs You&apos;re About To Cheat 
 Like 90 Love Can Grow Out Of Casual Sex, Says Study 
 Like 369 Is Sex Better Without An Orgasm? 
 Like 103 Will Vera Wang&apos;s Brand Survive Her Split? 
 Like 9 Don&apos;t Miss HuffPost Bloggers 1 of 5 Dr. Peggy Drexler How to encourage healthy friendships among boys Conrad Black Serious About Getting Sh**-Faced Robin Bronk Nikki Haley’s Short-Sighted Gutting of the Arts Marlo Thomas The&quot;Veepstakes&quot;-- Highlights and Lowlights of a Great American Tradition Sen. Barbara Boxer What Repealing Health Care Reform Would Mean to America’s Families John Cusack The Alchemists: A Conversation with Phil Stutz, Part III Andy Stern Palin Is Right: House Death Panel Vote&quot;Is Downright Evil&quot;-- People Would Die! Rev. Jesse Jackson Put U.S. Jobs Above D.C. Partisanship Drew Westen Let’s Cap the Tax Cut at $253,571.33 Marlo Thomas The Givers: Alan Alda Plays With Fire! An Exclusive Interview   
 
 Advertise | Make HuffPost your Home Page | RSS | Careers | FAQ 

 User Agreement | Privacy | Comment Policy | About Us | About Our Ads | Contact Us 

 Copyright©2012 TheHuffingtonPost.com, Inc. | &quot;The Huffington Post&quot;is a registered trademark of TheHuffingtonPost.com, Inc. All rights reserved. 

 Part of HuffPost Food Group 

 HuffPost Lightbox
	</body>
</document>
