<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002315" url="http://www.autonet.ca/auto-news/automotive-industry-news/2012/04/12/pitfalls-of-auto-technology/" time="2012-07-12-18:14" support="2" score="0.0013073355739685471" bingtitle="Pitfalls of auto technology" webtitle="Pitfalls of auto technology">
			<query id="000550" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="001462" bing-rank="136"/>
	<description>I agree with both posters but getting the car within a few blocks of home is a good deal. Usually a fast food restaurant or the like. It would be fun to use the address ...</description>
	<body>
		Autonet.ca 
 My Garage 0 Car saved Car saved Cars saved 

 Toronto, ON Change City Français 

 Home New Cars Used Cars Reviews News 
 Automotive Industry New Car Models Eco-Friendly News Car Finance&amp;Insurance Motorcycle My Mechanic Recalls Photo Galleries 
 Auto Shows Blogs Video 
 
 Autonet.ca Home Auto News Car Finance&amp;Insurance Pitfalls of auto technology 
 
Car Finance&amp;Insurance
 Autonet.ca - Search 
Pitfalls of auto technology
 April 12th, 2012 - Joe Duarte 
Story is a cautionary tale for any of us who have programmed our residence in our vehicles’ navigation systems.
 
 Thieves steal car, burglarize home 

With the amount of technology in today’s vehicles, it was only a matter of time before criminal minds put it to use for their clandestine activities.

A recent stolen vehicle recovery in Medina, Wash., demonstrates how today’s car thieves are using in-vehicle technology, such as GPS navigation systems, to find an owner’s residence, break in and burglarize it. Fortunately for the owners in this situation, the 2012 Lexus GX 460 sport utility vehicle was equipped with an aftermarket anti-theft system–the LoJack Stolen Vehicle Recovery System–which enabled police to find the vehicle and apprehend the thieves in just a little over an hour after the vehicle was reported stolen.

While the Lexus owner was having lunch at a restaurant, thieves stole the Lexus she had purchased less than two weeks prior. When she left the restaurant and discovered her vehicle missing, she immediately reported the theft to police, who entered the data into the state crime computer, activating the LoJack System. Approximately one hour later, on the tracking computer installed in a patrol car, an officer with the Medina Police Department received the silent LoJack homing signal from the stolen Lexus. He quickly located the car abandoned on the street, not far from the owner’s residence. When the owner arrived at her residence, she discovered her home had been burglarized and realized the thieves had gained access through the garage by using the opener in her car. Police apprehended the suspects.

“This recovery story is a cautionary tale for any of us who have programmed our residence as ‘Home’ in our vehicles’ navigation systems,” said Patrick Clancy, Vice President, Law Enforcement, LoJack Corporation. “While this may be a great convenience, it can also make crime more convenient for thieves, enabling them to easily hit the home button, find the owner’s house, enter it with a garage door opener (in many cases part of the features already) inside the vehicle and ransack the premises.”

  
Tags: anti-theft , GX 460 , Lexus , navigation , thieves 
 
More in Car Finance&amp;Insurance

 Auto insurance satisfaction Auto insurance premiums Fighting insurance fraud Ford Mustang Personal insurance right in your trunk Canada&apos;s most-stolen vehicles 
 
17 comments

 Jack Pontiac says: 12 April 2012 at 16 h 04 min 

Your‘Home’Address to program into your GPS system would the the Closest COP SHOP nearest where you Live!

LOL !
 Ian says: 12 April 2012 at 16 h 08 min 

My GPS has a code entered to prevent this sort of thing.

My wife’s came with her Nissan and has no code option so“home”is a park blocks from our home.

Guess I’m also lucky in that my garage is detached from the house.
 Brad in Canada says: 12 April 2012 at 16 h 49 min 

I agree with both posters but getting the car within a few blocks of home is a good deal. Usually a fast food restaurant or the like. It would be fun to use the address of the Dome. That would mess up a thief big time.
 MissC says: 12 April 2012 at 17 h 12 min 

Makes me glad I don’t have a GPS unit or a garage! lol
 Deanomite says: 12 April 2012 at 17 h 17 min 

Gee, how did people ever find their way home in the pre-GPS days (which wasn’t that long ago)?

Too much technology in today’s plastic vehicles, turning many drivers into mindless drones who can’t think for themselves. Not to mention the added cost on the purchase price and potential for more things to go wrong with increasingly complex vehicles.

I’ll stick with my 25 year old daily driver, thank you very much. My GPS is between my ears, and for those really tricky situations, folded up in the glove box.
 Homer says: 12 April 2012 at 17 h 35 min 

Why the hell do you need your home saved on GPS within your own city, or town. Unless you just moved in you should know your area well enough to get home with your own route.
 S. Wolf says: 12 April 2012 at 18 h 23 min 

The real problem with all this automotive tech is that it markedly increases the chances of something going wrong or otherwise breaking down and needing expensive/time consuming repairs down the line. It’s one of the major reasons why I’m still driving my’92 Mazda. No bells and whistles, just a simple, solid, reliable vehicle. What more could I want? Certainly not something which beeps, honks, flashes or sings La Marseillaise when I lock or unlock it, or pretends to know the way home through traffic better than I do.
 Jack Pontiac says: 13 April 2012 at 18 h 01 min 

Or even better than using the Cop Shop as your address, would be the Local HELLS ANGELS Chapter Clubhouse! Then a‘spanking’! LOL!
 Jonno says: 18 April 2012 at 1 h 31 min 

99% of people leave their insurance papers in their vehicles with their home address on it. No GPS receiver necessary.
 Russ says: 18 April 2012 at 7 h 47 min 

Criminals figured this out along time ago!!!

The MO was to target people attending funerals.
 Ricardo valuzenlua says: 18 April 2012 at 10 h 11 min 

I programmed my GPS to go to the nearest jail.
 James says: 18 April 2012 at 10 h 23 min 

And?

Your Insurance Papers are (manditorily–in many jurisdictions) required to be in the vehicle, and also have the home address of the RO of the vehicle…
Simpler to keep the garage door opener (for a woman) in her purse…safer too.
 Corey says: 18 April 2012 at 10 h 26 min 

Can we stop carrying our insurance and registration now too, that might lead them criminals to our houses too
 Will says: 18 April 2012 at 13 h 40 min 

Yes, but if you leave your insurance papers in the car, they have your address anyways.
 Anny says: 18 April 2012 at 15 h 59 min 

What would you say about this, my car was stolen once right from my driveway.
 Max says: 18 April 2012 at 17 h 33 min 

This was a pointless article, as many commenters have noted insurance/registration document in the vehicle already have an address. In most cities you hardly need an AtoZ to find the home.
 Clair says: 18 April 2012 at 20 h 35 min 

this is highly overated, Lexus is not the only brand of vehicle with the new lojack system, and whar kind of word is lo jack anyway, stolen vehicle is built in many onstar gm vehicle, and some other brands as well, this technology is not new Its at least five years old. This is just sensationalism at its peak, wanting people to be terrified of using technology. Realistically when was the last time you heard of a smart criminal using technology to break into a house, do you know how much time that takes?
 
 
Leave a comment
 Click here to cancel reply. 
 Name (required) 

 E-Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 

 

 

 I accept terms of service . 
 
 
Our Experts

 Click on a picture for info 
 

 
Contribute to news

 Netiquette Terms of Service 
 

 
Automotive Industry News

 Institute ranks safety systems Traffic congestion study F1 McLaren-Mercedes toons up What your car colour says about you Chevy Confidence Program Land Rover Adventures 2012 Jeep Grand Cherokee 
 Automotive Industry News Archives 

 
New Car Models

 2013 Lexus LS 2013 Mitsubishi Mirage Bentley EXP 9 F Mazda MX-5 Mini Paceman 2013 Nissan Sentra McLaren enhances MP4-12 
 New Car Models Archives 

 
Eco-Friendly News

 Toyota named top Green brand Companies ready hydrogen vehicles New diesel emission standards Mazda SkyActiv plans for Le Mans Hybrids dominate Le Mans qualifying BMW i3 Honda Fit EV tops in economy 
 Eco-Friendly News Archives 

 
Car Finance&amp;Insurance

 Auto insurance satisfaction Pitfalls of auto technology Auto insurance premiums Fighting insurance fraud Ford Mustang Personal insurance right in your trunk Canada’s most-stolen vehicles 
 Car Finance&amp;Insurance Archives 

 
Motorcycle

 Brammo Empulse electric motorcycles 10 awesome movie motorcycles 10 of the most beautiful sport bikes Top 10 Motorcycle Stunts The ABCs of motorcycle security equipment 10 most expensive motorcycles in the world 
 Motorcycle Archives 

 
My Mechanic

 The Mechanic: The implications of replacing components The Mechanic: car warranty The Mechanic: to fix or not to fix The Mechanic: car lifespan The Mechanic: tires The Mechanic: good ol’days The Mechanic: car connectedness 
 My Mechanic Archives 

 

 

 
Vehicle Recalls Canada

 GULF STREAM COACH issued a ... PORSCHE issued a recall on ... TURTLE TOP issued a recall ... NOVA BUS issued a recall ... 
 See more 

 
Photo Galleries

 Autonet’s best family vehicles Lame gimmicks used in vehicles World’s most expensive cars Celebrities who endorse vehicles 
 Photo Galleries 
 Autonet.ca NEWSLETTER SUBSCRIBE or Unsubscribe NEW CARS 
 NEW CARS NEW SUVS NEW TRUCKS NEW VANS 
 USED VEHICLES 
 USED CARS USED SUVS USED TRUCKS USED VANS 
 News 
 Automotive Industry New Car Models Eco-Friendly News Car Finance&amp;Insurance Vehicle Recalls Canada Photo Galleries 
 CAR REVIEWS 
 NEW MODELS TEST DRIVES USED CARS 
 TOOLS 
 CAR APPRAISAL CAR DEALERSHIPS COMPARE CARS 
 BLOGS VIDEOS FOLLOW US 
 FACEBOOK RSS TWITTER YOUTUBE 
 ADVERTISE WITH US CONTACT US 
 Find Help on Autonet.ca Privacy Policy 

Autonet.ca is a leading voice for everything automotive in Canada with exclusive car news, reviews and videos, comprehensive new car information and used car listings from across Canada. Autonet content also appears in print in more than 200 newspapers across Canada through Bowes Publishing, Osprey Media and Sun Media.

Copyright © 1995 - 2012 Autonet.ca All rights reserved.
 Autonet is a member of the canoe network 
Protection and respect of your privacy on the Canoe Network

The Canoe Network appreciates the concerns you may have with respect to the circulation of personal information on the Internet and, with your collaboration, wishes to address these issues. This is why we feel it is important that you fully understand the type of information we collect from you when visiting our Web sites along with its intended use. Please read the following sections carefully. We also strongly suggest that you refer to this section periodically for changes or updates. Please be assured that the Canoe Network will not collect any personal information without your prior consent .

The collection and processing of personal information

When?

The collection and processing of personal information takes place under very precise conditions and at specific times. When registering for our various personalized e-mail services, or for participating in online contests, the Canoe Network requests that you enter your name, postal address, e-mail and other personal information by filling out an online form. At these very specific times, and prior to entry, the Canoe Network will explicitly advise you that the information that you are about to submit will be processed and be subject to a host of data collection practices including saving, storing, editing, detailing, archiving and destruction. The Canoe Network also provides, within reasonable limits, means to verify the accuracy and to update your personal information. As well, on certain online forms, the Canoe Network asks you if you wish to receive information on other services, contests or news about the Canoe Network and its partners. You are always given the option to decline such offers or to end your subscription to a previously requested service.

Why?

The collection of personal information allows the Canoe Network to provide services relevant to your needs and, in the event that you win one of our contests, it allows us to reach you. It also allows us to send you, from time to time, requested information by e-mail.

The length of time the CANOE Network retains your personal information will vary depending upon the rules and requirements of each individual contest, promotion, or activity.

Who?

It is important to note that the CANOE Network will never disclose your personal information with sponsors, advertisers, partners and other clients. Your personal information can only be accessed by the CANOE Network. If ever we request information for another purpose, you will be automatically and explicitly informed at the time such information is requested.

We will never disclose any personal information to parties outside of the CANOE Network without your explicit prior consent. Furthermore, please be advised that all personal information collected by the CANOE Network is stored in server sectors that are inaccessible to the public.

Despite the above, at any time, you may request that the CANOE Network end its use or planned use of your personal information.

In summary, the following are the only times at which the CANOE Network may disclose your personal information: upon request by a legal authority or in good faith when such action is deemed necessary (a) in order to abide by applicable laws or regulations or to intervene in a lawsuit against the CANOE Network, (b) in order to protect or defend the legal or property rights of the CANOE Network or those of its users, and (c) to intervene, under extreme circumstances, in order to protect the personal safety of CANOE Network users or the safety of the general public.

Opting-out

You can opt-out of providing personal information and from receiving information on CANOE Network updates and new services, as well as direct email offers from selected CANOE Network partners and sponsors. This is done at the point of initial collection of information and during the editing or updating process. The process to opt out of most CANOE Network email materials is the same as the process for updating user information profiles described above. In addition, all such email materials have easy-to-follow unsubscribe directions posted at the bottom of the email. If you have any questions or concerns, please contact us.

Be careful!

The CANOE Network contains links to third-party Web sites, these are provided solely for your convenience. Clicking on these links will take you outside of the CANOE Network. Please be advised that the CANOE Network has no control over these third-party sites and, while the CANOE Network may feature such links, the CANOE Network will not, at any time, accept liability for these sites. Consequently, personal information that you provide to a Web site outside of the CANOE Network is subject to the privacy protection policies of the given third-party site. In the event of abuse by such sites, the CANOE Network cannot, at any time, be held responsible. Therefore, we strongly urge you to carefully read the privacy protection policies of all third-party sites you choose to enter.

We also wish to inform you that the risks associated with the supplying of personal information in a chat room, via e-mail or on a Web-based message board are not covered by our privacy protection policy, thus, you must be extremely careful if you choose to supply personal information through these means. You are submitting this information at your own risk. Indeed, this information may be collected and used by third parties without your prior consent. In other words, if you choose to provide personal information online and this information is available to the public, you may, eventually, receive unsolicited e-mail from third parties. The CANOE Network declines all responsibility in this regard. We urge you to remain cautious and vigilant, at all times, on the Internet.

Security

The CANOE Network has set up security measures to protect you from the loss or unauthorized use of your supplied personal information. As well, our CANOE Network servers are equipped with firewall technology. Despite these measures, and given that no technology is foolproof, we must advise you that there will always remain a certain amount of risk and that your personal information may be disclosed, without your consent, unintentionally, and without fault on the part of the CANOE Network. The CANOE Network declines any responsibility in the event that such confidential information is disclosed, unless caused by negligence on the part of the CANOE Network.

Protection of children and teens on the Internet

Children and teenagers are increasingly using the Internet and discovering its many advantages. However, as is the case in many other environments, their greater vulnerability may be targeted for crime and exploitation. This is why we urge you to monitor the Internet use of your children and teenagers and provide them with advice on security and recommendations based on common sense. Such measures will often prevent your children and teenagers from being exposed to offensive content, or from becoming victims of harassment or other criminal acts.

To reduce these risks, as a parent, you should exercise a reasonable amount of supervision of Internet use by your children and teenagers. They should be told to never give out their personal information, such as their name, address or phone number, on any Internet forum.

It is also important that children and teenagers be encouraged to share their concerns with you in the event that they receive disturbing or provocative messages.

These recommendations will help your children and teenagers surf the Internet in an informed fashion and allow you to ensure that they fully benefit from the learning and development possibilities that exist online.

&quot;Cookies&quot;

What is a cookie?

&quot;Cookies&quot; are little bits of information that are sent to your computer when you visit a Web site. They are saved, either temporarily or permanently, on your hard drive, leaving a trace of your passage. The information can include such things as the date and time of your last visit, a given answer to an online question, personal information, etc. Cookies can also enhance your Web experience by recording your navigation preferences for a given Web site.

The use of cookies on the Web has become standard practice. Most Internet browsers will accept them by default. If you so choose, you may, at any time, change your parameters to disallow the use of cookies. However, in doing so, you will be unable to access the full features of certain sites.

It should be noted that the actual cookie files stored on your hard drive are harmless. They may be read and deleted at any time. Thus, you always have complete control.

The use of cookies on the CANOE Network

On the one hand, the CANOE Network uses cookies to monitor traffic, anonymously, on its Web sites. It allows us to estimate the size of our audience.

Each visitor is assigned a unique cookie, for a temporary period of six (6) hours that allows us to determine the total number of repeat visits to the CANOE Network.

While the information cannot be used to identify a visitor, cookies provide important data for our marketing department. Indeed, this information enables us to inform our sponsors of the total number of visitors for each of our sites and the length of each visit. In turn, it allows our sponsors to estimate or measure the probable or actual impact of their ads. It also allows us to determine our ad rates. While this information helps our sponsors buy ad space, it does not allow them to identify you individually.

On the other hand, the CANOE Network uses cookies to offer you personalized services such as speciality content, personalized bulletins, etc. To access these services, the CANOE Network asks that you complete an online form, supplying certain personal information along with your online content preferences. Upon registration, and by allowing us to remember your password, a cookie file is created and stored on your computer, enabling us to &quot;recognize&quot; you every time you visit one of our sites.

Personal information collected by the CANOE Network is used for the sole purpose of offering you relevant content, tools and advertising based on your indicated preferences, allowing you to make the most of our services each time you visit one of our sites. Your information stays exclusively within the CANOE Network and is, at no time, shared with clients, partners, sponsors or other outside parties.

We hope that this information has provided you with a better understanding of our strict privacy protection policies. Please note that the CANOE Network reserves the right to modify these policies at any time. Thus, we invite you to periodically consult this section for possible updates and changes.
	</body>
</document>
