<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002220" url="http://3docean.net/item/dining-room-04-set-a-fast-food-restaurant/478345" time="2012-07-12-18:07" support="4" score="0.005585821671428947" bingtitle="3D Models - Dining room 04 Set - a fast food restaurant. | 3DOcean" webtitle="3D Models - Dining room 04 Set - a fast food restaurant. | 3DOcean">
			<query id="001053" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="001064" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="001021" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="001047" bing-rank="22"/>
	<description>Become an Author; Payment Rates ... Cars; HDRI Images ... from this set can be used for the interior fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		ActiveDen Flash and Unity 3D AudioJungle Stock Music and Audio ThemeForest Website Templates VideoHive Motion Graphics GraphicRiver Graphics, Vectors and Print 3DOcean 3D Models and Materials CodeCanyon Code, Plugins and Mobile Tuts+ Marketplace Tutorials and Screencasts PhotoDune Stock Photography 
 
 Create Account Sign In 
 
 Make Money 
 Become an Author Payment Rates 
 Forums 
 Notices 3DOcean All Marketplaces Item Discussion Item Requests Site Feedback Off Topic 

 Forum Rules 
 Community 
 Social Media / RSS Feeds The Envato Marketplaces Community Badges Envato Notes Public Collections 

 Featured Files Popular Files Top Authors Top New Authors 
 Affiliates 
 Affiliate Program Banners&amp;Logos 
 Help 
 Getting Started Support Center Licenses Legal Agreements API Sitemap 
 
 
 All Files 
 Popular Files Top Authors Top New Authors 

 View All Categories 
 3D Models 
 Animals Anatomy Base Meshes Buildings and Architecture Clothes&amp;Accessories Deco Objects Design Elements Electronics Engines and Parts Fantasy and Fiction Food and drinks Furnishings Humans Music Nature Products Render Setups Science Sports Tools Toys and Games Theme Packages Vehicles Weapons and Armor Miscellaneous 

 Popular Items 
 Cars HDRI Images 
 Sky Interior Exterior 
 CG Textures 
 Bones Buildings Concrete Doors Fabric Fauna Flora Ground HDRI Images Humans Ice Metal Ornaments Paper Plaster Plastic Roads Roofing Skies Splatter Stone Tiles Walls Water Windows Wood Miscellaneous 

 Popular Items 
 Materials&amp;Shaders 
 Ceramic Fabric Glass Glow Marble Metal Organic Plastic Sci-fi Stone Water Wood Miscellaneous 

 Popular Items 
 Base Meshes Scripts&amp;Plugins 
 Scripts Plugins 

 Popular Items 
 More 
 Animation Data 2D Concepts 
 Search 
 Home \ Files \ 3D Models \ Furnishings \ Furniture \ 
Dining room 04 Set - a fast food restaurant.
 
 Item Details Comments 
 
You must be signed in to make a purchase
 Create Account or Sign In More Images 
Dining room 04 Set–a fast food restaurant furniture include 3D Models: 
round table with chairs and a rectangular table with benches.
Room environment included.
Furniture from this set can be used for the interior fast-food restaurant, cafe, coffee shop.
Colorful chairs will help him fit into any interior, regardless of the color solution.
 More items by humster3d 
You must sign in or sign up to purchase this item.
 
 $ 30 Regular Licence 
 $ 30 Purchase 
 Regular Licence rendered still or animated use in client or personal projects such as mockups, commercials, free games, fliers, artwork - Details 
 
 $ 60 Extended Licence 
 $ 60 Purchase 
 Extended Licence projects meant for sale such as games, movies, physical objects, posters, t-shirts - Details 
 Add $2 if you are not using prepaid credits 
 1 Purchases 
 0 Comments Buyer Rating Minimum of 3 votes required
for Rating Tweet 
 humster3d 

 Has been a member for 1-2 years Item was Featured Author was Featured Sold between 10 000 and 50 000 dollars 
 View Portfolio 
 Created 18 August 11 3D File Formats Included .3ds (multi format) , .c4d (cinema 4d) , .hrc (softimage) , .lwo (lightwave) , .max (3ds Max) , .mb (maya) , .obj (multi format) Animated? No Created In 3ds max 2010 , cinema 4d r11 , maya 8.5 Geometry Polygons Materials? Yes Poly Count 0 Rigged? No Textured? Yes UV Layout? No 
 
 3D furniture 3d models benches cafe chair coffee shop design desk detailed dining room fast food furniture home interior kitchen materials photorealistic restaurant table textured 
 ©All Rights Reserved humster3d - Contact Envato Support 
 ActiveDen AudioJungle ThemeForest VideoHive GraphicRiver 3DOcean CodeCanyon Tuts+ Marketplace PhotoDune 
 
Follow Us
 Subscribe to Blog 
 Follow us on Twitter 
 Be a fan on Facebook 
 RSS Feed 
Help and Support
 Knowledgebase 
 Contact Support 
 About Envato 
Monthly Newsletter
 Subscribe 
 Check out the archive Marketplace Members
1,778,234
Total Marketplace Items
1,804,610
 CG and 3D tutorials from beginner to advanced. CHECK OUT CGTUTS+ Adobe After Effects tutorials from beginner to advanced. CHECK OUT AETUTS+ Envato 
 COPYRIGHT©2012 ENVATO | TERMS OF USAGE | SUPPORT/HELP | ICONS BY TANGO + WEFUNCTION + FAMFAMFAM 

Adobe®, Flash®, Flex®, Fireworks®, Photoshop®, Illustrator®, InDesign®and After Effects®are registered trademarks of Adobe Systems Incorporated.
 Request processing... by by by by by
	</body>
</document>
