<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002764" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/restaurants-1950s-fast-food-born-410331.html" time="2012-07-12-18:49" support="1" score="0.003735620003208063" bingtitle="Restaurants of the 1950&apos;s: Fast Food is Born - Yahoo! Voices ..." webtitle="Restaurants of the 1950&apos;s: Fast Food is Born - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="000367" bing-rank="45"/>
	<description>... quality, whole-bean, Arabica coffee at 10¢ per cup ... Healthy Fast Food Choices When we must eat fast food, we can ... Sometimes you simply must stop at a fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
Restaurants of the 1950&apos;s: Fast Food is Born
 Lori Ritchie , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
Jun 22, 2007 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: Fast Food 1950&apos;s Donuts The Fifties National Donut Day 
 Flag Close Post a comment It was during the early 1950&apos;s that The National Restaurant Association endorsed a new type of dinner called the &quot;take home&quot; meal. This was a meal that families could enjoy at home in front of their new black and white televisions. McDonald&apos;s unveiled their &quot;Speedee System&quot; at this time as well. Many restaurants had some form of drive-up window dating back to the 1930&apos;s, but when the speaker system was integrated into the drive-thru system, the concept dramatically increased the popularity of fast food. This article looks at the beginnings of some of the most recognized fast food businesses that originated during the 1950&apos;s.
The first Dunkin&apos; Donuts opened in Quincy, Mass., during this era. It was founded by 36-year-old William Rosenberg who first named his coffee-and-donut shop The Open Kettle. Rosenberg cashed in $1,500 in war bonds, borrowed another $1,000, and started a catering business that focused on coffee, pastries, and sandwiches to factory workers. The entrepreneur served top-quality, whole-bean, Arabica coffee at 10¢ per cup while the competition charged a nickel for cheaper coffee. Rosenberg signed his first Dunkin&apos; Donuts franchise agreement in 1955. The donut shop boasts an impressive selection of 52 kinds of donuts and has established locations in 37 countries.

The 1950&apos;s saw the debut of Church&apos;s Fried Chicken to Go. The first Church&apos;s was opened in downtown San Antonia, Texas by George W. Church. Church was a retired chicken incubator salesman and had spent more than twenty years in the poultry industry. This experience enabled the restauranteur to keep his chicken prices low by reducing costs. Fast-food restaurants at this time sold primarily hot dogs and ice cream. French fries and jalapenos were added to Church&apos;s menu in 1955. There were more than 1.500 Church&apos;s restaurants world-wide in the year 2002.

Denny&apos;s food stores began as Danny&apos;s Donuts in Lakewood, California during this decade. Harold Butler, 32, told his investors of plans to serve the best coffee and donuts, offer the best service and value in the industry, and to stay open 24 hours a day. As the company grew, the menu grew to include sandwiches and in 1959 became known as Denny&apos;s Restaurants. This food chain grew to become the largest U.S. full service family restaurant chain.

The first Burger King hamburger stand located in Miami, Florida sold hamburgers and milkshakes for 18 cents each during the fifties era . Founders James McLamore and David Edgerton each brought extensive restaurant experience to the creation of the Burger King chain. The collaboration between these two entrepreneurs has led to a worldwide fast food store empire with more outlets than any competitor besides McDonald&apos;s.
 
Published by Lori Ritchie 

I am currently a Registered Nursing student (graduation date of May 2007), freelance writer, bimonthly columnist. I currently work in a facility with Alzheimer and dementia affected individuals and I am a w...  View profile 
 
 Tips for Making Healthy Choices at Fast Food Restaurants Many fast food restaurants are now offering healthy choices. This means Americans can get their instant satisfaction without receiving a side order of thunder thighs. But, how... Fast-Food Survey Results - Where&apos;s Your Beef? Zagat and the Today Show surveyed 5,535 people to find out who has the best fast-food. Dave would have been proud. Healthy Fast Food Choices When we must eat fast food, we can still choose healthy fast food options that will help us keep our calories, fat content, and salt intake at healthy levels. Healthy Choices at Fast Food Restaurants Sometimes you simply must stop at a fast food restaurant. But you don&apos;t have to ruin your diet! There are a few healthy options at most fast food joints. Red Robin Versus Burger King&amp;McDonald&apos;s Who is better - the fast food juggernauts Burger King and McDonald&apos;s or the sit-down restaurant Red Robin? The answer shall be determined in this four round fight. 
 
 Fast Food is Everywhere in CA Eat Fast Food and Still Be Healthy Breaking the Fast Food Habit Fast Food Failures What Kind of Fast Food Tonight? Fast Food Calories: Where to Find Them How to Stay Safe and Clean in Fast Food Restaurants 
 
 
 
26 Comments
 Post a Comment 
 JTH 4/27/2011 
I it is ok
 Anonymous 2/15/2011 
this website suckkkksss
 omar 2/23/2010 
im in skool reseaching food and this web site sucks :|
 jh 2/23/2010 
this web sucks
 Mike and stephanie 5/29/2009 
agrreeeeeeeeed
 ccookkiiee 5/5/2009 
pepto bismol shouldnt be pink..agreed?
 funky chicken 4/24/2009 
i would like the chicken MCtesticles...
 cunt nugget 4/24/2009 
hi...
 derek burgstaller 4/23/2009 
i can&apos;t think. i have no brain. the fact that i am able to write word should surprise you all.
 marvin arroz 4/23/2009 
this is my favorite website!!
 
 Displaying Comments «Prev 1 2 3 Next» 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Shine and Lifestyles Network. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
