<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002994" url="http://www.roadfood.com/Forums/Why-is-it-so-difficult-starting-a-Hot-Dog-business-in-NJ-m667208.aspx" time="2012-07-12-19:05" support="1" score="0.0017193440361959061" bingtitle="Why is it so difficult starting a Hot Dog business in NJ?" webtitle="Why is it so difficult starting a Hot Dog business in NJ?">
			<query id="000801" bing-rank="56"/>
	<description>Drive up to exit 12 on the NYS thruway and get a ... with new graphics, a new slicer, insurance, credit card ... chicken sandwiches given to them by a fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		The most memorable local eateries along the highways and back roads of America Sign In | Register for Free! Restaurants Recipes Forums EatingTours Merchandise FAQ Maps Insider 
 Forum Themes: Mobile Original Welcome ! All Forums &gt;&gt; [Restaurant Professionals Forum] &gt;&gt; Professional Hot Dog Vendors 
 
 Forum Menu Log in 
 
 
 
 
 
 RSS Feed Thread Options 
 View Printable Page Thread Reading Mode 
 
 
 
 Why is it so difficult starting a Hot Dog business in NJ?
 
 Author Message 

 mamaof03 
 
 Total Posts:
 1 Joined: 9/5/2011 Location: South Brunswick, NJ 
 
 
 Why is it so difficult starting a Hot Dog business in NJ? Mon, 09/5/11 12:55 PM ( permalink ) I am trying to give my brother a hand in helping him start his Hot Dog Business. He is located in Central New Jersey and is finding it very difficult getting things started.
He is looking to place the truck some where in Old Bridge, like the Home Depot. Any suggestions would be greatly appreciated.
   #1 

 

 agmccall 
 
 Total Posts:
 238 Joined: 9/28/2010 Location: Albany, NY 
 
 
 Re:Why is it so difficult starting a Hot Dog business in NJ? Mon, 09/5/11 1:31 PM ( permalink ) First and foremost, if you read this forum at all you will know this, go to the Health inspector and get the rules and regulations. My HD gave me a package specifically designed for mobile vendors.
 
Second, Talk to the people who control where you want your cart and see what they require. Better yet, try and find a place you will not have to pay to play.
 
That is what I did to start, but, there is a lot more to do.
 
al
   #2 

 

 backahead 
 
 Total Posts:
 77 Joined: 12/10/2010 Location: Tappan, NY 
 
 
 Re:Why is it so difficult starting a Hot Dog business in NJ? Mon, 09/5/11 4:39 PM ( permalink ) Go across the street from Home Depot.  Costs less. Kinda late in the year to get started though. Drive up to exit 12 on the NYS thruway and get a dog from me :)
   #3 

 

 chefbuba 
 
 Total Posts:
 1390 Joined: 6/22/2009 Location: Near You, WA 
 
 
 Re:Why is it so difficult starting a Hot Dog business in NJ? Mon, 09/5/11 6:03 PM ( permalink ) mamaof03 


I am trying to give my brother a hand in helping him start his Hot Dog Business. He is located in Central New Jersey and is finding it very difficult getting things started.
He is looking to place the truck some where in Old Bridge, like the Home Depot. Any suggestions would be greatly appreciated.
 

You have to go through these people to be considered for Home Depot.
   #4 

 

 agmccall 
 
 Total Posts:
 238 Joined: 9/28/2010 Location: Albany, NY 
 
 
 Re:Why is it so difficult starting a Hot Dog business in NJ? Mon, 09/5/11 7:05 PM ( permalink ) chefbuba 


 mamaof03 


I am trying to give my brother a hand in helping him start his Hot Dog Business. He is located in Central New Jersey and is finding it very difficult getting things started.
He is looking to place the truck some where in Old Bridge, like the Home Depot. Any suggestions would be greatly appreciated.
 

You have to go through these people to be considered for Home Depot.
 
When chefbuba says you have to go through them, he means, pay them. And pay them well.
 
al
   #5 

 

 JodyP 
 
 Total Posts:
 321 Joined: 1/15/2008 Location: Cumming, GA 
 
 
 Re:Why is it so difficult starting a Hot Dog business in NJ? Tue, 09/6/11 12:07 PM ( permalink ) First of all there are a lot of hoops to jump through to be successful in this business. Way too many people have been lured into this business by the slick ads for hot dog carts and the amount of money you can make. From what I have seen and researched is that there are very few states / municipalities that allow someone to purchase or build a cart and jump into business. In a lot of areas the cart is the least expensive part of the business. You might be better off finding some small events or festivals to vend at. Most of these charge less than $100 for a two day event. Another avenue is to look for weekly markets and see if you can set up there.
 
In the south I have not seen many successful food ventures in front of Home Depot or Lowes. The contractor sales are way down due to the economy and on most weekends one of their vendors are giving away free hotdogs. On the plus side a lot of these stores are not using Street Eats Limited anymore (In my area) and are doing everything on a per store location per the managers approval. Still no customers = no revenue. Worst case scenario is they may still require you to be open when they are open. A Street Eats Limited requirement.
 
I am migrating towards the food truck craze. There are daily food trucks events going on every week. I have completely revamped my cart with new graphics, a new slicer, insurance, credit card machine, and soon an onboard generator. We added a sandwich press earlier this year. I will probably add a small propane flat top griddle and exhaust hood. Food truck events are usually sponsored by non-profit groups and fall outside of the Health Department. The food truck events charge between $50 and $75 per event. Depending on your rig it might be worth looking into.
   #6 

 

 chefbuba 
 
 Total Posts:
 1390 Joined: 6/22/2009 Location: Near You, WA 
 
 
 Re:Why is it so difficult starting a Hot Dog business in NJ? Tue, 09/6/11 12:14 PM ( permalink ) Jody....why would you get a pass from the hd because something is sponsored by a non profit?
   #7 

 

 JodyP 
 
 Total Posts:
 321 Joined: 1/15/2008 Location: Cumming, GA 
 
 
 Re:Why is it so difficult starting a Hot Dog business in NJ? Tue, 09/6/11 2:13 PM ( permalink ) In Georgia any event / festival sponsored by a non-profit group or government entity is exempt from HD inspections or fees. There are a few of the larger events that might require a temporary HD inspection and token fee, but most do not. We do a monthly event put on by a private group where we are required to pay a temporary permit fee and get a monthly inspection. The Food Truck events are operating under the exemption because each one is sponsored by a non-profit group. I know this is going to change in the near future but I am not sure what direction it will go. I think we will have to have some kind of monthly inspection and or fee. An Atlanta city councilman is actually trying to pass an ordinance in Atlanta / Fulton County to protect the Food Truck events. The quality of the product and the mobile units at the Food Truck events are a lot better than what you see at many of the local festivals. Most of the units are commercially manufactured to food grade and serve some kind of gourmet food items. Actually I won’t mind seeing HD inspections at the local events, some of the stuff I have seen definitely wouldn’t fly and it would cut down on the competition.
   #8 

 

 chefbuba 
 
 Total Posts:
 1390 Joined: 6/22/2009 Location: Near You, WA 
 
 
 Re:Why is it so difficult starting a Hot Dog business in NJ? Tue, 09/6/11 6:13 PM ( permalink ) I just don&apos;t understand how a non profit CAN&apos;T get someone sick, and would be exempt from inspection. Fee&apos;s yes, but inspection no.
I would say that the likelihood of it would be greater with a non profit, most of their people know nothing about handling food.
 
I did an event last week, one of the service clubs was doing burgers, all bare handed, no place to wash.
I watched the guys cooking throw raw burgers on the grill then grab buns and prepare burgers all with the same contaminated hands. All out in public view under a tent.
No wonder my line was longer than theirs.... both same price.
   #9 

 

 JodyP 
 
 Total Posts:
 321 Joined: 1/15/2008 Location: Cumming, GA 
 
 
 Re:Why is it so difficult starting a Hot Dog business in NJ? Tue, 09/6/11 7:20 PM ( permalink ) Actually what I am talking about is that non-profit organizations sponsor the festivals / events the same way your local city sponsors a weekend event. They apply for a blanket festival permit. If the festival or event is organized by a church or any other non-profit organization then the food vendors are exempt from HD inspections / fees. But you are right on the money about the non-profit groups who are also food vendors. They know little if anything about safe food handing. I seen food left all day in cookers and never see anyone using gloves. I have started to stay away from events that I know have non-profits serving food. Besides the food handling they will under cut you in a minute. Several years ago I did a festival that had a lady’s club selling chicken sandwiches given to them by a fast food restaurant. By late lunch their food was already 6 to 7 hours old and they cut their price in half. I was trying to sell a hamburger plate with chips and a drink for $5.50 and they dropped their price to $2.00 for a sandwich, chips and a drink. Needless to say I didn’t do well that day.
   #10 

 
 Online Bookmarks Sharing: 
 Jump to : Jump to - - - - - - - - - - [Roadfood News&amp;Information Forums] - - - - Roadfood News Forum - - - - The Roadfood Insider [Regional Forums] - - - - Where Should I Eat? - - - - Trip Reports - - - - Eat and Greets - Roadfood Get-togethers [Lunch&amp;Dinner Forums] - - - - Soups - - - - Mexican - - - - Chicken - - - - BBQ - - - - International Food - - - - Seafood - - - - Sandwiches - - - - Prime Cuts - - - - Chili - - - - Pizza - - - - Hamburgers - - - - Hot Dogs, Sausages&amp;Bratwursts [Breakfast Forum] - - - - Breakfast [Side Dishes Forum] - - - - Side Orders [Desserts Forum] - - - - Ice Cream&amp;Custards - - - - Other Desserts [Snacks&amp;Candy Forum] - - - - Snacks&amp;Candy [Beverage Forum] - - - - The Beverage Forum [Miscellaneous Forums] - - - - Roadfood Restaurants in the Media - - - - Miscellaneous - Food Related - - - - Recipes&amp;Cooking Techniques - - - - Fast Food Franchises&amp;Non-Roadfood Chains - - - - Miscellaneous - Off Topic&amp;&quot;Lighter Fare&quot; [Restaurant Professionals Forum] - - - - Restaurant Professionals Forum - - - - Professional Hot Dog Vendors - - - - Roadfood Classifed - For Sale and Want Ads 
 
Current active users
 There are 0 members and 1 guests. 
Icon Legend and Permission

 
 New Messages No New Messages Hot Topic w/ New Messages Hot Topic w/o New Messages Locked w/ New Messages Locked w/o New Messages 
 
 Read Message Post New Thread Reply to message Post New Poll Submit Vote Post reward post Delete my own posts Delete my own threads Rate post 
 
 
 
 
 

 2000-2012 ASPPlayground.NET Forum Version 3.9 What is Roadfood?    |    Privacy Policy    |    Contact Roadfood.com    Copyright 2011 - Roadfood.com
	</body>
</document>
