<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002968" url="http://www.millenniumseating.com/store/p/133-42-inch-Island-Style-Contour-Booth.html" time="2012-07-12-19:03" support="1" score="0.0005618278846921497" bingtitle="42-inch Island Style Contour Booth 76842 - Restaurant Furniture ..." webtitle="42-inch Island Style Contour Booth 76842">
			<query id="000602" bing-rank="12"/>
	<description>Availability: Build to Order - Usually ships in 3-4 Weeks ... This item usually ships in: 3-4 Weeks; Shipping Method ... Quick-Ship Waste Receptacle</description>
	<body>
		42-inch Island Style Contour Booth 76842
 TOLL FREE: (866) 379-8422 
 Mon - Fri, 9am - 5pm EST My Account | Quote Cart 
 
 
 Restaurant Booths Restaurant Chairs Restaurant Tables Cafeteria Seating Breakroom Seating Outdoor Furniture 
 
 PRODUCTS Cluster Seating Restaurant Benches Waste&amp;Trash Receptacles Outdoor Restaurant Furniture Restaurant Booths Restaurant Booths Contour Booths Upholstered Booths Wood Restaurant Booths Retro Diner Booths Restaurant Chairs Restaurant Chairs Metal Restaurant Chairs Wooden Restaurant Chairs Stacking Restaurant Chairs Retro Diner Chairs Outdoor Restaurant Chairs Restaurant Tables Restaurant Tables Table Bases Laminate Table Tops Wood Table Tops Retro Diner Tables Commercial Bar Stools Commercial Bar Stools Metal Bar Stools Wood Bar Stools Retro Bar Stools Outdoor Bar Stools Diner Furniture Diner Furniture Diner Booths Diner Chairs Diner Stools Diner Tables Customer Service Have Questions? 

 (866) 379-8422 
Mon-Fri 8-5 EST

» Send an email Home &gt; Restaurant Furniture &gt; Restaurant Booths &gt; Contour Booths &gt; 
42-inch Island Style Contour Booth
 Item #: ply-76842 
 Like Tweet 
 Picture shown is with optional upgrades Click to Enlarge Plymold Availability: Build to Order - Usually ships in 3-4 Weeks List Price: $1,231.00 
You Save: $699.01
 Was: $615.99 Sale: $531.99 
Shipping: Request a Quote for Rates Quantity: 
This item is sold in multiples of 1 with a minimum order of 1. BELLY ROOM:
 Select Belly Room Standard +1.5&quot;per side +3&quot;per side +6&quot;per side 
 TABLE EDGE: ( view swatches )
 Select Edge Color Adobe Atlantis Atlantis-Vinyl Black Black-Vinyl Brittany Blue Brown-Vinyl Burgundy Concrete Dove Gray Dove Gray-Vinyl Frosty White-Vinyl Hollyberry-Vinyl Hunter Green Lagoon-Vinyl Midori Midori-Vinyl Mountain Purple Natural Almond-Vinyl Pacific Sienna Silverpine Spectrum Red Spectrum Red-Vinyl St.Croix Sky Taupetone-Vinyl Wineberry Wineberry Vinyl 
 BENCH LAMINATE: (view swatches) 
 Select Bench Laminate Antique Roca Aqua Boomerang Atlantis Beigewood Black Blue Agave Brittany Blue Bronze Legacy Burnished Chestnut Butcherblock Maple Carbon EV Castle Oak Cesium EV Chai Tea Charcoal Boomerang Citrus Orange Cloud Cloud Nebula Congo Spruce Curry Tigris Dove Grey Earthen Terra Fashion Grey Figured Mahogany Flame Soapstone Fortuneberry Fouthill Pear Frosty White Fusion Maple Garden Oasis Ginseng Tea Golden Oak Graphite Nebula Green Tigris Grey Glace Grey Nebula Grey Pampas Hunter Green Huntington Maple Indigo Jasper Envision Khaki Brown Kiwi Lapis Blue Lodestone Manitoba Maple Maroochy Brush Mercury Glass Mission Adobe Mission Stucco Misted Zephyr Mistique Moonlight Montana Walnut Mystique Marine Natural Almond Natural Tigris Navy Legacy Nepal Teak Neutral Glace New Burgundy North Sea Oiled Soapstone Olive Legacy Oxide Oxygen Pepperdust Pewter Brush Pomegranate Port Possum Rustic Slate Saffron Tigris Sanibel Maple Slate Grey Solar Oak Spectrum Blue Spectrum Red Spectrum Yellow Sweet Corn Tawny Legacy Titanium EV Tumbled Mosaic Tuscan Marble Tuscan Red Tuscan Walnut Varnish Crayon Verdi Oxide Violin Figured Annigre White Nebula White Tea White Tigris Wild Cherry Windsor Mahogany Windswept Windswept Pewter Woolamai Brush 
 TABLE LAMINATE: (view swatches) 
 Select Table Laminate Antique Roca Aqua Boomerang Atlantis Beigewood Black Blue Agave Brittany Blue Bronze Legacy Burnished Chestnut Butcherblock Maple Carbon EV Castle Oak Cesium EV Chai Tea Charcoal Boomerang Citrus Orange Cloud Cloud Nebula Congo Spruce Curry Tigris Dove Grey Earthen Terra Fashion Grey Figured Mahogany Flame Soapstone Fortuneberry Fouthill Pear Frosty White Fusion Maple Garden Oasis Ginseng Tea Golden Oak Graphite Nebula Green Tigris Grey Glace Grey Nebula Grey Pampas Hunter Green Huntington Maple Indigo Jasper Envision Khaki Brown Kiwi Lapis Blue Lodestone Manitoba Maple Maroochy Brush Mercury Glass Mission Adobe Mission Stucco Montana Walnut Mystique Marine Mystique Moonlight Natural Almond Natural Tigris Navy Legacy Nepal Teak Neutral Glace New Burgundy North Sea Oiled Soapstone Olive Legacy Oxide Oxygen Pepperdust Pewter Brush Pomegranate Port Possum Rustic Slate Saffron Tigris Sanibel Maple Slate Grey Solar Oak Spectrum Blue Spectrum Red Spectrum Yellow Sweet Corn Tawny Legacy Titanium EV Tumbled Mosaic Tuscan Marble Tuscan Red Tuscan Walnut Varnish Crayon Verdi Oxide Violin Figured Annigre White Nebula White Tea White Tigris Wild Cherry Windsor Mahogany Windswept Windswept Pewter Woolamai Brush 
 FRAME FINISH: ( view swatches )
 Select Frame Finish Almond Black Black Wrinkle-Interior Only Brown Gray White 
 Description Specifications Shipping Info Product Reviews Product Warranty 
 Nobody builds better basic seating. Plymold has pioneered and perfected contour seating. If you want
amazing durability and easy maintenance-at a lower initial cost-then Contour seating is your answer.
All contour seating has been thoroughly tested to standards derived from ANSI/BIFMA.
 Booth consists of 24&quot; x 42&quot; table top with self edge Island style frame Wide selection of frame options including wall, island, grout-in and solo Laminate front and back seats Layout dimensions are 63&quot;W x 42&quot;L x 36&quot;H Available with extra belly room at no additional cost Vinyl edge is available at no additional cost Dur-a-edge is available at additional cost Wide range of colors and frame finishes help you create just the right combinations Optional upholstered back and seat pads for additional style and comfort 18&quot; normal (Seat height) 36&quot; (Overall height)
 
 Application: Commercial Use Dimensions: 63&quot;W x 42&quot;L x 36&quot;H Seating Capacity: Seats 4 


 Standard Contour Booth Space Requirements 
 Booth opening size of 63&quot; is required. Opening sizes are with a 24&quot; wide top, unless otherwise specified. Wider table tops and frames are available. 
 



 Floor Glide Detail 
 Thread-in glides can be adjusted to level. It is recommended that frames be anchored to the floor to prevent personal injury. 
 
 This item usually ships in: 3-4 Weeks Shipping Method: LTL Freight Unless specified, estimated freight charges do not include additional carrier services such as Customer Call Ahead, Lift Gate, Residential Delivery or Inside Delivery. If you are unsure of what your specific shipping needs might be, please call 866-379-8422 or email sales@store.millenniumseating.com for assistance 
 Product Reviews Write a review! Read all reviews 
 Rated 0.00 stars -
 based on 0 customer reviews. Please contact customer service for details. Related Items 
 
 42-inch Wall Style Contour Booth Sale: $499.99 
 
 Quick-Ship Waste Receptacle Price: $517.99 
 
 You are viewing: 42-inch Island Style Contour Booth ply-76842 
 
 
 Search: 
 
 Sign up for savings  Mailing List: First Name: 
 Last Name: Email: 
 

 Articles About Us Contact Us Maintenance Privacy Policy Terms&amp;Policies Restaurant Furniture Blog Site Map Seating by Plymold 
 
 Millennium Seating 1983 Lower Roswell Road , Marietta , GA 30068 Phone: 866-379-8422 , 770-565-1965 Mon - Fri, 9am - 5pm EST
Email: sales@millenniumseating.com 
Copyright © 2001 - 2012 Millennium Seating . All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
