<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002221" url="http://www.kltv.com/Global/story.asp?S=13912552" time="2012-07-12-18:07" support="2" score="0.002194226855582752" bingtitle="Police say E.Tx man used photocopied bills at Jack in the Box ..." webtitle="Police say E.Tx man used photocopied bills at Jack in the Box - KLTV.com-Tyler, Longview, Jacksonville, Texas | ETX News">
			<query id="001063" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="001302" bing-rank="26"/>
	<description>... photocopied 10-dollar bills at a Diboll fast-food restaurant. ... Youth group hosts city-wide bake sale to pay ... Senate judiciary committee took up a bill that would make it ...</description>
	<body>
		KLTV.com-Tyler, Longview, Jacksonville, Texas | ETX NewsPolice say E.Tx man used photocopied bills at Jack in the Box
 SITE SEARCH WEB SEARCH BY 
 
 KLTV Faces Slideshows Big Red Box See It, Snap It, Send It KLTV.com Mobile Text&amp;Email Alerts News Tips Who&apos;s on 7 RSS Feeds America Now 
 
 Texas Headlines Weekly News Archives Education News Politics Business Tech RSS Feeds 
 
 Interactive Radar Hurricane Tracker Text&amp;Email Alerts Mobile StormTracker National Radar Current Radar Image Personal Forecast Pollen Center KLTV.com Mobile ThunderCall 
 
 The Red Zone Victory Lane 7 Sports Smackdown Die Hard Sports Pro Pigskin Pick&apos;em Texas Sports Headlines 
 
 ETMC Medical Resource Guide Senior Resource Women&apos;s Health Men&apos;s Health 
 
 Birthday Club 
 
 Main Summer Back to School Entertainment Money Home/Family Health Food Pets Tech Travel Beauty&amp;Style Tax Guide VideoBytes Press Releases 
 
 America Now ABC Shows Online At the Movies Horoscopes 
 
 Healthy Women Community Calendar Baby Boomer Daily A Better East Texas Everyday Heroes Community Spotlight ASK Seek Knock 
 
 Who&apos;s on 7 Employment Online Media Kit 388 Filed with the FCC EEO Summary 
 
 
 Email 
 Share | 
 Print 
 
Police say E.Tx man used photocopied bills at Jack in the Box
 Posted: Wednesday, January 26, 2011 1:01 PM EST Updated: Thursday, January 27, 2011 8:59 AM EST John Martin. Photo Source: Angelina County Jail. 
By Jeff Awtrey - email 

DIBOLL, TX (KTRE) - Diboll Police arrested a man Tuesday for allegedly using photocopied 10-dollar bills at a Diboll fast-food restaurant.

John Kenneth Martin, 35, is charged with forgery.

Det. Brandan Lovell said Martin used one of the bills at Jack in the Box, located at 400 N. Temple Drive, on Friday. A worker at the restaurant saw the bill was counterfeit after she took it from him and called police, Lovell said.

Martin had already left before police arrived but surveillance video allowed police to identify Martin and his vehicle, Lovell said.

Police located Martin on Tuesday at his travel trailer on the 200 block of Hamner Street. Officers spoke with him, but he refused to allow them to search his vehicle and trailer, Lovell said. Police obtained a search warrant and found three counterfeit 10-dollar bills in his vehicle and three more in his trailer, Lovell said.

Lovell said he copied the bills out of a copier in his trailer. Police seized four laptop computers, two printers and a copier from the residence.

&quot;He admitted guilt and showed us how he&apos;s doing it,&quot; Lovell said. &quot;It was pretty obvious they were fake bills.&quot;

 Copyright 2011 KTRE. All rights reserved. 
 
 
 Top 5 News Stories More&gt;&gt; 
 
 Services set for Tyler teacher who drowned in Dallas lake 

 Services set for Tyler teacher who drowned in Dallas lake 
 Updated: Tuesday, July 10 2012 7:10 PM EDT 2012-07-10 23:10:29 GMT The funeral arrangements are set for a TJC teacher who drowned over the weekend in a lake in Dallas.
 More &gt;&gt; The funeral arrangements are set for a TJC teacher who drowned over the weekend in a lake in Dallas.
 More &gt;&gt; 
 FedEx truck overturns on busy ETX roadway 

 FedEx truck overturns on busy ETX roadway 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 10:27 PM EDT 2012-07-10 02:27:35 GMT An accident is slowing traffic in north Tyler. More &gt;&gt; An accident is slowing traffic in north Tyler. More &gt;&gt; 
 BREAKING NEWS 

 Tyler Police request assistance locating 18-year-old 

 Tyler Police request assistance locating 18-year-old 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 9:41 PM EDT 2012-07-10 01:41:24 GMT The Tyler Police Department has asked for the public&apos;s assistance in locating a missing 18-year-old. More &gt;&gt; The Tyler Police Department has asked for the public&apos;s assistance in locating a missing 18-year-old man. More &gt;&gt; 
 Lightning strike spooks E. Texans at Rangers Stadium 

 Lightning strike spooks E. Texans at Rangers Stadium 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 8:01 PM EDT 2012-07-10 00:01:24 GMT You may have been watching the Rangers game Sunday when the crowd heard something much louder than the crack of a bat. You might even say it was electrifying. More &gt;&gt; You may have been watching the Rangers game Sunday when the crowd heard something much louder than the crack of a bat. You might even say it was electrifying. More &gt;&gt; 
 Tyler toddler dies in rollover crash in Wyoming 

 Tyler toddler dies in rollover crash in Wyoming 
 Updated: Monday, July 9 2012 7:25 PM EDT 2012-07-09 23:25:49 GMT A Tyler family is mourning the loss of their two-year-old after the family was involved in a major single-vehicle accident in Wyoming. More &gt;&gt; A Tyler family is mourning the loss of their two-year-old after the family was involved in a major single-vehicle accident in Wyoming. More &gt;&gt; 
 
 
Explore KLTV.com
 Home Big Red Box See It, Snap It, Send It KLTV.com Mobile Email Alerts News Tips Who’s on 7 RSS Feeds America Now News Texas Headlines Love It or Hate It Education News Politics Business News Technology News Telemundo Weekly News Archives Weather Interactive Radar National Radar Hurricane Tracker Current Radar Image Personal Forecast Pollen Center ThunderCall Sports Sports 7 Sports Smackdown Texas Sports Headlines Sports Video Love It or Hate It Race Day Challenge Pro Pigskin Pick’em Video Better East Texas Check this out! Crimefighters Does it Work? Restaurant Reports Contact Us News Team Advertise With Us Jobs @ KLTV All content©Copyright 2000 - 2012 WorldNow and KLTV, a Raycom Media Station .
All Rights Reserved. For more information on this site, please read our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service .
	</body>
</document>
