<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002297" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Escondido/Jack-in-the-Box_195" time="2012-07-12-18:12" support="1" score="0.0010410926424716759" bingtitle="Jack in the Box - Fast Food Restaurant Escondido, CA 92025" webtitle="Jack in the Box - Fast Food Restaurant  Escondido, CA 92025">
			<query id="000245" bing-rank="247"/>
	<description>Jack in the Box a Fast Food restaurant with a location at 238 E Felicita Ave in Escondido, CA. ... of the Tacoma Tribune, our source on this matter and for the drink recipes ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Jack in the Box
 
Average User Rating
 
5
 
Average
 
Sponsored Link


 
(760) 746-7504

 http://www.jackinthebox.com/ 
 CA &gt; Escondido &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Jack in the Box listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Jack in the Box to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Social 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Jack in the Box
 Jack in the Box is a Fast Food restaurant located at 238 E Felicita Ave in Escondido, CA 92025. Jack in the Box has been described as an Good Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 5 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Jack in the Box
 
 
 
All Reviews for Jack in the Box


 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Jack in the Box:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   0

 
Comments
 
 
Jack in the Box Tips
 Awesome drink machine, SLOW service.
 
Allyssa P. Here&apos;s a tip: stop eating fast food. too bad you won&apos;t. no matter how much I say I want to, I won&apos;t either. Value menu.
 
Matt Free sandwich 2-23-10
 
Manny G. This location has a Coke Freestyle Fountain with lots of unusual Coke beverage choices.
 
Ryan C. 
Jack in the Box News
 Sonic Higher Ahead of Earnings New ... restaurants, principally in the south central and southeastern United States. Its restaurants offer made-to-order hamburgers and other sandwiches, as well as signature items. Other companies on the watch on this earnings event are Jack in the Box ... Top 5 Companies in the Restaurants Industry with the Best Relative Performance (BWLD, RT, JACK, YUM, KKD) Buffalo Wild Wings (NASDAQ:BWLD) ranks first with a gain of 3.44%; Ruby Tuesday (NYSE:RT) ranks second with a gain of 1.37%; and Jack in the ... casual dining restaurants. The restaurants feature made to order menu items including New York style chicken ... Pay tribute to Benny Goodman in Bridgewater Benny’s vision has been captured in the essence of James Langton’s New York All-Star Big Band ... trombone in the best tradition of legends such as Will Bradley and Jack Teagarden; and the versatile sax section, consisting of the Anderson ... Recipe Swap: Cozy up this winter with a hot, frothy drink According to Rosemary Ponnekanti, of the Tacoma Tribune, our source on this matter and for the drink recipes that follow, hot toddies crop up in Charles Dickens and Jack London ... the teeth of the Central New York winter. Fixing Congress and Finding Peace: An Interview with Jack Abramoff Jack Abramoff helped break Congress, and now he’s trying to fix it. In the mid-2000’s, Abramoff was earning $20 million a year selling his clients access to the Republican House leadership. He owned restaurants ... the New York governor&apos;s ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing Jack in the Box Jack in the Box is among the nation&apos;s leading fast-food hamburger chains, with more than 2,200 quick-serve restaurants in 19 states. New York Magazine -- NYC Guide to Restaurants, Fashion, Nightlife ... Daily coverage of New York&apos;s restaurants, nightlife, shopping, fashion, politics, and culture. NYMag.com is the online counterpart to New York Magazine. NYC.com | New York Hotels - Broadway Tickets - New York ... Save more with NYC.com, the trusted New York City experts. Book New York hotels and lodging, buy New York Broadway tickets and event tickets, reserve New York ... The Official New York City Guide to NYC Attractions, Dining ... Visit NYCgo for official NYC information on travel, hotels, deals and offers like Restaurant Week, and the best restaurants, shops, clubs and cultural events. The Standard Hotels in Los Angeles, Hollywood, Miami and New York City Andre Balazs’ The Standard Hotels are located in Hollywood, Downtown Los Angeles, Miami Beach, and New York City. These chic hotels feature comfortable ... 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 68° 
Fri
 
 64° - 97° 
Sat
 
 61° - 90° 
Sun
 
 57° - 82° 
 
Address
 
Jack in the Box

238 E Felicita Ave

Escondido, CA 
 
92025
 
Telephone
 (760) 746-7504 
Jack in the Box
 
 Rating :  5 out of 10 based on 5 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Jack in the Box Photos
 
 Fast Food 
 
 Local Places
 
 Carls Jr Restaurants Escondido 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Jack in the Box 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Kotija Mexican Food 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Barbecue Pit the Wrangler Family 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Sushiya 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food KFC 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Del Taco Incorporated 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Taco Bell 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Cost Plus World Market 
Cuisine: Movie Theaters Escondido Promenade 
Cuisine: Shopping Centers Holiday Wine Cellar 
Cuisine: Wine Shop Deer Park Winery and Automotive Museum 
Cuisine: Tourist Attractions 
 

See all Escondido Movie Theaters 
See all Escondido Shopping Centers 
See all Escondido Wine Shop 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Jack in the Box Coupons 

 Jack in the Box Escondido 

 Jack in the Box Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Escondido Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P Q | R | S | T | U | V | W | Y 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
