<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002622" url="http://www.leasingprofessional.com/lease-agreement/restaurant-lease-agreement.htm" time="2012-07-12-18:41" support="1" score="0.0013040285783626896" bingtitle="Agreements For Restaurant Leases And Bar Leases" webtitle="Agreements For Restaurant Leases And Bar Leases">
			<query id="001050" bing-rank="129"/>
	<description>This form is designed for a freestanding restaurant that will pay percentage rent in addition to minimum rent for its food service location.</description>
	<body>
		Home About What Clients Say FAQ Using Your Form Free Stuff 
 Free Clauses&amp;Advisories Free Exhibits Terminology 
 Terms Of Use/Sale Contact 
   
 
 Leases 
 Lease Agreements Lease Related Agreements State Leases 
 Management Forms Tech Forms Purchase Forms Healthcare Forms Discount Packs Strategies 
   
 Agreements For Restaurant Leases And Bar Leases 
 Products Often Span Multiple Categories--Use A Keyword Search To Locate All Suitable Products Please Click On Plus Signs Below To Expand Product Descriptions And Links To Product Pages 
 LA 1627 Pro-Landlord Shopping Center Percentage Rent Lease For Restaurant Tenant With Liquor License 
 
LA 1627 Pro-Landlord Shopping Center Percentage Rent Lease For Restaurant Tenant With Liquor License

This pro-landlord lease agreement is designed for a large shopping center leasing space to a restaurant tenant who will also have a liquor license. This percentage rent lease has a stepped up minimum rent schedule over the lengthy initial term of the lease. Generally, a fairly long initial lease term is required to amortize the extensive improvements necessary for food service tenants. The lease also contains two renewal option periods for the tenant.

The tenant is to receive a construction allowance based upon the amount of square footage in the premises. This product contains a lengthy construction exhibit, plus exhibits for guarantee of the lease, signage criteria, a tenant&apos;s certificate confirming the details of the tenant&apos;s possession after it occupies the premises, and retail rules and regulations.

Number of Single Spaced Pages: 125
 
 LA 1211 Lease For Coffee And Juice Bar (Starbucks Type) Tenant On Ground Floor Of Office Building Without Percentage Rent 
 
LA 1211 Lease For Coffee And Juice Bar (Starbucks Type) Tenant On Ground Floor Of Office Building Without Percentage Rent

This lease agreement is designed for an upscale coffee and juice bar (Starbucks Type) retailer taking space on the ground floor of an office building. The tenant is not required to pay percentage rent, but is responsible for its proportionate share of operating expenses.

The premises are taken&quot;as-is,&quot;subject to the landlord&apos;s construction obligations in the lease&apos;s work letter. The tenant is to receive a construction allowance computed the amount of square foot in the premises.

Number of Single Spaced Pages: 42

 More Information About This Product&gt; 
 
 LA 521 The Pro-Tenant Freestanding Gross Restaurant Lease 
 
LA 521 The Pro-Tenant Freestanding Gross Restaurant Lease

This lease form is extremely pro-tenant in orientation.

It contains zoning warranties by the landlord for the premises, a right of first refusal, a purchase option for the tenant, a radius clause prohibiting competing restaurants, and a tenant only right of termination.

Number of Single Spaced Pages: 13

 More Information About This Product&gt; 
 
 LA 681 Percentage Rent Lease For Freestanding Restaurant 
 
LA 681 Percentage Rent Lease For Freestanding Restaurant

This form is designed for a freestanding restaurant that will pay percentage rent in addition to minimum rent for its food service location.

Number of Single Spaced Pages: 12

 More Information About This Product&gt; 
 
 LA 1435 Retail Percentage Rent Lease For Ground Floor Sandwich Shop 
 
LA 1435 Retail Percentage Rent Lease For Ground Floor Sandwich Shop

This lease is designed for a small sandwich and salad food service operation located on the ground floor of an office building.

The tenant pays percentage rent, and has the benefit of an exclusive in the building for the type of food the tenant serves.

Number of Single Spaced Pages: 26

 More Information About This Product&gt; 
 
 LA 391 The Pro-Tenant Ground Lease For A Restaurant 
 
LA 391 The Pro-Tenant Ground Lease For A Restaurant

This lease is designed for a restaurant tenant leasing premises suitable for construction of a new restaurant.

The tenant appears to have had good negotiation leverage in the transaction, from the tone of the document&apos;s provisions.

Number of Single Spaced Pages: 12

 More Information About This Product&gt; 
 
 LA 707 Lease For Sports Bar In A Retail Strip Center Without Percentage Rent 
 
LA 707 Lease For Sports Bar In A Retail Strip Center Without Percentage Rent

This lease is for a tenant leasing space in a retail strip mall for a sports bar operation. The tenant is responsible for its pro-rata share of CAM (Common Area Maintenance) expenses in excess of a&quot;expense stop&quot;specified in the lease. The tenant has no obligation to pay percentage rent.

The tenant will accept the premises in their&quot;as-is&quot;condition, but will receive a construction allowance from the landlord to construct its improvements to the premises with its own contractor. Exhibits included: Rules and Regulations, Work Letter, Certificate of Acceptance of Premises.

Number of Single Spaced Pages: 38

 More Information About This Product&gt; 
 
 LA 1225 Lease For Restaurant And Bar Constructed By Tenant On Landlord&apos;s Real Estate 
 
LA 1225 Lease For Restaurant And Bar Constructed By Tenant On Landlord&apos;s Real Estate

The form that follows is for a restaurant tenant (also serving alcoholic beverages) who leased the landlord&apos;s property, and built a new restaurant on the site.

The lease gives the tenant a right of first refusal to purchase the property in the event the landlord receives a third party offer for the real estate that it wants to accept.

Number of Single Spaced Pages: 25

 More Information About This Product&gt; 
 
 LA 1425 Percentage Rent Lease For High End White Tablecloth Steakhouse Restaurant 
 
LA 1425 Percentage Rent Lease For High End White Tablecloth Steakhouse Restaurant

The form that follows is for a restaurant tenant (also serving alcoholic beverages) with a white tablecloth operation.

This extensive form covers construction issues, as well as use and radius protection, percentage rent, and liquor license details.

Number of Single Spaced Pages: 73

 More Information About This Product&gt; 
 
 LA 641 Ground Lease For New Regional Shopping Center Pad Restaurant 
 
LA 641 Ground Lease For New Regional Shopping Center Pad Restaurant

This lease is for a new high end restaurant to be located on a regional shopping center pad ground leased by the tenant. The tenant is to receive a construction allowance, pay percentage rentals, and receive a term on the ground lease lengthy enough to amortize the expensive improvements involved. The restaurant will also serve alcoholic beverages.

Number of Single Spaced Pages: 50

 More Information About This Product&gt; 
 
 LA 1205 Pro-Landlord Shopping Center Food Court Lease 
 
LA 1205 Pro-Landlord Shopping Center Food Court Lease

This lease for food court space in a shopping center is landlord oriented.

It provides for both minimum and percentage rent, as well as monthly CAM payments by the food court tenant.

Number of Single Spaced Pages: 33

 More Information About This Product&gt; 
 
 LA 1433 Net Lease For “Gentleman’s Club” With Liquor License 
 
LA 1433 Net Lease For“Gentleman’s Club”With Liquor License

The following form is designed for a transaction in which the landlord leases a building to the operator of a gentleman&apos;s club with a liquor license.

Number of Single Spaced Pages: 20

 More Information About This Product&gt; 
 
 LA 1503 Pro-Landlord Net Lease For Commissary Serving Multiple Unit Restaurant Company Tenant 
 
LA 1503 Pro-Landlord Net Lease For Commissary Serving Multiple Unit Restaurant Company Tenant

The following form is designed for a commissary lease for a restaurant tenant with multiple outlets in the same market. The lease contains a 27 page construction exhibit detailing the landlord&apos;s work for the premises, in addition to several other exhibits.

Number of Single Spaced Pages: 76

 More Information About This Product&gt; 
 
 Related Products 
 
Related Products

 See Strategies For Restaurant Leases 

 See Restaurant Management Agreements 
 
 Related Discount Power Pack 
 
Related Discount Power Pack

 See DISCOUNT POWER PACK 14:  Restaurant And Bar Leases
	</body>
</document>
