<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002870" url="http://reportyourcomplaint.com/walmart-customer-service-complaint-rude-employees-whom-dont-know-company-policies-and-practices/" time="2012-07-12-18:56" support="2" score="0.0035485359949700953" bingtitle="Walmart Customer Service Complaint - Rude Employees Whom Don&apos;t ..." webtitle="Walmart Customer Service Complaint - Rude Employees Whom Don&apos;t Know Company Policies and Practices | Report Your Complaint.com">
			<query id="000592" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000568" bing-rank="74"/>
	<description>When I was asked to come to the counter, the woman ... Thats why I am cannceling my credit card threw walmart. ... fast food fast food restaurant food fraud health Helpful helpful ...</description>
	<body>
		Log In 
 
 RYC (Home) Companies Complaints Reviews Compliments Helpful tips&amp;info Credit repair About us Site Index Blog 
 

 
Random Posts

 Glassdoor.com - a review of an interesting job, salaries and interview information website The Bedbug Registry, hotels with bedbugs and how to avoid getting eaten alive by these disgusting bugs! UNCC Barnes&amp;Noble bookstore textbooks review - it is always cheaper to shop around and buy or rent elsewhere! Sprint&apos;s New Common Cents Mobile - A Review of A New Pre-Paid Cellular Carrier Provided by Sprint Straight Talk Cell Phone Service Review - I Got Rid Of My Verizon Wireless Cell Phone And Switched To Wal-Mart&apos;s Cell Service! Hungry Man TV dinners review - had the salisbury steak Hungry-Man dinner and it tasted like crap! AT&amp;T;and their slimy service CLEAR Internet Complaint - Lying Customer Service Representatives and Another Foriegn Offshore Call Center! National Cancer Coalition charity review - this is definitely a top rate charity! Most popular posts, complaints, reviews and raves along with the top keywords and phrases for June on ReportYourComplaint. 
 
Recent Comments

 skyday on Great Stuff insulating foam sealant review–this stuff works great for sealing and insulating gaps and cracks SCAM on Childhood leukemia Foundation–a review of a shady charity that uses auto dialers and other shady practices to get donations Mike on HomeVestors home buyers is a shady scam and offers you far less than your home is worth! Chris Brady on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? Lee on Stanley Steemer–fraudulant business practices, abusive telemarketing and a bad rug cleaning experience! Lisa Carroll on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? brenda on Walgreen’s pharmacy–incorrectly filled prescription and they refused to fix it! S.K. Thompson on Virginia State Troopers Complaint–Police officers have too much power and get away with breaking laws! 
 Privacy Policy 
Walmart Customer Service Complaint–Rude Employees Whom Don’t Know Company Policies and Practices
 By bigpappa3456 
 





Today I needed to go to Wal-Mart to pick up a couple things before the work week began.  As I was walking through the main entrance, you can just feel how crappy the store really is.  The main reason that I return is for the lower prices for certain items.  I cannot stand going there because not only are other customers rude, but the associates at Wal-Mart are worse.

They have absolutely no customer service skills and are not helpful at all.  I first went back to the electronics section and when I first entered the area, there were 3 employees just standing there talking and socializing.  I don’t understand how Wal-Mart allows its employees to just stand around socializing and being useless.  I then went to look at the Bluetooth headsets they had and I found what I wanted so I selected that headset.

I had to go to the register that was in the electronic section because the headset was in a plastic security box.  When I went to the register there was no one to be found at all in the entire electronic section.  That is just one example of why Wal-Mart is a piece of crap store and hires the worst employees of our society.  I stood at the register and waited almost 10 minutes for an employee to come over and assist me.

I was absolutely pissed off because the guy was an absolute idiot ad didn’t know what he needed to do to get the box undone.  After I was able to get that handled, I headed to the deli department to get some sandwich meats.  When I went over there were 4 employees behind the counter assisting customers.  It was extremely loud and I could barely concentrate on what I needed to get.  When I was asked to come to the counter, the woman asked me what I needed.


 Your Ad Here 


I went up and asked her for a pound of Prima Vera chicken breast and she then asked me what number cut I wanted.  I didn’t want it to be too thick but I didn’t want it falling apart in my hands.  There number cutting scale is number s 1 thru 10, 1 being the thinnest and 10 the thickest.  I decided to choose a number 2 and didn’t think that it would be just right where I wanted.

When she was done slicing and packaging the meat, the entire package was disgusting.  The meat was put into the bag messy as all hell and the bigger problem was the thickness of the meat.  The thickness was like a slice of bread.  It was absolutely disgusting and I was pissed off because a number 2 should not be the thickest cut, but the second thinnest piece.

I was pissed, but not shocked because I was at Wal-Mart and that should be expected.  I know this won’t be the last time I shop at Wal-Mart because I tend to compare prices and find the lower price at Wal-Mart.  I just can’t get over how Wal-Mart just let all the little things that makes customers pissed off go.  I don’t understand why the company can’t see that customers are not happy with shopping, but it all makes sense because they only care about money.




 
Posts Related to Walmart Customer Service Complaint - Rude Employees Whom Don&apos;t Know Company Policies and Practices

 
 Walmart cashier and customer service complaint–customer service at Walmart downright sucks! 

// I went to the Walmart the other day and saw that there was only a very few cash registers open and the lines were ...
 
 Walmart–Employees that suck!, Rude Customer Service and Untrustworthy Employees! 

// Everytime I have to go into Walmart I cringe.  The only reason I shop here is because its the only store in town.   I ...
 
 American Eagle Outfitters- Rude Company Policies and Irritating Credit Card Offers!! 

// When I was at the mall shopping for new clothes, I had walked by American Eagle.  Many of my friends had worn clothes from ...
 
 Great Clips, rude employees and a haircut that wasn’t great! 

// I decided to get a haircut the other day and was in for what turned out to be the worst haircutting experience I have ...
 
 Wal-mart, racism and rude employees at the deli counter! 

// I went to Wal-Mart with my kids to get some groceries recently. All was fine until I got to the deli counter to order ...
 
 
 Tags: deli , deli counter , deli meats , horrible customer service , Not recommended , rude employees , Walmart , Walmart customer service complaint , Walmart sucks 
 
6 Responses to Walmart Customer Service Complaint–Rude Employees Whom Don’t Know Company Policies and Practices 

 january hazelwood on March 5, 2011 at 5:05 PM 

have you ever had a job working with the public? If not let me fill you in customers are rude they feel like they can get away with it because the employees are at work the way they support their families .I work with the public i have been yelled at and even cursed. maybe you think just because i am an employee at walmart i dont deserve to be treated with respect. i am a dignified third class citizen because i work for a living and dont you forget it.

Like or Dislike: 1   0 
 totally annoyed on May 2, 2011 at 4:55 PM 

Wow, January, I have to say I was pretty surprised to read your response. As a working class citizen (who refers to themself as“third class?!”) that has dealt with the public for years, I believe I have some say so in this. I seriously doubt the author of this article had intentions of slamming every single Walmart employee. Your attitude is exactly why the internet is riddled with negative comments about the corporation. There is no gray area when it comes to poor customer service-it’s either good or bad. I think your response speaks for itself and explains why there are so many problems with so many Walmart employees- poor attitude and lack of education.

Like or Dislike: 1   0 
 worst employees of our society on May 18, 2011 at 2:27 PM 

I am a Walmart Employee and yes she did slam us all and i quote“That is just one example of why Wal-Mart is a piece of crap store and hires the worst employees of our society”Everywhere you go there are good and bad employee and by the sounds of things this woman is probably the worst of the worst. She likes to complain alot but not once did i here that she let management know and how is walmart supose to know if no one says anything not to mention that is one store in how many

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 Jayne McGill on June 3, 2011 at 3:34 PM 

I visited the Wal-mart in Aberdeen, NC today around 9 am. The cashier named Polly had the BEST customer service I have ever experienced at that store. She was pleasant and patient and my transaction was purchasing 45 gift cards for my department at Firsthealth Moore Regional Hospital. Well–she was so organized and patient and I would like to pass on. Thank you for your time.

Jayne McGill–FNS

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 Annie Nonomous on June 6, 2011 at 2:36 PM 

As a current employee of the store you speak of, I will say this: I would not totally blame the associate in front of you.

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 lolYUP on July 28, 2011 at 12:00 AM 

Ok, Well I just had a not so good time at walmart. And its was the 3rd time in 5 days. I have been in and out of the store. Not one nice employee. Lisbon, CT store for everyones info. The lady this evening tho was the worst. She was giving everyone in the line additudes. Tapping her feet. Rude body movements. (sying) Like everyone was a bother to her. If lifes that hard as a cashier why don’t employees treat the company like crap. Not the ones that make it possible for them to get paid. Because the one thing I didn’t see here is that. You are at work. People every day in walmart or not deal with not so nice people. The customer is always right. If the customer cusses at you call the police. But the next sweet old lady in line isn’t a *(THUG)* Its just about doing the job. Don’t like it. move on. Thats why I am cannceling my credit card threw walmart. And After being the last strew, until I hear of people having a good visit. I AM NO LONGER PAYING YOU TO BE RUDE!!! And if people did this as well. They would have not choice but to correct this!! Well, Good luck to all you mad walmart employees. I am sure you will post something to this. Lol. Be my guest. I am sure it will be short like the others from walmat that commented. (Employees) They can’t even write more then a few lines. How can you exspect them to ring out a order. Or know where something is in there department. lol. Have fun with this. I am sure you will. LOL…

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
Search Website
 Most Popular
Complaints, Reviews, and Compliments! Want your company&apos;s product or service reviewed?
 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 Your Ad Here 
Tags
 automotive Awesome bad customer service car car dealer car dealership chain restaurants Charlotte Charlotte NC complaint compliment Customer service disgusting Educational fast food fast food restaurant food fraud health Helpful helpful information highly recommended honest review Horrible horrible customer service horrible service How to illegal Interesting Not recommended rave recommended restaurant review ripoff rude save money scam sucks Terrible unfair business practices unhealthy untrustworthy Walmart website Copyright©2012 Report Your Complaint.com . All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
