<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002689" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/196/1028034/restaurant/Blakes-Lotaburger-Las-Cruces" time="2012-07-12-18:45" support="3" score="0.0057780832018611995" bingtitle="Blake&apos;s Lotaburger - Las Cruces | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Blake&apos;s Lotaburger - Las Cruces | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000999" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="000995" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000987" bing-rank="55"/>
	<description>Blake&apos;s Lotaburger is a fast food restaurant with the kind of ambiance you would expect. ... the burgers and fries are not made until you order ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Las Cruces » Las Cruces » Blake&apos;s Lotaburger 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Albuquerque Denver Los Angeles New York Phoenix San Antonio Tucson More... 
 
Blake&apos;s Lotaburger

 View all 3 Blake&apos;s Lotaburger locations 
 
(575) 524-1743
 Las Cruces 2915 N Main St 
 Las Cruces , NM 88001 See all 2 reviews Menu Add menu photo   4 people have voted 100 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 Pizza Hut $ Las Cruces - Pizza, Fast Food 1492 N Main St 
 
 Red Lobster 72% $$ Las Cruces - Seafood 575 S Telshor Blvd 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews
 Bloggers, have you reviewed this restaurant? Add your review to this page. 
 Diner reviews

Diner reviews are sorted by relevance

 September 6, 2011 FAST FOOD...REAL GOOD GREEN CHILE CHEESEBURGERS by Mr Sensitive ( 245 reviews ) I will ditto what Bibliomaniac said (except for the out of town guest part!). Blake&apos;s Lotaburger is a fast food restaurant with the kind of ambiance you would expect. But it is bright and clean. Rate the ambiance about a B minus. The service is the norm for a fast food place. Rate it a C+. But here&apos;s the difference: the food is prepared after you order it. It may take slightly longer than Wendy&apos;s or Micky D&apos;s, but the wait is worth it. Blake&apos;s green chile cheeseburger is very good. The burger and bun itself is better than Wendy&apos;s, Micky D&apos;s etc....and the chile is outstanding...full of flavor and high on the heat. Good stuff. Now I am not going to sit here and tell you that Blake&apos;s green chile cheeseburger is in the top three or four around town, but it is right up in the top eight or ten. Rate this burger a B+. For a fast food joint they make a very good green chile burger. No other fast food restaurant in town makes a better one. Rate Blake&apos;s overall THREE STARS....but their green chile burger is four! February 7, 2010 Likes it First Place Out-of-Town Guests Want to Eat... by Bibliomaniac ( 4 reviews ) Okay--this is not your typical fast food. Though it may look like any other burger joint, you are in for a pleasant surprise! First of all, the burgers and fries are not made until you order them. This means they are hot and fresh. You may wait a while for your order, but it will be worth it! You have to get the cheeseburger with the green chiles on it. A New Mexico invention that is sooo yummy! Hubby gets the Lottaburger--it is huge. I prefer the Itsaburger; it is smaller but still plenty filling. We always bring out-of-town guests here--and on return visits it is the first place they want to go back to! In fact, when my husband was deployed overseas for eighteen months, Blake&apos;s was the first place he went to eat when he got back home to New Mexico! Don&apos;t expect much in the way of atmosphere. It looks kind of like an old-drive inn restaurant from the 1960s, complete with faded pictures on the walls. If you choose to eat on the front patio, you will be treated to a... more» Okay--this is not your typical fast food. Though it may look like any other burger joint, you are in for a pleasant surprise! First of all, the burgers and fries are not made until you order them. This means they are hot and fresh. You may wait a while for your order, but it will be worth it! You have to get the cheeseburger with the green chiles on it. A New Mexico invention that is sooo yummy! Hubby gets the Lottaburger--it is huge. I prefer the Itsaburger; it is smaller but still plenty filling. We always bring out-of-town guests here--and on return visits it is the first place they want to go back to! In fact, when my husband was deployed overseas for eighteen months, Blake&apos;s was the first place he went to eat when he got back home to New Mexico! Don&apos;t expect much in the way of atmosphere. It looks kind of like an old-drive inn restaurant from the 1960s, complete with faded pictures on the walls. If you choose to eat on the front patio, you will be treated to a beautiful view of the Organ Mountains to the east (though you will have to look past Hwy 70 in front of you...) But, no one comes to Blake&apos;s for the view--it is all about the awesome,spicy burgers. Hope you enjoy it! 
 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by Soup Fork Blake&apos;s... by Soup Fork Blake&apos;s... 
 View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 Wienerschnitzel $ Las Cruces - Fast Food, Burgers, Hot Dogs/Sausages Sonic Drive-in $ Las Cruces - Burgers, Fast Food Spanish Kitchen 69% Las Cruces - Mexican Sports Dogs 94% $ Las Cruces - Hot Dogs/Sausages SportsDogs Everyones a... $ Las Cruces - Hot Dogs/Sausages, American 
 More nearby restaurants People reached this page by searching for: 
 blakes lota burger las cruces blakes lotaburger in las cruces blakes lotaburger las cruses new mexico 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
