<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002401" url="http://newyork.citysearch.com/profile/7158426/new_york_ny/sushi_you.html" time="2012-07-12-18:20" support="3" score="0.004125943093461468" bingtitle="Sushi You - New York, NY, 10022 - Citysearch" webtitle="Sushi You - New York, NY, 10022 - Citysearch">
			<query id="000995" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="001001" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000984" bing-rank="134"/>
	<description>If you order a california roll and chicken cutlet bento box, then Go Sushi is around the corner. Also this is not a fast food restaurant ... you should expect ...</description>
	<body>
		Deals Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Hotels Shopping Best Of Citysearch 

 Mobile Login / Join 
 More More Go! Advertise With Us 
 Citysearch has shed its old skin! In addition to our new look, there&apos;s a boatload of new features. Poke around! Tell us what you think! 
 New York, NY Metro &gt; Manhattan &gt; Restaurants &gt; Sushi You 
Sushi You
 (212) 752-2987 
 246 E 51st St , New York , NY | Directions  
 10022 40.756101 -73.969801 
 Menu Share Save 
   Own this Business? Recommend this business? Thumbs Up Thumbs Down ? 67 % 100 6 6 Votes Add a Photo Neighborhoods: Midtown East, Midtown East (Turtle Bay), Midtown Cuisine: Japanese Categories: Restaurants 
 View More 
 Payment Methods: MasterCard, Visa 
 View Less 
 At a Glance ? 
 100% food quality
 “In a sense, it&apos;s like any authentic experience, the more interest you show in traditional japanese food and how it was meant to be eaten (don&apos;t drown your sushi in soy sauce), the more the owners warm to you.” 
 50% service
 “Most restaurants that set up this way will slide the tables to accomadate whatever size party comes in so although the place was 20% full, I thought that I would be nice and slide the half of our table over slightly, as a waitress typically would do anywa” Site Feedback 
 Overview Tips (6) Photos (0) 
 Write a Tip for Sushi You 
 Sign in to Write a Tip 
 Write a Tip... optional 
 
 
Tips for Sushi You
 Recommends goodgoo Joined 1 years ago 5.0 January 31, 2011 
 Why don&apos;t you go?. I went SUSHI YOU first time with my Japanese friend at lunch time.
It was almost packed small this restaurant, but there was 4seats available. We order CHIRASHI SUSHI, which my Japanese friend recommended.

It was my first time to eat not piece SUSHI.

CHIRASHI SUSHI is... From WIKIPEDIA :-)

Chirashizushi (=CHIRASHI SUSHI) is a bowl of sushi rice with other ingredients mixed in (also refers to barazushi). It is commonly eaten in Japan because it is filling, fast and easy to make. Chirashizushi most often varies regionally because it is eaten annually as a part of the Doll Festival, celebrated only during March in Japan. The ingredients are often chef&apos;s choice. Edomae chirashizushi (Edo-style scattered sushi) is an uncooked ingredient that is arranged artfully on top of the sushi rice in a bowl.

SUSHI YOU CHIRASHI SUSHI is really great taste and a lot of variety of SASHIMI !!

I went back to SUSHI YOU night time again.

Chef is cute Japanese Sushi chef !

I like to see him make Sushi all the time.

Taste great too.

Why don&apos;t you go SUSHI YOU?

I highly recommend this restaurant. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends akkima Joined 2 years ago 5.0 November 11, 2010 
 Best Good Sushi Restaurant in East Midtown!. I Knew Sushi You long time.
But, I didn&apos;t know it&apos;s a new ownership from 2010 September.
I loved former Sushi you too, But I love New Sushi You than old one. Because of the young sushi chef is really nice person!

Of course all Sushi are delicious.

Price also good!!

If you don&apos;t know how to order sushi, you can ask him OMAKASE which chef can arrange for you by your favor or your budget.

I like around 50th street 2nd avenue area, there are a lot of choice to eat.

I really recommend Sushi You !! … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends SA0 Joined 2 years ago 5.0 August 31, 2010 
 Great sushi in a hole in the wall. I signed up for citysearch account so I could write about this place. I think it is the real deal. I went there for lunch today because I was in the neighborhood. I had the sashimi deluxe for $16. I think it was fantastic at any price.

It is nothing fancy, just fresh fish served courteously and authentically. Just a chef behind the bar, and his wife serving the food. There were about 15 other people there at lunch, and I was the only one who was not Japanese. I think the word of mouth for this place among the Japanese must be very strong.

I intend to go again, and maybe do an omakase. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends MikeAiken Joined 4 years ago 5.0 March 17, 2008 
 Sushi is the equal of anywhere in the city. The other reviews here are interesting as I can see where they are coming from. But get to know this husband and wife team (plus maybe one or two other staff members), then you feel right at home and on subsequent visits you are treated like family.

The key is that they take their sushi (and the broader menu) very seriously. In a sense, it&apos;s like any authentic experience, the more interest you show in traditional japanese food and how it was meant to be eaten (don&apos;t drown your sushi in soy sauce), the more the owners warm to you. If you order a california roll and chicken cutlet bento box, then Go Sushi is around the corner.

Also this is not a fast food restaurant, the gentlemen behind the counter is a master sushi chef and takes ownership of every piece of sushi he prepares for you. He makes the same amount of effort in ordering the freshest sushi to put on your plate. This may take an extra bit of time but man have you found a secret.

If you come here, you should expect some of the best sushi in the city (the equal, if not better than Nobu.) In fact, with the exception of what Masa flies in from Japan and other countries (which of course is very expensive), I would bet the locally ordered fish is from a comparable source. Alternately, if you want a wait staff hovering over your table and recommending warm saki, then Haru is more your liking.

For my first experience, I ordered a basic lunch bento box (hey, I was on a lunch budget) and was so shocked by the sushi quality that I walked up to the sushi chef and asked his background. Just to make sure it wasn&apos;t because it was the ubiquitous salmon and yellow tail, I returned for dinner and ordered omakase. I was floored. Basically, you should consider Sushi You as if a sushi master had retired and opened his kitchen to a few friends and family. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Doesn&apos;t Recommend amw22 Joined 6 years ago 2.0 December 06, 2006 
 You may not want to go if you&apos;re not Japanese. I also never write reviews, but felt so awful after the way my father and I were treated at dinner tonight I had to. When we stepped in from the cold there was a table for two in the back, which my dad started to, but the waitress motioned us to one right by the door. Next to walk in were two Japanese businessmen, and they were shown the table in the back. After a very long wait, our food arrived, but even though we started, and waited another 10-15 minutes, my dad&apos;s soup and rice, plus a saucer for me to pour soy sauce into, never arrived. It took another 5 minutes for the waitress to pay attention to us--which, given the size of the space (an alcove below street level, about the size of a small dry cleaner&apos;s), was rather astonishing. We explained what was missing. She said, it&apos;s coming. She walked back to the kitchen, and came back with food for other tables. She refilled water glasses at other tables. She stood on the side a bit. Finally she noticed us trying to catch her eye, and went back to the kitchen. Five minutes later, the bowl of rice came. She left so quickly we could hardly utter we were still missing a soup and a saucer. Eventually she came back with the saucer. We had to mention the soup again. My dad had almost finished his grilled fish by then. As I watched him pick at the bones and fins I realized it looked nothing like the long, tender fillet that those at the next table were eating--and the waitress had mentioned this was the restaurant&apos;s cooked fish option, so it was supposed to be the same dish! Trying to pay became another ordeal: waiting, and waiting, then finding out we couldn&apos;t charge our meal because we were short their minimum--by cents. We waited to get change for cash. When that didn&apos;t look likely, we counted out exact change. I didn&apos;t want to leave a tip; my dad left 20%. The only difference between us and the others that I could see was that they were Japanese, and we were not. We have never been made to feel so out of place. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart 
 See more tips for Sushi You 
 Write a Tip for Sushi You 
 Sign in to Write a Tip 
 Write a Tip... optional 
 
 
People who viewed this also viewed…
 
 79 % Megu Midtown 845 United Nations Plz 
 New York, NY 
0.3 mi away 78 % Riingo Restaurant 205 E 45th St 
 New York, NY 
0.3 mi away 89 % Fusia Asian Cuisine 677C Lexington Ave 
 New York, NY 
0.3 mi away 
 
Things to do near Sushi You
 
 Restaurants Movie Theaters Banks 

 Bars Shopping&amp;Malls Hotels 
 
 About Apps Careers Privacy Policy Terms of Use Contact Us Blog FAQs 
 
Partner Sites:

 Ask Kids     Bloglines     Expedia     Hotels     Hotwire     Insider Pages     MerchantCircle     Reference     The Daily Beast     Thesaurus     Urbanspoon 
 ©2011. Citysearch is a registered trademark of CityGrid Media. Data provided by Infogroup. All rights reserved. 
 Popular Categories Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Shopping Hotels Deals Sports&amp;Recreation Cafes Movie Theaters Directory&amp;Services 

 Change City New York City Los Angeles Houston Chicago Atlanta Seattle Portland Philadelphia Austin San Francisco More…
	</body>
</document>
