<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002490" url="http://www.alibaba.com/product-free/104990660/GASTRONORM.html" time="2012-07-12-18:33" support="9" score="0.020936918030711505" bingtitle="GASTRONORM products, buy GASTRONORM products from alibaba.com" webtitle="Gastronorm - Buy Gastronorm Product on Alibaba.com">
			<query id="000292" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000530" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000403" bing-rank="228"/>
			<query id="000729" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000405" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="000528" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001346" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000749" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="001344" bing-rank="54"/>
	<description>Model Number: GASTRONORM TRAY 2-1 PERFORATED ... Enter the product you are looking for in the Search ... for fast food restaurant gbl association foodservice supplies</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to Alibaba.com, Join Free | Sign In 

 Buy 
 Newly Added Products How to Buy Safety&amp;Security Center Post Buying Requests Browse assessed suppliers 
 Sell 
 Newly Added RFQs How to Sell Display New Products Manage Products 
 Community 
 Ask It! Forums Price Watch AliDictionary Trade Shows 
 My Alibaba 
 Message Center Check My Contacts Display New Products Manage Products Post Buying Requests Download TradeManager Premium Memberships 
 My Favorites 

 Help 
 Help Center Submit a Complaint Report IPR Infringement Suggestion Contact Us 
 
 Alibaba.com Products 
 Products Suppliers Buyers 
 Advanced Search Post Buying Request About 567 results: Other Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supplies (269) More... Less There are 567 GASTRONORM from at least 86 suppliers on Alibaba.com Related Searches: GASTRONORM , gastronorm container , pan gastronorm , Wholesale GASTRONORM Home &gt; Products &gt; Service Equipment &gt; Restaurant&amp;Hotel Supplies &gt; Other Hotel&amp;Restaurant Supplies (69339) Language Options 
 French German Italian Russian Spanish Portuguese Korean Japanese Arabic 
 
GASTRONORM
 
 FOB Price: Get Latest Price 
 Mr. ezat elbaz Unverified Company eagle [
 Egypt
 ] 



 Contact Details View this Supplier&apos;s Website See larger image: GASTRONORM Report Suspicious Activity Suspicious activities include posting prohibited/restricted item, fraud, etc. Add to My Favorites Online Showroom: 50 Products  Similar Products from this Supplier Product Details Company Profile Quick Details 
 Place of Origin: Turkey Brand Name: BILGE Model Number: GASTRONORM TRAY 2-1 PERFORATED 
 Specifications 
GASTRONORM TRAY 2-1 PERFORATED
 
 GnSize 2/1 Clearance 600 x 500 mm ExternalDimensions 650 x 530 mm 

 200 mm 150 mm 100 mm 065 mm 040 mm . 020 mm 
 Eagle international for import and export was established to provide its customers with easy access to finest goods, our staff has extensive experience with Italy `s and Germany&apos;s markets, we pride ourselves on our commitment to quality, reliability and speed. Most of our customers come from Middle East countries, Take a moment to pay attention to the information of our company, if we can be of help to you, we will bring Italy andGermany to your door.
Our mission
Our goal is to bring Italy and ...
 View more &gt;&gt; 
 
Basic Information

 Product/Service (We Sell): gas valve,thermostat,selector,hotplats,gastronorm,silicon cabel,heater,adjustable foot,cast knee valve,cast double foot valve,spray valve,pre-rinse unit,burner,thermocabel,fryer basket,catering equipment,catering accessories,kitchen accessories,hotel kitchen accessories,cooker spar parts  Product/Service (We Buy): gas valve,thermostat,selector,hotplats,gastronorm,silicon cabel,heater,adjustable foot,cast knee valve,cast double foot valve,spray valve,pre-rinse unit,burner,thermocabel,fryer basket  Number of Employees: 11 - 50 People  
 
Trade&amp;Market

 Main Markets: Africa
Mid East
 Total Annual Sales Volume: US$1 Million - US$2.5 Million  Export Percentage: 71% - 80%  Total Annual Purchase Volume: US$2.5 Million - US$5 Million  
 
Substantiated Complaints Received over last 90 days

 Reason for Complaint Status Settlement Date {{ajaxTableContent}}
 Send your message to this supplier From: Enter email or Member ID Password:  Enter Alibaba.com Password. Forgot your password? Enter the code shown: Load new image To: Mr. ezat elbaz eagle Message: Enter your inquiry details such as product name, color, size, MOQ, FOB, etc. Enter between 20 to 8,000 characters. Send Sourcing Products&amp;Suppliers on Alibaba.com Search Products Enter the product you are looking for in the Search Bar and click Search Contact Suppliers Click Contact Now to send an inquiry or I’m online, Chat now to chat online Check Messages Check quotes&amp;messages from suppliers in your email inbox or Message Center Click here to learn more Loading... Buyers who viewed this product also viewed Page 1 of 1
	</body>
</document>
