<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002527" url="http://rnbphilly.com/2243402/mice-infest-burger-buns-at-local-fast-food-restaurant/" time="2012-07-12-18:35" support="2" score="0.0010050165569810575" bingtitle="Mice Infest Burger Buns At Local Fast Food Restaurant | 100.3 WRNB" webtitle="Mice Infest Burger Buns At Local Fast Food Restaurant | 100.3 WRNB">
			<query id="001377" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="001484" bing-rank="235"/>
	<description>... to the former employee, mice are nothing new at this fast food restaurant. He claims the manager order ... Discussion: Ariz. Governor Signs Bill To Allow Bible Classes ...</description>
	<body>
		BP NEXT BP Radio The Urban Daily Hello Beautiful NewsOne Elev8 GIANTLife TV One Jobs Black Doctor 
 Subscribe 
 
 Follow @rnbphilly 
Thursday, July 12
 
Main menu
 Skip to primary content Skip to secondary content 
 Home RNBPhilly 
 Entertainment News Photos Videos 
 Tri-State 
 Local News Philadelphia Weather Philadelphia Traffic 
 Music 
 Local Music 
 Events Contests On-Air 
 DJs Music Playlist Listen Live 
 Contact Us 
 About Advertise With Us Mobile Text Club Facebook Twitter 
 Jobs 
 Internships 
 
 
 Local Weather Local Traffic Listen Live!
 On Blackplanet Radio 
 Home  &gt;  Local News  &gt; Mice Infest Burger Buns At Local Fast Food Restaurant 
Mice Infest Burger Buns At Local Fast Food Restaurant
 Jan 17, 2012 0 Comments By RNBPhilly 
 

A local McDonald’s has a serious rodent problem. Fox news has reported that a former employee video taped a mouse running around in a bag of Big Mac hamburger buns, enjoying a meal as he nibbled on bread that was later served to costumers. According to the former employee, mice are nothing new at this fast food restaurant. He claims the manager order employees to wipe off mice feces and continue to served the buns as long as the mice didn’t nibble on the bread.
 
“I was going back there to get something else and I heard some rustling, so I turned around, and I look, I seen a mouse inside the bread. Not on top of the package, but inside of the package,”said the former employee.
 
 Click Here to read more of the story
 

 
Tags: mice in big bac &gt; mice mcdonalds &gt; mouse in macdonalds bun 
 Newer Post → ← Older Post 
 
More Related Content
 
 
Comments
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. blog comments powered by Disqus 
 
In The Studio
 Listen Live!
 On Blackplanet Radio DC Todd DC Todd Email • Posts 
 On-Air-Schedule: Lady B 3:00p - 7:00p MoShay LaRen 7:00p - 12:00a The Tom Joyner Morning Show 6:00a - 10:00a DC Todd 10:00a - 3:00p 
 advertisement 
Features
 
 Gossip The Basement Party Local News Tom Joyner Morning Show New Music Sports Photos Videos 
 
Most Popular

 Guess Which Singer Who Was Just Dumped By Her Baby Daddy Is Pregnant AGAIN? Michael Vick Wedding Pictures [Photos] 
 advertisement 
Philadelphia Yellow Pages
 Business: City: State: Alabama Alaska Arizona Arkansas California Colorado Connecticut Delaware District of Columbia Florida Georgia Hawaii Idaho Illinois Indiana Iowa Kansas Kentucky Louisiana Maine Maryland Massachusetts Michigan Minnesota Mississippi Missouri Montana Nebraska Nevada New Hampshire New Jersey New Mexico New York North Carolina North Dakota Ohio Oklahoma Oregon Pennsylvania Rhode Island South Carolina South Dakota Tennessee Texas Utah Vermont Virginia Washington West Virginia Wisconsin Wyoming 
 advertisement 
 
 
 Around the Web 

 
 PraisePhilly.com 

 Alicia Keys “Keep A Child Alive” To Honor Oprah Winfrey Bishop Secular: Where’s The Love In Reality TV? [EXCLUSIVE AUDIO] LHS: Clues and Categories with Neicy T 7-11-12 [AUDIO] State Abbreviations Sanctified Sermon Topic: Tic Toc It Don’t Stop [AUDIO] Black Woman Are Among Country’s Most Religious Groups 
 
 Hot1079Philly.com 

 Christina Milian Disappointed In The Dream! (Video) Philly Pastor Says “F” Meek Mill For Making “Amen” [Exclusive Video] DJ DAMAGE Leaks Caution Tape 2 Intro By DJ Drama Why Is Hip-Hop So Controversial? [Opinion] Move Over Beyonce, Jay-Z Reveals His Celebrity Crush! 
 
 TheUrbanDaily.com 

 Tameka Foster’s Friends Defend Her Bad Mother Reputation Rapping Paster Says “F” Meek Mill For Making “Amen,” Meek Mill Responds Nas Previews ‘Life Is Good’ At ESPY Awards [VIDEO] Is Kanye West “Whipped?” Cynthia Bailey On Sheree Whitfield, “Love and Hip Hop: Atlanta” 
 
 HelloBeautiful.com 

 Is NeNe Leakes Getting The Boot From “RHOA?” Who Do These 3 Little Beauties Belong To? [PHOTO] Christina Milian Blasts The Dream’s Parenting Skills [VIDEO] Dads Need Work-Life Balance Support Too Professor&amp;Author, Dr. Ebony Utley, Releases New Provocative Book, “Rap And Religion: Understanding The Gangsta’s God” 
 
 
 
 Top Stories 

 Will The Philadelphia School District Ever Recover? Female Celebrities And Their Dads Sisterlocks VS. Traditional Locs The World’s Worst Weaves 
 About Us: 
 About Us Privacy About Our Ads Terms of Service Advertising EEO Careers 
 
 Copyright©2012, Interactive One . All Rights Reserved Powered by WordPress.com VIP
	</body>
</document>
