<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002256" url="http://gulfportwatchdog.com/2010/11/twisted-tarpon-on-st-pete-beach/" time="2012-07-12-18:09" support="2" score="0.0026586321251071176" bingtitle="TWISTED TARPON ON ST. PETE BEACH | GULFPORT WATCHDOG" webtitle="TWISTED TARPON ON ST. PETE BEACH | GULFPORT WATCHDOG">
			<query id="001417" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000569" bing-rank="172"/>
	<description>... especially since we buried our loose change in the ... was similar to something you will find at a fast food restaurant. ... Most likely , I would have changed my order. I can ...</description>
	<body>
		Log In Register 
 
 Home 2009 2010 2011 Articles Election 2011 Foodie Alert 
 
 Contact Gulfport Watchdog 

 Subscribe 
 

 
MISSION STATEMENT

 To create an informed electorate through accurate reporting and publication of news and thoughtful opinion on all matters affecting local government which includes City Government, Pinellas County Government and all other entities which have a direct impact on Gulfport. To provide a voice in local affairs to residents of all sections of the City and to create understanding among various factions in the City. To promote environmental awareness, patronage of local businesses by local citizens, responsible economic development and the work of the Gulfport Community Foundation. To stimulate involvement in local government by a larger percentage of our citizens.
 
 

 
TWISTED TARPON ON ST. PETE BEACH
 By Foodie Adventurer 
I have visited this new St. Pete Beach restaurant three times in a week; they didn’t have to do any twisting to get my attention.

I recently was looking for a new adult, casual-dining experience with a couple visitors, but I had three Grands (9, 7 and 5 years old) tagging along, too. I found the spot that satisfied all of us for lunch: the new Twisted Tarpon restaurant. Filthy Phil’s kicked the bucket so to speak, so the Sloppy Pelican restaurant next store reopened the two-decker, beach-front Filthy Phil’s restaurant as the Twisted Tarpon and expanded it with a huge outdoor area that includes a horseshoe bar, large-screen TV, dining tables, and a sandy-beachy dining experience splashed with colorful Adirondack chairs and low tables.

The sandy area provided a spot for the Grands to explore, especially since we buried our loose change in the sand for their enjoyment and an impromptu treasure hunt. The wait staff was efficient, friendly, and easy on the eyes.

I enjoyed margaritas ($3.00 all day) that didn’t taste like limeade. I asked for a cocktail that wouldn’t make me gag on the sugar syrup, and at all three recent visits, the bartenders filled my request, happily. The food from their tempting menu was freshly prepared, hot, and exploding with flavor. The potato skins were the real thing, not reheated, leftover baked potatoes. These were Idaho potato boats, with crunch, melted flavorful cheese, crisp bacon, and a sprinkling of fresh chives. I had forgotten how good potato skins could be.

Anything we ordered with prime rib was a melt-in-your mouth experience. My friends had prime rib sandwiches, and I had the prime rib quesadilla with caramelized onions and roasted sweet red peppers. My dip of choice was blue cheese instead of the usual ranch served, for if you savor crumbled blue cheese atop your sizzling grilled beef, then you will want to go with this beef flavor enhancement.

The blackened Mahi Mahi was thick, flaky, moist. And the seasoning was just enough to allow the sweetness of the fish to come through. Our seafood platter had the plumpest scallops I ever had on a platter. The batter added a nice, flavorful, ungreasy crunch for the bar-food fanatics that were visiting us. Our only disappointment was the melted dipping“butter”they served, which was really thick, yellow margarine glop.

The manager agreed that the food they serve deserved real butter. They also are putting in needed dimmer lighting indoors and in the outdoor dining areas, which should cut down on the garish glare that I found unpleasant. Also, I hope they get the closed caption turned on the TV for those folks who come to chill out and catch some sport highlights and would like to know what the announcer is saying.

The Grands were happy with their juicy burgers with all the trimmings, and finding some loot in the sand to go on a Dollar-Store run made for a relaxing afternoon with friends and family.

Wishing you many gatherings of family and friends at this fun spot with delish food!

Foodie Adventurer
November 18, 2010

Twisted Tarpon
678 75th Ave
St Pete Beach, FL 33706
(727) 367-9977

P.S. What’s Up with The Wharf Restaurant?

2001 Pass A Grille Way
St. Pete Beach, FL 33706
(727) 367-9469
Fax (727) 637-9729

I have enjoyed the atmosphere and basic seafood dishes in the past and usually brought visitors, too. The food served on Sunday, November 14, was“gag”able. I couldn’t find any seafood in the seafood chowder. It was really a leftover baked potato soup with a thick floury, gummy, sitting-on-the stove-for-days sauce. The potato skins, again where leftover baked potatoes, with a greyish color, and a nasty texture and taste that was sickening. The oysters were a tasteless, overcooked mess. I guess they are raking in the alcohol money and don’t need to worry about giving the locals and visitors a tasteful dining experience. Or maybe it was just a bad night…a real bad night!

 This entry was posted
 on Monday, November 22nd, 2010 at 8:59 am and is filed under Foodie Alert .
 You can follow any responses to this entry through the RSS 2.0 feed.

 You can skip to the end and leave a response. Pinging is currently not allowed. 
 
7 Responses to“TWISTED TARPON ON ST. PETE BEACH”
 
 2iview November 22, 2010 at 11:11 am 
Sounds like a place I would like to try! Thanks!

To bad about the Wharf.

I found the same sort of experience with Billy’s. For years they were a good place to entertain visitors but my past few experiences have not been up to par.

I’m looking forward to the Neptune Grill!
 Foodie Adventurer December 4, 2010 at 8:51 am 
I had to go back to Twisted Tarpon to try some of their other menu items and their $3 (all day) margaritas. (Woody’s has a happy-hour margarita, but it is not their standard. You get that sugary mix from a plastic bottle. I don’t know how they think that this promotion would entice anyone to buy their regular margarita, since unless you ask, you don’t know that they are differenly made drinks.) The margaritas at Twisted Tarpon were made just the way I like them. I told the bartenders I didn’t want limeade,and everytime they give me just the right sweet-sour&amp;tequila explosion I enjoy.

I thought the frozen french fries were homemade: large thin spears of idahoes with the skin left on, giving me an outter crunchy and inner creamy treat. The huge, homemade grilled burger was cooked perfectly,dripping with personality and flavor and cheese and red onions and roasted sweet peppers. My husband’s haddock was dressed in a tasty, delicatly crisy coat that highlighted the tender fish, not overpowering it.

They gladly substitute the fries for an excellent cold, fresh-made coleslaw or the veggie for the day.

I’m wondering if their desserts have been given as much thought as their other menu items? I guess I’ll have to check it out!
 larry December 19, 2010 at 7:27 pm 
Worst crap delivered as a customer. They will be out of business soone. Liquor sales is what the owners care sbout. Service and quality of food is the worst
 Michelle Jones December 20, 2010 at 5:49 pm 
I went to the Twisted Tarpon last night and the food was horrific. I ordered a cheese burger that was similar to something you will find at a fast food restaurant. My husband had a burger also and he was equally unimpressed. The manager, a young man with long-hair came by to ask how our food was which was nice. I told him that it was not very good and he said that I was the first person to complain and that I probably don’t know what a good burger tastes like. How mean. The restaurant was empty on a Friday night which is not a good sign.
 donnbee December 22, 2010 at 10:31 am 
I was hoping for a wonderful experience at Twisted Tarpon, I was a great fan of Philthy Phil’s. Unfortunately, it was horrible. The service was very slow. I had the endles salad, soup and bread sticks. Well I was served at huge bowl of lettuce, I mean just lettuce. When I questioned the server, she yes that is how we serve our endless salad. I think in all fairness, they should give the customer warning on that, suchas, instead of calling it a“salad”, say it is a chopped wedge salad and I would have known it was only lettuce. They should have informed me that there were no bread sticks being served that day. They were served rolls, when questioned I was told all bread was made fresh every day and they did not make bread sticks today. Okay, perhaps they should have mentioned it when I ordered. I had two small cups of soup. I know you are thinking, I should have went to Olive Garden. When I seen this offered on the menu, I thought it sounded good. It was either $6.95 or $7.95 so it wasn’t a GREAT deal. Actually, it was no deal at all because it certainly wasn’t what I expected!!!! The server was did not have a concern in the world for my dissatisfaction. I still tipped her, however, not like I would have. It would have been so simple, when I ordered that, she could have said“we are serving fresh made rolls today, instead of bread sticks. Will that be okay?”Most likely , I would have changed my order. I can always get rolls, hot fresh bread sticks are hard to come by. Merry Christmas everyone!!!!
 Sandy Gatewood January 1, 2011 at 10:37 am 
My husband&amp;I tried the Twisted Tarpon, it was Twisted alright, worst service I have ever received when we received our food, we were ask if we wanted a to go box, I ask were they closing, the waiter said no&amp;walked away, RUDE&amp;the manager had a real attitude, just because we complained we did not get our drinks when we ordered nor did we get extra butter we ordered. The manager proceeded to tell us our credit card was no good, I told him it was fine when we had ordered a drink at the bar downstairs&amp;he proceeded to raise his voice the bill was $38.35 my husband proceeded to hand him $40&amp;we left. We stopped at our bank to check the credit card balance and there is no problem with the credit card. I would not recommend this restaurant to anyone, just because of the manager&amp;I heard from someone else he does not like gray haired people, funny he will be gray before his time if he continues to talk to people the way he did us.
 Foodie Adventurer January 3, 2011 at 11:55 pm 
I’ve been out of town for a few weeks, but will check the Twisted Tarpon again. Maybe the chef left or new management is in place. Sorry Ms. Jones got a fast-food type cheesburger. Mine was a house-made 1/2 pound of juicy deliciousness on a homemade bun, not the thin, tasteless, overcooked stuff that comes off of an assembly line.
The whole group I was with on a couple of occasions was raving about the atmosphere, food and service, but things can change. I expect employees of near-by restaurants may want to put down the new boy in town, not finding one positive thing to comment on. But not hearing any positive comments from other diners makes me think there may be something to all the negative ones. I hope it was just a holiday glitch!
Foodie Adventurer
 
 
Leave a Reply
 Click here to cancel reply. 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (will not be published) (required) 

 Website 
 CAPTCHA Code * 
 

 

 
 
How to Read Full Articles:
 Please click on the Title of the articles to read the full articles. 

Click on the GULFPORT WATCHDOG heading to bring you back to the Home Page. 
Join us on Facebook
 
Paypal Payment
 Donation to Gulfport Watchdog 

 Donation 

 Other Amount: 

 

 Your Email Address : 

 

 
Latest Articles

 WATCHDOG TAKES A BREAK! PIA’S SAVES FOODIE FROM GASTRONOMIC MELTDOWN ABSENCE MAKES THE HEART GROW FONDER! GULFPORT’S SILVER LINING! MORE “NO BRAINER” CUTS AND CASH! 
 
Recent Comments

 DogFish on GULFPORT: A SLUM CITY? DogFish on WATCHDOG TAKES A BREAK! Cecilia on GULFPORT: A SLUM CITY? Frank Verdino on CRUNCHING THE BUDGET CRUNCH! 2iview on WATCHDOG TAKES A BREAK! David Hastings on WATCHDOG TAKES A BREAK! 
 
Contributors
 Any person who, in the interest of creating a more informed, more involved citizenry in the social, political and commercial well being of the city of Gulfport may submit articles or comments to The Gulfport Watchdog. 

All news items are welcome.

Anonymous submissions will not be accepted.

The editor reserves the right to edit and/or reject any item submitted without exception.

Preliminary discussions via e-mail are encouraged.

Editor:
 “Big Dog” 
(Bob Newcomb)

Social Media Editor:
 Margarete Tober 

Contributors:
 “Bird Dog 18” 
(Al Davis)

 &quot;DogFish&quot; 
(Jim Greenwald)

 Foodie Adventurer 
(Rose-Marie Seawall)

 Copyright©2012 GULFPORT WATCHDOG . All Rights Reserved.
 Magazine Basic theme designed by c.bavota of Tinker Priest Media .
Powered by WordPress .
	</body>
</document>
