<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002224" url="http://www.goodtimesburgers.com/company.html" time="2012-07-12-18:07" support="1" score="0.0025327850303279746" bingtitle="Company : Good Times Burgers &amp; Frozen Custard" webtitle="Company : Good Times Burgers&amp;Frozen Custard">
			<query id="001439" bing-rank="149"/>
	<description>Good Times Burgers &amp; Frozen Custard - All-Natural Beef, Fresh-Cut Fries, Frozen Custard Made Fresh Daily.</description>
	<body>
		Our Story  /  Executive Info  /  News  /  Investor Relations  /  Franchise Info 
 
 
 Good Times Restaurants Inc. opened its first restaurant in 1987 in Boulder, Colorado. 

The Company owns and operates, and franchises, restaurants in Colorado, Wyoming, and North Dakota.

We are a quick service restaurant chain serving a high quality, fresh, unique, proprietary selection of hamburgers made with Meyer All-Natural, All-Angus beef, specialty chicken sandwiches, signature Wild Fries and Fresh Cut Fries, Beer Battered Onion Rings and fresh, creamy Frozen Custard in a variety of flavors, sundaes and Spoonbenders.

Good Times has been a public company since 1992 and is traded on Nasdaq Smallcap, ticker: GTIM

Our corporate offices are located at 601 Corporate Circle, Golden, Colorado 80401. You may reach us by phone at (303) 384-1400.
 
 Executive Management Team 


 Boyd E. Hoback 
President&amp;CEO

 Scott G. LeFever 
Vice President of Operations

 Susan M. Knutson 
Controller

 Nicholas G. Biegel 
Director of Product Development

 Nicholas B. Corbishley 
Director of Marketing

 William K. Mitchell 
Director of Franchise Operations

 Gary N. Staton 
Director of Human Resources
 
 Board of Directors 


 David L. Dobbin 
Chairman

 Geoffrey R. Bailey 
Director, Member of the Compensation and Executive Committees

 Gary J. Heller 
Director

 Boyd E. Hoback 
Director

 Keith A. Radford 
Director, Chairman of the Audit Committee

 Eric W. Reinhard 
Director, Member of the Compensation&amp;Executive Committees

 Alan A. Teran 
Director, Member of the Audit Committee and Chairman of the Compensation Committee

 
 The Good Times Times 

Contact: Christi Pennington, Executive Assistant christi@gtrestaurants.com 

---
Tuesday, June 19, 2012
 Good Times Enters Into A Material Definitive Agreement 

Burger Business Article: Look Out Good Times Makes Its Move! 

Wednesday, April 11, 2012
 Good Times Announces Heathcote Capital Engagement 


Thursday, April 5, 2012
 Good Times Announces March Sales Increase 

Monday, March 12, 2012
 Good Times Raises Over $42,000 For Type 1 Diabetes Research 


Thursday, March 8, 2012
 Good Times Teams with Room 214 For Social Media 

Monday, January 9, 2012
 G ood Times Reports 1st Quarter Sales Results 


Tuesday, November 15, 2011
 Good Times Reports Continued Improvement In Sales Results  


Monday, October 3, 2011
 Good Times Announces Cheech&amp;Chong Radio Campaign 


Monday, September 12, 2011
 Good Times Introduces New Products Featuring Santiago&apos;s Authentic Green Chile 


Tuesday, April 5, 2011
Denver Business Journal

 Good Times chooses Sukle Advertising 
Good Times Restaurants Inc. has hired Sukle Advertising&amp;Design of Denver as its new advertising agency. The Golden-based restaurant chain (Nasdaq: GTIM) retained Sukle Advertising for fiscal 2011, which began Oct. 1, 2010. Sukle Advertising has been tasked with coming up with new packaging, menu boards and employee uniforms. The agency previously has worked with another Denver-area restaurant chain, Noodles&amp;Company. 

 (click here for more) 

 Investor Relations 

 2012 

 Form 8K Election of a Director Form 8K Departure of a Director Form 8K Entry Into A Material Agreement 
 Securities Purchase Agreement 
 Quarterly Report Form 10-Q: 2nd quarter 2012 
 XBRL Instance Document (Q2 2012) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Schema (Q2 2012) XBRL Extension Calculation Linkbase (Q2 2012) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Definition Linkbase (Q2 2012) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Label Linkbase (Q2 2012) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Presentation Linkbase (Q2 2012) 
 

 Form 8K Entry Into A Material Agreement and Election of Director 

 Quarterly Report on Form 10-Q: 1st quarter 2012 
 XBRL Instance Document (Q1 2012) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Schema (Q1 2012) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Calculation Linkbase (Q1 2012) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Definition Linkbase (Q1 2012) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Label Linkbase (Q1 2012) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Presentation Linkbase (Q1 2012) 
 

 Form 8-K Amended and Restated Agreement w/Wells Fargo 

 Annual Report (10K) 
 XBRL Instance Document (10K 2011) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Schema (10K 2011) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Calculation Linkbase (10K 2011) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Definition Linkbase (10K 2011) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Label Linkbase (10K 2011) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Presentation Linkbase (10K 2011) 
 
 2011 
 Form 8-K  Results from Annual Meeting and Other Events Proxy Statement and Notice of Annual Meeting Quarterly Report (Q3 2011) 
 XBRL Instance Document (Q3 2011) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Schema (Q3 2011) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Calculation Linkbase (Q3 2011) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Definition Linkbase (Q3 2011) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Label Linkbase (Q3 2011) XBRL Taxonomy Extension Presentation Linkbase (Q3 2011) 
 Quarterly Report (Q2 2011) Quarterly Report (Q1 2011) 
   
 
 2010 
 Proxy Statement Quarterly Report (Q1 2010) Quarterly Report (Q2 2010) Quarterly Report (Q3 2010) Annual Report (10K) 

 Corporate Governance 

 Code of Ethics (pdf) Audit Committee Charter (pdf) 

Our public filings can also be retrieved from the EDGAR database at www.sec.gov. 


 Contact 

Investor Relations Contact christi@gtrestaurants.com Franchise Info 

Good Times offers a concept that serves success, opportunity and fun. We provide our franchisees with a high level of support and personal care throughout the franchise process. Good Times seeks both individual and multi-unit development franchisees for development in western and mid-western markets.

Good Times is currently limiting franchise opportunities to those candidates who possess both the financial capacity and business experience, preferably with an operating partner with experience in the quick service restaurant industry. Good Times provides training teams; real estate, design and construction support; operations support; product development; marketing support and, purchasing programs. We are very selective when awarding a Good Times franchise. We want this to be more than a fifteen year business relationship and we want it to be a rewarding endeavor for both parties.


 Basic requirements to own a Good Times franchise: 

 The term of a Good Times franchise is 15 years, plus renewal options A minimum of $300,000 in liquid assets (not including your home, personal items or borrowed funds) and a net worth of $750,000 You or your Operating Partner must have prior or current successful restaurant experience Royalty fees are 4% of gross sales* Advertising fees range from 3.5% to 5.5% of gross sales 


 Markets available for franchising: 
 A potential Good Times site should have a high daytime employment and retail activity, traffic count of at least 20,000 cars per day, business and strong residential population and not be a seasonal tourist destination. 


 Franchise Facts: 

 Good Times must approve all potential sites. We will assist you in site selection, architectural and construction, supplier selection, equipment, grand opening promotion and advertising. Good Times does not provide financing. We may assist qualified persons by recommending a third party lender. Good Times provides pre-opening training and materials and on-site opening support. 
 
If you feel you are a qualified candidate, please contact our franchise department, goodtimes@gtrestaurants.com, to obtain additional information, including a confidential application. 


*Traditional franchise site, this may change for special venues or licensee arrangements based on a variety of conditions and variables.

Legal Disclaimer: This information is not intended for an offer to sell or the solicitation of an offer to buy a franchise. It is for informational purposes only. California, Hawaii, Illinois, Indiana, Maryland, Michigan, Minnesota, New York, North Dakota, Oregon, Rhode Island, South Dakota, Virginia, Washington and Wisconsin regulate the offer and sale of franchises. If you are a resident of one of these states we will not offer you a franchise unless and until we have complied with applicable pre-sale registration and disclosure rights in your jurisdiction. 
 Menu Find Happiness Friends With Benefits Happiness Happens Company Contact Us 
 ©2012 Good Times Burgers&amp;Frozen Custard Legal + Privacy     Site Map     Employment
	</body>
</document>
