<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002225" url="http://www.flickr.com/photos/wafflewhiffer/4587505888/" time="2012-07-12-18:07" support="1" score="0.0017734976762582158" bingtitle="Phil A. O&apos;Fish - 1976 McDonald&apos;s | Flickr - Photo Sharing!" webtitle="Phil A. O&apos;Fish - 1976 McDonald&apos;s | Flickr - Photo Sharing!">
			<query id="001447" bing-rank="152"/>
	<description>... that would have been on a wall or near the menu board ... I mean,for a cheap low end fish sandwich. ... Fish; sandwich; Phil A. O&apos;Fish; mascot; hat; net; fast food; restaurant</description>
	<body>
		You aren&apos;t signed in    Sign In    Help 
 Home The Tour Sign Up Explore 
 Explore Home Last 7 Days Interesting Popular Tags Calendar Most Recent Uploads Video on Flickr Galleries Getty Images World Map Places The Commons Creative Commons FlickrBlog code.flickr The App Garden Camera Finder Flickr for mobile 
 Upload 
 
Hey, wait a minute!

We noticed that you may be using an unsupported browser. All the basics will still work, but to get the most out of Flickr please upgrade to the latest version of Chrome , Safari , Firefox , or Internet Explorer .

 
 
To take full advantage of Flickr, you should use a JavaScript-enabled browser and install the latest version of the Macromedia Flash Player .
 
   ☆  Favorite Actions ▾ Share via email Share on Facebook Share on Twitter   Share ▾ 

 Newer Older 
 

 
Phil A. O&apos;Fish - 1976 McDonald&apos;s
 
And now for a quick break from the on-going Twinkies celebration to
bring you this important new find...

I was so excited to get this vintage McDonald&apos;s Filet-O-Fish sign!
It&apos;s a thin plastic sign, dated 1976, that would have been on a wall
or near the menu board in the restaurant back then.

On the sign we see a dapper little fish mascot named Phil A. O&apos;Fish! (Gulp!) Discovering this very obscure little character from
McDonaldland just blew me out of the water! (Pun intended). I don&apos;t
remember him from my childhood, and have never heard of him in the
last 15+ years of collecting.

This sign will find a treasured place on my wall soon. Rescuing
characters like this from obscurity is one of the great joys I get out
of collecting.

Does anyone out there remember Phil A. O&apos;Fish?

1976
 
Comments and faves

 ★ 
 Roadsidepictures , Neato Coolville , gregg_koenig , jeremy pettis , and 32 other people added this photo to their favorites.
 
 Waffle Whiffer ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
Here&apos;s a close-up of Phil:

 
 
 Roadsidepictures ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
WoW!! What an awesome find! I don&apos;t recall
ever seeing this character.
 
 brad renner [deleted] ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
no i dont recall him at all, but i love him!
 
 Neato Coolville ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
Nice to meet Phil A. O&apos;Fish. I&apos;ve never
heard of him before. Too bad he didn&apos;t catch
on or there might&apos;ve been Phil A. O&apos;Fish
statues and playground rides. Do you think
he was ever used in any commercials?
 
 gregg_koenig ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
aRe you kidding me - - this is so rAd!!!
 
 Waffle Whiffer ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
[:::] Roadside -- He must not have lasted for
long.

[:::] Brad -- I&apos;m wondering if he was used in
a test market, perhaps. We&apos;ll see what
information surfaces.

[:::] Neato -- I guess he never made it into
the playground, but I wouldn&apos;t be surprised
now if he turns up in a vintage commercial.
Maybe he was used on a sandwich wrapper or
box even! (wishful thinking)

[:::] Gregg -- A pair of these bad boys
turned up recently. After picking my jaw up
off the floor, I managed to snag one.
 
 gregg_koenig ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
congrats! - LOVE it!
 
 CheshireCat666 ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
How have we never heard of this guy? there&apos;s
always at least ONE person in Flickr who has
a sample of every obscure little pop culture
item ever made

You&apos;re a hero!
 
 BACKYard Woods Explorer ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
I do remember seeing a similar sign in the
local McDonald&apos;s. A cool looking character.
Wonder if he did any TV commercials that I
somehow missed?
 
 Waffle Whiffer ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
[:::] CheshireCat -- With the Irish sounding
last name, I wonder if maybe he arrived on
the same boat as Uncle O&apos;Grimacey.
 
 Waffle Whiffer ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
[:::] BackYard -- There may have been another
sign similar to this without the mascot. The
ocean scene looked familiar to me, too.
 
 BACKYard Woods Explorer ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
Very possible...
 
 Roadsidepictures ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
Jason is going to do backflips when he sees
this...unless he got the other one! ;-)
 
 IAAFOTS ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
not only don&apos;t i remember him, but i used to
have an ongoing complaint when i was a kid
that McDonaldland had no character
representing for the poor Filet-O-Fish
(because that&apos;s what i always ordered)
 
 BACKYard Woods Explorer ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
Maybe the Filet-O-Fish wasn&apos;t aimed at kids.
I remember my parents liking it.
 
 Waffle Whiffer ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
[:::] IAAFOTS -- Captain Crook was the
closest thing. He would row in his boat on
Filet-O-Fish Lake, and there were some
Filet-O-Fish sandwich-fishes, which you can
see in this poster of Jason&apos;s -- www.flickr.com/photos/jasonliebigstuff/181716
8636/ 

[:::] BackYard -- I&apos;m sure I&apos;ve eaten and
McDonald&apos;s at least once a month for the
majority of my life, and I&apos;ve still never
tried a Filet-O-Fish sandwich! Maybe it&apos;s
time.
 
 curly-wurly ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
Phil A. O&apos;Fish is BRILLIANT! I wonder if he
ever met Deep-Sea Dave. It kind of seems like
Phil was forced into eating a fish sandwich,
and he&apos;s disturbed by how much he liked it.
 
 Waffle Whiffer ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
[:::] Curly -- Phil and Dave may have gone
shopping together for clothes.

Guys -- Check out the great Deep-Sea Dave
from Curly Wurly! -- www.flickr.com/photos/curly-wurly/4574125760/ 
 
 j(ay) ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
Hmmm, something about him seems vaguely
familiar but maybe I’m just remembering some
old Charlie the (Star Kist) Tuna commercials…

Regardless. Great find!
 
 JasonLiebig ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
This is uber-spectacular. I got the other
one of these that recently surfaced. Yay!
 
 Mary (David&apos;s wife) ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
Maybe they only flushed him out (groan!)
during Shamrock Shake time?
 
 CheshireCat666 ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
what the...you never had a Filet-O-Fish?
They&apos;re delightful! I mean,for a cheap low
end fish sandwich.
 
 Waffle Whiffer ( 27 months ago | reply ) 
 
[:::] j(ay) -- Seems like Charlie might have
been an inspiration for this guy.

[:::] Jason -- Yes! I&apos;m glad you did. It&apos;ll
go great with your other F-O-F signs. :-)

[:::] Mary -- Maybe Phil fell into the
deep-fryer and was never heard from again!

[:::] CheshireCat -- I know, hard to believe!
When I go to McD&apos;s I&apos;m usually craving a
Quarter Pounder, and that cannot be denied.
In honor of Phil, I&apos;m going to sit down and
eat a Filet-O-Fish in the near future. I&apos;ll
take a picture of it and give a review of my
findings.
 
 bolio88 ( 26 months ago | reply ) 
 
I don&apos;t remember him - but that&apos;s a great
sign!
 
 ellynkocher ( 26 months ago | reply ) 
 
i don&apos;t remember him -- obviously an irish
fellow, har -- but i do remember the slogan
of the time,&quot;we do it all for
you.&quot;i read that and immediately
started humming it.

my mom thought i was cute when i was a wee
one in the 70s and could recite the entire&quot;two all beef patties special sauce
lettuce cheese pickles onions on a sesame
seed bun&quot;jingle. only i would say&quot;sammy seed.&quot;
 
 Waffle Whiffer ( 26 months ago | reply ) 
 
[:::] Bolio -- Thanks!

[:::] Ellyn -- Funny that you bring up the
Big Mac jingle. It was around this same time
(mid &apos;70s) as a young boy that I remember
getting a shot at the doctor&apos;s office. I was
nervous. The nurse asked me to say the Big
Mac jingle over and over until she was
finished. It worked, and I hardly felt a
thing! :-D
 
 ellynkocher ( 26 months ago | reply ) 
 
it&apos;s one that really stays with you -- kind
of like a big mac. :)
 
 poptartsbox ( 26 months ago | reply ) 
 
The McDonald&apos;s fish sandwich was introduced
right here in Cincinnati by a guy named Cye
Landy in 1963!
 
 Waffle Whiffer ( 26 months ago | reply ) 
 
[:::] PopTartsBox -- A fresh catch from the
Ohio River, maybe. :-)
 
 Cool &apos;Cuda ( 26 months ago | reply ) 
 
The Fliet-O-Fish had a mascot?
 
 NYKID10014 ( 22 months ago | reply ) 
 
WOW this is a great find. Never heard of him
either.
I&apos;m sure they pulled this ad because that
sandwich looks so disgusting. I mean really?
Dried out, flat&amp;all bun, mmm same as
today. LoL
 
This photo was invited and added to the McDonald&apos;s artwork group.
 
 THATS RIGHT ( 20 months ago | reply ) 
 
 Please join group if you have not already
and share your photos and videos for all to
see.
 
 
PLANET EARTH BACK IN THE DAY
This group is dedicated to the past.
 www.flickr.com/groups/1414874@N24/ 
 
This photo was invited and added to the PLANET EARTH BACK IN THE DAY group.
 
 

 Want to format your comment? 
 By Waffle Whiffer Brandon + Add Contact 
 
This photo was taken on May 7, 2010 .
 3,612 views 36 favorites 32 comments 0 galleries 
This photo belongs to

 Waffle Whiffer&apos;s photostream (1,434) 
 
 

This photo also appears in

 McDonald&apos;s (Set) 
 
 The 1970s (Set) 
 
 Signs (Set) 
 
 Restaurant Mascot Extravaganza (Group) 
 
 FOOD NOSTALGIA (Group) 
 
 Golden Age of Advertising:... (Group) 
 
 1970&apos;s (Group) 
 
 Advertising Characters and... (Group) 
 
 Advertising through the years (Group) 
 
 Advertising Sillyness from... (Group) 
 
 Age of Aquarius (60&apos;s,70&apos;s) (Group) 
 
 Animals in Advertising (Group) 
 
 Anything Anthropomorphic (Group) 
 
 Brands, Marks&amp;Logos (Group) 
 
 Fast Food (Group) 
 
 fast food outlets (Group) 
 
 FastFood Signs (Group) 
 
 Generation X (Group) 
 
 Great Signs (Group) 
 
 I love Mcdonald&apos;s!!! (Group) 
 
 McDonald&apos;s (Group) 
 
 Of a Bygone Age. (Retro Stuff) (Group) 
 
 Restaurant Signs (Group) 
 
 Retro Nostalgic Skooldays (Group) 
 
 Retro Restaurants (Group) 
 
 See The Sign (Group) 
 
 Sign City (Group) 
 
 Signs, Signs, (and logos) (Group) 
 
 Signs, Signs... (Group) 
 
 Spirit of &apos;76 (Group) 
 
 That&apos;s Cool! (Group) 
 
 Vintage Advertising (Group) 
 
 vintage goodies (Group) 
 
 I Love Old Signs! (Group) 
 
 AMERICAN FOOD (Group) 
 
 McDonalds (Group) 
 
 McDonald&apos;s artwork (Group) 
 
 PLANET EARTH BACK IN THE DAY (Group) 
 
 ...and 30 more groups 
 
Tags
 
 McDonald&apos;s sign 1976 1970s fish Filet-O-Fish sandwich Phil A. O&apos;Fish mascot hat net fast food restaurant
	</body>
</document>
