<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002124" url="http://restaurantmom.blogspot.com/2007/07/restaurant-review-ikea-restaurant-1000.html" time="2012-07-12-18:01" support="10" score="0.013103399739873916" bingtitle="Central Florida Restaurant Mom: Restaurant Review - IKEA ..." webtitle="Central Florida Restaurant Mom: Restaurant Review - IKEA Restaurant, 1000 IKEA Drive, Elizabeth, NJ">
			<query id="000292" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="000776" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000229" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="001339" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="001089" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="001094" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="000767" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="000774" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000305" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="001082" bing-rank="105"/>
	<description>After placing our trays down at the table, I went up to get drinks. I ... down - and really, it is nothing more than you would do at a fast food restaurant but ...</description>
	<body>
		skip to main | skip to sidebar 
 Central Florida Restaurant Mom 
 
 A Mom with two kids writes reviews on kid-friendly (and not so kid-friendly) restaurants in the greater Orlando FL area. 
 
 Enter your search terms Submit search form 
 Web restaurantmom.blogspot.com 
 
 
 Saturday, July 07, 2007 
 
 Restaurant Review - IKEA Restaurant, 1000 IKEA Drive, Elizabeth, NJ 
 
 To finish up my reviews from my recent New Jersey trip, I decided to get a sneak peek at an internationally known restaurant that is coming here to Orlando this Fall . Yes, of course I&apos;m talking about IKEA. Okay, I know IKEA is known the world over as a furniture store, but I was eager to try their Swedish food (I am Restaurant Mom after all).

Every IKEA has the same basic floor plan with a &quot;restaurant&quot; (really a cafeteria) and Swedish Food Market so you can bring your favorite goodies home (oh yeah, and they have furniture and stuff, too). I don&apos;t know if the restaurant prices at the Orlando store will be the same as the NJ store, but I can&apos;t imagine they will be that different. And I have to tell you that the IKEA cafeter ia has the best kids&apos; meal deal I have ever seen - Mac-n-Cheese and a drink for 99 cents. The kid&apos;s drink alone is 79 cents so this is a huge bargain. I figure it is a loss leader to lure folks in, just like their 99 cent breakfast special (I&apos;ll have to wait until the Orlando IKEA opens to try that). There other items on the kids menu are the Kid&apos;s Meatball Plate with five Swedish meatballs, potatoes, and lingonberries; and a PB&amp;J;that comes with a small fruit cup and a drink - both of these go for $1.99 - still a huge bargain. Oh, and milk and chocolate milk can be chosen as the kids&apos; drink. What is also very cute are kid-sized trays so kids can carry their own food through the line.

The adult meals are just as reasonable. IKEA&apos;s specialty, of course, are the Swedish meatballs. These are offered in 10, 15, or 20 meatball portions, ranging from $4.29 to $5.99. Grandpa decided to get the 20 Meatball Plate so that he, Grandma, and my brother could share. The Plate also comes with potatoes and lingonberries. BB decided to get the PB&amp;J;which actually turned out to be a package of Uncrustables - I guess it is quick for IKEA but it would have bee n nice to have a freshly made sandwich. It came with a very small fruit cup that looked like canned fruit cocktail. Oh well, what do you want for $1.99? I got the Gravad Lox Plate ($4.99) which is similar to the lox you&apos;ll find at a bagel place, only a bit milder and smoother in flavor and texture. I also picked up a Daim cake which is an almo nd cake with what appears to be a coating of chocolate, almonds and toffee bits. It came with a Daim candy on the side, which is a Swedish version of a chocolate toffee candy (think Heath or Skor bar). Heading to the check-out lane, Grandpa grabbed a Lingonberry bottled soda. Everyone else went with a fountain beverage ($1.25) and we picked up our glasses and placed them on our trays. One un-kid-friendly thing is that they don&apos;t have kids&apos; cups, plastic or otherwise (at least the NJ store didn&apos;t when we were there). So the kids have to drink out of small glasses. Also, I couldn&apos;t find a straw anywhere in the restaurant - even for the adults! They did sell straws inside the store on the first floor so maybe they were trying to increase sales (lol)?


After placing our trays down at the table, I went up to get drinks. I found lingonberry juice available at the fountain and decided to try it. I&apos;m usually not a big fruit juice drinker but this was a really light juice, somewhere between a berry and grape taste. I got a regular cola for BB. Grandpa was a little peeved that he had bought the Lingonberry soda in a bottle because he didn&apos;t realize the juice was available at the soda fountain. BB blissfully ate his Uncrustable and fruit cup so I guess the pre-packaged food didn&apos;t bother him. My Gravad Lox was great - it was melt-in-your-mouth slightly salty flavor with a hint of fish taste - and the dill mustard that went with it was wonderful as well. I also stole one meatball from the Meatball Plate. By itself, it was very good - tender and tasty. Adding the cream sauce made it even better and then adding the lingonberry sauce to that was great - the tangy fruit really complementing the meat and cream sauce . Our one gripe was the temperature of everything on the meatball plate - it was all lukewarm - it would have been better hotter. My Daim cake for dessert was extremely sweet and rich. The cake itself was in very thin layers and was very light but the chocolate candy topping really put it over the top. At one point I picked off the topping and ate the rest of the cake underneath. Of course, that didn&apos;t stop me from eating the Daim candy that came with it - yummy chocolate toffee goodness, but in a small, palatable size.

Once you are done at the IKEA restaurant, you bus your own tables, bringing the trays up to a cart with your dirty plates on it. Signs all around say it is to keep the prices down - and really, it is nothing more than you would do at a fast food restaurant but now you are putting away real plates and utensils. I look forward to checking out the Orlando IKEA store when it rolls into town and trying some of the other menu items - and getting some more Gravad Lox!
 
 Posted by
Restaurant Mom at 7:09 PM   

 Labels: New Jersey , Scandinavian 


 
Click here to post your comments:
 
 Post a Comment 
 


 
 Newer Post Older Post Home Subscribe to: Post Comments (Atom) Copyright©by Restaurant Mom. All rights reserved.
 
Subscribe To
 Posts Atom Posts Comments Atom Comments 
About Me
 Restaurant Mom Before I had kids, I loved going to nice restaurants and trying new cuisines. When I had kids, I thought that might end because all of the nice restaurants are just for adults. So, while I don&apos;t go to the really fancy restaurants with the kids, I wanted them to try new foods and new experiences and not be one of those kids that only eats at a burger joint. So, I eat out with my big boy (BB) who is eleven and my little boy (LB) who is seven and I encourage them to try new foods. They aren&apos;t always the most well-behaved boys so I try to pick restaurants that are somewhat kid-friendly. I&apos;ll be sharing my reviews with all of you. Keep checking back every week or so to see new reviews or click on the RSS feed below to be alerted when new reviews get posted. Enjoy! View my complete profile 
Follow Me on Twitter
 Get the Twitter Widget widget and many other great free widgets at Widgetbox ! Not seeing a widget? ( More info ) 
Send me Restaurants to try in your area!
 I&apos;m always looking for restaurants to try out, so please email me at restaurant_mom@yahoo.com with new restaurants in your area that you would like me to check out! Thanks!
 
Blog Archive
 
 ►  2011 (2) 
 ►  June (1) 
 Coupon - Free Medium Firehouse Sub on July 4, 2011... 
 

 ►  May (1) 
 Restaurant Review - AMC Downtown Disney 24 Dine-In... 
 
 

 ►  2010 (1) 
 ►  March (1) 
 Are Make-Your-Own Frozen Yogurts shops a fad that ... 
 
 

 ►  2009 (20) 
 ►  December (2) 
 Quick Bites - Crazy Good Swedish food deals at IKE... Restaurant Review - TooJay&apos;s Original Gourmet Deli... 
 

 ►  November (4) 
 Restaurant Review - The Cheesecake Factory, Mall o... Restaurant Review - Menchie&apos;s Frozen Yogurt, 7339 ... Restaurant Musings - To Tip or Not to Tip for Take... Quick Bites - New Menus at Quick Service Restauran... 
 

 ►  September (2) 
 Restaurant Review - Anthony&apos;s Coal Fired Pizza, 80... Restaurant Review - Zen, Omni Orlando Resort, 1500... 
 

 ►  August (2) 
 Like Meal Deals? Orlando Magical Dining Month is B... Restaurant Review - Redrock Canyon Grill, 9101 Int... 
 

 ►  June (1) 
 Restaurant Review - Kafe Kalik, Prime Outlets Mall... 
 

 ►  May (2) 
 Restaurant Musings - Another Orlando area restaura... Restaurant Review - Biergarten Restaurant, Germany... 
 

 ►  April (3) 
 Quick Bites - Ostrich and Buffalo burgers at Fuddr... Restaurant Review - bd&apos;s Mongolian Grill, 300 S. S... Restaurant Review - BJ&apos;s Restaurant&amp;Brewhouse, 4... 
 

 ►  March (1) 
 Help! I need a Brunch place for Easter and Mother&apos;... 
 

 ►  January (3) 
 Restaurant Review - Outta Control Magic Comedy Din... Quick Bites - Grow an Avocado Plant, Courtesy of C... Restaurant Review - Hagan O&apos;Reilly&apos;s Irish Pub, 16... 
 
 

 ►  2008 (15) 
 ►  December (2) 
 Restaurant Review - T-Rex restaurant, Downtown Dis... Quick Bites - Lobsters meet The Claw 
 

 ►  November (1) 
 Restaurant Review - Elephant Bar Restaurant, 4054 ... 
 

 ►  August (2) 
 Central Florida Foodies Rejoice! It is Epcot Food ... Ice Cream Review - Bruster&apos;s Real Ice Cream, 971 N... 
 

 ►  June (2) 
 Restaurant Review - Azteca d&apos;Oro, 12403 South Blos... Restaurant Review - Texas Roadhouse, 1150 Blackwoo... 
 

 ►  May (2) 
 Restaurant Review - American Pie Pizza Company, 33... Restaurant Review - Mellow Mushroom, 2015 Aloma Av... 
 

 ►  March (1) 
 Restaurant Review - Jockamo&apos;s New Orleans Kitchen,... 
 

 ►  February (2) 
 Restaurant Review - Roy&apos;s Hawaiian Fusion Cuisine,... Restaurant Review - IKEA Orlando, 4092 Eastgate Dr... 
 

 ►  January (3) 
 Review - The Dinner A&apos;Fare, 2735 Old Winter Garden... Restaurant Update - Dolly&apos;s Parton&apos;s Dixie Stamped... Restaurant Review - Infusion Tea, 1600 Edgewater D... 
 
 

 ▼  2007 (35) 
 ►  December (2) 
 Restaurant Review - Old Spanish Sugar Mill, DeLeon... Restaurant Review - Dolly Parton&apos;s Dixie Stampede,... 
 

 ►  November (1) 
 Restaurant Review - Cheeburger Cheeburger, 504 N. ... 
 

 ►  October (2) 
 Restaurant Review - Pei Wei Asian Diner, 3011 E. C... Restaurant Updates for Winter Garden Village at Fo... 
 

 ►  September (3) 
 Restaurant Review - Chipotle, 10149 West Colonial ... Restaurant Review - P.F. Chang&apos;s China Bistro, 420... My Other Blog - Musings from a Restaurant Maven 
 

 ►  August (4) 
 Restaurant Review - Manny&apos;s Original Chophouse, 35... Orlando&apos;s Magical Dining Month - September Restaurant Review - Joe&apos;s Crab Shack, 10 Blake Blv... Restaurant Review - Black Bean Deli (a Cuban cafe)... 
 

 ▼  July (3) 
 Restaurant Review - Roy&apos;s Hawaiian Fusion Cuisine,... Restaurant Review - IKEA Restaurant, 1000 IKEA Dri... Rita&apos;s Water Ice Coming Soon to Hunter&apos;s Creek! 
 

 ►  June (2) 

 ►  May (5) 

 ►  April (3) 

 ►  March (2) 

 ►  February (3) 

 ►  January (5) 
 

 ►  2006 (28) 
 ►  December (3) 

 ►  November (3) 

 ►  October (3) 

 ►  September (3) 

 ►  August (3) 

 ►  July (1) 

 ►  June (2) 

 ►  May (3) 

 ►  April (7) 
 
 
Labels
 
 Airport area (1) Altamonte Springs (6) Asian (9) Bahamian (1) Baldwin Park (1) BBQ (5) Blogging (1) Breakfast (3) Brunch (2) Buffet (3) Burgers (6) Central Orlando (5) Chicken (3) chocolate (1) Clermont (4) Closed (1) deli (1) Dinner Show (2) Fast Food Toys (1) Fast-Food (2) Festival Bay Mall (2) Florida Mall area (6) fondue (1) Food Preparation (2) German (1) Haines City (1) Hunter&apos;s Creek (1) ice cream (3) International Drive area (5) Irish (2) Italian (5) Japanese (1) Kids Night (1) Kissimmee/Celebration (1) Lake County (2) Latin American (2) Magic (1) Mall of Millenia area (9) Metrowest (1) Mexican (8) Mt. Dora (1) New Food (1) New Jersey (2) Northeast Orlando (1) Ocoee (5) Orlando Dining Month (1) Oviedo (1) Pizza (7) Plant City (1) Podcast (1) Polk County (2) Sand Lake Road (7) Sandwiches (6) Scandinavian (4) Seafood (6) Steak (2) strawberry (1) Sushi (1) Tea Rooms (2) Theme Park food (8) Tipping (1) Top Ten (1) U-Pick (1) Vegetarian (1) West Orlando (3) Wings (1) Winter Garden (6) Winter Park (2) 
 
Other Local Restaurant Review Websites
 
 Chowhound.com-Florida Eating Orlando Furious Foodies GoCityKids - Orlando Orlando Menus at AllMenus.com Orlando Sentinel-Dining Orlando Weekly - Dining Scott Joseph&apos;s Orlando Restaurant Guide Tasty Chomps! Watch Me Eat 
 
Blog Roll
 
 Musings from a Restaurant Maven Moms Like Me - Orlando Adventures in (Orlando) Dining Columbus (OH) Foodie Cookie Madness Dining with Monkeys (Memphis, TN) Dinners From Hell - Dining w/Kids Disney Food Blog Eating L.A. (Calif) Faith For Today Food Blog S&apos;cool Foodie Universe&apos;s Restaurant Reviews (L.A.) Guest Room Museum - art collections Heat Eat Review Jaden&apos;s Steamy Kitchen The Candy Blog Ultimate Orlando Blog 
 
 
 Join The Worldwide Restaurant Reviewers BlogRoll 
 
Site Meter
	</body>
</document>
