<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002066" url="http://watkinslynn.typepad.com/pages_pucks_and_pantry/scrapbooking/" time="2012-07-12-17:58" support="1" score="0.0018426864370878486" bingtitle="Pages, Pucks and Pantry: scrapbooking" webtitle="Pages, Pucks and Pantry: scrapbooking">
			<query id="001223" bing-rank="186"/>
	<description>I rarely photoshop my food photos and if I do it&apos;s ... And I&apos;m always game to try something new if a fast food restaurant ... calendar I bought at Starbucks (little boxes in the ...</description>
	<body>
		Pages, Pucks and Pantry 


 
scrapbooking

December 03, 2011
 
 Scrapbooking - Christmas Cards Layout 2010 
 
 

It&apos;s become tradition for me every year to take bits of each Christmas card I receive and make a layout with those pieces along with the card that we sent out. Last year I completed the layout by April (you can check it out here ), this year I didn&apos;t finish until November!

We actually received less traditional Christmas cards last year and more photo cards, which isn&apos;t a bad thing, I just can&apos;t figure out how to make a layout with them!
 
 Posted at 01:10 PM in Christmas , scrapbooking | Permalink | Comments (1) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | 
 
December 01, 2010
 
 Scrapbooking - December Daily 
 
 I have no idea what insanity entered my mind and made me decide that I was going to try Ali Edwards December Daily album. I mean really, I&apos;m usually so dang stressed during the holidays with everything I have to do that adding one more item to my list of things to do should probably send me over the edge.

But...I went and started it anway (So maybe I&apos;m about to go over the edge, look out below!!!). I made the album as simple as I could. I used leftover cardstock and scrapbook paper. I used embellishments out of my stash. I used stickers that I probably picked up during the stone age. I tried not to sweat about making the thing&quot;cute&quot;or&quot;edgy&quot;or&quot;prefect&quot;or&quot;magazine worthy&quot;or anything other than&quot;get the dang book made&quot;. It helped that I started this process at the end of October. Of course I didn&apos;t finish putting the pages together until last night.

The idea of the December Daily album is to every day, print out a photo and journal about that day so that immediately after the holidays you have a completed album documenting the days leading up to Christmas. The trick is to have the album and it&apos;s 25 blank pages done before December 1st so that you aren&apos;t spending time trying to create the page every night... you just plop down your photo and journal and the entry for the day is done. At the end of the season, your holiday album will be complete (I actually made mine 26 days as we celebrate Boxing Day in our household).

A December Daily album isn&apos;t something that I plan on doing every year. Without kids, decorations and such, don&apos;t really change much every year. Maybe I&apos;ll do one every five years to see what might change or if we move, I might make one sooner since a different space to put out all my Christmas stuff would change it up a bit. But I look forward to documenting the season so I&apos;m able to reflect back on the holidays sometime in the future when my memory might not be that good, and bring back the special feelings and fun of this time of year.

Oh and technically I&apos;m not actually done and ready on this first day. See the cover of my album is one of those acrylic types. That came with a thin plastic cover that you are supposed to remove before using. Which I didn&apos;t remove. Therefor the couple hours I spent stamping, dating and embellishing last night went to waste. I figure Ali won&apos;t be too mad at me if I wait until after the holidays to finish the cover.

The photos are of the back sides of some of the pre-done pages. Don&apos;t ask me why I photographed the backs and not the fronts. Photos were taken on my iPhone. For more information about December Daily check out Ali Edwards project blog here .

 
 
 Posted at 03:12 PM in scrapbooking | Permalink | Comments (2) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | 
 
June 07, 2010
 
 Answers To Questions 
 
 Yes, that is Tiggher in the middle of the table in the kitchen. No, we no longer set the table ahead of time. Don&apos;t think we haven&apos;t tried to keep her off the table. Firm voices, squirting with water...nothing keeps her from her nice little spot in the sun. We&apos;ve watched her literally jump on the table and move salt and pepper shakers and vases, just so she has a spot to stretch out on. No we do not feed her at the table nor do we feed her any people food. She has just decided the middle of the table, where the sun shines and she can look out on the world, is HER spot. We are just her staff. We comply.

For the first anniversary of this blog I answered some questions that I periodically got from readers. I figured it may be time to answer some again.

 What&apos;s up with the name of the blog? Is it a food blog, a hockey blog or what? Though the blog is mainly about food (Pantry), I do occasionally post about hockey (Pucks), and scrapbooking (Pages). Since I&apos;ve recently started participating in a monthly scrap group and have a specific scrap project I&apos;m working on, you might see more scrap related posts. As for hockey, ahem. I had my breath held this year because I thought maybe it was&quot;THIS YEAR&quot;. But alas. It wasn&apos;t. I&apos;m still mourning. But yes, especially during the playoffs, there are some posts about hockey now and then.

 What&apos;s the point of your blog? In a nutshell? To get me to cook. Since, like Julia Child, I kinda started cooking late in life and I&apos;m a bit behind the cooking curve. I have a large, immense, gigantic, way to big cookbook collection that I&apos;m trying to cook from. The goal is to cook at least one dish from each cookbook. Let&apos;s just say if I was to cook one recipe a week for the rest of my life, I still might not make it through my collection. 

 Why haven&apos;t you updated the header/put a link to your Twitter account/done an RSS feed etc.? Time. Or lack of it. Also, some of the food blogs I follow are so crowded with this that and the other that I find it distracting. I&apos;m trying to keep this blog simple. That being said, I do hope to be able to get some better functionality stuff going in the coming year. 
 Do you take your own photos?   Of the meals I cook yes. Usually I just plate the dish and take it with
the lights on the stove if there is no natural light. I take most of
the hockey photos and scrap photos. If the photo isn&apos;t mine, I try to
give sources. I use
Wikipedia a lot for generic photos. Every once in a while Mr. L will
take the photo (usually when I&apos;ve done something stupid, like burned my
hand on a pot).

 What kind of camera do you use?   Though I have a Canon Rebel XT, I currently use a little Canon PowerShot SD1100 which I am NOT fond of. We&apos;re looking for a new Canon that&apos;s more like my old SD950. I take photos in auto mode. I do not use a tripod. I rarely photoshop my food photos and if I do it&apos;s usually just the&quot;auto correct&quot;key.

 Who do you cook for?  Mostly Mr. L and my mom. I do take some things into work to my assistant and every once
in a while I get enough courage to take something I&apos;ve made to a
potluck.

 Do you throw big dinner parties? In my mind? Yes. Constantly. I&apos;m the Queen of Entertaining. In real life? Not so much. In fact, rarely.

 How many cookbooks do you own?   Um. A Lot. Too many. More than I could ever use. Yeah, that answer is
another post entirely. I can&apos;t tell you the count without trying to
justify the answer! 
 How do you chose the recipes you make from cookbooks?  There is no set way. Sometimes, if there is an interesting National
Day, I may look through my books trying to find a recipe that has that
ingredient. More often than not, I just pick up a cookbook and try to
find something to cook. Sometimes this is easy as only a handful of
recipes pop out at me. Other times it&apos;s a gargantuan task as I want to
make everything in the book. Sometimes it&apos;s by default...I may be in an&quot;orzo&quot;phase so those are the recipes that stand out and scream to be
cooked. Or maybe I&apos;ve been cooking a lot of meat dishes and look for a
fish dish. I may make a dish because it&apos;s something I know my mom can
eat. Sometimes (most of the time) I&apos;m really tired and busy and want to
make something simple. Or maybe I just got off the scale and all those
delicious fattening recipes just remind me of extra inches on my hips
so I try to go low-cal. Currently I only have access to about one sixth
of my cookbook collection so I try to find things in the cookbooks that are
available in the house.

 How often do you buy new cookbooks?  I never buy new cookbooks. Never. Really. They just show up on my
doorstep. Yeah, that&apos;s the ticket, they just show up asking to come
inside and be part of my collection. Yeah...be sure to tell Mr. L that
if you ever run into him. Yeah, tell him you give me cookbooks, that&apos;s
why new ones are in the house. Seriously, they are like rabbits, they
just multiply.
 Why didn&apos;t you learn to cook earlier?   See cookbook question. That will be answered when I get enough guts to post about my cookbook collection.
 What cooking magazines do you subscribe to?   HAHAHAHA. Just a couple. Bon Appetit . Gourmet if it was still in publication. And Food and Wine. Oh
and Savour. Of course Cooks Illustrated. Fine Cooking. The New Food Network magazine. Food Everyday. Cooking LIght. Should I include Sunset
Magazine since I cut out the recipes? And Martha Stewart Living? Better Homes and Garden?...and...well, maybe the question should have
been which cooking magazines I DON&apos;T subscribe to!

 Do you ever eat out at restaurants? You talk about them, why don&apos;t you review them?   Honestly we do eat out a fair amount, especially when we travel. I&apos;ve
felt a bit uneasy about restaurant reviews since I&apos;m not an expert.
That being said, since I enjoy reading others reviews and use them to find interesting places to eat, I think I might
start posting my own. I&apos;ve done a few here and there though. See question below.

 Do you take photos of the food you eat in restaurants? If it&apos;s breakfast or lunch I&apos;ll do it. If it&apos;s outside eating I&apos;ll do it. If it&apos;s some sort of fast food place, I&apos;ll do it. But I really don&apos;t have the courage to whip out my camera in the middle of a nice restaurant. That&apos;s probably one of the reasons I haven&apos;t reviewed some of the great places we&apos;ve been to (i.e. Manresa)...I have no photos to go along with the review. But who knows, maybe I&apos;ll figure out a way.

 Do you eat a lot of fast food? It may seem that way, but we honestly don&apos;t. That doesn&apos;t mean we don&apos;t talk about it. And I&apos;m always game to try something new if a fast food restaurant advertises it.

 Why don&apos;t you post more Small Plates with the National Food Days? Time. Or lack of it. Sound familiar? I try to Tweet the National Days so if you are interested you can follow me there .
 Do you come up with the National Days for Small Plates?   No, these are actual real days. I don&apos;t make any of them up. Yes, there
really is a&quot;Don&apos;t Cry Over Spilled Milk Day&quot;, a&quot;Crab Meat Newburg
Day&quot;and a&quot;Take Your Pants for a Walk Day&quot;.

 Where do you find these days?   Just do an Internet search. There are a ton of places that list most of
the food days and plenty of the off the wall days. Even places that
send out e-cards list special or strange days.

 Do you cook everything on the National Days?   I do see what days are coming up during the month and see if they work into my meal plan. The problem is, life
sometimes gets in the way and it may be several days after the National
Day that I actually cook with that ingredient. Because of this I rarely
post a National Days recipe until quite a while later.

 Just how old are you anyway?   Like I&apos;m going to tell you that.

 Is Mr. L a real person? Why yes, yes he is. Thank you for asking.
 Why don&apos;t you use real names or post photographs of yourself?   Because we are actually government spies...no wait, we are in the
witness protection program...no wait, we are complete paranoid
freaks...no wait...we&apos;re aliens from the planet Karmactuan! You may catch photos of us in you pay attention, and most of you know our
names anyway, but we like a little air of mystery.

 Do you go to all the Sharks games?   I used to. For many, many years a group of us went to every pre-season
game, every home game, the playoffs, various road trip games and yes,
even to some practices. And I watched or listened to every road game on
the TV or radio. There was no life outside of hockey. Then there was
the lockout and I found Mr. L and other things in life started
happening. I still have season tickets. This past year for various reasons, we didn&apos;t go to many regular season games but plan on rectifying that this coming season.

 What did you think of the Sharks losing to the Hawks in the playoffs? Lalalalalalala, I can&apos;t hear you...... But as an FYI, I am rooting for the Hawks over the Flyers. Sorry, but I just can&apos;t let go of the Pronger hatred. 

 Are you caught up with your scrapbooks? Are you out of your mind?
 Do you ever scrap?   Not as much as I&apos;d like to but having a couple of monthly groups to get together with is helping. I have a major scrap project I&apos;m trying to work on which means even less time to do normal scrap pages. But I am trying to carve out some time to keep that up.

Well, I think
that&apos;s all the questions I remember people asking over the last year or so.
If you can think of something else, just let me know and I&apos;ll try to answer in the comments. 
 Posted at 02:54 PM in Hockey , Personal , scrapbooking , Updates | Permalink | Comments (5) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | 
 
May 01, 2010
 
 Happy National Scrapbook Day 
 
 

I never know what to do with all the Christmas cards we receive each year. The photo cards are easy as some go up on the refrigerator until the next holiday season and the rest are incorporated into our photo albums. Certain cards I put back with all the Christmas stuff as they will be incorporated into present wrapping next year. But the rest of the cards? I&apos;ve always hated to just throw them out.

I&apos;ve seen versions of this in scrapbook magazines over the years and have always wanted to try it. I took a square punch and punched a square from each Christmas card we received. I also put the Christmas card we sent out, uncut, on the left hand side, with what the card said inside, underneath. I wish I had been doing this every year. I think it would be cool to see how cards change over the years. It also gives me a place to record the Christmas card we send out.

All items are from cards we received except for&apos;Holiday Cards 2009&apos;which are letter stickers of unknown manufacturer and the Believe, Joy, Present buttons which were some embellishments I had in my stash. Bazzill white cardstock.
 
 Posted at 08:02 AM in scrapbooking | Permalink | Comments (3) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | 
 
April 30, 2010
 
 Pages, Pucks and Pantry 
 

Every once in a while (if the Hockey Gods are nice to me), my three passions intercept.Tomorrow is National Scrapbook Day (Pages), the Sharks are currently in the second round of the Stanley Cup playoffs (Pucks) and, as always, I&apos;m all about the food (Pantry). If recipes haven&apos;t been posted on the blog lately it&apos;s because I&apos;ve been busy planning pages to spend National Scrapbook Day scrapbooking with some girlfriends or I&apos;ve been watching (nail biting, holding my breath) the Sharks play. That doesn&apos;t mean I haven&apos;t been cooking or that there isn&apos;t food involved. We&apos;ve checked out a new pizza place and had a nice wine dinner at Zanottos. Mr. L has been making his own beef jerky and I&apos;ve had my hand at making some crockpot chocolate candy (which around here is now known as the Chocolate Peanut Candy Crack).

If you are a regular reader of this blog, don&apos;t be surprised that there might be more hockey and scrapbooking related posts for a while. Fingers crossed that the hockey continues through June. Oh and that little scamp in the photo? Our cat Tiggher. She snuck up on the table while I was taking photos. Luckily she didn&apos;t make off with any of the beef jerky. It&apos;s good enough I would have fought her for it.
 
 Posted at 11:57 PM in Food and Drink , Hockey , scrapbooking | Permalink | Comments (2) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | 
 
December 01, 2009
 
 Scrapbooking - Mom&apos;s Advent Calendar 
 
 Every year I fill a Christmas countdown calendar full of daily treats and sayings for Mr. L. It&apos;s a fun way to be a bit more personal during the holidays and to provide a nice little treat every day. I have a cardboard calendar I bought at Starbucks (little boxes in the shape of a tree) and a wooden one with little drawers that swing open from Target.

Last year, upon seeing the one I had done for Mr. L, my mom commented that she too, would love a daily treat. So this year I figured I&apos;d make her a countdown calendar of her own. I spent several days creating the calendar and then went and bought many different bags of candy.Since my mom is a diabetic, I bought special sugar free candy, each individually wrapped.

The entire countdown calendar is about 9&quot;x 9&quot;with each little treat box being about an inch and a half. I covered the outside areas with scrap paper (I did not cover the inside or sides of the individual boxes). The numbers used as dates were provided in the countdown box kit from Karen Foster. The paper used is Basic Grey. Doo Dads were from my stash and the Christmas balls on the top came from Michaels.

And while this seems all great and good, and a terrific little present to give mom at the start of the month, I found out I had made a tactical error. All that sugar free candy, each individually wrapped? Didn&apos;t fit in the little boxes. Seriously, none of them. So yesterday I presented my mother with this great Christmas countdown calendar and a separate bag of candy. With instructions that instead of opening the cute little boxes everyday, she had to reach into the bag and get a piece of candy. Not exactly what I had in mind. Next year I have to find her sugar free candy that fits!

 Karen Foster Countdown Calendar , Basic Grey Eskimo Kisses Collection Pack 

Note: The countdown calendar comes with a little template to use to cut out scrap paper to fit the front of the individual boxes. I did not notice this template until I had already cut out all the finger holes for each piece of scrap paper...


 
 Posted at 02:08 PM in Christmas , scrapbooking | Permalink | Comments (3) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | 
 
June 08, 2009
 
 And the Winners Are..... 
 
 Hello. Let me introduce myself. I&apos;m Tiggher and I&apos;m a new addition to the Mr. and Mrs. L household. I understand there was a contest going on and I was asked to chose winners. A contest to win books. I like books. I like to chew on books. In fact, if it&apos;s made out of paper or has paper in it I consider it a perfect chew toy! Newspapers, magazines...such wonderful things to play with! And since my humans are so tired (something to do with the fact that they aren&apos;t nocturnal like me and they don&apos;t feel the need to get up at 5:30 AM to play with their tails) I guess I can muster up the energy to help them out.

So mama human took these little delicious pieces of papers that had numbers on them and dangled them in front of me. It was my job to snag a piece of paper. Of course I think I was supposed to give the papers back once I picked one but I had much more fun biting it and playing with it. You should have seen my momma human chasing me around the living room trying to get those pieces of paper back. And I got to do it three times! This little girl loves making her humans get some exercise.

Mama human says that she&apos;ll do some formal introductions to me soon. I&apos;m just a very happy little kitten that is glad that she was rescued from the pound by my new family.

Cooking Winner- bmk
 






Scrapbooking Winner - Chef Barbie
 






Hockey Winner - Robin Trellis
 






So the winners just need to e-mail my mama human at hkydiva at yahoo dot com with
their addresses. I&apos;ll try to get the packages out in a few weeks.
Congrats!

 Cooking #9















 Scrapbooking #1















 Hockey #3
 
 Posted at 11:04 PM in Food and Drink , Hockey , scrapbooking | Permalink | Comments (8) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | 
 
June 04, 2009
 
 Scrapbooking Giveaway 
 
 Before you reply to this post, remember to read the rules here .


The scrapbooking giveaway consists of the Paper Crafts Gourmet idea book. The book has recipes and some awesome ideas for food containers, wraps, tags, invitations etc, that pertain to the recipe. (For a Mardi Gras party there is a recipe for Louisiana Gumbo and instructions on how to craft a mask, an invitation and a gift box for goodies). Color photos of each recipe with color photos and instructions on each papercrafting idea.

For more information go here .
 
 Posted at 11:36 AM in scrapbooking | Permalink | Comments (4) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | 
 
 It&apos;s Giveaway Time 
 
 Welcome to my second annual&quot;It&apos;s my blogiversary and I&apos;m giving stuff away&quot;give-away. And this year I&apos;m actually doing it only a week late! (Instead of 3 weeks like last year).

I haven&apos;t poisoned my husband, my family or friends yet so I&apos;m assuming I&apos;ll continue this little blog adventure for another year. And though I rarely post about my two other passions...hockey and scrapbooking...they too, will be represented in my give-away.

There will be three giveaways (can I use the word giveaway even more??)...one for scrapbooking, one for hockey
and one for food. I will make a separate post for each. You will have
to decide which giveaway you are interested in. You can only sign up to
win ONE of the three. If you don&apos;t see something you like, what the
heck, try to win it anyway and give it to a friend! Since I know I now have more than one reader outside the US, I will open this up to everyone. Just realize that if you win and live in a foreign country,
you will have to help me figure out how to do the paperwork and get it
to you as cheaply as possible. Though this is my second give-away I still ask you to be gentle with me and not get mad because either you didn&apos;t win or you didn&apos;t like the prize you won :) I&apos;ll post the actual prizes shortly.

 Giveaway Rules: 

 There will be three separate posts, one for hockey, one for scrapping and one for food Put a reply on the post that corresponds with the item you would like to win You can only post for ONE of the three (if you reply on two or all three posts, you will be disqualified) You will have until Sunday at noon Pacific time on the 7th to play Winner will be picked by Random Generator...or the new kitten if she decides to leave the new kitty condo to come play Winner will be announced Monday evening...or Tuesday if my Monday trip to the dentist is worse than anticipated. Am I forgetting anything? 

Good luck!




 
 Posted at 09:05 AM in Food and Drink , Hockey , scrapbooking | Permalink | Comments (1) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | 
 
May 13, 2009
 
 Scrapbooking - Toaster 
 
 This is one of the first scrapbook pages I ever crafted. I know it was a scrap lift but it was so long ago I can&apos;t remember of what or whom. It was also one of the first scans I ever did...as you can see, it&apos;s a bit wonky.

I loved the quote with the photo. Toaster just had this pose and look about her that I felt went well with the saying.

We love our cat. Currently she isn&apos;t feeling well. We&apos;re waiting for test results to come back on Friday.
 
 Posted at 11:45 PM in Personal , scrapbooking | Permalink | Comments (6) | TrackBack (0) 

 | | 
 » 
 About 
 
Cooking Blogs
 
 Hye Thyme Cafe 
 CulturalConstruct 
 Noble Pig 
 Bucaio 
 Culinary Concoctions by Peabody 
 
 
Currently Cooking From
 
 
 Lucie Snodgrass: Dishing Up® Maryland: 150 Recipes from the Alleghenies to the Chesapeake Bay 
 
 Brian Yarvin: Ploughman&apos;s Lunch and the Miser&apos;s Feast: Authentic Pub Food, Restaurant Fare, and Home Cooking from Small Towns, Big Cities, and Country Villages Across the British Isles 
 
 Frank DeCaro: The Dead Celebrity Cookbook: A Resurrection of Recipes from More Than 145 Stars of Stage and Screen 
 
 
The Book Place
 
 
 Jenny Lawson: Let&apos;s Pretend This Never Happened: (A Mostly True Memoir) 

 
 David Sedaris: Squirrel Seeks Chipmunk: A Modest Bestiary 

 
 
 Archives 
 
 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 

 More... 
 
 Categories 
 
 Appetizers Bacon Baking Beef Beverage Blogger Recipe Books Cake Candy Cats Cheese Chicken Chocolate Christmas Cookies Crockpot Current Affairs Desserts Eggs Fast Food Film Fish Food and Drink Food Blog Events Food Fashion Food Review Food Section Food Stores Food Trucks Fruit Garden Gourmet Unbound Grains Grilled Halloween Hockey Magazine Magazine Mondays Meme Noodles Olympics Pasta Personal Pinterest Pork Potato Recipe Restaurants and Bars Rice Salad Sandwich scrapbooking Seafood Side Dishes Small Plates Soups Sports Spotlight On-Food Blogs Starbucks Television Travel Updates Vegetables Web/Tech Weblogs 
 Subscribe to this blog&apos;s feed Blog powered by TypePad
	</body>
</document>
