<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002249" url="http://detroitblackfoodsecurity.org/policy.html" time="2012-07-12-18:08" support="3" score="0.0072789489382177755" bingtitle="Food Security Policy" webtitle="Food Security Policy">
			<query id="000419" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000170" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="000167" bing-rank="221"/>
	<description>&quot;Creating a Food Secure Detroit&quot; Preamble ... business loans, etc.) so that businesses that receive ... occur at any point in the food system from farm to table ...</description>
	<body>
		Home AboutUs FoodSecurityPolicy FoodCoop MediaandLinks Photos JobPostings 
 
 A City of Detroit Policy on Food Security 
 &quot;Creating
 a Food Secure Detroit&quot; 

 Preamble 

Community
 Food Security can be defined as the condition which exists when all of the members of a community have access, in close proximity,
 to adequate amounts of nutritious, culturally appropriate food at all times, from sources that are environmentally sound and
 just. This food security policy was developed to affirm the City of Detroit&apos;s commitment to nurturing the development
 of a food secure city in which all of its citizens are hunger-free, healthy and benefit from the food systems that impact
 their lives. This policy also affirms the City of Detroit&apos;s commitment to supporting sustainable food systems that provide
 people with high quality food, employment, and that also contribute to the long-term well-being of the environment.

This policy addresses the following areas:

Current access to quality food in Detroit

Hunger and Malnutrition

Impacts/Effects of an Inadequate Diet

Citizen
 Education

Economic Injustice in the Food System

Urban Agriculture

The
 Role of Schools and other Public Institutions

Emergency Response

This document
 is organized by a statement of the issues, followed by actions needed to address those issues. This policy also calls for
 the formation of a Detroit Food Policy Council devoted to addressing the issues outlined herein.

 Current
 Access to Quality Food in Detroit 

Access is germane to any discussion about a community&apos;s
 food security. Access is the availability of quality food within a reasonable distance from where people live. Access also
 includes the ease and ability to travel to where quality food is available, as well as the affordability of that food and
 its cultural suitability to specific population groups within the community.

In the city of Detroit,
 the most accessible food-related establishments are party stores, dollar stores, fast-food restaurants and gas stations. Although
 most neighborhoods may have a grocery store within a&quot;reasonable&quot;distance, the quality and selection of food items
 is exceedingly lacking. Most city stores have a very limited variety of unprocessed (fresh) vegetables and fruits. Most foods
 are canned, boxed, frozen and/or highly processed. Highly processed foods are nutrient-poor, with excessive salt, sugar, and
 harmful fats. These stores also lack food alternatives for persons with the chronic conditions, such as heart disease, hypertension
 and diabetes, who require low-salt, sugar-free, healthy carbohydrates and healthy fats. These and other chronic health conditions
 exist and are growing at alarming rates in the African-American community.

The lack of access to transportation,
 an inadequate public transportation system, and safety issues are all factors impacting a person&apos;s ability to choose when
 and where they shop for food items. Fast-food restaurants, dollar stores, party stores and gas stations are often the closes
 and most convenient establishments from which people get food.

With regard to affordability, the cheapest
 food items are usually the most heavily processed and unhealthy items. Fresh food items are more expensive, even though they
 are often of poor quality. The availability and affordability of local and/or organic vegetables, fruits and meats is practically
 non-existent in Detroit, while merely crossing jurisdictional borders gives one that access. In fact, many Detroiters with
 transportation and economic means regularly, if not exclusively, shop for food beyond the borders of this city.

Actions
 Needed:

Increase the number of culturally appropriate food outlets within a reasonable distance in all
 Detroit neighborhoods.

Perform research on the type and location of food establishments and the extent
 to which these stores fulfill neighborhoods needs.

Create mechanisms with store operators and the Michigan
 Dept of Agriculture food safety inspection system to ensure that Detroit stores comply with food safety codes and maintain
 clean and sanitary food preparation and sales environments within stores.

Ensure that food stores carry
 a variety of fresh foods and food items for persons with special needs and chronic conditions.

Put in
 place monitoring mechanisms to ensure that food items are safe and fresh.

Review bus stops and put in
 place bus lines that give people direct access to grocery stores without the need of a transfer. Assess the need for&quot;grocery
 routes&quot;which reflect actual shopping needs (evenings and weekends).

Make locally grown and organic
 foods accessible throughout the city by supporting increased production within neighborhoods, neighborhood farmers markets,
 and small business assistance to neighborhood stores that agree to participate in a&quot;good neighbor program&quot;in which
 they agree to sell more locally grown fresh and healthy foods, do not sell alcohol and tobacco to minors, and negotiate other
 mutual benefits with neighborhood organizations that can appropriately represent neighborhood desires.

Oppose
 distribution of genetically modified foods (GMO)&apos;s in the City of Detroit.

 Hunger and
 Malnutrition 

The ability to sustain one&apos;s life through eating adequate and healthy
 foods is the most basic of all human rights. The City of Detroit should be committed to abolishing hunger, food insecurity,
 and malnutrition. According to the U.S. Department of Agriculture, an estimated 400,000 households in Michigan live with hunger
 or the threat of hunger. With thousands of vulnerable persons and families within the city finding that their resources are
 not enough to cover rent, utilities, medicine, clothes and other basic necessities, one could guess that a substantial number
 of the hungry live in Detroit.

The Director of the WIC program in Detroit writes that the program services
 approximately 65,000 residents per year; seventy-five percent are infants and children up to five years old. Year 2000 census
 data indicated that 12% of children had low birth weight, 20-26% of the children were anemic, and 10% were overweight. A recent
 pediatrician&apos;s report documented that&quot;even mild to moderate under-nutrition in young children is linked to problems
 that last throughout the lifespan.&quot;

While Federal programs, such as food stamps and WIC have helped
 to alleviate the most severe forms of hunger, they haven&apos;t adequately impacted food security. As well, the elderly population
 suffers from hunger and malnutrition due to isolation, lack of access to stores, inability to prepare nutritious meals, illness,
 general poor health and cognitive challenges.

Actions Needed:

Institute and support
 community self-help projects that address both hunger and malnutrition.

Support and increase community
 food banks, as well as information about and access to them.

Identify government and other resources
 that support programs to alleviate hunger and malnutrition, especially to the most vulnerable of the population.

Advocate
 for increased availability of state issued food benefits to eligible recipients and educate community residents about the
 role and importance of food stamps as the society&apos;s commitment to meeting basic needs of fellow citizens who are ill-served
 by the marketplace.

Encourage and work with faith-based institutions to do extensive out-reach and ensure
 that the food needs of young families and the elderly are met.

Educate the community and families about
 the benefits of breastfeeding and the risks associated with infant formulas.

 Impacts/Effects
 of an Inadequate Diet 

Recent research suggests that many of Detroit&apos;s children are
 consuming&quot;foods&quot;which do not promote optimal health. The study indicated that many children are getting energy
 primarily from powdered fruit flavored drinks. Children who do not have an adequate diet perform poorly in school because
 they are absent more due to illness, have shorter attention spans, retain less, and often exhibit inappropriate behaviors.

Far too many children and adults are overweight or obese and as a result suffer from poor self-esteem, lack
 of energy, social challenges and various health problems. Obesity should be of major concern in the city of Detroit. Clearly,
 at the heart of efforts to address obesity must be the understanding that this is a cultural phenomenon that is deep rooted
 in the habits that have been developed by post World War II generations of the American populace and federal policies that
 greatly subsidize less healthy processed foods making them abundant and cheap over fresh produce.

The
 movement towards convenience slowly led families away from the preparation of fresh foods that sustained health and wellness,
 to pre-packaged, instant foods that reduced the time spent in kitchens, but compromised nutrition. That downward spiral has
 continued with the proliferation of&quot;fast food&quot;restaurants throughout the city of Detroit. Many families get significant
 percentages of their food from such establishments. Research has shown that the fat contained in burgers and fries contribute
 significantly to obesity in children and adults. The tendency of those establishments to&quot;supersize&quot;their product
 has led to over-consumption, and again contributes to obesity and poor health.

Many Detroiters suffer
 from illnesses that could be prevented or controlled by improved eating habits including hypertension, diabetes, and heart
 disease. It has been suggested that certain cancers may be caused by nitrates and nitrites in processing meats that are used
 frequently in the African-American community such as smoked meats, bacon, sausage and lunch meat. African American communities
 also face higher risk from diabetes, cardio-vascular disease, and other diet-related illnesses.

The
 elderly, whose health is often more fragile than young and middle-aged people, are even more adversely impacted by poor diet
 and nutrition. Poor diet accelerates the aging process, contributing to degeneration of internal organs and mental capacity.

Culture is dynamic, and it can&apos;t be created or altered by individuals. Creating culture is a collective
 venture. Impacting the lifestyle habits that contribute to obesity and poor health will require the commitment of the City
 of Detroit and a broad cross-section of the institutions, families and individual members of our communities.

Actions
 Needed:

Conduct research specific to the population of the city of Detroit to quantify rates of malnourished,
 overweight and obese children and adults, as well as rates of diet-related diseases and dental problems of youth. Set in place
 mechanisms to track or monitor the rates over time.

Educate the public and policy-makers on this issue
 to bring attention to the scope of the issue and the immediacy needed in seeking solutions.

Research
 and address cultural barriers to improving eating habits.

Provide and promote opportunities for shared
 meal preparations at Community Kitchens, and growing more fresh fruits and vegetables in backyards and within neighborhoods.

 Citizen Education/Food Literacy 

Providing affordable,
 healthy food choices and easy access to those stores and markets which offer those choices is but one step towards impacting
 the health of our community through the foods we eat. How to select healthy choices, understand food labels and ingredients,
 and culturally appealing healthy methods of food preparation are essential as well. It is also important that our community
 understands the connection between what they eat and dealing with the health issues faced by so many. There exist a need for
 youth and adults to be able to unpack and counter the marketing messages of the mainstream food system that creates a disproportionate&quot;toxic food environment&quot;with billboards and other forms of marketing in poor communities and communities of color.

Actions needed:

Provide on-going education through the City of Detroit Health
 and Wellness Promotion Department, schools, churches and appropriate agencies on healthy food choices and culturally appropriate
 food preparation.

Oppose especially marketing of sugar-, fat- and salt-laden food and beverages to kids
 and in schools and other youth-oriented environments.

Provide education on food choices and preparation
 as related to specific conditions and diseases prevalent in our community such as high blood pressure, heart disease, diabetes,
 asthma, allergies and cancer.

Encourage grocery stores, Eastern Market and food markets to offer healthy
 recipes and healthy food preparation demonstrations, and sponsor educational sessions and food preparation classes.

Educate community, parents, and youth about and oppose contracts with soda manufacturers in schools.

 Economic Injustice within the Food Systems 

There exist two
 grocery stores owned and or operated by African Americans in Detroit. It is unknown whether any food wholesalers, farmers,
 distributors or food processing facilities providing food for the city of Detroit are owned, operated, or even hire Detroiters,
 specifically African-Americans; or if any of the food products consumed in our community were developed by people from our
 community. Aside from cashiers, baggers, stock persons and a few butchers, Detroiters, specifically African-Americans are
 absent from the food system. Our primary and predominant role is that of consumer.

Detroit&apos;s majority
 population must be represented at all levels and in all aspects of the food system. Having an economic/agricultural safety
 net to support the most vulnerable in our community should be included in our goals. Redefining wealth and prosperity within
 our social relationships and spiritual values will be a major step towards ensuring economic justice.

Actions
 Needed:

Identify and eliminate barriers to African-American participation and ownership in all aspects
 of the food system.

Explore providing employment and re-distribution of wealth through cooperative community
 ownership.

Convene dialogues and create partnerships with local universities and national organizations
 advocating for African-American communities to develop entrepreneurship and low-cost loan programs which encourage African
 American entrepreneurship.

Hold those accountable within the food system that profit from Detroiters
 to integrate Detroiters into their operations at all levels.

Develop frameworks for providing business
 incentives (such as tax incentives, small business loans, etc.) so that businesses that receive public subsidies return maximal
 benefits to the surrounding community in terms of healthy food access, local employment and other forms of community responsiveness.
 Such frameworks should be developed in collaboration with community organizations and residents. Incentives should support
 stores development and improvement in currently underserved neighborhoods.

 Urban Agriculture 

Detroit has a history of gardening and farming lots that goes back decades. African-Americans, who left southern
 states to provide for their families through factory jobs in the Detroit area, brought with them their connection to the land
 and their knowledge of how to grow vegetables and flowers. They knew how to preserve food, as well. Mayor Coleman A. Young
 started the Farm-A-Lot program in the 1970s which allowed residents to obtain a permit to farm vacant lots in their neighborhoods.
 The program provided seeds, seedlings and tilling of the land. Today, there is an urban agriculture movement in Detroit that
 is recognized throughout the U.S., Canada and Europe. Three farms currently exist within the city, as well as over 100 community
 and school gardens as well as hundreds of family gardens. There are also extensive training programs and support for urban
 agriculture ranging from bio-intensive growing methods to building a solar passive greenhouse.

Detroiters
 recognize that the value of the vacant land in the city goes beyond the construction of a structure. Residents have turned&quot;abandoned&quot;lots into productive agricultural resources. Mini farmers markets are springing up citywide providing
 Detroiters with fresh, organic food grown right in the neighborhood. Urban agriculture should be recognized as an essential
 contributor to the local food system. It ensures a ready supply of nutritious, high quality vegetables and fruits. The entry
 costs associated with intensive food production on small urban farms in a cooperative environment is much lower and accessible
 than the current trend of mega farms. Urban growers stand to benefit from increased opportunities to market local products.
 The potential market for local value-added products makes urban agriculture even more attractive as a local economic development
 tool.

Actions Needed:

Community, school and home gardens and mini-farms should
 be protected and supported through local, state and federal legislation.

The City of Detroit should
 support the efforts of the Detroit Black Community Food Security Network and others to identify and turn into production,
 multiple acres of City land on a long term lease with an option to purchase.

Update city codes and laws
 to allow urban agriculture, food production, and farmers markets on a neighborhood scale.

The City should
 acknowledge the importance of community gardens and protect them as resources that will not be taken over for other types
 of development.

The City of Detroit should provide resources and equipment for communities, schools
 and urban farms such as tractors, tools, seeds, topsoil, compost, fencing and access to water.

Identify
 and model other State programs that support small urban farms and help absorb the costs associated with food production, marketing
 and organic certification.

USDA initiatives to support the marketing and distribution of locally grown
 products to schools and creation of school gardens should be explored and encouraged.

Wherever possible,
 produce from local school gardens should be used in the preparation of school meals.

Encourage large
 public institutions such as Wayne State University, local hospitals, and large employers to source their cafeterias from local
 growers.

 The Role of Schools and other Public Institutions 

Schools
 and other institutions such as churches, community associations, social service agencies, nursing homes, homeless shelters
 and missions, hospitals, home daycare centers, and before and after school programs can have major impact on the dietary habits
 and health of the community. That impact can be made by purposefully educating the community as well as intentionally making
 healthy food options a priority. These institutions are possibly the most direct ways to reach the greatest number of people.
 As well, the growing nationwide interest in locally grown organic foods and value-added food products should be considered
 as an economic opportunity as it becomes necessary and is fitting that Detroiters seek independent employment. Our community
 should also become the suppliers of healthy food choices to the institutions within our community.

Many
 school related groups have traditionally relied on candy sales to raise funds for parent groups, clubs and athletic teams.
 Other fundraising options should be explored that do not promote excessive consumption of processed sugars.

Students
 attending Detroit schools should have the opportunity to plant, tend and harvest foods in school gardens. Students working
 in school gardens eat more fresh fruits and vegetables than those who do not. Many schools across the nation are realizing
 that farm-fresh produce is superior to canned and frozen foods. They are also realizing that supporting local or regional
 farmers helps to sustain local and regional food systems. When children have a greater understanding of where foods come from,
 they generally develop a greater appreciation for those foods, and are more willing to try food choices that may not be considered
 popular.

Schools and other public institutions have the responsibility of educating the citizens of
 the City of Detroit about health and wellness. Newsletters, meetings, and other gatherings should regularly feature information
 about diet, exercise and other components of health and wellness.

Block clubs, community associations
 and churches should be encouraged to partner with the City of Detroit to develop a network of community gardens. These gardens
 will increase the amount of fresh, affordable, nutritious food available to Detroiters, will promote community building and
 intergeneration communication and will help to improve the city&apos;s aesthetics and air quality. Additionally, publicly owned
 land should be made available whenever possible to develop community gardens.

Actions Needed:

Schools and other public institutions should encourage young people to pursue careers in agriculture, aquaculture,
 animal husbandry, bee-keeping and other food related fields, so as to reduce the dependency of Detroiters on others for food.

Schools and other public institutions should eliminate soda pop, candy, gum, and&quot;foods&quot;with high sugar content, artificial preservatives, and artificial dyes from vending machines. They should be replaced with
 high-quality snacks and beverages that promote health and wellness such as fruit, nuts, granola bars, wholegrain chips, 100%
 juices and water.

Schools should be encouraged to develop food curriculum for pre-K through 12th grade
 and beyond. Curriculum could include aspects of production, processing, healthy eating, and recycling and composting.

Every school should have a school garden that can provide food for their lunches.

Schools
 should require school lunch programs to incorporate fresh local and regional foods and develop relationships with those farmers
 who can provide educational opportunities for children.

Encourage the formation of health ministries
 in churches that includes a focus on developing healthy dietary habits.

Encourage churches to offer
 healthy choices at church functions, and incorporate church-sponsored gardens and healthy food preparation information as
 part of any food banks or programs.

 Emergency Response 

A
 food related emergency may involve the unintentional or deliberate contamination, or sudden loss of access to food. A food
 emergency could occur at any point in the food system from farm to table and may be the result of natural disasters, human
 error or intentional threat. Any food emergency must be quickly identified followed by a well-coordinated and communicated
 response. That response should include pre-established lines of communication, alternate food and water supplies and delivery
 systems, as well as close coordination with local, State and Federal emergency responders.

Actions Needed:

A food emergency plan, that includes strategies for prevention of food emergencies, for the City of Detroit
 that is communicated and made available to the public.

Coordination among church and community organizations,
 elected officials and other community leaders, law enforcement, schools, churches and other institutions, hospitals and other
 medical facilities for dissemination of information and training as first responders in case of a serious event or situation.

Development of adequate food reserves in case of an emergency.


 
 
 Food Security: When all of the members of a community have easy access to adequate amounts of
 affordable, nutritious, culturally appropriate food. 
 The Detroit Reality: 
1. Many Detroiters
 do not have a grocery store within a mile of the homes
2.&quot;Fast food&quot;has practically replaced home cooked
 meals in many Black households
3. Detroit&apos;s majority African population is dependent on others to feed it
	</body>
</document>
