<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002575" url="http://www.urbanspoon.com/r/189/1017271/restaurant/Dog-n-Suds-Lafayette" time="2012-07-12-18:38" support="4" score="0.004738474369642563" bingtitle="Dog n Suds - Lafayette | Urbanspoon" webtitle="Dog n Suds - Lafayette | Urbanspoon">
			<query id="000519" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000770" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="001335" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000516" bing-rank="122"/>
	<description>... food, and they bring it to your car, complete with a tray ... Lets be clear this is a drive in not a ... like I was just going to another fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Sign In 
 
 Lafayette » Lafayette » Dog n Suds 
 
 Switch city 
 
 Chicago Cincinnati Indianapolis Los Angeles Louisville Milwaukee New York More... 
 
Dog n Suds
 
(765) 447-5457
 Lafayette 601 Sagamore Pky S 
 Lafayette , IN 47905 
 ourdognsuds.com 
 on facebook.com 
 See all 19 reviews Cuisine American , Burgers , Hot Dogs/Sausages Features Kid Friendly , Outdoor Dining Menu $ Under $10 per entree Coney Cheese Dog, Foot Long Coney Dog, Foot Long Coney Cheese Dog, Foot Long... View menu 
 Hours M T W T F S S Breakfast Lunch               Dinner               Late 
   329 people have voted 88 % like it Add your vote 
 I like it I don&apos;t 
 
 Share Send to phone Edit Restaurant Add to a Guide 
 
 Restaurant sponsors You might also like...
 
 La Scala 79% $$ Lafayette - Italian 312 Main St 
 
 Red Lobster 60% $$ Lafayette - Seafood 820 Sagamore Pkwy N 
 
 Add your review Blogger reviews

 August 10, 2008 Lafayette Eats Dog n Suds is a drive-in eat in your car type establishment. You pull up to the speaker, order your food, and they bring it to your car, complete with a tray that attaches to your window... More from Lafayette Eats 
 
 Diner reviews

Sort by: Relevance | Date | Positive | Negative 

 September 12, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by AlohaPhD ( 47 reviews ) A must-stop every time I make it back to Lafayette. Coney cheese dog is delicious with a quality dog and classic coney sauce. Creamy root beer served in a frosty mug. Need I say more? Love the nostalgic drive-in service. October 13, 2009 Really likes it Yum! by EggDropErin ( 441 reviews ) Oh how I miss Dog N Suds being near Indianapolis. The Indianapolis Zoo has one that is only open in the summer, otherwise you must travel far and wide from where I live. We were in the Lafayette area last week, and I could not wait to sink my teeth into a coney. They had prompt service. Fresh, hot food. I put away two foot long coney cheese dogs like they were nothing. My frosty mug of root beer was refreshing, even though it was slightly chilly outside. Very happy to have eaten here! 1 out of 1 found this review helpful June 18, 2010 Likes it Delicious Root Beer by Charles Smith ( 5 reviews ) There is nothing like their root beer, and it compliments the coney cheese dogs perfectly. Fast service, great food, great hours, what more could you ask for? 2 out of 3 found this review helpful March 20, 2011 Really likes it by aboy ( 15 reviews ) Lets be clear this is a drive in not a four star restaurant. I love it. Its cheap, quick, good, and most of all a great atmosphere. One thing I will say is the coney sauce is sweet here its not like chili sauce, and that is a turn off for some people. But if you are a hotdog enthusiast you have to try it. Their root beer is the best! A Lafayette tradition. 1 out of 1 found this review helpful June 19, 2010 Likes it THE BEST EVER by Brent Nelson ( 2 reviews ) From the time I was a kid to the day I die, Dog-N-Suds will be the best. This is a must Eat while in the Lafayette area. 2 out of 2 found this review helpful June 18, 2010 Likes it Original by Marilyn ( 1 review ) Lafayette is full of burger kings, mcdonalds, and taco bells. I think it&apos;s great to have such an original treasure like Dog n Suds. The coney dogs and ice cold root beer are two things that I look forward each summer. Along with their many other awesome menu items! 2 out of 2 found this review helpful September 4, 2011 Likes it Mobile review by Jessica ( 20 reviews ) Classic drive in with great food and icy cold root beer :-) October 21, 2010 Likes it What can I say? by Lori Darling Geartz-Sposato ( 9 reviews ) Wonderful dogs&amp;the root beer was the best I&apos;ve ever had...AWESOME!!!! July 5, 2011 Likes it Amazing Food by Deb. M ( 1 review ) The best thing about summer is going to Dog n Suds! They have the best root beer around as well as corn dogs!! Staff is always fast and friendly ..We live in Connecticut and every time we visit its one of the first places we go!! ... 2 out of 3 found this review helpful June 26, 2010 Likes it Wonderful by Char ( 1 review ) I have only been in Indiana a few years. Someone suggested that we got there and I thought it was great. I am originally from Chi-Town and I think I know hot dogs. And I have to say that DNS is just as great as the Chicago style. The service is awesome! 2 out of 3 found this review helpful June 25, 2010 Doesn&apos;t like it Disappointing by hostetle ( 10 reviews ) The Root Beer is good. The frosted mugs are cool. The food is not very good. The fries are the fast food fries, that if you don&apos;t dip in something, they just aren&apos;t good. The hot dogs, are just hot dogs, nothing special. I really wanted some nostalgia, to be reminded of being a kid and going with my family, but instead, I felt like I was just going to another fast food restaurant. One that didn&apos;t really have that great of food. 1 out of 2 found this review helpful June 24, 2010 Likes it Absolutely Wonderful by Rhonda Ullrich ( 2 reviews ) I can&apos;t wait for them to open in the Spring and am always sad to see them close in the Fall. The food is great, the staff is friendly, The Owners are Wonderful. Who could not like this place. It&apos;s a fun experience for kids and brings back old memories for us older kids! 1 out of 1 found this review helpful +1 more review from Rhonda Ullrich November 22, 2010 We Miss You Is it Spring Yet??? July 31, 2010 Likes it Family tradition by yeltonla ( 1 review ) My Mom and Dad always took my three sisters and me to Dog&amp;Suds every spring as soon as they opened. When my sisters were really little, they got the baby root beer mugs. When I had kids of my own, they loved going there with me, too. Now that I have grandkids, it&apos;s really fun taking them to Dog&amp;Suds. Great food and FABULOUS FROSTY Root Beer! 1 out of 1 found this review helpful June 18, 2010 Likes it Best Coney&apos;s ever by Darlene ( 2 reviews ) I love their coney dogs. I am always in a rush to get back in the spring when they re-open. Visited at least 3 times in the first week they opened this year bc we were going to be moving (to Brownsburg) and I wanted to get as much as I could. Dog-N-Suds is my all-time favorite place to eat in Lafayette!! 1 out of 2 found this review helpful June 18, 2010 Likes it Dog &apos;n&apos; Suds 4 Ever by Mickey Sticks ( 1 review ) Best place to eat in the summer in Lafayette, hands down. The Coney Cheese Dogs with Onion, the mushrooms and the DNS Root Beer are the BOMB! Nothin&apos; beats it! 1 out of 2 found this review helpful May 1, 2010 Doesn&apos;t like it Mobile review by Emily Jayne Bressler ( 5 reviews ) I&apos;m not a big fan 1 out of 4 found this review helpful June 19, 2010 Likes it Love it! by ginlyn ( 1 review ) I love Dog N Suds! I grew up in Lafayette, IN and have moved to Atlanta, GA. I miss their Coney Dogs so much that whenever I am visiting family, I always make it a point to stop in and have lunch. 
 
 Add a photo Restaurant photos

 by Dustin Washington Breaded... by Dustin Washington Foamy 
 All 18 photos View larger map Driving directions 
Nearby Restaurants

 MT Fuji Japanese Steakhouse 86% $$ Lafayette - Steakhouse, Japanese Champ&apos;s Lafayette Hostess Cake Continental Lafayette Subway $ Lafayette - Sandwiches/Subs, Fast Food Akropolis 88% $$ Lafayette - Greek 
 More nearby restaurants People reached this page by searching for: 
 dog n suds menu dog n suds hours best thing to eat at dogs and suds drive in dog and suds root beer mugs dog n suds menu lafayette 
 
 Add Restaurant Advertise Contact Us Blog Go Mobile Terms of Service Privacy FAQ About Us Careers 


 Partner Sites: Ask Answers Life123 Bloglines Citysearch Insider Pages MerchantCircle
	</body>
</document>
