<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002493" url="http://ufdc.ufl.edu/UF00026102/00103" time="2012-07-12-18:33" support="1" score="0.0002594299916635212" bingtitle="The Apopka chief - UFDC Home - All Collection Groups" webtitle="Apopka chief">
			<query id="000609" bing-rank="194"/>
	<description>remodeling or rebuilding his fast-food restaurant. ... dience to your order, I met with two men, who said ... ers as well as seasonal items for the home and garden.</description>
	<body>
		UFDC Home  |  Florida Newspapers myUFDC Home  |  Help  |  RSS 
 
 SHOW TABLE OF CONTENTS 













 
 P RINT O PTIONS X   
 
 Select the options below to print this item  Include brief citation? 

 Citation only 
 Print thumbnails 
 Print current page 
 Print all pages 
 Print a range of pages from page A 1 page A 2 page A 3 page A 4 page A 5 page A 6 page A 7 page A 8 page A 9 page A 10 page A 11 page A 12 page A 13 page A 14 page A 15 page A 16 page B 1 page B 2 page B 3 page B 4 page B 5 page B 6 page B 7 page B 8 page B 9 page B 10 page B 11 page B 12 page B 13 page B 14 page B 15 page B 16 page C 1 page C 2 page C 3 page C 4 page C 5 page C 6 page C 7 page C 8 page D 1 page D 2 page D 3 page D 4 page D 5 page D 6 page D 7 page D 8 to page A 1 page A 2 page A 3 page A 4 page A 5 page A 6 page A 7 page A 8 page A 9 page A 10 page A 11 page A 12 page A 13 page A 14 page A 15 page A 16 page B 1 page B 2 page B 3 page B 4 page B 5 page B 6 page B 7 page B 8 page B 9 page B 10 page B 11 page B 12 page B 13 page B 14 page B 15 page B 16 page C 1 page C 2 page C 3 page C 4 page C 5 page C 6 page C 7 page C 8 page D 1 page D 2 page D 3 page D 4 page D 5 page D 6 page D 7 page D 8 
    
 
 
 
 
 
 
 The Apopka chief 
 ALL ISSUES CITATION SEARCH THUMBNAILS MAP IT! PAGE IMAGE ZOOMABLE   Go To: page A 1 page A 2 page A 3 page A 4 page A 5 page A 6 page A 7 page A 8 page A 9 page A 10 page A 11 page A 12 page A 13 page A 14 page A 15 page A 16 page B 1 page B 2 page B 3 page B 4 page B 5 page B 6 page B 7 page B 8 page B 9 page B 10 page B 11 page B 12 page B 13 page B 14 page B 15 page B 16 page C 1 page C 2 page C 3 page C 4 page C 5 page C 6 page C 7 page C 8 page D 1 page D 2 page D 3 page D 4 page D 5 page D 6 page D 7 page D 8   
 
 
 Contact Us | Permissions | Preferences | Technical Aspects | Statistics | Internal | Privacy Policy 
 ©2004 - 2011 University of Florida George A. Smathers Libraries.
All rights reserved. 
 Acceptable Use, Copyright, and Disclaimer Statement 
Powered by SobekCM
	</body>
</document>
