<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002873" url="http://www.thehealthyeatingguide.com/healthyeatingplans.html" time="2012-07-12-18:56" support="1" score="0.00014379474693134152" bingtitle="Healthy Eating Plans and a Free Healthy Sample Menu Plan to Help ..." webtitle="Healthy Eating Plans and a Free Healthy Sample Menu Plan to Help You Get Started">
			<query id="000870" bing-rank="112"/>
	<description>Here are 8 simple steps to help you begin creating your own healthy meal plans: 1. Eat 6 small meals a day. 2. Cut out refined carbs such as white bread, flour, rice, etc ...</description>
	<body>
		[ ? ] Subscribe To This Site 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
Healthy Eating Plans and a Healthy Sample Menu Plan




 
Making healthy eating plans is a great way for you to develop a lifetime of healthy eating and exercise habits and can also help you lose fat and/or gain muscle, depending on your goals.



Here are 8 simple steps to help you begin creating your own healthy meal plans:





 1. Eat 6 small meals a day .
2. Cut out refined carbs such as white bread, flour, rice, etc. and cut out foods and drinks high in sugar. Choose whole grain and whole wheat carbs instead.
3. Eat more fruits and vegetables ...a lot more (start with 3-4 servings per day and work your way up to 8-9).
4. Start eating more protein, but be sure to choose lean sources of protein .
5. Eat less saturated and trans fat, and more healthy fats like mono- and poly-unsaturated fats.
6. Watch your salt intake by learning how to read a nutrition label .
7. Exercise for 30-60 minutes a day, at least 4 days a week. Check out our free exercise plans section for some great exercise tips.
8. When eating out, do your homework and look at the restaurant nutrition facts online before you go.

To help you develop the right healthy eating plans, we have put together a sample menu plan designed for people on a 2,000 calorie diet. This healthy eating plan is designed for people who are looking to lose fat and gain lean muscle. This meal plan is also higher in heart healthy monounsaturated fats (but contains limited amounts of saturated fat and no trans fat).




 Healthy Eating Plan – 2,000 Calorie Diet Calories Fat Carbs Protein Breakfast: 4 egg whites 64 0 0 16 1 whole egg 70 4 0 6 1 banana 121 0 31 1 ½ cup oatmeal 150 3 27 5 1 cup low sodium v8 50 0 10 2 Mid-morning snack: 1 cup carrots 35 0 9 1 Lunch: 2 oz. Dietz&amp;Watson reduced sodium turkey 60 1 1 12 1 slice (.5 oz.) mozzarella cheese 60 5 1 6 1 South Beach Diet whole wheat wrap 110 3 25 5 1 cup romaine lettuce 15 0 3 0 1 tomato 25 0 5 1 1 tsp. olive oil 40 5 0 0 1 tsp red wine vinegar 5 0 0 0 1 serving Whole Grain Wheat Thins (16 crackers) 140 6 21 2 2 T Sabra Supremely Spicy Hummus 80 6 2 1 Mid-afternoon snack: 1.5 T almond butter 146 12 5 5 1 Fuji apple 80 0 22 1 Pre-workout snack: Clif Organic Z Bar 120 3 22 3 Post-workout snack: 

 1 scoop EAS Whey Protein 



 120 2 2 23 1 cup skim milk 80 0 12 8 Dinner: 4 oz. chicken breast 130 1 0 27 2 garlic cloves 9 0 2 0 1 tsp. Dijon mustard 5 0 0 0 2 cups romaine lettuce 5 0 1 0 1 tomato 25 0 5 1 1 tsp. olive oil 40 5 0 0 1 tsp. balsamic vinegar 5 0 2 0 1 tsp. lemon juice 0 0 0 0 ½ cup black beans 140 1 25 7 Night time snack: 1 Sargento Light String Cheese 50 3 1 6 TOTALS 2,051 66 239 143 




 

 Next: Nutritional Value Calculator
 Return From Healthy Eating Plans to Counting Calories
 Return to The Healthy Eating Guide Home Page 

 Copyright 2012, The Healthy Eating Guide
	</body>
</document>
