<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002703" url="http://www.tripadvisor.com/ShowTopic-g28926-i29-k3369816-How_much_would_meals_cost_for_a_family_of_4_per_day-California.html" time="2012-07-12-18:46" support="2" score="0.00096819678697109" bingtitle="How much would meals cost for a family of 4 per day - California ..." webtitle="How much would meals cost for a family of 4 per day - California Forum - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="000865" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="000861" bing-rank="74"/>
	<description>For lunch, a fast food restaurant usually offers reasonably ... I assume you will have a car. In any case ... The kitchens allow you to eat home-like meals in, even if ...</description>
	<body>
		Home California 
 California Tourism California Hotels California Vacation Rentals Flights to California California Restaurants Things to Do in California California Travel Forum California Photos California Travel Guide 
 Hotels Flights Vacation Rentals Restaurants Things to Do Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
California
 
 California Tourism California Hotels Vacation Rentals Flights to California California Hotel Deals More On California Restaurants Things to Do Travel Forums Photos Videos California Deals Discount Hotels Hotel&amp;Air Packages Travel Guide 
 Free Newsletter 
Interested in California ?

We&apos;ll send you updates with the latest deals, reviews and articles for California each week.
 
Popular cities

 Anaheim Hotels Bakersfield Hotels Big Bear Lake Hotels California Desert Hotels Carlsbad Hotels Carmel Hotels Fresno Hotels Greater Palm Springs Hotels Lake Tahoe (California) Hotels Long Beach Hotels Los Angeles Hotels Mammoth Lakes Hotels Monterey Hotels Monterey Peninsula Hotels Napa Hotels Napa Valley Hotels Oakland Hotels Ontario Hotels Orange County Hotels Palm Springs Hotels Redding Hotels Sacramento Hotels San Diego Hotels San Francisco Hotels San Jose Hotels Santa Barbara Hotels Santa Cruz Hotels South Lake Tahoe Hotels Sunnyvale Hotels 
 Explore the world! TripAdvisor has reviews and information on over 400,000 locations, including: Hotels 
 Island Inn in Sanibel Island La Concha Resort: A Renaissance Hotel in San Juan Wingate Inn Augusta Northeast Business Hotel Nishiura Piccola Ribeira 
 Travel Destinations 
 New York City hotels Key West Beijing deals San Francisco deals 
 Sightseeing 
 Giardini Pubblici Indro Montanelli in Milan 
 
 Home 
 United States California (CA) Forums 
 
 
California Forum: How much would meals cost for a family of 4 per day
 
Hotels travelers are raving about...

 Pacific Terrace Hotel 849 Reviews San Diego, CA Read reviews Suites at Fisherman&apos;s Wharf 281 Reviews San Francisco, CA Read reviews
	</body>
</document>
