<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002208" url="http://www.articlesbase.com/medicine-articles/flu-remedies-3151475.html" time="2012-07-12-18:06" support="1" score="0.0015704943302359516" bingtitle="Flu Remedies - Free Articles Directory | Submit Articles ..." webtitle="Flu Remedies">
			<query id="000250" bing-rank="195"/>
	<description>Traditional medicines, prescriptions, over the counter ... the morning you may grab a coffee, energy drink, or high calorie snack from a fast food restaurant or ...</description>
	<body>
		Free Online Articles Directory 
 Why Submit Articles? Top Authors Top Articles FAQ AB Answers 

 Publish Article 
 
 Login Login via Register 

 Hello My Home Sign Out 
 Email 
 Password 
 Remember me?
 Lost Password? 
 Home Page &gt; Health &gt; Medicine &gt; Flu Remedies 
Flu Remedies
 Posted: Aug 28, 2010 |Comments: 0 | 
Thousands of people get the flu every year. There is no one sure fire way to cure the symptoms of the flu however there are hundreds of different ways to get relief from the flu. Everyone has their own way to cure their symptoms of the flu, and some ways work better for some and still others choose different methods. Traditional medicines, prescriptions, over the counter medications, homeopathic and herbal remedies all have ways to reduce the signs and symptoms of the flu. Its up to you to choose what works best for you.

Although the number one flu remedy is of course to not get the flu, but no matter how hard we try there is no sure way to avoid getting the flu. Even flu shots that are offered at hospitals, pharmacies and clinics don&apos;t always prevent someone from getting the flu.  Depending upon your beliefs will determine what flu remedies and preventions are right for you.

 Herbs -

 Elderberry extract is derived from the sambucus tree or shrub. The extract is used to treat flu like symptoms at first sight. Elderberry extract can be used in a juice or syrup to shorten the duration of cold and flu like symptoms. Elderberries contain potassium, vitamin C and anthocyanins, a powerful antioxidant and anti-inflammatory. Although there has been nothing proven on why it reduces the cold and flu the main theory is that elderberry has very high oxygen radical absorption capacity, reducing free radicals in the body. 

Take 1 teaspoon of elderberry extract four to five times daily after the first sign of a cold or flu. Take it until symptoms subside, then 1 teaspoon daily for general health.

 Boneset is another herb from genus Eupatorium of the flowering plants, which helps to lessen the symptoms of the flu as well. Normally it is ingested as a tea because of the toxic affects the plant can have if ingested whole. Boneset is known to reduce fever from viral or bacterial infections through the act of sweating. Additionally boneset promotes the removal of phlegm through coughing. 

To make boneset infusion takes one ounce of dried boneset leaf and one quart of boiling water. Mix them in a quart mason jar and leave to steep for 4 hours. Strain out the dried herbs, reheat and drink. Lemon and honey can be added to taste.

 Echinacea is another popular herb used to shorten the duration of cold and flu symptoms. Echinacea is believed to enhance the immune system.  Echinacea is also a blood cleanser and signals the release for white blood cells to fight infection. In addition Echinacea is excellent for cold and flu prevention by keep the immune system strong and intact to fight off the attacks of bacteria and viruses. 

Echinacea tinctures can be taken daily under the tongue for general health and 3-5 times a day during symptomatic times.

 Abra Bath is an organic product you can add to your bath water to reduce body aches, congestion and relieve chills associated with the flu. Abra is formulated with specific organic herbs to relieve the symptoms of the flu. Ginger is one of nature&apos;s antiviral herbs. Ginger is used as an antiseptic, antioxidant and pain reliever. Ginger is used to treat colds, sore throats, inflammation, reduction of fever, and pain. Ginger can be used as a spice in food, hot tea, or in a smoothie.

 
 
 Homeopathic- 

 Oscillococcinum is a homeopathic medicine, which relieves symptoms of the flu. Originally manufactured in France and has been in used in over 50 countries for the past 65 years. Easily accessible in local vitamin stores, natural food stores, organic grocery stores and online through Boiron. 

 Over the Counter Medicine -

 Flu Relief nasal spray is another way to relieve the flu symptoms. Nasal sprays relieve nasal congestion and blockage that can be caused by a cold or flu. Nasal sprays come in two forms decongestants and saline solutions. The decongestants clear the nasal passage and reduce stuffiness. Saline water solutions loosen the mucus in the nasal passage to relieve congestions. Saline solutions contain no medication but rely on the salt in to cleanse the nasal passage. Acetaminophen, Tylenol, or Ibuprofen are over the counter pain relievers. These products can reduce fever, headaches or aching muscles caused by the flu. Robitussin is an over the counter cough medicine the can quiet a persistent cough related to the flu or a cold. Robitussin is specially formulated to help with symptoms associated with the flu. Vicks vapor rub is topical decongestant uses to relieve congestion associated with the flu. Over the counter decongestants help relieve congestion in the chest, nose and throat. Decongestants help to loosen mucus and excrete them out the body. Throat lozenges are used for symptoms of a sore throat. Throat sprays have the same affect on sore throats. Sudacare shower soothers are mint tablets that once added to the bath water creates non-medicated vapors of lavender, eucalyptus, menthol, and camphor. This helps sooth, relax and relieve symptoms of the flu such as aches, congestion and fatigue. 

 Natural- 

 Gargle with warm salt water to reduce a sore throat. Salt is used as an antiseptic and disinfects the throat of germs. It is natural and inexpensive and can be used as often as needed. Rest is the most important part of recovering from the flu. The body is usually weak and drained from fighting off the flu virus that it is fatigued. Rest allows the body to recuperate after fighting against the flu. Drink fluids. Water is the most important thing to drink, but other fluids include hot teas, Gatorades to replace electrolytes, or pedialyte. Avoid caffeinated drinks that will act as a diuretic. When your body is fighting an infection, it is easier to become dehydrated and with all the symptoms that you are experiencing from the flu you don&apos;t want to add symptoms from dehydration. Fluids also flush out toxins or reminisce of infection. Health juices such as mangosteen, noni, goji, aloe vera and acai berry are good replenishing drinks as well. In addition to keeping the body hydrated they have added vitamins, minerals and antioxidants to boost the bodies immune system. Clean out your ears with hydrogen peroxide. Hydrogen peroxide disinfects and kills germs. By putting a couple of drops in each ear you can kill cold and flu germs that can build up in the ear and cause infection. Use a cotton ball or Q-tip and allow the hydrogen peroxide to fizz and bubble. Drain from the ear with a tissue, then reapply until it no longer bubbles. Garlic is one of food sources that has high anti-bacterial properties. It can be used to help fight infection within the body. Additionally it has the ability to boost the immune system. Vitamin C is a natural cold reliever. It can be consumed through foods or supplement form. Vitamin C is prevalent in fresh fruits and vegetables. By consuming large quantities of vitamin C you can help the body fight infection and relieve symptoms of the flu. 

 Prescription Medication (Must be obtained through a medical professional)- 

 Tamiflu is a prescription medication used to treat symptoms of the flu. It decreases the severity of symptoms such as stuffy nose, cough, sore throat, fever/chills, aches, and tiredness. It also increases recovery time by 1-2 days. Relenza additionally decreases flu symptoms and increases recovery time. Relenza stops the influenza virus from continuing to grow within the body. It can also prevent the flu inflection for people who are surrounded by infected persons. 

So whatever remedy you choose to use, you have the option to choose how you treat your symptoms of a cold and flu this season. Remember that if your symptoms worsen it is recommended to see a physician to determine the type of strain you have. Always keep yourself informed and take steps to prevent getting the cold or flu.

http://www.universalhealthinfo.com/Flu_Remedies.html
 Retrieved from &quot; http://www.articlesbase.com/medicine-articles/flu-remedies-3151475.html &quot; Sarah Labdar - About the Author: 


 Everyday Health, Live your Life to the fullest! 



 
Questions and Answers
 Ask our experts your Medicine related questions here... Ask 200  Characters left 
 
 How is influenza a virus transmitted? 
 
 How many cold viruses are there? 
 
 How is the cold virus transmitted? 
 
 Rate this Article 1 2 3 4 5 vote(s) 0 vote(s) Feedback Print Re-Publish Source:   http://www.articlesbase.com/medicine-articles/flu-remedies-3151475.html 
Article Tags:

 flu 
 , 
 influenza 
 , 
 cold 
 , 
 virus 
 , 
 bacteria 
 , 
 remedies 
 , 
 herbal remedies 
 , 
 natural remedies 
 , 
 over the counter 
 , 
 prescription 
 
 
Related Articles
 
Latest Medicine Articles
 
More from Sarah Labdar
 
 
 Antiviral Herbal remedies for Quick and Dependable Relief 
 
As opposed to the way over-the-counter drugs including prescription antibiotics do the job which often targets the elimination of infectious pathogens, like fungus infection and unhealthy bacteria, antiviral herbal products enhance the body&apos;s capability to heal itself even from theoretically incurable disorders.
 By: Tatiana Mavromatis l Health l Feb 02, 2011 
 Colds&amp;Flu Remedies 
 
The&quot;best&quot;flu remedy seems to vary by who you talk to. Some people think that certain over-the-counter medications are the best way to get relief. Others feel homeopathic remedies work the best. Still others feel that only their doctor can help make them make the appropriate choice.
 By: dou9dir9mi l Health l Dec 15, 2011 
 Why Addicts are Scared of Going to a Drug Rehab Center 
 
There are many people who are suffering from addiction of dangerous drugs. They keep taking drugs frequently without bothering about its harmful consequences. As a result, they become drug addicts and risk their own life. It may be difficult for them to come out of the serious addiction they are going through.
 By: Clinton Dixon l Health &gt; Medicine l Jul 07, 2012 
 Alcohol Treatment Centers Are Right Place for Alcohol Dependents 
 
The United States of America is listed among the nation that has many alcohol dependents who are suffering from various alcohol addiction problems. Family issues, financial problems, violence, loneliness, anger, frustration, depression are some of the factors that turn a normal individual into an alcohol dependent.
 By: Clinton Dixon l Health &gt; Medicine l Jul 07, 2012 
 In Vitro Fertilisation Treatment 
 
Anyone who has gone down the road of IVF Treatment, or is considering it as an possibility, can grasp that it&apos;s a journey which might seem daunting, scary and after all full of uncertainty. One attainable fertility treatment is in vitro fertilization, that after you don&apos;t {seem to be} conversant in how it works will seem a lot of difficult than it truly is really.
 By: homer mk l Health &gt; Medicine l Jul 06, 2012 
 Are your medicines authentic enough? 
 
PharmaSecure&apos;s excellent approach indeed creates immense value for numerous consumers and medicine manufactures across the country.
 By: Jessica Blox l Health &gt; Medicine l Jul 06, 2012 
 Complex Knee Revisions- Helps in Relieving Knee Pain 
 
Knee pain is a common problem which is faced by a large number of people worldwide. A large number of reasons may lead to knee pain. Knee pain is acute among the aged population. Some of the most common reasons of this knee pain in the older men and women include arthritis, injuries in the ligaments, kneecap dislocation, etc.
 By: Jack Oliver l Health &gt; Medicine l Jul 06, 2012 
 Add These Foods To Your Diet For Weight Loss 
 
Why do we eat? The most basic reason is hunger, however with the growing rate of obesity this shows us that people eat for more reasons than just hunger. People eat out of boredom, loneliness, hunger, or deprivation. All of which can lead to excessive overeating and added weight gain. By choosing the right foods to eat when you are actually hungry you can limit cravings to eat for these other reasons. Superfoods contain essential nutrients that the body needs to properly function.
 By: Sarah Labdar l Health &gt; Nutrition l Jun 18, 2012 
 The Importance of Vitamin C 
 
Vitamin C plays a vital role in how the body functions, even though it is only considered a micronutrient. Vitamin C is essential to immune function, iron absorption, bone building, wound healing, healthy skin, blood pressure and eyesight. Because vitamin C is vital to so many of the bodies functioning maintaining appropriate levels within the body is important. Vitamin C acts as a catalyst within the body, speeding up chemical reactions using less energy.
 By: Sarah Labdar l Health &gt; Supplements&amp;Vitamins l Jun 12, 2012 
 More Reasons You Need to Eat Breakfast In The Morning 
 
Breakfast is the most important meal of the day. And it really is! Eating breakfast kick starts your metabolism, provides your body with essential nutrients, helps maintain a healthy weight and protects you from disease. Even with the facts about how important breakfast is, 30% of Americans still skip breakfast. Why?
 By: Sarah Labdar l Health &gt; Nutrition l Jun 12, 2012 
 Foods to Fight Acne Breakouts 
 
For years people have been saying that pizza, French fries, chips, cookies and junk foods cause acne breakouts. In actuality there is no proven evidence that shows the connection to specific foods causing acne. Eating unhealthy carbohydrates sets off a chain reaction within the body causing the release of insulin, changing hormone levels in the body, which increases oil production and cellular multiplication.
 By: Sarah Labdar l Health &gt; Acne l Jun 09, 2012 
 Homeopathy For All Your Ailments 
 
Homeopathic medicine is just one of many alternative medicines making a comeback in the U.S., which is strange since homeopathy is the second most commonly, used form of medicine in the world. Homeopathy like many of the other alternative medicines is based on the body&apos;s innate capacity to heal itself. With homeopathy a minute dose of a natural substance is consumed to stimulate self-healing. The basis for homeopathy is centered on the idea of&quot;like cures like&quot;.
 By: Sarah Labdar l Health &gt; Alternative Medicine l Jun 05, 2012 
Discuss this Article
 Author Navigation 
 My Home Publish Article View/Edit Articles View/Edit Q&amp;A; Edit your Account Manage Authors Statistics Page Article Widget 

 My Home Edit your Account Update Profile View/Edit Q&amp;A; Publish Article 
 Author Box Sarah Labdar has 268 articles online Contact Author Subscribe to RSS Print article Send to friend Re-Publish article Articles Categories All Categories Advertising Arts&amp;Entertainment Automotive Beauty Business Careers Computers Education Finance Food and Beverage Health Hobbies Home and Family Home Improvement Internet Law Marketing News and Society Relationships Self Improvement Shopping Spirituality Sports and Fitness Technology Travel Writing Health Acne Allergies Alternative Medicine Anti Aging Cancer Dental Care Disabilities Diseases and Conditions Hair Loss Hearing Medical Tourism Medicine Men&apos;s Health Mental Health Nutrition Plastic Surgeries Quit Smoking Sleep Supplements&amp;Vitamins Vision Wellness Women&apos;s Health Need Help? 
 Contact Us FAQ Submit Articles Editorial Guidelines Blog 
 Site Links 
 Recent Articles Top Authors Top Articles Find Articles Site Map Mobile Version 
 Webmasters 
 RSS Builder RSS 
 Business Info 
 Advertising 
 Use of this web site constitutes acceptance of the Terms Of Use and Privacy Policy | User published content is licensed under a Creative Commons License .
 Copyright © 2005-2012 Free Articles by ArticlesBase.com, All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
