<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002229" url="http://ph.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20111103062339AAFuhdZ" time="2012-07-12-18:07" support="2" score="0.0009562982970476668" bingtitle="What is the average number of deliveries per night for a fast food ..." webtitle="Yahoo! Answers - What is the average number of deliveries per night for a fast food restaurant in London, UK?">
			<query id="000249" bing-rank="202"/>
			<query id="000230" bing-rank="160"/>
	<description>Food &amp; Drink; Games &amp; Recreation; Health; Home &amp; Garden ... number of deliveries per night for a fast food restaurant in ... have any idea what the average utility bill ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Philippines Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Local Businesses &gt; United Kingdom &gt; London &gt; Resolved Question 
 Joseph Member since: November 03, 2011 Total points: 91 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
What is the average number of deliveries per night for a fast food restaurant in London, UK?
 -If demand was there and you could easily keep up, how many deliveries would be reasonable to expect?
-if someone can answer this I wonder do you also have any idea what the average utility bill might be for a kebab shop? just the standard grill/rotating grill/fryer/fridge set up

thanks in advance I would be most appreciative of any help here 
 8 months ago Report Abuse 
 by Ed Fox Member since: November 10, 2010 Total points: 102,280 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 OMG! Not another Kebab shop. London&apos;s full of them. You want a KFC or a Mickey D&apos;s but can you find one when you need one? No all you can see are f--king kebab shops. 
 8 months ago Report Abuse 
 67% 2 Votes 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; What is the average … &quot;was originally asked on Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (1)
 
 by Xl Gondola Member since: June 29, 2011 Total points: 8,561 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 You&apos;re asking for an out and out guess based on a steady demand, Unless you know how long it takes to prepare each dish, how will you know if you have the capacity to keep up with demand?

For the second part of your question, just get hold of the published company accounts for any mobile kebab or kebab booth business. 
 8 months ago Report Abuse 
 33% 1 Vote 
 
Discover Questions in London 

 British Accent Help?? Does Royal Mail work on Sunday? Bank of England&quot;printing money&quot;? Where can I hire a conference room in London? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Local Businesses 
 United Kingdom 
 Aberdeen Belfast Birmingham Brighton Bristol Cardiff Edinburgh Glasgow Leeds Liverpool London Manchester Newcastle Other - United Kingdom Sheffield Swansea 
 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Asia Pacific Pte Ltd. (Co. Reg. No. 199700735D). All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
