<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002542" url="http://www.furnitureonnet.com/local/all.php?q=mn&amp;page=5" time="2012-07-12-18:36" support="1" score="0.00021634687798483828" bingtitle="New and used furniture for sale by owner (75 furnitures) in MN ..." webtitle="New and used furniture for sale by owner (75 furnitures) in MN - Furnitureonnet.com">
			<query id="000924" bing-rank="220"/>
	<description>formerly from a fast food restaurant chain, it has been stripped ... call me asap on my cell or text: --(please leave a ... characterless log futon frame that sells in stores ...</description>
	<body>
		Blog | Furniture For Sale | Furniture Stores | Local Furniture Sales | Popular items 

 
 Furniture Sales in MN 

 bemidji 

 brainerd 

 duluth, mn 

 mankato, mn 

 minneapolis, mn 

 rochester 

 southwest MN 

 st. cloud, mn 

 st cloud 


 
 
 (75) - Furnitures for sale in MN Beautiful furniture for sale may barter also!! (motley) $1 
 ( ) - I&apos;m posting some log and granite furniture, these are new and ready for a new home. these are very well built and i included pics seperatly but we can work out a package deal also! first: this is a granite topped log end table,tv table or anything e [...]
 brainerd.craigslist.org/fuo/3101880988.html 2012-07-09T21:52:05-05:00 *best built futon frames anywhere* wholesale * (pine city) $299 
 ( ) - Photo&apos;s do not do the beauty and quality of these frames justice. shop and compare no furniture store can offer you a more unique high quality futon frame at my prices. compare my giant log frame at $ to the big log frame that sells in stores fo [...]
 brainerd.craigslist.org/fuo/3093847751.html 2012-06-29T14:05:00-05:00 Why pay more warehouse mattresses/furniture (hwy 10 st cloud) 
 ( ) - Name brand furniture at closeout prices min north of becker, just off hwy at mcdonalds st cloud save hundreds new items arrive daily, lowest prices, best selection open everyday! hwy to east exit st cloud, to stop light at mcdonalds/copper [...]
 brainerd.craigslist.org/fuo/3091549985.html 2012-07-09T07:29:49-05:00 Riverside converting counter height table all real wood&amp;stools (deerwood, mn) $950 
 ( ) - Asking $ . /obo i keep dropping it, its killing me to give this away! i really need to sell this though asap, so please if interested at least call/text me w/ an offer? (paid just for the table&amp;four chairs $ , . a year ago, plus $ for the [...]
 brainerd.craigslist.org/fuo/3081905980.html 2012-06-29T14:16:32-05:00 mattress sets k,q,fxl,txl (emily) $65 
 ( ) - These are hotel beds that were used in a large minnesota resort. they are nothing plush but good servicable box spring and mattress sets. box spring and mattress sets are available in king, $ ,( left) sorry queen sets are gone. we have a couple of [...]
 brainerd.craigslist.org/fud/3080705901.html 2012-06-30T08:48:03-05:00 2 dressers great furniture (cross lake) $200 
 ( ) - great dresses for sale call steve at - - $ or b/o
 brainerd.craigslist.org/fuo/3077368507.html 2012-07-10T14:30:03-05:00 Outdoor storage box (breezy point) $45 
 ( ) - ( ) outdoor storage deck boxes. great condition. stackable. &quot; long, &quot; wide x &quot; deep. great for using down by the dock or beach. perfect for storing fishing rods, life jackets, beach toys, outdoor patio furniture cushions, etc. we paid $ each [...]
 brainerd.craigslist.org/fuo/3068989187.html 2012-06-30T07:38:38-05:00 Primitive antique blue wall shelf-price reduction (pierz) $25 
 ( ) - New, strong, hand built with quality pine wood and bead board backing. finished in antique blue and a natural wax for extra protection. shelf dimensions: width: in, length: . in, depth: . in cash only, if interested please e-mail me with &quot;blue [...]
 brainerd.craigslist.org/fuo/3066010447.html 2012-06-28T20:54:17-05:00 New country style wall shelf-price reduction (pierz) $45 
 ( ) - New country style wall shelf is handcrafted with quality pine wood and a bead board back to last a lifetime. finished in distressed burgundy wine and a natural wax for extra protection. shelf dimensions: length: . in, width: . in, height: . i [...]
 brainerd.craigslist.org/fuo/3066008087.html 2012-06-28T20:54:12-05:00 Whitewash country wall shelves (pierz) $25 
 ( ) - New, strong, hand built country shelves with quality pine wood and bead board backing. whitewash finish with a top clear coat for a lifetime of protection. one shelf is $ or the pair for $ shelf dimensions: length: in, width: . in, depth: [...]
 brainerd.craigslist.org/fuo/3066007090.html 2012-06-28T20:53:58-05:00 
 Previous 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 Next 
 


 Copyright©2010 furnitureonnet.com . All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
