<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002590" url="http://www.dwinsider.com/Disney/disney-world-restaurants.html" time="2012-07-12-18:39" support="25" score="0.06280839469810509" bingtitle="Disney World Restaurants; Restaurants at Disney World" webtitle="Disney World Restaurants; Restaurants at Disney World">
			<query id="000196" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="000851" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000218" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001329" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000946" bing-rank="150"/>
			<query id="000607" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="001363" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000201" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="001012" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000970" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000467" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="000194" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000187" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="001346" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000204" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="001032" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="000876" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="001322" bing-rank="120"/>
			<query id="001008" bing-rank="179"/>
			<query id="000419" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000216" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000953" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000198" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="001010" bing-rank="242"/>
			<query id="000212" bing-rank="228"/>
	<description>Children like this fast food restaurant with ... You receive a ticket when you are seated, which ... For breakfast pick from eggs cooked to order ...</description>
	<body>
		Disney 
 World Restaurants
 


 
My Favorite Restaurants at 
 Disney World



 
 

The table service restaurants that I include in my favorite restaurants at 
 Disney World have really good food with hearty 
 portions. If you eat an average amount of food 
 at a meal, you may find that two adults can 
 split one meal (Disney does not frown on this 
 and will be happy to bring an extra plate), 
 and with the addition of beverage and dessert, 
 both will be quite satisfied. Note that tax 
 and gratuity are additional at table service 
 restaurants. Priority seating is recommended 
 for the table service restaurants.

The counter service restaurants also serve hearty portions and one kid&apos;s meal 
 is adequate for two young children with the 
 addition of an extra beverage. It is permissible 
 for adults to order a kids meal too if they 
 are lighter eaters. Note: to eat at a restaurant 
 in the parks, you must have an admission ticket 
 for the park.

 Magic Kingdom 

 Table 
 Service: Cinderella&apos;s Royal Table at the 
 Castle (call for priority seating early!) Breakfast, 
 lunch, and dinner are served at Cinderella&apos;s 
 Royal Table. Breakfast begins at 8:00 a.m. with 
 hearty servings of scrambled eggs, bacon and 
 sausage, potatoes, pastries, fruit, granola, 
 and beverages. This &quot;Once Upon a Breakfast&quot; Disney Character meal sells out in the first 
 15 minutes it becomes available; see tips for 
 assuring priority 
 seating .

Insider Tip: If you are there for the first 
 seating, you will be in the park before it opens! 
 The &quot;Fairytale Lunch&quot; is 
 served from Noon to 3 p.m. Adults can choose 
 from pasta, grilled salmon, ham&amp;turkey 
 sandwich on focaccia, and prime rib. Kids menu 
 includes pasta, chicken strips, pretzel dogs, 
 and prime rib. Magic Kingdom&apos;s dinner has a choice of several delicious entrees including 
 tuna, beef, lamb, pork tenderloin, and Portabello 
 mushrooms.The kids menu is the same as for lunch. 
 
 For a souvenir purchase the Bibbiddi Bobbiddi 
 Brew frozen smoothie served in the Cinderella 
 collectors mug.

 Counter Service: Cosmic Ray&apos;s Starlight Cafe in Tomorrowland, 
 serving lunch and dinner
Children like this fast food restaurant with 
 kid-friendly foods like cheeseburgers, corn 
 dogs, chicken nuggets, hot dogs, and fries. 
 Adults have tasty rotisserie and barbeque entrees, 
 sandwiches, and salads to choose from. An animated 
 Cosmic Ray sings and plays tunes at the piano. 
 Noisy, but fun. .

 EPCOT 

 Table 
 Service: Marrakesh in Morocco, serving 
 lunch and dinner (priority seating) Morocco 
 serves up some of the most delicious, hearty, 
 and unique foods at Epcot at both their table 
 service and counter service restaurants. Try 
 the traditional kebabs or lemon chicken with 
 garlic, green olives and preserved lemon; Chicken 
 Bastilla (an unusual savory pastry sprinkled 
 with cinnamon and powdered sugar); couscous; 
 or roast lamb.

 Counter Service: The Land&apos;s Sunshine Seasons, serving lunch and 
 dinner. Tasty sandwich choices are the Grinder, 
 Cuban Sandwich, and turkey/cheese on focaccia. 
 Salads, soups, and grilled or rotisserie entrees 
 complete the menu. Children can pick from macaroni 
 and cheese, mini sub sandwich, or chicken leg.

 Hollywood Studios 

 Table 
 Service: Mama Melrose&apos;s, serving lunch 
 and dinner (priority seating) Adults will enjoy 
 the upscale salads and pasta dishes; both kids 
 and adults will savor the focaccia base 
 pizza options (wood-fired flatbreads). Antipasti, 
 salads, soups, and a dessert tray filled with 
 specialties like tartufo and hazelnut cheesecake 
 are outstanding.

 Counter Service: ABC Commissary, serving breakfast, lunch, and 
 dinner. Breakfast is traditional with scrambled 
 eggs, pancakes, and the trimmings, or continental 
 style. For lunch and dinner, fast food entrees 
 are burgers, wraps, fish and chips, and Cuban
sandwiches; kids pick from chicken nuggets, 
 fish and chips, or a noodle stir fry.

 Animal Kingdom 

 Table 
 Service: Rainforest Cafe (priority seating) 
 A breakfast bonanza is served up with Eggs Benedict, 
 French Toast, Mexican-style breakfast pizza, 
 waffles, fruit plates, and sirloin steak with 
 scrambled eggs; or try a breakfast smoothie. 
 For 
 dinner there is a wide assortment of the usual 
 and unusual appetizers, soups and salads, burgers, 
 sandwiches, seafood specialties, pizza, steak, 
 chicken, and pasta. Complete the dining experience 
 with a homemade dessert like Key Lime Pie or 
 Volcano Brownie Cake. Kids too have their choice 
 of everything from pastas and pizza to seafood 
 and hot dogs.

 Counter Service: Flame Tree BBQ has a wonderful selection of BBQ items. My personal favorite is the pork sandwich.

 Resort Restaurants 

 Table Service: Beaches 
 and Cream at Yacht Club Resort serving lunch 
 and dinner. Delicious sandwiches star at this 
 restaurant. Plus this is the place to go for 
 ice cream drinks and desserts.The fun food specialty is 
 the Kitchen Sink—a huge ice cream sundae 
 full of scoops of flavored ice creams and every 
 topping of the house; 3 of us tried to eat a 
 Kitchen Sink and couldn&apos;t!

 Food 
 Court: Pepper Market at Coronado Springs 
 Resort, serving breakfast, lunch, and dinner
You receive a ticket when you are seated, which 
 is stamped with your food selection at each 
 station and later given to the cashier for payment. 
 For breakfast pick from eggs cooked to order, 
 waffles, biscuits and gravy, breakfast meats, 
 hash browns, fruits, cereals, and bakery items. 
 
 For lunch and dinner, visit the Grill Station 
 for ribeye steak, grilled tuna, or rotisserie 
 chicken; the Pizza Kitchen for pizzas and calzones; 
 the Pasta Kitchen for pasta with Alfredo or 
 red sauce; the Soup Kitchen; the Wok Kitchen 
 for stir frys and egg rolls; the Mexican Kitchen 
 for tacos, nachos, fajitas, and quesadillas; 
 and the Deli Station for fresh made sandwiches 
 and salads. The Bakery station serves up cookies, 
 cakes, ice creams, and other taste treats. Kids 
 have their own Kid&apos;s Kitchen menu.   






 
 
 
 
 Choosing 
 Theme Parks   Setting 
 a Budget   When 
 to Go   Tickets   Transportation   Lodging   Attractions   Dining   Sample 
 Itineraries   Trip 
 Planning   Shopping   Find 
 a Disney Store   Pictures   Special 
 Events   Pets   Florida 
 Residents   Phone 
 Numbers   Weather   Personal 
 Favorites   Related 
 Links / Trade Links 

 

 
 



 
 
 
 
 

 

 
 ABOUT 
 US              CONTACT 
 US              PRIVACY 
 POLICY              SUPPORT              DW 
 INSIDER HOME 

Copyright©2010 
 Disney World Restaurants by DW Insider. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
