<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002242" url="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2012/04/11/us-counters-drug-smugglers-in-mexican-newspapers/" time="2012-07-12-18:08" support="2" score="0.0027908456622553635" bingtitle="US counters drug smugglers in Mexican newspapers | Fox News" webtitle="US counters drug smugglers in Mexican newspapers | Fox News">
			<query id="001315" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="000939" bing-rank="217"/>
	<description>... cars across the border, typically to a fast-food restaurant or ... Speculators Are Bidding Up Your Grocery Bill &apos;Mad ... CEO Pay Up 14% In 2011: Labor Union; Philly Fed ...</description>
	<body>
		Fox News Digital Network   Fox News   Fox Business   uReport   Fox News Radio   Fox News Latino   Fox Nation   Fox News Insider 
 Register Login 
 Account 
You&apos;re logged in as Account 

 Edit Profile Logout 
 

 Search Site 
 On Air Now › 

 On Air Personalities › 

   
 
 Home Video Politics U.S. Opinion Entertainment SciTech Health Travel Lifestyle World Sports On Air 
 
 Previous Slide Next Slide 
 
 U.S. HOME Crime Economy Immigration Disasters National Interest Terror Military Religion Education Smarter America 
 
US counters drug smugglers in Mexican newspapers
 


Published April 11, 2012 

 Associated Press 
 
 SAN DIEGO–  The war on drugs is going to the classified sections of Mexican newspapers.

Smugglers have long advertised work as security guards, housecleaners and cashiers, telling applicants they must drive company cars to the United States. They aren&apos;t told the cars are loaded with drugs.

Starting this week, U.S. Immigration and Customs and Enforcement began buying ad space in Tijuana newspapers to warn jobseekers they might be unwitting pawns.

&quot;Why don&apos;t we do the same thing that (cartels are) doing? It&apos;s successful for them. Why wouldn&apos;t it be successful for us?&quot; Lester Hayes, a group supervisor for ICE in San Diego, recalls his agents telling him.

There have been 39 arrests since February 2011 at San Diego&apos;s two border crossings tied to the ads for seemingly legitimate jobs, according to ICE, which hadn&apos;t seen such significant numbers before.

Those arrests have yielded 3,400 pounds of marijuana, 75 pounds of cocaine and 100 pounds of methamphetamine—a tiny fraction of total seizures but enough to convince U.S. authorities that smugglers are increasingly turning to the recruitment technique.

Drug smugglers always look to exploit weak links along the 1,954-mile border, even if the window of opportunity is brief. In the past several years, they have turned to makeshift boats on the Pacific Ocean and ultralight aircraft in the deserts of California and Arizona. In the San Diego area, there has been a spike in teenagers strapping drugs to their bodies to walk across the border from Tijuana.

Some suddenly popular techniques are limited to particular pockets of the border. ICE has not spotted significant spikes in newspaper ads outside of San Diego.

Ads that authorities connect to drug smugglers appear innocuous. They offer work in the United States—an invitation that only people who can cross the border legally need apply—with a phone number and sometimes a location to apply in person.

New hires are told to drive company cars across the border, typically to a fast-food restaurant or shopping center in San Diego, according to ICE. When they arrive, they are often told there will be no work after all that day and must leave the car and walk back to Mexico after being paid a small amount.

The drivers are typically paid $50 to $200 a trip—much less than the $1,500 to $5,000 that seasoned smugglers are typically paid for such trips, Hayes said.

The tactic lowers expenses for drug traffickers and also lures drivers who are less likely to appear nervous when questioned by a border inspector because they are never told they are ferrying drugs, said Millie Jones, an assistant special agent in charge of investigations for ICE in San Diego.

The drugs are stashed in the usual ways. Fifteen pounds of methamphetamine were found in a pickup truck&apos;s phony exhaust pipe in November. More than 250 pounds of marijuana were discovered in a van&apos;s overhead compartment last April.

More than 200 pounds of marijuana were found in vacuum-sealed plastic bags smothered in grease. Drugs are typically mixed with mustard, ketchup and fabric fresheners to defuse odors and ward off dogs used by authorities.

For years, U.S. authorities have bought newspaper space and broadcast airtime south of the border to deter illegal border crossings. The Border Patrol has a long-running media campaign in Mexico and Central America that includes musical &quot;corridos,&quot; short documentaries and public service announcements.

The ICE ads that began appearing Sunday in classified sections of Tijuana&apos;s Frontera and El Mexicano are nothing fancy. Bold black letters say, &quot;Warning! Drug traffickers are announcing jobs for drivers to go to the United States. Don&apos;t fall victim to this trap.&quot;

Mexican newspapers have faced online competitors but the papers&apos; classified sections are relatively robust compared to U.S. publications.

Victor Clark, director of Tijuana&apos;s Binational Center for Human Rights, doubts the ads will work without specific instructions on how to confirm whether a company is legitimate, such as calling an ICE telephone number.

&quot;It&apos;s very difficult for someone who is unemployed to know whether it&apos;s a trap,&quot; Clark said. &quot;I don&apos;t think many people are inclined to investigate if they are desperate for work.&quot;

The cases can be challenging for prosecutors because drivers may not know they are smuggling drugs.

Debra Hartman, a spokeswoman for the U.S. attorney&apos;s office in San Diego, declined to say how many cases have been prosecuted or cite any examples. Rachel Cano, assistant chief of the San Diego County district attorney&apos;s southern branch, said each case is different.

&quot;Just like any other case, a theft case, we look at all of the facts and if there are sufficient facts that meet the elements of a crime and we can prove it beyond a reasonable doubt, then we file charges,&quot; Cano said.

Guadalupe Valencia, a San Diego defense attorney, said the ads by U.S. authorities might inadvertently help defendants. Attorneys will argue it is an acknowledgement that people are often tricked.

&quot;It has always been my opinion that there are many unknowing couriers,&quot; he said. &quot;The challenge for the prosecution is you always have to prove knowledge.&quot;
 
 
 
   Print   Email   Share   Comments Recommend Tweet 
 
Share This Article

 
 
Newsletter Signup
 
Sign up for free e-mail news alerts from FoxNews.com and FoxBusiness.com.
 Newsletter Signup 
 View Article 
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. 
You must login to comment.
 
 View Article 
 
Advertisement
 
Trending in U.S.
 
 
1

 Report by former FBI director finds Penn State concealed child sex abuse 
 Facebook Twitter 
2

 Wis. police: Father suspected of killing 3 daughters told ex-wife he harmed their children 
 Facebook Twitter 
3

 Detective calls on feds to take over &apos;honor killing&apos; investigation 
 Facebook Twitter 
4

 Michigan woman dresses up corpse, watches NASCAR with it 
 Facebook Twitter 
5

 Missing Ohio mom reportedly hesitated before going on North Carolina vacation with boyfriend 
 Facebook Twitter 
 See all trends 
Smarter America
 
 More  › 
 
 
 Angela Hunt wins Eric Breindel Collegiate Journalism Award 
 
 
 NYC adding free Wi-Fi hotspots to payphones Study: Southeast absorbs more carbon than it produces 
 
Advertisement
 
Also on the web
 
 Weekly Jobless Claims Hit Four-Year Low Import Prices Post Biggest Drop Since December &apos;08 U.S. Jobless Claims Fall 26,000 To 350,000 Troika: Ireland Program Implementation &apos;strong&apos; Coming Up: Jobless Claims, U.S. Import Prices 
 
 Monkey Terrorizes Hospital; Official Claims It&apos;s A Hoax UNJUST DESSERTS: Woman Allegedly Attacks Husband With Ice Cream &apos;Buxom Bandit&apos; Turns Herself In Got Big Bucks? Hunters Build Deer Stand &apos;Mansions&quot; Ex-CIA Agent Says Roswell UFO Was Definitely Out Of This World 
 
 Putin Pushes Pragmatic Relations With Raul Castro Marta Montenegro: Beer Boosts Bone Mass UEFA will not use goal-line technology Blatter defends role in payment scandal Rodgers: Anfield challenge is immense 
 
Sections
 
 Home Video Politics U.S. Opinion Entertainment SciTech Health Travel Lifestyle World Sports Weather 
 
Shows
 
 America Live America&apos;s News HQ America&apos;s Newsroom Cavuto Fox News Sunday Fox&amp;Friends First Fox&amp;Friends Fox&amp;Friends Weekend Fox News Watch Fox Report Geraldo at Large Greta Hannity 
 
 
 
 Happening Now Huckabee Justice with Judge Jeanine Red Eye w/ Gutfeld Special Report Specials Studio B The Cost of Freedom The Five The Journal Editorial Report The O&apos; Reilly Factor War Stories 
 
Tools
 
 Trending uReport Newsletters&amp;Alerts Blogs Mobile Podcasts Radio Fox News Store Apps&amp;Downloads 
 
About
 
 Careers Internships - FNCU Fox Around the World Advertise With Us Terms of Use Privacy Policy Ad Choices Contact Us Email Newsroom FAQ Media Relations 
 
Follow
 
   Facebook   Twitter   Google+   LinkedIn   RSS   Newsletters 
 
 
This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.©2012 FOX News Network, LLC. All rights reserved. All market data delayed 20 minutes.
	</body>
</document>
