<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002880" url="http://www.shopping.com/tyj50-8a2/products" time="2012-07-12-18:56" support="11" score="0.010266023888467781" bingtitle="&quot;tyj50 8a2&quot; - Shopping.com" webtitle="tyj50 8a2- Shopping.com">
			<query id="000042" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="001233" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="001391" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="001108" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="001485" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="001243" bing-rank="168"/>
			<query id="001045" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="001265" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="001516" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="000542" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="000605" bing-rank="167"/>
	<description>Whether the operation is checkweighing food portions in a fast-food restaurant ... Space At Top For Invoice Number, Date, In.your Order Number, In. In.our Order Number ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to Shopping.com! Other Shopping.com sites: Close 
 
 
 
 
 
 Shop By Department 
 Clothing 
 Women Men Girls Boys Infants and Toddlers See all... Shop by Brands 
 Shoes 
 Womens Mens Kids See all... Shop by Brands 
 Computers 
 Cartridges and Toners Flash Memory Monitors PC Laptops PDAs Printers Software See all... Shop by Brands 
 Electronics 
 Camcorders Cellular Phones Digital Cameras GPS Devices MP3 Players Flat Panel Televisions Speakers and Subwoofers Buying Guides See all... Shop by Brands 
 At Home 
 Furniture Garden Home Furnishings Kitchen Pet Supplies Building Supplies See all... Shop by Brands 
 Health 
 Cosmetics Fragrances Health Aids Nutrition Personal Care See all... Shop by Brands 
 Kids 
 Baby Care Car Seats Cribs and Bassinets Strollers Toys Video Games See all... Shop by Brands 
 Community Shop by Brands See all 
 
 Sign In   Join   My Lists Search Related: Synchronous motor    less» Shopping 
 tyj50 8a2 
 Showing results for &quot;
tyj50 8a2
&quot; Show on Sale Results 1 - 40 of 1500+ Sponsored Results Back2Natural Brown Dark 8oz - 50% Off $25.00    $11.25 1TE50 Structural Bolt,1-8,5 1/2 L,pk... $63.70 Grainger Microwave Oven Turntable Turn Table... $12.99 -55% 
 Back2Natural Brown Dark 8oz - 50% Off Back2Natural Brown Dark 8oz - 50% Off 
 Orders Over $50 Ship Free! ( In stock ) 
While supplies last! Restores hair to natural color. Plus it is gentle and safe so you can use with complete confidence. Outstanding results when used on faded hair, extensions, hair... More 

While supplies last! Restores hair to natural color. Plus it is gentle and safe so you can use with complete confidence. Outstanding results when used on faded hair, extensions, hair systems and relaxed, processed or damaged hair. Strengthens and improves human hair of any texture or condition. 8oz bottle. Important: Avoid contact with eyelashes, eyebrows, clothing or porous surfaces. Although sensitivity is unlikely a patch test is recommended. Less 
 HairDirect Store not rated See Store Info /back2natural-brown-dark/ycvwktjEjd05LaYgRgik0A==/info $25.00 $11.25 55% Off +$9.00 shipping Visit Store 
 Hook Scale 20 Kg (10 Kg X 50 G) 2 Revolutions 8&quot; Dial Hook Scale 20 Kg (10 Kg X 50 G) 2 Revolutions 8&quot; Dial 
 New ( In stock ) 
Hook Scale 20 Kg (10 Kg X 50 G) 2 Revolutions 8&quot; Dial These rugged hanging dial scales are designed for heavy-duty use and are ideal scales for a variety of uses. The 8&quot; (20cm) dial is... More 

Hook Scale 20 Kg (10 Kg X 50 G) 2 Revolutions 8&quot; Dial These rugged hanging dial scales are designed for heavy-duty use and are ideal scales for a variety of uses. The 8&quot; (20cm) dial is easy-to-read and the dial mechanism is protected by a lens while the plastic housing eliminates dents and scratches, thereby enhancing long-term use and accuracy. The heavy-duty plated 4&quot; (102mm) S-hook suspends commodities while weighing. The MCS-60M model incorporates an adjustable pointer which may be set anywhere on the dial in order to offset additional weight. Both net and gross weights are indicated fast and accurately with knife-blade pointers. 17.00 L. 14.00 W. 7.00 H. Less 
 Global Industrial 8 store reviews See Store Info /hook-scale-20-kg-10-kg-x/XynnlutAVZnJaizh-E1Ucw==/info $174.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store 
 L8T AR12 Battery for Acer BATBL50L6 BATBL50L8 BATCL50L4 BATCL50L6 by Level 8 Technology 
 L8T AR12 Battery for Acer BATBL50L6 BATBL50L8 BATCL50L4 BATCL50L6 by Level 8 Technology Battery, Manufacturer: Acer, PN: AR12, UPC: 815252010253 from $41.82 Free Shipping 2 stores See Details -55% 
 Back2Natural Brown Medium - 50% Off Back2Natural Brown Medium - 50% Off 
 Orders Over $50 Ship Free! ( In stock ) 
While supplies last! Restores hair to natural color. Plus it is gentle and safe so you can use with complete confidence. Outstanding results when used on faded hair, extensions, hair... More 

While supplies last! Restores hair to natural color. Plus it is gentle and safe so you can use with complete confidence. Outstanding results when used on faded hair, extensions, hair systems and relaxed, processed or damaged hair. Strengthens and improves human hair of any texture or condition. Important: Avoid contact with eyelashes, eyebrows, clothing or porous surfaces. Although sensitivity is unlikely a patch test is recommended. Less 
 HairDirect Store not rated See Store Info /back2natural-brown-medium/gfoKnB5mKkwuRoBHjIM5LA==/info $25.00 $11.25 55% Off +$9.00 shipping Visit Store 
 Create-Your-Own 50% Recycled Form, 3-Part, 8 1 - 2in. x 11in., Box Of 250 Create-Your-Own 50% Recycled Form, 3-Part, 8 1 - 2in. x 11in., Box Of 250 
 ( In stock ) 
Create your own forms! Provide black and white, print-ready artwork. Each part is printed with the same information. Please note: we cannot print copyrighted forms. Consecutive numbering... More 

Create your own forms! Provide black and white, print-ready artwork. Each part is printed with the same information. Please note: we cannot print copyrighted forms. Consecutive numbering available for an additional charge. Printed in the upper right corner unless otherwise specified. Please indicate a starting number, up to 7 digits. Add additional delivery day for consecutive numbering. Made from recycled, carbonless paper. Greener choice - contains 50% recycled and 30% postconsumer recycled content. Features a bright white top sheet and clean multi-part color sheets. Taylor Corp. Green Products part of a large selection of office supplies. Create-Your-Own 50% Recycled Form, 3-Part, 8 1 - 2in. x 11in., Box Of 250 is one of many Green Products available through Office Depot. Made by Taylor Corp.. Less 
 Office Depot 137 store reviews See Store Info /createyourown-50/aqD9CEW8EmCjRjP5OQAsTw==/info $129.99 Free Shipping Visit Store -55% 
 Back2Natural Medium Blonde 8oz - 50% Off Back2Natural Medium Blonde 8oz - 50% Off 
 Orders Over $50 Ship Free! ( In stock ) 
While supplies last! Restores hair to natural color. Plus it is gentle and safe so you can use with complete confidence. Outstanding results when used on faded hair, extensions, hair... More 

While supplies last! Restores hair to natural color. Plus it is gentle and safe so you can use with complete confidence. Outstanding results when used on faded hair, extensions, hair systems and relaxed, processed or damaged hair. Strengthens and improves human hair of any texture or condition. Important: Avoid contact with eyelashes, eyebrows, clothing or porous surfaces. Although sensitivity is unlikely a patch test is recommended. Less 
 HairDirect Store not rated See Store Info /back2natural-medium/qq3Soa_jnIOt_DnctT3jYQ==/info $25.00 $11.25 55% Off +$9.00 shipping Visit Store 
 8 Mil ImagePro Satin- 50in x 100ft 8 Mil ImagePro Satin- 50in x 100ft 
 ( In stock ) 
LexJet&apos;s next-generation 8-Mil ImagePro Satin Photo Paper is a cost-effective option for producing high-quality photographic display prints on multiple makes and models of inkjet printers... More 

LexJet&apos;s next-generation 8-Mil ImagePro Satin Photo Paper is a cost-effective option for producing high-quality photographic display prints on multiple makes and models of inkjet printers. The lustrous, instant-dry microporous coating on the latest generation of ImagePro Satin provides an improved white point for greater contrast, outstanding dot control, a wider color gamut and excellent image sharpness.If a laminating film is required for extra protection or rigidity, you can use ImagePro Satin Photo Paper with either a pressure- sensitive film or heat-activated (thermal) film.LexJet ImagePro Satin works well on a wide range of printers, including piezo and thermal printers from Canon, HP, Encad, Epson, Mimaki, and Roland, and is engineered for the latest inksets, including Canon Lucia, Epson UltraChrome K3 HDR and HP Vivera.LexJet 8 Mil ImagePro Satin is a 2011 Hot One Award winner. Less 
 LexJet Store not rated See Store Info /8-mil-imagepro-satin/sX1LBk2aGkrA4VBlbmd3BA==/info $221.00 +$9.99 shipping Visit Store 
 French Paper - CONSTRUCTION - A2 Envelopes - 50 PK French Paper - CONSTRUCTION - A2 Envelopes - 50 PK 
 ( In stock ) 
French Paper - CONSTRUCTION - A2 ENVELOPESby The French Paper Co.Package: 50 ENVELOPES ENVELOPE Size: A2 ENVELOPE (4.375&quot; x 5.75&quot;)Basis Weight: 28/70lb TEXT --Acid free / Chlorine free ... More 

French Paper - CONSTRUCTION - A2 ENVELOPESby The French Paper Co.Package: 50 ENVELOPES ENVELOPE Size: A2 ENVELOPE (4.375&quot; x 5.75&quot;)Basis Weight: 28/70lb TEXT --Acid free / Chlorine free --Laser&amp;Ink Guaranteed for Construction Text Weight (Cover may be limited by its thickness)--All French paper products are made with clean, renewable energy / 100% Green HydropowerNote colors and their recycled content... Virgin Fiber (non-recycled): Pure White FSC Certified (non-recycled): Insulation Pink FSC Certified&amp;30% recycled: Grout Gray, Electric Red, Paver Red, Timber Green, Nightshift Blue 100% recycled/30% post-consumer: Recycled White, Whitewash, Tile Green, Cement Green, Steel Blue, Factory, Green, Fuse Green, Safety Orange, Brick Red, Charcoal Brown, Blacktop The earthy, yet durable shades of Construction paper, made exclusively by French paper mills, is a great addition to those creative projects with a subtle influence of earthy tones. These shades are very different in color, but share a family of undertones which will allow for mixing and matching of various shades.We carry this practical line of paper in various sizes&amp;weights. You can view all Construction products at paper-papers with easy navigation on our site, you can quickly find all the Construction Paper and Envelopes. Construction is made up of 18 color selections (15 colors&amp;3 shades of white). Here at Paper-Papers we stock a high majority of these colors in the paper&amp;various envelope sizes. Less 
 PAPER-PAPERS 1 store review See Store Info /french-paper/BXDCEEH69mrjBG5zKp9SBg==/info $7.57 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di103.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/71/6c/7a/31516c6b3133326a3274515a66414241576477-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=9&amp;d;=160.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 4ipnet EAP110 IP50 2x2 MIMO 802.11n Access Point with 8 ESSIDs, IP50 metal housing 4ipnet EAP110 IP50 2x2 MIMO 802.11n Access Point with 8 ESSIDs, IP50 metal housing 
 Fantastic prices with ease&amp;comfort of Amazon.com! ( In stock ) 
The 2x2 MIMO 802.11n/b/g 4ipnet EAP110 Enterprise Access Point housed in IP50 dust-proof metal case is ideal for high-performance wireless connectivity in enterprise or industrial... More 

The 2x2 MIMO 802.11n/b/g 4ipnet EAP110 Enterprise Access Point housed in IP50 dust-proof metal case is ideal for high-performance wireless connectivity in enterprise or industrial environments. The operation temperature can stand from -22 to 158 °F (-30 ~ 70 °C). The EAP110 leverages the benefits of the IEEE 11n standard - high throughput, greater coverage, and more consistent signal - and supports 802.3af PoE power supply for installation flexibility. Designed for bandwidth-hungry applications such as voice-over-WLAN, video conferencing, and video surveillance, EAP110 packs two detachable antennas for optimal data transmission and field replacement flexibility. EAP110&apos;s built-in Wireless Layer 2 Firewall blocks security breaches at the edge of the network, serving as a firewall between the outside world and the Intranet. With the Layer 2 Firewall, wireless clients are protected from popular security breaches such as ARP spoofing, password sniffing, DHCP spoofing, and other malicious attacks commonly found in public wireless environments. EAP110 supports Tunnel-based AP Management. It can physically be deployed at any location with an IP network. With Tunneled AP Management, wireless clients associated to EAP110 can enjoy the network services provided by the 4ipnet secure WLAN controller with high security level. For more details, please visit the &quot;Indoor Access Point&quot; at 4ipnet official website. Less 
 Amazon Marketplace 230 store reviews See Store Info /4ipnet-eap110-ip50-2x2/qlz1Qlk132j2tQZfABAWdw==/info $160.00 +$6.49 shipping Visit Store http://di1-4.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/11/93/bc/88004995-100x100-0-0_Sharp+Sharp+ANPH50LP2+Replacement+Lamp+Module+2+Fo.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=10&amp;d;=149.88&amp;rt;=mr 
 Sharp ANPH50LP2 Replacement Lamp Module 2 For XGPH50X XGPH50XNL 
 Sharp ANPH50LP2 Replacement Lamp Module 2 For XGPH50X XGPH50XNL MPN: ANPH50LP2, 2000 Hours from $149.88 Free Shipping 7 stores See Details -10% http://di103.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/38/5f/64/4247565a483742646a3644393135792d5a7251-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=11&amp;d;=102.49&amp;rt;=mr 
 Sales Order Books, 2-Part, 5 5 - 8in. x 8 1 - 2in., 50 Sets Per Book, Pack Of 10 Books Sales Order Books, 2-Part, 5 5 - 8in. x 8 1 - 2in., 50 Sets Per Book, Pack Of 10 Books 
 ( In stock ) 
Convenient and easy-to-customize templates Convenient booklet format keeps your copies in sequential order. Carbonless duplicating forms available with 2 parts. Printed in black ink with up... More 

Convenient and easy-to-customize templates Convenient booklet format keeps your copies in sequential order. Carbonless duplicating forms available with 2 parts. Printed in black ink with up to 4 lines of text. Designs and options come only as shown. Add optional stock or custom logo at no charge. Perforated for easy separation. Consecutive numbering is available with up to 6 digits. Indicate a starting number or if no starting number indicated, numbering will begin with 1001. Taylor Corp. Custom Forms part of a large selection of office supplies. Sales Order Books, 2-Part, 5 5 - 8in. x 8 1 - 2in., 50 Sets Per Book, Pack Of 10 Books is one of many Sales Orders&amp;Statements available through Office Depot. Made by Taylor Corp.. Less 
 Office Depot 137 store reviews See Store Info /sales-order-books/8_dBGVZH7Bdj6D915y-ZrQ==/info $114.49 $102.49 10% Off Free Shipping Visit Store http://di104.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/4d/54/2d/31776e4770383838747854786e766162547967-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=12&amp;d;=12.99&amp;rt;=mr 
 Microwave Oven Turntable Turn Table Tyj50-8a7 Synchronous Motor Microwave Oven Turntable Turn Table Tyj50-8a7 Synchronous Motor 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
PART NUMBER: TYJ50-8A7 220/240 VOLT 50 Hz 4 W 4 r/min THE PLASTIC SHAFT IN THE BACK IS HALF MOON SHAPE AND 12mm LONG IT FITS: KENWOOD MW410E, MW430M, MW435E, MW536E, CJ66SS DELONGHI... More 

PART NUMBER: TYJ50-8A7 220/240 VOLT 50 Hz 4 W 4 r/min THE PLASTIC SHAFT IN THE BACK IS HALF MOON SHAPE AND 12mm LONG IT FITS: KENWOOD MW410E, MW430M, MW435E, MW536E, CJ66SS DELONGHI AG820AGH, AC925EQK, AC930AMQ BELLING BELSTW25 PANASONIC NNK652, NNA524, NN-A524MBBPQ, NN-A524MBBTQ, NNA554, NN-A554WBBPQ, NN-A554WBBTQ, NNA5724, NN-A5724MBBPQ, OPN / OEM: MOP0405001S, PANE63265U00XN, PANE63268960JP, F63265U04XN GOODMANS GSS20 RUSSELL HOBBS HOB GJ/AL31 Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /microwave-oven-turntable/MT-1wnGp888txTxnvabTyg==/info $12.99 Free Shipping Visit Store -55% http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/61/73/5f/6875502d654876506b57623437316a694e4151-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=13&amp;d;=11.25&amp;rt;=mr 
 Back2Natural Dark Blonde 8oz - 50% off Back2Natural Dark Blonde 8oz - 50% off 
 Orders Over $50 Ship Free! ( In stock ) 
While supplies last! Restores hair to natural color. Plus it is gentle and safe so you can use with complete confidence. Outstanding results when used on faded hair, extensions, hair... More 

While supplies last! Restores hair to natural color. Plus it is gentle and safe so you can use with complete confidence. Outstanding results when used on faded hair, extensions, hair systems and relaxed, processed or damaged hair. Strengthens and improves human hair of any texture or condition.NO HARMFUL INGREDIENTS  NO AMMONIA  NO DEVELOPER  NO LEAD ACETATE. Extensively tested (with incredible results) on human hair only. Important: Avoid contact with eyelashes, eyebrows, clothing or porous surfaces. Although sensitivity is unlikely a patch test is recommended. Less 
 HairDirect Store not rated See Store Info /back2natural-dark-blonde/as_huP-eHvPkWb471jiNAQ==/info $25.00 $11.25 55% Off +$9.00 shipping Visit Store -55% http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/64/36/46/715a5a5657785f334e74626e67586c4b635067-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=14&amp;d;=11.25&amp;rt;=mr 
 Back2Natural Light Blonde 8oz - 50% Off Back2Natural Light Blonde 8oz - 50% Off 
 Orders Over $50 Ship Free! ( In stock ) 
While supplies last! Restores hair to natural color. Plus it is gentle and safe so you can use with complete confidence. Outstanding results when used on faded hair, extensions, hair... More 

While supplies last! Restores hair to natural color. Plus it is gentle and safe so you can use with complete confidence. Outstanding results when used on faded hair, extensions, hair systems and relaxed, processed or damaged hair. Strengthens and improves human hair of any texture or condition. Important: Avoid contact with eyelashes, eyebrows, clothing or porous surfaces. Although sensitivity is unlikely a patch test is recommended. Less 
 HairDirect Store not rated See Store Info /back2natural-light-blonde/d6FqZZVWx_3NtbngXlKcPg==/info $25.00 $11.25 55% Off +$9.00 shipping Visit Store http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/71/35/4f/526e45576f35355970534957716b7365647851-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=15&amp;d;=69.95&amp;rt;=mr 
 Cohiba Black Robusto 5&quot;1/2 * 50, Box of 8 Cohiba Black Robusto 5&quot;1/2 * 50, Box of 8 
 ( In stock ) 
Cohiba Black is the first line extension of the venerable Cohiba brand in 5 years. This medium bodied Robusto in a glass tube is composed of a variety of tobaccos aged to perfection: a dark... More 

Cohiba Black is the first line extension of the venerable Cohiba brand in 5 years. This medium bodied Robusto in a glass tube is composed of a variety of tobaccos aged to perfection: a dark Connecticut Broadleaf wrapper, a sun-grown Dominican Piloto Cubano binder and exquisitely flavorful Dominican and Mexican filler tobaccos. Meticulously handcrafted in the Dominican Republic, COHIBA Black cigars are adorned with a hearty Connecticut Broadleaf wrapper that is aged on the plant to yield an exceptionally rich, dark and bold leaf. This cigar comes in an eye-catching mahogany box and boasts a characteristic deep color and rich, complex flavor. Less 
 NeptuneCigar. com 45 store reviews See Store Info /cohiba-black-robusto/q5ORnEWo55YpSIWqksedxQ==/info NeptuneCigar. com $69.95 +$8.49 shipping Visit Store http://di103.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/74/6a/55/385a4556586d6851582d4e6b326f7846563341-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=16&amp;d;=24.25&amp;rt;=mr 
 1TYJ2 Rubber,buna-n,1/2 In Thick,4 X 36 In 1TYJ2 1TYJ2 Rubber,buna-n,1/2 In Thick,4 X 36 In 1TYJ2 
 ( In stock ) 
Rubber Strip, Oil Resistant, Commercial Grade, Buna-n/nitrile Rubber, Thickness 1/2 In, Width 4 In, Length 36 In, Black, Smooth Finish, Adhesive Backing Type, Min Temp Rating -30 F, Max... More 

Rubber Strip, Oil Resistant, Commercial Grade, Buna-n/nitrile Rubber, Thickness 1/2 In, Width 4 In, Length 36 In, Black, Smooth Finish, Adhesive Backing Type, Min Temp Rating -30 F, Max Temp 220 F, Durometer 70a, Elongation 200%, Tensile Strength 1000 Psi, Standards Astm D2000 Bf Less 
 Grainger 32 store reviews See Store Info /1tyj2-rubberbunan12/tjU8ZEVXmhQX-Nk2oxFV3A==/info Grainger $24.25 +$10.24 shipping Visit Store http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/6a/4f/6a/5a6451665a4a4534345a4a584f4b2d44474777-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=17&amp;d;=9.95&amp;rt;=mr 
 #3 Mini Envelopes (2 1/8 x 3 5/8) - Natural - 50 PACK #3 Mini Envelopes (2 1/8 x 3 5/8) - Natural - 50 PACK 
 ( In stock ) 
Please note this envelope size is not mailable via USPS. Small in size but big in style, our #3 mini envelope (2-1/8 x 3-5/8) is another multifunctional envelope from our extensive... More 

Please note this envelope size is not mailable via USPS. Small in size but big in style, our #3 mini envelope (2-1/8 x 3-5/8) is another multifunctional envelope from our extensive assortment of fine stationery. Designed like a standard-sized envelope with a pointed flap, this miniature version is ideal for a variety of usages, such as coordinating with your favorite seating or place cards, as well as housing gift-cards on packages or flower arrangements; it may also be used for standard-sized business cards (2 x 3 dimension). Less 
 Envelopes.com Store not rated See Store Info /3-mini-envelopes-2-18/jOjZdQfZJE44ZJXOK-DGGw==/info $9.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store -25% http://di104.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/63/42/47/614544457253626839335166445a2d4f6c3141-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=18&amp;d;=56.24&amp;rt;=mr 
 A50 60 Capsule A50 60 Capsule 
 ( In stock ) 
A50 60 CapsuleFor everyone out there that wonders if insane, out-of-this-world, vascularity, strength, and muscle gains are impossible - its time to wake up and smell A50 For years now,... More 

A50 60 CapsuleFor everyone out there that wonders if insane, out-of-this-world, vascularity, strength, and muscle gains are impossible - its time to wake up and smell A50 For years now, you have been force fed wannabe underground anabolic based formulas that do nothing but fall short of promises and guarantees. Before and after pictures of paid professional bodybuilders who have no freakin clue what they are being paid to endorse. Our competitors are too busy drinking their own kool-aid to be honest with you. Rather than say they cant get it done, they package it up in a pretty little box, throw a hologram on it andSupplement FactsServing Size: 1 CapsuleAmount Per Serving% Daily Value***A50 Proprietary Active60 mgProprietary Co-Active Matrix400 mg***Percent Daily Values are based on a 2,000 calorie dietWarnings: Keep out of reach of children. As with all dietary supplements, consult your healthcare professional before use. See product label for more information. Less 
 VitaminLife 371 store reviews See Store Info /a50-60-capsule/cBGaEDErSbh93QfDZ-Ol1A==/info $74.99 $56.24 25% Off +$5.95 shipping Visit Store http://di103.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/6c/6f/76/53336b70307a777059656747564e774c494351-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=19&amp;d;=105.95&amp;rt;=mr 
 Locking Device Connector, 250v, 50a, 2p3w Locking Device Connector, 250v, 50a, 2p3w 
 New ( In stock ) 
Construction: Terminal Screws: #10-32 BrassCord Grip Assembly: Impact Modified NylonFace Terminal Assembly: Impact Modified NylonCover housing: Super Tough NylonConnector Contacts: High... More 

Construction: Terminal Screws: #10-32 BrassCord Grip Assembly: Impact Modified NylonFace Terminal Assembly: Impact Modified NylonCover housing: Super Tough NylonConnector Contacts: High Performance Copper AlloyTerminal Clamp Nut: Zinc-Plated SteelAssembly Screws: Zinc-Plated SteelTechnical Specs: Dielectric Voltage: Withstands 3500V per UL498Maximum working Voltage: 600V AC or 250V DCCurrent Interupting: Certified for current interrupting at full rated currentTemperatur e rise: Maximum 30 deg C temperature rise at full rated current after 50 cycles of overload at 150% rated current for either AC or DC applications per UL498Terminal Identification: (X, Y Z Brass Hot) (G, Green, Grounding) (W, Silver, Neutral)Cord Accomodation: Round portable service cords in accordance with device ratings as defined in UL Standard 62, CSA C222 No 49Cord Grip Range: 3 Wire: 300&quot;-950&quot; (762-2413), 4 and 5 Wire: 465&quot;-1115&quot; (1181-2921) Flammability: HB or better per UL94 or CSA 222A50A rating: 250VOperating Temperatures: Maximum continuous 60 deg C, minimum -40 deg C without impactStandards: UL Standards: UL Listed to Standard 498 (Attachment Plug and Receptacles)UL Listing File: UL Listed File #E1381- Guide #AXUTFederal Specifications: Federal Specifications WC596 (where applicable) Complies With: Complies with NEMA Standards WD-1, WD-6 and UL 498Overseas Approval: NOM, CECSA Standard: Certified to CSA Standard C222 No42M1984 (General Use Receptacles) and C222 No 1822M1987 (Industrial Locking Type, Special Use Attachment Plugs, Receptacles and Connectors) where applicableCSA Certification File: CSA Certified File #LR16215- Guide #20T2 7.30 L. 3.20 W. 2.60 H. Less 
 Global Industrial 8 store reviews See Store Info /locking-device-connector/lovS3kp0zwpYegGVNwLICQ==/info $105.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/35/37/6a/4d4d4967686b6c4e4571614a50535377617777-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=20&amp;d;=35.89&amp;rt;=mr 
 2 1/2&quot; Width,8&quot; Diameter The Perfect Bow Solid Colors (Textured Poly Satin), 50 Bows/Color/Box 2 1/2&quot; Width,8&quot; Diameter The Perfect Bow Solid Colors (Textured Poly Satin), 50 Bows/Color/Box 
 ( In stock ) 
The Perfect Bow Solid Colors by Berwick comes in 32 lovely colors and is made from textured poly satin. Available in the following sizes: PF2 - 14 loops, 5/8&quot; ribbon width, 2-1/2&quot; diameter... More 

The Perfect Bow Solid Colors by Berwick comes in 32 lovely colors and is made from textured poly satin. Available in the following sizes: PF2 - 14 loops, 5/8&quot; ribbon width, 2-1/2&quot; diameter size, 50 bows/box; PF5 - 18 loops, 7/8&quot; ribbon width, 4&quot; diameter size, 50 bows/box; PF9 - 20 loops, 1-7/16&quot; ribbon width, 5-1/2&quot; diameter size, 50 bows/box; PF40 - 20 loops, 2-1/2&quot; ribbon width, 8&quot; diameter size, 50 bows/box; PF409 - 20 loops, 1-7/16&quot; ribbon width, 8&quot; diameter size, 50 bows/box; and PF100 - 20 loops, 5&quot; ribbon width, 12&quot; diameter size, 24 bows/box. Product Characteristic: Packaging Bow / Fabric Content: 100% Polypropylene Less 
 JKM Ribbon&amp;Trims Wholesale Store not rated See Store Info /2-12-width8-diameter/57jMMIghklNEqaJPSSwaww==/info JKM Ribbon&amp;Trims Wholesale $35.89 Free Shipping Visit Store -44% http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/41/4f/66/444e72524869752d77737a79613548376c7451-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=21&amp;d;=11.02&amp;rt;=mr 
 [pack] Employee Application Form, 8-1/2 X 11, 50/pad, 2/pack [pack] Employee Application Form, 8-1/2 X 11, 50/pad, 2/pack 
 Fast Delivery, 110% Price Match Guarantee ( In stock ) 
Complies with state and federal laws prohibiting discrimination. Employment history, references, education, personal information, physical record and check-offs for special questions. Space... More 

Complies with state and federal laws prohibiting discrimination. Employment history, references, education, personal information, physical record and check-offs for special questions. Space for interviewer&apos;s remarks. Form Size (W x H): 8 1/2 in x 11 in; Number of Columns: N/A; Forms Per Page: 1; Number of Entry Lines: N/A. Less 
 Lions Deal Restaurant Supply Store not rated See Store Info /pack-employee/AOfDNrRHiu-wszya5H7ltQ==/info Lions Deal Restaurant Supply $19.52 $11.02 44% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di106.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/69/62/58/7850553775766639394d636477757935473167-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=22&amp;d;=7.57&amp;rt;=mr 
 French Paper - CONSTRUCTION - WHITEWASH - A2 Envelopes - 50 PK French Paper - CONSTRUCTION - WHITEWASH - A2 Envelopes - 50 PK 
 ( In stock ) 
French Paper - CONSTRUCTION - A2 ENVELOPESby The French Paper Co.Package: 50 ENVELOPES ENVELOPE Size: A2 ENVELOPE (4.375&quot; x 5.75&quot;)Basis Weight: 28/70lb TEXT --Acid free / Chlorine free ... More 

French Paper - CONSTRUCTION - A2 ENVELOPESby The French Paper Co.Package: 50 ENVELOPES ENVELOPE Size: A2 ENVELOPE (4.375&quot; x 5.75&quot;)Basis Weight: 28/70lb TEXT --Acid free / Chlorine free --Laser&amp;Ink Guaranteed for Construction Text Weight (Cover may be limited by its thickness)--All French paper products are made with clean, renewable energy / 100% Green HydropowerNote colors and their recycled content... Virgin Fiber (non-recycled): Pure White FSC Certified (non-recycled): Insulation Pink FSC Certified&amp;30% recycled: Grout Gray, Electric Red, Paver Red, Timber Green, Nightshift Blue 100% recycled/30% post-consumer: Recycled White, Whitewash, Tile Green, Cement Green, Steel Blue, Factory, Green, Fuse Green, Safety Orange, Brick Red, Charcoal Brown, Blacktop The earthy, yet durable shades of Construction paper, made exclusively by French paper mills, is a great addition to those creative projects with a subtle influence of earthy tones. These shades are very different in color, but share a family of undertones which will allow for mixing and matching of various shades.We carry this practical line of paper in various sizes&amp;weights. You can view all Construction products at paper-papers with easy navigation on our site, you can quickly find all the Construction Paper and Envelopes. Construction is made up of 18 color selections (15 colors&amp;3 shades of white). Here at Paper-Papers we stock a high majority of these colors in the paper&amp;various envelope sizes. Less 
 PAPER-PAPERS 1 store review See Store Info /french-paper/ibXxPU7uvf99Mcdwuy5G1g==/info $7.57 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/65/7a/47/634c6856766c325f55427251494a7736656941-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=23&amp;d;=749.99&amp;rt;=mr 
 Marshall MA50C (1x12&quot; 50W 2-Ch Combo) Marshall MA50C (1x12&quot; 50W 2-Ch Combo) 
 1x12&quot;50W 2-Ch Combo ( In stock ) 
This Marshall MA100C 50-watt all-tube combo amplifier is priced to fit your budget, and it&apos;s just the right size for portable gigging! The 2-channel, 1 x 12&quot; MA50C gives you everything from... More 

This Marshall MA100C 50-watt all-tube combo amplifier is priced to fit your budget, and it&apos;s just the right size for portable gigging! The 2-channel, 1 x 12&quot; MA50C gives you everything from sparkling clean tones all the way to molten sustain, and its solo-friendly boost switch and Crunch Balance knob allow you to effectively add another &quot;channel&quot; to your onstage arsenal. You also get onboard reverb, an effects loop, and a 2-button footswitch with the massive- sounding, versatile, and affordable Marshall MA50C!Marshall MA50C 50-watt, 2-channel Tube Combo Amplifier at a Glance:Tweak your favorite tones with two channels (and then some)Add dimension to your soundAuthentic Marshall tube power means authentic Marshall toneTweak your favorite tones with two channels (and then some)The MA50C gives you clean and overdrive channels, each with an independent volume control and a 3-band EQ for serious tone shaping. The overdrive channel is equipped with an additional gain knob, a boost switch, and Crunch Balance knob. The gain knob adds an additional level of gain staging, providing the classic Marshall crunch sound. Engaging the boost switch delivers a mean Marshall grind for effortless soloing or powerful metal riffing. The MA50C&apos;s Crunch Balance knob sets the level difference between the overdrive and boost levels, effectively yielding a three-channel sound. An included footswitch allows switching between the current channel settings.Add dimension to your soundThe Marshall MA50C combo gives you presence and resonance controls in the Master section, for an extra dimension of overall tonal control with a wide range of sound shadings. A select spring reverb is built in; the depth of the reverb effect is also controlled in the Master section. From subtle to outrageous, these functions add a ton of tonal goodness to the MA50C&apos;s already amazing range of sounds!Authentic Marshall tube power means authentic Marshall toneWhen you want tube-flavored, crank-able Marshall, tone, just plug into the MA50C! Its power amp stage features two EL34 pentode tubes; the preamp stage uses three ECC83 (or 12AX7) dual triode tubes. This tried-and-true combination gives you the authentic, heavy Marshall sound you know and love. The rear panel has serial effects loop In and Out jacks plus 8-Ohm and 16-Ohm speaker outputs. The MA50C&apos;s included footswitch also connects via the rear panel.Marshall MA50C 50-watt, 2-channel Tube Combo Amplifier Features:Output: 50 wattsTubes: 3 x ECC83, 2 x EL34Channels: TwoOverdrive boostCrunch Balance control3-band EQ per channelSpring reverbEffects loop2-way footswitchSpeaker s: 1 x 12&quot;25&quot; x 20.07&quot; x 10.63&quot;Weight: 50 lbs.Marshall&apos;s MA50C packs 50 watts of authentic all-tube tone into an affordable and very portable combo! Less 
 Sweetwater 46 store reviews See Store Info /marshall-ma50c-1x12-50w/ezGcLhVvl2_UBrQIJw6eiA==/info $749.99 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/76/52/42/6e596b3730534b793061514c69745263755977-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=24&amp;d;=43.47&amp;rt;=mr 
 Chain Pen: Set of 50 Pens Chain Pen: Set of 50 Pens 
 Same-day shipping before 1:00PM EST on most products. ( In stock ) 
This chain pen is sold as a set of 50 units. The writing instrument includes an adhesive-lined base to easily attach to any flat surface. This chain pain has a 26&quot; steel ball string to... More 

This chain pen is sold as a set of 50 units. The writing instrument includes an adhesive-lined base to easily attach to any flat surface. This chain pain has a 26&quot; steel ball string to prevent theft. The writing utensil is medium point black ink. This bank counter pen, chain pen is the most popular writing instrument used by a variety of businesses. This chain pen, also known as a reception desk pen, has a black finish with a chrome-plated, metal ball chain. The chain ensures the pen stays with its base. A chain pen, like bank pens and security pens, can be used on counters, tabletops and with ballot boxes. This chain pen comes with a flat square base that adheres firmly to any flat surface with the included double-sided adhesive. The chain pen, such as the reception pen or security pen, is inexpensive, making it an ideal purchase for any business. Places like post offices, hotels, banks and retail stores often buy this chain pen for countertop use. Buy an affordable chain pen today for your business! Please Note: When ordering, 1 unit = 50 pens. Dimensions: Base Size: 1-3/8&quot;w x 1-3/8&quot;d Chain Lengtht: 26&quot; Less 
 Displays2go Store not rated See Store Info /chain-pen-set-of-50-pens/vRBnYk70SKy0aQLitRcuYw==/info $43.47 No Shipping Info Visit Store -5% http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/64/57/51/4773586c6a324965456652526b675a51306367-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=25&amp;d;=99.99&amp;rt;=mr 
 Create-Your-Own 50% Recycled Form, 2-Part, 8 1 - 2in. x 11in., Box Of 250 Create-Your-Own 50% Recycled Form, 2-Part, 8 1 - 2in. x 11in., Box Of 250 
 ( In stock ) 
Create your own forms! Provide black and white, print-ready artwork. Each part is printed with the same information. Please note: we cannot print copyrighted forms. Consecutive numbering... More 

Create your own forms! Provide black and white, print-ready artwork. Each part is printed with the same information. Please note: we cannot print copyrighted forms. Consecutive numbering available for an additional charge. Printed in the upper right corner unless otherwise specified. Please indicate a starting number, up to 7 digits. Add additional delivery day for consecutive numbering. Greener choice - contains 50% recycled content with 30% postconsumer recycled content. Taylor Corp. Green Products part of a large selection of office supplies. Create-Your-Own 50% Recycled Form, 2-Part, 8 1 - 2in. x 11in., Box Of 250 is one of many Green Products available through Office Depot. Made by Taylor Corp.. Less 
 Office Depot 137 store reviews See Store Info /createyourown-50/dWQGsXlj2IeEfRRkgZQ0cg==/info $105.15 $99.99 5% Off Free Shipping Visit Store http://di111.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/50/6c/7a/58687a56356f535651344552433736387a3177-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=26&amp;d;=15.99&amp;rt;=mr 
 Microwave Oven Turntable Turn Table Tyj50-8a19 Synchronous Motor Microwave Oven Turntable Turn Table Tyj50-8a19 Synchronous Motor 
 Earn 2% eBay Bucks on qualifying purchases! Backed by eBay Buyer Protection Program. Terms and Conditions apply. ( In stock ) 
WE BOUGHT THESE MOTORS IN A TRUCK-LINE SALVAGE AUCTION. THEY ARE NEW IN ITS ORIGINAL FACTORY CARTON PART NUMBER: TYJ50-8A19 100/120 VOLT 50/60 Hz 4 W 4/4.8 r/min THE PLASTIC SHAFT IN THE... More 

WE BOUGHT THESE MOTORS IN A TRUCK-LINE SALVAGE AUCTION. THEY ARE NEW IN ITS ORIGINAL FACTORY CARTON PART NUMBER: TYJ50-8A19 100/120 VOLT 50/60 Hz 4 W 4/4.8 r/min THE PLASTIC SHAFT IN THE BACK IS HALF MOON SHAPE AND 3/8&quot; LONG IF FOR ANY REASON YOU ARE NOT HAPPY WITH THIS PURCHASE, PLEASE RETURN IT FOR A REFUND Less 
 eBay 1,235 store reviews See Store Info /microwave-oven-turntable/PlzXhzV5oSVQ4ERC768z1w==/info $15.99 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di1-1.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/99/60/07/85499928-100x100-0-0_Raymarine+A50D.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=27&amp;d;=620.84&amp;rt;=mr 
 Raymarine A50D - 5 in. GPS Receiver 
 Raymarine A50D - 5 in. GPS Receiver Marine, Fixed, LCD TFT Display, 1200 Waypoints from $620.84 Free Shipping 6 stores See Details http://di109.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/61/54/4a/6e2d65375f41656c6a6b6557655a7350593077-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=28&amp;d;=107.35&amp;rt;=mr 
 Starrett 50A Trammel Heads With Divider Points And Pencil Socket, 3&quot; And 2-1/2&quot; Point Size Starrett 50A Trammel Heads With Divider Points And Pencil Socket, 3&quot; And 2-1/2&quot; Point Size 
 Get free shipping on orders over $25! ( In stock ) 
The Starrett 50A improved trammel heads with adjustable divider points (2-1/2” and 3” size) and pencil socket measure the distance between any two points that are too far apart to be... More 

The Starrett 50A improved trammel heads with adjustable divider points (2-1/2” and 3” size) and pencil socket measure the distance between any two points that are too far apart to be reached with dividers. The heads are die cast with black wrinkle finish and have hardened, forged steel points, for easily reproducible and accurate transfer of measurements, scribing lines, arcs, and circles, and marking distances between two points. The heads accommodate a beam up to 3/8” (9.5 mm) thick and 3/4” (19 mm) wide. Calipers measure the distance between two opposing sides of an object. They make inside, outside, depth, or step measurements, according to their type. Calipers are commonly used in architecture, metalworking, mechanical engineering, machining, manufacturing, carpentry, and medicine. The simplest calipers have two legs to mark the two points and require a ruler to take the measurement. More complex calipers use two sets of jaws instead of legs and have up to two graduated scales. Vernier, dial, and digital calipers give direct and accurate readings and are functionally identical, having a calibrated scale with a fixed jaw, and another jaw with a movable pointer that slides along the scale. The vernier caliper has a scale sliding parallel to the main scale for an additional, fractional reading to improve measurement precision. The dial caliper has a circular dial with a pointer on a toothed gear rack replacing the second vernier scale. As with the vernier, this second measurement is added to the reading from the main scale to obtain the result. The dial caliper is used also for measuring size differential between two objects. The digital caliper takes the same sort of differential measurements as the dial caliper by zeroing the display at any point along the slide, with an LCD (replacing the dial) that displays a single, easily read value in both English and metric units. Some digital calipers can hold data readings between measurements and send them to data collection devices. The L. S. Starrett Company was founded in 1880, originally manufacturing bench vises, squares, and other tools. They acquired other companies throughout the years, expanding their services into making precision measurement instruments and tools, such as calipers, micrometers, saw blades, and gauges. Starrett is headquartered in Athol, Massachusetts and has manufacturing facilities in Brazil, the United Kingdom, China, and other locations. Less 
 Amazon 1,806 store reviews See Store Info /starrett-50a-trammel/aTJn-e7_AeljkeWeZsPY0w==/info $107.35 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di111.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/79/6c/64/744e37674c4c635378487a336d6969425f7577-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=29&amp;d;=320.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 2 Square 50 Inch Strip Wall Light 2 Square 50 Inch Strip Wall Light 
 ( In stock ) 
The 2 Square 50 Inch Strip Wall Light by Artemide presents a wall mounted luminaire great for direct diffused linear Fluorescent Lighting, particularly suited for bathroom mirror... More 

The 2 Square 50 Inch Strip Wall Light by Artemide presents a wall mounted luminaire great for direct diffused linear Fluorescent Lighting, particularly suited for bathroom mirror applications. The 2 Square 50 Inch Strip Wall Light&apos;s incorporates a diffuser in frosted acrylic with an extruded aluminum body with white powder coat or anodized aluminum finish. The 2 Square Strip Wall Light&apos;s die-cast end caps are available in aluminum or white powder coated finish. Mounts to standard electrical junction box provided with white cover plate, mounts to center of the 2 Square Strip Wall Light. Since 1959 Artemide has offered high quality products with a vast range of options that are perfect for creative and sophisticated commercial and residential applications. Less 
 Lightopia Store not rated See Store Info /2-square-50-inch-strip/yldtN7gLLcSxHz3miiB_uw==/info $320.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di1-2.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/ba/2a/af/99803800-100x100-0-0_Scotsman+Scotsman+CU50PA1A+Undercounter+Ice+Maker+.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=30&amp;d;=1658.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Scotsman CU50PA1A - Undercounter Ice Maker w/ Bin, 65 lb per 24 Hr, 26 lb Storage, Pump Drain 
 Scotsman CU50PA1A - Undercounter Ice Maker w/ Bin, 65 lb per 24 Hr, 26 lb Storage, Pump Drain from $1,658.00 Free Shipping 2 stores See Details http://di1-4.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/ae/04/dc/105573909-100x100-0-0_nortel+networks+bcm50+6+0+bundle+power+cord+includ.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=31&amp;d;=829.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Nortel Networks BCM50 6.0 BUNDLE POWER CORD INCLUDED [ntbu4174] Firewall 
 Nortel Networks BCM50 6.0 BUNDLE POWER CORD INCLUDED [ntbu4174] Firewall from $829.00 Free Shipping 5 stores See Details http://di102.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/62/77/58/354f5053503772574765645738346c46586f51-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=32&amp;d;=9.95&amp;rt;=mr 
 #10 Regular (4 1/8 x 9 1/2) Envelopes - HOT Note - 50 PACK #10 Regular (4 1/8 x 9 1/2) Envelopes - HOT Note - 50 PACK 
 ( In stock ) 
Want to give your customers an easy way to remember the call to action? Tensions HOT Note is a #10 regular business envelope featuring a self-stick note built right into the face of the... More 

Want to give your customers an easy way to remember the call to action? Tensions HOT Note is a #10 regular business envelope featuring a self-stick note built right into the face of the envelope. With the easily removable sticky note, your marketing message will serve as a visual reminder on computer monitors, in daily planners or on a refrigerator! The security and integrity of the envelope structure remains in tact after the Hot Note is peeled off. At a tilted 10-degree angle, the yellow removable note measures 2 1/2 x 3 on a white envelope. The Notes are perforated out of the envelope face and feature repositionable adhesive with release material backing. Less 
 Envelopes.com Store not rated See Store Info /10-regular-4-18-x-9/bwX5OPSP7rWGedW84lFXoQ==/info $9.95 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di108.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/68/52/79/584575512d475752564b6849582d6977755141-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=33&amp;d;=109.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Heatshield Products Inferno Wrap 2&quot; Wide by 50&apos; Long Heatshield Products Inferno Wrap 2&quot; Wide by 50&apos; Long 
 Ships 0-1 Days ( Out of stock ) 
Insulation Type: Insulator keeps heat in uses: Header pipe exhaust wrap Exhaust heat shield wrap Header Wrap Rated To : Tired of your “Brand X” advertised 2000F header wrap becoming brittle... More 

Insulation Type: Insulator keeps heat in uses: Header pipe exhaust wrap Exhaust heat shield wrap Header Wrap Rated To : Tired of your “Brand X” advertised 2000F header wrap becoming brittle and falling apart? Look no further than our Inferno Header Wrap to solve the problem. Unlike fiberglass and basalt exhaust wraps (which should have an advertised operating temperature of 1200F); our Inferno Header Wrap is made from silica filament yarn making this header wrap strong and flexible while operating at its designed operating temperature of 2000F continuous and 3000F intermittent. Inferno Header Wrap will sustain the extreme temperatures that your glowing pipes from turbo down pipe header manifold or racing applications require. Simply put there is not a header or exhaust wrap on the market that will take higher temperatures and last longer. You can actually wrap the header with Inferno Wrap run it heat it up and then unwrap our Inferno Wrap from the header when needed. Fasten header wrap with Thermal-Tie hose clamps or wire. Our header wrap is asbestos free and is made from a base high quality silica yarn. Header heat wrap is also water and fungus resistant it is also noncombustible. Rated for 2000F continuous use 3000F intermittent Reduces under hood temperatures up to 50 percent Increases horsepower Great turbo manifold wrap Header heat wrap rolls are 1/16 inch thick Always wear safety glasses dust mask gloves and long sleeves are recommended when handling this product Proudly made in the USA Less 
 Pure Diesel Power Store not rated See Store Info /heatshield-products/hRyXEuQ-GWRVKhIX-iwuQA==/info $109.00 No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di105.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/36/2d/4b/48364c616330516d7232755773714869364751-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=34&amp;d;=30.09&amp;rt;=mr 
 2 1/2&quot; Width,8&quot; Diameter The Perfect Bow Solid Colors (Textured Poly Satin), 50 Bows/Color/Box 2 1/2&quot; Width,8&quot; Diameter The Perfect Bow Solid Colors (Textured Poly Satin), 50 Bows/Color/Box 
 ( In stock ) 
The Perfect Bow Solid Colors by Berwick comes in 32 lovely colors and is made from textured poly satin. Available in the following sizes: PF2 - 14 loops, 5/8&quot; ribbon width, 2-1/2&quot; diameter... More 

The Perfect Bow Solid Colors by Berwick comes in 32 lovely colors and is made from textured poly satin. Available in the following sizes: PF2 - 14 loops, 5/8&quot; ribbon width, 2-1/2&quot; diameter size, 50 bows/box; PF5 - 18 loops, 7/8&quot; ribbon width, 4&quot; diameter size, 50 bows/box; PF9 - 20 loops, 1-7/16&quot; ribbon width, 5-1/2&quot; diameter size, 50 bows/box; PF40 - 20 loops, 2-1/2&quot; ribbon width, 8&quot; diameter size, 50 bows/box; PF409 - 20 loops, 1-7/16&quot; ribbon width, 8&quot; diameter size, 50 bows/box; and PF100 - 20 loops, 5&quot; ribbon width, 12&quot; diameter size, 24 bows/box. Product Characteristic: Packaging Bow / Fabric Content: 100% Polypropylene Less 
 JKM Ribbon&amp;Trims Wholesale Store not rated See Store Info /2-12-width8-diameter/6-KH6Lac0Qmr2uWsqHi6GQ==/info JKM Ribbon&amp;Trims Wholesale $30.09 Free Shipping Visit Store -12% http://di107.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/31/51/67/6a58344765727149514a2d42756878446e3941-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=35&amp;d;=2849.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 8 x 50 mL Fixed Angle Rotor 8 x 50 mL Fixed Angle Rotor 
 ( Out of stock ) The 75003335 8 x 50 Rotor includes an aerosol-tight lid and holds 50 mL round bottom tubes directly. Adapters are available for 1.5 mL microtubes and all round bottom tubes from 3.5 to 38 mL. McQueen Labs Store not rated See Store Info /8-x-50-ml-fixed-angle/1QgjX4GerqIQJ-BuhxDn9A==/info $3,245.00 $2,849.00 12% Off Free Shipping Visit Store http://di110.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/77/66/56/633055554338475a4b4c796a5731795a454541-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=36&amp;d;=12.19&amp;rt;=mr 
 SNAPSKRU® Anchor + 8 x 1 1/2 Combo Screw (50) SNAPSKRU® Anchor + 8 x 1 1/2 Combo Screw (50) 
 ( In stock ) 
SNAPSKRU® Anchor + 8 x 1 1/2 Combo Screw (50) - SNAPSKRU® anchors lock symmetrically on the wall and the ceiling for truly secure fastening. When activated with a screw, the SNAPSKRU®... More 

SNAPSKRU® Anchor + 8 x 1 1/2 Combo Screw (50) - SNAPSKRU® anchors lock symmetrically on the wall and the ceiling for truly secure fastening. When activated with a screw, the SNAPSKRU® anchor opens with an audible &quot;pop,&quot; locking the anchor on the wall. The drywall gypsum and its paper are kept in compression and thereby immediately reinforced, providing much greater holding power than other self drilling anchors that are just a small screw in a larger screw. Less 
 FMW Fasteners Store not rated See Store Info /snapskru-anchor-8-x-1/wfVc0UUC8GZKLyjW1yZEEA==/info $12.19 +$5.00 shipping Visit Store -42% http://di103.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/56/7a/50/564d4f475645685473594e427131595f624377-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=37&amp;d;=31.99&amp;rt;=mr 
 8 1/2&quot; x 5 1/2&quot;x 3 1/2&quot; White Barn Take Out Box with Handle 50/CS 8 1/2&quot; x 5 1/2&quot;x 3 1/2&quot; White Barn Take Out Box with Handle 50/CS 
 In Stock ( In stock ) 
The barn take out box is a great alternative to foam and plastic take out containers. With its convenient built in handle, the barn take out box makes your prepared meals easy to grab-n-go... More 

The barn take out box is a great alternative to foam and plastic take out containers. With its convenient built in handle, the barn take out box makes your prepared meals easy to grab-n-go. Barn boxes are often used as gift boxes, deli boxes, bakery boxes, and as catered lunch box containers for bus trips, meetings, golf outings and special events. Add combination meals to your take out menu with the barn take out box. Sold 50 per case. Overall Dimensions: Length: 8 1/2&quot; Width: 5 1/2&quot; Height: 3 1/2&quot; 9548 Less 
 The WEBstaurant Store 267 store reviews See Store Info /8-12-x-5-12x-3-12/VzPVMOGVEhTsYNBq1Y_bCw==/info The WEBstaurant Store $55.28 $31.99 42% Off No Shipping Info Visit Store http://di104.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/67/43/4d/5141714a317934417a76376665716255524867-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=38&amp;d;=229.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Extended 2 Year Warranty AIT-2 50/100GB Extended 2 Year Warranty AIT-2 50/100GB 
 ( In stock ) 
Extended 2 Year Warranty for all AIT-2 50/100GB internal and external tape drives. Guaranteed 2 year replacement warranty from date of purchase. Warranty Policy: The warranty starts from... More 

Extended 2 Year Warranty for all AIT-2 50/100GB internal and external tape drives. Guaranteed 2 year replacement warranty from date of purchase. Warranty Policy: The warranty starts from the date of purchase indicated on the invoice and ends 2 years from that day. The warranty covers mechanical failure only. Cosmetic damage does not apply or will be honored. Only 1 replacement or exchange will be allowed under the extended warranty agreement. All warranted products must match the serial number originally ordered. All warranted products must be shipped back and received by YobiTech &apos;before&apos; the last day of the warranty expiration. All replacement products will be shipped out upon receipt of the original product. Yobitech will offer free ground shipping on outgoing replacement parts. Customer is responsible for shipping cost for incoming warranted products Note: Please do not attempt to open or tamper with the original product. YobiTech reserves the right to void any warranty rights if tamper seals or Mfg. labels are been broken or removed. In cases of EOL (end-of-life) products, same item availability may vary due to market conditions. If YobiTech is unable to replace the original part with the same exact part number, YobiTech will contact the customer and offer a substitution product with similar or better specifications. If the customer cannot use the substitution part, YobiTech will offer customer a courtesy refund (less extended warranty fees) on the current cost of the original product. Less 
 Yobitech 50 store reviews See Store Info /extended-2-year-warranty/gCMQAqJ1y4Azv7feqbURHg==/info $229.00 Free Shipping Visit Store http://di110.shoppingshadow.com/images/di/69/35/49/6451526a52615f57374d425841685862476451-100x100-0-0.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=1&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=39&amp;d;=108.25&amp;rt;=mr 
 3TEG2 Rubber,epdm,1/8 In T,36 X 36 In,50a 3TEG2 3TEG2 Rubber,epdm,1/8 In T,36 X 36 In,50a 3TEG2 
 ( In stock ) 
Rubber Sheet, Weather Resistant, Military Specification, Epdm Rubber, Thickness 1/8 In, Width 36 In, Length 36 In, Black, Smooth Finish, Non-adhesive Backing Type, Min. Temp. Rating -55... More 

Rubber Sheet, Weather Resistant, Military Specification, Epdm Rubber, Thickness 1/8 In, Width 36 In, Length 36 In, Black, Smooth Finish, Non-adhesive Backing Type, Min. Temp. Rating -55 Deg. F, Max. Temp. 300 F, Durometer 50a, Elongation 400%, Tensile Strength 1600 Psi, Standards Astm D2000 M4ca510 Less 
 Grainger 32 store reviews See Store Info /3teg2-rubberepdm18-in/i5IdQRjRa_W7MBXAhXbGdQ==/info Grainger $108.25 +$11.28 shipping Visit Store http://di1-3.shoppingshadow.com/images/pi/f8/bb/a9/35307747-100x100-0-0_Ridgid+Ridgid+15682+300+Complete+Threader+38+Rpm.jpg?p=JW2frmjDnP&amp;a;=2&amp;c;=1&amp;l;=3033102&amp;t;=07%2F12%2F12%2012%3A56%3A55%20PM&amp;r;=40&amp;d;=999.0&amp;rt;=mr 
 Ridgid 15682 300 Complete Threader (38 Rpm) 
 Ridgid 15682 300 Complete Threader (38 Rpm) from $999.00 Free Shipping 6 stores See Details 1 2 3 4 5 ... 38 Next  » Why are these stores listed?   
 
Sponsored Listings
 
   
 Tyj50 
 Die günstigsten Preise vergleichen. Bis zu 85% bei Produkten sparen 
 www.delupe.de/Tyj50 
 
   
Related Guides:
 
 TOP 10 8GB MP3 PLAYERS 
 by Staff_Contributor Great music is greatly enhanced with a wonderful player... 0 
Prices are provided by the merchants. We assume no responsibility for accuracy of price information provided by merchants. Please alert us to any pricing discrepancies and we will alert the merchant. Sales taxes are estimated at the zip code level. Shipping costs are estimates. Please check store for exact shipping costs. To learn more about why certain stores are listed on the site, click here 

Product specifications are obtained from third parties, and while we make every effort to assure the accuracy of product information, we do not assume any liability for inaccuracies. Store ratings and product reviews are written and submitted by online shoppers to assist you as you shop. They do not reflect our opinions. We take no responsibility for the content of ratings and reviews submitted by users.
 
Products on Sale
 -55% Back2Natural Brown Dark 8oz - $11.25 $25.00 HairDirect -44% [pack] Employee Application $11.02 $19.52 Lions Deal Restaurant Supply -55% Back2Natural Brown Medium - 50% $11.25 $25.00 HairDirect -25% A50 60 Capsule $56.24 $74.99 VitaminLife 
Guides from our Merchants
 
 Formax Shredder, Cross Cut Vs Strip Cut Shredders 
 When choosing a shredder, the most difficult decisions to... 0 
 
 
About
 Home About Us Jobs Contact Us Privacy User Agreement 
Work with us
 Join our Partner Program Merchant Login Join our Merchant Program Advertise with Us 
Helpful Stuff
 Merchant Directory Brand Directory Site Index Popular Pages Shopping Guides 
eBay Family
 eBay Free Local Classifieds PayPal Apartments for Rent Tickets 
Shopping Sites
   France   Germany   United Kingdom   Australia   USA 
Copyright©2000-2012 Shopping.com
 http://img.shoppingshadow.com/jfe/JavaFrontEnd-fe121.rtb15.dt_seotags-9011 http://img.shopping.com/jfe/JavaFrontEnd-fe121.rtb15.dt_seotags-9011
	</body>
</document>
