<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002557" url="http://freeappalert.com/2011-06-30" time="2012-07-12-18:37" support="5" score="0.015388566186032793" bingtitle="FreeAppAlert - Free iPhone App Specials for 2011-06-30" webtitle="FreeAppAlert - Free iPhone App Specials for 2011-06-30">
			<query id="001095" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="001094" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="001079" bing-rank="191"/>
			<query id="001076" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="001073" bing-rank="215"/>
	<description>Christian Collection $0.99; Escape Artist $0.99; Simone&apos;s Star - Fiaba And Friends - iPhone edition $0.99; Diet Defense $0.99; TwistedPhrase! $0.99; Astroid Dodger $0.99</description>
	<body>
		free app alert 
 Paid iPhone Apps that just became free .
 Get alerts via email or follow @freeappalert become a fan subscribe iPhone iPad 
New Newly free iPhone apps for 2011-06-30 App 
links open in 
iTunes 

 EM Coding Category: Medical Was: $4.99· View Description · Retweet Simplify your process, improve accuracy, and increase your billing. **FREE FOR A LIMITED TIME** See EMCodingApp.com for more about how to improve your billing.

&quot;If your salary is dependent on how well you bill and code, this application is worth tens of thousands of dollars a year to your bottom line.&quot; - From a review of E/M Coding in The Happy Hospitalist - http://bit.ly/aHVOhF



Whether you are learning E/M Coding (Evaluation and Management Coding) for the first time or are looking for a tool to do your billing faster, E/M Coding App can help. It is, quite simply, the clearest and best designed E&amp;M;coding tool available.

If you manage a group of doctors, E/M Coding App is the best way to teach accurate coding and to improve your billing.

&quot;I developed this app to improve my own E/M Coding and to help other doctors learn to code effectively.&quot;
- Dr. Benjamin Wertheimer, MD, creator of the E/M Coding App;
 [close] SOS 4 Life - Health Records Category: Medical Was: $4.99· View Description · Retweet SOS 4 Life – Health Records is your international mobile Health Record that helps you take better care of your own health when travelling, living or working abroad.

SOS 4 Life - Health Records enables you to store your most important medical information, and translate it into the most commonly spoken languages at the touch of a button.

Get SOS 4 Life - Health Records today to help you communicate effectively with healthcare and other professionals abroad and to make sure that you receive the best possible care - anywhere in the world.

Easy access: SOS 4 Life - Health Records stores your most important health related information directly on your mobile phone, reducing your need for paper based records and allowing you fast and convenient access to your crucial health data whenever needed.

One-Touch Translation: SOS 4 Life - Health Records translates your health information into many of the world’s most spoken languages at the touch of a button, more accurately and reliably than a translation machine, and with no need for an internet connection.

Safety and Security: SOS 4 Life - Health Records stores your health information PIN protected directly on your phone - no one has access but yourself. If you want to, create a tailored public profile and your personal wall paper for added speed of access to information in emergency situations.

Features:
• Is an application made by medical doctors for patients and doctors who find themselves in emergency situations anywhere in the world

• Allows you to store your most important medical information on your mobile phone and translate it into the most commonly spoken languages at the touch of a button – simply change the language in any section by clicking on the country flags

• Contains multi-lingual data bases of the most common conditions, allergies and immunizations - easy for you to select and easy for your doctor to understand

• Allows you to select either parts or your entire personal medical record and send it to anyone via email

• Has 1-touch-dialing enabled to call your emergency contacts directly from your application

• Will protect your personal medical information with a PIN and stores all your information only on your personal mobile phone

• Can display selected sections of your personal medical records publicly (i.e. without password protection) for those who might access your phone in an emergency situation

• &apos;Wall paper&apos; option to facilitate access to information in emergency situations

• &apos;Notes&apos; section for storing additional infomation

• Stores crucial medical information

o Emergency contacts
o Personal details including Blood Group, Height etc.
o Insurance details
o Medical conditions including date and current state
o Allergies including typical reactions and severity
o Immunizations including status and dates
o Medications including frequency and dosage

• Translates the entire application and all information into some of the world&apos;s most spoken languages without the need for an internet connection – at a single touch into

o Spanish
o English
o German
o French
o Italian
o Portuguese
o Dutch
o Other (coming soon)

Video: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ScwR7kIz5vk
;
 [close] FengshuiCatcher Category: Utilities Was: $4.99· View Description · Retweet Fengshui is Chinese traditional technique to distinguish the better evironment to live. FengshuiCatcher can help you to decide the direction of the furniture. It also can tell you what is the tool to avoid the bad direction of furniture.;
 [close] القرآن الكريم Free Offer Ended - Now: $4.99 Category: Books Was: $4.99· View Description · Retweet *** اكتشاف أسبوع -- الحرة ***


اكتشاف الكريم في سورة علامتنا التجارية الجديدة قارئ الكتاب الاليكتروني مذهلة! والحد الأقصى من المزايا الموجزة في تطبيق واحد لتعزيز تجربة المستخدم الخاص بك! السمات الرئيسية :
-- الوصول الفوري إلى النسخة العربية ، ونذكر من هذه النقطة قراءة الماضي -- الوصول الفوري الى الترجمة الانكليزية لآية العربية
-- الصوت في تلاوة المكافآت ، وهذا التطبيق توفير ميزات أخرى لا أقترح في التطبيق واحد!
-- حسابات الصلاة باستخدام مدرستين وموقعك
-- على اي فون 3GS لطيفة البوصلة تشير إلى الاتجاه Qilba!;
 [close] iParrot Phrase Spanish-Vietnamese Free Offer Ended - Now: $4.99 Category: Education Was: $4.99· View Description · Retweet Translate Spanish Phrase to Vietnamese
Taking-with Translator for iPhone/iPod Touch

!!! SALE for a LIMITED TIME !!!
!!! Download Now at 60% OFF !!!

iParrot Phrase sets a new standard for instant multi-language translation software. Designed exclusively for the iPhone/iPod Touch, it&apos;s stocked with over 20 kinds of perfectly pronounced oral language for instant use. iParrot Phrase is organized into categories such as: Greetings, Transportation, Shopping, and Asking for helping etc. So it is enough for you to find the sentences you need instantly. Organized for instant access and ease, it is especially useful while traveling abroad. Virtual fluency available in Chinese, English, Japanese, Russian, French, German, Spanish, Italian, Korean, Portuguese, Arabic, Thai and Vietnamese.

- Learn foreign language wherever you go
- Listen and practice pronuncing phrases on the screen
- 400 practical travel phrases at your fingertip
- Perfect for students and business travelers;
 [close] Noble Coran Free Offer Ended - Now: $4.99 Category: Books Was: $4.99· View Description · Retweet Le Coran en version intégrale en Espagnol et en Arabe est disponible dans cette application. Découvrez notre nouvel ebook, avec un confort de lecture inégalé !

Des fonctions exclusives utilisant la localisation de votre téléphone !

Liste des principales fonctions :
- Lecture d’une version Espagnole ou Arabe au choix avec mémorisation du dernier point de lecture
- Accès a une interprétation d’un verset Arabe en Espagnol
- Partagez vos lectures de Versets sur Facebook&amp;Twitter
- Marquez et retrouvez vos versets (marques page textes et Audio !)
- Recitation Audio d’une sourate à la demande

En plus dans cette version retrouvez ce que d’autres applications proposent séparément !
- Le calcul des horaires des prières par rapport a votre position géographique selon deux écoles,
- Sur les iphones 3GS seulement : une magnifique boussole indiquant la direction de la Mecque
;
 [close] Heilige Koran Free Offer Ended - Now: $4.99 Category: Books Was: $4.99· View Description · Retweet Le Coran en version intégrale en Allemand et en Arabe est disponible dans cette application. Découvrez notre nouvel ebook, avec un confort de lecture inégalé !

Des fonctions exclusives utilisant la localisation de votre téléphone !

Liste des principales fonctions :
- Lecture d’une version Allemand ou Arabe au choix avec mémorisation du dernier point de lecture
- Accès a une interprétation d’un verset Arabe en Allemand
- Partagez vos lectures de Versets sur Facebook&amp;Twitter
- Marquez et retrouvez vos versets (marques page textes et Audio !)
- Recitation Audio d’une sourate à la demande

En plus dans cette version retrouvez ce que d’autres applications proposent séparément !
- Le calcul des horaires des prières par rapport a votre position géographique selon deux écoles,
- Sur les iphones 3GS seulement : une magnifique boussole indiquant la direction de la Mecque
;
 [close] Holy Quran Free Offer Ended - Now: $4.99 Category: Books Was: $4.99· View Description · Retweet **** Week of Discovery - Free ****

Discover The Holy Coran in our brand new amazing ebook reader !

A maximum of features condensed in one application to enhance your user experience !

Main features :
-Seemless access to Arabic or English version, recall of the last reading point
-Direct access to the English translation of an Arabic verse
-Audio recitation

In bonuses, this application provide additionnals features that other do not propose in a single app !
-prayer calculations using two schools and your location
-on the iphone 3GS a nice compass indicating the Qilba direction !;
 [close] Keno Trek Category: Games &gt; Action Was: $3.99· View Description · Retweet Keno Trek is Keno + 5 exciting bonuses + a great science-fiction theme!

Boldly go where no game has gone before! Choose your favorite numbers, then your bet, and press &quot;Engage.&quot; You can play at speeds between Warp 1 through 5.

You can win up to 50 free games with a multiplier, get up to 20 extra &quot;balls,&quot; pick a planet to get a prize, and race to tap the different &quot;Keno Trek Enterprise&quot; to receive the maximum bonus.

Keno Trek provides hours of fun. If you like other casino games like poker, texas hold &apos;em, slot machines, roulette, or black jack, then you&apos;ll want to add this exciting Keno game to your collection!

LEGAL NOTE: Keno Trek is not affiliated or endorsed by the Star Trek franchise, or Paramount Studios. Celebrity voices impersonated. No copyrighted images or sounds were used in the making of Keno Trek.

More Bimza Games Keno Apps:
Keno Gold - #1 Keno Game on the App Store!
Keno Fairy - Earn 12 Free Bonus Games!


More Bimza Games:
Booger Tap
Blame
Tap 2K;
 [close] Wild West Subtraction Math Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Education Was: $2.99· View Description · Retweet * * * 100% OFF FREE 4th of July Sale * * *

High speed, addictive math game, with 10 action packed levels.
&quot;Math doesn&apos;t have to be boring&quot;

Each level brings more challenging subtraction problems and more gold coins for the math wiz. But be careful each math problem is timed, and the faster you answer the more gold you get. Answer a number of questions in a row, get more bonus coins. Need more time, buy time for coins.

10 total levels of math fun
- Earn or lose coins based on your answers
- Bonus coins based on achievement
- Write on the screen to help you answer the hard questions
- Buy more time with the coins your earn
- Each level adds more digits and more complex numbers

Every time you play, the game has different questions. The questions increase in difficulty as you practice subtraction. Each level brings you closer to being a math master.

Awesome reward system
- Your earn gold coins based on how fast you answer
- Achievement bonus for the number of correct answers
- Gold stars are added for each correct answer
- Each level has up to 5 gold stars (100% 5 stars)
- Use your rewards to pause the game while answering the question

Educational tool for your future math wiz
- Reward system keeps them interested
- High speed game helps teach kids to instantly know the answer.
- Write on the screen helps the kids visualize the answer and answer the harder problems

Soon your kids will be telling you how many stars, and gold coins they have.;
 [close] Flashpoint News - World Pulse Pocket Edition Category: Education Was: $2.99· View Description · Retweet Flashpoint News - News Travels Fast.

Flashpoint News is a new high-tech way of viewing global news. As it happens where it happens. With Flashpoint you always have your finger on the pulse of the globe.

Based on aggregating news from RSS feeds that you can input yourself, Flashpoint lets you view hotspots of global news from the last 24 hours. As news erupts anywhere in the world, you&apos;ll see it happen on Flashpoint.

Highly customizable, you can make Flashpoint your own unique news browser, tailored to your own news tastes.

Download Flashpoint News now and get a grip on global news.

We will update Flashpoint regularly based on feedback from our customers, so don&apos;t hesitate to let us know if there are any features you want added.;
 [close] Why the Platypus Doesn&apos;t Sing Category: Books Was: $2.99· View Description · Retweet &quot;Believe in yourself&quot; is the message in the new children&apos;s story, &quot;Why the Platypus Doesn&apos;t Sing.&quot; This brilliantly illustrated story centers on the Platypus who lives in the pond with Monkey Monkey, Coco Koala and Lucky Ducky. You child will learn to believe in his or her own talents and abilities. Written and illustrated by multi-award winning writer Mark Rocchio.;
 [close] Guitar Kit Free Offer Ended - Now: $3.99 Category: Music Was: $2.99· View Description · Retweet Guitar Kit is super convenient tool for searching guitar chord forms.
You can search almost fingering form and display it. Guitar Kit has enough huge preset library.
And you can create your original fingering forms.

Guitar Kit has very large preset library, but you can view a target chord form so easily!
You can directly select a chord form by smooth scrolling wheel or focus on a little chord forms by typing a part of chord name. You can search by some Enharmonic Equivalents.

If you tap the guitar picture, play each note. And if you select a chord in the list or wheel, play chord any times.

By using Make tab, you can create your original chord forms.
And you can handle those as like preset library completely.

And Favorites Tab allow to memory your favorite chord forms.;
 [close] WoMenTaiWanZheXieNian-S Free Offer Ended - Now: $19.99 Category: Books Was: $19.99· View Description · Retweet A popular modern novel about TaiWan. This edition is in Simplified Chinese.;
 [close] WoMenTaiWanZheXieNian-T Free Offer Ended - Now: $19.99 Category: Books Was: $19.99· View Description · Retweet A popular modern novel about TaiWan. This edition is in Traditional Chinese.;
 [close] iFood Sydney Free Offer Ended - Now: $2.99 Category: Navigation Was: $1.99· View Description · Retweet This application allows you to easily find restaurants closest to you or in a particular suburb. There are hundreds of fast food restaurant listings which can be viewed in a list or on a map, and are easily searched upon and sorted.iFood Sydney will grab your current location and show you the fast food restaurants which around you. It will show you the details of the restaurants plus the distance and the directions! how cool is that? We have added all popular fast food names including McDonald, KFC, Hungry Jack and Nandos ! Do you think there are some other good fast food restaurants we should add? No problem. Just drop us a line from support page and we will add your favourite restaurant in our next version.

Features:
Location aware, with the distance from your current location being displayed.
Get directions to the restaurant from your current location
Search by name or address.
Sort by name, suburb or distance.
View the restaurant direction on a map.
View the restaurant locations on a map.;
 [close] Animals English Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Games &gt; Educational Was: $1.99· View Description · Retweet Apprenez des dizaines mots en anglais, familiarisez vos enfants à l&apos;anglais tout en les amusant avec ce superbe jeu de mémoire sur le thème des animaux.;
 [close] A.B.C English Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Games &gt; Kids Was: $1.99· View Description · Retweet Learn english letters while playing a wonderful memory game with Capsule the rabbit.
Try to be fast, you&apos;ll have a time bonus. Try to turn the card only once or they might move at level 3...;
 [close] عناية وحماية الجلد من اشعة الشمس Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Medical Was: $1.99· View Description · Retweet هل تضطر ان تتعرض للشمس لعدة ساعات وتحتار في الحمايه اللازمه من حروق الشمس! ام هل تصطحب اطفالك الى الشاطئ ليلهوا ويلعبوا وتريد دهن اجسامهم باللوشن لحمايتهم ولكنك لست متأكد من رقم الاس بي اف!
******************************************************************
يوفر هذا البرنامج المعلومات اللازمه علميا لمعرفة نوع جلدك (او جلد اطفالك) ومدى حساسيته للتعرض للشمس الحارقه
فالبرنامج يطرح استفسارات معينه لقياس ومعرفة نوع الجلد لكي يوافيك بنوع جلدك من بين ستة انواع ومن ثم يوضح لك ما سيحصل للجلد اذا تعرض لاشعة الشمس ويقترح عليك نوع الحمايه التي يجب ان تدهن جسمك ووجهك بها (نوع اللوشن) اي درجة الاس بي اف وهي مقدار الحمايه ومدى منع اشعة الشمس من التغلغل الضار الى خلايا جلدك وهي ما يكتب على انواع الزيوت واللوشن المباعه في الاسواق;
 [close] Woodwork Korea Category: Education Was: $1.99· View Description · Retweet This is focused on traditional woodwork and furniture of Korea(Orientalism) and introduced especially as below.
1. The traditional Korean furniture (made from one of Korea official craftsmasters) are presented by photos and briefs.
2. The woodwork joint techniques(on the basis of Korean traditional method) are displayed as woodblock jointing model
3. The woodworking tools(Oriental and Korean style) appear from view
4. You can search for production site and get in touch with it for the detail and study as Location map Service.;
 [close] PikFliks Category: Photography Was: $1.99· View Description · Retweet Make your photos literally “come alive” by turning them into movies. Then share them on Facebook or email using the &apos;synch&apos; button.

PikFliks can take photos as a stand-alone time-lapse camera to record the big moments and events in your life, make stop-motion animations, or construct beautiful time-lapse video. Set your time interval and walk away - Pikfliks will take the photos for you. When you’re done you can review and edit the sequence, scale, orientation of the pictures that have been taken, and then play as a movie.

In Manual mode, Pikfliks puts the control in your hands – it will give you an alarm to prompt you when you should take the next picture in the sequence. You can even overlay the previous shot to line up the next shot using the optional “onion skin” transparency function. And if the shot is not quite right, you can edit to rotate, shift or re-scale pictures against the “onion skin” to get the right image before saving.

When you’ve finished taking pictures, PikFliks will convert the images into a movie that can be played at varying speeds, and with a range of slideshow effects.

Select the &apos;synch&apos; button to create the movie, connect to itunes it can be saved to itunes on your computer.

Some ideas of what you can do with PikFliks:

1. IT’S A TIME MACHINE
Prop it up, choose a time interval and walk away – PikFliks compresses time and makes it EASY to convert to video and share. Watch flowers bloom…watch the sun set…watch your new house be constructed in seconds…watch your child grow up in minutes!

2. PRESERVE YOUR BIG MOMENTS
Record parties, weddings and other key events on “auto”, in compressed time to capture the entire “mood” of the event. Rather than a single snapshot, Pikfliks will sit in the corner and snap the entire event!

3. VIDEO DIARY
Preserve your day! Pikfliks will capture your day into a minute to use as video diary and share with friends on Facebook.

4. ANIMATE
Make stop-motion animations - bring drawings and toys to life!

PikFliks Key Features:
-Allows a wide variation in time-lapse intervals – from seconds to weeks
-Automatic, time-interval based manual and “full manual” (untimed) modes
-Use “onion skin” transparencies to line up pictures against others in the sequence
-Edit individual images with multi-touch finger gestures to line up/ rotate/ re-scale and match to the rest of the sequence
-Can use either front and rear facing cameras
-Auto flash setting
-Play back at a variety of speeds (from slide-show speeds to normal video playback pace), with a number of transition effects to duplicate the “flick book” feel
-Overview pane allows users to edit/ delete and move images in the sequence
-Easy sharing via email and Facebook

Information:
For more information, instructional videos and some great examples of uses, please visit pikfliks.com. You can also share videos and keep up to date with PikFliks development at pikfliks.com.

Help us to improve Pikfliks:
We value your input and feedback to enhance and develop the PikFliks app into the future, so please visit us at pikfliks.com and let us know your thoughts and recommendations.;
 [close] Sky Prayers Free Offer Ended - Now: $1.99 Category: Travel Was: $1.99· View Description · Retweet * Now Free for limited time.

Have you ever been in an overseas flight wondering about Muslim prayer time and Qibla direction and don&apos;t know what to do?

There is an app for that!

Sky Prayers is a unique app that will make finding prayer times and Qibla direction in the air plane a trouble less experience.

How it Works?
The app comes with an offline map where you can choose your location (you can know your location based on plane entertainment screen information). After you pick your location, the shortest path to Makka will be drawn from the plane location which shows the Qibla direction. After that you can see the prayer time at that location as well.

Features:
- Offline Maps with 5 level zoom.
- The most accurate Prayer times by moonsighting.com based on map location and device time zone.
- Different prayer time calculation methods.
- Draw Qibla direction on the map.

This app is a must for every Muslim travailing overseas.

بمناسبة نجاح التطبيق في تغطية تكاليف النشر لمدة سنة وموسم الإجازات نعلن ان التطبيق سيكون مجاني لمدة شهر ابتداءً من 29/6 حصريا في المتجر السعودي

مما فيل في البرنامج:
&quot;برنامج Sky Prayers يعمل كما هو مسوق له في وصف البرنامج وقمت بتجربة البرنامج في رحلة بالطائرة وعمل بشكل ممتاز جداً بوضع الـ Offline مع الخرائط،&quot;
موقع عالم أبل

&quot;الآن تحققت أمنية كل مسافر مسلم باستخدام هذا البرنامج الذي يعتبر خير معين للمسلم في سفره على طاعة الله والالتزام بمواعيد صلواته من خلال إرشاده إلى اتجاه القبلة ومواعيد الصلوات بطريقة مبتكرة.&quot;
موقع أخبار التطبيقات

تم عرض التطبيق في برنامج حياة تك المتميز على قناة المجد
http://youtu.be/QA9gi1UD3HQ

هل سافرت يوما بالطائرة عبر المحيطات ووجدت صعوبة في تحديد اوقات الصلاة واتجاه القبلة ؟
الآن امنية كل مسافر مسلم أصبحت حقيقة مع هذا البرنامج!
هذا البرنامج هو خير معين للمسلم في سفره على طاعة الله والمحافظة على صلواته بإرشاده إلى اتجاه القبلة واوقات الصلاة بطريقة فريدة ومبتكرة.

طريقة عمل البرنامج:
البرنامج يوفر لك خارطة العالم دون الحاجة للاتصال بالانترنت. كل ماعليك الرجوع لشاشة التسلية في الطائرة لتحديد مكانك على الخارطة ثم تحديده في خارطة البرنامج. سيقوم البرنامج بشكل تلقائي برسم الطريق الأقصر لمكة المكرمة وسيكون هو دليلك لاتجاه القبلة. البرنامج يحوي ايقونة بشكل طائرة يمكن تحريكها لتحديد مكانك على الخارطة ويمكن لفها في كافة الاتجاهات لتسهيل تحديد اتجاه القبلة بالنسبة للطائرة. بعد ذلك يمكنك الضغط على الزر الظاهر فوق الطائرة لعرض اوقات الصلاة.

مميزات البرنامج:
- خريطة دون للاتصال بالانترنت مع خمس مستويات تكبير
- أدق طريقة لحساب وقت الصلاة عن طريق موقع moonsighting.com حسب المكان في الخريطة بناءً على ساعة الجهاز
- تحديد اتجاه القبلة على الخريطة
- طرق متعددة لحساب اوقات الصلاة متوافقة مع جميع المذاهب الاسلامية;
 [close] Size conversion Free Offer Ended - Now: $1.99 Category: Utilities Was: $1.99· View Description · Retweet ★★★★★&quot;Size conversion&quot; is used to convert clothing,shoe and Ring sizes from all around the world.

This little useful Application can convert Men and Women clothing measurements to and from US, UK and Continental sizes, and shoe sizes from the US, UK, Canada, Mexico, Korea, Japan and several other countries !
Clothing categories include Sweaters, blouses, coats, dresses, suits,bra and many more...;
 [close] Chatisfaction Free Offer Ended - Now: $2.99 Category: Social Networking Was: $1.99· View Description · Retweet --- Free until July 1st to celebrate our Mac app store version ---
*** NEW VERSION IS HERE!!! ***
*** THIS VERSION REQUIRES iOS 4.1 Update! ***
Now supports iPhone 4 as well as NEWEST iPod and iPad with FaceTime Chat (yes, chat with iPod, iPad 2 and iPhones together!!)

Statuses are now enabled - choose from a list of topics so people know what you want to talk about

Abuse protection enabled - if someone tries to chat with you in a way you do not want to chat, report them and they are removed from the Chatisfaction Network.

*** INTERNATIONAL SUPPORT IS NOW ENABLED! AFTER ENTERING YOUR NON-US NUMBER FOLLOW THE INSTRUCTIONS ON THE SCREEN ***

Chatisfaction is committed to a safe video chat environment!
http://www.chatisfaction.com/openletter/

So you have your brand new iPhone 4 and want to try out FaceTime but you do not know anyone else who has it?

Chatisfaction® allows you to chat with other people with like interests. Whether you are looking to try out FaceTime or want to chat with people in your local area, Chatisfaction® puts you in touch.

After signing in to Chatisfaction® you will see a list of everyone who wants to video chat with FaceTime. Simply select their status and your iPhone will initiate a call to them. Press the FaceTime button and voila! You are using FaceTime!

Please note that Chatisfaction® will require one SMS message to your phone to verify that you own it.

If you are using an iPod or iPad 2 touch a verification email will be sent.

No matter what you are looking for, Chatisfaction® has it. If you are looking for a chat with someone in your local area, someone with similiar interests, or just testing out your new video enabled iPhone, iPod or iPad, Chatisfaction® provides the gateway for you.

Chatisfaction® is a registered trademark of Dirty Bird Interactive Inc.

Dirty Bird® is a registered trademark of Dirty Bird Interactive Inc.;
 [close] ArtCamera Category: Utilities Was: $1.99· View Description · Retweet Free for 1 day only!
Beautiful Art Filters to spruce up your photos!

With 33 different filters, ArtCamera brings the art and talent of Andy Warhol, Pablo Picasso, Claude Monet to your iPhone/iPod touch photos.

ArtCamera features:
* 33 different artistic filters, including art paint, false mirror, old photo, pencil paint and many others
* Attractive animated user interface
* Take a picture or load one from your camera roll
* High resolution support
* Mix multiple filters on one image
* Copy image to the clipboard for future use
* E-Mail your images directly from app
* Upload your images to Facebook and Twitter

***********************
For 1 day only you get ArtCamera absolutely FREE;
 [close] MyNewHabit Category: Utilities Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Have You tried to break bad habits without success? have you tried going to the gym every day and you left a few days? have tried to lose weight without success?

This app is a simple and elegant way to keep track of your new habit. Share your intentions with others through twitter and facebook. with the help of others will get it. also receive points for each day you get your order q. can compete with your friends who gets more points.

here&apos;s a few tips to achieve your goals.

1.Icon
Put the icon in a place you always see, the dock is a perfect place. This help you to reminder your task each time you open your device.

2.Share
Connect your Twitter and Facebook account. Share with friends is a motivation. You do not want to disappoint them.

3.Start
Start with simple things. if it is hard you don&apos;t want do it.

4.Good Feelings
Do things that make you feel better. eat Healthy , more exercise, read more, quit smoke, break bad habits. That&apos;ll help you to want to do it.

5.Repeat
This is the key, repeat each day the same action for 14 days and this action will be a habit. You&apos;ll do this without thinking about, like an habit. If this is not enough time, do it again for 14 more days.;
 [close] iSTAR Drummer Free Offer Ended - Now: $1.99 Category: Games &gt; Music Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet TOP 1 in 3 countries.
iSTAR Drummer is an iPod music game which can actually produce the drumbeat. We have tried to maintain the experience effect of drum set performance. Now the special offer is USD2.99 available for Version 1.22.

The game has 10 pieces of built-in free music, varied in style. Meanwhile, we have matched each piece of music with corresponding real drum set sound effect. The drumbeat setting of each piece of music reproduces 90% of the original beating drum notes in the recording studio, so if you beat correctly in iSTAR Drummer, then you are most close to the real correct beat. The difficulty of the music includes simple, common and iSTAR.

STAR ROAD simulates the process, in which, a drummer, from an unknown band which is going to break up, grows into a star by participating in global talent shows.

In later versions, we will increase more interesting functions. We are also building our music store, which then will offer more interesting and diversified music. This is a BIG, and we hope you will like it.

Twitter:http://twitter.com/iSTAR_Drummer;
 [close] Cuvinte Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Games &gt; Word Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Cuvinte - este un joc cu ajutorul caruia poti sa-ti testezi vocabularul. Scopul acestui joc este, sa compui cuvinte adaugind o litera si folosindu-te de cele deja existente in joc.;
 [close] forest_memory Category: Games &gt; Board Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Forest Memory is a new kind of memory game that will give you hours of fun.

The goal of the game is to match the pictures on the cards.
There are different levels of difficulty so all ages can play from children to adults;
it’s a great way to improve your memory.

There is a choice of 1 – 4 players so you can play your friends and family as well!

While there are a variety of pictures on the cards in Forest Memory you can also use your own pictures from your photo library.

Play Forest Memory to pass the time on the subway, play it with your kids or anywhere you like.;
 [close] Shakeme Clear - 걸어가면서 흔들어 전화걸자! (Shake a call in walking!!) Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Utilities Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet 이제, 걸어가면서 흔들어 전화걸자! (Now, Let&apos;s shake a call in walking!!)
- 이동중 전화를 걸어야 하는데, 한손 밖에 사용 못하는 경우
- 날씨는 추운데, 장갑은 벗기 싫고 전화는 걸어야 하는 경우
- 애인에게, 가족에게 전화를 자주 거는 경우
- 앞을 보며 걸어가야 하는 상황에 전화를 거는 경우

이 앱을 다운 받아 전화번호를 등록후, 이제 재밌게~!!!
흔들어서 전화를 걸어보세요.

어플 실행하면, 바로 등록된 사람의 목록이 차례로 나타나며, 목록 넘김은 아이폰을 세우시면 차례로 넘어갑니다. 그리고 원하는 사람이 나타났을 때 Shake!! 흔드시면 그 사람에게 전화가 걸립니다.

- 흔들기 강도, 리스트 넘어가는 속도등을 조절하실 수 있습니다.
=====================================
Now, Let&apos;s shake a call in walking!

- When you only can use one hand to make a call among the movement somewhere.
- When it&apos;s very cold day and you must take off your gloves to make a call.
- When you often and often call to lover or your family.
- When you go on a street, you want to see the street selecting a phone number.

You must download this app and enjoy it.
You can make a call by shaking your phone.

When you launch this app, the person list is disappear.
You hold the phone in a vertical position to scroll down through the list in order.
If you find the person you wish to call, you slowly move the phone to a horizontal position and shake it.
Then, you will make a call to the person.

You can set up shake sensitivity and scrolling through speed at the setting.
=====================================
2011. nzin.net
관련 문의(contact me) : nzin@ssu.ac.kr / lomoon4@nate.com;
 [close] ポケナビ Category: Utilities Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet 「トレースナビ」は農産物の生産履歴の管理を簡単に行えるアプリケーションです。

■主な機能
【作業履歴】
・生産者ごとの栽培履歴(管理作業、施肥作業、防除作業)の登録、参照を行うことができます。
・栽培履歴の登録時に基準判定処理を行い、判定結果を確認できます。
・作業日ごとのコメントや写真を登録することができます。
【農薬検索】
・栽培品目ごとに、病害虫・雑草による農薬の絞り込み検索できます。
・農薬のラベル情報を表示し、確認してから農作業を行うことができます。
【栽培暦】
・栽培品目ごとに、作業時期と作業内容や関連する病害虫・雑草名を表示し確認することができます。;
 [close] Rotate Monster Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Games &gt; Family Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Rotate Monster is an addictive rotate game.

With about ninety levels to beat, the game gradually progresses in its difficulty.
Your task is to guide the blue boy box into a hole by tapping two buttons(clockwise or anticlockwise).
Along the way you will meet evil boxes to eat you, locked boxes to block you, whirlpool boxes to impede you, and the protagonist will appear alone, with one or two girl box or other fellows, you just can&apos;t tell what will happen next.
It&apos;s really a perfect time killer(I have spent hours on it to beat thirty levels or so), and full of innovative challenges.
If you are a picky puzzle fan, you will only find it a little hard control.
And again, if you are a puzzle game fan, it should be regrettable to miss this! Worth every penny!
Rotate monster has 112 challenging levels.

Ok! Start the game! Good luck!


- v1.0 : Rotate Monster has 112 challenging levels


Twitter: (http://twitter.com/#!/Jinean_Li)
Facebook:( http://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=1829416509)
Weibo:(http://weibo.com/jinean)
youtube:(http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fRNQeQB4Jls)
Video:(http://v.youku.com/v_show/id_XMjc2NDIzMjMy.html);
 [close] rotate star Category: Games &gt; Trivia Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Drag the star to Rotate it.When stars of different color run into ,they will switch automatically. Make the stars of the same color stay together just like the magic cube. then you win;
 [close] Breakdown Plus Category: Games &gt; Strategy Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Breakdown will never let you down with its unique gameplay, made just for your entertainment!!!

Breakdown challenges with 40 levels of amazing gameplay. Sharpen your skills with limited time and with unlimited supply of bombs. Bring down the Alien structure to rubble using your attack strategy.

Breakdown is an action-packed strategy game with an appealing graphic, styling and plenty of excitement to keep you on your toes. Test your nerve in this simple yet addictive split-second reaction game.

Regardless of your interest and skill level, you’ll never get bored with Breakdown. There’s fun for everyone. You’ll be itching to play each level one more turn and for hours.

Bombing has never been this fun!

Features:

• 40 exigent levels
• Stimulating game play, graphics and music
• Static blocks are present in higher levels
• OpenFeint and Game Center integrated for global scoring;
 [close] PhotosForMe Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Photography Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet ********************
Free for a limited time
If you like the application, please rate it :)
********************

You can keep your photos private with this application.

Just define a password and you will be the only one to have access to your photos.

You can import the photos from the iPhone library or take it from the camera.

You can send your private photo by email or copy it to the iPhone library.

You can zoom on your photos and the application supports portrait and landscape orientation.

Nobody will know your secrets :);
 [close] The Meeting Price Category: Utilities Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Calculate the cost of your meetings and find out if you are productive!

Simple application to calculate what it costs the meetings based on the salary of the members.

Background activity to be able to perform other tasks on the device.

------------------------------------

¡Calcula el gasto de tus reuniones y descubre si son productivas!

Sencilla aplicación para calcular lo que cuestan las reuniones en base al sueldo de los integrantes.

Actividad en segundo plano para que puedas realizar otras tareas en el dispositivo.;
 [close] كتلة الجسم المناسبه Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Healthcare&amp;Fitness Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet هل اردت مره ان تعرف ما هي كتلة جسمك المناسبه لطولك!
**********************************************************************
يوفر هذا البرنامج ادأه لاحتساب الكتله المناسبه لطولك ولعمرك. بحيث يطلب من المقتني ادخال العمر والطول والوزن ومن ثم ليوافيه بقيمة مقياس الكتله البي ام اي وما تعنيه القيمه من حيث كون كتلة الجسم مقبوله او تحت الوزن الطبيعي او فوقه.
والبرنامج يقبل الوحدات الامريكيه (قدم٬ انش٬ باوند) او الوحدات المتريه (سم٬ كغم) ليناسب الوحدات المستعمله اينما كنتم.;
 [close] Feelz Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Social Networking Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Finally it has arrived! The new application to give a new spin-off to your emotions and feelings. Feelz is a facebook based application to simplify your &quot;communication&quot; with friends. No more writing, just tap our Feelz cat to transform your anger, love, sympathy, tenderness into cat&apos;s reactions. What can be sweeter than a purring cat appearing on the screen of your girlfriend? Flatter the cat and demonstrate to your facebook friends that you remember them.

The application is so easy to use that my grandmother sends me feelz every day. She is a facebook user and therefore she doesn&apos;t need to remember another new login and password. Facebook for iPhone and its integration with Feelz make it all for her.
New feelz arrive with Push notifications so you always know that someone has thought of you at the moment. And obviously your friends also need the Feelz app to send and receive feelz.

Discover the new way of expressing and delivering your emotions with our Feelz app.;
 [close] Zoo&amp;Farm Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Entertainment Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet FREE for limited time only. get it while stocks last!
32 Amazing &apos;Zoo&amp;Farm&apos; sounds from all your favourite animals and insects presented with stunning icons and animations. Make your own track list with the built in sequencer, use the pitch slider to create funny alternative sounds or use the shake feature to play random sounds at every shake. You can even set the built in timer to trigger your sounds to unsuspecting victims.

Farm sounds:
Sheep, Chicken, Cow, Piglet, Dog, Duck, Pig,Cat,Mouse,Chicks,Donkey,
Crickets, Crow, Geese, Turkey, Bees

Zoo Sounds:
Lion, Elephant, Zebra, Rattle Snake,Hyena Dolphin,Flies,Frog,Kookaburu,Jungle Birds,Parrot,Bear,Wolf,Cougar,Mosquito,Chimp

Features
• 32 Super high quality sounds
• High Definition Graphics specially designed for the iPad and new HD Retina display iPhone and iPod touch as well as full support for standard definition devices.
• High performance OpenGL App.
• Stunning visuals including animated Monkey character and fruit machine style lit icons.
• Use the built in pitch sampler to make your sounds dark or squeaky funny.
• Includes a sequencer for stringing sounds together to create your very own original mix. Simply drag and drop icons into the centre.
• Built in timer allows you to trigger your sounds unexpectedly to freak out your friends. ;
 [close] Zombie Street Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Games &gt; Role Playing Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Defense shooting action armed with splendid effects - Zombie Street Defense

* New&amp;Noteworthy Featured! - United States
* New&amp;Noteworthy Featured! - Hong Kong
* New&amp;Noteworthy Featured! - Canada
* New&amp;Noteworthy Featured! - Japan

* AppBuddy Review
http://www.appbuddy.com/iphone-app/zombie-street

* AppSafari Review
http://www.appsafari.com/games/15840/zombie-street/


Build a stronghold and rescue your colleagues by escaping from the city occupied by zombies!

★ Desperate struggle against zombies to escape from the zombie city.
- Alone in the city, you have only one pistol!
- Buy weapons and mercenaries and upgrade, and you can block the endless zombies.

★ High quality graphic.
- Natural animation characters and splendid shooting action.
- Graphic displaying beautiful and characteristic city background every place.
- The splendid effect of shooting.
- Powerful effect of blowing the zombies off.

★ Rhythmic BGM and realistic weaponry effects.
- Rhythmic BGM cannot be missed in the desperate struggle against zombies.
- Realistic and exciting shooting effects of each weapon.

★ The five types of extraordinary weapons which will protect you.
- The five types of extraordinary weapons necessary for your survival.
- All weapons contain powerful hitting impact.
- As you go on, you can obtain more powerful weapon.

★ 4 trustworthy comrades who will support you.
- 4 comrades with great styles.
- Each uses extraordinary weapon helping you.
- Playing the game, you will meet new comrades, and you can kill the zombies with them.

★ Special skills provided to overcome crisis.
- Special skills are supported to settle the crisis in one shot.
- If you are in a dangerous situation surrounded zombies, let’s use the air bombardment.

★ Upgrade system giving various fun.
- About 20 types of extraordinary upgrades provided.
- Numerous factors such as weapon and mercenaries, special weapon, barricade, and etc can be provided.
- Let’s see how stronger you become through steady upgrade.
- Let’s kill the zombies and gather my own achievements in OpenFeint


YouTube Game Movie Link :
http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zu0wAhPmjWY;
 [close] Alien Airfield Plus Category: Games &gt; Arcade Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Once the alien starts attacking, there’s no looking around. It’s now or never. Do you want to survive and be remembered as a brave heart or do you want run away and be remembered as a loser?

Take charge and hold the fate of your army camp with your own bare hands with our latest game.

Defend your army base from the Alien Attack. Destroy the invading creatures by eliminating them with your agile shooting skills. Terminate all incoming alien pest forces wave by wave!

PS: Special power-ups get enabled. Bonus items will help you terminate all your enemies present on the screen.

Alien AirField is a well-made game, with smooth and steadfast controls and colorful graphics that look great. Get into action in this all new shooting game.

Features:

• Integrated with OpenFeint and Game Centre for global scoring
• Three colored aliens
• Agile and fast paced action game;
 [close] Attack Buster Plus Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Games &gt; Action Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Attack Buster is no big war game, but we are sure you will be engaged fighting the odds for your survival.

Getting trapped in a deserted city under attack is the worst nightmare you could ever imagine happening to you. This game is no worse, in putting you under terrible attack.
Prepare your escape strategy to outrun the missiles and bombs hurled at you by the rogue army of terrorists.

The game is well programmed for easy controlling of the character for effective gameplay. The accelerometer will be put to its best use to escape from the attack, pump up your adrenaline and boost away to glory.

But watch out, it’s harder than it looks! Cruise your way using accelerometer to escape from the explosive aerial attack. Attack Buster is a game that you can enjoy playing anywhere and anytime. With striking hand drawn graphics, Attack Buster is all set to amuse you and will keep you busy for hours together.

Features:

• Addicting, fun and entertaining
• Witty graphics and sound
• Integrated with OpenFeint and Game Centre for global scoring;
 [close] iEveryday For Face Free Offer Ended - Now: $1.99 Category: Photography Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet ==================================
FREE FOR ONLY 4 DAYS, DON&apos;T MISS OUT
==================================

Take a photo for yourself , your kids or your lover very day.
Then make a video after some days or a few years later.
You must be surprised by what has been changed on your face so far
How can we do this with iPhone?

Good question!
iEveryday is coming on the App Store to meet your above requirements.

HIGHLIGHTS
==============
* Take a photo every day
* Multiple group supported
* Adjust your photo with previous photo when you decide to take a photo
* Adjust your photo by your set face Glid
* Reminder you to take a photo every day at your proper time, get into the habit
* Easy to browse and manage your photos
* Make a smooth video
* Support three video speed: Slow, Normal, Fast
* Share your photos or videos to EMail, Facebook
* Import photos from Camera Roll
* Export photos into Camera Roll
* Export Video into Camera Roll;
 [close] 세계단편문학 Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Books Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet 세계 단편 문학 9편을 아이폰에서 쉽게 볼수 있게 담았습니다.
아이폰으로 짜투리 시간에 주옥같은 세계 단편문학작품을
접할수 있도록 하였습니다.

수능 언어 영역과 대입 면접 논술 등에서 작은 도움이 될것입니다.
--------------------------
지원 기능

책장을 넘기는 듯한 자연스러운 동작
즐겨찾기 기능 제공
레티나 디스플레이 지원
썸네일 보기 지원
---------------------------------

세계단편 문학 작품

가든 파티:캐더린 맨스필드(Katherine Mansfield)
귀여운여인 : 안톤 체홉
마지막수업 : 알퐁스 도데(Alphonse Daudet)
목걸이 : 기 드 모파상(Guy de Maupassant)
비계덩어리 : 기 드 모파상(Guy de Maupassant)
아를르의 여인 : 알퐁스 도데(Alphonse Daudet)
죽은사람들 :제임스 조이스(James Joyce)
하숙집 : 제임스 조이스(James Joyce)
해변에서 : 캐더린 맨스필드(Katherine Mansfield);
 [close] WeightShaker Category: Games &gt; Action Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet WeightShaker is a fun simulator/game that makes you laugh while giving you a workout! With this app you can:

*Practice your shaking technique in Practice Mode.
*Test your shaking speed in Speed Mode.
*Test your stamina and see how long you can last in Endurance Mode.
*View your personal high scores as well as your ranking on the global Game Center Leaderboard charts.
*Earn funny Game Center achievements like: &quot;Fantastic Forearms!&quot; or &quot;What are those tissues for?&quot;

Best of all, you will look just plain awesome playing it!;
 [close] eMultiply Category: Education Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet This application allows the individual to learn Multiplication tables.
The application displays a easy to use Main Menu, which helps navigate thru different options.

Option 1: Why Learn Tables

The first option is an introduction that explains why to learn the Times/Multiplication tables.

Option 2: Read Tables

The Second Option is the one which allows the user read and learn the times/multiplication tables for numbers 1 to 20. The user can pick a Number using the Picker.

Once you pick a number to read the table, that brings up a new view which by default displays the table.


This view has a tabbed interface. You can see the tabs on the bottom of the screen. The default tabs displays the table allowing the user to read. If you pick the test option from the bottom, it will remove the values from the table and allows the user type in the Values.
Once you are done with entering the values on the Test screen and click done from the key board, the answers will be evaluated and you will see a tick or cross across the lines.

Option 3 : Test a table @ Random

This screen will look same as the test screen in option 2 except that the lines will be jumbled and no more in sequence.

Option 4: Test Tabes (1..20) @ Random

This test allows testing of Tables any where from 1..20 picked at random.

On all the Test screens the answers are evaluated once the User selects the Done button from the keyboard.;
 [close] Fire Stars Category: Games &gt; Family Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet ***** FREE for a limited time *****

To celebrate the ongoing success of our game Pengi, we give you Fire Stars completely FREE for a limited time!!!!

Enter the breathtaking world of the Fire Stars!

Consisting of:

✦ Groundbreaking puzzle game
✦ 32 levels, ranging from easy to hard
✦ Over 25,000 stunning puzzles!
✦ Each puzzle has only a single solution!
✦ 2 Modes of play
✦ Awe-inspiring graphics!

Other features:

✦ Leaderboards
✦ Hints, if ever stuck on a puzzle, see the next correct move
✦ Statistics
✦ In-game tutorial
✦ No two puzzles are ever the same!

These aren&apos;t just any regular stars, they are on FIRE!
Fling these balls of fire in any direction, but make sure that each one ends up on the spot that matches its color. You must complete each puzzle in the amount of moves indicated.

✦ This game is incredibly easy to learn, but will keep you entertained for hours!;
 [close] Super Mega Worm Vs Santa Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Games &gt; Adventure Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Save Mother Earth!

Guess who has been a naughty boy this Christmas? Santa and his little helpers have crossed the line and now they must pay. Join Wojira, The Great Mega Worm, as it returns in this all new adventure set in the North Pole. Crawl and eat your way through waves of elves and their evil machines as you grow and evolve into the ultimate weapon of mass destruction to become the Super Mega Worm!

Features:

- 15 Action Packed Levels
- Final Showdown Vs. Santa!
- Over 15 New Items to Eat and Destroy
- 3 New Super Abilities
- 2 Chaotic Game Modes
- GameCenter Leaderboards and Achievements
- Universal App (Supports all iOS devices.)
----------------------
Trailer

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hIiD59SD_mM

----------------------
Reviews

&quot;But considering the amount of fun and cheer we got out of bringing chaos to the North Pole, we&apos;d never recommend against buying this twisted holiday game. If it sounds good to you, chances are you&apos;ll love it.&quot; 3/4 - SlideToPlay.com

&quot;This Christmas edition of the game is great for veterans of the original, who want more Super Mega Worm goodness, and the tweaked gameplay and hilarious new Christmas theme will please them.&quot; 4/5 - ThePortableGamer.com


&quot;Super Mega Worm vs. Santa brings all that fun to the North Pole, where penguins and elves become your prey. It&apos;s more amusing to decimate the forces of Christmas than it is rednecks and soldiers, so this festive edition to the game definitely scores brownie points for that.&quot; 7/10 - Destructoid.com


-------------------
Follow Us

Twitter:
http://twitter.com/deceasedpixel

Facebook:
http://www.facebook.com/pages/Deceased-Pixel/126012137446122;
 [close] Hidden-View Category: Games &gt; Puzzle Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet HiddenView is an experimental puzzle game with basic physics and shaders.
There are about 30 levels in the game. In each level, a stone image is displayed in different forms with several see-through/transparent objects. These objects reveal part of the background image. Your task is to find what the background image represents (for e.g. they can be utensils, animals, every-day items, etc) with the help of these objects.

A star shaped object in each level is interactive (i.e. it can be selected and dragged), while the rest are just helper objects. You can also move the objects by tilting your phone.
Once you guess, what the background image is, enter your answer by clicking &quot;Enter answer&quot; at the top. (Please don&apos;t use any special characters or spaces) If your answer is correct, the background image is displayed and the game moves ahead.

On the top left is the level progress indicator, and on the top right is the restart button. Your game progress is saved, when you quit the game.

Highlights:

No time limit, no audio, no menu system, no scores, no story-board
Truly original idea/concept
Uses own graphics engine

Please Note: This game works with shader supported (i.e. 3GS or later) devices only

A sample demo video is available here: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vM18PPJiNOg&amp;feature;=player_profilepage;
 [close] 쿠폰D-Day Category: Lifestyle Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet [소개]
쇼셜 쇼핑후 받은 쿠폰을 사용하실때 SMS를 찾지 못해 당황했던 경험이 없으신가요?

본 어플은 최근 급증하는 쇼셜 쇼핑의 구매를 통해 얻게 되는 쿠폰 SMS, 번호, 바코드 이미지 등을 보다 쉽게 관리하기 위해 만들어졌습니다.

쿠폰 사용 기간이 언제까지인지 잊어버려서 사용하지 못한 쿠폰이 없으신가요? 이제 더이상 그렇게 버려지는 쿠폰을 막을수 있습니다.
쿠폰을 등록해 놓으면 기본 1일, 7일(사용자가 변경가능)전에 푸쉬알림을 날려줍니다. 이를 통해 미리 기간 만료가 될 쿠폰을 알아 내어 사용을 할수가 있습니다.

또한 만료근접한 쿠폰이 있을 경우 앱아이콘 위에 뱃지를 띄워줘서 보다 쉽게 쿠폰의 상태를 확인해 볼수 있습니다. 뱃지기능과 푸쉬알림 기능을 활용하면 더이상 쿠폰을 사용하지 못한채 날려버리는 실수를 범하지 않게 됩니다.

비밀번호 등록을 통해 내 쿠폰을 남들이 보지 못하도록 막아 놓을수 있습니다.

구글맵을 이용하여 쿠폰을 사용할 위치(지도)를 등록해서 사용처를 바로 볼수 있습니다.

해당 쿠폰에 해당하는 금액(수량)을 입력할수 있어서 전체 사용/일부사용을 선택적으로 적용할수 있습니다.

마감일순 정렬기능 통해서 마감임박한 쿠폰 리스트를 볼수 있습니다.

[주요기능]
- SMS를 통해 받은 쿠폰 번호 등록
- 유효기관 관리를 통한 만료 일정기간전 알림기능(푸쉬알림, Batge표시)
- 쿠폰 이미지 등록 기능
- 지도를 이용해서 쿠폰을 사용하는 장소를 미리 등록
- 비밀번호 잠금 기능
- 쿠폰의 전체 사용 / 일부 사용기능
- 마감일 / 등록일순 정렬 기능;
 [close] Cows vs Aliens Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Games &gt; Family Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Download the @FreeAppADay Store App and wish for more top rated paid apps like Cows vs Aliens to become FREE for a day!

Aliens are invading and you need to save your cows by herding them into the barn as fast as possible!

** Picked by Apple as a Featured App! **

** Named TUAW.com&apos;s &quot;Daily App&quot;! **

** Named Gizmodo.com &quot;App of the Day&quot;! **

** Rated &quot;Addictive&quot; 148apps.com! **

** &quot;Coupled with the interesting control mechanic and compelling scoring system, Cows vs Aliens has totally reeled me in.&quot; -- Jared Nelson, Touch Arcade **

In Cows vs Aliens, the newest game from XMG Studio, tap and hold on the screen to prod cows into the barn. Protect your herd of cattle and keep the aliens out of the barn! Keep herding cows to increase your time, maximize your score and complete as many waves as possible. Then beat your Game Center friends to show everyone who is best cowboy of them all!

The new update to the game brings 4 new levels of gameplay (Summer, Fall, Winter and Area 54 levels join the original Spring level); a new scoring system which lets you earn Milk Points that you can redeem for power-ups, boosters, saves, and extras including a fun Cows vs Aliens ringtone.

If you want to keep the updates coming rate us 5 stars and comment! Its the motivation we need to keep delivering the best in mobile games to our fans.

For more, follow us facebook.com/xmgstudio or @XMGStudio.

Retina display-optimized graphics make it look great on any device!

For now, this game is only available for iOS 4.0 and above. If you want it on a lower version, contact us on Twitter or Facebook!;
 [close] Graph Crayon Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Games &gt; Family Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet “Graph Crayon is free today for a limited time, in association with http://www.DailyAppDream.com. Download the Daily App Dreams App to find out about the other free apps on offer each day!&quot;


You must be able to complete the set without repeating the same line and without releasing a finger, while respecting the reference image.
Complete the graph and find the figure shape.
Try to get the best score being the fastest of all.
Improve your mental agility and will test all your memory.

Complete the 32 levels of this game..


ENJOY;
 [close] Gun Studio Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Entertainment Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Have you ever wondered what you’d look like with a gun? With Gun Studio you can now easily add a gun to your photo and see what you’d look like without a the danger of shooting anyone!

Select from 40 awesome guns!;
 [close] Despierta Category: Utilities Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet &quot;Despierta&quot; is a new generation alarm clock. Record your self, or someone special for you, with a nice-motivating message which will wake you up in the morning flavored with a soft background music.

Start your days with all the energy and motivation you need! You make your destiny, so help you since the very first second of your day.

It&apos;s really easy to use! Just set the time using the arrows. Then go to the Mic icon, select one of the six voice banks and record your message. Finally, select the background and that&apos;s it! Start the alarm.

Despierta works in background, so you DON&apos;T need to have the App open to work. Set your alarm, and then keep using your phone as usual.;
 [close] TopAlbaniaLivePlay Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Music Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Top Albania Radio on air, Top Radio live, Listen Top Albania Radio Live. Degjo Top Albania Radio.

Top Channel was established on 30 July 2001 in the International Center for Culture (Qendra Ndërkombëtare e Kulturës) in Tirana, and since then has seen a very fast growth and success and it has become preferable by a growing number of people. It is believed that Top Channel holds an average viewing percentage of 70% as of 2006, though these are based on approximate evaluations of various experts and not officially confirmed. Based on a survey in 2003, Top Channel was ranked as the most watched TV channel in Albania with 50 % of the national audience, thus leaving far behind the second watched TV which accounts for 17 % of the national audience. In an earlier survey (2002) it has been ranked in third place with 11.9% audience share, right behind the public broadcaster TVSH. Its success relates to its informational programs about the problems that Albanian society is facing, as well as to the comparatively high technology by which it operates. Also other media outlets making up Top Media include Top Albania Radio, the daily newspaper Shqip, and part of the pay TV platform DigitAlb.
In the past years it has also sought partnership with international development agencies such as UNDP, UNICEF, IOM, OSCE, USAID, Albanian and French Red Cross, and many others, and sustains partnership with international private companies such as Vodafone. In addition, Top Channel has seen growing partnership with international news agencies such as Reuters in exchanging news coverage.
Vjollca Hoxha, wife of Dritan Hoxha, has taken over the business since 2008.;
 [close] Dog Pile Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Games &gt; Arcade Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet ★★★Featured in &apos;What&apos;s Hot&apos;★★★

Rating ★★★★ - Young or old, this is a must-have in your games list.
- appadvice.com

Rating 9/10 - &quot;Dog Pile HD takes that simple game play, tacks on a cute factor and punches out an amazing game that is fun for everyone...this game has a serious replay factor.&quot;
- padgadget.com

Rating 8/10 - &quot;...what really makes this game work is the level design. Between the different moving objects and things like the introduction of the black hole, every level in the Space set feels like a different experience. Dog Pile is a nice mash-up that will certainly keep you entertained long enough to make it worth the price of admission. &quot;
- iphonelife.com

Rating 4.5/5 - &quot;Plenty of addictive fun with plenty of customizations to prolong the life of the game.Funky music and cute graphics as well.&quot;
- iphonegameruk.webs.com

Rating 4.5/5 - &quot;This game it’s so addictive that i played it at home and everywhere i go.&quot;
- ititothemes.wordpress.com

Rating 4/5 - &quot;Fun, whimsical little casual game&quot;
- crazymikesapps.com

&quot;The graphics and sound are adorable, perfectly matching the whimsical style and gameplay. The control of the game was similarly flawless; the Dog Pile uses a fun combination of touch, swipe, and tilt controlling that really gets you into the game.&quot;
- freshapps.com

&quot;The art and design will appeal to children while the challenge will also appeal to adults.&quot;
- thegamerwithkids.com

&quot;Ideal for all ages. It&apos;s a lot of fun. Allows customization.&quot;
- dailyappshow.com

Unleash the Fun!

★ Ad free Full Version
★ 250 BONES to spend customizing your dog pack!

Get your Dog Pack ready to play the craziest game show around! It’s time to sit up and cheer... “Dog Pile!”

Dog Pile is packed with features:
★ Stunning yet adorable graphics in HD!
★ Interactive gameboards come to life as you play!
★ Collect dog bone biscuits and outfit your favorite Dog Pack!
★ Simple swipe controls get your Dog into the action!
★ Match your Dog on the Pile below before time runs out!
★ Use tilt controls to guide your Dogs through insane obstacles for big points!
★ Start by playing the thrilling Carnival courses before really unleashing your dogs in the zany Space Challenge!
★ Every level offers a fun and unique set of obstacles and gizmos to try!

Bark about Dog Pile on Facebook and Twitter:
http://www.facebook.com/DogPileGame
http://twitter.com/DogPileGame;
 [close] Bird&apos;n Bee Category: Games &gt; Action Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet IT&apos;S HERE.
Bird &apos;n Bee is THE bird-consuming, bee-avoiding, weird-pink-monster-kissing action game you&apos;ve been waiting for for years.

LOOKING FOR A CHALLENGE?
Don&apos;t miss the chance to try your hand at the single MOST DIFFICULT game for iPhone yet.

VIOLENT RAGE.
Get your rage bar to the full to unleash the beast inside you. Let the mountains tremble with your rabid laughter as the hunter becomes the hunted.

SUDDEN PULSES OF ADDICTIVE GAMEPLAY.
Experience sudden bursts of fun and excitement.

RUTHLESS COMPETITION.
Compare your scores with friends and complete strangers via Game Center global scoreboards. Try and beat the developers&apos; scores. Let songs be sung about your glorious success. Fame and fortune is one click away.;
 [close] my Body Mass Index Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Healthcare&amp;Fitness Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet *************************************************************************
Ever wondered what is the BMI!! or ever wondered about
your
fat type!!!
*************************************************************************

This app calculates the body mass index and states your body
fat status.

It accepts both units systems; metric and imperial.

It helps people keep well informed about their weight
by stating the status of your weight.
************************************************************************;
 [close] Sudoku Fun! Category: Games &gt; Educational Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Sudoku is a logic-based, combinatorial number-placement puzzle. The objective is to fill a 9×9 grid with digits so that each column, each row, and each of the nine 3×3 sub-grids that compose the grid (also called &quot;boxes&quot;, &quot;blocks&quot;, &quot;regions&quot;, or &quot;sub-squares&quot;) contains all of the digits from 1 to 9. The puzzle setter provides a partially completed grid, which typically has a unique solution.

The app keeps track of your best time! So, you can try beating your best time every time you play! Enjoy!;
 [close] Mr.Ninja Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Games &gt; Action Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Only now FREE!!
Following smash hits of &quot;Mr.&quot; series in US,New &quot;Mr.&quot; appears!
Nobody gets left behind to enjoy this hilarious NINJA and KATANA action game! The name is...&quot;Mr.Ninja&quot;!

Slash the aliens in the invaded KARAKURI castle!


*** About &quot;Mr.Ninja&quot; ***

*Extremely simple to play.
Step1...Tap the screen to jump.
Step2...Slash the aliens.
Step3...And slash the aliens. all of them!

That&apos;s all!

*This couldn&apos;t be better!
-One-touch control.
-Cool design with characteristic color scheme.
-Hilarious NINJA and KATANA action game.
-3 Game Modes are available.

*Game Center enabled!




Presented by PONOS;
 [close] Memory Match Fun! Category: Games &gt; Family Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Memory Match Fun! The classic card memory game with 10 different themes! Adorable themes that challenge and improve your memory and cognitive skills! Flip cards over and try to find matches! Great fun for entire family especially the little kidos. Ages 2 - 10 years. The game also saves your high score! ;^);
 [close] Sonic Planets Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Music Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Listen to sounds of the universe. Sit back and chill out to the voices of the planets as they evolve in space. See how many planets you can spot and keep an eye out for UFOS!
 
 

Shake to reset. Planets are movable!;
 [close] Calculator* Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Utilities Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet &gt;&gt;Also check out Mendero&apos;s &quot;Todo*&quot; and &quot;Notes*&quot;&lt;&lt;

Calculator* is an easy-to-use pocket calculator with stylish design! Find your personal favourite among 8 background themes!

Calculator* is one of several apps designed by Mendero. If you like the design of Calculator*, search for Mendero in App Store to find the other apps. You can also join us on Facebook and Twitter!;
 [close] SnapBot Category: Photography Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Assemblo Snapbot is the simple way to share up to four photos straight from your iPhone over email or straight to Facebook!

Share your photos with the press of a button.

We&apos;ve got more features planed for later releases, so keep your feedback coming and we&apos;ll keep working to make Snapbot the number one app in photo sharing!

- Share in the moment with family and friends, using Facebook sharing.
- Great for businesses: Snap and email legible documents quickly and easily.
- Ideal for trades and delivery people: take and share work site photos,
- Excellent for bloggers: Easily email high resolution photos to use in your blog!

Assemblo Snapbot features include:

- Share one, two, three or four photos over email or straight to Facebook.
- Simple, easy to use interface
- Preview, retake or delete any photo straight from the app
- Share photos without clogging up your camera roll.
- Save your photos to the camera roll if you want to keep them.
- Full support for all camera enabled devices (iPhone3, iPhone3GS, iPhone4, iPad4)
- Retina support

Download Assemblo Snapbot today!

Tell us how YOU use Snapbot. Send your photos and feedback to tap@assemblo.com!;
 [close] Mirror™ Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Utilities Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Sale ends SOON! Hurry 50% OFF this week only!!!

Turn your iPhone into a handy pocket mirror!

Uses black screen or front camera as a Mirror™ effect for better reflection.
The first mirrors used by people was water surface. Now anyone can have it in the pocket! Sometimes you need to check your hair or teeth. Then Mirror™ comes to help you!

- Different frame modes
- Mirror™ remembers your last frame
- Use it for fun!
- Tap the screen to change the mirror frame.;
 [close] ASCII Art for iPhone Category: Utilities Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet This app converts input text to ascii art picture,
and send out the ascii picture as email.

You can greet or make wish in a impressive way.

It copies the picture to pasteboard, and
can be used anywhere you want.

It supports three style: futurist, block&amp;wireframe,
and 5 colors.;
 [close] EvuTubes : Pipe Puzzle Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Games &gt; Puzzle Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet A pipe puzzle with 72 levels. Your goal is delivering the liquid from source to target.

Version 1.0.1:
9 bonus levels added.
Version 1.0.2:
Game menu changed.
9 new bonus levels added.;
 [close] Tip Ninjamaster Calculator Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Travel Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Are you going on a business trip? Bring along the Tip Ninjamaster to as a tip calculator!

The Tip Ninjamaster not only computes your tip but he also imparts knowledge on tipping/gratuity.

This application is lightweight, accurate, easy to use and does not require the internet.

Have fun by letting the Tip Ninjamaster entertain you with his tip abilities!;
 [close] Pocket News - Spain Free Offer Ended - Now: $1.99 Category: News Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet ***************************************
Special Promotion: next 200 customers gets this app for FREE !!! Please tell a friend...
***************************************

Get all your latest local and national news about Spain fast and easy from this app. This app will aggregate all the news together for you in an easy to use interface.

We&apos;ve also added five primary news categories for everyone to enjoy
• Top Stories
• International
• Technology
• Sports
• Entertainment

*****************************
FEATURES:
*****************************
• &quot;Keep It Simple&quot; - Unlike other apps, you commonly have to jump back and forth between different screens to drill down and down when all you really want is today&apos;s news.

• &quot;Speed&quot; - You want speed....we&apos;ve tuned every corner of this app to maximize of efficiency.

• &quot;Large Full Resolution Images&quot; - Others give you thumbnail images, we rather give you full resolution of all images with no performance hit.

• &quot;One View&quot; - Pocket News allows you to scroll and read all in one simple view.

• &quot;Speedy Navigation&quot; - Left and right paging buttons are also available for you to browser three headlines at a time.

• &quot;Bookmark&quot; - We also have a selector that highlights the current article you are reading so you don&apos;t loose your place.

• &quot;Offline&quot; - Want offline reading? We&apos;ve got it. Perhaps you will be traveling to some where with no data connection; airplane, train, boating, mountains. We got you covered. Pocket News saves all the articles locally in your iPhone/iPod Touch so you can browse through them when data connection is not available.

• &quot;Instant Download&quot; - To save articles for offline viewing, simply open and close the app when you have data connection. Your latest news feed will then saved and ready to go.

• &quot;Sharing&quot; - You may also share the stories you find by simply clicking on the email button and sending it off to your family and friends.

• &quot;Full Article&quot; - There is also a full article button for you to explore the article in it&apos;s entirety at Yahoo News.


Please note that all Pocket News data content is a live feed from Yahoo News rss services. Yuan Venture is in no way affiliated or partnered with Yahoo and their respective partners. All copyright and trademark information and contents delivered through the feeds are the properties of Yahoo and their respective owners.;
 [close] Stamps List Category: Lifestyle Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet ✪✪✪✪ GREAT APP FOR STORING ALL YOUR STAMP INFORMATION

************** KEY WORDS *****************
Stamps, Stamp, list, collection, catalog, mint, USA, grade, format, cancel, gum, Scott #
**********************************************************

✪✪ We are aware that the list feature does not show the stamp detail. It has been addressed and a new update has been submitted to Apple for release.

-- FEATURES

- Save as many Stamps as you want
- Attach a picture with every stamp.
- Instantly email the stamp information without leaving the app.
- Email as many times as you want
- Pick from 6 different characteristics of Stamps such as
- Format
- Grade
- Hinged
- Centering
- Gum
- Cancel
- Country
- Search by scott, other, description
- Record Sell information for each stamp
- Key in as much comments as needed in the stamp sale feature
- Scroll through all of your stamps in a cover flow format.


Each Stamp Save has the following options to store

-- Scott #
-- Other #
-- Quantity
-- Cost
-- Value
-- Desc
-- Date Acquired
-- Extra Info
-- Format
-- Grade
-- Hinged
-- Centering
-- Gum
-- Cancel
-- Country

✪✪ Record your stamp sale. Record as much as you want.

Each Stamp Sell has the following options to store
-- Stamp id
-- Date Sold
-- Asking Price
-- Selling price
-- Sold to
-- Comments


✪✪ We are working on an update for the Facebook share feature.


✪✪ We are working on an update for the Print option.


Please rate our application and provide user feedback, so we can refine this application. Thank you for your patronage.;
 [close] Pocket News - Germany Free Offer Ended - Now: $1.99 Category: News Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet ***************************************
Special Promotion: next 200 customers gets this app for FREE !!! Please tell a friend...
**************************************

Get all your latest local and national news about Germany fast and easy from this app. This app will aggregate all the news together for you in an easy to use interface.

We&apos;ve also added five primary news categories for everyone to enjoy
• Top Stories
• International
• Technology
• Sports
• Entertainment

*****************************
FEATURES:
*****************************
• &quot;Keep It Simple&quot; - Unlike other apps, you commonly have to jump back and forth between different screens to drill down and down when all you really want is today&apos;s news.

• &quot;Speed&quot; - You want speed....we&apos;ve tuned every corner of this app to maximize of efficiency.

• &quot;Large Full Resolution Images&quot; - Others give you thumbnail images, we rather give you full resolution of all images with no performance hit.

• &quot;One View&quot; - Pocket News allows you to scroll and read all in one simple view.

• &quot;Speedy Navigation&quot; - Left and right paging buttons are also available for you to browser three headlines at a time.

• &quot;Bookmark&quot; - We also have a selector that highlights the current article you are reading so you don&apos;t loose your place.

• &quot;Offline&quot; - Want offline reading? We&apos;ve got it. Perhaps you will be traveling to some where with no data connection; airplane, train, boating, mountains. We got you covered. Pocket News saves all the articles locally in your iPhone/iPod Touch so you can browse through them when data connection is not available.

• &quot;Instant Download&quot; - To save articles for offline viewing, simply open and close the app when you have data connection. Your latest news feed will then saved and ready to go.

• &quot;Sharing&quot; - You may also share the stories you find by simply clicking on the email button and sending it off to your family and friends.

• &quot;Full Article&quot; - There is also a full article button for you to explore the article in it&apos;s entirety at Yahoo News.


Please note that all Pocket News data content is a live feed from Yahoo News rss services. Yuan Venture is in no way affiliated or partnered with Yahoo and their respective partners. All copyright and trademark information and contents delivered through the feeds are the properties of Yahoo and their respective owners.;
 [close] FindMeNow Category: Utilities Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Soon version 1.1 with iOS 3.x compatibility...

Send via SMS or email your position!!
Find Me Now is a geolocalization utility intended for cross platform sharing of your GPS position. Coordinates are sent as an internet map link compatible with all smartphones and many other mobile devices or as a plain text with latitude and longitude.

Concept by Enrico Antongiovanni
Programming by Stefano Peruzzi&amp;Marco Marchesin;
 [close] Shirt Bling Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Entertainment Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet Represent yourself virtually with the coolest bling ... now available for iPhone and iPod Touch.

Wear your iPhone or iPod Touch proudly, and the bling will sway side-to-side with your body as you strut your stuff!

Personalize your style by changing the bling and the shirt. For a cooler look, create a custom shirt using the color picker, or take a photo using the built-in camera for a more realistic look.;
 [close] Gender Predictor Category: Entertainment Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet The application will predict the gender of your coming baby, based on the mother birthday and the month of conception.

The result will immediately predict your baby whether it&apos;s boy or girl.

This application is based on the Chinese Gender Chart, which is very famous around the globe.;
 [close] SwissLoterie Category: Lifestyle Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet En panne d&apos;inspiration pour remplir une grille de loterie suisse à numéros?

SwissLoterie est une application qui vous permet de générer six nombres aléatoires entre 1 et 45 ainsi qu&apos;un nombre compris entre 1 et 3 (pour la loterie suisse à numéros) ou entre 1 et 50 et 1 et 9 (pour l&apos;Euromillions). Cette application se destine tout particulièrement à remplir une grille de la loterie suisse à numéro ou d&apos;Euromillions.
A noter que cette application n&apos;est qu&apos;une aide et ne prétend donner en aucun cas la bonne combinaison.

Il est aussi possible d&apos;aller voir en ligne les résultats des deux loteries.
;
 [close] My Enigma - Enigma Machine Simulator Category: Education Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet My Enigma is a simplified, yet faithful, simulation of the German cryptographic encoding machine used in World War II. The Enigma is one of the most studied and storied rotary encoding machines. The allies’ effort breaking Enigma’s encryption was instrumental in winning World War II.

The simulator demonstrates the original three rotor system with a fixed reflector and includes the double stepping feature. Initial version does not include the plug board and only uses rotor types I, II and III. The primary reason was to keep operation simple for demonstration and use.

To encode, set the rotors to a three letter configuration and then type on the simulated keyboard. The lamps above the keyboard will light up with the encoded letter just as the original machine. The original and encoded strings are also displayed as you type. Double tap on the fields to copy and paste the text to or from email and SMS.

To decode, set the rotors to the same configuration as you used for encoding. Then type the encoded message and the lights will now show the original message. You can also paste a message into the input field and have it decoded all at once.;
 [close] Go Green Officemate Free Offer Ended - Now: $0.99 Category: Lifestyle Was: $0.99· View Description · Retweet It is 2011 and everyone is saying, &quot;Go Green!&quot; so we decided to do just that.

Go Green Officemate celebrates the &quot;Go Green&quot; effort.

This environment-inspiring application features a green calculator for quick and easy computation on the go. The lil&apos; note features a themed memo pad perfect for to-do lists, notes to self, or whatever!

With a touch of a button, e-mail your text anywhere! The Go Green detail makes this a unique office accessory a must-have.

Finally, do you know you can use your iPhone/iPod as a flashlight? The flashlight features an environment ribbon to surely light your way at night!

Let&apos;s save the planet together!

It&apos;s that easy and fun!

Best of all - Updates are FREE!

Go Green Officemate works OFFLINE and does not take up much space on your device.

We are very interested in continually enhancing this application. We value your reviews and e-mails so please keep them coming!;
 [close] 
 Previous Day 
Recently free apps May still be free 

 Added on 2011-06-29 

 Via-Connect $8.99 Stores Sales Monitor $79.99 前列腺手册 $4.99 Croatian TV Guide $4.99 iParrot Phrase Spanish-Chinese $4.99 iBuy Home $2.99 꽃단배 떠가네 $2.99 NYKA Columbus $2.99 Veggie Trolls $2.99 Sex Match $199.99 DirBackup $19.99 Water Invaders $1.99 Best Aesop&apos;s Fables (with search) $1.99 bebop!! $1.99 New York English - 뉴욕 영어 $1.99 Costa Rica Trip Ideas $1.99 Coding for iPhone: Part 1 $1.99 Hero Defense Pro $1.99 EZMP3 Player (Support Apple Lossless) $1.99 Trackpad Magic Mobile $1.99 Odd Cat Out $1.99 大家來搶錢 HD $1.99 Zurich Traffic $1.99 iTilt $1.99 KOU - Catch a mole! $0.99 Ninja Pinball $0.99 Mad Maze Office $0.99 Just a Ball $0.99 iBBQ - Fire It Up (SALE!) $0.99 DomainFinder $0.99 Caretas $0.99 Holitapp US $0.99 Match Balls $0.99 The Balloon Popper $0.99 Ways to Propose $0.99 NotesLinker $0.99 Quick Event $0.99 حافظ الأسرار $0.99 Dogfight 1951 $0.99 Loan Mortgage Calculator $0.99 Trolls Impossible Puzzle $0.99 Forge $0.99 Cowboy Tappi - Tappi Bear $0.99 Impossible-Code-Decipher $0.99 Save My Marriage $0.99 Panda Warrior: Zombie king&apos;s treasure $0.99 Smart Diet:Nutrition&amp;Calorie Tracker $0.99 Rocket Boy 2D $0.99 Enduro $0.99 A Well-fixed Sheep Pen Prevents the Wolves-JoyOrange $0.99 
 Advertise Here Get Alerts 
 Follow @freeappalert on Twitter
 Fan freeappalert on Facebook
 Subscribe to RSS Feed
 Tell Others 
 Think FreeAppAlert is awesome? Be sure to share
it with friends so they can get in on free apps too. More 
 Advertise 
 About FreeAppAlert 
 Contact Us 
 
©2009 FreeAppAlert
	</body>
</document>
