<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002041" url="http://tonedcurves.tumblr.com/healthy-eating" time="2012-07-12-17:57" support="1" score="0.001397519766249844" bingtitle="Toned Curves" webtitle="tonedcurves - healthy eating">
			<query id="001225" bing-rank="233"/>
	<description>Put some pepper, throw a lemon slice on it, and ... A recent study found that a fast-food restaurant making four ... million tons of plastic through packages and containers ...</description>
	<body>
		Home About Ask Email Twitter Archive Theme 
 
I’m Ida Maria. I’m 21 years of age and I currently reside in Sweden. I am on the road to a healthy and strong body and somewhere along the way I decided to start this blog.

This is a blog about health, fitness and wellbeing. It is to be a bank of inspiration, motivation and knowledge.

 


Twitter
 healthy eating 
Here you’ll find tips, tricks, advice and facts about food, nutrition and healthy eating. You can also check out my healthy eating tag .


 



General advice on healthy eating

(some via bostyouresteem , veganhope )

 
Healthy eating is a lifestyle, not a diet.
 
Food is your friend. Don’t be scared of it, don’t see it as the enemy, and don’t scarf it all down at once. Good food is good for you, it’s the easiest thing to remember.
 
Eat well, live well. The healthier you eat, the better you’ll feel. Your skin looks better, you sleep better, you have more energy. Plus, focusing on things the healthy way, meaning exercise is about making yourself stronger and healthy food is a reward for yourself, truly ends up balancing you. If you care more about your body, you’ll be putting yourself first and your life will make more sense.
 
Drink water before you eat your meal.
 
Have a big water bottle with you all day. Every time you go to the bathroom, re-fill it.
 
Make the kitchen a safe haven. Clean out the crap and organize what you like. If you open the cabinet and an avalanche of food tumbles out, you need to start over. Live with your parents? Make your own space, even if it’s small. Fill it with your organic peanut butter, your yogurts, and your whole wheat bread. Label it with your name if your family won’t stay away, or encourage them to all eat healthy.
 Pick the right dressings For dressings, go clear instead of thick and white or orange. Pick the right side dishes. Go for veggies instead of mashed potatoes. 
Never be hungry.  If you’re the kind of person who likes to snack while you’re working on homework or work, make it fruit or veggie sticks. Slice up a bunch of water heavy fruits (like watermelon, kiwis, and strawberries) and dump it all into a bowl&amp;take it to your computer and chow down without guilt.
 
Go natural and keep it simple. Ignore those commercials offering youth in a jar or weight loss in a bottle. Don’t buy into the idea that pills or a certain berry are going to make you perfect. Just keep it clean and healthy. If you’re eating well and getting some exercise in, you’re good to go.
 

 
Set your meals up before hand. That way it’s easier to stick to an eating schedule and actually gaining a healthy lifestyle.
 

 
Learn how to cook two things. Eggs and fish. Eggs are great protein. When cooking fish, put a little olive oil in the pan, be careful not to let it snap up and burn your bare arms, and drop the fish in. It cooks quickly, so keep an eye on it. Fish gets lighter when it’s cooked, from pink to whitish. Put some pepper, throw a lemon slice on it, and eat up!
 

 
If you’ve snacked on fruits and veggies all night and you’re still hungry, you probably need a little fat and protein. Eat a some cottage cheese, an egg or a spoonful of peanut butter, it should satiate you.
 

 
Don’t deny yourself. Craving ice cream? Do frozen yogurt! It’s still yummy and sweet.
 
Go darker for veggies. Pick spinach over lettuce. Make your own salad instead of a bag-of-salad.
 
Lack any and all skills in the kitchen? Make best friends with your blender. You can pick any combo of fruits and whip them up with some yogurt, ice cubes, and a little bit of juice to make a yummy snack.
 
If you don’t like veggies, sneak them into stuff – scramble, soup, burritos.
 
Reward yourself, but not with food. If you have a week of healthy breakfasts reward yourself with a movie or magazine that you really want.
 
Know what you are putting in your mouth! Become as educated as you can about ALL the food you&amp;your family is eating.
 
Have fresh fruits and veggies cut up and ready to go! Make sure it’s the first thing you reach for.
 
Make grocery lists!
 
Take a picture of your grocery cart in the store and post it to facebook, twitter or tumblr. Be accountable for what is in your cart.
 
 Have a trail mix (homemade) on hand. Nuts, cacao nibs, dried fruit&amp;berries are always good. 
 
Before you eat a snack, do something! Drink water, dance, work out for a few minutes, call a friend, play a game – stall!
 
Know your body. Learn about the biology of your body and what it is set up to eat and why. Learn about your intestines and your stomach, learn about the way your mouth is set up, understanding biology is really key to understand health.
 
Going on a road trip? Have a plan. Bring snacks. Check out the city you are going to and find the healthy grocery stores and restaurants.
 
Remember that your tastes do change if you let them. Give it a few weeks.
 
Slowly eliminate and slowly add. You will be amazed how much you can eat when you cut out the bad stuff.
 
Clean your kitchen every night! A clean sink is the goal. It’s more fun to cook if your kitchen is clean and you don’t have to start by doing the dishes.
 
Going to a gathering? Don’t compromise. If you have to, bring your own dish, or eat before you go.
 
Brush your teeth! After meals, or when you are tempted to snack (just because, not because you are hungry).
 
Eat only at the dinner table. If you eat in front of the TV or your computer you’re not thinking of what you’re eating and it’s easier to put bad stuff in your mouth.
 
Let vegetables, beans and lentils be the main dish. Don’t overcook them though as that makes them less nutritious.
 
Avocado is a great subsitute for butter on your bread.
 Eat a bowl of fruit and berries when you get sugar cravings. 

 



12 foods that are not eco-friendly

(source: woman’s day )

1. Rice

Rice is the major calorie source for half of the world’s population, but growing rice accounts for one-third of the planet’s annual freshwater use, according to Oxfam. Luckily, a new farming method known as System of Rice Intensification has been developed that enables farmers to produce up to 50 percent more rice with less water. Oxfam is working to get rice-producing countries to convert 25 percent of their rice cultivation to SRI by 2025.





2. Genetically modified foods

As with human health risks, it’s unlikely that all the potential environmental harms of genetically modified foods have been identified, but here are some of the main concerns about GMOs.

 Lower level of biodiversity: By making a crop resistant to a certain pest, the food sources for other animals could be removed. Also, the addition of foreign genes to plants could be toxic and endanger the animals that consume the plant. Spread of altered genes : Novel genes placed in crops won’t necessarily stay in designated agricultural fields. The genes can easily spread via pollen and share their altered genes with non-genetically modified plants. Creation of new diseases: Some GM foods are modified using bacteria and viruses, which means they could adapt and create new diseases. 





3. Sugar

More than 145 millions tons of sugar are produced in 121 countries each year, according to the World Wildlife Fund, and production on such a scale takes its toll on the Earth. Sugar may be responsible for more biodiversity loss than any other crop, according to a 2004 WWF “Sugar and the Environment” report, due to its habitat destruction, its intensive use of water and pesticides, and the polluted wastewater discharged during the production process. Thousands of acres of the Florida Everglades have been compromised after years of sugar cane farming — subtropical forests became lifeless marshland after excessive fertilizer runoff and irrigation drainage. Waters around the Great Barrier Reef are also suffering due to the large quantities of pesticides and sediment from sugar farms.





4. Meat

According to the Environmental Defense Fund, if every American substituted one meal of chicken with vegetarian food, the carbon dioxide savings would be the same as taking more than half a million cars off U.S. roads. Here are some of the U.N. Food and Agricultural Organization’s findings on meat and the environment:

 18 percent of greenhouse gas emissions come from livestock — more than from transportation. 70 percent of previously forested land in the Amazon was cleared to pasture cattle. The world’s largest source of water pollution is the livestock sector. Livestock are responsible for a third of the nitrogen and phosphorus in U.S. freshwater resources. Livestock account for about 20 percent of land animals, and the 30 percent of Earth’s land they occupy was once inhabited by wildlife. 





5. Fast food

Fast food is hurting more than just our waistlines. A typical fast-food meal often comes with overly packaged food, straws and plasticware, and an assortment of individually wrapped condiments. According to Californians Against Waste, less than 35 percent of fast-food waste is diverted from landfills even though most of it is recyclable paper and cardboard. So it’s no surprise that litter characterization studies have identified fast-food restaurants as the primary source of urban litter.

But it’s not just the packaging that’s a problem. A recent study found that a fast-food restaurant making four hamburgers emits the same amount of volatile organic compounds as driving a car 1,000 miles. If you calculate the carbon footprint of a cheeseburger, you’re in for a real shock: The greenhouse gas emissions arising each year from the production and consumption of cheeseburgers is roughly the amount emitted by 6.5 million to 19.6 million SUVs.





6. Foods that contain palm oil

Palm oil is found in an estimated 10 percent of U.S. groceries — it’s in chips, crackers, candy, margarine, cereals and canned goods. About 40 millions tons of palm oil, which is considered the cheapest cooking oil in the world, is produced each year, and 85 percent of it comes from Indonesia and Malaysia. In these countries, 30 square miles of forests are felled daily, and palm oil plantations account for the highest rates of deforestation in the world. When the rain forests disappear, so does almost all of the wildlife, including orangutans, tigers, bears and other endangered species.





7. Packaged and processed food

The majority of the food you’ll find in the grocery store is processed and packaged, which is bad news for the planet. Processed food contains multiple chemicals and often involves energy-intensive production processes. Plus, all that packaging typically ends up in a landfill, where plastic poisons the environment and can take thousands of years to break down. In fact, in 2006 the U.S. generated 14 million tons of plastic through packages and containers alone, according to the EPA. Unfortunately, even those eco-friendly packaged items made from cardboard are coated in a thin layer of plastic. The solution? Buy local, eat fresh fruits and vegetables, and buy foods like rice, oats and pasta from the bulk bins.





8. Many non-organic foods

Organic produce is grown without pesticides, which keeps chemicals from entering the water supply and helps prevent soil erosion. Organic farming also uses fewer resources than traditional farming. According to a study by The Rodale Institute, organic farming practices use 30 percent less energy and water than regular growing. In fact, a study by David Pimentel, a professor at Cornell University’s College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, found that growing corn and soybeans organically produced the same yields as conventional farming and used 33 percent less fuel. However, not all produce needs to be bought organic.





9. Some seafood

Fisheries analysts at the U.N. Food and Agricultural Organization report that 70 percent of the world’s fisheries are fully or overly exploited, depleted or in a state of collapse. Fish like bluefin and Atlantic salmon are severely overfished, and environmental groups are working to get them endangered species status. The overfishing of a particular species doesn’t damage that population alone — it can have serious effects further up the food chain and decrease biodiversity. Check out the Environmental Defense Fund’s seafood eco-ratings to determine what fish is safe for both you and our oceans.





10. White bread

It’s well known that whole grain and wheat breads are more nutritious than white bread, but brown breads are also less harmful to the environment. Wheat flour must be refined and go through a series of alteration processes to make white bread, but whole wheat flour spends less time in production. Any ingredient that requires extensive refining requires more energy and resources and has a greater impact on the planet.





11. High-fructose corn syrup foods

High-fructose corn syrup is one of the most environmentally damaging ingredients for a variety of reasons. Firstly, corn is grown as a monoculture, meaning the land is used solely for corn and not rotated, which depletes soil nutrients, contributes to erosion and requires more pesticides and fertilizer. The use of such chemicals contributes to problems like the Gulf of Mexico dead zone, an area of the ocean where nothing can live because the water is starved of oxygen, and atrazine, a common herbicide used on corn crops, has been shown to turn male frogs into hermaphrodites. Milling and chemically altering corn to produce high-fructose corn syrup is also an energy-intensive practice.





12. Much non-local food

Many people eat local for the freshness or to support the community, but the most widely touted benefit of local food is that it reduces fossil fuel consumption. According to the Leopold Center for Sustainable Agriculture, the average fresh food items on your dinner table travel 1,500 miles to get there. Although there’s disagreement over whether “food miles” are the best measure of a food’s carbon footprint, buying food at your local farmers market is one way to guarantee your food hasn’t traveled too far to get to your plate.



 



World’s Healthiest Foods

Vegetables

 Asparagus Avocados Beets Bell peppers Broccoli Brussels sprouts Cabbage Carrots Cauliflower Celery Collard greens Cucumbers Eggplant Fennel Garlic Green beans Green peas Kale Leeks Mushrooms, crimini Mushrooms, shiitake Mustard greens Olives Onions Potatoes Romaine lettuce Sea vegetables Spinach Squash, summer Squash, winter Sweet potatoes Swiss chard Tomatoes Turnip greens Yams 





Seafood

 Cod Halibut Salmon Sardines Scallops Shrimp Tuna 





Fruits&amp;Berries

 Apples Apricots Bananas Blueberries Cantaloupe Cranberries Figs Grapefruit Grapes Kiwi Lemons Limes Oranges Papaya Pears Pineapple Plums Prunes Raisins Raspberries Strawberries Watermelon 





Eggs&amp;Dairy

 Cheese Eggs Milk, cow Milk, goat Yogurt 





Beans&amp;Legumes

 Black beans Dried peas Garbanzo beans (chickpeas) Kidney beans Lentils Lima beans Miso Navy beans Pinto beans Soybeans Tempeh Tofu 





Poultry&amp;Lean Meats

 Beef, lean organic Calf’s liver Chicken Lamb Turkey Venison 

Nuts, Seeds&amp;Oils

 Almonds Cashews Flax seeds Olive oil, extra virgin Peanuts Pumpkin seeds Sesame seeds Sunflower seeds Walnuts 





Grains

 Barley Brown rice Buckwheat Corn Millet Oats Quinoa Rye Spelt Whole wheat 





Spices&amp;Herbs

 Basil Black pepper Cayenne pepper Chili pepper, dried Cilantro/Coriander seeds Cinnamon, ground Cloves Cumin seeds Dill Ginger Mustard seeds Oregano Parsley Peppermint Rosemary Sage Thyme Turmeric 





Natural Sweeteners

 Blackstrap molasses Cane juice Honey Maple syrup 





Other

 Green tea Soy sauce (tamari) Water 


 

 



 ▲ , , at : 
▲ 0  NOTES ▲ Permalink ▲ Reblog Leave a comment 







 Search 
navigation
 Personal food Healthy Eating Groceries Vegetarian, Vegan&amp;Raw Recipes Exercises Yoga Running Music Sleep&amp;Stress Tips&amp;Facts Tools&amp;Resources Quotes Need A Boost? 
disclaimer
I am not a nutritionist, trainer or doctor. If you ask me any questions you&apos;ll get my personal opinion, not a professional opinion.


Askbox

I am incredibly happy that so many people find this blog a source of inspiration and motivation. I love getting messages from followers. In fact, I do squeal every time there’s a number showing above my inbox icon. Let’s motivate and inspire each other! I am ready to change, are you?
 
 
 fly to Top Athenability
Design by Athenability
Powered by Tumblr
	</body>
</document>
