<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002412" url="http://www.toiletpaperplus.com.au/serviette-dispenser/2307947-tork-dispenser-fro-napkins-xpressnap-cafe-clear-black-n10" time="2012-07-12-18:20" support="1" score="0.00040712764480213814" bingtitle="Tork Dispenser for Napkins Xpressnap Cafe Clear Black N10" webtitle="Tork Dispenser for Napkins Xpressnap Cafe Clear Black N10">
			<query id="000399" bing-rank="223"/>
	<description>PURPOSE: GARBAGE BAGS: DISPENSERS: CLEANING SUPPLIES ... are preparing an elegant dinner or managing a fast food restaurant ... Plastic Cups; Hand Sanitisers; Serviettes; Sponges ...</description>
	<body>
		Home My Account FAQ&apos;s Free Delivery About Us Contact Us 
 Advanced Search 
 TOILET
PAPER HAND
TOWEL FACIAL
TISSUES SOAPS GENERAL
PURPOSE GARBAGE
BAGS DISPENSERS CLEANING
SUPPLIES 
 
 Dishwashing Liquid Dishwashing Powder Disinfectant Nappy Wash Laundry Detergent Cleaning Products Window Glass Cleaner 
 
 Toilet Rolls Jumbo Rolls Interleaved Toilet Tissue 
 
 Single Sheet Hand Towel Roll Hand Towel Kitchen Roll Hand Towel Centrefeed Towel Wipers 
 
 Dispensers DISPENSERS 
 
 Bulk Liquid Hand Soap Pod Soap Individual Hand Soap 
 
 Air Fresheners Gloves Microfibre Mops&amp;Buckets Plastic Cups Sanitisers Serviettes Sponges&amp;Scourers Sun Screen Wipes Rubbish Bins 
 
 Toilet Roll Dispensers Jumbo Roll Dispensers Interleaved Toilet
Tissue Dispensers Hand Towel Dispensers Air Freshener Dispensers Soap Dispensers Tissue Dispensers Wiper Dispensers Serviette Dispensers Sanitiser Dispensers 
 
 
Serviette Dispenser
 
 
 
Tork Dispenser for Napkins Xpressnap Cafe Clear Black N10
 
 Our Price: $40.60 (inc GST) 

 
 R.R.P: $60.50 
 

 
Description:


Whether you are preparing an elegant dinner or managing a fast food restaurant, Tork has the perfect napkin. The Tork napkin range caters for your needs from air-laid textile feel napkins through to Tork Xpressnap dispenser napkin systems. Why pay retail pricing, when you can buy quality products online from Toilet Paper Plus and save on the price of Tork Dispensers. Toilet Paper Plus offers fast, free delivery anywhere in Australia.
Please Note: Tork Dispensers may take up to seven days delivery.


Features:       

 Colour: Black Material: ABS Plastic  System: N10  New Tork Xpressnap Cafésaves on space, costs and napkin consumption  Ideal for use on individual tables and on counters where space is limited  Hygienic one-at-a-time napkin dispensing significantly decreases wastage and cost  Use the AD-a-Glance message display panel to promote your business, announce specials or events and generate revenue 


Details

 Product Code: 2307947

 Product Quantity: One Dispenser per Carton 

Similar Quality Products:
This product has no related products. 
 
   


 
 
LOGIN
Email Address
 Password
 
 Remember Me 
 
 Forgotten password? 
 
 My account | Logout GIFT VOUCHERS
AVAILABLE Toilet Paper 
 Toilet Rolls Jumbo Rolls Interleaved Toilet Tissue 
 Hand Towel 
 Single Sheet Hand Towel Roll Hand Towel Kitchen Roll Hand Towel Centrefeed Towel Wipers 
 Facial Tissue Soaps 
 Bulk Liquid Hand Soap Pod Soap Individual Hand Soap 
 General Purpose 
 Air Fresheners Gloves Microfibre Mops&amp;Buckets Plastic Cups Hand Sanitisers Serviettes Sponges&amp;Scourers Sun Screen Wipes Rubbish Bins 
 Garbage Bags Dispensers 
 Toilet Roll Jumbo Roll Interleaved Toilet Tissue Hand Towel Air Freshener Soap Tissue Wiper Serviette Sanitiser 
 Cleaning Supplies 
 Dishwashing Liquid Dishwashing Powder Disinfectant Nappy Wash Laundry Detergent Spray and Wipe Window Cleaner 
 
 TERMS&amp;CONDITIONS | PRIVACY POLICY 

©2011 TOILET PAPER PLUS 2010

Site Design by www.kirstycurnow.com
	</body>
</document>
