<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002162" url="http://notalwaysright.com/page/40" time="2012-07-12-18:03" support="13" score="0.023222922060121016" bingtitle="Funny &amp; Stupid Customer Stories – Not Always Right" webtitle="FunnyStupid Customer StoriesNot Always Right">
			<query id="000238" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="000275" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000276" bing-rank="195"/>
			<query id="000270" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="000586" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="001252" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="000112" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001493" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="000934" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="001189" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000250" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000959" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="000576" bing-rank="95"/>
	<description>Fast Food, Restaurant | Ontario, Canada | Food &amp; Drink ... Me: “Since you’re using a credit card, I need to see your ...</description>
	<body>
		Add Your Quote!  |  About/FAQ   Contact  |  Top   Random   Hall of Fame  |  Extras  |  Store Featured Story: 
 Never Say No To La Novia (1,857 thumbs up) FOR SALE: 
 The YAM Network (Auction ends Thursday, July 12, 2012!) 
 Some People Aren’t Backward Compatible 
 library | Ohio, USA | Extra Stupid , Technology 
 (I work at a public library. Patrons often ask us how to print from the computers.) 

 Patron: “I need to pay for my printing.”

 Me: “Okay. When you hit the print button, how much did it say it was going to cost?”

 Patron: “I did not hit the print button.”

 Me: “What computer were you sitting at?”

 Patron: *impatient* “I was not sitting at a computer. I am trying to print from the typewriter!”

 Me: “I’m sorry, I am confused. You were not sitting at a computer, but at the typewriter? And you want to print what you typed?”

 Patron: “This is ridiculous! I cannot believe you won’t help me!” *leaves* 
 ( 750 Thumbs Up!) 
 Young (At Heart), Wild, And Free 
 Airport | Seattle, WA, USA | Rude&amp;Risque 
 (I am doing a pat down on an older woman in a wheelchair. As I clear each area, I’m letting the woman know that I am moving to a new area. Fairly quickly, it becomes obvious that the woman is intoxicated.) 

 Me: “Okay, ma’am, I’m going to clear your back now.”

 Woman: *throws her arms out and says quite loudly* “Honey, I’m loaded! You can do whatever you want to me!”
 ( 589 Thumbs Up!) 
 Try Wallmart 
 Furniture Store | Queensland, Australia | Crazy Requests 
 (I work in the kitchen department of a furniture store.) 

 Customer: “This kitchen says $899.00. What do you get for that price?”

 Me: “Well, miss, that price covers kitchen cabinets, a bench top, legs and handles, but not the sink, tap or appliances.”

 Customer: “So, you get everything?”

 Me: “Everything except the sink, tap, and appliances.”

 Customer: “Oh, so you don’t get the sink, tap, or appliances, but everything else?”

 Me: “Yep, everything else in that kitchen.”

 Customer: “So, you get the wall?”

 Me: “No…the wall is not included.”

 Customer: “But it says everything except the sink, tap, and appliances. It doesn’t say you don’t get the wall.”

 Me: “Ma’am, I assure you, I am confident that I cannot sell you our wall.”

 Customer: “Are you sure? Can you check for me please? Can you just make sure because that’s not what it says.”

 Me: *speechless* “I’ll get my manager.”

 Manager: “No, ma’am, the walls are not included with the price of our kitchens. Otherwise, we could only sell four of them before we’d need to rebuild the entire store.”
 ( 944 Thumbs Up!) 
 Together And Equal 
 Retail | Billings, MT, USA | At The Checkout , Top 
 (I am a cashier. Sometimes people will go through a checkout line sharing a cart. Two middle-aged women come through the line.) 

 Me: *pointing at their purchases* “Are you two together?”

 (Woman #1 looks lovingly into Woman #2′s eyes and holds her hands.) 

 Woman #1: “Yes, we are…”

 Woman #2: “Honey, I think she meant if we’re buying all this together.”

 Woman #1: “Oh. No, we’re separate. Two transactions, please!”
 ( 1,464 Thumbs Up!) 
 How About Some Split Pee Soup 
 Restaurant | San Diego, CA, USA | Food&amp;Drink , Language&amp;Words 
 Customer: “I’d like a latrine!”

 Me: “Oh, okay, the bathroom is just—”

 Customer: “No! How much is a latrine?”

 Me: “Well, ma’am, there’s no charge for using the—”

 Customer: “No! Of soup! How much?”

 Me: “OH! A tureen!”

 Customer: “Yes, how much is a latrine of soup?”
 ( 711 Thumbs Up!) 
 Just Gender Role With It 
 Convenience Store | New Berlin, WI, USA | Children , Parents , Top 
 (I work in a gas station and am the only female employee that works the second shift on a regular basis. I have very short hair and am often mistaken for male if customers aren’t paying attention. Sometimes, it is a great source of amusement for me because it seems to bother them more than it bothers me. One early evening, a customer comes in with her little girl who is probably about 4.) 

 Me: “Did you find everything all right?”

 Customer: “Yeah, just this and…” *to her daughter* “Did you find the candy you want, sweetie?”

 (I notice now that the little girl is giving me a horrified look as if I have just told her there is no Santa.) 

 Customer’s Daughter: *starts pulling on her mother’s shirt* “Mommy! Mommy! Is that a boy or a girl?”

 (The mother ignores her, but the little girl continues to ask and gets progressively louder each time. I am finishing running her credit card and hand her the receipt. At the top of every receipt is the name of the cashier. The woman picks up her daughter who is now glaring at me and finally answers her after reading my obviously female name.) 

 Customer’s Daughter: *now yelling so loud everyone in the store can hear* “MOMMY!!! IS IT A BOY OR A GIRL?!”

 Customer: “Shh! She’s a girl, sweetie. Now hush.”

 (I’m trying very hard not to laugh, as everyone in the store is now staring.) 

 Me: “Mystery solved! Have a good—”

 Customer’s Daughter: *shrieking* “WHY DOES SHE HAVE SUCH SHORT HAIR?!”

 Customer: *turning six shades of red* “Because some women just like their hair to be short.”

 (The customer’s daughter turns to me and points accusingly.) 

 Customer’s Daughter: “YOU! You shouldn’t have such short hair! Girls have long hair! DUH!”

 (After the woman has left with her boisterous, opinionated child in tow, a regular customer comes to my register.) 

 Regular: *jokingly* “Well, hello again, young man! Having a good evening?”
 ( 1,372 Thumbs Up!) 
 No Recognition Or Cognition 
 Computer Store | Canada | Language&amp;Words , Technology 
 (A customer comes in asking for dictation software. I showed him a very popular dictation package.) 

 Customer: “Does that use voice recognition?”

 Me: “Yes, it does.”

 Customer: “Oh, I don’t want that! Voice recognition doesn’t work. Do you have any dictation software that doesn’t use voice recognition?”

 Me: “No, we do not.”

 Customer: *looks annoyed and leaves* 
 ( 634 Thumbs Up!) 
 Thanks For Shopping At Las Saggy Knees 
 Supermarket | Peterborough, UK | Food&amp;Drink , Language&amp;Words 
 Customer: “Excuse me, do you have any las-ange?”

 Me: “Las-ange?”

 Customer: “Yes, it says on my list,‘las-ange.’”

 (He shows me a shopping list with the word‘lasagne’written on it.) 

 Me: *showing him lasagna* “Here’s the lasagna.”

 Customer: “No, no! That’s lasag-knee. I want las-ange.”

 Me: “Well, lasag-knee is the same as las-ange.”

 Customer: “Hmm, I’d better leave it. I don’t want to upset the misses by getting the wrong stuff!”
 ( 623 Thumbs Up!) Page 40/819 First « ... 38 39 40 41 42 ... » Last 
 
19,759
Fans 
5,025
Followers 
10,881
Subscribers 
 
Navigate
 Announcements At The Checkout Awesome Customers Bigotry Bizarre Body Problems Bookstore Canada Children Coffee Shop Comics Comics Single Crazy Requests Criminal/Illegal Extra Stupid Extras Food&amp;Drink Funny Names Geeks Rule Geography Health&amp;Sickness History Holidays Home Improvement Hotels&amp;Lodging Language&amp;Words Liars&amp;Scammers Love/Romance Married Customers Math&amp;Science Money Issues Movie Theater Musical Mayhem Old Comics One-Liners Parents Pets&amp;Animals Physical Politics Religion Roundups RSS-Announce Rude&amp;Risque Students Technology Theme Time Top Tourists/Travel Uncategorized Underaged Xcluded View by Job 911 Airline Airport Animal Shelter Announcements Apartment Complex Aquarium Arcade Art Gallery Artist Auto Mechanic Auto Parts Baby Store Bail Bonds Bakery Bank Bar Beach Beauty Salon Blood Bank Boat Rental Bookstore Bowling Alley Bridal Store Buffet Bus Cable Company Cafe Call Center Camera Shop Camera Store Camp Candy Shop Car Dealership Card Shop Car Rental Car Wash Cash Advance Casino Catering Cellphone Store Charity Check Cashing Chemist Child Care Chocolate Shop Church Clinic Clothing Store Coffee Shop College Comic Book Store comic store Computer Lab Computer Repair Computer Store Concert Hall Concession Stand Construction Contractor Convenience Store Copy Shop Costume Shop Country Club Craft Store Cruise Ship Customer Service Dance Studio Daycare Day Spa Deli Dentist Department Store DMV Doctor Dog Daycare Dog Kennel Dollar Store Donut Shop Drug Store Drugstore Dry Cleaner Electronics Repair electronics store EMT Fabric Store Farm Farmer&apos;s Market Fast Food Fencing Club Ferry Fish Store Flea Market flooring company Florist Flower Shop Frozen Yogurt Shop Furniture Store Garden Store Gas Station Gift Shop Golf Course Government Graphic Design Grocery Grocery Store Gun Store Gym Hair Salon Hardware Store Help Desk Highway Patrol home home furnishings home furnishings store home improvement Home Security Hospital Hotel Ice Cream Shop Ice Cream Store Insurance Internet Cafe Investment Firm ISP Jewelry Store Key Shop Landscaper Laundromat Law Firm Lawn Care Lemonade Stand library lifeguard Lingerie Store Liquor Store Locksmith Mall Marina Marine Biologist Massage Medical Office Military Miscellaneous Morgue Mortgage Company Movie Theater Museum Music Festival Music Store newspaper Non-Profit Nursing Home Office Office Supply Store Online Store Optometrist Outdoor Supply Store Paintball Field Paramedic Park Parking Lot Party Planner Party Store Party Supply Store Pawn Shop Pest control Pet Groomer Pet Hotel Pet Store Pharmacy Phone Company Photo Lab Pizza Pizza Delivery Pizza Place Plant Nursery Plumber Police Polling Station Pool Pool Maintenance Pool Supply Porn Billing Portrait Studio Post Office Power Company Print Shop Private School Property Management Publishing Radio Station Real Estate Recording Studio Record Store repair shop Resort Restaurant Retail Retirement Home Roadside assistance Sales Sandwich Shop School Security Self Storage Shipping Company Shoe Store Sign Installer Ski Resort Smoke Shop Smoothie Shop Snack Bar Software Company Souvenir Store Sporting Goods Store Summer Camp Supermarket Tanning Salon Tattoo Parlor Taxi Tax Preparer Tea Shop Tech Support Telemarketing theater Theatre Theme Park Thrift Store Ticket Sales Tire Center Tour Tour Guide Tourist Attraction Toy Store Train Station Travel Agency Travel Store Tree Nursery Tutor TV Studio University Vet Video Editor Video Game Store Video Rental Video Rental Store Video Store Vitamin Store Water Park Web Design Well Driller Wine Store Zombies Zoo View by Month July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 
Not Always Sites

 Not Always Romantic Not Always Related Not Always Working 
Friends

 The Awesomer Passive Aggressive Notes Retail Hell 

Archives
 
 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 
 
Most Viewed Stories

 Why Barkeeps Should Rule The World 19823 views Scamming In Plain Sight 16245 views Coming To A Theater Near You: Gangsta Ushers 15614 views Choose Your Battles 14569 views Don’t Mess With The Candyland Gang 14165 views Fighting Fire With Fire 9399 views The Road To Yell(ing) Is Paved With Good Intentions 7101 views Human Watching 5118 views For My Next Trick… 4220 views Who Needs Enemies When You’ve Got Bricks 3033 views 
 

 
Not Always Right Poll
Sorry, there are no polls available at the moment. 

 
 
 
About Not Always Right

Not Always Right features funny&amp;stupid customer stories that show the customer is NOT always right! More... 

 About/FAQ 
 Press 
 Contact 
 Term of Use 
 Privacy Policy 
 Send Us An Extras/FB/Twitter Tip 
 Link To Us 
 Apps 

Copyright 2007-2012 NotAlwaysRight.com 
Subscribe&amp;Follow

 Facebook 
 Twitter 
 RSS 
 Email Subscription 


Network Sites

 Not Always Romantic 
 Not Always Related 
 Not Always Working 

 IYAMLOL 
 IYAMCHEAP 
 IYAMYOURS 
 IYAMBAD 
 IYAMHEALTHY 
June 2012 Top Referrers


 Passive Aggressive Notes Etiquette Hell Retail Hell Underground Consumerist STFU Parents Customers Suck! You Are Not A Photographer Funny Junk The Mary Sue Tech Comedy 

 Join Our Top Referrer Program!
	</body>
</document>
