<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002455" url="http://www.ketknbc.com/marijuana-bust-in-rusk-county" time="2012-07-12-18:30" support="2" score="0.0018848141946196505" bingtitle="Marijuana bust in Rusk County | KETK" webtitle="Marijuana bust in Rusk County  | KETK">
			<query id="000207" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000519" bing-rank="153"/>
	<description>Car crashes into fast food restaurant in Tyler ... There was also several plant trays discovered throughout the home ...</description>
	<body>
		Contact Us News Team Jobs 
 Search Home 
Connect with us:

 KETK on Facebook KETK on Twitter Subscribe to our RSS feeds Connect with Mobile Devices 
 
 login register 
 
 News 
 Local News 
 Tyler News Longview News Jacksonville News Lufkin News Nacogdoches News Kilgore News Henderson News 
 Regional News National News World News Decision 2012 Neal Barton&apos;s POV 
 What&apos;s your POV? 
 Hitting the Road TalkBack with Garth Maier Crime Watch Mike&apos;s Mail Bag Money Matters **NEW** News Clips Weird News 
 Weather 
 NEW Interactive Radar Radar Seven Day Forecast Dayplanner Temperatures Watches&amp;Warnings National Temperatures East Texas Burn Bans 
 Sports 
 2012 Olympics 
 Olympics Zone 
 HS Football HS Football Scoreboard 
 East Texas Live 
 Contact East Texas Live One Big Happy Table 
 Community 
 Contests Upcoming Events 
 Submit an Event 
 See It. Shoot It. Share It. Photo Galleries 
 Upload Photos 
 TylerWatch Holiday Vacations - Enchanting Ireland with Bob Brackeen 
 On TV 
 KETK News Team TV Schedule NBC Full Episodes 
 Linked 
 
 Breaking News 
 &apos;Loan Ranger&apos;strikes again! Posted: Thursday, July 12, 2012 - 10:57am 
Marijuana bust in Rusk County
 
Rusk County Sheriff&apos;s Office
 
 Share 
 
 Tweet Share on Facebook Email this page Print this page 
 Report a Problem 
ADVERTISMENT
 2 Comments 
 POSTED: Thursday, February 16, 2012 - 3:57pm

 UPDATED: Thursday, February 16, 2012 - 10:03pm
 
Related
 
 Suspect Arraigned for 2nd Degree Felony Possession of Marijuana UPDATE: Rusk County drug suspects are arraigned Rusk County deputy finds 5 pounds of pot in SUV Shooter identified in alleged Rusk County hunting accident Rusk County drug bust 
 
 Rusk County— On Wednesday, February 15, at approximately 12 pm, a traffic stop conducted by Rusk County Sheriff’s Office, K-9 Deputy, Jason Smith, led to the arrest of the driver when approximately 1 ounce of marijuana was discovered. This traffic stop led to an investigation and discovery of more drugs located at the driver’s residence
.
During an interview with the driver, Billy Gene Gatlin, 27, of Overton, admitted to selling drugs which led to a further investigation involving the suspect’s residence. A short time later the suspect consented to the search at his residence, in the 9000 block of Hwy 323, in New London.

The Rusk County Sheriff’s Office Narcotic Officers searched the suspect’s residence. During the search approximately¼pound of marijuana, scales and a firearm was discovered in a bedroom. There was also several plant trays discovered throughout the home, which contained marijuana seedlings.

Gatlin was arrested and charged with Delivery of Marijuana, and Possession of Marijuana, both State Jail Felonies. He was arraigned today by Precinct 5, Justice of the Peace, Joe Sorrells, with a $10,000 bond set for each charge. The suspect was later released after posting bond.

Sheriff Danny R. Pirtle stated this was a job well done by all law enforcement involved and we appreciate the Overton Police Chief Clyde Carter and Captain Clayton Taylor for their assistance in this investigation.



 
 YouTube Video:  No YouTube 
Comments News Comments 
 
cannadude February 16, 2012
at 4:45pm 
 
Save that jail space for violent criminals. Stop wasting our money and ruining lives.
 
 reply 
 
Freedom February 16, 2012
at 3:52pm 
 
More of our tax money wasted on a victimless crime. We would save a ton of money (and jail space) if we regulated it like wine.
 
 reply 
 Post new Comment You have 500 characters left. Login or Register 
You must login or register to post this item.
 I have a username&amp;password I am a new user and would like to register Username: Enter your KETK username. Password: Enter the password that accompanies your username. Choose a Username: Spaces are allowed; punctuation is not allowed except for periods, hyphens, and underscores. E-mail address: A valid e-mail address. All e-mails from the system will be sent to this address. The e-mail address is not made public and will only be used if you wish to receive a new password or wish to receive certain news or notifications by e-mail. Password: Confirm password: Provide a password for the new account in both fields.   East Texas Weather 
81°F

Overcast

High: 88°F Low: 70°F 

Wind: NE at 7 mph

 More Weather | Radar | 7 Day Forecast | Dayplanner 
 
ADVERTISMENT
 
 Special Features 
 See It. Shoot It. Share It. Sponsored by GRANT&amp;FLANERY TalkBack with Garth Maier Sponsored by CASH NOW Money Matters Sponsored by Texas Financial and Retirement KETK Student of the Year Nominations Win a 40 inch HDTV! 
 Special Reports 
 Run your car on natural gas The Changing Word 
ADVERTISEMENT
 
 Privacy Policy Terms of Service Closed Captioning Public Files 
 
KETK NBC

4300 Richmond Road
Tyler, Texas 75703
 TEL: (903) 581-5656
 FAX: (903) 561-2459
 EMAIL: info@ketknbc.com 
 
 News 
 Weather Local News National News World News Neal Barton&apos;s POV East Texas Live TalkBack Sports News 
 Community 
 Events See It. Shoot It. Share It. Photo Galleries Contests 
 
 
 KETK on Facebook KETK on Twitter Subscribe to our RSS feeds Connect with Mobile Devices 
 
 Contact Us News Team Jobs 

Copyright©2012 ComCorp of Tyler, Inc. All Rights Reserved
	</body>
</document>
