<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002786" url="http://ca.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20100208095649AA4id3m" time="2012-07-12-18:50" support="8" score="0.010505641773819217" bingtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - How much does a person who washes the ..." webtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - How much does a person who washes the dishes earn in a fastfood restraurant?">
			<query id="000764" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="001012" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="001452" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="000770" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="001043" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000760" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000774" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="000229" bing-rank="218"/>
	<description>... used to work washing dishes in a fast food restaurant, a very ... However, there are still trays and cooking ... the most delicious food that you have ever put ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Canada Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog (USA) 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Food&amp;Drink &gt; Ethnic Cuisine &gt; Resolved Question 
 verynear Member since: January 13, 2010 Total points: 96 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
How much does a person who washes the dishes earn in a fastfood restraurant?
 Hi
I want to know how much a very simple worker can earn each day for doing simple works such as washing the dishes in a restaurant ....
thanks 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Rita Ricenberg Member since: February 11, 2010 Total points: 1,158 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 My current housekeeper used to work washing dishes in a fast food restaurant, a very big and famous one. She was working during evening hours and according to her the pay per hour was 9 dollars for the first 8 hours and then 10 for additional hours. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 100% 1 Vote 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (7)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Nonparti... Member since: October 08, 2009 Total points: 5,081 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Fast food hardly as any dishes, because everything is paper and cardboard. However, there are still trays and cooking equipment that need washing.

I was a dishwasher in several real restaurants for a few years. You&apos;ll be working cleaning towers of dishes, cooking equipment, empty fryers, help cooking sometimes, and might even bus a table a few times.

Often your working later that ANY of the chefs.

Personally I think working at a Old Folks Home is the way too go, because of the health benefits that go with it and the hours are usually more that of a normal job.

You can expect to make minimum wage, usually no more than that. Even at a 5 star restaurant. Sometimes though the dishwashers and waiters share tips, but this is RARE. If you have a cool boss sometimes they will have tones of soda cans you could recycle for extra money. A few restaurants I worked at didn&apos;t have the time to take care of them. So I did it for them and made about $50 extra a week.

Some scummy restaurants will pay you under the table, which I honestly would avoid. If the owner can&apos;t do things by the law its only a mater of time before they are caught and your out of a job. Plus you won&apos;t get a real job reference, no taxes back at the end of the year, and usually pays less. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by WickedGo... Member since: June 07, 2009 Total points: 93,590 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Minimum wage, plus all the&quot;bus-tray buffet&quot;you can eat!

(You should read Pete Jordan&apos;s excellent book on the subject,&quot;Dishwasher&quot;, or at least visit his website...
 http://www.dishwasherpete.com/ ) 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by ~ Floridian`` Member since: July 21, 2007 Total points: 64,127 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Can&apos;t be much, minimum wage, because fast food places use almost totally throw away plates, cups, etc.!!! 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Janet❤ Member since: June 09, 2009 Total points: 1,177 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Minimum wage.period. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by chefgril... Member since: August 30, 2006 Total points: 135,413 (Level 7) Badge Image: 
 Add Contact Block 
 Whatever the minimum wage is in your state. 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by tingtang... Member since: September 17, 2009 Total points: 344 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 minimum wage 
Source(s):
 ive tried this job 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by fryed_sm... Member since: November 03, 2008 Total points: 1,066 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Depends on where you live! My brother lives in Culpeper VA and is 16. He earns 7.35 an hour. Hope I helped! 
 2 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 
Discover Questions in Ethnic Cuisine 

 Favorite punjabi food? Is stuffed mushrooms and spaghetti a good combination? I have a bowl of pasta, but the sauce portion has run out. What should I do? Is it ok to reheat rice with a little water on the day after cooking.? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Food&amp;Drink 
 Beer, Wine&amp;Spirits Cooking&amp;Recipes Entertaining Ethnic Cuisine Non-Alcoholic Drinks Other - Food&amp;Drink Vegetarian&amp;Vegan 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Canada Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Canada Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines
	</body>
</document>
