<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002244" url="http://www.usatoday.com/money/industries/food/2009-12-10-cheapeats10_ST_N.htm" time="2012-07-12-18:08" support="1" score="0.0021864212654967986" bingtitle="McDonald&apos;s, Burger King, Taco Bell add to fast food value deals ..." webtitle="McDonald&apos;s, Burger King, Taco Bell add to fast food value deals - USATODAY.com">
			<query id="001439" bing-rank="197"/>
	<description>Change in third-quarter sales vs. a year earlier: ... plans to nationally roll out a Dollar Breakfast Menu ... obviously feeling the need to make every dollar count ...</description>
	<body>
		Cars     Auto 
 Financing     Event 
 Tickets     Jobs     Real 
 Estate     Online 
 Degrees     Business Opportunities Shopping 
 Search How do I find it? Subscribe to paper   
 
 
 
 
 
 Home News Travel Money Sports Life Tech Weather 
 
 Money Markets 
 Markets Home Mutual Funds ETFs Most Active Stocks Commodities Currencies Key Interest Rates Internet 50 Stock Market Answers: Ask Matt World Stocks Free Annual Reports 
 Economy 
 Economy Home Economic Calendar Jobs 
 Companies/Execs 
 Executive Suite Company News Company Calendars Annual Reports Jobs 
 Personal Finance 
 Personal Finance Home Mutual Funds ETFs Retirement Taxes Mortgage Rates CD and Savings Rates Your Money: Sandra Block Investing: John Waggoner Your Portfolio Calculators Free Annual Reports 
 Mutual Funds ETFs Cars 
 Cars Home Drive On community Test Drive: James R. Healey Video Reviews Research a Car Buy a Car Sell a Car Incentives Recalls Other Reviews 
 Real Estate 
 Real Estate Home Find a Realtor Sell It Yourself Home Value Apartments Moving Home Improvement 
 Small Business 
 Small Business Home Ask an Expert: Steve Strauss Entrepreneurial Tightrope: Gladys Edmunds Strategies: Rhonda Abrams Franchises 
 
 
 GET A QUOTE: 
 
 
 
 
 
   What&apos;s 
 this? 
 
 

Search hundreds of franchises and business opportunities to find the one that is right for you. Find a franchise: 
 Select Category All Automotive Business Services Children&apos;s Services Cleaning Services Computer&amp;Internet Food&amp;Restaurants Health&amp;Beauty Home Services Onsite Services Retail Sports&amp;Leisure Travel&amp;Lodging 
 Select Investment Up to $10,000 Up to $25,000 Up to $50,000 Up to $100,000 Up to $150,000 Up to $200,000 Over $200,000 All Levels   
 
 Quick Request Form:
 Request information from your favorite 
 franchises and business opportunities.  Click here 
 
 
 McDonald&apos;s, Burger King, Taco Bell add to fast food value deals 

 Updated  |  Comment  |  Recommend E-mail | Print | 
 
 
 
   Enlarge McDonald&apos;s McDonald&apos;s new Mac Snack Wrap has Big Mac&apos;s ingredients rolled into a tortilla for a $1.49. 
 
 
 
  FAST FOOD GIANTS 
 Fast-food chains are offering deals to boost sagging same-store sales. Change in third-quarter sales vs. a year earlier: McDonald&apos;s 1 2.5% Wendy&apos;s 2 0.1% KFC -2.0% Taco Bell -2.0% Burger King -4.6% Arby&apos;s 2 -6.5% Pizza Hut -13.0% 1 - U.S. only; 2 - company units; Source: Technomic 
 
 
 
 By Bruce Horovitz, USA TODAY Fast food&apos;s sales hook in 2010 will be just two words: Eat cheap. 
Many big names in fast food are rolling out products geared to drag in slow-to-spend consumers. Today, McDonald &apos;s makes official plans to nationally roll out a Dollar Breakfast Menu in January. Burger King is trying to dazzle eaters with $1 double cheeseburgers.

The moves come at a time when fast-food giants—many of which initially benefited from the financial meltdown—are seeing sales erode. As a category, fast food has faced falling sales for 28 of the past 30 weeks, reports NPD. McDonald&apos;s on Tuesday reported its second-consecutive monthly same-store sales dip in the U.S.

&quot;It&apos;s a tough economic situation out there, and the fast-food pie has shrunk,&quot; says Ron Paul , president of Technomic, a consulting firm. Because of high unemployment, he says, consumers are increasingly hitting grocery stores and &quot;turning on their ovens again.&quot;

While value offerings are common in the slow winter season, the scope of the deals show the cold realities this winter:
 
 •McDonald&apos;s. Pushing value on two fronts, it&apos;s unwrapping its value breakfast two years after Burger King unveiled one. &quot;Our customers are obviously feeling the need to make every dollar count,&quot; says Neil Golden, chief marketing officer. With fewer folks working, fewer eat breakfast out. Among items to be sold for $1: Sausage McMuffin, hash browns and 12-ounce coffee.

McDonald&apos;s also will roll out Mac Snack Wrap, which has Big Mac&apos;s ingredients rolled into a tortilla. At $1.49, it&apos;s half the price of a Big Mac.

 •Burger King. Since October, it has sold $1 double cheeseburgers, &quot;the strongest value for the money in the marketplace,&quot; says new products chief John Schaufelberger. A franchisee group sued, saying owners lose money at that price.

 FOOD FIGHT: Burger King franchisees sue chain over $1 promotion 

Burger King is testing other $1 items. One is The Little Enormous Sandwich, made with egg, sausage, cheese, hash browns and bacon. There&apos;s a $1 chicken sandwich. And it&apos;s testing its BK Breakfast Muffin, which sells for $1 vs. $2.49 for an Egg McMuffin at McDonald&apos;s.

 • Taco Bell . In a down market, &quot;Everyone plays value,&quot; says David Ovens, chief marketing officer. In two weeks, it rolls out an 89-cent Beefy 5-Layer Burrito. In February, it rolls out the Five Bucks Box with four food items and a medium drink. It has begun very limited tests of value breakfast deals with its 79-cent, 89-cent and 99-cent menus.
 
 Posted Updated E-mail | Print | To report corrections and clarifications, contact Reader Editor Brent Jones . For publication consideration in the newspaper, send comments to letters@usatoday.com . Include name, phone number, city and state for verification. To view our corrections, go to corrections.usatoday.com . 
 Guidelines: You share in the USA TODAY community, so please keep your comments smart and civil. Don&apos;t attack other readers personally, and keep your language decent. Use the &quot;Report Abuse&quot; button to make a difference. Read more . Newspaper Home Delivery - Subscribe Today 
 Home • News • Travel • Money • Sports • Life • Tech • Weather 
 About USATODAY.com: Site Map | FAQ | Contact Us | Jobs with Us | Terms of Service 
 Privacy Policy/Your California Privacy Right | Advertise | Press Room | Developer | Media Lounge | Reprints and Permissions News Your Way:   Mobile News |   Email News |   Add USATODAY.com RSS feeds |   Twitter |   Podcasts |     Widgets Partners: USA WEEKEND | Sports Weekly | Education | Space.com | Travel Tips 
 Copyright 2011 USA TODAY, a division of Gannett Co. Inc.
	</body>
</document>
