<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002720" url="http://thestir.cafemom.com/food_party/124728/gross_thing_23459_about_fast" time="2012-07-12-18:47" support="4" score="0.009855936804343993" bingtitle="Gross Thing 23,459 About Fast Food Joints | The Stir" webtitle="Gross Thing 23,459 About Fast Food Joints | The Stir">
			<query id="000436" bing-rank="209"/>
			<query id="000170" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000419" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000416" bing-rank="217"/>
	<description>I mean really, a fast food restaurant was found to have ... same conditions apply on the other side of the counter. ... Receive our Hottest Stories Daily</description>
	<body>
		Cafemom 
 Mom Groups&amp;Conversations Videos for Moms The Stir 

 Log In Join Now 
 The Stir 
 Pregnancy Baby Toddler Big Kid Teen Food &amp; Party Healthy Living Love &amp; Sex In The News 

 Entertainment Sports Technology Beauty &amp; Style Home &amp; Garden Writers Columns 
 Search Cafemom&apos;s The Stir 
 Facebook Twitter Pintrest YouTube RSS 
 BUZZING Giveaways Moms Matter 2012 Recipe a Day Summer Family Fun More 
 How Your Astrological Sign Can Help Plan Your Vacation Suri&apos;s Scientology Childhood Sounds Kind of Awesome One Simple Way to Lose Weight Must See: Mom Gives Baby Yucky Peas (VIDEO) These Couples Would Make &apos;50 Shades of Grey&apos; Even Hotter (PHOTOS) Is This Republican Protest of Michelle Obama Racist? 15 Things I Would Tell My 15-Year-Old Self Natural Remedies for Migraines (VIDEO) 20 Most Bizarre Celebrity Aliases 9 Things Not to Say to a Vegetarian 52 Wackiest Celeb Baby Names of All Time Adorable&amp;Delicious Watermelon Cupcakes 7 Most Annoying Internet Sensations (VIDEO) 5 Cheap Ways to Fight Cellulite Reality Show About Extended Breastfeeding: Good Idea? 
 
 Food &amp; Party 
 
Gross Thing 23,459 About Fast Food Joints
 Posted by Adriana Velez on August 19, 2011 at 10:22 AM 
 Comments (8) | Likes (2) 
 
 A Burger King in Chicago was recently shut down by health inspectors when they found over 200 species of flying bugs all over the place. That&apos;s not 200 bugs, that&apos;s 200 different kinds of bugs. Imagine thousands of sticky little feet landing on the soda machines, the toilets, the burgers waiting for pick-up, the collective buzz as clouds of winged insects crowd over a dropped French fry. I&apos;ll pause now while you shudder in horror.

As grossed-out as I was when I first heard this story, I wasn&apos;t at all surprised. I mean really, a fast food restaurant was found to have filthy conditions? I&apos;m shocked, shocked!

Isn&apos;t this what we&apos;ve come to expect from fast food joints? We&apos;ve just heard about the mom crusading against filthy playlands . If the tables and playground are dirty, it goes without saying that the same conditions apply on the other side of the counter. In fact, it&apos;s probably even dirtier in those kitchens.

Here&apos;s the scariest part of the story: the Great Winged Infestation of Chicago wasn&apos;t discovered by a routine inspection. It was discovered after a concerned customer made a complaint call. Oh wait, actually, the wasp nest found hanging over the back door is equally scary. But my point is, the underfunded city agencies in charge of regularly inspecting restaurants don&apos;t have the time or resources to check every restaurant regularly. 

You would think that as industrialized as fast food has become, where food is not so much cooked as re-heated, there would be more time to focus on sanitation. But the opposite seems to be happening. No point lining a sow&apos;s ear with silk, right? Sure higher-end restaurants get caught with unsanitary conditions too, but in general, they&apos;re usually cleaner. And before we all pile on the employees of this Burger King, I think responsibility goes much higher. Obviously the manager is a slacker. But is anyone at BK Corporate sending out a message to managers and franchise owners that they need to clean up their act?

I already never eat fast food. But who cares what I do. What I&apos;m really wondering is, will other people read about the BK infestation and keep eating at fast food restaurants anyway? Is this something we&apos;re ready to face, or do we want to be kept in the dark?

 Has the Burger King infestation story turned you off of fast food? 

 
 

 Image via Burning Image /Flickr 
 About the author Adriana Velez 
 is a staff writer who dabbles in food, parenting, news, entertainment, molecular biology, and anything else that that pops into her head. She lives with her husband and elementary school-aged son in Brooklyn, land of urban farms and artisan everything.  
 More Filed Under: chain restaurants , eating out , food safety , in the news 
 Comments (8) | Likes (2) 
 Extra Sugar 
 
Featured Videos

 After Losing Her Hair to Chemo,... Sex Myths Debunked 5 Guys and a Breast Pump! A Day at the Museum with Her Two Moms 
 Tasty Treats from Our Partners
	</body>
</document>
