<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002025" url="http://www.neatorama.com/2009/02/14/why-you-may-not-want-to-let-your-friends-eat-at-mcdonalds-or-yourself/" time="2012-07-12-17:56" support="3" score="0.00561976159584994" bingtitle="Why You May Not Want to Let Your Friends Eat at McDonalds (or ..." webtitle="Why You May Not Want to Let Your Friends Eat at McDonalds (or Yourself)">
			<query id="000370" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="001123" bing-rank="176"/>
	<description>... such notorious incidents, the setting of a fast food ... We eat at the fast food places when we are on a trip, but that is ... or environmental laws whatsoever, threw some trash ...</description>
	<body>
		Quick Login | Regular Login | Register | Neat Stuff HOME |  
 NEATOSHOP 
 Main Page New Bestsellers Personalized 
 Gifts Collectibles 

 All T-Shirts Funny 
 T-Shirts Science T-Shirts Neatorama 
 T-Shirts Featured 
 Artists 

 Mother&apos;s 
 Day Gifts Father&apos;s 
 Day Gifts Gift 
 for Geeks Bacon Store Small 
 Gifts 
 
  | RSS | LITE |  
 TOPICS 
 Art&amp;Design Business Collaborations Entertainment Features 

 Living Pictures Science&amp;Tech Society&amp;Culture Video Clips 
 
  | BEST OF NEATORAMA |  
 NEATOBLOGS 
 Art Bit Lit NeatoBambino NeatoGeek Spotlight 
 
  |  
 Why You May Not Want to Let Your Friends Eat at McDonalds (or Yourself) 
 By Queuebot in Food&amp;Drink on Feb 14, 2009 at 5:57 pm 
Wow…we all knew fast food was bad for us, but really? For starters, their burgers can apparently last for 20 years…longer than the average vehicle. Next up: you would have to walk for seven hours to burn off a Super Sized Coke. Seriously.

Heck, even pet food can be healthier than McDonalds according to a recent study–and the list goes on. So, before you head out for your next set of burger and fries read this and be amazed (or utterly disgusted). Of course you could also watch Supersize Me but this list arguably tops even some of his encounters.
 
 In 2007, the employees of an Orlando-area McDonald’s were caught on camera pouring milk into the milkshake machine out of a bucket labeled “Soiled Towels Only.” That particular restaurant had already been cited for 12 different sanitary violations. Though McDonald’s proudly stands by its safety standards, and not every restaurant has such notorious incidents, the setting of a fast food restaurant staffed with low-paid employees at a high turnover rate arguably encourages bending the rules. (McDonald’s isn’t alone in this, of course–Burger King is actually ranked as the dirtiest of all the fast food chains.) 
 
 Link 

From the Upcoming ueue , submitted by Urbanist .
 
   
 Tags: disgusting , Food , health , mcdonalds 

 Neat stuff from the NeatoShop :

 
 
Sally - POP! Vinyl Figure 
Hellboy - PVC Figure Set 
Mood Swing Soap 
 
 Josh 
 Feb 14th, 2009 at 
 6:24 pm 
The very weird thing about McDonald’s is what the food actually does to my appetite. If I start eating it about 1 or 2 times per week I will start get to hungry more often. If I stop eating it and go somewhere else like Wendy’s or Arby’s I do not get this effect nearly as bad. But the kicker is if I go to Subway and eat a 6″sub I will actually get to a point where I am almost never hungry until around 5 or 6 PM and can skip breakfast and lunch.
 mother hubbard 
 Feb 14th, 2009 at 
 6:31 pm 
Look. I worked in various restaurant/fast food joints as a teen many moons ago and can honestly say, at least half of the employees/management were the scum of the earth. Rat hairs in the ice cream tub? No problem. Just pick‘em out before you dip. No hot water for dishes? What the hell are you complaining about!! Get another job or just shut up! Yep. I heard ALL that and more. My solution? I almost NEVER eat out. Too expensive, too many preservatives/fake ingredients for moi. AND by cooking at home I don’t have to worry about someone spittin’in my special sauce. The other plus? I’m middle-aged and still at my ideal weight. Folks, this is a no-brainer.
 Moon 
 Feb 14th, 2009 at 
 6:34 pm 
If you dry it properly, ANY food will last for 20 years. This isn’t exclusive to McDonald’s.
 Matt 
 Feb 14th, 2009 at 
 6:51 pm 
Somehow, my friends and I eat at Macca’s and we’re just fine. Amazing!
 matt 
 Feb 14th, 2009 at 
 7:02 pm 
Once again somebody else takes a shot at McDonalds. Newsflash, ALL FAST FOOD IS BAD and a lot of places are much, much worse for your body than McDonalds. McDonalds does not force food down anyone’s throat and the corporation here lately has done everything possible to make it know just how bad the food is but yet, not surprisingly, people continue to clog their arteries with their food. All McDonalds does is provide a good for the needs of people.

I worked at McDonalds for a couple of years. We consistently received 95 or higher on our Health scores, with a string of 100′s 2 years in a row. The only deductions were for some problems with the tile flooring in the dry storage area that was of no harm whatsoever to people’s health. Also, no the burgers do not last for 20 years. I mean, sure you could keep them frozen for that long but I guarantee you once unthawed, they would fall apart and be tasteless (they were tasteless to begin with though).

I feel not pity at all for the people that get fat off of fast food. It’s your own fault. Don’t blame McDonalds.

Now, I will say, the dirty bucket with shake mix in it is absolutely uncalled for and disgusting but is not isolated to McDonalds.
 gonzz 
 Feb 14th, 2009 at 
 7:39 pm 
Ya no they all make good food ,they got us on advertising, and ya got to love the toys.But subway man id never do it!I eat out lots around the world but it seems there just dirty,and there buns suck they should get a reputable company to make there buns.
 v.dog 
 Feb 14th, 2009 at 
 7:54 pm 
I’ve got no problem with Maccas- as a treat on the odd occasion. Eating it on a regular basis however, should be avoided.

People need to take responsibility for their own health and well being, it’s not like the Fast Food Companies are forcing it down your throat.
 Johnny Cat 
 Feb 14th, 2009 at 
 9:04 pm 
Every once in a while I will get a wild hair and decide to get some McD’s. Every time I regret it.
 Werty 
 Feb 14th, 2009 at 
 9:11 pm 
Must be nice to have your own computer to type this on and not have to use the one down at the library.

Must be nice to be rich enough to afford an apartment with a kitchen instead of having no other option than to eat pre-prepared fast food all the time.

Must be nice to be wealthy enough that you never take your blinders off to see that the people you call fat at their own fault are actually POOR PEOPLE who are forced to fill their stomaches with crap and they would never be able to survive otherwise.

Must be nice to have enough money to be a bigot.

People these days……
 nerdalert 
 Feb 14th, 2009 at 
 9:26 pm 
seriously, I expected a better post than this from neatorama.
 James Schend 
 Feb 14th, 2009 at 
 9:36 pm 
Hasn’t the“McDonalds food lasts for 20 years”thing been debunked 80,000 times by now? I bet it’s been debunked at least once on this site.

How about we stop spreading urban rumors, and start spreading facts, eh?

There’s two factors here:
1) Any well-done burger patty will last for a very long time, it’s basically a dried meat at that point. Like beef jerky, which also lasts (gasp shock awe) many years.

2) All non-burger ingredients in a McDonalds hamburger goes bad pretty much exactly how you’d expect them to…I dare you to eat one after even 1 week in a refrigerator.

&gt;Must be nice to be wealthy enough that you never take
&gt;your blinders off to see that the people you call fat
&gt;at their own fault are actually POOR PEOPLE who are
&gt;forced to fill their stomaches with crap and they
&gt;would never be able to survive otherwise.

WTF? It’s a hell of a lot cheaper to buy healthy ingredients from a store than McDonalds hamburgers. Are you serious, or did I get trolled?
 Alex 
 Feb 14th, 2009 at 
 9:55 pm 
A friend of mine once worked for Taco Bell. He never ever ever ate there again after working there 
 Bobo 
 Feb 14th, 2009 at 
 10:37 pm 
@Alex

That’s true for almost anyone who works at a food restaurant. I worked at Red Lobster and Olive Garden, never ever going to even get NEAR them anymore. Just that the food is tiring after a while, and some of the things they do isn’t so pleasant.
 hunderfund 
 Feb 14th, 2009 at 
 10:53 pm 
i think this article was a really poor attack on mcdonalds. and who cares that they’re eating cows…its a hamburger, what’d you expect?
 matt 
 Feb 14th, 2009 at 
 11:46 pm 
@Werty

My comments were not intended to degrade the poor. They were intended for the ones who choose to eat McDonald’s on a regular basis, poor or wealthy.

And as James said, if you are poor then you should be buying food from the store and cooking in bulk yourself, not spending the money on fast food.

So, therefore, I stand by my comments of feeling no pity whatsoever towards the people who get fat off of McDonald’s food.
 LV 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 12:23 am 
Its all about the convenience of it. It takes a lot less time to run into Mcd’s and get a quick bite then it does to cook a meal. (AKA lazy.)
I want to know what“poor people”go to Mcd’s on a regular bases? $17.00 for 3 people to eat there when the same meal can be cooked at home for about $6.00
We eat at the fast food places when we are on a trip, but that is about it.
If one eats at any of them on a regular bases they will have bigger problems than getting fat.
 Frau 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 12:23 am 
@ Alex–the same reason I do not eat at Subways.

I am lucky that there are no fast food places within 6 miles of me. The cost and quality of“meals”at McD’s simply do not meet my ideas of what is a good value.

And pet food may be better in nutrtion–but it does not taste all that great.

Yes I have had a small nibble of a piece of kibble. I wanted to know why the dog did not like his“new and improved best testing ever”food.
 MaiQ 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 1:08 am 
 http://tinyurl.com/c95gbn More crimes from McDonalds
 renderanything 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 1:39 am 
Ugh. I haven’t eaten at McDonalds in probably fifteen years. I’ve never been tempted too, and adding the effects of this article gives me even less reason to want a quarter pounder with cheese.
 James Schend 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 1:45 am 
MaiQ, what are you complaining about? That some McDonalds employees in some country that probably has zero littering or environmental laws whatsoever, threw some trash in the parking lot instead of the dumpster? Oh, and in the last few photos they hired some guys to pick it up?

Yes, that’s certainly damning–I guess?
 ilikecows13 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 1:51 am 
I don’t understand why we only ever hear about McDonalds. Ever since“Super Size Me”came out a few years ago, the cool kids have decided it’s the most disgusting, vile, horrid corporation to ever exist in our day and age, and we all follow–pitchforks in hand. I’m not sure–I’ve done no research to back this up, but I have a feeling that other companies are breathing huge sighs of relief; thinking they can get away with whatever they want because anytime anything happens with any of the McDonald’s restaurants, McDonalds is what is going to pay, and the focus is PERMANENTLY off of them. Recently, KFC transferred it’s oh-so-secret recipe from one place to another safer place. We all cheer and are all warm and fuzzy because after all, the thing was written in PENCIL and was signed by Harland Sanders. We don’t question the integrity of that recipe. All we are concerned with is the fact that it is orignal and C. Sanders wrote it all by himself. What if we found out that soiled towel squeezings and spider eggs were part of his secret ingredients?

Don’t just diss Mickey D’s if you are going to diss bad-for-you-food. Either eat it, or don’t. McDonalds isn’t the only company out there trying to make a buck off of being cheap.
 Christophe 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 2:46 am 
Another one-sided ranting against fast food.

It’s the first time I said that, but this post is not neat, with dubious facts in it.

Check your local health administration website to see that fast food joints are not the only one by far to have sanitary problems.

And : like most of us, I like meat, and yes fast food calories are not the healthiests.
 darlzwik 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 5:12 am 
“Must be nice to be rich enough to afford an apartment with a kitchen instead of having no other option than to eat pre-prepared fast food all the time.”

“Must be nice to be wealthy enough that you never take your blinders off to see that the people you call fat at their own fault are actually POOR PEOPLE who are forced to fill their stomaches with crap and they would never be able to survive otherwise.”

“Must be nice to have enough money to be a bigot”

Most poor people are that way because they’re not too bright. (or their parents aren’t) I’ve seen poor people pile into an expensive cab and go get an unhealthy pizza, and then take it home in the cab. These were welfare recipients. For the money they spent on that cab and really malnutritious food, they could have eaten 5 days out of a grocery store. It wasn’t like they didn’t have time to cook, they just sat around on their fat asses watching T.V.

I agree, the real issue isn’t McDonald’s. food. It’s the fact that stupid people seem to be the ones having all the kids.

Question: What kind of sustainable society do you expect us to have when the stupid, unhealthy people are the ones reproducing the most?

Answer: Wait and see.
 Frank 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 6:05 am 
“Supersize me”is no example for a well done documentary, but for well done entertainment. Most results are quite arguable:
 http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Supersize_me#Alternative_experiments 
 SenorMysterioso 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 6:13 am 
I dont understand the point you are trying to make about money. I can eat for a few days on the same amount of money it costs me to eat one meal at McDonalds. I doubt that McDonalds is a multi billion dollar corporation because they cater to the poor.

I eat McDonalds about once a month now. I could hear a million horror stories about it and I would not think twice about eating there. I never understand the point of the McDonalds stories like this. Yes some stores have poor business and health practices and yes the food is unhealthy but when it comes down to it I do not care what other people choose to put in their bodies. An exception I have to this is lazy parents who feed their kids too much fast food. A child is not in control of their nutrition so parents should be a little more diligent in the decisions they make about their kids’health.

As for this post not being what youve come to expect from Neatorama, I agree. There really is no neat or interesting angle to this story but keep in mind that its a queue post not a post from one of the authors we’ve come to know. I often like even the mediocre posts because of the conversations that take place in the comments 

Also–I miss the mouth burning deep fried crispy delight that was the McD’s apple pie. This dried out, baked cardboard apple thing they have now is no substitute for the original.

Does anybody else remember when you used to get a little packet of cookies shaped like McDonalds characters in your happy meal? I wonder why they did away with those
 whitcwa 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 8:51 am 
Alex, I expect better posts than this. I confess I eat at McD’s often, mostly at lunch because I like to leave work and walk. I am not obese, stupid or poor. I am in excellent health and exercise regularly. I appreciate a good bargain and make sensible choices like avoiding fries, sugary sodas, and the big sandwiches. They are a lot cleaner than most inexpensive restaurants. I see them cleaning constantly. I have no financial interest in McD’s. Food snobs say we should all eat locally grown fresh food prepared at home, but not everyone can afford to do that. McD’s fills a role in our society. If you don’t like it don’t eat there.
 ted 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 9:27 am 
Yeah, this was kind of like one of those“Wal-Mart is evil”attack posts. Or maybe a toned-down PETA ad.

I’m starting to dislike the Upcoming Queue, too.
 D Bozko 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 12:14 pm 
The article was one sided and flawed. Eating at home can be cheaper and healthier but fast food is easy. Fast food isn’t evil. It alone doesn’t make you fat. It alone doesn’t give you high blood pressure or high cholosterol. McDonald’s gives the public what they want and all these fast food detractors should give it a rest. People have choices, it’s just that they sometimes make bad ones.
 Moon 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 1:10 pm 
 Yeah, this was kind of like one of those “Wal-Mart is evil” attack posts. Or maybe a toned-down PETA ad.

I’m starting to dislike the Upcoming Queue, too. 

Wal-Mart IS evil, though!

 
 jmk816 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 2:02 pm 
“Most poor people are that way because they’re not too bright.”- Wow statements like that make me weep. Based on one citing of anecdotal evidence darlzwik is convinced that all poor people are stupid and probably thinks they deserve to be poor. I guess that means I’m studying the wrong thing, since darlzwik seems to have solved the issues of poverty (Sociology), maybe next he can move on to racism and gender inequality.

Sorry that was so ignorant it needed to be pointed out. Also when we are talking about the difference between buying things in bulk and going to fast food, it’s not just the cost of the food but the space and the cost of the appliances that are needed to store it and the time and the skills that are needed to cook it. When you look at the issue this way the price of buying in bulk goes up considerably.
 darlzwik 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 3:50 pm 
If you are poor, and you don’t have“The skills that are needed to cook it”, (food) and you go and have more kids, you“deserve”more than just being poor.

I didn’t say“all poor people”I said most poor people.
 Werty 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 4:44 pm 
You Hypocrit, YOU YOURSELF HAVE CATS YOU ADMIT YOU DON’T FEED

 http://www.neatorama.com/2009/01/27/cat-adopts-a-bunny/ 

darlzwik
January 28th, 2009 at 5:41 am

It would be real surprising around my yard. Our cats eat rabbits any time they can. I’ve even seen the mother use live young rabbits to teach her kittens to kill. If the rabbit gets away, she goes and brings it back. But then, I don’t feed the cats very much. I let them in the basement in the winter, but other than that, they can’t even come in.
 Werty 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 5:16 pm 
BTW David Darlzwik how is your life going in Michigan?

Do you really think that in Grand Rapids there is nobody poor who take offense at your remarks?
 darlzwik 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 8:00 pm 
If I fed the cats too much, they wouldn’t eat the mice and the rabbits, which is why I have cats.

Are you saying that because someone will be offended, I shouldn’t voice my opinion? There is always someone taking offense at something; we seem to have professionally offended people making a career of it.

Oh yeah, my life in Michigan is going great. I love it here. I love the 4 seasons, all the water, all the trees, and although I don’t live in G.R., I have been there, and it’s a lovely place. All of southern Michigan is nice, even Detroit.
 JMM 
 Feb 15th, 2009 at 
 8:27 pm 
If you really want a barf attack just talk to the produce people at Whole Foods. ACCKKKKKGGG&gt;

My best friend worked there for 3 days and then she just couldn’t take it anymore.
 Joe 
 Feb 16th, 2009 at 
 1:39 am 
This article is nothing but a childish attack on McDonald’s and an oh-so-tired soap-boxing crusade against the Hummer.

The Hummer is still a relatively low-volume product, and it is obvious they require quite a lot of petroleum resources to run. But there just aren’t enough of them to make a lick of difference to the environment. They are thoroughly modern vehicles that expel a fraction of the various gases emitted by economy cars 10 or 20 years old.

The rest of the article reads like one of those“fact-filled”chain e-mails we all despise.

You don’t like McDonald’s? Don’t eat there. Problem solved.
 JKirchartz 
 Feb 16th, 2009 at 
 10:32 am 
I havn’t eaten McDonalds in over a decade, since all their food tastes like cardboard, and they use some orange sludge to thicken their milk-shakes (even the white vanilla ones) gross!
 Chelsea 
 Feb 16th, 2009 at 
 1:01 pm 
I’d like to point out a bit of misinformation in the lead-in to the article. The poster summarized a few of the facts from the article, including the tidbit that“you would have to walk for seven hours to burn off a Super Sized Coke. Seriously.”Actually, the full article states that seven hours of walking would burn off the calories in a Super Sized MEAL consisting of a Coke, Big Mac, and fries. The soda alone might take you 2-3 hours, depending on the kind of exercise you engage in and your resting metabolic rate.

I’m all for pointing out the cause-effect relationship between high calorie foods and weight gain, but don’t spread inaccuracies by ineptly paraphrasing your own post.
 SpuriousLogic 
 Feb 16th, 2009 at 
 3:51 pm 
This article must have come from the queue because it’s totally biased and clueless.
I love the part about how“McDonald’s supports the destruction of the Amazon rainforest”because the chickens eat soy feed grown on the rainforest. That whole statement is predicated on the premise that only chickens raised for McDonalds eat soy based feed and the soy based feed can only be grown on rainforest land.
 The El Bee En 
 Feb 17th, 2009 at 
 8:08 am 
Good thing we don’t live in China!
 d 
 Feb 17th, 2009 at 
 10:03 am 
i agree with nerdalert. i expected a better post from neatorama.
 Slix 
 Feb 17th, 2009 at 
 4:56 pm 
Anyone watching“Supersize Me”will find an extra showing exactly what happens to McDonald’s food over time. Other than the fries, everything deteriorated as expected. Odd that this site would misrepresent that, while citing“Supersize Me”at a later point.

Also, the lead in from Neatorama had a poor misrepresentation.“Seven Hours to burn off a Super-sized Coke.”When the artical states that was the time for a Coke, fries and burger. Come on Neatorama, you guys are too good to go sensationalizing stuff.
 MaiQ 
 Feb 17th, 2009 at 
 9:32 pm 
To The El Bee En

We do live in China! It is beautiful nature here, but we are still shocked by things like that.

I think the best way to get rid of things like that is to bring more publicity without blaming anyone.
 D BEE 
 Mar 1st, 2009 at 
 3:53 pm 
lallalalalalalallalalala
 
 
 Keep track of the comments with Comment RSS 
 Don&apos;t Miss: New 
 Stuff | Bestsellers | The 
 Cute Store 
                    Funny 
 T-Shirts | Zombie Shop 

Need a gift? Get unforgettable gifts for:
 Geeks | Pranksters | Kids | Hipsters | Shutterbugs Search for: 
 
 
 The latest from NeatoBambino :
 Adorable Star Wars Bassinet Baby’s First Lightsaber Duel Parents Hide Baby In Carry-On Gadget Reminds You When You’ve Left a Kid in the Back of the Car Crib Turned into a Desk 
 

 So, Do You Believe in Global Warming Now? (59) Official Olympics Outfit of Team USA: Chic or Dud? (17) The Serial Hugger: Is It a Crime to Trick Strangers into Giving You a Hug? (10) What Is It? game 233 (9) Girls Have More Math Anxiety Than Boys (7) 
 
 Get Gifts for Your 
 Favorite Geeks from the NeatoShop! 
 
 Back 
 to School Items 
Get ready for back to school with tons of cute Bags&amp;Backpacks and Lunch 
 Boxes 
 Featured Items from the NeatoShop 
 
 
Spooky Corks - Wine Bottle Stoppers (Set of 3) 
Cthulhu Tentacle Bottle Opener 
 
 
 NEATORAMA STUFF 
 Contact Us 
 Privacy Policy 

 SUBMIT A LINK 
By Email GET NEATORAMA BY EMAIL 
 Email: 

 List of Authors 

 Design by Adam Koford
	</body>
</document>
