<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002393" url="http://www.fitday.com/fitness-articles/nutrition/healthy-eating/how-to-keep-your-calorie-count-low-when-eating-out.html" time="2012-07-12-18:19" support="5" score="0.010068737747002777" bingtitle="How to Keep Your Calorie Count Low When Eating Out / Nutrition ..." webtitle="How to Keep Your Calorie Count Low When Eating Out / Nutrition / Healthy Eating">
			<query id="001378" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="000561" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000624" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="001504" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000859" bing-rank="200"/>
	<description>If you do find yourself in a fast food restaurant, choose the lower calorie ... Another way to keep a low calorie count when eating out is to order dressings and sauces on ...</description>
	<body>
		Create Free Account Log In 
 
 ABOUT PRODUCTS ARTICLES FORUMS 
 
 WHAT IS FITDAY? START LOGGING SUCCESS STORIES 

 OVERVIEW FITDAY PC PREMIUM FREE ACCOUNT 

 ALL FITNESS NUTRITION 

 HOME 
 
 Rss Facebook Twitter 
 
 Home Nutrition Healthy Eating How to Keep Your Calorie Count Low When Eating Out 
 
How to Keep Your Calorie Count Low When Eating Out
 
Keeping your calorie count low when eating out can sometimes be a challenge. This is especially the case if the food is delicious. Here are a few strategies for limiting your calorie count in restaurants.

 Select Healthier Restaurants 

In some restaurants, especially the fast food variety, it is very difficult to keep your calorie count low. When eating out, choosing restaurants that offer healthier food options will make it easier to stay at or below your daily caloric needs. Restaurants that cook with unhealthy oils or whose foods contain preservatives and unwanted chemicals are better avoided. Healthy options include restaurants that cook with fresh ingredients and healthy oils, and offer options such as soup, fresh vegetables, salads, whole grains, fruits and a variety of protein sources.

 Choose Lower Calorie Foods 

If you do find yourself in a fast food restaurant, choose the lower calorie food options. Salads, soups and sandwiches are sometimes available choices. Even in healthier restaurants, you will often have a choice between a creamy sauce and one with fewer calories. When given the choice between fried and grilled, choose the latter because it will generally contain fewer calories. When choosing a drink, you might choose sparkling water over soda. Always look for the lower calorie option. If in doubt, ask the waiter or waitress. They often have good suggestions.

 Order Dressings and Sauces on the Side 

Another way to keep a low calorie count when eating out is to order dressings and sauces on the side. Some restaurants will drench the food with sauce or dressing. When you order it on the side, you have control over how much you use. You will often find that you can enjoy your meal just as much with less of these ingredients.

 Remove the Fat and Skin from Meats 

When your meal arrives, consider cutting away any extra fat or skin from meats. Remove the skin from your chicken. Cut the fat off of your steak. Eat just a bit of the skin from your salmon. Fat and skin contain more calories. You can keep your calorie count low by removing the skin and fat or limiting your intake.

 Share Your Entree or Dessert 

Some restaurants give you enormous portions. You can limit your calorie count by asking your fellow diners ahead of time if they would like to share your meal or dessert. This way you can still enjoy these items, but do so in smaller portions. Be sure to separate any portion that seems excessive and ask for a to-go box. Most restaurant meals can be enjoyed the following day for lunch.

 Eat Slowly and Enjoy Your Food 

When you eat slowly, really chew your food and appreciate the taste of each ingredient, you will tend to eat less. This goes for the food that is on the table when you sit down, such as bread and butter, as well as your appetizer and main meal. If you slow down, you can still have a taste of everything on the table, but do so in very small amounts.

 

 
 

Article Comments

 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments 
RELATED ARTICLES
 
 
 The Nutrition of a Pineapple 
 When it comes to the popular hunt for delicious foods with nutritional value, the pineapple presents an... &gt;&gt; 
 Healthy Dining Out: The Importance of Choosing the Right Menu Item 
 Dining out can be fun, but it can sometimes be detrimental to healthy eating resolutions as well.... &gt;&gt; 
 Are Fast Food Salads and Veggies Nutritious? 
 Many people consider purchasing fast food salads as a way of eating healthy. While a fast food salad does... &gt;&gt; 
 Advertise on FitDay.com 
 Terms of Service Privacy Policy Contact FitDay Credits Affiliate Program 

Copyright©2000-2011 Internet Brands, Inc. All rights reserved.
FITDAY is a registered service mark of Internet Brands, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
