<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002368" url="http://mashable.com/2010/02/11/pizza-hut-pick-up-lines-2/" time="2012-07-12-18:17" support="2" score="0.0033691022212563064" bingtitle="Pizza Hut Looks to Start a Pick-Up Line Meme on Twitter" webtitle="Pizza Hut Looks to Start a Pick-Up Line Meme on Twitter">
			<query id="000959" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000965" bing-rank="48"/>
	<description>... from Pizza Hut encourages users to tweet pick ... I still order from pizza hut by calling on the ... that it had boldly gone where no fast food restaurant had ...</description>
	<body>
		Top Stories 
 Photo&amp;Video Galleries Top Lists 
 Trending Topics 
 Twitter YouTube Facebook iPhone Google Video More Topics... 
 People 
 Recommended Mashable Staff More people... 
 Jobs Events Try Our New Social News App 
 Welcome to Mashable! Sign in with Facebook or Facebook Mashable 
 Social Media 
 All Social Media How-To Facebook Twitter YouTube Google+ mRank 
 Tech 
 All Tech Apps&amp;Software Dev&amp;Design Gadgets Mobile 
 Business 
 All Business Advertising Marketing Media Small Business Startups Jobs 
 Lifestyle 
 All Lifestyle Family&amp;Parenting Health&amp;Fitness Home 
 Watercooler 
 All Watercooler Videos Pics Memes Comics Conversations 
 Entertainment 
 All Entertainment Film Gaming Music Sports TV 
 US&amp;World 
 All US&amp;World Politics Social Good U.S. World 
 Videos 

 Featured: Facebook 
 
 Trending Stories 

 
 NBC Launches App to Stream 3,500 Hours of London Olympics 0 
 Like Tweet 
 10 Stellar Space-Themed Accessories For Your Office 11 
 Like Tweet 
 5 Reasons Amazon Should Stay Out of the Smartphone Market 2 
 Like Tweet 
 
 Pizza Hut Looks to Start a Pick-Up Line Meme on Twitter 
 February 11, 2010 by Adam Ostrow 99 Like Tweet +1 Share Pin It Share 
 Twitter’s trending topics—to the dismay of some—are often filled with whimsical hashtags that emerge organically (today’s #awkwardsituation for example). Pizza Hut is trying to force the issue a bit with a new Valentine’s Day-themed promotion that encourages users to tweet pick-up lines, with the added bonus of free desserts for the most creative entries.
 
The promotion, announced on the @pizzahut feed earlier today, asks users to append #iluvPH to their (G-rated) tweets. It will run through Valentine’s Day, with the 100 best submissions as judged by Pizza Hut to be notified of their free “chocolate-topped dessert sticks” (sounds just like what you need after a 2,000 calorie pizza and wings binge) on Monday the 15th.

Looking at the promotion so far, it appears to be far from breaking into Twitter’s trending topics, but is seeing plenty of tweets, including the oft-tested, rarely (if not ever) approved, “How much does a Polar Bear weigh? Enough to break the ice” and, “Are you a parking ticket? Because you’ve got FINE written all over you.”

In the past, the chain has demonstrated a knack for attracting some buzz in the social media world, starting with a widely reported search for a Twitter intern long before that became a desirable job. That intern then offered up free food to those that became fans of Pizza Hut on Twitter and Facebook during a summer promotion, which have helped the company’s presence grow to more than 25,000 followers and 1.1 million fans, respectively. It also has an iPhone app that’s generated more than $1 million in sales.

That said, free stuff type promotions have become so commonplace on Twitter that it’s a lot harder to move the needle than even just a few months ago (#moonfruit dominated trending topics for days with its iPhone giveaway last July). Nonetheless, tying it to a holiday in a clever way adds a fun and engaging twist, and could get you what sounds like a terribly indulgent dessert if you choose to participate.
 Print Story Email Story Reprints 
Topics to follow

 Twitter 59,053 followers Follow Marketing 9,822 followers Follow Food 256 followers Follow Pizza Hut 3 followers Follow 
 
 More Stories in Marketing 

 
 Allure to Give Away 32,000 Beauty Products via Mobile Scanning 0 
 Like Tweet 
 How to Make B2B Content More Shareable 6 
 Like Tweet 
 
 Top Related Stories 

 
 Brewster Takes Your Digital Address Book to the Social Side 1 
 Like Tweet 
 Read the Sandusky Report Online, No Journalist Analysis Required 0 
 Like Tweet 
 
17 Comments
 To leave a comment on this story, please log in with Facebook or Twitter 
 Marcus Im 
I wonder how many companies are trying a promotion like this on Facebook and/or Twitter. Our philanthropic organization is trying it out for the first time this year…I’m excited to see the results (although the sacred Trending Topics is probably far from reach). Anyway, contests are always fun! Especially when they’re free.

We require our contestants to twitpic rather than just tweet a pick-up line…Maybe we made it too difficult to participate? I know how lazy people can be…What do you think?
 February 12, 2010 00:07:00 Reply Anonymous 
they totally stole this from joshgroban….
 February 12, 2010 00:44:00 Reply Anonymous 
The only thing good about Pizza Hut is the bread sticks!

Jess
 http://www.online-anonymity.cz.tc 
 February 12, 2010 01:42:00 Reply shreya mehta 
Today all are interested to grow there business and they all are target social media because social media is a platform where people share and give there ideas thoughts and like pizza hurt they promote their scemes and brand and increase the awareness and target its customers more easily that never before….

See More At: http://digitalmarketing.mehtainc.com/ 
 February 12, 2010 04:36:00 Reply Frederick M. Cheeseborough III 
I think pizza hut should focus on a website redesign instead of this twitter promotion. I ordered from papa john’s website during their $10 deal and papa john’s website was way more user friendly than pizza hut’s. I still order from pizza hut by calling on the phone because their website sucks just that bad.
 February 12, 2010 04:36:00 Reply OC Swimwear 
Funny I should read this today as I’m planning on launching a special offer on Twitter; giving free memberships to my site. Twitter is one of those things I love and hate in equal measure. Trying to come up with interesting stuff to Tweet about all the time…urghh….
 February 12, 2010 08:06:00 Reply shilpa4 
i like this

 http://mytwitteradder.com/ 
 February 12, 2010 06:51:29 Reply Anonymous 
Many of the restaurants in Cool Springs are now offering similar type promotions. Manny’s House of Pizza in Nashville gives away a free lunch every day to someone who retweets their message of the day. I think restaurants will find it is by far the highest return on their investment (little or nothing) when compared to traditional print media, mailers and tv or radio.
 February 12, 2010 13:44:00 Reply Joey Fratantoni 
These types of promotions do seem like they are a dime a dozen nowadays, and will continue to increase over the upcoming months. I personally think it is very wise of Pizza Hut to do this because it is for a holiday and everyone likes free stuff. I’m sure there will be great participation among Twitters users and loyal Pizza Hut followers. Thanks for sharing.
 February 12, 2010 17:52:00 Reply Anonymous 
I don’t know about you guys but I just got 10 free pick up lines from my BA new app
 http://cli.gs/XPtA8a 
 February 12, 2010 18:16:00 Reply Anonymous 
 pizza hut still my preferred place to get pizza. It just rocks!
 February 13, 2010 18:13:00 Reply MMA clothing 
oooo I want a free desert lol
 February 15, 2010 09:18:00 Reply Magic Logix 
Free chocolate topped dessert sticks for being the most creative sounds like a great idea. You know that half of the people that don’t win this twitter competition for best pick up line are probably eating some dessert sticks right now.
 February 16, 2010 17:11:00 Reply Anonymous 
Welcome to Opinion poll!

Hi Friends,You can vote and express your views about this poll by clicking following URL Link:

 http://www.opinionpoll.in/AF176 

(If the link doesn’t work while clicking, please copy the above URL and paste it in your web browser address bar.)

My favourite Pizza?

A) Domino Piza

B) Garcia s Famous Pizza

C) Mamma Mia

D) Pizza Hut

For More Polls Visit : http://www.opinionpoll.in 
 March 5, 2010 10:50:00 Reply 
 Anonymous 
Thanks for my comments added in your Url.
 March 5, 2010 10:51:00 Reply 
 Panerai Replica Watches 
This is cool
 March 22, 2010 12:48:33 Reply çeviri 
In January 2009, the chain got considerable media attention for its announcement that it had boldly gone where no fast food restaurant had ventured before.
 April 28, 2010 20:48:00 Reply 
 
 Subscribe To Mashable 
 Recommend on Google Follow @mashable 
 LinkedIn YouTube Stumble RSS 
 RSS Feed 
604,677+ Subscribers
 
 
 Android iPhone iPad 
 More subscription options» 
 Mashable News In Your Inbox 
 
 Top Stories My Stories (Personalized) 

 All Stories Activity From People I Follow Latest Social Media News Tech&amp;Gadgets Highlights Web Video Roundup Today in Mobile Dev&amp;Design Highlights Business&amp;Marketing Latest Startups News The Social Good Brief Latest Media News Announcements 
 
 Trending Videos 
 
 Top Stories Today 

 1 
 ‘Angry Birds’Creator Drops Trailer for New‘Amazing Alex’Game 10 
 Like Tweet 2 
 Reddit Unlocks the Secret of Cryptic Subway Code [UPDATED] 97 
 Like Tweet 3 
 5 Hilarious‘Fifty Shades of Grey’Parodies 7 
 Like Tweet 4 
 ‘Arrested Development’Prepares to Start Production for Netflix 13 
 Like Tweet 5 
 NYC Is Turning Payphones Into Wi-Fi Hotspots 12 
 Like Tweet 
 
 Trending Topics 

 Entertainment 3,656 followers Follow Gadgets 8,256 followers Follow YouTube 14,493 followers Follow World 796 followers Follow Twitter 59,053 followers Follow Startups 10,107 followers Follow Lifestyle 166 followers Follow US 1,021 follower Follow Small business 2,511 followers Follow 
 
 Top From Our Partners 

 
 The Daily Dot Top 10 Pinterest Hoaxes 11 
 Like Tweet 
 The Atlantic The Story Behind the First Photo Ever Posted on the Web 4 
 Like Tweet 
 Geekosystem Researchers Transmit Electricity Through Solid Concrete 3 
 Like Tweet 
 Space.com Could We Build Star Trek’s Starship Enterprise? 5 
 Like Tweet 
 Tecca How to Organize Family Plans With Google Calendar 6 
 Like Tweet 
 
 Partners 

 
 ←Previous Story Next Story→ YouTube Documents Iranian Protests Via Smuggled Footage [VIDEO] Apple Fast Approaching 10 Billion Song Downloads Back to top Topics Lists News 
 Blogger Lists Blogging Lists Bookmarks Lists Browser Lists Business Lists Celebrity Lists Current Events Lists Dating Sites Lists Design Lists Desktop App Lists Events Lists Facebook Lists Firefox Lists FriendFeed Lists Games Lists Google Lists Health and Environment Related Lists Holiday Lists Identity Lists Jobs Lists Maps Lists Megalists Mobile Lists Moms and Family Resource Lists Money and Finance Lists Movie Lists Music Lists MySpace Lists Open Source Lists Photo Lists Politics Lists Productivity Lists Programming and Web Development Lists RSS Lists Research Lists Shopping Lists Social Media Lists Social Network Lists Sports Lists Startups Lists Template Lists Torrents Lists Travel Lists Tumblr Lists Twitter Lists Video Lists WordPress Resource Lists iPhone Resource Lists 
 
 Twitter YouTube Facebook Google MySpace Video iPhone Firefox Blogger AJAX APIs Apple Bebo Business Celebrities Digg Fashion Flickr FriendFeed Friendster Games Google Maps Google Wave Microsoft Mobile Music Politics Search Social Media Social Networking Sports Startups Web Design Web Apps WordPress Yahoo 
 
 Advertising amazon android apple apps att bizspark blackberry Business celebrities contributor design education Entertainment Events Facebook fashion features Film first to know series foursquare Gadgets gallery games Gaming gmail Google How-To humor infographic iOS ipad iphone iphone app iphone apps jobs linkedin List Lists Marketing mashable mashable video Media microsoft Mobile Movies Music myspace netflix Politics pop culture privacy samsung Search security Small Business smartphone Social Good Social Media social networking software startup Startups steve jobs Tablet tablets Tech television trending tumblr TV Twitter verizon Video video games viral viral video viral videos Yahoo YouTube 
 
About Mashable

Mashable is a leading source for news, information and resources for the Connected Generation. Mashable reports on the importance of digital innovation and how it empowers and inspires people around the world. Mashable’s 20 million unique visitors and 6 million social media followers have become one of the most engaged online news communities. Founded in 2005, Mashable is headquartered in New York City with an office in San Francisco.
 
Partners
 W3 EDGE Rackspace Intridea Dynect DNS 
Global Syndication Partners
 ABCNews CNN Metro Yahoo ©2005-2012 Mashable, Inc.
Reproduction without explicit permission is prohibited. All Rights Reserved. 
Company

 About Us Contact Us Announcements Submit News Advertise Reprints Privacy Policy Terms of Use Subscribe 
 
Site

 Mashable Follow Jobs Events Mobile Version iPhone App iPad App Android App Blippr Mashable France 
 
Resources

 Guidebooks Lists How To Trending Mashable Awards Subscriptions 
 
Channels

 All Social Media Tech&amp;Gadgets Business&amp;Marketing Watercooler Entertainment US&amp;World Video Mobile Dev&amp;Design Media Social Good Startups 
 Share this story to Facebook Twitter LinkedIn 140
	</body>
</document>
