<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002118" url="http://www.keepkidshealthy.com/preschool/preschoolnutrition.html" time="2012-07-12-18:01" support="17" score="0.036989037953611456" bingtitle="Nutrition for Preschool Children - Keep Kids Healthy" webtitle="Nutrition for Preschool Children - Keep Kids Healthy">
			<query id="000180" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="001129" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="001142" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000220" bing-rank="241"/>
			<query id="001120" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="001110" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="001153" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000869" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="001025" bing-rank="225"/>
			<query id="000429" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000181" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="000054" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000357" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="000859" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="000367" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="001518" bing-rank="242"/>
			<query id="001277" bing-rank="75"/>
	<description>a discussion of nutrition in preschool children, with info on the food guide pyramid ... Vegetable group servings include 1/2 cup of chopped or raw vegetables, or 1 cup of ...</description>
	<body>
		Bookstore 
Site Map 
Contact Us 
Help 
About Us 
What&apos;s New? 
 
 
 
 Search this site: 
 Advanced Search
 
 
 
 
 

 
 Main Menu Pediatrics Parenting Experts Ask the Pediatrician Index of Topics Pediatric Problems Parenting Tips Common Problems Development Safety Discipline Nutrition Healthy Habits Well Child Visits Medicine Cabinet 
 Online Resources What&apos;s New Reviews Growth Charts Online Forums Vaccine Schedule Baby Names Guide BMI Calculator Lead Screening Height Calculator Product Recalls 
 
 Newsletters: Subscribe to get free news, tips and updates. 
 Recommend Us tell a friend about us or email this page to a friend 
 
 
 
 
 
 Advertisement Children&apos;s Skin Care 
 
 Related Topics Vegan Children 
 
 
 Main &gt; Nutrition &gt; Preschool &gt;Preschool Nutrition 
 Preschool Nutrition 
 
 You should now be giving your child homogenized whole cow&apos;s milk. You can also begin to use 2%, low fat, or skim milk instead. Your child&apos;s diet should resemble that of the rest of the families, with 3 meals and 2 nutritious snacks each day. You should limit milk and dairy products to about 16oz each day and 100% fruit juice to about 4-6 oz each day and offer a variety of foods to encourage good eating habits later.

 
 Related Topics 
 Vegan Children 
Feeding practices to avoid are continuing to use a bottle, giving large amounts of sweet desserts, soft drinks, fruit-flavored drinks, sugarcoated cereals, chips or candy, as they have little nutritional value. Also avoid giving foods that your child can choke on, such as raw carrots, peanuts, whole grapes, tough meats, popcorn, chewing gum or hard candy.

Your child&apos;s nutrition is important to her overall health. Proper nutrition can also prevent many medical problems, including becoming overweight, developing weak bones, and developing diabetes. It will also ensure that your child physically grows to her full potential.

The best nutrition advise to keep your child healthy includes encouraging her to:

 Eat a variety of foods Balance the food you eat with physical activity Choose a diet with plenty of grain products, vegetables and fruits Choose a diet low in fat, saturated fat, and cholesterol Choose a diet moderate in sugars and salt Choose a diet that provides enough calcium and iron to meet their growing body&apos;s requirements.

You can also help promote good nutrition by setting a good example. Healthy eating habits and regular exercise should be a regular part of your family&apos;s life. It is much easier if everyone in the house follows these guidelines, than if your child has to do it alone. You should also buy low-calorie and low-fat meals, snacks and desserts, low fat or skim milk and diet drinks. Avoid buying high calorie desserts or snacks, such as snack chips, regular soft drinks or regular ice cream.

The Food Guide Pyramid for young children was designed by the US Dept. of Agriculture to promote healthy nutrition in children over two years of age. It is meant to be a general guide to daily food choices. The main emphasis of the food pyramid is on the five major food groups, all of which are required for good health. It also emphasizes that foods that include a lot of fats, oils and sweets should be used very sparingly. 
 
 Food Guide Pyramid 
 
 
 What counts as one serving? 
 To ensure good nutrition in your child and that they grow up healthy, they will need to eat a large variety of foods. The amount of foods that they eat is much less important. Remember that your child&apos;s appetite may decrease and become pickier over the next few years as his growth rate slows. As long as they are gaining weight and have a normal activity level, then you have little to worry about. You can still offer them a variety of foods, but can decrease the serving sizes if they don&apos;t eat a lot.
 Grain group servings include 1 slice of bread, 1/2 cup of cooked rice or pasta, 1/2 cup of cooked cereal, and 1 ounce of ready to eat cereal. Your child should eat 6 servings from this group.

 Vegetable group servings include 1/2 cup of chopped or raw vegetables, or 1 cup of raw leafy vegetables. Your child should eat 3 servings from this group.

 Fruit group servings include 1 piece of fruit or melon wedge, 3/4 cup of 100% fruit juice, 1/2 cup of canned fruit, or 1/4 cup of dried fruit. Your child should eat 2 servings from this group.

 Milk group servings include 1 cup of milk or yogurt or 2 ounces of cheese. Your child should eat 2 servings from this group.

 Meat group servings include 2 to 3 ounces of cooked lean meat, poultry or fish, 1/2 cup of cooked dry beans. You can substitute 2 tablespoons of peanut butter or 1 egg for 1 ounce of meat. Your child should eat 2 servings from this group. 
 
 Fats, Oils and Sweets 
 No more than 30% of your diet should come from fats. For a 1600 calorie diet, that would equal 53g of fat each day, with most preschool children requiring even less. The type of fat that you eat is also important. Saturated fats in foods such as meats, dairy products, coconut, palm and palm kernal oil, raise cholesterol more than unsaturated fats , which are found in olive, peanut, and canola oils, or polyunsaturated fats in safflower, sunflower, corn, soybean and cottonseed oils. Limit saturated fats to no more than 10% of daily calories. 
Sugars supply a large amount of calories, with little nutritional value. They include white sugar, brown sugar, corn syrup, honey and molasses and foods like candy, soft drinks, jams, and jellies.

Selection tips:

 use lean meats and skim or lowfat dairy products use unsaturated vegetable oils and margarines that list a liquid vegetable oil as the first ingredient on the label read the nutrition label on foods to check for the amount and type of fat it includes limit foods that contain a large amount of saturated fats limit foods high in sugar and avoid adding extra sugar to your foods
 
 
 Prevention of Feeding Problems 
 The best way to prevent feeding problems is to teach your child to feed himself as early as possible, provide them with healthy choices and allow experimentation. Mealtimes should be enjoyable and pleasant and not a source of struggle. Common mistakes are allowing your child to drink too much milk or juice so that they aren&apos;t hungry for solids, forcing your child to eat when they aren&apos;t hungry, or forcing them to eat foods that they don&apos;t want. Also, avoid giving large amounts of sweet desserts, soft drinks, fruit-flavored drinks, sugarcoated cereals, chips or candy, as they have little nutritional value.
Your child may now start to refuse to eat some foods, become a very picky eater or even go on binges where they will only want to eat a certain food. An important way that children learn to be independent is through establishing independence about feeding. Even though your child may not be eating as well rounded a diet as you would like, as long as your child is growing normally and has a normal energy level, there is probably little to worry about. Remember that this is a period in his development where he is not growing very fast and doesn&apos;t need a lot of calories. Also, most children do not eat a balanced diet each and every day, but over the course of a week or so their diet will usually be well balanced. You can consider giving your child a daily vitamin if you think he is not eating well, although he probably doesn&apos;t need it.

While you should provide three well-balanced meals each day, it is important to keep in mind that most children will only eat one or two full meals each day. If you child has had a good breakfast and lunch, then it is okay that he doesn&apos;t want to eat much at dinner. Although your child will probably be hesitant to try new foods, you should still offer small amounts of them once or twice a week (one tablespoon of green beans, for example). Most children will try a new food after being offered it 10-15 times.

Other ways to prevent feeding problems are to not use food as a bribe or reward for desired behaviors, avoid punishing your child for not eating well, limit mealtime conversation to positive and pleasant topics, avoid discussing or commenting on your child&apos;s poor eating habits while at the table, limit eating and drinking to the table or high chair, and limit snacks to two nutritious snacks each day. You should also not prepare more than one meal for your child. If he doesn&apos;t want to eat what was prepared for the rest of the family, then he should not be forced to, but you should also not give him something else to eat. He will not starve after missing a single meal, and providing alternatives to the prepared meal will just cause more problems later.
 
 
 Calcium Requirements 
 Calcium is a mineral that is mostly present in your child&apos;s bones. Having a diet with foods that are high in calcium to meet daily requirements is necessary for the development of strong bones. It is also an important way to prevent the development of osteoporosis in adults.
 Preschool age children require about 500 to 800 mg of calcium each day. See the table below for the calcium content of common foods and check the nutrition label to choose foods high in calcium when you prepare your families diet. Also choose foods that are fortified with calcium.
 

 examples: Food Servings Calcium Content Milk, whole or lowfat 1 cup 300 mg White beans 1/2 cup 113 mg Broccoli, cooked 1/2 cup 35 mg Broccoli, raw 1 cup 35 mg Cheddar cheese 1.5 oz 300 mg Yogurt, lowfat 8 oz 300 mg Orange juice, calcium fortified 1 cup 300 mg Orange, medium 1 40-50 mg Sweet potatoes, mashed 1/2 cup 44 mg 



 
 
 Iron Requirements 
 Iron is another mineral that is important for your child&apos;s growth. Having a diet with foods that are high in iron to meet daily requirements is necessary for the development of strong muscles and production of blood.
 Preschool age children require about 10 mg of iron each day. See the table below for the iron content of common foods and check the nutrition label to choose foods high in iron when you prepare your families diet. Also choose foods that are fortified with iron (cereals, bread, rice, and pasta).
 

 examples: Food Servings Iron Content Beef, chicken, fish Liver Peanut butter Nuts and seeds Green peas, lima beans Pinto beans Spinach Greens, turnip/collard Strawberries Tomato juice Squash Whole grain bread Raisins Watermelon 



 
 
 Submit a Link | printer friendly format 
 
 
 

 




 
 

 

 


 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 Contact Us 
Copyright©1999 - 2011 Keep Kids Healthy, LLC All rights reserved.
 disclaimer | privacy policy | site index | online bookstore | help 

 Updated: February 2, 2003 

 Special Offers: Free Web Pages 

 Shop Online: amazon.com | drugstore.com | eBay! | 
 Also visit: 
 ADHD advice and information
 Expert Pediatrician - child health and parenting advice
 About Pediatrics - Expert Pediatric Parenting Advice 
 Father&apos;s First Year - read about Dr. Iannelli&apos;s new book
 
 Important disclaimer : The information on keepkidshealthy.com is for educational purposes only and should not be considered to be medical advice . It is not meant to replace the advice of the physician who cares for your child. All medical advice and information should be considered to be incomplete without a physical exam, which is not possible without a visit to your doctor.
	</body>
</document>
