<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002190" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/Long-Beach/Lucky-Wok-Chinese-Fast-Food" time="2012-07-12-18:05" support="1" score="0.001642578052730253" bingtitle="Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food - Fast Food Restaurant Long Beach, CA ..." webtitle="Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food - Fast Food Restaurant  Long Beach, CA 90806">
			<query id="000167" bing-rank="136"/>
	<description>Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food is a Fast Food restaurant ... A: &quot;Number one, it&apos;s very hot. It gives you that ... You will soon begin to receive the newsletters you ...</description>
	<body>
		0 Friend Requests Friend Requests 0 Messages Send a New Message Messages 0 Notifications Notifications 
 
 Find Friends Login 
 or login with: User Pages Photos Events Videos Polls Forum Threads Restaurant Search Results For User Search Results For Pages Search Results For Photos Search Results For Events Search Results For Videos Search Results For Polls Search Results For Forum Threads Search Results For Restaurant 
 Places Deals Recipes Photos Members Blog 
 
 Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Lucky Wok Chinese Fast
Food

 
Average User Rating
 
5
 
Average
 
Sponsored Link


 
(562) 218-2102

 
 CA &gt; Long Beach &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food
 Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food is a Fast Food restaurant located at 1001 E Pacific Coast Highway # 12 in Long Beach, CA 90806. Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food has been described as an Good Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 5 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food, Chinese, Chinese Accepts Credit Card: N/A Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: N/A Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food
 
 
 
All Reviews for Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food


 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   0

 
Comments
 
 
Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food News
 World Chefs: Hom seeks the yin-and-yang in Chinese food NEW YORK ... using a wok? A: &quot;Number one, it&apos;s very hot. It gives you that grilled, smoked flavor. And it&apos;s fast, quick and easy.&quot; Q: You worked in your uncle&apos;s restaurant when you were 11. Were you as enthusiastic about Chinese food then? New York: Tucking into the Big Apple But not this time -- my new trick is not only to plan what sight I&apos;ll take in but also to make sure there is a good eatery nearby. The food bit started on a great note; I was lucky ... restaurants; my latest find, suggested to me by delightful New York ... Delta to Bring Renowned Chefs, Fresh Food and Beverage Options to Expanded Terminal C at New York&apos;s LaGuardia NEW YORK ... Chinese favorites including Lo Mein, roasted and barbecued meats and dumplings. At Xun Su, all of the Lo Mein dishes are wok&apos;d to order in front of guests, and the menu offers a higher level of quality and freshness than typical ... A taste of heaven Beyond the front door and a shelf of lucky green bamboo shoots ... with their own trips to New York City. Food would sometimes spoil on the long bus trip back. The Hoowa is named for their old home in China. It translates roughly as &quot;expatriots ... Insatiable appetites for food and travel Like the artisan confectionary at Few and Far, a food-cum-homeware store on London&apos;s Brompton Road. Or cheese in Paris at Barthelemy, followed by a tour of the wonders of Le Bon Marche&apos;s food hall. In New York ... restaurants so we&apos;re pretty lucky in ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing Chinese Fast Wok - New York Restaurant - MenuPages Chinese ... Thanks for subscribing! You will soon begin to receive the newsletters you selected. To enjoy more benefits and personalization available on MenuPages.com, register now! Lucky Wok Chinese Restaurant - Lisle, IL (630) 305-8833 · 6452 College Rd · &quot;I ordered the Tofu Country Style (extra spicy.&quot; ... &quot;I love dumplings and hot and sour soup .&quot; Fast Food Chinese Restaurants in USA - ads at PennySaverUSA Get e-mail alerts when new listings show up that match this search! This is a great time-saver. You can stop these e-mails anytime. Lucky Chinese Fast Food - El Cajon - El Cajon, CA Categories: Restaurants Chinese Restaurants Fast Food Chinese, Fast Food. 1571 N Magnolia Ave El Cajon, CA 92020 Neighborhood: El Cajon (619) 448-3101 Panda Express: Chinese Food, Wok-Cooked and Served Fast © 2002-2012 Panda Restaurant Group, Inc. All rights reserved. Privacy Policy Gift Card Terms&amp;Conditions 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 63° 
Fri
 
 66° - 95° 
Sat
 
 63° - 88° 
Sun
 
 61° - 77° 
 
Address
 
Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food

1001 E Pacific Coast High
way # 12

Long Beach, CA 
 
90806
 
Telephone
 (562) 218-2102 
Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food
 
 Rating :  5 out of 10 based on 5 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food Photos
 
 Fast Food Chinese Chinese 
 
 Local Places
 
 Subway 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Popeye&apos;s Chicken&amp;Biscuits 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Le Yen Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Pete&apos;s Patio Long Beach 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food The Quizno&apos;s Master LLC 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Gondola Getaway 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Jack in the Box 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Prospector Family Restaurant&amp;Cocktail Lounge 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Tita Susan Fast Foods 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food McDonald&apos;s 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food KFC 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Taco Bell 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Wingstop Restaurant 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Angkorwat Art of Cambodia 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Arts Council for Long Beach 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Delightful Designs 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Fyb 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries Holdredge Gallery 
Cuisine: Art Museums Galleries 
 

See all Long Beach Art Museums Galleries 
See all Long Beach ATMs 
See all Long Beach Bars and Pubs 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food Coupons 

 Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food Long Beach 

 Lucky Wok Chinese Fast Food Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 Long Beach Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H I | J | K | L | M | N | O | P Q | R | S | T | U | V | W | Y Z 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
