<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002882" url="http://www.qualityhealth.com/tag/high-cholesterol+original-articles" time="2012-07-12-18:57" support="2" score="0.0017736670880265273" bingtitle="Cholesterol + Original Articles - QualityHealth: Health ..." webtitle="Cholesterol + Original Articles">
			<query id="000081" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="000864" bing-rank="246"/>
	<description>... some hair salons and barbers have been dispensing more ... from the salad bar of your local deli or fast-food restaurant ... Unlimited soda refills. Burgers the size of ball ...</description>
	<body>
		Search Login --Email-- -Password- Forgot Password Create Your Profile 
 Health Centers 
 ADD/ADHD Allergies Alzheimer&apos;s Disease Anxiety Arthritis Asthma Autism Bipolar Disorder Breast Cancer COPD Cancer Caregiving 

 Children&apos;s Cholesterol Colds&amp;Infections Crohn&apos;s Disease Dental&amp;Vision Depression Diabetes Diet&amp;Weight Loss Eating&amp;Nutrition Epilepsy Erectile Dysfunction Fitness&amp;Exercise 

 Flu Treatment Healthy Aging Heart Health Heartburn&amp;GERD IBS Incontinence Men&apos;s Health Center Meningitis Menopause Mental Health Migraines&amp;Headaches Multiple Sclerosis 

 Osteoporosis Pain Management Parkinson&apos;s Disease Pregnancy Relationships Sexual Health Skin Care&amp;Beauty Sleep Management Smoking Cessation Stomach&amp;Digestive Women&apos;s Health 
 News Expert Q&amp;A Tools 
 Ask Your Doctor Symptom Checker Health Encyclopedia Glossary Surgery&amp;Procedures Alternative Medicine In-Depth Reports 
 Recipes Drugs 
 A B C D E F 

 G H I J K L 

 M N O P Q R 

 S T U V W X 

 Y Z 
 Community 
 Blogs Support Groups 
 Special Offers 
 Health Offers Grocery Store Coupons 
 Create Your Profile 
 
Cholesterol + Original Articles
 
 Stenting vs. Bypass: What Are the Key Differences? 
 Understand the key differences between these two treatment options for coronary artery disease (CAD). Questions of the heart aren&apos;t only for romantics and pop musicians. Cardiologists face plenty of them too. Of course, rather than ruminating on love, heart doctors have to weigh medical decisions that often have no clear right or wrong answers. One of their most common dilemmas is whether to recommend stents or bypass surgery to patients with severe coronary artery disease (CAD). 
 Peripheral Arterial Disease: What You Need to Know 
 Up to 12 million people in the U.S. are currently living with this condition. Here are the risk factors and treatments options. So you have a cramp in your leg. It&apos;s just part of getting older, right? Well, maybe not. Recurrent pain in the legs is one symptom of peripheral arterial disease, or PAD. Up to 12 million people in the United States are living with this circulatory disorder. 
 &quot;Sedentary Lifestyle&quot;: What Do The Buzzwords Really Mean? 
 Here&apos;s what counts as a sedentary lifestyle plus the easiest ways to avoid leading one. The news headlines are clear: &quot;Sitting All Day Is Killing You,&quot; &quot;Couch Potatoes Double Risk for Heart Disease,&quot; &quot;Move It to Live.&quot; Perhaps you can&apos;t blame the media for sensationalized stories when there&apos;s such solid evidence linking cardiovascular disease to a sedentary life spent sitting to work, sitting to travel, sitting to watch television, and, now, even sitting to interact with friends virtually. 
 5 Symptoms Men Ignore 
 Men can prevent health risks by paying attention to changes in their body and seeing their doctor when something isn&apos;t right. When it comes to scheduling doctor visits, some men are notorious procrastinators. This can be risky. Routine preventive care can find diseases in men in the early stages, when there are more options for treatment and better chances of treating the issue. 
 Health by the Numbers: Cholesterol 
 High cholesterol puts you at a higher risk for serious health conditions, including heart attack and stroke. Here&apos;s a look at cholesterol by the numbers. Your body produces cholesterol, a waxy, fat-like substance, but it&apos;s also is found in certain foods. If you eat too much of the wrong kind of foods, you can develop high blood cholesterol, which increases the odds of getting coronary heart disease.
Plaque comprised of cholesterol and other substances builds up in the arteries and causes a condition called atherosclerosis (hardening of the arteries). 
 Is Avandia Safe? 
 The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) has established new restrictions on the use of Avandia, a widely used diabetes treatment. In 2004, the FDA approved Avandia, in combination with insulin, to treat type 2 diabetes. Avandia is the brand name for rosiglitazone. In 2007, the agency reported a possible association between rosiglitazone and an increased risk of cardiovascular events, such as heart attack. 
 Is Heart Attack Possible Without Risk Factors? 
 Even if you exercise, eat right, and never smoke, you could still be at risk. You&apos;ve seen the numbers and they&apos;re grim. According to the CDC, an estimated 935,000 heart attacks occur each year and of those, one third are fatal. One in four deaths is caused by heart disease and a heart attack is one possible outcome of heart or cardiovascular disease. 
 Green Tea for Health&amp;Beauty 
 With a wealth of antioxidants, green tea is used for weight loss, skin care, and for anti-aging. Is it too good to be true? Research shows the benefits of green tea may range from rejuvenating older skin to warding off cancer. It contains a cornucopia of antioxidants and minerals such as magnesium, zinc, calcium, iron, and vitamins C, D, and K.
Green Tea for Weight Loss
You are right to be suspicious of the green tea &quot;miracle&quot; weight loss formulas, but there is some truth to the fad. 
 Why Do Men Die First? 
 Recent statistics compiled by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) give women at birth an average life expectancy of 80.4 years compared with 75.4 years for men. So why is there such a gap? On average, men in the United States die approximately five years earlier than women. Statistics compiled by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) in 2010 give women an average life expectancy of 80.4 years compared with 75.4 years for men. 
 Heart Disease in the Family? Protect Yourself 
 Family history significantly increases your chance of developing heart disease. Reduce your risk with these steps. Some diseases seem to run in families. Heart disease is one of them. A family history significantly increases your risk for also developing heart disease.
Unfortunately, heart disease is common-and deadly. More than 600,000 Americans die from heart disease annually. 
 4 Heart Facts Every Woman Should Know 
 When it comes to your cardiovascular health, the essentials are clear. At one point in the melodramatic (but undeniably enchanting) movie Titanic the heroine, Rose, remarks, &quot;A woman&apos;s heart is a deep ocean of secrets.&quot; That&apos;s the truth! Beyond harboring long-lost loves and tales of tragic shipwrecks, your heart holds health secrets. 
 Low-Cholesterol Dos and Don&apos;ts 
 Follow these simple strategies to get your cholesterol levels where you want them to be. You&apos;re working hard to eat right so you can lower your cholesterol levels. You&apos;re reading nutrition labels, buying fewer pre-packaged foods, and testing yourself often. But you&apos;re still struggling to keep your cholesterol down. What are you doing wrong?
The answer may surprise you. 
 5 Exams That Could Save Your Life 
 These simple tests can help detect common health conditions before they escalate. In today&apos;s busy world, medical exams often take a backseat to work, family, and other commitments. In fact, 28 percent of women don&apos;t go for their annual Pap tests, and only 32 percent know their cholesterol numbers. Could this behavior be compromising your health? Here&apos;s a list of five exams you can&apos;t afford to put off another day. 
 10 Holiday Eating Tips 
 These healthy eating tips will help you make it to New Year&apos;s without the extra pounds or the guilt. A healthy diet can be difficult to maintain at any time of year, but once the holiday season rolls around, the task becomes ten times harder. It all begins at Thanksgiving dinner with freshly carved turkey, mashed potatoes with sour cream, corn-bread stuffing, and of course, the all-American apple pie. 
 What Does &quot;Zero Trans Fats&quot; Really Mean? 
 Nutrition labels can be deceiving. Learn how to cut though the hype and make healthier choices. If the nutrition label reads &quot;zero grams trans fat&quot; it must be healthy, right? Wrong! As it turns out, federal regulations allow labels to read &quot;zero grams trans fat&quot; as long as a product contains less than 0.5 grams of the artery-clogging fat per serving. 
 Give Your Fridge a Makeover 
 With these six easy tips, you can transform your refrigerator and your health. When you run to your fridge for a midnight snack, what do you grab? Leftover takeout? Ice cream? Pizza? If so, your fridge may be in need of an extreme makeover.
As most of us know, we are what we eat, and the best way to change the way we eat, look, and feel is by changing what we keep in our kitchens. 
 A Year of Living Less Dangerously 
 Keeping up with all your health screenings may seem daunting, but this list can get you started on a year of healthy living. In a perfect world, we&apos;d all know exactly when we need to get our important health screenings. In reality, however, these checkups and exams often take a backseat to work, family, and other obligations.
Fortunately, you can get on the right track by making a simple phone call to your doctor. 
 Most Women Don&apos;t Know Their Cholesterol Numbers 
 Women are far more likely to remember their high-school weights than their cholesterol levels. Adult women are more than twice as likely to know how much they weighed in high school than they are to know their current cholesterol number, and only half have had their cholesterol tested in the past year, according to results of a nationwide survey. 
 The 5 Healthiest Foods You&apos;re Not Eating 
 Add these super foods to your diet, and give your health an instant boost. By now, you probably know which foods you should avoid sugary colas, greasy snacks, fatty fast foods. But what about the many nutritious foods nature has to offer? While many people are familiar with the well-publicized superfoods, such as berries, salmon, and spinach, there&apos;s an abundance of lesser-known treats that can also do wonders for your health. 
 The Truth About Triglycerides 
 When it comes to assessing cholesterol, HDL and LDL get most of the focus. But there&apos;s another category that deserves equal attention. Triglycerides are essential to human life. These chains of fatty acids are absorbed into your system from the foods you eat and are even created by your own body. They circulate through your bloodstream, providing energy to cells and enabling your body to function. 
 Southern Home Cooking Lightens Up 
 Sugar, butter, and cream may be one celebrity chef&apos;s go-to ingredients, but that doesn&apos;t mean you should follow in her footsteps. You can still recreate the cuisine of the Queen of Southern Cooking without doing damage to your health. Let a team of experts show you how. Now that Paula Deen&apos;s been diagnosed with Type 2 diabetes, it&apos;s time for her followers to rethink adding all that butter, cream, and sugar to food to make it taste good.
It&apos;s certainly possible to switch out high-fat, high-cholesterol ingredients for more healthful ones, nutrition experts say. 
 Find Your Personal Fitness ID 
 One size doesn&apos;t fit all when it comes to getting in shape. No matter where you start out, you have a unique fitness ID to discover, develop, and change as you grow. The American College of Sports Medicine (ACSM) agrees that fitness is not a one-size-fits-all thing. Every person has unique factors that affect their health, fitness level, and fitness goals.
That&apos;s why trying to fit into someone else&apos;s fitness profile doesn&apos;t usually work and, in fact, often causes injury. 
 Can a Heart Attack Occur Without Chest Pain? 
 If you&apos;re used to the dramatic representations of heart attacks on TV, you may be surprised to learn about real-life scenarios. How many times have you seen this act on TV? The character on the screen gets a glazed look in his eyes, stumbles, and clutches his chest as he slowly (and dramatically) falls to the ground. This is the classic Hollywood depiction of a heart attack. And while this scenario might accurately describe some heart attacks, it&apos;s not representative. 
 10 Healthy, Kid-Friendly Kitchen Must-Haves 
 Almond butter. Sweet potatoes. Avocados. Jicama. Keeping foods like these on hand will help your child look at healthy eating as less of a chore and more of a choice. Want your kids to start enjoying the healthy meals and snacks you prepare for them? You may need to rethink your grocery shopping list. If you&apos;re buying the same items week in and week out, your child may be bored with your cooking. Switch things up a bit, nutrition experts suggest, by buying the makings for meals kids will love despite the fact that the meals are healthy. 
 How to Use 10 Powerful Herbs 
 Suffering from anxiety? Stomach issues? A cold that wont quit? Theres an herb for you. Herbs and spices are as at-home in your medicine chest as they are in your pantry. That&apos;s because they possess powerful healing properties that have been used as medicinals for thousands of years. Check out these 10 common herbs you may already have growing in your yard or sitting in your spice rack. 
 Cholesterol: The Good and the Bad 
 Youve probably heard the terms good cholesterol and bad cholesterol bandied about, but what are the key differences between the two? This go-to guide clears the confusion. You&apos;ve probably heard the terms &quot;good cholesterol&quot; and &quot;bad cholesterol&quot; bandied about and may not understand their significance. Cholesterol is one of the risk factors for heart disease, so it pays to know what it is and how you can control it.
Cholesterol
Cholesterol is a naturally occurring waxy substance that attaches to proteins in our blood and travels throughout our body. 
 Should Kids Be Screened for High Cholesterol? 
 Get the experts&apos; take on this much debated matter of the heart. Should you or shouldn&apos;t you? That&apos;s the big question when it comes to cholesterol screening for children and adolescents, and the answer seems far from clear.
In 2007, the United States Preventive Task Force (USPTF), an independent panel of experts, established screening guidelines for lipid abnormalities in children. 
 White Foods May Reduce Stroke Risk 
 White fruits and vegetables contain as many essential nutrients and other health-promoting substances as do red, yellow, and green foods. And some of these substances may be especially important for aging adults. Don&apos;t be fooled by their lack of color—white fruits and vegetables contain as many essential nutrients and other health-promoting substances as do red, yellow, and green foods. And some of these substances may be especially important for aging adults. 
 An Apple Peel a Day 
 Studies have found that the skin on an apple contains a substance that not only promotes muscle growth and prevents the loss of muscle that comes with aging, but may also lower blood sugar, cholesterol, and triglycerides. Laboratory studies have found that the skin on an apple contains a substance that not only promotes muscle growth and prevents the loss of muscle that comes with aging, but may also lower blood sugar, cholesterol, and triglycerides.
In addition to vitamins, minerals, fiber, and other substances such as antioxidants and phytochemicals that are known to protect against cancer and other forms of chronic disease, apples contain a chemical called ursolic acid. 
 Broken Hearts: How Your Relationship Affects Your Heart Health 
 The ups and downs associated with relationships don&apos;t pertain only to emotions. In fact, your partnership, good or bad, can have a real effect on your body. When you and your partner or significant other are happy together, your stress level plummets, and your heart thanks you for it. Conversely, a toxic relationship puts considerable stress and unhappiness on a couple, and their hearts can show the strain, experts say. 
 Exercise: Just What the Doctor Ordered? 
 Physicians and fitness experts are teaming up to help patients exercise their way to wellness. One of the top fitness trends of 2011 is teaming physicians with fitness experts to bring the power of exercise to health care. That&apos;s because exercise is often the best medicine.
Studies say that physical inactivity costs the U.S. health care system about $102 billion dollars per year. 
 Many Seniors Leave Hospital Without Their Regular Meds 
 An alarming number of older patients fail to continue taking their regular medications after they return home, particularly if they spent time in intensive care. While hospitals can be lifesavers, especially for the elderly, an alarming number of older patients fail to continue taking their regular medications after they return home—particularly if they spent time in intensive care. Why? Mainly because they neglect to renew their prescriptions. 
 Why Starchy and Fatty Foods Are Hard to Digest 
 Starchy foods are essential for energy, and fatty foods can make you feel fuller. But there are a host of health complications that can ensue if you consume too much of both. Learn how eating the right combination of foods can help your digestive system function at its best. Did you know that your gut contains 500 species of bacteria and that altogether, they weigh about three pounds? These bacteria play a critical role in digestion and other important health-related functions. Eating the wrong foods can throw off the delicate balance of good and bad bacteria and cause a host of digestive (and other) health problems. 
 How Flaxseed Can Fix Your Digestion 
 You&apos;ve heard of the digestive and nutritional benefits of flaxseed, now learn how you can incorporate this potent grain into your daily menu. Flaxseed is a grain that is rich in soluble fiber. It&apos;s also a plant source of phytochemicals called lignans and omega-3 fatty acids—a powerful antioxidant.
Flaxseed has been commonly used as a laxative to improve constipation and promote digestive health. 
 10 Easy Ways to Lower Your Cholesterol 
 Heart disease is the number-one killer of men and women in the United States. The good news is there are many simple steps you can take to reduce your risk of developing high cholesterol and managing the problem if it occurs. Heart disease is the number-one killer of men and women in the United States, with about 2,200 Americans dying from the problem each day. Too much bad (LDL) cholesterol or not enough good (HDL) cholesterol in your blood can put you at risk for coronary heart disease, heart attack, or stroke. 
 Demystifying Metabolic Syndrome 
 If your doctor diagnoses you with metabolic syndrome, don&apos;t panic and think you&apos;ve come down with some fatal disease. Instead, consider it a warning sign that your long-term health is at risk, and resolve to take action. If your doctor diagnoses you with metabolic syndrome, don&apos;t panic and think you&apos;ve come down with some fatal disease. Instead, consider it a warning sign that your long-term health is at risk, and resolve to take action.
While metabolic syndrome puts you at risk for developing type 2 diabetes and cardiovascular disease, a variety of lifestyle changes can help put it behind you. 
 Health Advice at the Hair Salon 
 Over the last few years, some hair salons and barbers have been dispensing more than just trims. They&apos;ve been giving out health advice, too. In some communities, particularly where many African-Americans live, the local salon or barber shop is a cultural institution. Men and women alike visit these social hubs on a regular basis not only to get their hair done but to connect with friends and neighbors in a familiar, comforting environment where they can talk, share, vent, and just be themselves. 
 How to Eat Healthy at the Airport 
 There&apos;s always something to eat at the airport, especially if you&apos;re at one of the larger &quot;hub&quot; airports. Unfortunately, where there are more food vendors, there are more opportunities for unhealthy options and food safety violations. Eating at airports, especially when you&apos;re in a hurry, is pretty much the nutritional equivalent of eating at a truck stop. But the problem is not just finding and choosing healthier foods or piecing together something that resembles a balanced meal. It&apos;s also about finding food that&apos;s safe to eat. 
 All About Egg Yolks, Whites, and Substitutes 
 Whole or separated, in recipes or on their own, eggs are an important part of most people&apos;s diets. But if you&apos;re concerned about heart disease, shouldn&apos;t you worry about the fat and cholesterol in eggs? Not when you know which parts of the egg to use, and when to use them. Whole or separated, in recipes or on their own, eggs are an important part of most people&apos;s diets. But if you&apos;re concerned about heart disease, shouldn&apos;t you worry about the fat and cholesterol in eggs? Not if you know which parts of the egg to use, and when to use them. 
 &quot;Balanced Diet&quot;: What Does It Mean for You? 
 Following a balanced diet can help you lower your blood sugar and cholesterol, and it ensures you&apos;ll enjoy lots of delicious and healthy options. Here&apos;s how to do it. If the thought of following a &quot;balanced diet&quot; has you so confused you&apos;re a bit, well, off balance, not to worry. The June issue of Diabetes Forecast, the magazine of the American Diabetes Association, outlines some simple steps for adopting a diet that&apos;s not just balanced, but tasty and easy to follow, too. 
 Heart Disease: Fight the Number One Killer 
 Heart disease is the number one killer of women in the U.S. Did you know there are four steps you can take to reduce your risk of heart disease by up to 82 percent? Although breast cancer is the disease women fear most, according to a study by the Society for Women&apos;s Health Research, heart disease is actually the number one killer of women—approximately 500,000 women die annually from heart disease—far surpassing the death rate of breast cancer, about 41,000 each year. 
 What Does the Polypill Promise? 
 This once-a-day single pill combines aspirin, blood pressure, and cholesterol drugs to reduce heart disease risk and treat the problem once it develops. If you haven&apos;t heard about the polypill yet, chances are you will soon. Research is showing that a once-a-day single pill that combines aspirin, blood pressure, and cholesterol drugs to reduce heart disease risk and treat the problem once it develops may be safe and effective. 
 Omega-3, Omega-6, Omega-9: The Basics 
 Omega-3, omega-6, and omega-9 fatty acids confer a variety of health benefits when consumed on a regular basis and in the right amounts. Three-six-nine, the goose drank wine... or was it fish oil? If it was fish oil, or certain vegetable oils, that would be one healthy goose because the omega-3, omega-6, and omega-9 fatty acids found in these oils confer a variety of medical benefits when they are consumed on a regular basis and in the right amounts. 
 Heart-Smart Salad Bar Selections 
 Building a salad can be one of the best things you can do for your heart, or one of the worst. Here&apos;s how to construct a cardio-friendly creation, without sacrificing great flavor. In these busy times, grabbing a quick meal from the salad bar of your local deli or fast-food restaurant chain may not only shave precious minutes from your day; it may also provide all the ingredients you need for a healthy heart—if you choose well. 
 Should You Take Safflower Oil for a Healthier Heart? 
 There&apos;s good news for people looking to lower their risk for heart disease. A new study published in the journal Clinical Nutrition reveals that taking a daily dose of safflower oil—about 1 2/3 teaspoons—might help keep heart disease at bay. The findings come from a study of obese, postmenopausal women who have type 2 diabetes and were given the safflower oil for 16 weeks. 
 In Pursuit of the Perfect Chip 
 Nowadays, it&apos;s easy to find great-tasting chips made from taro root, sweet potatoes, soybeans, black beans, pinto beans, adzuki beans, pita bread, rice, or even apples. Every body loves chips! And the good news is: Your choices are no longer restricted to potato or corn. Now it&apos;s easy to find great tasting chips made from taro root, sweet potatoes, soybeans, black beans, pinto beans, adzuki beans, pita bread, rice, or even apples. 
 Your Kitchen Makeover for Heart Health 
 Taking stock of the kinds of foods in your pantry and refrigerator and replacing the ones that increase your risk for cardiovascular disease with nutritious, flavorful whole foods, will help you and your family make heart-smart food choices and reduce your risk of heart disease. Heart disease is the number-one killer of both men and women. But making just a few simple changes to your diet can make a big difference in keeping you and your family heart-healthy. And the first place to start is in the kitchen.
Start Your Heart Healthy Kitchen Makeover Here
The American Heart Association recommends that you eat a wide variety of nutritious foods every day. 
 Updated Heart Guidelines for Women 
 What &quot;real world&quot; preventative steps should you incorporate into your life to lower your chances of heart disease? Earlier this year, the American Heart Association (AHA) updated its cardiovascular prevention guidelines for women, which take into account what works best for women in the &quot;real world&quot; settings as opposed to findings from clinical trial research.
First... 
 Whose Heart Health Is Ideal? 
 Nearly 2,000 people were evaluated against seven heart-healthy criteria set by the American Heart Association. The results may surprise you. Just one out of 1,900 people evaluated in a study published in Circulation, met the criteria for ideal cardiovascular health set by the American Heart Association (AHA).
The study, initiated by researchers at the University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine in Pennsylvania, evaluated 1,933 people, ages 45 to 75, through surveys, physical exams, and blood tests. 
 What Causes a Heart Attack? 
 A new study reveals some surprising factors when it comes to what brings on a heart attack. Everyday occurrences such as drinking coffee and alcohol, physical exertion and even breathing can help spur a heart attack, according to a Belgium study published in the journal The Lancet. The study researchers analyzed data from 36 separate studies of potential triggers for heart attack in people ranging in age from 44 to 72 years old. 
 Employee Fitness Programs: A Win-Win 
 It&apos;s hard to find time for fitness, a sensible diet, and health screenings, especially when you work full time. That is, unless health and fitness opportunities come directly to you. It&apos;s hard to find time for fitness, a sensible diet, and health screenings—especially when you work full time. That is, unless health and fitness opportunities come directly to you. Employee fitness and health programs are par for the course at many large companies. 
 All About Quinoa 
 This tasty, nutritious little seed has become a favorite among natural food lovers everywhere. See what people are saying about this article on our Facebook page!
Once considered a mere provision for people in third world countries, this tasty, nutritious little seed has become a favorite among natural food lovers everywhere.
Quinoa—pronounced keen-wah, with an emphasis on keen—is a high-protein seed that is eaten like a grain. 
 Hate the Doctor? Here&apos;s the Bare Minimum for Health 
 If you can&apos;t remember the last time you saw a doctor (taking your kids to the pediatrician doesn&apos;t count), you&apos;re probably long overdue for a checkup. Whether it&apos;s ego, lack of time, or just not fond of needles, men are known to resist medical care. If you can&apos;t remember the last time you saw a doctor (taking your kids to the pediatrician doesn&apos;t count), you&apos;re probably long overdue for a checkup. Whether it&apos;s ego, lack of time, or just not fond of needles, men are known to resist medical care.
The statistics from the U. 
 The New USDA Dietary Guidelines, Decoded 
 All-you-can-eat buffets. Unlimited soda refills. Burgers the size of ball fields. When it comes to food, America serves it up. It&apos;s no wonder one-third of our children and two-thirds of adults are overweight or obese. Here&apos;s what you need to know to help your family eat better. In an effort to improve the overall health of our nation, the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) recently released new dietary guidelines (January 2011). The revised guidelines place a stronger emphasis on reducing calorie consumption and increasing physical activity. 
 Nuts about Nuts? Your Heart Says Thanks 
 What&apos;s the story behind the crunchy snack that&apos;s good for your heart? Nuts about nuts? Good for you! They make everything from brownies to cookies taste better, they&apos;re delicious in stir-fries, and they add texture and crunch to salads. Best of all, nuts are good for your cardiovascular health, so feel free to work them into your daily meal plan. 
 4 Bad Sleep Habits Men Have 
 Sleep deprivation is a growing epidemic in this country, and neither gender has a lock on it. But there are a few behaviors of which men seem to be particularly guilty. Sleep problems seem to be a national emergency, and neither gender has a lock on bad sleep habits. But there are a few behaviors of which men seem to be particularly guilty. Check out this list and see if any of these unsound practices sound familiar:
Overdoing the caffeine. 
 Work Stress: Hazardous to Your Health 
 According to a new study, women who experience high stress on their jobs have an increased risk for heart attack or other forms of heart disease. According to a new study, women who experience high stress on their jobs have an increased risk for heart attack or other forms of heart disease.
The findings, based on data from 17,415 healthy middle-aged women participating in the Women&apos;s Health Study,... 
 Risks and Benefits of Eating Heart-Healthy Fish 
 When it comes to mercury exposure from fish, what do you need to know to make the healthiest choices? According to a recent Swedish study published in the American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, the benefits of eating fish may outweigh the potential negative impact of mercury exposure from fish.
The study analyzed responses from more than 900 Swedish adults about the amount of fish in their diet and then examined the subjects&apos; red blood cells for levels of mercury and selenium. 
 Normal Cholesterol, High Triglycerides 
 High triglyceride levels can increase heart disease risk. Here&apos;s what you should know. Even though your latest physical may have shown that your cholesterol levels are normal, you may still be at risk for heart disease if your triglycerides level is high.
A 20-year study conducted by the University of Washington School of Public Health... 
 What&apos;s Really in Your Coffee Creamer? 
 It probably doesn&apos;t matter what type of creamer you use, or what&apos;s on the ingredient list if you drink a cup of coffee a day. But if you drink several cups a day, and add more than the standard serving size of creamer per cup, you may be getting more fat and sugar than you bargained for. If you only drink one cup of coffee a day, it probably doesn&apos;t matter what type of creamer you use, or what&apos;s on the ingredient list. But if you drink several cups a day, and add more than the standard serving size of creamer per cup, you may be getting more fat and sugar than you bargained for. 
 5 Resolutions for a Healthy Heart 
 Heart disease may be the leading cause of death for both men and women, but there are many things you can do now to avoid it. Heart disease may be the leading cause of death for both men and women, but there are many things you can do now to avoid heart disease. And what better time than the beginning of the New Year to put prevention steps in effect?
Here are five things you can do to ensure a heart-healthy New Year. 
 Get Heart Healthy With Digital Trainers 
 Heart rate monitors help you keep track of your fitness level and even offer motivating messages. Several companies, including Suunto, Polar, and Timex, make heart rate monitors that help you keep track of your fitness level, tells you the number of calories burned, gives you your heart rate and even provides you with motivation-boosting messages, displayed on the watch face. 
 The Dangers of Being &quot;Skinny Fat&quot; 
 What is the normal weight obesity condition and what can you do about it? Mayo researchers have coined a new condition: normal weight obesity (NWO) also known as &quot;skinny fat.&quot;
According to research from the Mayo Clinic, more than half of American adults thought to have normal body weight, as defined by their body mass index... 
 Understanding Lipoprotein Tests 
 To determine if you are at risk for developing cardiovascular disease, your doctor may suggest that you be given a cardiac risk assessment. Among the tests used to assess your cardiac risk is a lipoprotein (a), or Lp(a), blood test. Have a family history of heart disease? To determine if you are at risk for developing cardiovascular disease, your doctor may suggest that you be given a cardiac risk assessment. Cardiac risk assessments include a series of tests, as well as a review of your personal medical history, to help assess the likelihood that you may have a future cardiovascular event such as a heart attack or stroke. 
 Bypass Surgery or Angioplasty: Which is Most Effective? 
 New study findings released this fall have found that coronary artery bypass surgery is more effective than coronary angioplasty and stenting in patients with severe heart disease. If you or a loved one suffers from heart disease, there are a variety of treatment options available. The trouble is, which one is the best? Which is most effective?
New study findings released this fall have found that coronary artery bypass surgery is more effective than coronary angioplasty and stenting in patients with severe heart disease. 
 5 Heart-Smart Fall Foods 
 Take advantage of the bounty of autumn with these healthy, hearty, heart-smart foods. Good nutrition is essential in your fight against heart disease, and autumn offers some of the most colorful-and healthful-foods. To stay heart healthy, the American Heart Association (AHA) recommends that you stick to a diet that includes:
At least 4. 
 5 Heart-Smart Fall Activities 
 Here are five ways to help you enjoy the outdoors this autumn and stay heart fit. If the record-breaking heat kept you cooped up indoors this summer, the cool, crisp days of autumn give you the perfect excuse to spend time outside.
The days may be getting shorter, but that shouldn&apos;t keep you from enjoying fun fall activities, just remember to dress for the weather and the activity you have planned. 
 How Your Heart Works 
 Our heart is at the center of our physical well-being, literally. And when it doesn&apos;t work correctly, it can mean big trouble. Here, an engaging, but easy-to-understand rundown of how this crucial organ works. The heart is so synonymous with love that when we talk about a broken heart, it&apos;s usually an emotional response to a romantic relationship that&apos;s gone bad. But, in fact, our hearts are at the center of our physical well-being—literally. The heart, about the size of clenched fist, is a cone-shaped muscle located under the rib cage, between the lungs and behind the sternum (breastbone). 
 The Truth about the &quot;Beer Belly&quot; 
 Beerthe beverage favored by most men nationwide. It could accompany your nightly dinner or favorite TV program. A six-pack may join you during your weekend barbeque or while you watch the game. Regardless of when you consume it, one thing tends to remainthe beer belly. Beer-the beverage favored by most men nationwide. It could accompany your nightly dinner or favorite TV program. A six-pack may join you during your weekend barbeque or while you watch the game. Regardless of when you consume it, one thing tends to remain-the beer belly. 
 Milk: It Does Your Heart Good 
 Although dairy foods have long been associated with heart disease because of their high content of saturated fat, a new study from Sweden suggests that they may actually help maintain heart health. Although dairy foods have long been associated with heart disease because of their high content of saturated fat, a new study from Sweden suggests that eating dairy foods may actually help maintain heart health by lowering high blood pressure and cholesterol levels. 
 5 Heart-Smart Summer Foods 
 Now is the perfect time to take advantage of the produce available at your local farmers&apos; market or green grocer. Now is the perfect time to take advantage of the bounty of seasonal produce available at your local farmers&apos; market or green grocer. Not only are the fruits and vegetables now in the marketplace good for lowering inflammation and cholesterol, both important for cardiovascular health, the nutrients they provide can also slow down age-related changes that can lead to a variety of chronic diseases, improve your skin and help you maintain a healthy weight. 
 4 Heart-Smart Summer Activities 
 In addition to being fun, regular physical activity can help keep your cholesterol and blood pressure in check. So if you&apos;re looking for ways to stay fit this summer, we&apos;ve got plenty of great calorie-burning ideas. The warmer weather and longer days of summer are great inducers to be outdoors and be active. In addition to being fun, maintaining an active physical routine can also keep you heart healthy by reducing your risk of heart disease, improving your blood cholesterol levels and preventing and managing high blood pressure. 
 The Heart Benefits of Garlic 
 Although garlic may not ward off evil spirits, it may be instrumental in warding off a variety of health problems, including heart disease. Although scientific studies showing a heart-protective benefit are not conclusive, they are showing promise in the use of garlic to help prevent heart disease, including atherosclerosis (plaque buildup in the arteries that can prevent blood flow and possibly lead to heart attack or stroke), high cholesterol, and high blood pressure. 
 Cholesterol Drugs for Healthy Adults: A Risky Move? 
 Risks have been found for healthy people taking cholesterol drugs. In February of 2010, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approved the expanded use of AstraZeneca&apos;s cholesterol-lowering drug Crestor as a preventive medication for people who don&apos;t have cholesterol problems. Crestor, as well as other cholesterol-lowering drugs, or statins, including Lescol, Lipitor, Mevacor, Pravachol and Zocor, are FDA approved for people with high cholesterol levels to reduce their heart disease risk. 
 Key Cholesterol Terms: What You Need to Know 
 When it comes to taking care of your cholesterol, understanding certain terms is essential. Read on for a primer on the big three: LDL, HDL, and triglycerides. When it comes to your heart health, understanding your blood cholesterol levels can be lifesaving. Cholesterol levels play an important role in determining your risk for getting coronary heart disease. When too much cholesterol is present in the blood, plaque may form in the arteries reducing blood flow to the heart. 
 7 Tips for Eating Clean 
 If you want to get the junk out of your diet once and for all, commit to eating as many fresh, local, unprocessed foods as possible. It may take a little extra effort on your part, but it can be done. If you want to get the junk out of your diet once and for all, commit to eating as many fresh, unadulterated foods as possible. It can be done.
You play a much bigger role than you may think in the control of the American food supply. Your shopping choices are like a vote. 
 The Five Worst Things You Can Do to Your Heart 
 Heart disease is the number one killer of both men and women in the United States, but it is also highly preventable. These are the five worst things that you can do to your heart. Although heart disease is the number-one killer of both men and women in the U.S., it&apos;s often an avoidable problem. While some risk factors for heart disease, such as family history or age, can&apos;t be changed, there are many things you can do to prevent heart disease that aren&apos;t burdensome or complicated and will help you avoid using medication. 
 5 Semi-Healthy Fried Foods 
 When you consider some of the outrageous deep-fried concoctions availablefried cookies, fried ice cream and batter-fried bacon, for exampleyou may think there&apos;s no such thing as healthy fried food. Well, think again. When you consider some of the more outrageous deep-fried concoctions available-fried cola dough, fried cookies, fried ice cream, and batter-fried bacon, for example-standard fare, like French fries and fried onion rings, starts to sound downright healthy. 
 5 Foods that Can Kill Your Sex Drive 
 Not in the mood? Those fries you had with lunch may be dampening your desire. Read on for a list of foods that are most likely to take a toll on your libido. Not in the mood? That cheeseburger and fries you had for lunch today may be dampening your desire. Believe it or not, your sex drive is affected by many of the lifestyle choices you make from day to day, including what you eat and drink. Some of these choices, like eating gassy foods or drinking too much vino, can affect you the very same day (or night). 
 What You Should Know About Metabolic Syndrome 
 The number of people affected by metabolic syndrome is rising, and expanding waistlines may be a contributing factor. According to the American Heart Association (AHA), about 47 million adults in the U.S. suffer from metabolic syndrome, a condition that includes a cluster of risk factors specific for heart disease, stroke and type 2 diabetes. The underlying causes of metabolic syndrome are being overweight or obese and physically inactive and having genetic factors such as a family history of hypertension and heart disease. 
 10 Cooking Tips to Lower Your Cholesterol 
 Eating a low-cholesterol, low-saturated-fat diet can go a long way in helping you manage your blood cholesterol levelsand it doesn&apos;t have to be boring. Eating a low-cholesterol, low-saturated-fat diet can go a long way in helping you manage your blood cholesterol levels (aim for a total cholesterol level of less than 200 mg/dL) and reduce your risk of having a heart attack and stroke-and it doesn&apos;t have to be boring. 
 How to Prevent a Second Heart Attack 
 If you&apos;ve already had a heart attack, the scary reality is that you have to go above and beyond to prevent another one. Find out how. According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, each year about 785,000 Americans have a heart attack (also called myocardial infarction) and about 470,000 have a second heart attack. But just because you&apos;ve had one heart attack, it doesn&apos;t mean that there aren&apos;t things you can do to prevent the onset of a second attack. 
 7 Tips for a Safe, Healthy Cookout 
 Don&apos;t let your afternoon get sidelined by illness or an accident. Mosquitoes, weight gain, E. coli, oh my! With barbecue season in full swing, you may be wondering how it&apos;s possible to make your next outdoor feast safe and healthy without sacrificing flavor and fun. If you heed the following tips, you&apos;ll find that taking the proper precautions and having a good time needn&apos;t be mutually exclusive. 
 5 Salad Bar Survival Tips 
 If you adhere to the following tips, you can construct a salad that&apos;s both nutritious and delicious. Salad bars present an interesting challenge. They provide a cornucopia of the most healthful foods, but they&apos;re also chockful of dietary pitfalls. Load up on cheese, bacon bits, croutons, and creamy salad dressing, and your salad will become as calorie-drenched and fatty as a burger and fries. 
 Slow Down the Clock With Exercise 
 Your cardio-respiratory fitness level decreases more rapidly after age 45. Fortunately, there are ways to slow down this decline and maintain a higher fitness level throughout middle age and your senior years. Time goes faster as you get older, but you can slow the age-clock down. It&apos;s all about fitness and healthy living. According to a report in the Archives of Internal Medicine, your cardio-respiratory fitness level declines more rapidly after age 45. 
 How Red Yeast Rice May Lower Your Cholesterol 
 Findings from a new study may provide an alternative to people troubled by statin-related pain. While cholesterol-lowering statins can be a lifesaver for people at risk for heart disease, they can also cause muscle pain and tenderness (called statin myopathy) in a certain percentage of them-estimates range from ten percent to twenty percent-resulting in patients having to stop taking the drugs. 
 Teens and High Cholesterol: A Rising Problem 
 Do you believe that high cholesterol is a condition that only affects adults? If so, you might be surprised to know that the problem can actually start quite young. Do you believe that high cholesterol is a condition that only affects adults? If so, you might be surprised to know that the problem can actually start quite young. In fact, in January of 2010, the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) reported that one out of every five teens has elevated cholesterol levels. 
 What Statins and Gallstones Have in Common 
 If you&apos;re taking statin drugs to reduce your cholesterol levels, you may not only be lowering your heart attack riskyou could lower your risk of developing gallstones as well. If you&apos;re taking statin drugs to reduce your cholesterol levels, you may not only be lowering your heart attack risk-you could lower your risk of developing gallstones as well. In a new study published in the Journal of the American Medical Association, Swiss researchers found that patients taking statin drugs for one year reduced their risk of developing gallstones by one-fifth. 
 Eating to Getand StayHeart Healthy 
 The statistics are daunting. Sixty-seven percent of Americans ages 20 and older are overweight or obese. So what can you do? The statistics are daunting. According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, 67 percent of Americans ages 20 and older are overweight or obese. And along with the extra pounds, comes the risk for a constellation of serious health problems, including heart disease, diabetes, some cancers, arthritis and other conditions. 
 Cigarettes: Just One Can Be Harmful 
 According to a recent study presented at the Canadian Cardiovascular Congress, smoking just one cigarette stiffens the arteries of young adults by a staggering 25 percent. According to a recent study presented at the Canadian Cardiovascular Congress, smoking just one cigarette stiffens the arteries of young adults by a staggering 25 percent. Arteries that are stiff or rigid increase resistance in the blood vessels, making the heart work harder. 
 Higher Education May Cut Your Heart Attack Risk 
 Can the amount of education you have impact your risk for heart disease? According to a study in the journal Heart, the answer may be yes. Can the amount of education you have impact your risk for heart disease? According to a study in the journal Heart, the answer may be yes. Results from INTERHEART, a international study of 52 countries, found that low education (eight years of school or less)─not income or occupation─was the strongest link to heart attack risk. 
 Men at Highest Risk for Sudden Cardiac Death 
 New information from a comparison of three major heart studies is showing a disturbing trend in mens heart health. New information from a comparison of three major heart studies is showing a disturbing trend in men&apos;s heart health. Men, especially African-American men age 40 and over, have a one in eight chance of experiencing sudden cardiac death, triple that of women in that age group, whose risk is one in 24. 
 Can Orange Juice Make Your Heart Healthier? 
 The health benefits of orange juice may exceed what you thought you knew. The health benefits derived from eating oranges are well documented. Rich in vitamin C, which offers antioxidant protection and helps boost the immune system, oranges are also a good source of fiber and other important nutrients like folate, thiamine, potassium, vitamin A and calcium, crucial for maintaining strong bones. 
 Kudzu Root May Reduce Risk for Metabolic Syndrome 
 Find out how a Japanese vine could help manage metabolic syndrome and decrease your risk of heart disease. A fast-growing vine long considered a nuisance because it takes over everything in its path (including ten million acres in the Southeast) may have redeeming qualities after all. A study published in the Journal of Agriculture and Food Chemistry found that kudzu, a vine imported from Japan, may help manage metabolic syndrome, a condition that includes a group of risk factors that increase the chance for heart disease, stroke and diabetes. 
 9 Habits for a Longer Life 
 
 The Incredible Heart Benefits of Avocados 
 Learn about the wonders that avocados can do for your heart. Avocados are more than just a delicious fruit to be enjoyed in favorite party dips like guacamole or as a garnish on sandwiches; they&apos;re a nutrient-rich food that packs a variety of nearly 20 vitamins, minerals and phytonutrients. They&apos;re also high in heart-healthy, unsaturated fats. 
 Obesity as Dangerous as a Lifetime of Smoking 
 Surely being overweight can&apos;t be nearly as bad for you as a smoking habit. Well, think again. New research from Great Brittan and the United States is showing that being severely obese—80 pounds or more above a normal weight—can reduce your lifespan by up to 12 years, similar to the effect of a lifetime of smoking. And even moderate obesity can cut life expectancy by about three years, according to the British study, which analyzed data from nearly one million people from around the world. 
 The Health Dangers of Red Meat 
 Learn more about the dangers of a diet filled with burgers, steaks, and lunch meat. Over the years, red meat has been linked to many serious medical conditions, including heart disease, cancers and even age-related macular degeneration, a condition that leads to blindness. Research shows again and again that the more red meat you eat, the higher your risk of developing a chronic disease and the greater your risk of dying an early death. 
 New Ways to Get Your Vegetables 
 Looking for new ways to factor some greenery into your diet? If so, read on. Low in calories, packed with vitamins and minerals, and essential for good health--vegetables are a powerhouse food! Nutrition experts say you can never have too many veggies in your diet but most of us aren&apos;t eating enough to reap their benefits.
In addition to simple side dishes, there are many familiar and easy ways to enjoy all kinds of vegetables, including soups, salads, pastas, stir-fries and even desserts. 
 Erectile Dysfunction May Be a Sign of Heart Disease 
 ED may be even more serious than it first seemed. At some time in their life, all men will experience erectile dysfunction (ED), the inability to get or keep an erection firm enough to engage in sexual intercourse. Although erectile dysfunction is sometimes called &quot;impotence,&quot; impotence refers to other problems that interfere with the sexual act, such as low libido, or lack of sexual desire, and problems with ejaculation or orgasm. 
 Butter vs Margarine: Which Is Best for Diabetics? 
 If you have diabetes, there may be a healthier choice. But be sure to read the label before making a selection. Years ago, margarine was typically made with partially hydrogenated oil, explains nutritionist Christine Avanti. &quot;The older margarine spreads were unhealthful because of the hydrogenation process,&quot; she explains. &quot;But fortunately the newer spreads are much more heart healthy. 
 The Heart-Healthy Benefits of Grapes 
 Read on for the reasons why this fabulous fruit is more than just your average snack. If you want lower blood pressure and better heart function, try eating grapes and drinking grape juice, especially dark red and purple grapes and grape juice. New studies are showing a link between grapes and reduced heart risks-and it&apos;s believed to be the result of phytochemicals, naturally occurring antioxidants found in plants. 
 Can Certain Foods Really Prevent Heart Disease? 
 A cereal that lowers cholesterol? A tea that prevents heart disease? If it sounds too good to be true, it probably is. You&apos;ve seen it all: Health claims made on food packaging that include everything from how to lower cholesterol to how to ward off heart disease. But how accurate are these claims?
According to the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) food labeling... 
 Healthy Fats for Diabetics 
 Dont ignore safflower, olive, and fish oils if you have diabetes. The much touted Mediterranean diet has practically elevated olive oil to the status of super food. But there are other oils out there that have health benefits, too. Safflower oil, for instance, appears to reduce blood sugar levels by 11 to 19 points, says Kelly A. 
 Triglycerides and Nerve Damage in Diabetics 
 For the first time, a simple blood test may hold the answer There may be good news for diabetics. Doctors can predict which diabetic patients may come down with the nerve condition called neuropathy by measuring their triglycerides, according to new research. Diabetics with elevated triglycerides are much more likely to suffer from the condition, which can cause tingling, pain and numbness in the hands, arms, feet and legs, according to a study from the University of Michigan and Wayne State University. 
 How to Raise Your Good Cholesterol Naturally 
 Here, simple ways to improve your numbers with no medication necessary. Understanding the role that cholesterol levels play in your heart health and taking steps to keep these levels under control can significantly reduce your risk for heart attack and stroke. Cholesterol is a soft, waxy substance that circulates in your bloodstream and in all the cells in your body. 
 Can the Mediterranean Diet Extend Your Life? 
 What you eator dont eatcan have a huge impact on how long you live. If you believe that longevity can be attributed to good genes, regular exercise, and perhaps a dose of plain old luck, you&apos;re only partly right. It turns out that what you eat-or don&apos;t eat-can have a huge impact on how long you live. The best way to dress your dinner table? With foods from the Mediterranean diet. 
 Cholesterol and Alzheimer&apos;s: What&apos;s the Link? 
 Studies are showing that even borderline high levels of cholesterol can increase your risk of developing this degenerative disease. For years, researchers have known that elevated cholesterol is tied to a host of diseases and conditions, mostly related to the heart. But a recent study offered up a surprising finding: Even borderline high levels of cholesterol can predict whether or not someone will suffer from Alzheimer&apos;s disease or other types of dementia as they age. 
 Cholesterol Medicine: A New Asthma Treatment? 
 If you use statin therapy to manage high cholesterol and also happen to suffer from asthma, you could find that your breathing may benefit. Possible Benefits of Cholesterol Medicine
If you use statin therapy to manage high cholesterol and also happen to suffer from asthma, you could find that your breathing may benefit.
This finding was released at the American Academy of Allergy, Asthma and Immunology annual meeting in the winter of 2009. 
 10 Easy Ways to Eat More Lean Protein 
 Here, simple ways to ensure you&apos;re getting enough of the good stuff into your diet. Proteins are important parts of muscles, blood, skin, and most body structures. They act as antibodies, enzymes, and hormones. They carry nutrients and other molecules and provide calories. Protein foods require more calories to be metabolized then carbohydrates or fats, therefore, they burn more calories to be processed and used by the body. 
 5 Hidden Sources of Trans Fat 
 These dangerous ingredients could be lurking in the most unexpected places. Are you confused about trans fats? If so, you&apos;re not alone. Trans fats, also known as trans fatty acids, have received a lot of press, but many people still don&apos;t understand exactly what they are or where they&apos;re hiding.
You might be more familiar with another name for trans fats, which is &quot;partially hydrogenated&quot; oils or fats. 
 4 Natural Remedies for Erectile Dysfunction 
 Move over Viagra. Some natural remedies for erectile dysfunction can be very effective. It&apos;s hard to ignore those uplifting ads for erectile dysfunction drugs such as Viagra and Cialis. But natural remedies for erectile dysfunction—from difficulties getting an erection to premature ejaculation—have long been used by various cultures throughout the world. 
 A Triple Threat: Lupus, Heart Disease, and Osteoporosis 
 Lupus affects more women than men, but it also worsens two of the most common health problems women have heart disease and osteoporosis. Lupus affects about 1.5 million Americans and nine times more women than men. There are several forms of lupus, but the most common is systemic lupus erythematosus. This autoimmune condition has serious side effects ranging from joint pain and stiffness, muscle aches, anemia and chronic fatigue. 
 Cat Owners Have a Lower Risk of Heart Disease 
 Cuddle up with that fabulous feline of yours. New research shows that cat owners are less likely to suffer from cardiovascular disease than non cat owners, according to the American Heart Association. Researchers involved with a Minnesota study analyzed 4,435 participants between the ages of 30 and 75 from the second National Health and Nutrition Examination Study. They found a decreased death rate from heart attack or other cardiovascular diseases such as stroke. 
 How to Choose the Healthiest Fish 
 How can you make the best choices for you and your family? Here, we help make it easier. Fish has a reputation as one of the most healthful foods you can eat. But given that there are so many types of fish in the world&apos;s waters, how can you wade through all of your choices and make the best ones for you and your family? What makes one fish more healthful than another?
First, know that simply by choosing fish over beef or other animal products, you&apos;re giving your health a boost. 
 Which Cuts of Beef are the Leanest? 
 Not all beef is created equal. Read on for a list of the leanest cuts. Lean beef is a nutrient-dense food. In other words, it is a nutritionally rich food that provides a substantial amount of vitamins, minerals and other nutrients with relatively few calories. It also has many nutritional benefits. It is a rich source of high quality protein and an excellent source of vitamin B12 and selenium and a good source of vitamin B6 and iron. 
 8 Worst States for Healthcare 
 How good will the care you receive be if you&apos;re sick or injured? The answer may depend partly on where you live. Find out how your state stacks up. If you tripped and fell and needed to go to the emergency room to have your leg examined, how quickly would you be seen by a doctor? When was the last time you had your cholesterol levels checked? Do you and your neighbors have health insurance?
The data for these questions and more helped to reveal how good healthcare is in various locations in this country. 
 5 Benefits of Eating Raw Foods 
 These days, many health gurus are touting raw food diets, claiming that food cooked at a high temperature loses its key nutrients. While experts don&apos;t suggest going 100 percent raw, they do acknowledge the amazing health benefits of uncooked and unprocessed fruits, vegetables, nuts, and seeds. Five reasons to include raw foods in your diet include:
1. Raw foods are nutrient-rich. 
 The Heart Benefits of Walking 
 If heart health is your concern, take a hike, literally. To find the fountain of youth is a task that has captivated humans for millennia. Although eternal youth is an impossibility—for now—recent studies seem to point to at least one thing that can turn back the hands of your heart&apos;s clock at least: exercise. 
 5 Fruits That Fight Disease 
 The next time youre in the produce aisle or the local farmers market, dont pass the following fruits by. There&apos;s a world beyond the same old apples and oranges you&apos;ve been buying forever. For starters, certain fruits have been shown to lower cholesterol levels and even ward off certain cancers. So, the next time you&apos;re in the produce aisle or the local farmers&apos; market, don&apos;t pass the following fruits by. 
 7 Exams Every Post-Menopausal Woman Should Have 
 Follow our head to toe guidelines for health screenings after menopause. For many women, life after 50 is an exciting time. Their careers are at their peak and they&apos;re enjoying time with family. They feel great and are cruising through menopause with minimal problems. Some, however, face health concerns resulting from disease, unhealthy habits, genetics, or simple wear and tear. 
 Will Soy Help or Harm You? 
 See how far the benefits of this disease-fighting protein can go besides promoting bone health and rich nutrition. Soybeans are legumes, such as peas, beans and lentils. They are one of the world&apos;s most important crops. Soybeans are consumed many different ways including edamame (young green soybeans), soy milk, soy nuts, soy yogurt, soy cheese, tempeh, miso, tofu and in a variety of meat substitutes such as veggie burgers. 
 65 or Over? Keep Your Heart Healthy 
 Sun and statins, among other things, can keep your heart ticking. Of the 550,000 people who die of cardiovascular disease every year, 82 percent of them are 65 and older. But staying heart healthy when you become a member of this age group is not an easy order. Over the years, your blood vessels and heart muscle become worn and damaged, even if you&apos;ve taken exceptional care of your heart. 
 Relieving Diabetic Nerve Pain at Home 
 The top 8 ways to treat diabetic neuropathy pain at home. If you&apos;re living with diabetes, you know that you&apos;re at a high risk for nerve damage or diabetic neuropathy. According to the American Diabetes Association, one out of two people with diabetes has nerve damage. It causes burning sensation, numbness, stinging, tingling, and weakness and extreme pain. 
 Heart Disease and Rheumatoid Arthritis 
 People with rheumatoid arthritis are more likely to develop cardiovascular disease. Heres how to lower your risk. When you have rheumatoid arthritis (RA) it&apos;s understandable that you would be more concerned with controlling pain and inflammation. However, you should also be aware of the strong link between heart disease and rheumatoid arthritis.
If you have RA, you&apos;re more likely to develop coronary heart disease, suffer unrecognized heart attacks and sudden cardiac death, according to the Mayo Clinic. 
 Insulin Resistance: A Growing Epidemic 
 The epidemic of insulin resistance puts one in three Americans at risk for type 2 diabetes and coronary heart disease. Find out how you can prevent insulin resistance. It&apos;s estimated that global diabetes rates will rise to 300 million in 2025, up from 135 million just over a decade ago. The rise is being attributed to the surging rates of insulin resistance linked to obesity. When insulin resistance coincides with obesity (especially abdominal obesity), cholesterol problems and high blood pressure, it&apos;s referred to as the metabolic syndrome or the insulin resistance syndrome. 
 Destress to Help Your Heart 
 Stress has been shown time and again to negatively impact the heart. Heres how to find relief. With the economy in shambles, the environment on the verge, and a collective lifestyle whose pace seems to get faster by the minute, it&apos;s hard for even the most Zen among us to feel stress-free nowadays. And all this stress can have an adverse effect on the cardiovascular system. 
 Are Buffets Sabotaging Your Diet? 
 Follow these tips to eat smart around all that good food. Buffets offer a seemingly endless array of food choices and by paying one price you can eat all you want or all you&apos;re able. While this may sound great, it can also be a recipe for disaster! In order to get more for your money (and who doesn&apos;t want that?), you eat more than you normally would, which may mean more calories, more fat, more salt and more sugar. 
 Is Your Family Out of Shape? 
 There&apos;s no better time than now to take control of your familys health. Every parent wants to do their best to raise healthy, happy children. More and more, we&apos;re discovering that the key is fitness--that winning combination of healthy eating and exercise that keeps our body, mind and spirit working at full capacity. 
 Statins May Help Control Crohn&apos;s Symptoms 
 Learn more about how cholesterol-lowering drugs (known as statins) may be beneficial to Crohn&apos;s patients. Studies and clinical trials for specific diseases often uncover data that may also benefit people with other disease. Researchers have found health problems that seem unrelated may in fact have an indirect relationship to Crohn&apos;s disease.
You&apos;re probably not familiar with the drug Atorvastatin by this name. 
 6 Ways to Cure a Blocked Artery 
 When one or more of your arteries are clogged, thankfully theres more than one way to undo the damage. Arteriosclerosis, the disease responsible for the sticky plaque buildup on arterial walls, affects as many as 12 million Americans. Unfortunately, many are unaware that their arteries are blocked, and left untreated, the plaque-filled lesions rupture and create blood clots that lead to a heart attack or a stroke. 
 Surprising Heart Attack Triggers 
 Though heart attacks seem to attack suddenly, theres usually an event that sets it off, and you can often take steps to bypass such events. A heart attack is a lifetime in the making. Over the years, the excess low-density lipoproteins (LDL) and triglycerides that result from poor food choices, bad habits such as smoking, unfortunate genetics, or even just natural processes can collect on the walls of blood vessels, forming atherosclerotic lesions called plaque. 
 Worst Supermarkets in America 
 See how your local grocery store measures up When you&apos;re picking out fresh ingredients to prepare a home-cooked meal for your family, you think you have control over the quality of the food. But due to some supermarkets&apos; poor health and safety standards, you may be getting more than you bargained for. 
 Eating Out When Dealing with Heart Disease 
 Whether you have high blood pressure or high cholesterol, you can still enjoy a delicious meal at any restaurant. Right after receiving a diagnosis of hypertension or high cholesterol, you might feel as if all the new restrictions and requirements will mean that you’ll never be able to dine out again. And though it’s safe to say that most fast food is now forbidden fruit for you, with an attitude adjustment and a greater nutritional awareness, you can score a heart-healthy meal even at the greasiest greasy spoon. 
 Diabetes and Heart Disease 
 Find out how diabetes and heart disease are related and what you can do to reduce your risk. According to the National Institutes of Health, diabetes is on the rise, with more than one in 10 adults over the age of 20 suffering from diabetes and one in three having prediabetes. The metabolic disorder—in which the body’s ability to... 
 Uncontrolled Diabetes: What Can Happen 
 The complications of the disease may sound daunting, but fortunately, lifestyle changes can help prevent them. Even for basketball fans, the name Larry H. Miller probably doesn&apos;t ring a bell. He wasn&apos;t Michael Jordan and he didn&apos;t even play. What he did do was create a car dealership dynasty that allowed him to buy the NBA&apos;s Utah Jazz franchise and turn it into a powerhouse. 
 Alcohol and Heart Health 
 As with most other substances we consume, alcohol can be harmful in excess and beneficial in moderation, especially when it comes to heart health. Researchers first reported this correlation between alcohol consumption and cardiovascular disease as early as 1904 in the Journal of the American Medical Association. But because alcoholism has been a long-standing problem in the United States, experts are reticent to wholeheartedly endorse raising a glass or two for your heart’s sake. 
 Managing Cholesterol at Home 
 Learn to manage your cholesterol where you spend the most time. Once you’ve come to terms with the fact that you’re among the 17 percent of Americans over the age 20 whose total cholesterol has been clocked at or above 240 milligrams per deciliter, you need to make a plan as to how you’re going to reverse this number and put a stop to the heart disease that is now encroaching upon your arteries with clogging plaque. 
 The Amazing Health Benefits of Seeds 
 They may be small, but they have big benefits. Seeds—they&apos;re for the birds, right? Sure, but they&apos;re also great for you. Whether you&apos;re a vegetarian, a vegan or a meat-eater, seeds have a place in your diet. You can eat them in larger quantities as a main course, grind them into butters, or use them in smaller quantities as garnishes for other foods. 
 Heart-Healthy Cooking Oils 
 Which cooking oils are actually healthy for you and which ones you should steer clear of? Let&apos;s face it: We need oil—cooking oil, that is. It makes food flavorful and moist, and without it, we couldn’t sautéor fry or whip up a cake from a store-bought mix. But it’s our insatiable desire for fried foods and baked goods that has given oil a bad name, one associated with type-2 diabetes, clogged arteries, and hearts strained by love handles gone wild with excess fat. 
 Heart Disease: The Genetic Link 
 The human genome was successfully mapped in April 2003, a relatively short time ago. In the wake of the maps completion, we have learned much about the link between genes and disease, but research is still in a nascent stageour genome is composed of 3 billion base pairs and 30,000 genes, after all. For years, scientists suspected that heart disease had a genetic component, making observations like people with a parent who developed coronary artery disease before the age of 55 faced a much greater risk of becoming afflicted with it themselves. Now the evidence written in our genes is coming to light on an almost daily basis. 
 How To Be a Healthy Role Model 
 Children learn what they live. Here are tips on how to teach your children well. We all want our kids to grow up eating nutritiously, getting plenty of exercise, and having a good outlook on life. How can you make that happen? Live healthfully yourself! You are a powerful influence on your children. If they see you &quot;walking the talk&quot; instead of just telling them what they should do, there&apos;s a great chance they&apos;ll grow up copying your good behaviors. 
 Alternative Medicines for Cholesterol 
 When your total cholesterol level climbs above 240, its time to take action to decrease your risk for a stroke or a heart attack. Quitting smoking, engaging in aerobic exercise at least three times a week, and eating a diet high in fiber and rich in fruits and vegetables will all contribute to the maintenance of a healthy balance of good cholesterol (HDL) and bad cholesterol (LDL); if the former is 60 or above, it actually prevents heart disease, while a level below 100 for the latter is desirable for people who have a higher likelihood for developing heart disease. 
 Heart Healthy Fats: What You Need to Know 
 Not all fats are created equal. Choose those that are best for your heart. Fat has gotten a pretty bad rap, and in all fairness, much of it is well deserved. Consuming too much saturated fat can up your LDL (or bad cholesterol) level, while trans fat, once considered to be a healthy alternative to animal fat, not only raises your LDL level, it also lowers your HDL, or good, cholesterol level. 
 Are Home Cholesterol Tests Worth It? 
 You might be tempted to try home cholesterol tests purchased from a pharmacy or online. But are they safe and accurate? When the heart&apos;s blood vessels become clogged with cholesterol, it sets the stage for a heart attack, and this year, nearly half a million Americans will die from heart disease, according to the American Heart Association (AHA). What&apos;s more, due in part to rising obesity rates and the popularity of fast food, heart-attack victims are getting younger and younger. 
 The Lowdown on Fiber and Heart Health 
 Long known to help your digestive system, fiber is good for your heart health, too. Find out why, and how you can incorporate more of it in your diet. As the saying goes, &quot;An apple a day keeps the doctor away.&quot; And for those who have high cholesterol or high blood pressure, this may very well be true. Apples are good sources of fiber, and experts believe that the more fiber you eat, the less likely you are to develop heart disease, which can lead to a heart attack. 
 4 Alternative Medicines for Cholesterol 
 When your total cholesterol level climbs above 240, its time to take action to decrease your risk for a stroke or a heart attack. Quitting smoking, engaging in aerobic exercise at least three times a week, and eating a diet high in fiber and rich in fruits and vegetables will all contribute to the maintenance of a healthy balance of good cholesterol (HDL) and bad cholesterol (LDL); if the former is 60 or above, it actually prevents heart disease, while a level below 100 for the latter is desirable for people who have a higher likelihood for developing heart disease. 
 5 Foods that Are Surprisingly Good for Your Heart 
 Spice up your diet with these foods that you might not have known are good for your heart. By now, you probably know that salmon and blueberries are good for your heart. In fact, you&apos;re probably sick of hearing that salmon and blueberries are good for you. Fortunately, you can keep your blood pressure and cholesterol levels low and still enjoy a more varied diet. 
 Is There Such a Thing as Healthy Fast Food? 
 &quot;Fast food&quot; and &quot;healthy&quot;: Is it possible for these two things to go together? If you&apos;ve seen the movie Super Size Me, chances are, you may not have had a Big Mac since. In his 2004 documentary, Morgan Spurlock, inspired by troubling statistics on American obesity, relied on the shock value of a thirty-day McDonald&apos;s diet to show audiences what they already knew about fast food: that it&apos;s not healthy. 
 Understanding the Role of Fat in Type 2 Diabetes 
 New research may be changing the way we view fat&apos;s relation to diabetes. Think fatty foods are bad for diabetics? A new study suggests that the opposite may be true: that extra fat in the buttocks and thighs may actually help prevent type 2 diabetes.
Researchers found that injecting subcutaneous fat (fat just below the skin) into the abdomens of mice helped improve sensitivity to insulin. 
 5 Foods that Are Surprisingly Good for Your Heart 
 Spice up your diet with these foods that you might not have known are good for your heart. By now, you probably know that salmon and blueberries are good for your heart. In fact, you&apos;re probably sick of hearing that salmon and blueberries are good for you. Fortunately, you can keep your blood pressure and cholesterol levels low and still enjoy a more varied diet. 
 Stress and Heart Health: What&apos;s the Link? 
 Read on to find out how stress can be a burden on your body. In the movies, traumatic news is enough to trigger a heart attack. On TV shows, a dramatic mother tells her rebellious teen son that he&apos;s going to give her a heart attack.
As it turns out, these situations may not be too far from the truth. Research shows a direct link between stress and an unhealthy heart. 
 Stress and Heart Health: What&apos;s the Link? 
 Poor diet and lack of exercise aren&apos;t the only factors that can damage your heart. Your stress levels also play a huge role. In the movies, traumatic news is enough to trigger a heart attack. On TV shows, a dramatic mother tells her rebellious teen son that he&apos;s going to give her a heart attack.
As it turns out, these situations may not be too far from the truth. Research shows a direct link between stress and an unhealthy heart. 
 5 Reasons Why Chocolate Can Be Good For You 
 This decadent dessert does more than just please your taste buds; it could benefit your health as well. It may be hard to believe that something as delicious as chocolate could actually be good for you, but it&apos;s true. According to a growing body of research, America&apos;s favorite sweet treat comes with a host of surprising health benefits: from regulating your blood pressure to reducing your risk of dementia. 
 High Cholesterol: Could Your Children Be at Risk? 
 Early steps in childhood to keep cholesterol low can help reduce the risk of heart disease or stroke later in life. High cholesterol is often thought of as an adult&apos;s health concern. However, research shows that parents may need to start thinking about the cholesterol levels of their children. In fact, it&apos;s now believed that coronary artery disease, which is caused by a buildup of cholesterol and plaque in the arteries and leads to heart disease and stroke, begins in childhood. 
 10 Foods That Cause Heart Attacks 
 Concerned about high cholesterol or high blood pressure? Avoid these foods at all costs. You probably already knew junk food is bad for your waistline, but did you ever stop to think about what it&apos;s doing to your heart? In particular, watch out for foods high in saturated fat, sodium, and cholesterol—all of which can raise the risk of heart disease and heart attack, according to the National Institutes of Health (NIH). 
 9 Worst Foods You Can Eat at the Fair 
 These nine foods simply aren&apos;t fair to your diet. A day at the fair conjures up ideas of friends, family, fun...and very possibly, fried foods. Although the fair has much to offer in the way of rides and activities, the truth is, many people come mostly for the food. Some stands may offer healthy choices, but they&apos;re often overshadowed by the seemingly endless supply of funnel cakes and corn dogs. 
 Eat More, Weigh Less 
 It may seem counterintuitive, but eating more of some foods can actually help you lose weight. Find out how. Eat more food, feel full all day long, and lose weight. It sounds too good to be true, like one of those fad diets that promises to help you shed 10 pounds while you watch TV. But this one is real. It&apos;s not that you can eat more Snickers, more pizza, or more sour-cream-and-onion potato chips. 
 5 Scary Health Risks of Sleep Deprivation 
 Not getting enough z&apos;s? You could be doing serious damage to your health. With a long list of to-dos and not enough hours in the day, you might be tempted to skimp on the amount of z&apos;s you get. Besides, you can sleep when you&apos;re dead, right? But, if you sleep less than six or seven hours a night, death might come sooner than you think. 
 Top Diet Tips As You Age 
 As you age, your body doesn&apos;t stay the same. Neither should your diet. When you think about aging well, wrinkle creams, exercise programs and even plastic surgery probably come to mind. But if you really want to make sure you&apos;re able to enjoy those later years, experts say you&apos;ve also got to know something about fine-tuning your diet. 
 4 Benefits of Eating Whole Grains 
 A diet rich in whole grains can help lower the risk of some serious health conditions. Numerous studies continue to reveal the many health benefits of eating whole grains. While the benefits are most pronounced for those consuming at least three servings daily, according to the Whole Grains Council, some studies show reduced risks of certain conditions from as little as one serving daily. 
 The Truth About Food Labels 
 The packaging of some of your favorite foods may be hiding crucial information from you. What do you look for when you check a food label? Some people may check for fat content, while other may want to see if the product contains whole grains or meat byproducts.
Companies have been required to list the nutritional information on the packaging of food products since 1994; however, what&apos;s written on the package may be presented in an intentionally misleading way. 
 Could You Be at Risk for a Stroke? 
 Learn what you can do to protect yourself from this debilitating health threat. According to the American Heart Association, stroke is the third leading cause of death in the United States. And although many people survive these medical emergencies, the disease can have a devastating impact, not only on the survivor, but on everyone who cares about him or her. 
 10 Worst Desserts in America 
 Do you find it difficult (and sometimes impossible) to skip dessert? If so, you&apos;re not alone. Obesity is on the rise in America, and the following ten desserts may have something to do with this national epidemic. According to the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey, more than 66 percent of U.S. adults are currently overweight, and 32 percent are obese. In fact, in 2007, Colorado was the only state that had a prevalence of obesity under 20 percent, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). 
 10 Most Fattening Ballpark Foods 
 No one goes to a baseball game to eat healthfully, but some stadium foods are more diet-deadly than others. There was a time when the national pastime was synonymous with peanuts and cracker jacks. Now, the ballpark menu has expanded-to include one fattening item after another. Stadiums often serve foods made famous by their hometowns (such as cheesesteaks in Philly, crabcakes in Baltimore, or pierogies in Pittsburgh), but many of them should come with an exercise plan on the side. 
 Healthiest and Unhealthiest Ballpark Snacks 
 Snacks to skip and healthier options when eating at the game. If you&apos;ve been to a baseball game lately, you know that an afternoon at the ballpark doesn&apos;t mean you have to derail your diet.
In recent years, major-league ballparks across the country have begun selling lighter fare, including fruit skewers, sushi and vegan dogs, at their concession stands. 
 7 Shocking Diet Flubs and Fixes 
 Learn how to pinpoint and fix the seven sneakiest diet blunders. Dieting is a bit like walking a tightrope: easy to start but hard to stay on. And according to experts, the most common diet missteps are caused by things that might surprise you--your schedule, your friends, your shopping habits, even your clothes. While these sneaky saboteurs could derail your efforts, the good news is that you can stop them from undermining your long-term weight-loss goals. 
 Health by the Numbers: Heart Health 
 Heart disease is the leading cause of death in the United States, killing more than 2,500 Americans each day. Here, a look at heart health by the numbers. Heart disease, known as a silent killer, claims the lives of millions of Americans each year. An umbrella term for multiple conditions that affect the heart and blood vessels, heart disease includes coronary artery disease, pulmonary heart disease, and hypertension. 
 5 Ways to Lower Your Cholesterol Naturally 
 These simple lifestyle changes can help you improve your levels no prescription required. See what people are saying about this article on our Facebook page!
If you&apos;ve been diagnosed with high cholesterol, you&apos;re not alone. More than 100 million American adults have &quot;borderline high&quot; total blood cholesterol levels of 200 mg/dL and higher, according to the American Heart Association. 
 Cholesterol-Lowering Medications 101 
 Along with a healthy diet and exercise regimen, certain medications can help get cholesterol levels in a normal range. It seems as though medications for lowering cholesterol are constantly being developed, tested, and enhanced. As a result, it can be difficult to keep them all straight, especially as new research comes out to show that drugs once thought effective don&apos;t actually work the way doctors had hoped. 
 What&apos;s Your Cholesterol IQ? 
 Do you know the facts about cholesterol? Test your knowledge now. High cholesterol affects an estimated 100 million Americans, or roughly one-third of the U.S. population, according to the American Heart Association (AHA). But despite its prevalence, most people are so unaware of the condition&apos;s risks that they don&apos;t even know their own cholesterol levels. 
 10 Ways to Reduce Your Heart Attack Risk 
 Heart disease is the nation&apos;s number one killer. Learn what you can do to prevent a heart attack. This year, 1.2 million Americans are expected to have a heart attack. Of those, about 452,000 will die, making coronary heart disease the nation&apos;s single leading cause of death, according to the American Heart Association.
Heart disease can affect anyone, but certain factors put you at greater risk. 
 10 Foods That Lower Cholesterol 
 These delicious superfoods can help to lower your levels. If you have high cholesterol, that doesn&apos;t mean you have to resign yourself to a bland diet. In fact, a tasty salmon entree, a handful of sweet berries, or even a glass of red wine can all help to lower your levels and improve your heart health. The next time you go grocery shopping, look for these cholesterol-lowering treats recommended by the American Heart Association. 
 10 Reasons to Eat Breakfast 
 It&apos;s often said that breakfast is the most important meal of the day. Find out why it&apos;s so important to get off to a good start. When you&apos;re hitting the snooze button for the third time, breakfast is probably one of the last things on your mind. After all, you still have to shower and then race to work in time to make that presentation. But according to experts, letting a hectic schedule force you to skip breakfast could compromise your health. 
 The 5 Most Fattening Winter Foods 
 Rich and creamy seasonal foods can quickly pile on the pounds. Check out these delicious, low-fat alternatives. When temperatures drop, it&apos;s tempting to stay indoors, bundled up in cozy blankets, surrounded by satisfying comfort foods. But along with these foods come extra pounds, which can be tough to lose once the weather warms up. Fortunately, there are alternatives to winter&apos;s most fattening fare. 
 Healthy Diets vs. Fads 
 Learn how to tell the difference between a healthy weight-loss plan and the latest craze. Have you heard about the latest diet trend? You drink nothing but cranberry juice for seven days and drop 10 pounds. The next week, you go back to your regular eating habits, and the weight miraculously stays off. It sounds too good to be true, right? That&apos;s because it is. 
 Sneaky Foods That Can Make You Fat 
 Some foods that seem healthy can be just as fattening as their obviously indulgent counterparts. Here are six that may be sneaking up on your waistline. Perhaps you&apos;ve tried to cut calories by replacing regular soft drinks with diet sodas or by switching from subs to salads, but you haven&apos;t noticed any weight loss. You might be surprised by how quickly sneaky extras, such as lattes loaded with whip cream and bleu cheese salad dressing, can add up. 
 9 Ways to Lower Your Cholesterol 
 Following these simple tips can help you lower your cholesterol levels and your health risks. Everyone needs a basic amount of cholesterola waxy, fat-like substance found in all cells of the body to function. But if your cholesterol is at an unhealthy level, it could mean you have an increased risk of developing heart disease. What can you do to keep your cholesterol at or reduce it to healthy levels? Try these nine tips:
Eat a hearty bowl of oatmeal for breakfast. 
 Understanding Your Cholesterol Levels 
 Do you know your LDL, HDL, and triglyceride numbers? Learn how to decipher these terms and reduce your disease risk. At this point, it&apos;s no secret that high cholesterol levels can lead to heart disease or stroke. But many Americans may not know their cholesterol numbers or what they mean. In addition to keeping your levels in check by making healthy lifestyle choices, follow these guidelines to learn what your cholesterol levels are and what they mean. 
 Can a Pet Boost Your Health? 
 According to some researchers, a four-legged friend can add years to your life. It&apos;s no secret that people rely on their pets for love, companionship, and a sense of security. After all, the iconic American family traditionally includes a mom and dad, 2.5 kids, and a pet of some kind. But as it turns out, the benefits of having a pet go far beyond camaraderie and protection; a four-legged friend can actually boost your health and, according to some researchers, lengthen your life by about seven years. 
 25 Heart-Smart Foods 
 Savor these treats without sacrificing flavor--or your health. At first blush, a heart-healthy diet might sound pretty bland: reduced salt, low cholesterol, limited calories, decreased fat. But luckily, there are a variety of foods that are both delicious and healthy, according to the American Heart Association (AHA). 
 Understanding Your Cholesterol Numbers 
 These numbers could potentially save your life. Your phone number, credit-card pin, social-security digits—these are all crucial numbers to remember. And according to health experts, you should also commit another set of numbers to memory. Why? These numbers could potentially save your life:
Total cholesterol
LDL bad cholesterol
HDL good cholesterol 
Total cholesterol is, of course, the total of your low-density (LDL) cholesterol, high density (HDL) cholesterol, and triglycerides. 
 Cholesterol Health Center 
 Causes Prevention Symptoms Treatments Management Caregiving Healthy Recipes Cholesterol News Diet&amp;Nutrition Eating&amp;Nutrition Advertisement     
Sign Up for Free Newsletters
 
 
 Healthy Heart Nutrition&amp;Fitness Managing Diabetes Healthy Living View All Newsletters 
 
 
Ask Your Doctor the RIGHT Questions!
 Get FREE tools and tips to get
the most from your doctor visit.
 Emailed right to you!
 Reason for visit Other 
 The Ask Your Doctor email series
may contain sponsored content.
18+, US residents only please. 
Explore Original Articles About...
 | general health lifestyle | emotional health | schizophrenia | alcohol and drug problems | cholesterol | ibs | men&apos;s health | diet and weight loss | mental health and addiction | lymphoma | cervical cancer | skin cancer | children&apos;s health and parenting | caregiving | chest pain | 
Get the MOST from QualityHealth
 Find QualityHealth on Facebook ! Connect with others and get our latest health tips and recipes. Like us! Follow QualityHealth on Twitter . Be the first to know about savings on health products you use every day! Ask Your Doctor the right questions at your upcoming appointment. Sign up for this free program today! Sign up for free newsletters to help you live a healthier life. Go now. Subscribe to our RSS Feed so you won&apos;t miss any of our health tips and special offers.     
   Stories   Recipes  Top Searches 
 
   1. 5 Foods That Fight Allergy Symptoms   2. &quot;Sedentary Lifestyle&quot;: What it Means   3. Top 10 Summery Ingredients   4. How Safe Is Your Cookware?   5. How Music Affects What You Eat   6. Can Caffeine Boost Your Workout?   7. 6 Natural Remedies to Relieve Nausea   8. Best Exercises for Arthritis Relief   9. Your Type-by-Type Hair Care Guide 10. 4 Instant Energy Boosts 
 
   1. Grilled Salmon Steaks   2. Island Grilled Bananas   3. Grilled Shrimp, Pasta, Pineapple Salsa   4. Grilled Sweet Potato and Mango Salad   5. Lower Fat Grilled Tuna with Capers   6. Grilled Tilapia, Spinach, Tomatoes   7. Grilled Salmon With Lime Cream Sauce   8. Citrus Honey Chicken   9. West Indian Garlic Cod 10. Tuna Steaks With Onion Cream 
 
   1. Asthma, Allergies Have Dangerous Link   2. Treat 5 Diabetes-Related Skin Problems   3. Risks and Benefits of Raw Dairy   4. Why Only Some Smokers Get Cancer   5. Peripheral Arterial Disease   6. Chocolate: A Cardiovascular Hero?   7. Age-Related Memory Loss for Men   8. 10 Habits That Hurt Your Eyes   9. Looking for a Fresh Start? Try This 10. Benefits of a Morning Exercise 
 Quick Links: Site: Sitemap Healthy Offers Ask Your Doctor Recipes News RSS Feeds Newsletters Encyclopedia: Glossary Drugs&amp;Medications Symptom Checker Surgeries&amp;Procedures Alternative Medicines In-Depth Reports My Account: Login Become A Member Community: View Profile My Support Groups Health Centers: ADD/ADHD Allergies Alzheimer&apos;s Disease Anxiety Arthritis Asthma Autism Bipolar Disorder Breast Cancer COPD Cancer Caregiving Children&apos;s Cholesterol Colds&amp;Infections Crohn&apos;s Disease Dental&amp;Vision Depression Diabetes Diet&amp;Weight Loss Eating&amp;Nutrition Epilepsy Erectile Dysfunction Fitness&amp;Exercise Flu Treatment Healthy Aging&amp;Retirement Heart Health Heartburn&amp;GERD IBS Incontinence Men&apos;s Health Center Meningitis Menopause Mental Health&amp;Addiction Migraines&amp;Headaches Multiple Sclerosis Osteoporosis Pain Management Parkinson&apos;s Disease Pregnancy Relationships&amp;Emotional Health Sexual Health Skin Care&amp;Beauty Sleep Management Smoking Cessation Stomach&amp;Digestive Women&apos;s Health Company Info: Editorial Policy Privacy Policy Advertising Policy Terms Of Use Affiliate Program Advertise with Us Contact Us Our Contributors ©2012 QualityHealth.com. All rights reserved.
The material on the QualityHealth Web site is for informational purposes only, and is not a substitute for 
medical advice, diagnosis, or treatment provided by a physician or other qualified health provider. See additional information.
	</body>
</document>
