<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002563" url="http://www.foodserve.com/FOODCO6/menuplanning.htm" time="2012-07-12-18:38" support="2" score="0.011064344092000222" bingtitle="Restaurant Inventory Software Food Inventory Software" webtitle="Restaurant Inventory Software Food Inventory Software">
			<query id="001261" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="001282" bing-rank="83"/>
	<description>... school, catering operation, non-profit cafeteria, fast food restaurant ... Forecast customers, forecast menu selection, produce the finished goods and order ...</description>
	<body>
		Live Chat Contact Us About FSS FOODCO FORMS Biometrics POS Home 
 
 
 FOODCO 
 7 --
 &quot;Simply powerful, powerfully simple&quot; 
 Overview Inventory Purchasing Recipes Receiving Menu Plan Menu Forecast Event Results Graphs Reporting   to preview the official site go to www.planyourprofit.com 
 

Restaurant Inventory Software

 Menu Planning Overview  - &quot;A big dog and a little dog are still both dogs&quot; - Milt Miller, Food Service Director
 
  


The FOODCO7 Meal Planner works for any food service operation. Whether you operate
 a school, catering operation, non-profit cafeteria, fast food restaurant or fine
 dining facility the basics of operation is the same. Determine how many people are
 coming, what the menu will be, how much of each finished product do we need to prepare
 and what do we need to have in inventory to accomplish today&apos;s task. Every day in
 every food service operation in the world some one is sitting down figuring out
 how much salad are we making, how many tomatoes to slice and top rounds to order.
 Some use a pencil and piece of paper, some a calculator and others pull it out of
 their head. The day to day operation of food production is at best a daunting task
 and just when you have a handle on it the chef completely rewrites the menu, summer
 changes to fall, the government writes a new list of nutrition regulations or the
 college students go back to school.

A systematic approach to food preparation and food production is the key to a successful
 operation. McDonald&apos;s, Jack In The Box, Wendy&apos;s, Cracker Barrel, Sodexho-Marriott
 and the major chain restaurants all have systems that help insure profitability.
 How can your operation compete, stay on budget or turn a profit? It all starts with
 a system. FOODCO6 Restaurant POS Software is a systematic approach to food service that once implemented
 can double, maybe even triple net-net profits.

 
 The FOODCO POS Software data on the right is from a school lunch program where
 every day, data is captured for lunch, breakfast and a la carte. I hear what you&apos;re
 thinking. My operation is much more sophisticated. We have six events a day and
 serve center of plate products that average $8.00 per pound. I will quote the food
 service director from the school where this data originated. &quot;A big dog and a little
 dog are both still dogs&quot;.



Whether you are serving peanut butter/jelly or filet mignon the process is exactly
 the same. Whether you run school lunch or a fine dining restaurant the issues are
 the same. How many people will we serve today? What is the menu? What tasks need
 to be performed to serve our guests? What is the cost?



Forecast customers, forecast menu selection, produce the finished goods and order
 for tomorrow&apos;s or this week&apos;s expected business. These tasks occur every day in
 every food service operation.



The front of house at your business and the methods of preparation are unique but the system of forecasting, production, cost analysis and profit and loss are
 exactly the same as school lunch . The only difference is the system
 and with the information this K-12 food service director has, staying on budget
 and making a profit are a foregone conclusion. FOODCO. It makes a difference.
 It makes profit.
 


  
 
Isn&apos;t it about time for you to make the profits you so richly deserve? 
 
  
  
 SEE THE REST OF THE PACKAGE HERE:  http://www.planyourprofit.com  
 
 
 
 About Us | Products | Contact Us | News | Support 
 POS Software | Restaurant Inventory Software | Point of Sale Software 
Copy right Food Service Solutions2009
	</body>
</document>
