<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002305" url="http://crossroadsnewnan.org/index2.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=73&amp;Itemid=119" time="2012-07-12-18:13" support="15" score="0.018316687674318873" bingtitle="Servant Evangelism Projects - Crossroads Church" webtitle="Servant Evangelism Projects">
			<query id="001225" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="000651" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000654" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000068" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000089" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000078" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="000640" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000066" bing-rank="123"/>
			<query id="000630" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000005" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="000655" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="000092" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="000635" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="001227" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000379" bing-rank="195"/>
	<description>Throw a dinner for the block. One family in a rough ... They then approach one of the managers of a fast food restaurant ... Boxes to Merchants with your Logo and Number ...</description>
	<body>
		Servant Evangelism Projects 

 
Servant Evangelism Projects are designed for small groups to reach out and share
God&apos;s love in practical ways. At Crossroads we encourage small groups to
participate in a couple of projects each year.



Below is a list of suggestions to get you started. Once you find the project of your
choice, click on &quot;Register Here&quot; to order supplies.

 Idea Description Team_Size Cost Cleaning Up at Food Courts If you can get your foot in the door at your local mall, ask if you can clean up the mess that people leave behind after their meal. We also distribute handy-wipes with our logo imprinted on them, and a connection card. 4 free Register Here! Community Dinner Throw a dinner for the block. One family in a rough part of London has been doing grill outs for the past few years. The couple provides the grill and the hamburgers. Everyone else brings a part of the dinner. The result: Neighbors are talking to one another for the first time, they are watching out for each other and, naturally, the crime rate has gone down. 2 free Register Here! Fireplace Ash Removal Self-explanatory. Note: Never remove hot ashes. Even when they seem just a bit warm, they pose a serious fire threat in the trash can. We recommend you place the ashes in a double layer grocery bag. 2 free Register Here! Garbage Can Return from Street You could do this one for your entire street each week. Usually garbage pick up is done early in the morning. Be the first one out. Return them near their garage but do it quietly. 1 free Register Here! Grocery Bag Loading Assistance Moms with lots of kids hanging on them like koalas often need assistance getting their bags loaded into the car from the cart. The elderly need the same sort of help. On this one almost everyone will try to give a tip. As with all kindness projects, to receive money would taint what we are trying to communicate &quot;God&apos;s love in a practical package with no strings attached.&quot; This project may require permission from the store manager on the day of the event. The servers on this one need to be particularly safe-appearing folks. Smiling can help ease people&apos;s fears. Name tags or T-shirts identifying connection to your organization is a plus for this outreach because it makes the loading assistants look more official. 3 free Register Here! Grocery Cart Returns Approach shoppers as they finish unloading their carts with the offer, &quot;Hi, can I take that back for you? We&apos;re showing God&apos;s love in a practical way to shoppers.&quot; The shoppers will appreciate it, and the grocer will love you for it. 2 free Register Here! Grocery Store Bag Packing 
Increasing numbers of grocery stores offer rock bottom prices. One of the ways they can afford this is by cutting out services such as bag packing. We have our own aprons with our logo on the front. The first time we volunteered to do this, the manager was skeptical; but that feeling quickly melted. This project is reportedly very effective all over the U.S. To top it off, this is honest work. Name tags or T-shirts identifying connection to your organization is a plus for this outreach because it makes the baggers look more official.
 4 free Register Here! Interior Vacuuming Locate at gas stations or shopping center parking lots. Set up signs that explain what you&apos;re doing. Give a connection card to those you help. I recommend you establish a designated communicator to connect with drivers and explain why this is all taking place. 3 free Register Here! Interior Window Cleaning Which is dirtier, the inside or outside of your car windows? Often the inside is worse. Set up a cleaning station similar to the one above. Use paper towels to do the cleaning. If you want to get fancy, have scented cards printed with your church logo and phone number to hang in the car. 3 free Register Here! Move in Welcoming Party Greet new neighbors to your neighborhood with some cookies or a home cooked meal and a smile. 1 free Register Here! Restroom&amp;Toilet Cleaning at Public Places This is Steve Sjogren&apos;s favorite project. There&apos;s nothing like walking into a gas station, restaurant or retail store and offering, &quot;We&apos;d like to clean your toilet for free!&quot; Put a little cleaning kit together. The essentials: brush, air freshener, window cleaner, paper towels, toilet bowl cleaner, rubber gloves, doorstop. There&apos;s nothing magical about the technique here. Steve has cleaned commodes all over the world and says they are all pretty much the same as the ones in your home. This is probably one of the most frequently rejected projects we do - probably because the offer to clean a toilet is a bit overwhelming. No matter. Give them your connection card, smile, and say, &quot;OK! We&apos;ll come back some other time and clean when you need it. We&apos;re just trying to show you God&apos;s love in a practical way.&quot; 2 free Register Here! Trash Pick-Up With a small investment and a little courage, you can make your mark on your city. You will need debris pickup sticks (with a nail built into the end), five gallon plastic buckets to hold your roadside trash, and some signs that read, &quot;Kindness in Progress.&quot; We place these signs every fifty feet in a busy street or retail area. A team of 4-6 can clean the side of a road in less than an hour. Before cleaning in front of a store, I usually talk with the owner-manager to explain our project. I give him a connection card and say, &quot;We are picking up roadside debris along ____ Road. We&apos;re doing this to show the merchants here the love of Christ in a practical way.&quot; To date no one has been less than enthusiastic about our serving. There is a lot of trash to pick up at festivals and sporting events. Buy garbage bags, wear matching T-shirts, and pick up trash. People will notice this act of servanthood. Equipment: plastic gloves, sign — &quot;Kindness in Progress&quot; and T-shirts. 4 free Register Here! Umbrella Escorts Moms and the elderly find it tough to make it from stores to their cars in the rain. We use huge golf umbrellas to help them to their car with as little wetness as possible. 3 free Register Here! Buy Down Gas to Bargain Price Instead of paying the dollar plus price, buy down the price to a remarkable rate for a couple of hours and pay the difference to the station owner. When local prices were $1.29, we put up signs advertising a price of $.99. The total we spent for the two hours usually runs from $400-500 per station. When customers come in, we give them a connection card that briefly explains our project. Each time we&apos;ve done this outreach, we&apos;ve gotten fantastic response. Have enough people because a line may form. 4 high Register Here! Popcorn You can either make bags of popcorn before you get there, or rent/purchase your own &quot;carnival style&quot; popper and do it on the spot. You will draw more of a crowd with the machine on hand. 3 high Register Here! Purchasing Meals at the Food Court One small group meets regularly at the mall for their group. Occasionally, they take a spontaneous offering among themselves. They then approach one of the managers of a fast food restaurant and offer, &quot;We&apos;d like to pay the bill for as many customers as this amount of money will pay for.&quot; On one recent outreach, this group paid for $125 worth of food - that was about one hour&apos;s worth of sales. The manager became so excited he was explaining the gospel himself to the customers even though he was a burned out church attendee. Go figure! 1 high Register Here! &apos;Biggie Size&apos; Food Orders in Fast Food Drive-Thru Lanes Set up near the drive-thru order station. As customers drive up, offer to pay the difference between their order and the &quot;Biggie&quot; size - which is usually $0.39. Your offer will get the entire restaurant talking. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Breakfast Pop Tarts/Granola Bars Pop Tarts may not be all that healthy, but they are popular among most students. They are good hot or cold. Students will take them to eat later even if they&apos;ve already had breakfast. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Bulb Replacement There are only a few common bulb types used in domestic and foreign cars. Have an assortment of these available. Set up a station in the corner of a shopping center parking lot. Set up a sign, &quot;Free Light bulb Exam and Replacement.&quot; With just a few basic tools (screwdrivers) about anyone can pull this one off. Don&apos;t use powered screwdrivers - they are more likely to break lens covers. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Business Blasts Bring a small gift, such as a basket of candy, into small businesses for their employees. Bring in one package to be shared by store employees and leave a connect card. What to say? &quot;We appreciate how you serve the community with your business, and we wanted to do a random act of kindness to share God&apos;s love in a practical way.&quot; Make sure you only give items to employees, so they don&apos;t think you are &quot;soliciting&quot; customers. Ideas: Easter baskets in spring, Christmas stockings at Christmas. Leave a connection card that says, &quot;Happy Holidays! This is a busy time of year for you. We want you to know how much we appreciate you and to show you God&apos;s love in a practical way!&quot; 2 inexpensive Register Here! Care Package Make up care packages for an entire dorm. Include such things as: packages of hot chocolate, microwave popcorn, cookies, mints, and gum. Total cost around 62 cents. You&apos;ll need to get permission from the dorm. These can be distributed through student mailboxes or a box in the lobby. 1 inexpensive Register Here! Carnations to Cemetery Visitors Carnations are affordable, and everyone likes them. This project could be done anytime. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Cart Token for Shopping Carts Some grocery stores in urban areas require a token in order to get a shopping cart. Provide the tokens to shoppers as they enter. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Check Oil and Fill If you can find a sympathetic station owner, you can get permission to offer service like they did in the good old days. At the self-serve pump, ask if they would like to have their oil checked and topped off. About the only caution: If you top off their too low oil make sure you are using the same viscosity as they originally had. Be sure not to overfill - that can cause major engine problems. Make sure you explain that you are not from the station but are Christians showing God&apos;s love in a practical way. Otherwise, customers will assume you work for the station. 3 inexpensive Register Here! Coins Attached to Cards for Phone Calls or Parking Meters For years, we &quot;fed&quot; parking meters in Cincinnati. We changed tactics last fall when Sylvia Stayton was arrested. Perhaps you read about the &quot;meter feeding granny&quot; in your local paper. We were not aware that feeding someone else&apos;s meter was taboo. The law in Cincinnati is rather vague. Until it is clarified, we have chosen to attach a coin to a card that reads, &quot;It&apos;s time for some change!&quot; We place the card between the driver&apos;s window and the bottom rubber seal. The driver can use the coin to pay the meter or to make a phone call. This is a high volume project. Close to 200 of these can be placed in an hour in a crowded parking area. To attach the coin, use either rubber cement (smelly and slow) or a roll of adhesive. Several types of these are sold in the tape section of most office supply stores. Unless the weather is remarkably hot, even a quarter will stay attached. Thief alert: Often young kids or street people will follow and swipe the cards from cars. Ask them if they need money and how much. Usually they will ask for a buck or two. Make them a deal - allow these folks to get a quarter and give them the two dollars. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Cookies Everyone likes a cookie. We purchase these in small packets of four. Although manufactured cookies aren&apos;t as good as homemade, folks are reluctant to receive unpackaged food from strangers. We have had our greatest success with this in downtown business areas. Go for quality of product - not low cost - people will receive a name brand like &quot;Oreo&quot; more than a generic brand. All kinds of snacks are appreciated by students, especially around exam time. 3 inexpensive Register Here! Doggie Treats People often love their pets like family members. Either make a great doggie treat from scratch, or buy them from a gourmet pet shop. Wrap several with a ribbon and a connection card and give them out at parks or dog runs. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Dollar Drop At local malls where any sort of programmatic evangelism is not allowed, this is a way to get the attention of many quickly. We attach a connection card explaining our project to a dollar bill. We use Post-It note removable glue (available at local business supply stores). Then we go around the mall and nonchalantly drop dollar bills on the ground. For some free entertainment, stand a distance away and watch who picks up the dollar and how they respond to the message. 1 inexpensive Register Here! Donut Giveaway during Morning Traffic Times A couple of grandmas at our church have had great success giving away pastries in the morning. Who could say no to a sweet grandma type? As with any giveaway, there are a couple of options. These gals set up on a traffic island at a light. When it&apos;s red they step into traffic and ask, &quot;Would you like chocolate, maple or glazed?&quot; They then give them a connection card. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Drinks for Cashiers For several years now I have been practicing showing simple respect to retail workers - especially cashiers. In almost all retail locations, there are several opportunities to make &quot;impulse purchases&quot; such as packs of gum or soft drinks. In my case there is nothing impulsive about my purchase - it is well thought out! I always buy a drink for the cashier. I ask the cashier, &quot;What&apos;s your favorite softdrink?&quot; Without hesitation they tell me - then I walk back to the machine and pick up a cold one for them. Of course they ask me why I am doing this. A brief conversation ensues.

One thing I am always careful to tell those I serve is &quot;I am not serving you so you will come to my church... I will serve you not only today but in the future each time I see you because I am a Christ follower - His life in me is a life of serving, generosity, respect and love. This has nothing to do with marketing. If this was about marketing I / we would do things much differently - much slicker.&quot;

Ironically, when I tell people that, guess what their reaction is? They almost always say, &quot;Now I am really intrigued about this church you go to. This is exactly what I have been looking for...&quot;

Notice Fellow Customers
See the above project, but play it out, given the right opportunity to the two or three people behind you. For heaven&apos;s sake, you can afford a soft drink or Dasani that costs $1.25 times two or three. If you can afford the gasoline to get to the store you can afford the three drinks. Again, assume at all times, &quot;I am about to serve someone...therefore I will always carry with me at least a dozen connect cards...&quot; 1 inexpensive Register Here! Freshen-up Packs (mints&amp;moist towelettes) At sporting events, festivals and public places it&apos;s difficult to wash hands. A moist towelette is a practical, small gift. Package a few with some starlight mints and make a &quot;freshen-up&quot; pack. See cards for special connection card. Towelettes can be printed with your church name and logo and only cost about 1 cent per towelette. Mints are around 2 cents - total cost per packet 6 cents. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Fruit give away I was surprised at the popularity of this one. People really like fresh fruit and they will readily take it. I have tried this one across the US and it has gone over great guns. An orange, an apple and a banana are enough along with a connection card in a clear plastic bag. It works well door to door. Great way to invite neighbors to small group meetings! 1 inexpensive Register Here! Glow in the Dark Necklaces / Bracelets These are a hit! They run about $1.00 each, so they&apos;re a more expensive but effective touch! 3 inexpensive Register Here! Golf Ball Cleaning Most golfers carry dozens of balls in their bag. Sure there are golf ball cleaning machines spread throughout the course, but most don&apos;t take the time to clean them. With the permission of the course, set up a simple clean up station and clean golf balls before golfers begin their round. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Golf Balls Imprinted balls are surprisingly affordable. The average golfer loses three or four balls per outing. If it&apos;s lost on the course, another golfer will pick it up later with your logo and phone number on it. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Golf Tees Imprinted tees cost just a couple of cents per tee. Golfers can never get enough of these. Some golf courses will give them away for you at their counter. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Hand Cleaning Towelettes On a Friday afternoon, when the heat is on, who doesn&apos;t need a little refreshment on the drive home. Instead of giving away a soft drink, offer them a towelette. Pretty much everything in downtown shopping areas is a bit dirty. Problem is there&apos;s no place to wash up. Give away towelettes. Pumping your own gas can get messy. Therefore, we distribute towelettes with our name and phone number printed on them. When purchased in quantity, these are as little as 1.5 cents per packet, including two color printing. 3 inexpensive Register Here! Helium Balloons for Kids Balloons are festive. Kids are attracted to them from hundreds of yards away. We give them to the children while we talk to the parents and offer them an explanation with a connection card. 3 inexpensive Register Here! House Number Painting on Curbs With stencils, spray paint house numbers on curbs. Find decent looking stencils. Leave a connection card when you explain how you are showing God&apos;s love in a practical way. 2 inexpensive Register Here! House to House giveaways You can go house to house on the Fourth of July, Thanksgiving, Christmas, Mother&apos;s day and any other holiday.
Go door to door with a free picnic. Give away hot dogs, chips, buns, beans, and cookies, maybe even a watermelon.

Mum plants: A wonderful house-to-house gift.

Turkey dinner: Great for needy areas!

Holiday potpourri: Great alternative to food product or plant.

Poinsettias: take small poinsettia plants as &quot;&quot;house to house&quot;&quot; gifts.

Fruit: People really like fresh fruit and they will readily take it. Place one orange, apple, and banana inside a clear plastic bag, and tie it with a connection card attached.

Carnation Giveaway: Carnations are affordable, and everyone likes them. This project could be done anytime, but Mother&apos;s Day is a particularly good excuse.
 2 inexpensive Register Here! Light Bulb Replacement Sounds simple, but for some reaching up to a nine foot ceiling is a difficult chore. We offer a 60-watt light bulb with a connection card, and if they&apos;d like we replace burned out ones. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Lollipops / Blow pops These are great giveaway items for parks, festivals, and college campuses. Purchase at Sam&apos;s for around 6 cents apiece - it is an inexpensive but effective way to show God&apos;s love. 3 inexpensive Register Here! Minor House Repairs We usually focus this outreach on single parents and the elderly. It is important that you clarify what you are able to do in terms of repairs. There will always be more need than you can realistically meet. We do projects that can be done with our existing tools and supplies, and that can be finished in two hours. 3 inexpensive Register Here! Pay Laundromat Washer and Dryer Bring a roll or two of quarters and dimes. As patrons enter ask them if they&apos;d like hot or cold wash. You can also provide detergent. Note: This project works best for women. It&apos;s a bit odd for men to reach out to women in this setting. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Pay Library Fines Leave $20.00 for next person who has fines. Leave card in envelope for person to see why fine was paid. 1 inexpensive Register Here! Peanuts With most food giveaways, people are generally not comfortable with unsealed items. Check around for sources on this one. You should be able to find small bags that cost less than a quarter. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Pen and Pencil Giveaways For a very small investment, you can place your church name and phone numbers on the pencils and pens. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Photocopying Purchase photocopying coupons at a reduced rate at Kinko&apos;s or other copying place near the college campus. The price shouldn&apos;t be more than about five cents per copy. Give these punch cards out on campus. Place church logo and phone number on the card. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Polaroid Family Photos at Carriage Rides or Special events A couple will hold on to a decent photo of themselves for years. If you want to get fancy, have a photo frame that is tailor-made for the instant photo-sized picture. Attach a sticker of your church&apos;s logo and phone number. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Post Cards and Stamps College students actually do write home on occasion. Provide postcards complete with postage with a sticker that reads, &quot;It&apos;s good to write your mom!&quot; Include your connection card. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Quarter Drop Are you one of those people who can&apos;t walk past a pay phone without checking the coin return? For all those folks out there, here&apos;s an outreach just for them. We place a sticker on one side of the quarter and place these loaded quarters in coin returns of vending machines of various sorts. This one also works by just placing the coin on the ground or on a bench. A note on the sticker: Make sure the sticker is larger than the quarter. Some folks will leave the sticker on the quarter and try to insert it into the phone or vending machine - then you&apos;ll get a call from the repairman. 1 inexpensive Register Here! Restroom Deodorizer What restroom couldn&apos;t stand to smell a bit nicer? Either hang or attach one to the wall. On the front place your church logo and a slogan along the lines of, &quot;This restroom has been Vineyardized! Give us a call if we can be of more help.&quot; 2 inexpensive Register Here! Shoe Shines Small investment + some elbow grease = big return. Set this up in front of a grocery store on a Saturday or in front of a barbershop. This is a great project for talking to folks. You have a captive audience while you serve them! 3 inexpensive Register Here! Shopping Assistance for Shut-ins This would come by referrals. Work with shut-ins to get a list of needs, shop and deliver. 1 inexpensive Register Here! Single Moms&apos; Oil Change This is a great stand-alone project for a Saturday morning in the church parking lot. We provide this service strictly to single moms, though not necessarily just those in our church. This will require a team of folks with knowledge of the basics. About the only variable here is oil filter size. There are hundreds of sizes, so getting a sign up before the event is vital. This will not work at a filling station. The liability to the owner is unreasonable. 3 inexpensive Register Here! Smoke Detector Batteries All older and some newer detectors use 9-volt batteries. These should be replaced yearly. We do massive battery replacement outreaches on the October time change weekend. Attach a sticker with your logo and phone number to the detector face if it&apos;s possible. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Suntan Lotion Suntan lotion representatives talk to a thousand people a day using their product. We can do better. We bring along large bottles of cream and spray on lotions of various SPF ratings and offer to give people some. 4 inexpensive Register Here! Surf Wax Who says non-surfers can&apos;t relate to beach people? Buy the current popular brand of wax and hit the beach, dude! It&apos;s a definite door, or rather, board opener. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Tattoos or Face Painting Set up a little station and offer free temporary tattoos or face painting. Children love to have pictures painted on their cheeks or foreheads. Even an amateur artist can make a child&apos;s day by painting a face. Purchase paints designed for face painting - tempera paints can leave a rash. Don&apos;t use tempera or poster paints! This is popular with kids and teens alike. An advantage to this project is the time you can spend with the person as you paint their face or apply their tattoo. As you paint or tattoo them, pray that God will touch them with His Spirit. Perfect for Fourth of July or parks. Note: We recommend you don&apos;t paint the child unless the parent is nearby and gives permission. 5 inexpensive Register Here! Test Essay Booklets Many professors require that exams be done in those little blue books. They aren&apos;t expensive, but they are necessary. Purchase them in large numbers at a discount. Attach a connection card to it. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Tire Pressure Check A tire pressure gauge is a small investment. Checking this is easy for anyone. 1 inexpensive Register Here! Toilet Seat Covers At public events where there are only portable toilets, women especially appreciate a toilet seat cover. Buy in bulk and fold up into smaller sizes for distribution with a connection card. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Tree Limb Trimming Purchase an extending trimmer with a saw and pulley clipper. Beware of electric lines. Before trimming any limbs, get approval from the home owner. 3 inexpensive Register Here! Vinyl gloves Pumping gas is both troublesome and smelly. Disposable gloves are an inexpensive way of saying to strangers, &quot;God loves you -- and has a wonderful, lead-free plan for your life.&quot; We attach a sticker or card to these $.06 gloves (gloves available at Sam&apos;s). Self-serve stations have been very willing to allow us to place an acrylic dispenser by their cash registers. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Washer Fluid Fill Most tend to use their windshield washers more in the winter, but a refill project will work about any time of the year. This works well at self-serve stations. The liquid is affordable - as little as 79 cents a gallon. A caution here: Make sure you are refilling the washer fluid tank (blue liquid) and not the radiator overflow tank (green fluid). We&apos;ve made that mistake - $200 to repair. 2 inexpensive Register Here! Window Washing Picture windows aren&apos;t that difficult to clean once you get the hang of using a wide squeegee. (See &quot;Windshield Washing&quot; for more details.) 2 inexpensive Register Here! Windshield Washing This was one of our first projects when we first started serving years ago. It&apos;s a perennial favorite, and we still do it just about every weekend. The materials list is short and inexpensive: a good squeegee, a wiping rag, a connection card and windshield cleaner. (We recommend you not use Windex style cleaner - ask your car parts store what they recommend). If it&apos;s too hot (above 85 degrees F) or too cold (below freezing), you might end up making a dirty windshield even worse. If you are doing this at random in a parking lot, don&apos;t wash high-end cars. Their owners are unlikely to see your service as helpful. Car alarms? If you accidentally set one off, finish cleaning, and move on. We&apos;ve set off plenty. They will reset themselves shortly. Try it at a self-serve gas station - just like the good old days. Use a quality squeegee and work quickly. Give each customer a connection card to remember your service. Secure permission from gas station manager. 4 inexpensive Register Here! Boxes to Merchants with your Logo and Number Imprinted Larger retail stores will not go for this one, but most stores in a mall / shopping center will be grateful. Boxes are affordable when purchased in large numbers. 2 moderate Register Here! Business Window Washing This requires the purchase of good equipment in order to do a decent job. You will need several different sizes of brass squeegees, a special wide mouthed bucket, a lambs wool cleaning head, and cleaning solution. Once you get the hang of using a squeegee it&apos;s not that difficult, it&apos;s quick and actually fun. 2 moderate Register Here! Carbon Monoxide Detectors These have become very affordable recently. They can literally save lives during the winter. Attach your logo and phone number to the card that holds the CO detector button. 2 moderate Register Here! Church Match Books Christian matches? Why not? Our logo is on the front. Inside is a map to our location, our service times, and phone number. We have given away several hundred thousand of these over the past few years. We distribute these at restaurants, gas stations - even bars. Some have asked, &quot;Aren&apos;t you endorsing smoking by giving away match books?&quot; No, we&apos;re just showing them that God loves smokers! 2 moderate Register Here! Coffee/Hot Chocolate Coupons Purchase coffee coupons from a merchant in the mall and give them away to customers. The merchant is grateful for the sale and the steady stream of traffic. 3 moderate Register Here! Food Delivery to Shut-ins Find legitimate shut-ins in your neighborhood. Start a system with interested neighbors for a weekly hot food delivery. Keep in mind, many pre-Christians are very interested in helping others even though they don&apos;t yet know Christ. A project such as this could easily be an entry point to their hearts. 2 moderate Register Here! Gasoline for Your Neighbor How many people do you see buying less than a tank of gas when you fill up? I see that happening all the time. They can&apos;t afford a tank of gas at today&apos;s prices. Add $5.00 to their total and blow their minds. Of course, add in a connection card. 1 moderate Register Here! Gatorade at Biking Trails Some health conscious folks like runners, bikers and generally healthy people, don&apos;t drink soda. Offer them Gatorade or bottled water instead. 2 moderate Register Here! Hot Dog Grilling Like &apos;em or not, grilled hot dogs bring everyone nearby together. Even with providing the dogs, buns and condiments, this is an affordable outreach. We put up a banner that reads, &quot;It&apos;s Party Time!&quot; Provide music and you&apos;ve got a party that will draw strangers like a magnet. 3 moderate Register Here! Ice Cream Coupons Approach a local ice cream store and explain your desire to give away thousands of ice cream coupons. Chances are the owner/manager will be willing to give you a good deal on ice cream coupons. Attach a connection card to the coupon and you&apos;ll have a project that just about everyone in town or on campus will respond to. 2 moderate Register Here! Lamb&apos;s Lunch Throw a sit-down lunch party for residents at a low-income housing development. (See the appendix to Steve Sjogren&apos;s out-of-print book, Servant Warfare, for more information on this outreach.) 5 moderate Register Here! Memorial Service for the Unchurched We have begun to do gratis memorial services for the families of unchurched who come to us. As you reach out to the community, you will increasingly find that those you serve will consider you their church even though they are hardly connected with you. 4 moderate Register Here! Newspapers Some convenience stores allow the entire stack of newspapers to be purchased. We place a sign on the top of the stack that reads, &quot;Free Newspapers - Courtesy of Crossroads Church.&quot; Each paper has a card attached with removable adhesive. 1 moderate Register Here! Phone Cards for Long Distance Calls These cards make great giveaways. Contact long distance companies to find a good deal. Some companies offer a program that allows you to insert a custom message that plays before people access their free minutes. The company we use says, &quot;We like to provide these basically at cost to churches. This is our way of giving back to the church.&quot; If you are interested in finding out about this company, you can call Bill Tucker at (317) 776-7654 Ext. 111, or Michelle at (317) 776-7654 Ext. 122 or e-mail her at 
 This e-mail address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it
 . They also provide long distance at low rates for Vineyard churches with 12% of the total amount going back to the church each month. They would be glad to give you some information on that as well. 2 moderate Register Here! Pizza on Move-In/ Move-Out Day at the Dorms/ Apartments If you want to get the attention of an entire dorm, give away pizza. You will hardly need signs - the aroma will do all the marketing you need. Negotiate a discount with the pizza restaurant for large volumes, or the vendor may be willing to give you the pizza in return for an endorsement. 4 moderate Register Here! Roses Hand out roses or carnations in busy downtown areas or in front of busy stores. Even men find this appealing because they can give them away! Hand a flower and a connection card. Perfect for Valentine&apos;s Day. 2 moderate Register Here! Soft Drink Giveaways Fill coolers with ice and drinks. We always offer at least two options. We set up at grocery store entrances and say, &quot;Hi, would you like regular or diet?&quot; (It&apos;s easier to say yes when there are only two options!) Small home-use coolers usually are too small for this. We have purchased the mega Igloos that hold over 100 cans with ice. We buy Coke brand drinks instead of the cheaper stuff. (Over the years we&apos;ve received hundreds of comments of appreciation that we thought enough of those in our community to invest in decent beverages.) Our connection cards on this one are coated to be water and wilt resistant. The card goes under the opener - we now affectionately call these &quot;card holders.&quot; 4 moderate Register Here! Stamps in Front of the Post Office One church holds a major stamp outreach on April 15th for late tax filers. Not only do they give out stamps, but they also offer coffee and donuts - stress recovery food. They just stand by the mail drop-off boxes with a card table filled with food and stamps. 3 moderate Register Here! Sunday Morning Paper and Coffee Giveaways Purchase a number of Sunday papers, brew excellent coffee and visit your neighbors. Look for the houses that don&apos;t have a paper in the driveway but be sure you don&apos;t knock on the door too early. 3 moderate Register Here! 

 This information is being used with permission from servantevangelism.com. Please visit KindnessResources.com for additional resources!
	</body>
</document>
