<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002152" url="http://www.resumeporta.com/restaurant-assistant-manager-resume/" time="2012-07-12-18:02" support="1" score="0.0011247844799406337" bingtitle="Restaurant Assistant Manager Resume, Sample Restaurant Assistant ..." webtitle="Restaurant Assistant Manager Resume, Sample Restaurant Assistant Manager CV Template">
			<query id="000927" bing-rank="133"/>
	<description>Managed cash transactions and prepared credit card ... Fast Food Restaurant Manager Resumes Template; Restaurant Manager ... Assistant Store Manager Resume; Retail Store ...</description>
	<body>
		Resumes–Free Resume Templates 
Worlds Largest Resume Portal
 

 Restaurant Assistant Manager Resume 

Posted on September 22, 2010
 
This Restaurant Assistant Manager  resume format allows both entry level and experienced professionals to design their resumes. You can effortlessly create resume (CV) for making winning impression during the job interview. This sample resume template briefly describes about the resume objectives and job responsibilities of Restaurant Assistant Manager .

 Contact Information 

Logan Cheeke
12A 1 nd Floor,
Sindhi Soc., Mumbai
(022)-1234567
 

 
logancheeke@gmail.com

 

 Career objective 

 

Pursuing a Culinary Career in Restaurant Management or upper level Kitchen Operations Management.

 Career Achievements 

 Received Bachelors of Science in Hotel, Restaurant, and Tourism Management ACF SE Regional Knowledge Bowl Competition ACF National Knowledge Bowl Competition Attended 2008 World Pastry Forum Demonstration Classes 

 Experience 

 2008–2009 

 Assistant Restaurant Manager
 Jason´s Deli San Antonio, Mumbai

 Analyzed inventory daily and made par sheets for A.M. and P.M. shifts. Maintained a production line that was set up to be proficient. Helped ensure catering orders were produced and distributed in a timely manner. Checked produce daily and placed orders for items needed over the internet. Managed cash transactions and prepared credit card batches twice daily. 

 2006–2008 

 Assistant Restaurant Manager
 Luby´s Restaurant´s Incorporated, Mumbai

 Prepared and set up menu items for cafeteria–type service. Supervised the operation by reviewing previous year´s sales and customer volume for any given day; and used this information to determine the correct amount of food to be produced for the counter. Responsible for the daily inventory and duty of placing produce and milk orders. Analyzed nightly, production and sales of menu items in an effort to creatte accurate daily production sheets for each kitchen department. Checked in groceries, milk, and produce on a routine basis. 

 2003–2006 

 Hotel Front Desk Associate
 La Mansion del Rio Hotel, Mumbai

 Responsible for checking guests in and out of accommodations. Accountable for service transactions and coordinating bell and valet service with front desk needs. Registered guests into accommodations using the AS400 PMS. Operated with different departments of the resort in an effort to achieve the ultimate goal of“Delivering the Magic of the Rocky Mountains”; and graduated from“Potentials”a Vail Resorts employee training program. Trained new employees to meet performance standards. 

 Education and Certification 

 Hotel Management 

Mumbai University, Mumbai

 B.Com
 Mumbai University, Mumbai H.S.C (Commerce)
 S.K Somaiya College, Mumbai 

 References 

Sohan Singh
Manager
Radhika Restaurant, Mumbai
Sohansingh@gmail.com
 
Related Resumes:
 Fast Food Restaurant Manager Resumes Template Restaurant Manager Resume Restaurant Manager Resume Sample Restaurant Manager Resume Restaurant Manager Resume Sample Restaurant Management Personnel Resume Sample Restaurant Worker Resume Restaurant Management Personnel Resume Assistant Projection and Budgeting Manager Resume–Sample Assistant Projection and Budgeting Manager CV Template Restaurant Worker Resume Assistant Store Manager Resume Retail Store Assistant Manager Resume Sample Bar Assistant Resume Retail Assistant Manager Resume Sample Retail Assistant Manager Resume Assistant Manager Resume Assistant General Manager Resume Assistant Property Manager Job Resume Assistant Portfolio Manager Resume Sample Customer Service Assistant Manager Resume 


»Filed Under Hotel Resumes , Manager Resumes 

Comments
 
 Leave a Reply 
 
 Name (required) 
 

 Email Address(required) 
 

 Website 
 

 

 
 CAPTCHA Code * 
 
 

 
 
Advertisement


 
Meta

 Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.org 
 
 
 
Categories

 Accounting Resumes Acting Resumes Administration Resumes Advertising Resumes Agents Resumes Agriculture Resumes Airlines Resumes Analyst Resumes Animation Resumes Architect Resumes Assistant Resumes Associate Resumes Banking Resumes Business Resumes Clerical Resume Coach Resumes Communication Resumes Computer Resumes Construction Resumes Consultant Resumes Coordinator Resumes Counsellor Resumes Customer Service Resumes Data Resumes Designer Resumes Developer Resumes Director Resumes Driver Resumes Engineer Resume Entry Level Resumes Estimator Resumes Executive Resumes Financial Resumes Fire Resumes Government Resumes Graphics Resumes H R Resumes Help Desk Resumes Hotel Resumes I T Resumes Industrial Resumes Insurance Resumes Legal Resumes Library Resumes Management Resumes Manager Resumes Marketing Resumes Media Resumes Medical Resumes Network Resumes Nursing Resumes Officer Resumes Operation Resumes Other Resumes Planner Resumes Police Resumes Programmer Resume Receptionist Resume Recuiter Resume Resume Guide Resume Writing Tips Retail Resumes Sales Resume Scientist Resumes Security Resumes Supervisor Resume Teacher Resumes Technical Resumes Technician Resume Trainer Resumes Warehouse Resumes Web Resumes Writer Resumes 
 
Blogroll

 Jobs In India Letters Six Sigma
	</body>
</document>
