<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002173" url="http://blog.cleveland.com/metro/2010/04/break_ohios_booster_seat_law_a.html" time="2012-07-12-18:04" support="4" score="0.0014988337002819607" bingtitle="Enforcement of Ohio&apos;s new booster-seat law begins today ..." webtitle="Enforcement of Ohio&apos;s new booster-seat law begins today | 						cleveland.com">
			<query id="000734" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001458" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000924" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="001049" bing-rank="55"/>
	<description>Using seat belts alone isn&apos;t safe for young ... Keeping kids safe is the reason a number of ... Children will no longer be allowed to eat fast food, restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Sign in | Register for free Sign in to cleveland.com Username   Password Remember me I forgot my username or password» Don&apos;t have an account?
 Register now for free , or sign in with any of these services:

 

 AIM    Google    OpenID 
 Site Search Search Local Business Listings 
 
 Home News Business Sports Entertainment Interact Jobs Autos Real Estate Rentals Classifieds Find n Save 
 Home &gt; Metro - cleveland.com &gt; Breaking News 
Enforcement of Ohio&apos;s new booster-seat law begins today

Published: Wednesday, April 07, 2010, 9:00 AM
 By Diane Suchetka, The Plain Dealer The Plain Dealer 
 Follow 32 Tweet Share close Digg Stumble Upon Fark Reddit Share Email Print 
 Marvin Fong, The Plain Dealer Ronee Armstrong, 6, gets an adjustment to her booster seat by Thomas Vilt, Child Passenger Safety Coordinator at Rainbow Babies and Children&apos;s Hospital, in July 2009. CLEVELAND, Ohio -- The grace period is over.

Today, the rubber meets the road.

As of this morning, police can ticket you if you have child passengers -- from 4 to 8 years old -- who are not in booster seats and wearing seat belts.
 Around the Web 


 Read the law 

 BoostOhiokids.org 

 New national study of crash-involved children reaffirms recommendation for booster seat through age 8 
 
The new rule expands Ohio&apos;s existing car-seat and seat-belt laws.

It&apos;s not just parents who can be fined -- any adult driving with young children must make sure the kids are in booster or car seats.

The Ohio law went into effect in October. But only warnings could be issued for the first six months. That six months was up at midnight.

Now you can be fined $25 to $75, plus court costs, for a first offense.

Who exactly is covered by the law?

Children from 4 to 8 who weigh more than 40 pounds and are less than 4 feet 9 inches tall. Remember, they have to wear seat belts, too. They can still use a car seat, rather than a booster, at the older age, if the seat has been approved for the child&apos;s weight.

Younger children must be in car seats under Ohio law, and older children and adults in seat belts.

Why is Ohio requiring booster seats?

Car crashes are the leading cause of death for children age 4 to 8 in Ohio, according to AAA. Eighty-nine were killed and more than 21,000 injured in auto accidents between 2002 and 2007 in Ohio alone, the association says.

Their chances of being harmed in an accident dropped by 59 percent if they were in booster seats and seat belts, according to one study.

&quot;It&apos;s absolutely the right thing to do because children in this age group are at too great of risk if they&apos;re simply wearing an adult safety belt,&quot; said AAA spokesman Brian Newbacher.

Using seat belts alone isn&apos;t safe for young children. The lap belts fall against children&apos;s stomachs and can injure vital organs when small bodies are hurled forward in a crash. And children often push aside shoulder belts because they cut across their necks.

&quot;Even though it&apos;s a secondary law, it will have an impact because parents do look to laws for guidance,&quot; Newbacher said.

What that means is officers can&apos;t stop drivers for booster-seat offenses alone. If they pull a driver over for another offense, though, they can ticket him or her for not using the child restraints.

Keeping kids safe is the reason a number of organizations -- including AAA, the American Academy of Pediatrics , children&apos;s hospitals and public-safety groups -- pushed for the law for years.

If you&apos;re confused about the law or have any question about child safety seats, go to  the Web site for Rainbow Babies&amp;Children&apos;s Hospital&apos;s Injury Prevention Center.

You also can get answers by calling Rainbow&apos;s Car Seat and Safety Store Hotline at 216-844-2277.
 Related topics: aaa , child safety , rainbow babies&amp;children&apos;s hospital 
 
Sponsored Links
 
 Share this story Print Email Story tools 
 
More stories in Metro - cleveland.com
 Previous story
 A.M. News Links: Guns, arsonists and toads Next story
 Police find car Angel Bradley-Crockett was driving the night she was killed Copyright 2012 cleveland.com. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. 
 32 
Comments Feed 
 View: 
 
 Oldest first | Newest first   1 | 2 | 3 Next comments » emorson April 07, 2010 at 10:08AM Follow 

Well, will i get in within the 8 seconds? I believe this law will be used over and over again in racist ways.

Also, look at the photo... it looks like a piece of foam, a couple inches of foam, needed to lift a child so that the seat belt will cross the chest rather than the neck. Is this the purpose? Is it necessary to fill a car with little seats because the seatbelts haven&apos;t been designed properly?

sorry, I can&apos;t give your children a ride in a blizzard, because i don&apos;t have several pieces of foam for them to sit on.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new akronlaw25 April 07, 2010 at 12:41PM Follow 

I&apos;m curious why I can&apos;t just go to my dealer and pay them to modify my car accordingly... I&apos;d much rather do that than carry some booster seat around that makes my kids feel younger than they are.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new mos52 April 07, 2010 at 9:17AM Follow 

Yay! More government!

:(

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new akronlaw25 April 07, 2010 at 9:36AM Follow 

Another corporate giveaway. You&apos;re welcome Evenflo, Graco, etc.


I&apos;m sure that next we&apos;ll have to staple orange foam all over the interior of the car, lock our children in stasis suits, mandate all cars come standard wtih 26 airbags so that car accidents feel like you&apos;ve fallen on a cloud and lower the speed limit to 5 miles per hour on all highways and 2.5 miles per hour on city streets. Soon pavement will be replaced by styrofoam and only one automobile will be allowed on the road at any given time. Children will no longer be allowed to eat fast food, restaurant food, or anything other than whole fruits, vegetables, and grains. Children will be required to wear knee pads when running around outside.


Silly government, leave parenting to PARENTS.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new akronlaw25 April 07, 2010 at 9:41AM Follow 

When I was in high school I dated a girl who was 16 years old and 4&apos;8&quot;-4&apos;9&quot; If this law were in effect then, would I have had to keep a booster seat in my camaro for her?

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new neolib April 07, 2010 at 12:11PM Follow 

Nope.

 Who exactly is covered by the law?
Children from 4 to 8 who weigh more than 40 pounds and are less than 4 feet 9 inches tall. 

Unless you&apos;re saying, &quot;But she TOLD me she was sixteen!&quot;

;)

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new akronlaw25 April 07, 2010 at 12:33PM Follow 

yeah, i didn&apos;t really bother to read it, just commented blindly.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new neolib April 07, 2010 at 1:37PM Follow 

eh - you gave it the attention it deserved.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new burningliver April 07, 2010 at 9:39AM Follow 

Ok the information in this article is lacking. It says &quot;police can ticket you if you have child passengers -- from 4 to 8 years old -- who are not in booster seats and wearing seat belts.&quot; Gee, that sure looks like 8 year olds are subject to the new law. But the law itself says it applies to &quot;any child who is less than eight years of age and less than four feet nine inches in height.&quot; R.C. 4511.81(C). Where the article says &quot;children from four to eight&quot; are covered by the law, it should say kids from four to seven are covered; kids 8 or older, and kids taller than 4&apos; 9&quot; even if they&apos;re seven or under, are exempt.

As for you &quot;more government&quot; hacks, if you can&apos;t get behind keeping kids from getting banged up or killed, you&apos;re just out of your mind.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new metropark1 April 07, 2010 at 10:23AM Follow 

another step to the left....when will it end? It all started with seat belts, then cell phones in cars, then texting in cars, then idling cars, now this. Whats next? checkpoints and mandatory searches? Government is so much in our lives and business it is not funny...and now they want to &quot;force&quot; us to buy health insurance or pay a penalty.....USSA.....

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new cuzisaidso April 07, 2010 at 10:24AM Follow 

This law is not one based on racism as much as they will be attacking the poor. There is a lawmaker in Ohio getting rich off of this law and they ought to be ashamed of themselves. These seats are way too expensive, not easy to use, and an excuse for the police and city coffers to patent their budgets. This law has absolutely nothing to do with safety.

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new metropark1 April 07, 2010 at 10:28AM Follow 

I forgot to mention the smoking ban too...and how the county commissioners last year took it upon themselves to raise our taxes and plan for a convo center and med mart...its not going to end with this round of &quot;child seat enforcement:...oh no..there will be another law coming...maybe on pants on the ground or cussing in public or sporting events.....when will it end???

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new vicknows April 07, 2010 at 10:42AM Follow 

another reason to move out of OHIO
I believe saftey is No 1 for children as well as adults, but when you have a study that no one is aware of or can ask question is totaly wrong, I believe this could have been avoided by adding to the seat belt itself and what are we doing about the car industry that does not have suffiecient protection for children, so at out exspense when we purchase a new car you must purchase additional safety items, goes to show you , and what other states require them, did they also have safety studies? and how much was this study? who ordered it?

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new luvtatertots April 07, 2010 at 10:54AM Follow 

emorson, it has nothing to do with race, so sick of the crying about race, shut up already. its about $$$$ and nothing else. Another law, more freedoms taken away, when will it stop?

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new grouser April 07, 2010 at 11:05AM Follow 

It will stop when you vote out all the Democrats and replace them with Republicans because they are for family values, fiscal conservatism, lower taxes, less government and by God, this time they mean it when they say they&apos;re for these things!!!

 Inappropriate?  Alert us. Reply Post new   1 | 2 | 3 Next comments » 
 
Post a comment
 (You may use HTML tags for style) 
 

You must accept the terms of service before you can post a comment.
 
Post a comment
 
Sign in to cleveland.com
 Username Password 
  Remember me? I forgot my username or password» 
Don&apos;t have an account?

 Register now for free , or sign in with any of these services:
 
 AIM Google OpenID 
 
More Metro - cleveland.com

 Most Comments Most Recent 
 
 Metro - cleveland.com stories with the most comments in the last 7 days. 184 President Barack Obama pulls away from Mitt Romney in latest Quinnipiac University poll 54 Bobcats&apos; pre-draft trade ramps up speculation: NBA Draft rumors and links 52 Ohio State&apos;s Jared Sullinger doesn&apos;t deserve this pre-draft free fall: Doug Lesmerises commentary 14 President Barack Obama will return to Ohio next week on heels of expected health care decision (updated) 11 Romney willing to tackle tough issues, Obama planning bus tour, more: Presidential Race Roundup 
 
Most Active Users
 What&apos;s this? 
 Users with the most Metro - cleveland.com comments in the last 7 days 0 jillie23 
 

Users We Love
 &quot;LongSufferingBrownsFan&quot; recognized as a featured cleveland.com user 
Learn more about &quot;LongSufferingBrownsFan&quot;, cleveland.com&apos;s latest featured user. More Users We Love 
Connect with cleveland.com
 What&apos;s this? 
 
 All Facebook&amp;Twitter accounts » From Our Advertisers 

 
 Advertise With Us» 
Popular Tags
 What&apos;s this? 

 
 Site Search Search Local Business Listings 
 Site Map | Advertise | Contact us Make us your home page Home | News | Weather | Sports | Entertainment | Interact | Living | Jobs | Autos | Real Estate | Classifieds | Shopping | Place an Ad 
 Your Photos Your Videos Blogs Forums Travel Music 
 
 Post a Job Post a free classified ad Sell your car Sell/Rent your Home Apartments&amp;Rentals Claim your Business
    Listing for Free 
 
 Friday! Magazine High School Sports Arts Taste Going Out Guides Style 
 
 Subscribe to our content (RSS) Subscribe to Email Newsletters cleveland.com Twitter feed cleveland.com on Facebook cleveland.com mobile site 
 Special home delivery offers! The Plain Dealer 
 Sun News Registration on or use of this site constitutes acceptance of our User Agreement and Privacy Policy (Revised November 1, 2011)

©2012 Cleveland Live LLC. All rights reserved ( About Us ).
The material on this site may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, cached or otherwise used, except with the prior written permission of Cleveland Live LLC.

 Community Rules apply to all content you upload or otherwise submit to this site. Contact interactivity management .

 Ad Choices
	</body>
</document>
