<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002474" url="http://stayathomemoms.about.com/u/reviews/productreviews/Kids-Meal-Toys/form.htm" time="2012-07-12-18:32" support="1" score="0.0013698322548795889" bingtitle="Write a Review: Meal Toys - Kids Meal Toys&gt;" webtitle="Write a Review: Meal Toys - Kids Meal Toys">
			<query id="000183" bing-rank="225"/>
	<description>The promise of a toy makes some children beg for a kids&apos; meal at a fast food restaurant. ... Receive a one-time notification when your response is published.</description>
	<body>
		Parenting 
 Stay-at-Home Moms Search 
 Stay-at-Home Moms Help for Mom Household Tips Fun With Kids 
 
 Write a Review: Kids&apos; Meal Toys

 See Published Reviews 
 You know that look on your children&apos;s faces when they open up their kids&apos; meal from a fast food restaurant to see what kind of toy is inside. Sometimes that toy is worth keeping because they love it so much. Other times, the toy never even makes it into your house because it&apos;s such a dud.

Write a review of the kids&apos; meal toys your child has received from fast food restaurants. 
Hi there. I&apos;m really sorry to say this, but you won&apos;t be able to use this form because your browser doesn&apos;t have JavaScript enabled. You will need to turn on JavaScript if you want to submit a review. Thanks for understanding!
 
 * Required fields
 Guest Name * 
 Login with Member Name or Register 
 Email Receive a one-time notification when your response is published. Your Overall Rating * 1 Star 2 Stars 3 Stars 4 Stars 5 Stars Name or description of the kids&apos; meal toy * Fast food restaurant where you received this toy * Write Your Review * Describe the toy&apos;s pros and cons. Provide specific examples about why you would or would not recommend it to others. Date of Purchase Type the full date of your kids&apos; meal purchase, just the month and year or leave blank if you don&apos;t remember. How old is your child? If you have multiple children who received the same toy in their kids&apos; meals, include all of their ages. Was the toy age-appropriate for your child? * Please Choose Yes No How long did your child play with the toy? * Please Choose Only for a few minutes For a day or two For more than a week Several weeks Not at all Did the toy help justify the cost of the kids&apos; meal? * Please Choose Yes No Would you go back to get other toys in this series? * Please Choose Yes No What do you plan on doing with this toy? * Please Choose Keep it Trash it Already been thrown out Would you recommend this to a friend? * Yes No 
 Photo Guidelines 
 Optional: Upload a picture you took of the toy. 
5MB max
 Write a Caption Post my response on Facebook when it&apos;s published. Preview Submit Edit 
Articles and photos submitted to About.com must be original and not taken from other sources. Guide may email you with questions about your submission. See our User Agreement .
 Stay-at-Home Moms 
 About.com Parenting Stay-at-Home Moms 
 
 Advertise on About.com Our Story News&amp;Events Work at About SiteMap All Topics Reprints Help 

 Write for About User Agreement Ethics Policy Patent Info. Privacy Policy Your Ad Choices 
 
©2012 About.com. All rights reserved.

A part of The New York Times Company .
	</body>
</document>
