<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002266" url="http://au.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20071225031315AAbPFka" time="2012-07-12-18:10" support="4" score="0.010901210838165195" bingtitle="What is your biggest pet peeve about fast food restaurant ..." webtitle="What is your biggest pet peeve about fast food restaurant employees? - Yahoo!7 Answers">
			<query id="001473" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001189" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="001367" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="001504" bing-rank="100"/>
	<description>... the thing is sticking together so you just end ... I have to run my ass back to the the fast food restaurant and ... window, giving the annoying lady at the counter ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
 Mail 

 My Y!7 Yahoo!7 
 
 Yahoo! 7 Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo!7 Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Fast Food &gt; Resolved Question 
 *Lexi* Member since: 09 September 2007 Total points: 2,740 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
What is your biggest pet peeve about fast food restaurant employees?
 i hate it when you can&apos;t understand them on the speaker thing, and no matter how many times you clearly repeat your order they still mess it up. i also hate it when my fries spill out all over the bag because they just put it on and of course fell over. haha. you? 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 by howlsint... Member since: 02 September 2007 Total points: 1,058 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 Many times they never get the order right. Also It seems that more often than not, they don&apos;t even say thank you after getting your food, esp at the drive-through. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 33% 2 Votes 
 4 people rated this as good 
 
 Action Bar: 4 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo!7 Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; What is your biggest… &quot;was originally asked on Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (18)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Anon e Mouse Member since: 14 December 2006 Total points: 132,394 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Sometimes they are too busy talking to each other. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 17% 1 Vote by N M Member since: 18 December 2007 Total points: 1,669 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 when you&apos;re standing in front of them giving them your order and they still get it wrong or get someone elses order. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by Is that what you really think? Member since: 19 December 2007 Total points: 632 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 mmm when they act like it is an inconvenience for then to do their job. Like they are doing you a favor for providing you some heart clogging food. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 3 people rated this as good 
 by Lisa B Member since: 12 October 2006 Total points: 6,729 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I just feel bad that they dislike their jobs because it is something that offers bad pay and no incentive to go the extra mile for the customer. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 17% 1 Vote 
 3 people rated this as good 
 by J Member since: 23 December 2007 Total points: 2,093 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I hate when you say hi, and please and thank you and they are not polite to you at all. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 17% 1 Vote 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by The Master Member since: 22 October 2007 Total points: 18,689 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 There&apos;s many, but probably when they can&apos;t even put a simple sandwich together correctly. You take it out of the wrapper and the top bun is like half way off the sandwich and the sauce is running everywhere. You try and correct it yourself but the thing is sticking together so you just end of tearing it apart and making it worse. You spend the whole time trying to get less on you than in your mouth. Sometimes I think they could hire monkeys who could do it better.

Thanks for this question, I always wanted to rant about this :) 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Mark Member since: 03 April 2006 Total points: 3,826 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 The biggest pet peeve ever about fast food restaurant employees is: Whenever I order something at the drive-thru, I don&apos;t get everything I ordered. I have to run my ass back to the the fast food restaurant and as a customer, complain about it. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by Antionette M Member since: 13 July 2007 Total points: 566 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Well my biggest pet peeve of all is....

PEOPLE THAT COMPLAIN ABOUT FAST FOOD EMPLOYEES!

I&apos;m only rude when someone is rude to me on my job. For all the people that have not experienced working fast food, try taking an order from the drive thru, rceiving money from the person at the window, giving the annoying lady at the counter MORE ketchup for the 6th time, making drinks to hand out and putting stuff in the bag. All while trying to tell the NON-ENGLISH speaking immagrants in the kitchen how to make something correctly!

And do you realize how loud that kitchen is? Sometimes we honestly cant hear you. Traffic outside, weather, other people talking, or you just not clearly SPEAKING UP could affect that.


I say please and thank you all day long! And do you know how many times they say it back to me? Probably 6 times out off 200! If it wasnt for these fast food employees where would you people go to digest such disgusting food.

I have a lady that comes in every Tuesday and complains that we messed up her order, even though thats what she told us!

Think people before you speak next time.

As for people answering cell phones...thats rude. I&apos;ve done it once before during an order because my sister was going into labor. 
Source(s):
 18 year old college student who works at Burger King and Wendy&apos;s 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by Star Girl Member since: 23 December 2007 Total points: 2,447 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 when they say&quot;how may i help u madame&quot;-it is irritating 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Michael M Member since: 13 May 2007 Total points: 106,727 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 slow and do not care. no focus on the job. very poor service. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Blue eyed girl Member since: 07 January 2007 Total points: 762 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 GETTING ORDERS MESSED UP AND REPEATING WHAT YOU WANT AND THEN WHEN YOU GET YOUR FOOD IT&apos;S NOT WHAT YOU ORDERED. OR IF YOU GO INTO THE FAST FOOD THE PLACE THE BATHROOMS ARE ALWAYS REALLY NASTY. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Hot Patata Member since: 16 June 2007 Total points: 15,815 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I was in McDonald&apos;s this past week, and I saw woman actually ANSWER HER CELL PHONE and talk for half a minute, in the middle of taking an order at the counter. That takes the cake; although I have seen fast food employees on their cells before, I never saw it during an actual customer transaction. I wanted to fire her myself. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 17% 1 Vote 
 2 people rated this as good 
 by Andrea Member since: 11 July 2007 Total points: 1,382 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I rarely eat at fast food restaurants because I try to avoid high-fat, high-sodium, high-sugar, low-nutrient processed foods. Aside from food issues, uncleanliness disturbs me most about fast food restaurants. Fast food and other dining establishments should instruct employees to wash hands after wiping counters, mopping floors, and handling cash. Also, using the same dirty rag to wipe knives and clean beverage and ice cream dispensers is not sanitary. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by NunnKris... Member since: 07 November 2007 Total points: 4,023 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 i work in fast food. i try to be very polite to all the customers. and i like my job.

so i know its really hard in fast food, and very stressful. so i have respect to other people who work there in fast food.

however i dont like it when people are rude. you may have a bad day, but dont take it on me. ya know?

and SOMETIMES...when people get your order wrong at drive thru....SOMETIMES its not their fault....SOMETIMES its the speaker. i know we have bad head phones, so we had some wrong orders a few times because we couldnt hear the full order....however of course thats not always the case. 
Source(s):
 work at wendys 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by ha*ha*ha Member since: 22 October 2007 Total points: 12,400 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I&apos;m 15 so I tend to get the feeling that restaurant employees treat me worse than adult customers for some reason. I know Olive Garden isn&apos;t fast food, but I went there with a bunch of friends before homecoming last year and we were treated horribly by one of the employees (not even our waiter, she was our busser). She came up to us in the middle of our meal and asked us what time we needed to leave by and refused to refill our drinks. Worst experience I have ever had at one of those places. I still love Olive Garden, but now I only go there with my family and other adults. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 3 people rated this as good 
 by Dee Member since: 15 February 2007 Total points: 36,714 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 How they are rude.&amp;mess up the orders 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Jenn Member since: 25 March 2007 Total points: 355 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I don&apos;t like when they&apos;re not polite to customers... but i know that that is THE HARDEST job in the world. I worked in fast food for a year when I was 15, and I have so much more respect for the occupation. Whether or not we know it, we need those people or we would be upset that we can&apos;t get our food. We blame the front line people for the wrong things, but it&apos;s the back that does it... rough job. 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 4 people rated this as good 
 

 by Ozeki Member since: 14 June 2006 Total points: 38,193 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Answer hidden due to its low rating
 they smell 
 5 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 
Discover Questions in Fast Food 

 Interview questions for McDonalds? ? What time does Mcdonalds stop serving apple pies UK? New at working at Sonic Drive-Inn? Any Tips? Will i get hired at McDonald&apos;s ? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

 Anon e Mouse NunnKriss J Dee 
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo!7 does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo!7 Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo!7 Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo!7 Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
