<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002327" url="http://blog.laborlawcenter.com/2006/07/27/colorado-lunch-and-break-law/" time="2012-07-12-18:15" support="19" score="0.029043410061461928" bingtitle="Labor Law Center Blog » Blog Archive » Lunch and Break Law ..." webtitle="Lunch and Break Law Regulations in Colorado (CO) | Labor Law Center Blog">
			<query id="001422" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000730" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="001485" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="001454" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="001108" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="000042" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000262" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="000417" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000231" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001045" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="001516" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000542" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="000355" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000920" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000888" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="000982" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="001014" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="000857" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000168" bing-rank="99"/>
	<description>Hello, I’m 16 and I work at a fast food restaurant. ... I work as a building insp. for local county ... covered under the Colorado Minimum Wage Order Number 27.</description>
	<body>
		Home   ::   LaborLawCenter.com 
 labor law Adivision of labor law center 
 
 Lunch and Break Law Regulations in Colorado (CO) 
 July 27th, 2006 Posted by Sarah 
Lunches and Breaks are a subject of much interest by employers and employees alike. In reviewing state laws related to this area, I have found that Colorado has several pertinent state regulations.

If an employee works five or more consecutive hours, he or she is entitled under Colorado law to a 30 minute meal break. In order for this to qualify as an unpaid break, the worker must be completely relieved of his or her duties, and must be free to engage in personal activities during this time.

The Colorado lunch and break law recognizes that in some situations, it may not be feasible for an employee to be completely relieved of his or her duties. If an uninterrupted meal break is not a practical possibility, an employee must be allowed to consume an “on-duty” meal, during which he or she must be paid.

Colorado is also one of a handful of states that provides in the state code for specified rest periods. Employers in Colorado must provide workers a ten minute rest break for each four hours or “major fraction thereof” worked. The law states that these are to be paid breaks, and the employer is allowed to mandate that workers stay on the premises during the break.

While the lunch and break rules apply to most service professions such as retail stores, the food and beverage industry and housekeeping jobs, other professional jobs such as teachers, nurses, managers and administrative workers are exempted.

Finally, I think it may be of interest to note Colorado’s rules regarding times when employees are asked to wait. Under Colorado law, if an employee is waiting between job duties during the normal course of a work day, or is “on-call” but has great restrictions placed on their freedom to move about and engage in personal pursuits, this waiting time must be considered work time. On the other hand, if an employee is able to continue with personal pursuits away from the workplace and has ample time to respond to calls, this type of waiting may not be considered paid work hours.

A complete summary of Colorado’s lunch and break laws may be found on the Complete Colorado Labor Law Poster . This poster also contains detailed information on many other aspects of both federal and state labor laws.

Last 10 posts by Sarah

 Our New Community For HR Professionals, www.HumanResourceBlog.com Is Now Available - July 31st, 2007 South Dakota Labor Laws - August 24th, 2006 Labor Law Regulations in South Dakota (SD) - August 24th, 2006 Rhode Island Labor Law Regulations - August 24th, 2006 State of Pennsylvania Labor Laws - August 24th, 2006 Oregon Labor Law Requirements - August 23rd, 2006 Labor Law Requirements in Oklahoma - August 23rd, 2006 Labor Laws Governing Ohio - August 23rd, 2006 Employer Regulatory Requirements in North Dakota - August 23rd, 2006 State Labor Laws Governing North Carolina - August 18th, 2006 
 56 Comments&gt;&gt; Posted in Colorado , Employment Laws , Wage and Hour 
 
 
Posted by: Francine 

Are nonexempt employees in Colorado not required to take a lunch daily?
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Francine! That’s a great question! For a complete answer, please post it at our HR forum, http://www.humanresourcesblog.com .

And thanks for reading the blog! Amelia
 
Posted by: Dierdre 

I have concerns relating to unemployment benfits eligibility due to an unworkable environment.
I was recently sought out by the GM&amp;Owner of my company to address the unprofessional business practices of the Office Manager who, at that time was my supervisor. After months of consultation, they have decided to maintain the status quo, stating that they no longer wanted the burden of addressing the matter.
At one time (less than 1 week ago) I was told that the person in question would be let go by the end of the year and now she is back in a senior position to me, as of yesterday. They shared with me that some of the sensitive examples I was asked to share with them regarding her past behavior in the office, were discussed with her in detail.
I am left in an extremely negative environment with a documented history of verbal abusiveness on the person in question’s part toward those under her authority/woman.
I was told by the GM and Owner on several occassions that they were/are fully aware of her attitude and inability to work with other women in the office and that they saw no possibility of change on her part in the future, resulting in a decision to move forward. Now that decision has been reversed. What are my rights in this scenario? Thank you.
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Dierdre! Unfortunately, you have no specific rights in this situation. If you quit due to the“unworkable environment”you will likely not qualify for unemployment benefits. And this is a really, really bad time to be out of work.
We agree that this appears to be a toxic work environment, but we would offer a different perspective on it. It is not reasonable for the GM/Owner to expect someone who reports to the Office Manger to correct this situation. Whether he or she was collecting information on the Office Manger’s past performance or interpersonal skills, clearly they could correct the situation by firing the Office Manager…and decided not to. You were set up, but by the GM/Owner, not by the Office Manager. We suggest that you do the best job you possibly can, while looking for another position. It is possible that you will be terminated. In that case, at least you would be eligible for unemployment.
If you feel that you have a case for discrimination based on sex, you can certainly file a complaint with the EEOC. However, it sounds to us like this Office Manager simply has poor management skillls. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Zach 

Hello, my wife works in Colorado as an assisted living caregiver at an assisted living residence during the night shift. She works an 8hr shift during the night shift. Her employer is requiring her to take a 30min during her shift unpaid. They are telling her that she will be written up and fired if she disobeys this mandatory rule. However she must stay at work, on the floor that she works on and she must still perform her duties during this mandatory break time because there must always be 2 caregivers on each floor at any given time. Is it legal for her employer to force her to stay there on her floor performing her duties and not pay her for this half hour that she still has to work? I don’t know if we should take any sort of action about this or if we have any sort of legal ground to stand on. She is affraid she will be fired if she tries to make a big deal about it. Thanks for your reply in advance!!!

Zach
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Zach! It is legal for the employer to impose a mandatory 30-minute meal period, and for the employer to require that your wife eat her lunch at her work station. However, if she is still required to work during this time, she must be paid for it. Not doing so is a violation of both federal and state law.
Your wife should contact both the Colorado Workforce Commission and the U.S. Department of Labor, and file a complaint about her unpaid wages for the breaks. It is illegal for an employer to retaliate against a worker who files a complaint in good faith. (Unfortunately, if the employee goes directly to the employer, they make retaliate in a case like this.) HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~Amelia
 
Posted by: Mike 

A friend mentioned that he was told that, since his company is based out of state, they are exempt from Colorado law that requires the 30-minute lunch break. I was doubtful. Is my doubt warranted? He is not a teacher, nurse, or a manager-type.
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Mike! We are equally doubtful. Colorado employment law applies to employees in the state of Colorado. Most likely, your friend is legally an employee in the state of Colorado. Suppose he works at a bank or hotel in Colorado, owned by a company with headquarters in Florida or California. The Colorado employment laws—including the break law—would apply. (If this were not true, every employer on the planet could avoid labor laws including minimum wage and worker safety laws simply by locating the headquarters in a different state from the employees.)
If your friend was employed in Utah or Texas and on an assignment for a few days in Colorado, then Utah or Texas labor laws would apply to him. In many cases when an employee works from home on a regular basis, their home office becomes a branch office of the employer’s business—and if that home is in Colorado, the state break law applies.
We suggest your friend contact the Colorado Department of Labor and Employment for a ruling on which state’s laws apply. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Ashley 

I work a Food Court in Greeley, Colorado. We sell snack foods, soda, etc. At night I bring a wagon load of stuff to sell at a concessions stand. I started on Wednesday, and until yesterday hadn’t had one break or lunch. I told her I was taking a fifteen minute break, she later told me I only get a ten minute break. That is fine with me; however, she is now telling me that since I work the ball park and since it is rather slow, I shouldn’t be getting my break as regularly and there is a different law. I think she is full of it. Does the law about breaks and lunches apply whether or not I am working a slow job at the concessions stand?

Here’s an example:
On Friday I started at the food court from 3pm-5:20pm. At 5:20pm I headed up to the ball park and worked until 9:30. I then packed up and finally got out of there at 10:20 pm. I did not have one break and did not have a lunch either.

How is this supposed to work?
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Ashley! Colorado employees are entitled to a 30 minute meal break after 5 hours, unless the shift will be over in 6 hours. As you will note from the article above, employees must be permitted to take an on-duty (paid) meal break whenever the nature of the work prevents relief from all duties. Your concession job is a perfect example. If you are on an unpaid meal break and a customer arrives, who will wait on him or her? Because you are the only person working the concession stand, there is no one else. So, the law permits you to eat a meal at your work station, and be paid for that time. You can take short“mini breaks”whenever there are no customers. But if a customer arrives, you must interrupt your“meal break”.
In addition, you are entitled to a 10 minute break for every 4 hour work segment, at approximately the mid-point. If you start work at 3 pm and end at 10 pm, you are entitled to a break at 5 pm and a break about 8:30 pm. It appears that the employer must grant these breaks, even if you are working alone and there are down times during the shift. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Anna 

Hello, I’m 16 and I work at a fast food restaurant. I work over four hours every day, often 4:45. I’ve been working there since it opened three and a half months ago and I have never once received a ten minute break or lunch break. The company policy is to allow a three minute max“drink break”; and only then if it’s not busy. Is this allowed? It seems like it wouldn’t be, but it’s frustrating not getting a minute to sit down. I would also like to know what I could do about it if this isn’t right.

Thanks,
~Anna
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Anna! You are right—this is a violation of Colorado law. Each employee should receive a paid 10-minute rest break for each 4 hours worked. Contact the Colorado Department of Labor and Employment to file a complaint. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Confused 

Hi, this pertains to a teacher working a 6 hour day M-F. As a state employee of Colorado, does a teacher qualify for a paid or unpaid lunch break? Typical day is from 8am-2pm. Can the county say that they get no break at all?
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Confused! Yes, unfortunately, this is a very common complaint that teachers have in Colorado and other states. The Colorado break law specifically excludes teachers from coverage. In addition, the law permits employers to omit the meal break when the shift will be completed in 6 hours or less, in any occupation. But even if your shift were 8 hours or longer, as a teacher you are excluded. Sorry, wish we could be more help. ~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Jeff 

I work as a deputy sheriff in Colorado. My shift is a 10 hour shift. I get a 30 minute paid meal break roughly 3 hours into my shift, as I am required to respond to emergencies while on break. I then have to go 7 hours until the end of my shift without a break. It seems to me that this in violation, but I’m not sure if law enforcement is exempt form this. I’m familiar with criminal law, just not labor law. Thanks for your help.

Jeff
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Jeff! You are correct—Colorado law does not apply in this situation. First, state employment laws including break laws frequently exclude law enforcement officers or even all state and municipal employees. The Colorado meal and break law is quite limited in scope, and applies to employees in the following industries: retail, food&amp;beverage, housekeeping, beauty service, laundry&amp;dry cleaning and janitorial services. So the Colorado meal and break law does not apply to law enforcement officers.
Even if it did, by granting a 30-minute meal break after 3 hours, the employer is complying with the law. They are going above and beyond what would be required by making the meal break paid. Apparently the issue is that you do not receive two 10-minute paid breaks during the 7-hour portion of your shift. But again, that law does not apply to police officers.
Even in states where the meal break law applies to all employees, there is usually an exception if complying with the law would endanger public safety (for example, by leaving too few firefighters or police officers on duty.)
So the break and meal law in Colorado doesn’t apply to you, and the employer is in compliance. Our suggestion, if police regulations permit, is that you bring a snack and eat it while on duty during the 7 hours after your meal break. If you have a union, you might also raise this issue with them. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Jason 

I’m a sous chef in a retirement community, I am familiar with the break laws as is my staff. Here is the situation, corporate is stating that we have to take a thirty minute off the clock break, as a cook for 10 years I am not used to this, I am used to working my whole shift with no break, because there is always something to do. I told my employer that I understand the law, but I am refusing to take the break, because I have things that need to get done in order to do my job properly. They said that if my staff and I don’t start clocking out for breaks that they will deduct a half hour of pay from us. My question is, is this legal? I don’t think it is and would like some clarification please, and what can I do if it is illegal?
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Jason! We have good news and bad news for you. Here’s both: if you work through your mandatory unpaid break, the employer must pay you for it. However, the employer can fire you for not following the company break policy.

Details: Under Colorado law, every employee who works a shift of 6 hours or more must receive a 30-minute meal break after 5 hours. The law specifically applies to employees in the food and beverage industry, as well as retail, medical, etc. If the break is uninterrupted, it can be unpaid.

If the nature of the work prevents an employee from taking an uninterrupted 30-minute meal break, an on-duty, paid meal break is permitted. For a line cook working alone, the nature of the work prevents the employee from taking an uninterrupted meal break. If an order comes in while the line cook is on meal break, he or she must return to work to cook it.

However, the nature of a Sous Chef’s work does not make it impossible to take an uninterrupted meal break. It may be inconvenient, but it is not impossible. So your employer is merely complying with the law in your case (and presumably in the case of your employees.)

To be honest, all of that is irrelevant. The break law is a minimum standard, not a maximum standard. The employer can require more or longer unpaid meal breaks than the law demands. Any employee who does not comply with company break policy can and should be fired.

The employer’s threat to automatically deduct the time if you do not take the break is a bluff. If the employer did this, it would be illegal. Both the federal FLSA (Fair Labor Standards Act) and the Colorado minimum wage law require that employees be paid for all time worked. If you work from 8 am to 4 pm without a break, you must be paid for 8 hours. You can be terminated for not taking the required meal break, but you must be paid for 8 hours. If your employer begins“automatically”deducting for breaks that you never took, you should file a wage claim with the Colorado Department of Labor and Employment, so you can get paid for that half-hour each day.

That pay will come in very handy, because if you are fired for willfully violating the company break policy, you will not qualify for unemployment benefits.

Our suggestion is that you follow company policy by arranging your work so you have a 30-minute unpaid meal break each day, and have your employees do the same. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Carol 

Hello,

I have looked at the federal site and our state site, and still don’t know if the break and lunch laws apply to our industry or not. I suppose it would be Hospitality. Are hotel receptionists (front desk check-in people) excluded from the break and lunch laws?
 
Posted by: Carol 

And one more thing, if hospitality is excluded, do the laws still apply to the janitorial and housekeeping personnel working within a hotel? Thank you.
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Carol! Colorado has one of the most specific and restricted of meal break laws. The law applies only to employees in the following industries: retail, food and beverage, public housekeeping, medical profession, beauty service, laundry and drycleaning and janitorial services. This means that as a hotel front desk clerk, you are not covered by the meal break law. The hotel housekeeping staff is covered by that law, and so are any employees of a hotel restaurant. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi again Carol! Yes, the way the law is written, the hotel housekeeping staff is covered. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Sam 

Ok I’ve Been reading the laws of Colorado and I understand that I am entitled to a break every four hrs. Or an unpaid break after five. I work as a cook in a small restaurant and have been told I have to take a 30 min break. I know you havetold others it is mandatory but the law states that we are entitled, not that it is mandatory. So I am confused, please help.
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Sam! There are really two issues here: Colorado law and company policy. We are sorry to say that the employer is right on both counts.
Colorado law requires that employers grant a 30-minute meal period for shifts of 5 hours or more. Some states with similar laws permit the employee to waive the meal period in writing. Colorado does not. So, if you skip a meal period—even voluntarily—the employer has broken the law. In addition, there is nothing to prevent you voluntarily working through the meal period and then claiming at a later date that the employer deprived you of your rightful break. (If you do not take the break, how will the employer prove that they did not deprive you of it?)
However, even if Colorado did not have a meal break law, an employer in any state can require that employees take an unpaid 30 minute meal break on each shift. Any employee who does not follow this company policy can be disciplined or terminated.
If you are being asked to work during your meal break, then it must be paid. But as long as you are relieved of work duties, the employer is completely in the right here. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Gerad 

Mondays and tuesdays i work from 8am to 8pm with an hour lunch break at 12pm, wensday i work 10am-8pm with an hour lunch break at 12pm, friday i work 11am to 8 pm with an hour lunch break at 12pm, saturday i work at 8:30am till 7pm with an hour lunch break at 12pm, during those hours of work we don’t always get our 10 min breaks that we are entitled to. Some days they let us have one 10min break around 4pm when we tryed to explaine the break peroids to uppermanegment they told us they don’t have to give us breaks if we are to busy. Also stated breaks are give at their discretion (when ever they feel like giving us breaks).Since we brought this up to uppermanegment they responded back to us that we are to do the dirtyest hardest job at work, Becuase we mentioned our break periods they continue to faulter giving us breaks. Based on the laws in colorado and the hours we work how many breaks in each day are we entitled to and when are we allowed to take them. And Since we do not have a break room where are we allowed to take these breaks.
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Gerad! Under Colorado law, employees are entitled to a 30-minute meal break on each shift of 5 hours or more. There is no requirement that the employer provide a break room—employees can take their break at their work station, as long as they are relieved of all duties.

In addition, Colorado workers are entitled to a 10-minute paid break on each 4-hour work segment, as close to the middle of the work segment as possible. For example, if you start at 8 am and work until noon, you are entitled to one 10-minute break at about 10 am. You would be entitled to 2 or 3 breaks each day, depending upon your schedule.

However, the Colorado meal and break statute covers employees in only 4 industries: 1) Retail and Service 2) Commercial Support Service 3) Food&amp;Beverage 4) Health and Medical. If you are in another industry (for example, manufacturing) then the Colorado break laws would not cover you. This may be why you are encountering resistance from upper management (or, they may be complete idiots.) Theoretically, it is illegal for an employer to retaliate against an employee who files a complaint about unlawful conduct by the employer.

If you feel your employer is violating the law, file a complaint about break laws or retaliation with the Colorado Department of Labor and Employment. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia

Read more about this at: http://www.colorado.gov/cs/Satellite/CDLE-LaborLaws/CDLE/1248095305420 
 
Posted by: Sarah Stutton 

My am a nurse that works a twelve hour shift. Recently it was decided that the unit would be staffed with only one nurse. However, no attempt has been made to make sure we get breaks. I understand that this law does not apply to nurses, but they do not make sure we even get an opportunity to eat at all. Is this a violation?
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Sarah! You are correct. The Colorado break law does not apply to nurses. Unfortunately, this means that the employer is not obligated to make any arrangements at all for employee meals. The only exception would be if there were a union contract in place. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Ryuji 

My question is similar to Sam’s but focused on a slightly different part. My shift is 7hrs. My employer told me that I can have EITHER a 10min break OR a 30min meal break but not both. After reading the law which says (1) I am ENTITLED (which is translated to required in Sam’s answer) to a 30 meal break, (2) for every 4hrs I MUST (must = required right?) be allowed to take a 10min break, I don’t understand where the OR fits in to it. It reads like two separate laws. Since neither is in conflict of the other it doesn’t seem that one can be overridden by the other and I did not see an OR between the two laws, only a period. Am I correct to interpret that I get at least one 10min break AND a 30min meal break for a 7hr shift? If it is OR and not AND please explain it to me. I’m from California and such ambiguities do not exist in the laws of this subject.
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Ryuji! You are correct that Colorado law requires an employee be given a 30-minute unpaid meal break and one or two 10-minute paid rest breaks on a 7-hour shift. Example: You start at 7 am. You are entitled to a 10-minute paid break at about 9:30 am, and a 30-minute unpaid lunch from 12:00 to 12:30. Because you will be getting off at 2 pm or 2:30 pm, you are not entitled to an additional break. However, if you worked until 3:00 pm, you would be entitled to an additional paid 10-minute break.

The Colorado law is not ambigious, there are simply some employers who do not understand it. (There are a few exceptions for certain industries.) If you are not receiving your breaks, you should file a complaint with the Colorado Department of Labor and Employment. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Marla 

May I combine my 30 min lunch with my 2 breaks to have a 50 min lunch? I will place on my timecard that I only took a 30 min lunch.
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Marla! No, this would not satisfy the Colorado meal and break laws. Your employer is not required to agree to this, and most would not.

The Colorado law specifically states that the employee must take a 10-minute paid break in the middle of each work segment that is“the major portion”of 4 hours long. Taking a longer lunch break does not relieve the employer from giving the rest break.

Your suggestion would also cheat the employer, since you would be taking a 50 minute lunch break, but expecting to be paid for 20 minutes of it. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Richard 

Being new to Colorado. I just want to seek to understand. The 1/2 hour meal break policy is a little confusing. And Im coming from California!
A paid break is an interrupted break? And, when does that apply? I am a Restaurant owner and would like some clarification, You have always been a great source of information.
Thank You!
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Richard! Yes, under Colorado law, an employee must be given a 30 minute uninterrupted meal break when they are free of all work duties and permitted to engage in activities of their choice. That break can be unpaid. In Colorado, as in California, if the employee is required to work at any point during the break, he or she must be paid for the entire meal break.

Example: You have two cooks on duty, Jose and Carla. If Jose goes on his break and takes the entire 30 minutes uninterrupted, he need not be paid. However, suppose Jose is called back to help Carla with one order. Even if Jose works only 3 minutes, his break has been interrupted. He did not take a 30-minute break, and he must be paid for the entire time. You must still allow Jose to finish eating his meal under Colorado law, but he must be paid for the entire break.

In Colorado, the employee can be required to remain on the premises for an unpaid meal break.

It is not up to the employee to determine if a break will be paid or unpaid. As the employer, you determine if the employee will be completely relieved of all duties or not. Of course, you could choose to pay all employees for their breaks, whether they were interrupted or not, but that would be expensive and most employers do not do so.

In addition, Colorado requires that you give employees a 10 minute rest break on each 4 hour work segment. These short rest breaks must always be paid under both Colorado and federal law. Break laws can be complex, so feel free to post any additional questions you might have. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Colorado Teacher 

If teachers in Colorado are exempt from the laws for breaks and lunches. What are the rules for breaks and lunches for teachers in Colorado? I work from 9-4:12 with no lunch or bathroom break. Is that legal? Thanks
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Colorado! Unfortunately, there is no Colorado or federal law that requires meal or rest breaks for teachers. We will say that these working conditions for teachers are common in other states as well as Colorado, although we have no idea how the employer gets away with it.
OSHA regulations do require that employees be permitted to use the toilet when nature calls. Since you are not being given even a bathroom break, contact OSHA at http://www.osha.gov to see if they will do a safety inspection of your workplace. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Katy 

By Colorado Law, are employers able to require employees to punch out and back in for a full 30 minute lunch break on their timecard?
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Katy! Yes, an employer in Colorado can require that the employee punch out for a 30 minute meal break. The meal break can be unpaid if the employee is relieved of all duties, even if the employee must remain on the premises. Any employee who does not comply with this company policy can be disciplined or terminated.

The various state meal break laws are the minimum standard the employer must meet, they are not the maximum standard the employer can enforce. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: FAITH 

In the event that you demand your employee’s follow the law and take the 30 minute lunch, you postt he law, you write warning when they DON’T clock out for lunch on numerous occasions, what then.
Is the employer entitled to deduct 30 minutes from their workday because they were not authorized to have a‘working lunch’.
At times these employees actually work straight through, most take excessive‘ten min’breaks or simply eat without clocking out.
If I deduct 30 minutes pay for every shift over 5 hours without permission for a working lunch in addition to a dinal warning, is that legal? acceptable?
Thank you
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Faith! No, this is completely illegal. The old phrase“two wrongs don’t make a right”comes to mind. Both the Colorado and federal minimum wage laws require that you pay employees for all time worked. Last year, Wal-Mart paid more than $6 million in back wages to employees from two stores, for exactly this reason—they had been deducting meal breaks that the employees did not actually take.
When an employee is not completely relieved of all work duties during the meal break, federal law requires that the employee be paid for the break. Unfortunately, when the employee neglects to take a meal break, as an employer you have broken the law.

If an employee does not take a meal break, you have the right to discipline or terminate him or her. The best practice would be to write up employees once per week if they neglected to take all the meal breaks for that week. After one verbal warning and three written warnings, you fire the employee. This gives employees three weeks to adjust to this new policy. In our experience, if you terminate just one or two employees for not taking a meal break, the others will realize you mean business and comply with the law (and your company policy) regarding meal breaks.

You also have the right to enforce reasonable limits on 10-minute breaks. Although employees must be paid for short breaks, they need not be paid for an unauthorized extension of a 10-minute break. One of the best ways to monitor this is to require employees to clock out for breaks. But again, the employee must be paid for the 10-minute break. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Jeff 

I work at a manufacturing company as a sculptor. I have recently been told that it is state law that I have to start taking a 30 minute lunch every day. I have been there for a year and this is the first time it has came up. I previously worked for a bronze foundry and never had the lunch break required.

In reading your previous posts, it doesn’t sound to me like I am in any of the industries that are covered by the Colorado law. Am I correct in assuming this?
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Jeff! We agree with your analysis, that you are in an industry not covered by the Colorado meal break law. However, the employer can require that you take an unpaid 30-minute meal break each day, and discipline or terminate any employee who does not comply. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~Amelia
 
Posted by: Ben 

I work as a building insp. for local county government. I am not union. I am not overtime exempt. My job is such that I spend my day unsupervised completing a route that I set for myself. I pack my lunch and eat it between stops. Our bosses are telling us that we have to take a 30 min unpaid lunch break. If they are wrong what can I show them to settle this?
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Ben! Unfortunately, the employer is correct. Any employer can require workers to take a 30-minute meal break each day. If you are relieved of all duties during this meal period, it can be unpaid. Colorado law requires that every employee who works a shift of 5 hours or more be given an uninterrupted meal break. The law permits an on-duty or interrupted meal period only when the nature of the work makes it impossible or impractical for the employee to take an uninterruped break. Even if the employee wants to skip the meal period, or take an on-duty meal period, that is not his or her choice.

From your post, it appears that if you wanted to, you could arrange your day so that you stopped at a park or restaurant for 30 minutes to consume your lunch. Therefore, you are not entitled to an on-duty meal period. Your meal period can be unpaid. If we have misunderstood the situation, feel free to post additional details. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia

Read more about this at: http://www.colorado.gov/cs/Satellite/CDLE-LaborLaws/CDLE/1248095305420 
 
Posted by: Derek 

I work as a carpenter for a small family owned company. Roughly two and a half years ago we were informed that it has never been the owners policy for employees to have breaks. He expects 8 hours of productivity each day. We knew this was not accurate and after reviewing the specific laws of Colorado I see that what he has been doing is illegal. My question is, if we choose to contact the Div of Labor are we able to do this anonymously and is it possible for us to receive compensation for the 20 mins of deserved breaks a day we’ve missed for years now? Thank you very much for all of your continued help
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Derek! Your best bet is to contact the Colorado Division of Labor and Employment at http://www.colorado.gov/cs/Satellite/CDLE-LaborLaws/CDLE/1248095305236 , and file a complaint. They will investigate and may force the employer to begin giving you two 10-minute breaks per day. Unfortunately, it is not clear if you are even covered under the Colorado break law, since it applies to employees only in the retail, food&amp;beverage, commercial support services and health&amp;medical industries.

Even if you are covered under the Colorado break law, the employer probably does not owe you any back wages. You were paid for all the time you worked—you were just not given the paid rest breaks you should have had. Some states have laws that require the employer to pay a worker extra when the worker is not given a break. Colorado does not have such a law. The employer could be fined or assessed penalties, but they will not necessarily be paid to you and your coworkers.

It is very difficult for the state to keep a complaint anonymous, since they have to ask for work records for a specific employee. In most cases, you are required to give your name when making a complaint. However, you can have a conversation with someone at the agency without filing a complaint. It is illegal for an employer to retaliate against an employee who files a complaint in good faith, even if the complaint is later shown to be unfounded. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Braden 

I work for [employer name deleted] an office supply store, and they are very adamate about making its emplyees take a 30 minute lunch and two 15 minute breaks, I would personally rather never be forced to take any break, and most of the time I don’t even want to take a break. I feel much more productive if I don’t take breaks. Is it legal to absolutely require breaks, and is it legal for me to ask to not be required to take breaks unless I want to take them?
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Braden! Any employer can require that an employee take breaks, and can discipline or terminate any employee who refuses to follow this company policy. In addition, Colorado law requires that the employer give you a meal break and two 10 minute paid rest breaks. If you do not take these breaks, the employer has broken the law.

Generally speaking, in the U.S., the employer sets the policies in the workplace and the employee can follow them or find another job. (Ironically, one of the most common complaints we hear from workers not covered by a break law is that they spend all day on their feet without a break. For example, read the comment above yours from Derek who works construction all day with no breaks.)

If you are more productive without breaks, you are in the minority. Studies show that generally employees who take such breaks accomplish more work in less time. But either way, you are required by law to take the breaks and can be terminated if you do not. You can certainly ask your employer anything. You could ask for a limousine to take you to work and a million dollars in cash. However, the employer also has the right to refuse your requests. When your employer refuses your request to skip breaks, you are required to take them. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Eric 

I work a 8 hour shift with paid lunch as a security officer. Can I take power naps during my breaks without losing my job. Thanks
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Eric! No, there is no Colorado or federal law that protects your right to sleep on the job. Despite a number of studies that have shown power naps to be effective, they are generally not acceptable in the workplace, especially for security guards.

The problem with taking a nap as a security guard is that if a supervisor or customer arrives and finds you sleeping, they have no way of knowing if you have been sleeping for 5 minutes or 5 hours. So it is impossible for them to distinguish between“a power nap”and“sleeping on the job.”A security guard’s main duty is to be awake and alert, to watch for trouble. You cannot do that if you are asleep.

The other problem is customer relations. You don’t say what environment you are working in, but many security guards are contracted to watch office buildings, hotels, factories, etc. If a customer saw you sleeping, they would assume that all the security guards for your company sleep throughout their shifts. The security firm might lose their contract for this and other locations, simply because a customer misinterpreted your actions.

Most employee handbooks specifically forbid sleeping on the job, and that includes power naps. An employee who is caught sleeping even once can be disciplined or terminated. Most employers expect a worker to arrive at work fully rested and prepared to stay awake for the entire shift. This is true regardless of the time of day or night the employee works.

A Colorado employer must allow two ten-minute rest breaks during an 8-hour shift, but can set certain limits on activities during those breaks. Most employers would not allow you to practice with a stripper pole during your breaks, and most would not allow you to sleep. Because you are being given a paid meal break, this is considered an on-duty meal break, meaning you are working while on your meal break. That means, again, that the employer can require that you not sleep on your meal break.

So there is no law that the employer must allow you to“power nap”or snooze at work. You can certainly ask permission to do so. If you volunteered to clock out for your 10-minute breaks, and then clock back in afterwards, that would give the employer assurance that you were only sleeping for the 10 minutes of your break. However, if you overslept and clocked back in after 15 minutes or 30 minutes, the employer would know you were sleeping on the job and could terminate you. There is no law that an employer must grant this request to clock out for power naps during your shift, but you could certainly approach them about it. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: kerry burrier 

I work as a city bus driver for the city of Greeley, Colorado. Us drivers were informed in Feburary that we would no longer be paid for our rest breaks and lunches even though we can not take them with the routes we have to drive. We as drivers work 6 to 9 hour shifts without any rest periods. GET, the name of the city of Greeley’s Public Transportation System have stated that they have found exemptions to Colorado’s Regulation on break and lunch laws. Can you clarify if there is such an exemption? Myself and the other drivers were hired, being told we would get the pay they recently took away.I personnaly feel they are discriminating against us drivers as other City workers get their breaks and lunch periods
 
Posted by: kerry burrier 

Another note, I have been told by other fellow drivers that I could be termated as being a trouble maker for bring up the fact of all of us loosing our break abd lunch pay
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi kerry! Unfortunately, your employer is right. The Colorado break law only covers workers in 4 industries: retail, food&amp;beverage, retail support, and health&amp;medical. Those are the employees covered under the Colorado Minimum Wage Order Number 27. The break law applies only to employees covered by Minimum Wage Order 27. There is no state or federal law that requires a Colorado employer to give breaks to workers in other occupations. You can certainly contact the Colorado Department of Labor&amp;Employment, but our guess is that they will confirm that you are not entitled to meal or rest breaks under state law.

It is not discrimination for an employer to have different policies for employees in different jobs. It is also legal for an employer to have one break policy when workers are hired, and change that break policy. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi kerry! Usually an employer cannot fire a worker for lodging a complaint in good faith, such as a complaint about wages or the employer not following state or federal law. However, the employee can still be fired for being rude, argumentitive or insubordinate. You could raise this issue once, respectfully, with the employer. But if you argue with them or are rude, they can terminate you for that behavior. An employer cannot retaliate against an employee for filing a complaint with the Colorado Department of Labor&amp;Employment, as long as the complaint is in good faith. Even if it turns out the employer has done nothing wrong, the employee cannot be punished. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
Posted by: Dan 

Are employers required to provide a break room for employees
 
Posted by: Amelia 

Hi Dan! No, a Colorado employer is not required to provide a break area for employees. Some states like California do require break rooms, but Colorado does not. However, the Colorado employee must be allowed to pursue“other activities”(non-work activities) during his or her meal break, like reading a book or listening to music. If the employee is required to take the break at the work station and other activities are forbidden, then the employee is entitled to payment for the meal break. HTH, and thanks for reading the blogs!~ Amelia
 
 Name: Mail: Website : Message 
 Notify me of followup comments via e-mail 
 
 
RELATED LINKS
 
 Log In About Us Contact Us Disclaimer Privacy Policy 

 Subscribe to RSS 
 Subscribe to this blog via email Delivered by FeedBurner 
Popular Posts

 State Lunch and Break Law Governing Florida California Lunch and Break Law Regulations North Carolina Labor Law Board Arizona Labor Law Board Illinois State Lunch and Break Law Requirements Ohio Lunch and Break Law Requirements Server Minimum Wage Holiday Pay Law Requirements in the State of California (CA) Texas Minimum Wage Increase State Lunch and Break Law Governing Texas State of Michigan Lunch and Break Law Georgia Lunch and Break Law Regulations Arizona Lunch and Break Law Florida (FL) Maternity Leave Law Labor Laws Governing Ohio 
 
POPULAR TAGS
 
 wage federal EEOC Minimum Wage California poster US State increase new Department of Labor 2009 fmla HR news Human Resources employee HR law employer Discrimination 
 
CATEGORIES

 Compliance Issues (1770)
 Alabama (34)
 Child Labor Laws (3) Department of Labor (5) Employer Requirements (23)
 Labor Law posters (13) Labor Law Regulations (4) Updated Regulations (7) 
 Unemployment Laws (4) 
 Alaska (24)
 Department of Labor (6) Employer Requirements (17)
 Labor Law Posters (7) Labor Law Regulations (4) Updated Regulations (7) 
 Unemployment Laws (1) 
 Arizona (33)
 Department of Labor (7) Employer Requirements (25)
 Labor Law Posters (13) Labor Law Regulations (3) Updated Regulations (10) 
 Unemployment Laws (2) 
 Arkansas (34)
 Department of Labor (10) Employer Requirements (20)
 Labor Law Posters (10) Labor Law Regulations (5) Updated Regulations (5) 
 Unemployment Laws (3) 
 California (91)
 Child Labor Laws (3) Department of Labor (20) Employer Requirements (65)
 Labor Law Posters (36) Labor Law Regulations (10) Updated Regulations (15) 
 Unemployment Laws (4) 
 Colorado (40)
 Department of Labor (8) Employer Requirements (30)
 Labor Law Posters (9) Labor Law Regulations (7) Updated Regulations (13) 
 Unemployment Laws (3) 
 Connecticut (56)
 Child Labor Laws (3) Department of Labor (17) Employer Requirements (21)
 Labor Law Posters (10) Labor Law Regulations (4) Updated Regulations (7) 
 Unemployment Laws (14) 
 Delaware (38)
 Child Labor Laws (1) Department of Labor (12) Employer Requirements (20)
 Labor Law Posters (6) Labor Law Regulations (5) Updated Regulations (8) 
 Unemployment Laws (4) 
 District of Columbia (15)
 Child Labor Laws (1) Department of Labor (3) Employer Requirements (11)
 Labor Law Posters (9) Labor Law Regulations (1) Updated Regulations (1) 
 Unemployment Laws (1) 
 Florida (54)
 Child Labor Laws (2) Department of Labor (10) Employer Requirements (40)
 Labor Law Posters (21) Labor Law Regulations (9) Updated Regulations (10) 
 Unemployment Laws (4) 
 Georgia (44)
 Department of Labor (11) Employer Requirements (31)
 Labor Law Posters (15) Labor Law Regulations (7) Updated Regulations (7) 
 Unemployment Laws (4) 
 Hawaii (31)
 Department of Labor (8) Employer Requirements (23)
 Labor Law Posters (14) Labor Law Regulations (2) Updated Regulations (7) 
 Unemployment Laws (2) 
 Idaho (29)
 Department of Labor (11) Employer Requirements (18)
 Labor Law Posters (12) Updated Regulations (6) 
 Unemployment Laws (2) 
 Illinois (60)
 Child Labor Laws (3) Department of Labor (25) Employer Requirements (34)
 Labor Law Posters (21) Labor Law Regulations (3) Updated Regulations (9) 
 Unemployment Laws (2) 
 Indiana (29)
 Child Labor Laws (1) Department of Labor (8) Employer Requirements (17)
 Labor Law Posters (10) Labor Law Regulations (1) Updated Regulations (6) 
 Unemployment Laws (4) 
 Iowa (31)
 Department of Labor (11) Employer Requirements (17)
 Labor Law Posters (10) Labor Law Regulations (1) Updated Regulations (5) 
 Unemployment Laws (4) 
 Kansas (37)
 Department of Labor (9) Employer Requirements (21)
 Labor Law Posters (10) Labor Law Regulations (6) Updated Regulations (6) 
 Unemployment Laws (7) 
 Kentucky (35)
 Child Labor Laws (3) Department of Labor (11) Employer Requirements (17)
 Labor Law Posters (9) Labor Law Regulations (4) Updated Regulations (4) 
 Unemployment Laws (5) 
 Louisiana (25)
 Department of Labor (6) Employer Requirements (17)
 Labor Law Posters (10) Labor Law Regulations (2) Updated Regulations (5) 
 Unemployment Laws (1) 
 Maine (28)
 Department of Labor (11) Employer Requirements (17)
 Labor Law Posters (8) Labor Law Regulations (3) Updated Regulations (4) 
 Unemployment Laws (1) 
 Maryland (30)
 Department of Labor (12) Employer Requirements (17)
 Labor Law Posters (12) Labor Law Regulations (2) Updated Regulations (3) 
 Unemployment Laws (1) 
 Massachusetts (31)
 Department of Labor (12) Employer Requirements (18)
 Labor Law Posters (11) Labor Law Regulations (3) Updated Regulations (4) 
 Unemployment Laws (2) 
 Michigan (54)
 Child Labor Laws (2) Department of Labor (25) Employer Requirements (18)
 Labor Law Posters (10) Labor Law Regulations (1) Updated Regulations (8) 
 Unemployment Laws (9) 
 Minnesota (32)
 Department of Labor (12) Employer Requirements (18)
 Labor Law Posters (12) Labor Law Regulations (2) Updated Regulations (4) 
 Unemployment Laws (2) 
 Mississippi (31)
 Department of Labor (10) Employer Requirements (17)
 Labor Law Posters (9) Labor Law Regulations (2) Updated Regulations (5) 
 Unemployment Laws (4) 
 Missouri (40)
 Department of Labor (17) Employer Requirements (16)
 Labor Law Posters (12) Updated Regulations (5) 
 Updated Regulations (5) 
 Montana (26)
 Child Labor Laws (1) Department of Labor (9) Employer Requirements (15)
 Labor Law Posters (9) Labor Law Regulations (2) Updated Regulations (4) 
 Unemployment Laws (1) 
 Nebraska (28)
 Child Labor Laws (2) Department of Labor (10) Employer Requirements (14)
 Labor Law Posters (8) Labor Law Regulations (2) Updated Regulations (4) 
 Unemployment Laws (2) 
 Nevada (30)
 Department of Labor (9) Employer Requirements (20)
 Labor Law Posters (10) Labor Law Regulations (2) Updated Regulations (8) 
 Unemployment Laws (1) 
 New Hampshire (23)
 Department of Labor (7) Employer Requirements (16)
 Labor Law Posters (9) Labor Law Regulations (2) Updated Regulations (5) 
 Unemployment Laws (1) 
 New Jersey (34)
 Child Labor Laws (2) Department of Labor (15) Employer Requirements (16)
 Labor Law Posters (13) Labor Law Regulations (1) Updated Regulations (2) 
 Unemployment Laws (1) 
 New Mexico (26)
 Department of Labor (9) Employer Requirements (17)
 Labor Law Posters (10) Labor Law Regulations (2) Updated Regulations (5) 
 
 New York (45)
 Child Labor Laws (2) Department of Labor (10) Employer Requirements (27)
 Labor Law Posters (19) Labor Law Regulations (3) Updated Regulations (5) 
 Unemployment Laws (6) 
 North Carolina (29)
 Child Labor Laws (2) Department of Labor (10) Employer Requirements (18)
 Labor Law Posters (11) Labor Law Regulations (3) Updated Regulations (4) 
 
 North Dakota (21)
 Department of Labor (7) Employer Requirements (13)
 Labor Law Posters (6) Labor Law Regulations (4) Updated Regulations (3) 
 Unemployment Laws (1) 
 Ohio (43)
 Child Labor Laws (1) Department of Labor (8) Employer Requirements (29)
 Labor Law Posters (16) Labor Law Regulations (3) Updated Regulations (8) 
 Unemployment Laws (5) 
 Oklahoma (25)
 Department of Labor (9) Employer Requirements (15)
 Labor Law Posters (7) Labor Law Regulations (2) Updated Regulations (6) 
 Unemployment Laws (1) 
 Oregon (41)
 Child Labor Laws (7) Department of Labor (9) Employer Requirements (24)
 Labor Law Posters (14) Labor Law Regulations (3) Updated Regulations (8) 
 Unemployment Laws (1) 
 Pennsylvania (43)
 Child Labor Laws (1) Department of Labor (14) Employer Requirements (24)
 Labor Law Posters (15) Labor Law Regulations (2) Updated Regulations (5) 
 Unemployment Laws (4) 
 Puerto Rico (7)
 Employer Requirements (7)
 Labor Law Posters (7) 
 
 Rhode Island (30)
 Department of Labor (9) Employer Requirements (18)
 Labor Law Posters (9) Labor Law Regulations (3) Updated Regulations (5) 
 Unemployment Laws (3) 
 South Carolina (19)
 Child Labor Laws (1) Department of Labor (5) Employer Requirements (12)
 Labor Law Posters (7) Labor Law Regulations (2) Updated Regulations (3) 
 Unemployment Laws (1) 
 South Dakota (24)
 Department of Labor (7) Employer Requirements (15)
 Labor Law Posters (9) Labor Law Regulations (3) Updated Regulations (3) 
 Unemployment Laws (1) 
 Tennessee (27)
 Child Labor Laws (1) Department of Labor (7) Employer Requirements (16)
 Labor Law Posters (11) Labor Law Regulations (4) Updated Regulations (1) 
 Unemployment Laws (2) 
 Texas (32)
 Child Labor Laws (3) Department of Labor (8) Employer Requirements (16)
 Labor Law Posters (10) Labor Law Regulations (2) Updated Regulations (3) 
 Unemployment Laws (5) 
 Utah (27)
 Department of Labor (5) Employer Requirements (19)
 Labor Law Posters (9) Labor Law Regulations (6) Updated Regulations (4) 
 Unemployment Laws (3) 
 Vermont (25)
 Child Labor Laws (1) Department of Labor (9) Employer Requirements (15)
 Labor Law Posters (8) Updated Regulations (7) 
 
 Virgin Islands (6)
 Employer Requirements (6)
 Labor Law Posters (6) 
 
 Virginia (29)
 Department of Labor (9) Employer Requirements (19)
 Labor Law Posters (12) Labor Law Regulations (2) Updated Regulations (5) 
 Unemployment Laws (1) 
 Washington (32)
 Department of Labor (10) Employer Requirements (19)
 Labor Law Posters (14) Labor Law Regulations (1) Updated Regulations (4) 
 Unemployment Laws (1) 
 West Virginia (24)
 Department of Labor (8) Employer Requirements (16)
 Labor Law Posters (8) Labor Law Regulations (2) Updated Regulations (4) 
 
 Wisconsin (33)
 Child Labor Laws (1) Department of Labor (10) Employer Requirements (18)
 Labor Law Posters (8) Labor Law Regulations (5) Updated Regulations (4) 
 Unemployment Laws (4) 
 Wyoming (30)
 Department of Labor (13) Employer Requirements (16)
 Labor Law Posters (7) Labor Law Regulations (4) Updated Regulations (5) 
 Unemployment Laws (1) 
 
 Employee Benefits (366)
 Alabama (7)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Paid Leave (3)
 Vacation (2) 
 Unemployment Insurance (1) 
 Alaska (10)
 Insurance Benefits (2)
 Medical (2) 
 Paid Leave (3)
 Family (2) Medical (1) Sick (1) Vacation (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (1) 
 Arizona (7)
 Insurance Benefits (4)
 Medical (3) 
 Paid Leave (2)
 Family (1) Medical (1) Sick (1) Vacation (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (1) 
 Arkansas (5)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Paid Leave (2)
 Family (1) Vacation (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (1) 
 California (19)
 Insurance Benefits (6)
 Medical (5) 
 Paid Leave (10)
 Family (3) Medical (1) Sick (3) Vacation (2) 
 Retirement (1)
 401K (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (2) 
 Colorado (7)
 Insurance Benefits (2)
 Medical (2) 
 Paid Leave (5)
 Family (3) Sick (1) Vacation (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (1) 
 Connecticut (9)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Paid Leave (4)
 Vacation (1) 
 Retirement (1)
 401K (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Delaware (5)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (2) 
 District of Columbia (3)
 Paid Leave (3)
 Family (2) Sick (1) 
 
 Flordia (10)
 Insurance Benefits (2)
 Medical (2) 
 Paid Leave (3)
 Family (2) Vacation (1) 
 Retirement (2)
 401K (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Georgia (5)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Paid Leave (3)
 Family (1) Medical (1) Vacation (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Hawaii (6)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Idaho (5)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Paid Leave (1)
 Family (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Illinois (11)
 Insurance Benefits (3)
 Medical (2) 
 Paid Leave (4)
 Family (1) Medical (1) Vacation (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Indiana (5)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Paid Leave (1) Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Iowa (6)
 Insurance Benefits (2)
 Dental (1) Medical (2) 
 Paid Leave (1)
 Family (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Kansas (5)
 Insurance Benefits (2)
 Medical (2) 
 Paid Leave (1)
 Vacation (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (2) 
 Kentucky (6)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Paid Leave (3)
 Family (1) Vacation (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (2) 
 Louisiana (5)
 Insurance Benefits (2)
 Medical (2) 
 Unemployment Insurance (2) 
 Maine (9)
 Insurance Benefits (3)
 Medical (3) 
 Paid Leave (2)
 Family (1) Sick (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Maryland (5)
 Insurance Benefits (1) Paid Leave (2)
 Family (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (2) 
 Massachusetts (5)
 Insurance Benefits (3)
 Medical (2) 
 Unemployment Insurance (2) 
 Michigan (6)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Paid Leave (1)
 Family (1) 
 Retirement (1)
 401K (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (2) 
 Minnesota (7)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Paid Leave (2)
 Family (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (4) 
 Mississippi (7)
 Insurance Benefits (2)
 Medical (2) 
 Paid Leave (1)
 Family (1) 
 Retirement (1)
 401K (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Missouri (6)
 Insurance Benefits (2)
 Medical (2) 
 Unemployment Insurance (4) 
 Montana (3)
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Nebraska (4)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Paid Leave (1)
 Family (1) Medical (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (2) 
 Nevada (5)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 New Hampshire (9)
 Insurance Benefits (3)
 Medical (3) 
 Paid Leave (1) Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 New Jersey (11)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Paid Leave (4)
 Family (3) 
 Retirement (1) Unemployment Insurance (5) 
 New Mexico (7)
 Insurance Benefits (3)
 Medical (3) 
 Paid Leave (1)
 Family (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (2) 
 New York (8)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Paid Leave (2)
 Family (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (5) 
 North Carolina (9)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Paid Leave (5)
 Medical (5) 
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 North Dakota (6)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Paid Leave (1)
 Family (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (4) 
 Ohio (8)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Paid Leave (3)
 Sick (3) 
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Oklahoma (7)
 Insurance Benefits (2)
 Medical (2) 
 Paid Leave (1)
 Family (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (4) 
 Oregon (9)
 Insurance Benefits (2)
 Medical (2) 
 Paid Leave (4)
 Family (1) Sick (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Pennsylvania (7)
 Insurance Benefits (3)
 Medical (3) 
 Unemployment Insurance (4) 
 Puerto Rico (2)
 Unemployment Insurance (2) 
 Rhode Island (13)
 Insurance Benefits (5)
 Medical (2) 
 Paid Leave (1)
 Family (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (6) 
 South Carolina (7)
 Insurance Benefits (2)
 Medical (2) 
 Paid Leave (2)
 Family (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 South Dakota (5)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (4) 
 Tennessee (4)
 Insurance Benefits (1) Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Texas (8)
 Insurance Benefits (2)
 Medical (2) 
 Paid Leave (1)
 Vacation (1) 
 Retirement (1) Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Utah (4)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Vermont (7)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Paid Leave (2)
 Family (2) 
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Virgin Islands (1)
 Unemployment Insurance (1) 
 Virginia (8)
 Insurance Benefits (2)
 Medical (2) 
 Unemployment Insurance (6) 
 Washington (12)
 Insurance Benefits (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Paid Leave (6)
 Family (1) Vacation (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (4) 
 West Virginia (5)
 Insurance Benefits (2)
 Medical (2) 
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Wisconsin (7)
 Insurance Benefits (3)
 Medical (3) 
 Paid Leave (1)
 Medical (1) 
 Unemployment Insurance (3) 
 Wyoming (4)
 Insurance Benefits (2)
 Medical (2) 
 Unemployment Insurance (2) 
 
 Employment Laws (2150)
 Alabama (34)
 Hostile Environment (5)
 Discrimination (5) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (11) Wage and Hour (14)
 Minimum Wage (10) Overtime (2) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (3) 
 Alaska (35)
 Hostile Environment (6)
 Discrimination (5) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (13) Wage and Hour (12)
 Minimum Wage (9) Overtime (2) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (4) 
 Arizona (51)
 Hostile Environment (7)
 Discrimination (5) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (13) Wage and Hour (26)
 Minimum Wage (24) Overtime (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (6) 
 Arkansas (46)
 Hostile Environment (5)
 Discrimination (5) 
 Labor and Employment (15) Wage and Hour (21)
 Minimum Wage (17) Overtime (3) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (4) 
 California (94)
 Hostile Environment (15)
 Discrimination (10) Sexual Harassment (6) 
 Labor and Employment (30) Wage and Hour (39)
 Minimum Wage (23) Overtime (6) Salary (4) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (13) 
 Colorado (39)
 Hostile Environment (6)
 Discrimination (5) Sexual Harassment (2) 
 Labor and Employment (10) Wage and Hour (19)
 Minimum Wage (16) Overtime (3) Salary (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (3) 
 Connecticut (40)
 Hostile Environment (3)
 Discrimination (2) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (14) Wage and Hour (21)
 Minimum Wage (17) Overtime (4) Salary (2) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (2) 
 Delaware (38)
 Hostile Environment (3)
 Discrimination (1) Sexual Harassment (2) 
 Labor and Employment (12) Wage and Hour (13)
 Minimum Wage (9) Overtime (3) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (10) 
 District of Columbia (22)
 Hostile Environment (6)
 Discrimination (5) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (3) Wage and Hour (12)
 Minimum Wage (10) Overtime (3) Salary (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (1) 
 Flordia (53)
 Hostile Environment (5)
 Discrimination (5) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (13) Wage and Hour (29)
 Minimum Wage (25) Overtime (4) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (6) 
 Georgia (39)
 Hostile Environment (3)
 Discrimination (2) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (15) Wage and Hour (16)
 Minimum Wage (9) Overtime (4) Salary (2) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (6) 
 Hawaii (33)
 Hostile Environment (5)
 Discrimination (3) Sexual Harassment (2) 
 Labor and Employment (12) Wage and Hour (11)
 Minimum Wage (8) Overtime (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (4) 
 Idaho (38)
 Hostile Environment (3)
 Discrimination (2) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (14) Wage and Hour (18)
 Minimum Wage (15) Overtime (2) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (3) 
 Illinois (76)
 Hostile Enviroment (8)
 Discrimination (6) Sexual Harassment (4) 
 Labor and Employment (36) Wage and Hour (29)
 Minimum Wage (18) Overtime (2) Salary (3) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (4) 
 Indiana (47)
 Hostile Enviroment (5)
 Discrimination (3) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (11) Wage and Hour (26)
 Minimum Wage (24) Overtime (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (5) 
 Iowa (41)
 Hostile Environment (4)
 Discrimination (3) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (16) Wage and Hour (17)
 Minimum Wage (15) Overtime (2) Salary (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (4) 
 Kansas (38)
 Hostile Environment (5)
 Discrimination (4) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (15) Wage and Hour (15)
 Minimum Wage (12) Overtime (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (3) 
 Kentucky (52)
 Hostile Environment (5)
 Discrimination (5) 
 Labor and Employment (14) Wage and Hour (28)
 Minimum Wage (26) Overtime (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (5) 
 Louisiana (45)
 Hostile Environment (3)
 Discrimination (3) 
 Labor and Employment (22) Wage and Hour (18)
 Minimum Wage (12) Overtime (4) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (3) 
 Maine (29)
 Hostile Environment (2)
 Discrimination (2) 
 Labor and Employment (7) Wage and Hour (17)
 Minimum Wage (12) Overtime (4) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (3) 
 Maryland (38)
 Hostile Environment (2)
 Discrimination (1) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (11) Wage and Hour (23)
 Minimum Wage (16) Overtime (2) Salary (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (2) 
 Massachusetts (36)
 Hostile Environment (3)
 Discrimination (3) 
 Labor and Employment (14) Wage and Hour (15)
 Minimum Wage (11) Overtime (3) Salary (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (4) 
 Michigan (38)
 Hostile Environment (4)
 Discrimination (3) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (16) Wage and Hour (17)
 Minimum Wage (14) Overtime (2) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (1) 
 Minnesota (40)
 Hostile Environment (3)
 Discrimination (2) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (15) Wage and Hour (15)
 Minimum Wage (13) Overtime (3) Salary (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (7) 
 Mississippi (34)
 Hostile Environment (5)
 Discrimination (3) Sexual Harassment (2) 
 Labor and Employment (13) Wage and Hour (15)
 Minimum Wage (14) Overtime (2) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (3) 
 Missouri (71)
 Hostile Environment (6)
 Discrimination (4) Sexual Harassment (2) 
 Labor and Employment (14) Wage and Hour (41)
 Minimum Wage (38) Overtime (5) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (10) 
 Montana (38)
 Hostile Environment (3)
 Discrimination (2) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (10) Wage and Hour (21)
 Minimum Wage (19) Overtime (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (3) 
 Nebraska (27)
 Hostile Environment (4)
 Discrimination (3) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (10) Wage and Hour (11)
 Minimum Wage (8) Overtime (3) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (2) 
 Nevada (47)
 Hostile Environment (3)
 Discrimination (2) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (17) Wage and Hour (23)
 Minimum Wage (21) Overtime (3) Salary (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (3) 
 New Hampshire (45)
 Hostile Environment (5)
 Discrimination (4) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (15) Wage and Hour (22)
 Minimum Wage (18) Overtime (4) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (4) 
 New Jersey (49)
 Hostile Environment (4)
 Discrimination (4) 
 Labor and Employment (27) Wage and Hour (15)
 Minimum Wage (10) Overtime (3) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (3) 
 New Mexico (49)
 Hostile Environment (3)
 Discrimination (3) 
 Labor and Employment (15) Wage and Hour (27)
 Minimum Wage (25) Overtime (3) Salary (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (4) 
 New York (66)
 Hostile Environment (6)
 Discrimination (5) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (29) Wage and Hour (26)
 Minimum Wage (20) Overtime (7) Salary (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (7) 
 North Carolina (35)
 Hostile Environment (4)
 Discrimination (4) 
 Labor and Employment (6) Wage and Hour (18)
 Minimum Wage (13) Overtime (5) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (6) 
 North Dakota (24)
 Hostile Environment (2)
 Discrimination (1) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (8) Wage and Hour (11)
 Minimum Wage (9) Overtime (2) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (4) 
 Ohio (73)
 Hostile Environment (5)
 Discrimination (4) Sexual Harassment (2) 
 Labor and Employment (33) Wage and Hour (29)
 Minimum Wage (26) Overtime (3) Salary (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (6) 
 Oklahoma (33)
 Hostile Environment (4)
 Discrimination (2) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (12) Wage and Hour (14)
 Minimum Wage (10) Overtime (3) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (3) 
 Oregon (55)
 Hostile Environment (6)
 Sexual Harassment (6) 
 Labor and Employment (26) Wage and Hour (18)
 Minimum Wage (15) Overtime (3) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (6) 
 Pennsylvania (60)
 Hostile Environment (4)
 Discrimination (3) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (31) Wage and Hour (22)
 Minimum Wage (16) Overtime (2) Salary (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (4) 
 Puerto Rico (8)
 Hostile Environment (2)
 Discrimination (1) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (1) Wage and Hour (3)
 Minimum Wage (3) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (2) 
 Rhode Island (30)
 Hostile Environment (5)
 Discrimination (3) Sexual Harassment (2) 
 Labor and Employment (10) Wage and Hour (13)
 Minimum Wage (10) Overtime (3) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (2) 
 South Carolina (36)
 Hostile Environment (5)
 Discrimination (4) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (12) Wage and Hour (13)
 Minimum Wage (8) Overtime (4) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (5) 
 South Dakota (29)
 Hostile Environment (3)
 Discrimination (1) Sexual Harassment (2) 
 Labor and Employment (7) Wage and Hour (16)
 Minimum Wage (13) Overtime (3) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (3) 
 Tennessee (37)
 Hostile Environment (2)
 Discrimination (2) 
 Labor and Employment (14) Wage and Hour (19)
 Minimum Wage (11) Overtime (3) Salary (2) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (2) 
 Texas (63)
 Hostile Environment (2)
 Discrimination (2) 
 Labor and Employment (29) Wage and Hour (26)
 Minimum Wage (19) Overtime (10) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (5) 
 Utah (36)
 Hostile Environment (2)
 Discrimination (2) 
 Labor and Employment (17) Wage and Hour (13)
 Minimum Wage (10) Overtime (3) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (5) 
 Vermont (32)
 Hostile Environment (2)
 Discrimination (1) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (5) Wage and Hour (18)
 Minimum Wage (16) Overtime (4) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (7) 
 Virgin Islands (7)
 Hostile Environment (1)
 Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Wage and Hour (1)
 Minimum Wage (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (2) 
 Virginia (33)
 Hostile Environment (3)
 Discrimination (3) 
 Labor and Employment (13) Wage and Hour (14)
 Minimum Wage (9) Overtime (3) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (3) 
 Washington (46)
 Hostile Environment (3)
 Discrimination (3) 
 Labor and Employment (13) Wage and Hour (22)
 Minimum Wage (17) Overtime (4) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (5) 
 West Virginia (26)
 Hostile Environment (2)
 Discrimination (2) 
 Labor and Employment (8) Wage and Hour (13)
 Minimum Wage (9) Overtime (1) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (3) 
 Wisconsin (40)
 Hostile Environment (4)
 Discrimination (3) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (16) Wage and Hour (18)
 Minimum Wage (13) Overtime (2) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (2) 
 Wyoming (33)
 Hostile Environment (5)
 Discrimination (4) Sexual Harassment (1) 
 Labor and Employment (13) Wage and Hour (10)
 Minimum Wage (6) Overtime (3) 
 Worker&apos;s Compensation (3) 
 
 Federal Labor Laws (1734)
 Judicial Decisions (91) Regulations (1637)
 Davis-Bacon (5) Employee Polygraph Protection (25) Equal Employment Opportunity (145) Family and Medical Leave Act (64) Health and Safety (815) Migrant Worker Protection (16) Uniformed Services Employment Reemployment Rights Act (88) Walsh-Healey (5) Workers with Disabilities (70) 
 
 Federal Minimum Wage (337) Human Resources (123)
 Alabama (5)
 Employee Management (4)
 Hiring (2) 
 
 Alaska (4)
 Employee Management (3)
 Hiring (2) 
 
 Arizona (3)
 Employee Management (2)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Arkansas (4)
 Compensation (1) Employee Management (2)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 California (5)
 Compensation (2) Employee Management (2)
 Hiring (2) 
 
 Colorado (3)
 Compensation (1) Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Connecticut (4)
 Employee Management (3)
 Hiring (2) 
 
 Delaware (2)
 Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 District of Columbia (4)
 Compensation (3) 
 Flordia (4)
 Compensation (2) Employee Management (2)
 Hiring (2) 
 Evaluation (1)
 Promotion (1) 
 
 Georgia (4)
 Compensation (1) Employee Management (2)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Hawaii (2)
 Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Idaho (2)
 Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Illinois (4)
 Compensation (1) Employee Management (2)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Indiana (2)
 Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Iowa (2)
 Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Kansas (4)
 Compensation (1) Employee Management (3)
 Hiring (3) 
 Evaluation (1)
 Promotion (1) 
 
 Kentucky (3)
 Compensation (1) Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Louisiana (3)
 Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 Evaluation (1)
 Disciplinary (1) 
 
 Maine (3)
 Employee Management (2)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Maryland (5)
 Compensation (1) Employee Management (2)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Massachusetts (5)
 Compensation (1) Employee Management (2)
 Hiring (2) 
 
 Michigan (3)
 Compensation (1) Employee Management (2)
 Hiring (2) 
 Evaluation (1)
 Promotion (1) 
 
 Minnesota (3)
 Employee Management (2)
 Hiring (2) 
 
 Mississippi (3)
 Employee Management (2)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Missouri (4)
 Compensation (1) Employee Management (3)
 Hiring (3) 
 Evaluation (1)
 Promotion (1) 
 
 Montana (2)
 Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Nebraska (2)
 Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Nevada (3)
 Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 Evaluation (1) 
 New Hampshire (2)
 Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 New Jersey (5)
 Compensation (1) Employee Management (3)
 Firing (1) Hiring (2) 
 Evaluation (1)
 Disciplinary (1) 
 
 New Mexico (9)
 Compensation (1) Employee Management (7)
 Hiring (6) 
 Evaluation (1) 
 New York (2)
 Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 North Carolina (2)
 Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 North Dakota (3)
 Employee Management (2)
 Hiring (2) 
 
 Ohio (4)
 Compensation (1) Employee Management (2)
 Hiring (1) 
 Evaluation (1)
 Disciplinary (1) 
 
 Oklahoma (2)
 Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Oregon (2)
 Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Pennsylvania (3)
 Employee Management (2)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Puerto Rico (1) Rhode Island (4)
 Compensation (1) Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 Evaluation (1)
 Disciplinary (1) 
 
 South Carolina (2)
 Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 South Dakota (4)
 Employee Management (3)
 Hiring (2) 
 
 Tennessee (3)
 Compensation (1) Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Texas (4)
 Employee Management (3)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Utah (2)
 Employee Management (1)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Vermont (3)
 Employee Management (2)
 Hiring (2) 
 
 Virgin Islands (1) Virginia (3)
 Employee Management (2)
 Hiring (2) 
 
 Washington (4)
 Employee Management (3)
 Hiring (2) 
 
 West Virginia (4)
 Employee Management (3)
 Hiring (2) 
 
 Wisconsin (7)
 Compensation (1) Employee Management (3)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 Wyoming (3)
 Employee Management (2)
 Hiring (1) 
 
 
 Other (119) State (178)
 Alabama (18) Alaska (9) Arizona (16) Arkansas (15) California (38) Colorado (2) Connecticut (3) Delaware (2) District Of Columbia (3) Florida (5) Georgia (3) Hawaii (1) Illinois (1) Iowa (2) Kansas (2) Kentucky (1) Louisiana (2) Maine (1) Maryland (2) Massachusetts (2) Michigan (2) Minnesota (2) Mississippi (1) Missouri (3) Montana (2) Nebraska (1) Nevada (1) New Hampshire (1) New Jersey (1) New Mexico (1) New York (1) North Carolina (4) North Dakota (2) Ohio (2) Oklahoma (2) Oregon (1) Pennsylvania (2) Rhode Island (5) South Carolina (2) South Dakota (5) Tennessee (6) Texas (4) Utah (2) Vermont (2) Virgin Islands (1) Virginia (1) Washington (1) West Virginia (2) Wisconsin (1) Wyoming (1) 
 
 
ARCHIVES

 July 2012  (2) June 2012  (7) May 2012  (5) April 2012  (2) March 2012  (1) April 2011  (6) March 2011  (9) February 2011  (8) January 2011  (8) December 2010  (10) November 2010  (8) October 2010  (9) September 2010  (9) August 2010  (8) July 2010  (9) June 2010  (9) May 2010  (8) April 2010  (9) March 2010  (9) February 2010  (8) January 2010  (9) December 2009  (9) November 2009  (8) October 2009  (9) September 2009  (9) August 2009  (11) July 2009  (14) June 2009  (13) May 2009  (13) April 2009  (13) March 2009  (13) February 2009  (20) January 2009  (22) December 2008  (23) November 2008  (20) October 2008  (23) September 2008  (22) August 2008  (21) July 2008  (23) June 2008  (21) May 2008  (29) April 2008  (83) March 2008  (60) February 2008  (48) January 2008  (46) December 2007  (54) November 2007  (40) October 2007  (37) September 2007  (33) August 2007  (41) July 2007  (48) June 2007  (361) May 2007  (790) April 2007  (476) March 2007  (477) February 2007  (348) January 2007  (481) December 2006  (207) November 2006  (90) October 2006  (114) September 2006  (748) August 2006  (777) July 2006  (88) June 2006  (6) May 2006  (3) April 2006  (2) March 2006  (4) February 2006  (9) January 2006  (10) December 2005  (4) November 2005  (7) October 2005  (3) September 2005  (7) August 2005  (13) July 2005  (4) June 2005  (8) May 2005  (2) March 2005  (3) February 2005  (1) January 2005  (3) December 2004  (2) September 2004  (1) August 2004  (1) July 2004  (2) June 2004  (2) May 2004  (2) March 2004  (1) February 2004  (1) January 2004  (1) August 2003  (1) August 2002  (1) April 2002  (2) February 2002  (1) 
 
AUTHORS

 Adrianne Dunne Alexandra Waldron Amelia Figueroa Ashley Crawford Bethany Stroh Cara Lawrence Christine Carter Derrick Lange Emily Richardson Hannah Dixon Heather Connors Jane Morgan Jared Franklin John Bellamy Jolie Beckett Justine Murchie Karen Husson Kimberly Matthews Lindsay Ross Madison Thomas Marilyn Walters Mark Hathaway Nicole Andrade Rachel Maguire Sarah Fitzgerald Savannah Case Susan Symthe 
 
 
Copyright©2008 LaborLawCenter, Inc. All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
