<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002963" url="http://houston.citysearch.com/profile/9994755/sugar_land_tx/panda_garden_restaurant.html" time="2012-07-12-19:03" support="6" score="0.020613670844207788" bingtitle="Panda Garden Restaurant - Sugar Land, TX - Citysearch" webtitle="Panda Garden Restaurant - Sugar Land, TX, 77478 - Citysearch">
			<query id="000852" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="001145" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="000883" bing-rank="186"/>
			<query id="000350" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="001103" bing-rank="239"/>
			<query id="001135" bing-rank="75"/>
	<description>It was like eating fried chicken strips from a fast food restaurant but it was shrimp. ... chances on several other meals and ... with their plating when I got my order ...</description>
	<body>
		Deals Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Hotels Shopping Best Of Citysearch 

 Mobile Login / Join 
 More More Go! Advertise With Us 
 Citysearch has shed its old skin! In addition to our new look, there&apos;s a boatload of new features. Poke around! Tell us what you think! 
 Houston, TX Metro &gt; Sugar Land &gt; Restaurants &gt; Panda Garden Restaurant 
Panda Garden Restaurant
 (281) 265-0303 
 3563 Hwy 6 , Sugar Land , TX | Directions  
 77478 29.587901 -95.593101 View Website 
 Share Save 
   Own this Business? Recommend this business? Thumbs Up Thumbs Down ? 50 % 100 4 4 Votes Add a Photo Neighborhoods: Old Mill Park Categories: Restaurants Cuisine: Chinese 
 View Less 
 At a Glance ? 
 37% food quality
 “The egg roll, is mediocre.” 
 100% service
 “The service was excellent!” 
 100% value
 “The prices were great!” Site Feedback 
 Overview Tips (4) Photos (0) 
 Write a Tip for Panda Garden Restaurant 
 Sign in to Write a Tip 
 Write a Tip... optional 
 
 
Tips for Panda Garden Restaurant
 Doesn&apos;t Recommend Knicole Joined 4 years ago 1.0 May 12, 2008 
 The absolute worst Sweet&amp;Sour Shrimp I have ever had........ I have been eating Panda Garden for nearly 20 years, since I was a little girl, and have always ordered one of my 3 usuals. Well, we moved and had to order from the location on Highway 6 in Sugar Land. I ordered the sweet&amp;sour shrimp, as usual and I was shocked!! It came fried and breaded with this thick and&quot;bumpy&quot;batter. It was like eating fried chicken strips from a fast food restaurant but it was shrimp. I am not sure what all they put in the batter but, it was terrible!! I did try to give them several chances on several other meals and they just cannot produce food to the average Panda Garden standards. I have not ever gone into the restaurant, so I cannot say anything regarding that, however I will not ever eat from that location again. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Doesn&apos;t Recommend KVonnegut Joined 10 years ago 2.0 July 21, 2005 
 You&apos;ll get more than what you paid!!!. I ordered from one of their lunch menu. I was very much impressed with their plating when I got my order, it looked very upscale. Unfortunately, the food was not as appetizing as it looked. The egg roll, is mediocre. The HOT and SOUR soup was very tasty but halfway to the bowl, I scooped a strand of hair. I brought it to the manager&apos;s attention and he offered to bring me another one - I said NO THANK YOU. The MONGOLIAN BEEF, was the oddest I&apos;ve ever tasted. It was very sweet, &apos;seemed like the beef was macerated in a cup of granulated sugar. True, MONGOLIAN BEEF uses a smidgeon of sugar to taste but this is outrageously sweet that I can feel the sugar granules grinding on my teeth. It seemed like they are going for a texture similar to another famous Chinese Restaurant chain&apos;s MONGOLIAN BEEF. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends nrenaud Joined 8 years ago 3.0 August 26, 2004 
 DO NOT order garlic shrimp. I ordered the garlic shrimp today and it was anything but the norm. When I got back to work and opened up the container to only find shrimp with soaked in soupy tomato sauce with more cut up tomatoe halves. It should have been named shrimp tomato soup. The item was noted with a red chili next to it, indicating hotness but in was very sweet and syrupy. When I called to voice my opinon there was absolutely no recompense. So heed this warning, don&apos;t ever order something new, especial tomato shrimp soup! … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Recommends Clotheshorsecc Joined 10 years ago 5.0 September 25, 2002 
 A perfect dining experience!!!. I have nothing but positive things to say about the Panda Garden!!! The service was excellent! The food was awesome!!! The prices were great!!! I would eat there everyday if I lived closer!!!SOOO many wonderful specials to chose from!! … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart 
 
 Write a Tip for Panda Garden Restaurant 
 Sign in to Write a Tip 
 Write a Tip... optional 
 
 
People who viewed this also viewed…
 
 Panda Express 1401 Highway 6 # A 
 Sugar Land, TX 
2.6 mi away Golden Bo Restaurant In… 6122 Highway 6 
 Missouri City, TX 
2.2 mi away 100 % Hunan Empress Restauran… 15425 Southwest Fwy 
 Sugar Land, TX 
1.8 mi away 
 
Things to do near Panda Garden Restaurant
 
 Restaurants Movie Theaters Banks 

 Bars Shopping&amp;Malls Hotels 
 
 About Apps Careers Privacy Policy Terms of Use Contact Us Blog FAQs 
 
Partner Sites:

 Ask Kids     Bloglines     Expedia     Hotels     Hotwire     Insider Pages     MerchantCircle     Reference     The Daily Beast     Thesaurus     Urbanspoon 
 ©2011. Citysearch is a registered trademark of CityGrid Media. Data provided by Infogroup. All rights reserved. 
 Popular Categories Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Shopping Hotels Deals Sports&amp;Recreation Cafes Movie Theaters Directory&amp;Services 

 Change City New York City Los Angeles Houston Chicago Atlanta Seattle Portland Philadelphia Austin San Francisco More…
	</body>
</document>
