<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002397" url="http://www.dailyherald.com/article/20111225/news/712259870/" time="2012-07-12-18:19" support="1" score="0.0011331424901900539" bingtitle="California to stop towing unlicensed drivers - DailyHerald.com" webtitle="California to stop towing unlicensed drivers - DailyHerald.com">
			<query id="000694" bing-rank="210"/>
	<description>... California to prohibit police from impounding cars ... ago, he quit his job frying chickens at a fast-food restaurant ... Framer, Class Instructors, Sales Associates, Cashiers ...</description>
	<body>
		Select an RSS feed from the list below

 Top DailyHerald.com headlines Top DailyHerald.com Sports headlines Top DailyHerald.com Business headlines Top DailyHerald.com Life&amp;Entertainment headlines 
 Go 
View the complete list of DailyHerald.com RSS links | 
 Subscriber Total Access Learn more loading Home Delivery Order Customer Service   Santos Hall election still feels hollow Barry Rozner - column 
 Home 
 Thursday, July 12th Stories eEDITION Photos Videos Blogs Communities Weather 
 News 
 Cook Co. DuPage Co. Kane Co. Lake Co. McHenry Co. Chicago State&amp;Region Nation&amp;World Obituaries Politics 2012 Election 
 Sports 
 High School College Professional Bears Blackhawks Bulls Cubs White Sox Fire Rush Sky Wolves 2012 Summer Olympics 
 Business 
 Stocks&amp;Markets Finance Health Technology Real Estate Foreclosures Property Transfers 
 Life&amp;Entertainment 
 Celebrities Food Health&amp;Fitness Home&amp;Garden Movies Music Puzzles Television Theater Travel Celebrations Suburbs Got Talent 
 Discuss 
 Letters to the Editor Editorials Blogs 
 Autos 
 New&amp;Used For Sale by Owner Classic Motorcycles Wanted 
 Homes 
 Find a Home / Rental Real Estate News Home&amp;Garden Columns Property Transfers Foreclosures Place an Ad 
 Jobs 
 Find a Job Post a Job Post Your Resume 
 Classifieds 
 Merchandise For Sale Legal Notices Business Opportunities Announcements Place an Ad 
 Shopping 
 Merchandise For Sale Business Service Directory Garage Sales 
 Services&amp;Info 
 General Information Subscriber Services Newsroom Online Advertising Contact the Staff Subscribe 
 
 
 Quick Hits Politics State&amp;Region 
 Browse our Archives RSS     Article updated: 12/25/2011 4:43 PM 
California to stop towing unlicensed drivers

 Article Comments ( 0 ) Photos ( 1 ) 
 
 
Police officers check drivers at a sobriety checkpoint in Escondido, Calif., on Dec. 16. Starting Jan. 1, police in California can no longer impound vehicles from DUI checkpoints when the drivers only offense is driving without a license.
   
ASSOCIATED PRESS
 
   1 of 1     View other photograph collections text size: A A A By Associated Press 
ESCONDIDO, Calif.—Delfino Aldama was fixing a customers brakes this month when his smartphone chimed with a text message that tipped him to a police checkpoint more than an hour before officers began stopping motorists. The self-employed auto mechanic frantically called friends with the location and drove an alternate route home.

The Mexico native had reason to be alarmed: He does not have a drivers license because he is in the United States illegally, and it would cost about $1,400 to get his Nissan Frontier pickup back from the towing company. He has breathed a little easier since he began getting blast text messages two years ago from activists who scour streets to find checkpoints as they are being set up.
 Advertisement 
The cat-and-mouse game ends Jan. 1 when a new law takes effect in California to prohibit police from impounding cars at sobriety checkpoints if a motorists only offense is being an unlicensed driver. Thousands of cars are towed each year in the state under those circumstances, hitting pocketbooks of illegal immigrants especially hard.

When Aldamas 1992 Honda Civic was towed from a checkpoint years ago, he quit his job frying chickens at a fast-food restaurant because he had no way to make the 40-mile round trip to work. He abandoned the car rather than pay about $1,200 in fees.

A car is a necessity, its not a luxury, said the 35-year-old Aldama, who lives in Escondido with his wife, who is a legal resident, and their 5-year-old son, a U.S. citizen.

Assemblyman Gil Cedillo, a Los Angeles Democrat who tried unsuccessfully to restore driver licenses to illegal immigrants after California revoked the privilege in 1993, said he introduced the bill to ban towing after learning the notoriously corrupt city of Bell raked in big fees from unlicensed drivers at checkpoints.

A sharp increase in federally funded sobriety checkpoints in California has fueled controversy. The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration paid for 2,553 checkpoints last year, which authorities say helps explain why deaths caused by drunken drivers dropped to an all-time low in the state.

Police also ask for drivers licenses at the sobriety checkpoints. Supporters of the vehicle impounds say unlicensed drivers are also a roadside hazard and that the new law is misguided.

Its a terrible law, really disappointing, said Jim Maher, who sharply expanded checkpoints in Escondido after being named police chief in 2006.

All but three U.S. states—New Mexico, Utah and Washington—deny drivers licenses to illegal immigrants but controversy over checkpoints has been strongest in California. Cedillo believes thats because a 1995 state law has allowed police to impound vehicles from unlicensed drivers for 30 days, resulting in fees that can easily top $1,000.

Towing practices vary widely across the state. San Francisco allows 20 minutes to find a licensed driver to claim a vehicle at a checkpoint. The Los Angeles Police Department eased rules on 30-day impounds in March.

Checkpoints have divided Escondido, a city of 144,000 people near San Diego whose Latino population has surged in the last 30 years. Latinos moved into aging neighborhoods near downtown as newer subdivisions gradually spread to avocado orchards, vineyards and citrus groves. Nearly half the signs at a big strip mall near City Hall are in Spanish.

Like Hazleton, Pa., and Farmers Branch, Texas, authorities in Escondido have tackled illegal immigration on their own.

In 2006, the City Council voted to require landlords to check tenants immigration status but a federal judge blocked the ordinance and it never took effect. Last year, Escondido police forged an unusually close alliance with U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, which has four agents at police headquarters to check the immigration status of people who are questioned at checkpoints or elsewhere.

Its a never-ending battle, said Concilman Ed Gallo, a New Jersey transplant who blames illegal immigration for overcrowded homes and schools. We didnt pay attention to it for 25 years and look what happened. It was a long, slow process.

Several residents and a labor union sued Escondido in state court this month to create City Council districts, a bid to increase Latino representation. The lawsuit says the council has pursued aggressive anti-immigrant policies that have inflamed racial tensions.

Maher (pronounced mah-HAR) said the partnership with ICE is aimed only at rooting out illegal immigrants who commit crimes after arriving in the United States, including being previously deported. Those whose only offense is being in the country illegally wont be bothered by his officers, nor will any crime victims or witnesses.

Police say they have turned over 670 people to ICE for immigration proceedings since the joint effort began in May 2010. Their most common offenses were previous convictions for driving under the influence and drugs, with lower numbers for theft and assault.

We certainly have enough of our own criminals. We dont need someone elses here, Maher said.

Escondido has impounded more than 3,200 vehicles since 2006, mostly at the federally funded sobriety checkpoints. The city had towed about 1,000 at driver-license-only checkpoints until the American Civil Liberties Union and El Grupo, a Latino advocacy group, threatened a lawsuit in 2009, contending they violated the state vehicle code.

Maher insists he is targeting unlicensed drivers, not illegal immigrants or Latinos.

Six towing companies each pay the city $75,000 a year to take turns at checkpoints, keeping impound fees for themselves. About one-third of the cars towed are believed to be abandoned, allowing the towing companies to auction them.

It was kind of like letting them steal cars, said Olga Diaz, the only Hispanic on the City Council.

Websites that have sprung up in the last two years quickly alert motorists to checkpoints through social media networks and smartphones, severely undermining their effectiveness. A few years ago, Escondido police impounded 50 or 60 vehicles a night. Now they typically get about 20.

One of the final checkpoints before the new law takes effect was one of the slowest in memory for many of the 15 officers who stood under bright lights and encountered a December chill. Activists waved signs several blocks away, giving motorist an opportunity to turn away. Police impounded six vehicles—three for driving without a license and three for driving under the influence.

Aldama, who paid a smuggler $1,300 to lead him through the mountains east of San Diego on a weeklong trek 13 years ago, was able to reach all his friends before the checkpoint began. One he didnt call had his 1997 Ford Explorer towed at an Escondido checkpoint a few weeks earlier. The unemployed construction worker surrendered the SUV to the towing company because he couldnt afford the fees.
 
This article filed under

 News Nation/World 
 Web Talk Read 0 comments or post a comment 
 Share Facebook Twitter 
 Facebook Twitter Linkedin MySpace Delicious Reddit StumbleUpon Digg Google Bookmark Google Buzz Permalink 
 E-mail 
Article sent to (required) 
 E-mail 
Article sent from (required) 
 E-mail Name 
Subject Line (article title) 
 
Message (optional) 
 Success - Article sent Click to close Order reprint 
Interested in reusing this article?

Custom reprints are a powerful and strategic way to share your article with customers, employees and prospects.

The YGS Group provides digital and printed reprint services for Daily Herald. Complete the form to the right and a reprint consultant will contact you to discuss how you can reuse this article.
 Need more information about reprints? Visit our Reprints Section for more details. 
Contact information ( * required ) 
 Name * Company Telephone * E-mail * 
Article Information
 Title URL 
Message (optional) 
 Success - Reprint request sent Click to close Print 
 
More articles in News

 One dead in Route 53 crash near Schaumburg U-46 kids create an opera of their own Destined Lives cast Waukegan artist&apos;s ever-evolving works on display Bill helps minority, women-owned businesses Gail Borden Library automatic sorter up and running Chicago&apos;s Lyric Opera awarded $2M grant Mosquitoes test positive for West Nile virus in Fox River Grove Obama, Romney campaigns accuse each other of lies W.Va. sheriff says woman tortured; husband charged 
 
 Best Bets
     
 
 Mike North video 

 Mike North: Who does Tyler Clary think he is? 
 
 Sports 

 Bulls would be perfect fit for Howard 
 
 Theater 

 New approach for &apos;Three Sisters&apos; 
 
 Suburban Chicago&apos;s Got Talent 

 Time to vote! 
 
 Night life 

 Village Vintner has the right mix 
 
 
 Most Viewed
 Today Yesterday Most Commented 
 One dead in Route 53 crash near Schaumburg Teen dies a day after friends pull him from Fox River Are you 1 in 8 who deserves to get money back? Bulls would be perfect fit for Howard Rolling Meadows bowling alley closure surprises many 3 siblings to be sentenced together for abusing mom Dawn Patrol: Teen collapses in Fox, dies; Elgin limits gambling Rivers Casino plans to provide its own EMTs Mortgage rates at historic lows, but it&apos;s harder to refinance Kid-friendly &apos;Ice Age&apos; sequel plays it safe 
 See today&apos;s top 50 articles 
 Algonquin mom: Leaving disabled woman was best Mortgage rates at historic lows, but it&apos;s harder to refinance Arlington Hts. still wants movies downtown Teen dies a day after friends pull him from Fox River South Elgin man charged with cruelty to dog found in hot car Millions spent in duplicating South Elgin water service New restaurant to open in West Dundee DuPage guitar teacher gets 4.5 years for molesting student Bulls depth starting to take a hit Drew Peterson’s son sues Oak Brook over firing 
 See today&apos;s top 50 articles 
 More suburban Jews turning to the Republican Party Nekritz: Pension reform might wait until lame duck session Romney draws boos from NAACP when he dings Obama Algonquin mom: Leaving disabled woman was best Software glitches delay 911 response in Northwest suburbs Wheaton man appointed to election panel 
 See today&apos;s top 50 articles 
Top Jobs
 

 next prev 
 CERTIFIED MEDICAL ASSISTANT - Healthcare Fast paced surgeons office in NW suburbs seeks a Certified Medical Assistant with at least 5 years experience. CMA will work in an outpatient setting as part of our healthcare team, actively affecting quality patient care. The CMA assumes responsibilities for, but not limited to: maintaining patient flow, performing basic skills such as vital signs, point of care testing, phlebotomy, etc. The CMA must be mature, organized, computer savvy, must have knowledge of EMR (eClinicalWorks), able to multi-task, handle high patient volume as well as possess excellent communication skills. F/T, flexible schedule, commensurate salary, good location. Education/Special Skills Required: Current Medical Assistant Certification and Graduate of Medical Assistant Program. Candidates please email resume to: hr@suburbansurigicalcare.com (id:4307913) DRIVERS - Drivers: BLACK HORSE CARRIERS -has multiple openings in the Chicagoland area. Regional runs, local routes, spotter positions. Average wage between $1000 and $1500 per week. 5 day work week. These are full time positions come with full Benefits, 401K, paid vacation, high quality equipment. We also have part time positions available. If you have 3 yrs. Exp. and a Class A CDL with a clean MVR. Call 630-580-5170 or email to david.swords@blackhorsecarriers.com EOE. Drug Testing is a condition of employment (id:4307528) STEEL SAW OPERATOR - 4307282 - Warehouse ? Steel Saw Operator/Order Filler Steel distributor seeks a F/T, detail oriented team player. Position includes saw cutting&amp;order pulling. Steel cutting, forklift exp.&amp;the ability to lift 75 lbs req&apos;d. Hrs: 8:00a -5:00p. Benefits incl: Pd vacations/holidays, Health, Den-tal, Life Ins, 401K Plan. Mail resume to: Valbruna Stainless 370 Village Drive Carol Stream, IL 60188 Or fax to 630-871-6061 No phone calls or walk-ins please. (id:4307282) VISA MANAGER - Financial VISA MANAGER 2-5 yrs of similar or related exp., preferably at a financial institution; a two-year college degree is preferred. Oversees the daily operations of the Visa card services department. Fax resumes w/sal. reqs. to: 847-265-5262 or email: HR_Dept@myconsumers.org No phone calls. EOE (id:4307081) RESIDENT CARE MANAGER - Resident Care Manager Elk Grove Village Current LPN-RN and supervisory experience in Assisted Living a MUST www.pathwaysl.com (id:4307046) PRINTING POSITIONS - 4307539 - Printing Maintenance Technician Feeder Operator Bobst Blanking Pressman Graphic Packaging Intl. is currently seeking an experienced Maintenance Technician and Printing Feeder Operator for their Elk Grove Village, IL folding carton plant. The ideal Maintenance Technician candidate will be responsible for trouble shooting, performing breakdown repairs, and preventative maintenance on all production equipment. The ideal Feeder Operator candidate will have at least one year experience as an offset Printing Press Feeder. The ideal Cutting Pressman candidate must have at least one year experience on a Bobst Blanking Press. All positions must be able to work ANY shift and lift up to 40 lbs. Must be able to speak, read and write English. A competitive wage and benefits package await the right individual, including matching 401k, paid vacations and holidays. Please send resume to: Graphic Packaging Intl. Attn: Diana Diaz 1900 Greenleaf Elk Grove Village, IL 60007 Diana.diaz@graphicpkg.com M/F/D/V (id:4307539) CNC MAINTENANCE TECH - MAINTENANCE CNC Maintenance Tech Oilfield flow line products company seeks individual to maintain CNC machines (including hydraulic&amp;mechanical systems) and provide general plant maintenance for Island Lake, IL. facility. 3-5 yrs previous CNC machine maintenance experience required. Competitive wage&amp;benefit program includes Profit Sharing, 401(k), Health, Life&amp;Dental Insurance and pleasant working environment. Send resume to: Kemper Valve&amp;Fittings Corp. Attn: Human Resources PO Box 400 Wauconda, IL 60084 FAX: (847)487-9354 HR@kempervalve.com (id:4307457) DRIVER - DRIVERS/Retirees welcomed to drive late model vehicles. In&amp;around Des Plaines area. FT/ PT Approx $10.00/hr 847-871-0370 (id:4307099) ONCOLOGY RN - Healthcare ONCOLOGY RN&apos;S! Here is an opportunity to evolve into a new nursing career that is both exciting and challenging! Have your eve-nings, weekends, and holidays free! HINES&amp;ASSOCIATES, INC. We are expanding again and Offering a FT Case Management Position In our St. Charles location! Work in a telephonic position dealing directly with patients Must be an RN w/ Min. 3 yrs acute care or HHC exp. HOSPICE OR ONCOLOGY A PLUS! Fax resume to: 847-741-1728 Or call 877-429-7345 X 3426 with questions (id:4307336) 
 
 View all Top Jobs Place a job ad 
 
 Markets Report
 
 Market Place
 
 
 »Browse our Marketplace 
 DH Extras
     
 
 
 Facebook Activity
 
 Business Directory

Connect with a business or service in your area fast. First select a town, then enter a search term or choose one of the listed popular searches:
 Arlington Heights, IL» 
: popular searches below
 Arlington Heights Attorneys Arlington Heights Auto Repair Arlington Heights Beauty Salons Arlington Heights Dentists Arlington Heights Doctors Arlington Heights Hotels Arlington Heights Insurance Arlington Heights Mortgages Arlington Heights Realtors Arlington Heights Restaurants More Popular Searches Naperville, IL» 
: popular searches below
 Naperville Attorneys Naperville Auto Repair Naperville Beauty Salons Naperville Dentists Naperville Doctors Naperville Hotels Naperville Insurance Naperville Mortgages Naperville Realtors Naperville Restaurants More Popular Searches Elgin, IL» 
: popular searches below
 Elgin Attorneys Elgin Auto Repair Elgin Beauty Salons Elgin Dentists Elgin Doctors Elgin Hotels Elgin Insurance Elgin Mortgages Elgin Realtors Elgin Restaurants More Popular Searches Libertyville, IL» 
: popular searches below
 Libertyville Attorneys Libertyville Auto Repair Libertyville Beauty Salons Libertyville Dentists Libertyville Doctors Libertyville Hotels Libertyville Insurance Libertyville Mortgages Libertyville Realtors Libertyville Restaurants More Popular Searches Saint Charles, IL» 
: popular searches below
 Saint Charles Attorneys Saint Charles Auto Repair Saint Charles Beauty Salons Saint Charles Dentists Saint Charles Doctors Saint Charles Hotels Saint Charles Insurance Saint Charles Mortgages Saint Charles Realtors Saint Charles Restaurants More Popular Searches 
Don&apos;t see your town listed? Visit our full directory to begin your search.

Powered by Local.com 
 Browse our Archives     RSS 
 Site Index

 Home eEdition Photos Videos Blogs Communities Weather 

 News Cook DuPage Kane Lake McHenry Chicago State&amp;Region Nation&amp;World Obituaries Politics 

 Sports High School College Professional Bears Blackhawks Bulls Cubs White Sox Fire Sky Wolves 

 Business Stocks&amp;Markets Finance Health Technology Real Estate Foreclosures Property Transfers 

 Life&amp;Entertainment Food Health&amp;Fitness Home&amp;Garden Movies Puzzles Travel Celebrations 

 Discuss Letters to the Editor Editorials Blogs 

 Marketplace Jobs Homes Autos Merchandise 
 
 Community Finder
 
Select a county on the map to view a list of related communities in our coverage area.
 close 
 Cook County DuPage County Kane County Kendall County Lake County McHenry County Will County 
 
 Arlington Heights Barrington Barrington Hills Bartlett Buffalo Grove Carol Stream Deer Park Des Plaines Elgin Elk Grove Village Glenview Hanover Park Hoffman Estates Inverness Mount Prospect Palatine Prospect Heights Rolling Meadows Roselle Rosemont Schaumburg South Barrington Streamwood Wheeling Woodridge 
 
 Addison Aurora Bartlett Bensenville Bloomingdale Bolingbrook Carol Stream Downers Grove Elmhurst Glen Ellyn Glendale Heights Hanover Park Hinsdale Itasca Keeneyville Lisle Lombard Medinah Naperville Oak Brook Oakbrook Terrace Roselle Villa Park Warrenville West Chicago Westmont Wheaton Winfield Wood Dale Woodridge 
 
 Algonquin Aurora Barrington Hills Bartlett Batavia Burlington Campton Hills Carpentersville East Dundee Elburn Elgin Geneva Gilberts Hampshire Hoffman Estates Huntley Kaneville Lily Lake Maple Park North Aurora Pingree Grove St. Charles Sleepy Hollow South Elgin Sugar Grove Wayne West Dundee 
 
 Aurora 
 
 Antioch Bannockburn Barrington Barrington Hills Buffalo Grove Deer Park Deerfield Diamond Lake Fox Lake Fox River Grove Gages Lake Grandwood Park Grayslake Green Oaks Gurnee Hainesville Hawthorn Woods Indian Creek Ingleside Island Lake Kildeer Lake Barrington Lake Bluff Lake Forest Lake Villa Lake Zurich Lakemoor Libertyville Lincolnshire Lindenhurst Long Grove Mettawa Mundelein North Barrington Old Mill Creek Park City Port Barrington Riverwoods Rondout Round Lake Round Lake Beach Round Lake Heights Round Lake Park Spring Grove Third Lake Tower Lakes Vernon Hills Vernon Hills Volo Wadsworth Wauconda Waukegan Wheeling 
 
 Algonquin Barrington Hills Cary Crystal Lake Fox River Grove Huntley Island Lake Lake in the Hills Lakemoor Lilymoor Marengo McHenry Port Barrington Spring Grove Woodstock 
 
 Aurora Bolingbrook Naperville Woodridge 
 Customer Services | Jobs at Daily Herald | Advertise | Subscribe | Feedback 
 Copyright©2012 Paddock Publications, Inc. | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service | About our Ads Visit other Daily Herald sites: Select Site e-Edition Autos Jobs Real Estate
	</body>
</document>
