<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002619" url="http://bythechimneywithcare.wordpress.com/2008/12/13/stocking-stuffer-ideas/" time="2012-07-12-18:41" support="1" score="0.0011707617086230645" bingtitle="Stocking Stuffer Ideas « By the Chimney With Care" webtitle="Stocking Stuffer IdeasBy the Chimney With Care">
			<query id="000918" bing-rank="213"/>
	<description>Your neighborhood dollar store can be a great ... Decorative ice cube tray. 17. Barrettes, hair ties ... Gift certificate for a favorite fast food restaurant</description>
	<body>
		Home Our Story History of the Christmas Stocking Stockings to Buy 
 
 By the Chimney With Care 
 We’re proud to share our hand-crafted, heirloom quallity Christmas stockings with you. Custom orders available, too! 
December 13, 2008
 
Stocking Stuffer Ideas
Posted by phxazlaura under Stocking Articles , Stocking Stuffers | Tags: advertising , Christmas , Christmas gifts , Christmas stockings , Stocking Stuffers |
 [2] Comments   
 They usually start right around November 1 . . . the ubiquitous annual ads for stocking stuffers. When I was a kid, our stockings were one of the most joyful parts of Christmas morning, opened with squeals of delight as soon as we finished singing “Happy Birthday” to the Baby Jesus. Perhaps kids were easier to impress, once upon a time . . . or maybe my family just lived a simpler life. The thing is, our stocking stuffers were always small gifts. From my mom, we could count on weird things like squishy, overripe oranges, interesting things like rubber duckies, and she also was always good for Hershey’s Kisses® and assorted Christmas candies. My dad, on the other hand, preferred inexpensive fun things like Silly Putty, Play-Doh, and Slinkies.

 Could any of us ever have imagined that the stocking stuffer ads of today would pitch items “under $50”?! Isn’t the point of stocking stuffers to allow you to “stuff” the stocking? Let’s get real – there’s no reason to break the bank on your stocking stuffers. Small, inexpensive gifts can be loads of fun . . .  both to receive and to give. Your neighborhood dollar store can be a great place to find fun stocking stuffers – but make sure you go with a budget, because it’s easy to spend a lot of money in a hurry in those places. 

 Put on your creative thinking cap and you will probably come up with all kinds of wonderful stocking-sized gifts. Here’s a list of 113 ideas to get you started . . . 

 1. AA or AAA batteries 

 2. Journal or blank book 

 3. Shoelaces – fun or practical, depending on the receiver 

 4. Blank CDs or DVDs 

 5. Eyeglasses case 

 6. Decorative bottle opener or cork screw 

 7. Bubble baths or bath pearls 

 8. Calculator 

 9. Bookmark 

 10. Spare toothbrushes 

 11. Compact mirror 

 12. Gum, mints, favorite childhood candy 

 13. Crayons, colored pencils, or markers 

 14. Chocolate – or other favorite candy 

 15. Dave’s Insanity Hot Sauce 

 16. Decorative ice cube tray 

 17. Barrettes, hair ties, headbands 

 18. Kitchen gadgets 

 19. Address book 

 20. Decorative wine stopper 

 21. Desk, wall, or pocket calendar 

 22. Favorite herbs or spices 

 23. Stuffed animal 

 24. Flower or vegetable seeds 

 25. Lips tick or gloss – select fun colors and/or flavors 

 26. Playing cards 

 27. Nail clippers or file 

 28. Book or magazine 

 29. Gloves, scarf, earmuffs, or hat 

 30. Magnifying glass or decorative reading glasses 

 31. Crossword puzzle book 

 32. Golf balls, tees, glove 

 33. Greeting cards or stationery 

 34. Craft supplies 

 35. Coloring book 

 36. Hand lotion 

 37. Hand-crafted picture frame – buy at the craft store and decorate with glitter, stickers, or decorative items to suit recipient’s tastes 

 38. Candles 

 39. Decorative tea or hand towels 

 40. Perfume or aftershave 

 41. Homemade jam or canned fruit 

 42. Garden tools 

 43. Incense 

 44. Photos from recipient’s childhood 

 45. Bud vase 

 46. iTunes gift card 

 47. Gift certificate for a favorite fast food restaurant 

 48. Jigsaw puzzle 

 49. Flavored coffee or gourmet teabags 

 50. Kaleidoscope 

 51. Cold facial mask to relieve aches and stress 

 52. Silly straws 

 53. Keyring 

 54. Decorative soap dish or shower curtain rings
 

 55. Postage stamps 

 56. Decorative scissors or hole punch 

 57. Back scratcher 

 58. Shoehorn 

 59. Kite 

 

 60. Oranges, apples, kiwi, or another favorite fruit – make sure they’re not overripe, though! 


 61. Lottery tickets – Scratchers or Lotto 

 62. Miniature bottles of liquor or liqueur 

 63. Model kit 

 64. Handkerchief 

 65. Costume jewelry 

 66. Mouse pad 

 67. Sports water bottle 

 68. Christmas ornament 

 69. Mug or teacup 

 70. Lanyard or chain for eyeglasses
 

 71. Nail polish in a fun, lively color 

 72. Fishing lures or hat
 

 73. Baseball, batting glove, or ball cap 

 74. Nuts or dried fruits 

 75. Snowglobe 

 76. Lipstick case 

 77. Packets of flavored hot chocolate or cider mix 

 78. Personalized birth chart or horoscope book 

 79. Wall poster 

 80. Homemade cookies or brownies 

 81. Refrigerator magnet 

 82. Sachet or potpourri, decorated with a silk ribbon in a favorite color 

 83. Yo-yo 

 84. Scented soaps 

 85. Sewing, knitting, needlework, or woodworking patterns 

 86. Decorative watering can 

 87. Sheet music 

 88. Dog/cat toys 

 89. Wine glass charms/drink markers 

 90. Sidewalk chalk 

 91. Silly Putty, Play-Doh, or Slinky . . . all these years later, Dad’s ideas still work! 

 92. Change purse 

 93. Stickers or rubber stamps for scrapbooking 

 94. Flashlight 

 95. Boxed card set with phrases from a favorite book
 

 96. Movie gift certificates 

 97. Toy cars 

 98. Travel map or city guide 

 99. Decorative tissues 

 100. Razors 

 101. Travel mug 

 102. Napkin rings 

 103. Trinket box 

 104. Microwave popcorn 

 105. Useful tool (e.g., hammer, screwdriver, pliers) 

 106. Wallet or business card holder 

 107. Gel pens in a variety of colors
 

 108. Sudoku book 

 109. Wrist or ankle weights or workout bands 

 110. Zipper pouch 

 111. Travel game/toy, like Etch-a-Sketch, Boggle, or Pass the Pigs
 

 112. Rubber ducky – OK, Mom, once in a while, you got something right.
 

 113. Christmas accessories (e.g. earrings, socks, pin, vest) 

 
 
 
Share this:
 
 StumbleUpon Digg Reddit 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this.   
2 Responses to“Stocking Stuffer Ideas”

 Amy&apos;s Stocking Stuffers Says: 
 December 13, 2008 at 6:35 pm 
I like the idea of silly shoelaces, especially for kids under ten. It’s one of those“Why didn’t I think of that?”ideas!

When I was in junior high, we used to tie little jingle bells to our shoelaces in December. Our teachers tolerated it as long as we didn’t deliberately make extra noise during classes. Your post brought that memory back!
 Stocking Stuffers from Memory Lane«By the Chimney With Care Says: 
 January 9, 2009 at 11:11 am 
[...] follows is a list of nostalgic stocking stuffer ideas that come purely from my own childhood [...]
 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 

 
Archived Entry

 Post Date : December 13, 2008 at 8:30 am Category : Stocking Articles , Stocking Stuffers Tags: advertising , Christmas , Christmas gifts , Christmas stockings , Stocking Stuffers Do More : You can leave a response , or trackback from your own site. 
 
 Blog at WordPress.com .—Theme: Connections by www.vanillamist.com .
 Follow 
 Follow“By the Chimney With Care” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
