<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002899" url="http://countrykitchenpantry.com/2009/11/13/eating-on-only-five-dollars-a-week/" time="2012-07-12-18:58" support="2" score="0.001839299368677293" bingtitle="Eating on Only Five Dollars a Week - Country Kitchen Pantry ..." webtitle="Eating on Only Five Dollars a Week | Country Kitchen Pantry | Herbs, Vegetarian Recipes, Philosophy">
			<query id="000780" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="000855" bing-rank="150"/>
	<description>The nearest fast food restaurant is more than forty miles ... finding out I can still pay all my bills ... in the bottom of the steamer and put vegetables in the steamer tray on ...</description>
	<body>
		Home About Contact 
 Hippies, Prejudice, and Me Food Withdrawals, the $5 Food Budget’s Scourge 
Eating on Only Five Dollars a Week
 By Linda On Friday, November 13, 2009 · 7 Comments 
My goal, between now and the end of the year, is to spend only $5 per week on food.
 
 
Can I do it? We will soon find out.

Why the strict budget? Well, my income went down and now I’m finding out I can still pay all my bills (that’s good) but I will have to choose between firewood and food (not so good.) As it gets really cold here in the mountains, I definitely want to buy the firewood. A nice young man comes by and dumps the wood, a cord at a time, in my front yard right in front of the flower bed. We pay him $190 for all his labor, and usually need more than a cord per month once winter gets rolling.

I have a lot of food stored up here. I have canned foods I almost never touch. I was saving them for an emergency. They’re about a year old now and I really should consume them and then replace the stored items when I’m feeling more prosperous. I’ve also got lots of stored beans and rice, and other dry foods…you know, flours and things like that. I think this will serve to sustain me.

I’m nearly through consuming all the vegetables from my summer garden. I need to plant a winter garden soon…but that won’t suffice for this six-week budgeting experience. Therefore I expect that some of the weekly shopping money will be spent on vegetables. I’ll also need to buy tortillas, though if need be I can make them.

One thing I’m giving up entirely is bread. All it does is make me fat and fill me with candida. It may be the primary reason why I’ve had trouble losing weight. Whoever said bread is the“staff of life”really hooked me. All these years I thought of bread as essential…but no more. The supermarket here sells quality bread (the only kind I’d eat) for $4.50 a loaf. Obviously that will be too much for my $5 per week food budget. I’d rather spend my money on other things.

Another thing I’ll have to give up is my beloved Clif Bars. I’ve been buying them for breakfasts and snacks for a couple years now, and I’ll sure miss them. But at $1.50 a pop, I just can’t afford them now. I’ll probably make myself bowls of oatmeal to get the same effect without the high cost.

I’ll post my results after my first weekly shopping trip.

Oh, I also should mention—I will no longer go into town more often than once weekly to pick up mail and get groceries. Staying away from shopping areas is sure to help keep me from spending money!

…

Now for a word on what I’m eating today. I recently bought a rice steamer and I’m just loving it! I make brown rice with lentils (2 cups rice, one cup lentils) in the bottom of the steamer and put vegetables in the steamer tray on top. This week the veggies were potatoes and carrots. I take the resulting rice/lentils/veggies and fry them in a bit of olive oil, adding garlic powder, pepper, turmeric and ginger. This goes into a warm tortilla with fresh diced onion and a bit of hot sauce. A delicious, healthy and filling meal. Very vegan!

Similar Posts:

 Dinner for Breakfast Hummus Food Withdrawals, the $5 Food Budget’s Scourge Learning to Cook What is Starvation, and Why Should We Care? 


 budget food groceries saving money shopping Tagged with: budget • food • groceries • saving money • shopping 
  If you enjoyed this article, please consider sharing it! 
7 Responses to Eating on Only Five Dollars a Week 

 angel montoyo says: Monday, November 16, 2009 at 10:33 am 
Wow! this is a very tight budget…
Well good for you since you were able to manage having that kind of lifestyle and if I were in your situation maybe I get myself killed because I am a very ambitious person and I love shopping so this won’t work for me. Great work you have a very healthy lifestyle.
 Reply John leo says: Thursday, November 19, 2009 at 8:36 am 
This is a nice way to save money and lose weight, I think I am a little fat, so maybe I will have a try on this.
 Reply tommy says: Thursday, December 3, 2009 at 5:04 am 
seriously?
i cannot imagine live like that.
but if you satisfied with that condition i think it’s ok.
for my self i think it’s really difficult because i don’t like vegetables.
but great tips keep writing!
 Reply Chaz says: Tuesday, December 15, 2009 at 1:00 pm 
Wow! Do you have an updated post? I would love to hear how you are doing with this and what has been the hardest part.
 Reply eve says: Sunday, February 28, 2010 at 9:59 am 
life is getting very difficult these days and definitely your post is helping .it’s the king of things we need to read
 Reply Carolin says: Monday, July 18, 2011 at 7:16 am 
It’s a good way to save money but kinda hard to stay vegan 
 Reply Tom B. says: Monday, May 28, 2012 at 5:43 am 
5 dollars a week? I wonder is it possible to eat healthy and cheap.
 Reply 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 
 
 
To receive site update notifications via email, enter your email address:

 
 
 Delivered by FeedBurner 
 
About Me
 This is the journal of a kitchen philosopher queen wannabe.

A wannabe is a person who aspires to be something she is not. I&apos;m not a queen.. but I am a philosopher!

I&apos;m Linda Jo Martin, a natural foods vegetarian and herbalist living in a remote location in the Northern California mountains.

I write here about food, herbs, and my philosophy of life in these perilous times. 
My novel…
	</body>
</document>
