<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002072" url="http://cqder.com/lace/lace-doily.php" time="2012-07-12-17:58" support="18" score="0.0205097117145061" bingtitle="Lace Doily Answers and News" webtitle="Lace Doily Answers and News">
			<query id="000616" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="000210" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000522" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000553" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000179" bing-rank="141"/>
			<query id="001338" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000931" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="001401" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000773" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000148" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="001181" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="001024" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000868" bing-rank="230"/>
			<query id="001244" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001433" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000993" bing-rank="180"/>
			<query id="001276" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000428" bing-rank="160"/>
	<description>... dime store chocolates and dinner at a fast food restaurant? ... Aquarius: Manufactured holidays aren&apos;t your cup of ... results contain multi-variation listings, the item ...</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to Lace Doily
 
 Lace Home Sitemap 
 
Lace Doily Questions and Answers




Resolved Question: Having a 1900s themed wedding. Which fabric should I choose to use to ring pillows/flower girl basket etc:?
EyeletLaceDoilyWhich would best suit my wedding theme. Thanks :D  more 


Resolved Question: Can you use the doily method of crocheting to make a lace headband?
Let me clarify i want to make a lace headband but all of the lace headband tutorials ive read say that you need to know how to tat to make the headband. All i know is how to crochet and i have made doilys before using crochet. So is there anyway to use crocheting to make a headband that looks similar to lace. I hope this makes sense and let me know if it doesnt. Thanks in advance!  more 


Resolved Question: Please review my short story and give title suggestions!?
I wrote this story for a competition. I would like reviews before i send it in. I thank you in advance for taking the time out to do this. Also, title suggestions would be niceStory:There used to be a Caroline in school.Shy, bubbly, and innocent; a quiet girl with big eyes and long, blond curls. Her mother donned her in light pink bows and baby frills. She lived upon the grace of air, frothy and light, skimming the boarder of endearing and childlike.There was an Evangeline in school, in which everyone envied. They called her Eve, and her walk almost beckoned trouble of a family sort. Eyes would glance at her as she sauntered down the hall, smiling and waving. She wore the colors of winter. She was not shy with her ample curves. Gleaming blonde silk draped over bare shoulders and cascaded down her back. She drew in crowds.The block with the cracked sidewalks where Caroline came home to made an effort to appear welcoming. The iron railing seemed to say&quot;character,&quot;rather than&quot;rusted,&quot;although rusted is what they were. The ivy climbing the buildings said&quot;hidden garden,&quot;rather than&quot;untended.&quot;To Caroline, she lived in a dollhouse, charming and quaint. Evangeline lived with her aunt and uncle on a tree lined street, in a neighborhood where the soft smell of blossoms and cut grass filled the air. Children played in gymnasiums and dance studios in town, rather than in their perfectly manicured yards. After school, one could hear clumsy fingers practicing piano while parents took their brandies  in the study. She wondered who watched the children while adults attended cocktail parties and hosted dinner guests.Caroline read and spent hours studying paintings in books. She listened to a classical music and preferred a lace doily under the tea and sweets her mother prepared for her every afternoon. Evangeline could often be found driving with her convertible top down, surrounded by other girls blasting raunchy music. At night, she danced until she fell, laughing and later going to get greasy burgers at all night diners with friends. There was a man in town. The next week, there was not a man in town. There was also one less girl in school. She laid, with her long blonde hair covering her bruised arms, in a field covered by underbrush and debris, only to be found later by boys carrying badges and guns.  more 


Resolved Question: I need help finding my dream dress!?
The budget is 1800 or less. The wedding is going to be outdoors in the appalachin mountains in spring. the theme/style of the wedding is vintage romantic gardeny, for example the tables will be draped with vintage floral tablecloths and crocheted doilies and and antique lace runners, with mix matched antique/vintage china and crystal goblets with lace hankies and napkins, the center pieces are going to be mason jars filled with wildflowers and one of the planned acivities is catching fireflies. The dress needs to fit in with the style of the wedding. If I could describe the perfect dress I would say : Light, comfortable, flowing, little to no poof, with a long trailing train, fairy-esque, not a bright white, maybe a blush or antique-y yellowed look just something that would be perfect for a garden wedding and a reception lit by candlelight and fireflies............Thank you for any help! Remember the budget is 1800 or less, (preferably less) Oh and I am petite, 5&apos;3 slender 32bust 27waist 31hips if that helps, in dresses I usually buy a size 2, but 4&apos;s usually fit pretty well too.  more 


Voting Question: What kind of fabric is this?
It looks like crocheted/lace but its much thicker, and made of polyester or cotton, almost doily-like! but enough to make a whole dress... Could anyone tell me what the name of this kind of fabric is?  more 


Resolved Question: Furniture Help with type of resin?
I would like to take a beat up table and sand it down and paint it. That, I can do. But then I want to take a pretty lace doily (not sure of spelling) and put it on the top and coat it completely with some type of clear resin that allows for seeing it but can be wiped down and cleaned easily. A resin that hardens completely sealing the lace thingy in. What do I use? And how do I use it? Do I have to put something on the edges of the table before pouring the resin so it doesn&apos;t drip down? And what do I put that can be removed? Any experts out there willing to help me?  more 


Resolved Question: does this make me gay?
i like to have kinkie sex with hairy men in public rest areas but when i go home at knight i enjoy making lace doily&apos;s for the baptist church bingo and craft jamboree  more 


Voting Question: Where can you buy Lace Doilies?
  more 


Resolved Question: Why did Watson ask Holmes - Does your depravity know no bounds ?
Why did Watson ask Holmes - Does your depravity know no bounds when he was repeating the words lace doilies from the gypsy  more 


Resolved Question: Would you lovely people care to read this excerpt?
I am perhaps a little.... tripped, but perhaps not, also.It was pure euphoria that floated through the room. Touching each guest on the shoulder with whelm, entering their bodies at such potency and embedding their minds with bliss. As the guests made an entrance into Fern’s cosy warren, their eyes filled with wonder. She had out-done herself this time; the tea party looked magnificent. In the small circular room that hid under the grounds of an autumn-bound forest, not a nook had been forgotten in the organisational embellishment of the party. Silk scarves were laced over every shining lamp, casting colourful shadows onto the walls. The walls in which were painted – just for the occasion – in blue and yellow and silver swirls. A long oak table was covered by an over-sized doily. Miss-matched patterned tea-cups sat on it, and warm cakes emitted their scent into the room. Fern swayed in the middle of the room, her dress fanning out in an enchanting circle around her. She smiled at the people as they came near, but made no attempt to talk. Her socks were pulled past her knees and a small feather danced on top of her head. A pink and white teacup was dangling from her pinkie.  more 


Resolved Question: Good names for a 13 year olds craft/sewing/life blog?
I think I&apos;m going to start a craft/sewing/life blog. I was thinking of calling it sunshine girl in kinda curly looPy yellow letters with a sun in the background and the rest of the page to match but I think I can be more creative. Any ideas? my personality is quirky, fun, loving, I&lt;3 lace, and other cute vintage things (doilies too!). I&lt;3 my fam and church fam and want my blog to be cute! Thanks!  more 


Resolved Question: A poem about the poetry section...?
Little lace doilies and a cuppa-cuppa teaor coffee and cigarettes, fine by me.Lost love ripped and hearts in a vise.Strangers in alleys rolling the dice.Feelings and emotions and a vivid brushor desolate rancor with spirits to crush.You get all kinds here at poetry squareWon&apos;t be long before your losing your hair.  more 


Resolved Question: I am looking for a knitted lace pattern for a last name wall hanging.?
My husbands grandmother made him a doily looking wall hanging with our last name. She passed away and my brother in law wants one. I am not sure if it is knit or crochet but I know how to knit. Can anyone help me locate a pattern for a knitted lace alphabet hanging?  more 


Resolved Question: Not so nice to my dad, will you C/C please?
Paper laceNo toiled over lace doilieswhere I was allowed to placea cup, a drink, offered in fearOh my dear you had a spill.Not so much grams greatest thrillbut loved all the same.No blame placed, I heardin whispered words, ashamed.&quot;She&apos;s just a child,treat her so, nurture, she will grow.Things can be replacedbut mirror her fears and smileson your loving face.How can she know, she has more to liveYou my son have more to give.Admonish if you mustbut promise not to punishshow her the ways to grow,never strike a blowBe now loving and foreverdon&apos;t use history as a lever.You loved her, left hershe has returnedsalve with herthose scarring burns.&quot;He knows all thisYowee no and he is forgiven.  more 


Resolved Question: Suppose a soccer coach has been make up $25,000 per year but give ups his coaching job in order to make lace..?
..doilies. If his revenue from the sale of there doilies is $50,000 and his materials cost $20,000, then his economic profit is..?A) 5,000B) 25,000C) 30,000D) 50,000E) 80,000  more 


Resolved Question: any one know how to get sensi wax out of an old laced doily?
  more 


Resolved Question: The lilacs are blooming, can&apos;t you smell them? C/C?
Lilac ScentsYes it’s that lilac time again.You know spring is not official till lilacs waft their scent on airand open their souls to your eyes.Memories flood with each whiff;memories of lace and doilies and Grandma’s hug, (one always got a hug),and even the lilac water on her dresser.Yes, bouquets too, seemingly every table.Grandma, loved, lilacs-- best you did too,although I don’t know about Grandpa,but then I don’t think he was as gruffas seemed….maybe the lilacs softened himor was it Grandma’s own ‘lilac’ scent?My stalker is here again, now 67 blocks. For someone who claims he doesn&apos;t like my poetry....?  more 


Resolved Question: What are those lace doily hats people wear to church called?
Me and my mom found one in her closet and basically its like a little black round doily and she can&apos;t remember if they just called them doilies or if they had a name. its a hat. plz ty :D  more 


Resolved Question: YO Lace Knitting Doily?
In this pattern:Row 1: * YO, K1 *Row 2: KnitRow 3: * YO twice, K2 *Etc.. When I just got done doing YO&apos;s and I am on a new row and I have to knit that whole row, I notice very weak yarn from the previous row or yarning over... that I can either let that yarn off the needle or go under it to knit it...My question is:.am I knitting each and every single yarn strand I see? Or am I making sure to keep the yarn with the yarn overs I previously did? This is so hard to explain but perhaps someone knows what I am talking about....I took two photos of what I am talking about if you need me to email it to you! Thank you for any help !!  more 


Resolved Question: What&apos;s wrong with this lemon-oatmeal cookie recipe -- they come out like lace doilies?
Lemon Oatmeal Cookies1/2-cup shortening1-cup sugar1/2-cup brown sugar1-egg1-tsp lemon rind1/4-cup lemon juice3/4-cup flour1/2-tsp baking soda1/2-tsp salt1-1/2-cups rolled oatsCream shortening and white sugar, and then add brown sugar&amp;mixAdd egg, and beat until lightAdd lemon rind&amp;juicesSift flour, baking soda, and saltAdd gradually to creamed mixtureMix in rolled oatsDrop onto greased cookie sheetBake in 375* oven for 10-12 minutesMakes 5 dozenI tried adding 1/2 cup flour and 1/2 tsp baking powder, and it barely helped. I&apos;m freezing the mixture. What can I do to save it?  more 


Resolved Question: HELP! I need to find my own style!?
I&apos;d really like to have my own style! I&apos;m definitely not goth because I hate black. I&apos;m not country, either. Please suggest a style for me! I like colors like white and peachy pink, summer colours like soft orange and yellow, and I like unique items. I also like French-Vintage things like chaise longues, baby pink and baby blue colors, doilies, and white lace. I also use the French word Moi alot. Please help me find my own fashion style! It would be great if you could also include some photos of the style!  more 


Resolved Question: is paper doily the same thing as paper lace? NEEDED QIUCK?
  more 


Resolved Question: How do I clean antique lace such as doilies, tablecloths ,etc?
  more 


Resolved Question: What would be a great and appropriate crocheted lace choker pattern for this centerpiece?
It is a Celtic Dragonfly Y necklace centerpiece. Here is the link, scroll down till you see it, article # 0612.http://www.silverenchantments.com/celtic-druid-charms-pendants_pg2.htmlI have all kinds of colors available to me, and want to stay away from black,red,white or pink, as I have made several chokers in those colors already. Since it is a good-sized piece, I am unsure if I should use an elaborate pattern or a simple one. I am thinking that I should use a Celtic crochet pattern, but those are very large,and often used for doilies/ flowers.help ! Thank you for taking the time to read and answer my questrion !Wren, you are a genius ! I had forgotten that dragonflies are of the air AND water, and their elements are both. I now have the colors I am going to work with: both Air and water elements. Great job,Wren! I had totally forgotten about that,as i was so concentrating on the pattern,and not the important thing: The color correspondents. Thank you so much for reminding me,Wren! You are a genius ! :) ( love ya!)  more 


Resolved Question: Ok, im studying Wicca?
so im reading this book by Thea Sabin called Wicca for Beginners and im in the part where it begins talking about Altar surfaces and the Covering and Paraphernalia. It says that you can use extra fabrics, or tablecloths, or even leave it as is and paint symbols on it. Then it says&quot;You could even use your grandmother&apos;s lace doilies, as long as you&apos;re not building an altar to a deity like Thor or Aries.&quot;What I dont get is why. It doesnt explain why. Which leads me to another question, are there specifications to all altars to every God or Goddess in honor?Thanks for your help  more 


Resolved Question: need a painting technique!?
i would like to put a patterned look on my wall, paint it to make it look like lace. the only way i know to do this would be to put a doily or something on the wall and apply paint over it. this is not the method i want to use, does anyone have any better ideas?  more 


Resolved Question: What&apos;s mean&quot;to despicable sub-John Gielgud gestures of amazement&quot;?
Hello~I am a Korean..I read an article..by the way, i can&apos;t understand the meaning of&quot;to despicable sub-John Gielgud gestures of amazement&quot;What is that mean?whole article is below.Is Susan Boyle ugly? Or are we? On Saturday night she stood on the stage in Britain&apos;s Got Talent; small and rather chubby, with a squashed face, unruly teeth and unkempt hair. She wore a gold lace dress, which made her look like a piece of pork sitting on a doily. Interviewed by Ant and Dec beforehand, she told them that she is unemployed, single, lives with a cat called Pebbles and has never been kissed. Susan then walked out to chatter, giggling, and a long and unpleasant wolf whistle.Why are we so shocked when&quot;ugly&quot;women can do things, rather than sitting at home weeping and wishing they were somebody else? Men are allowed to be ugly and talented. Alan Sugar looks like a burst bag of flour. Gordon Ramsay has a dried-up riverbed for a face. Justin Lee Collins looks like Cousin It from The Addams Family. Graham Norton is a baboon in mascara. I could go on. But a woman has to have the bright, empty beauty of a toy - or get off the screen. We don&apos;t want to look at you. Except on the news, where you can weep because some awful personal tragedy has befallen you.Simon Cowell, now buffed to the sheen of an ornamental pebble, asked this strange creature, this alien, how old she was.&quot;I&apos;m nearly 47,&quot;she said. Simon rolled his eyes until they threatened to roll out of his head, down the aisle and out into street.&quot;But that&apos;s only one side of me,&quot;Susan added, and wiggled her hips. The camera cut to the other male judge, Piers Morgan, who winced. Didn&apos;t Susan know she was not supposed to be sexual? The audience&apos;s reaction was equally disgusting. They giggled with embarrassment, and when Susan said she wanted to be a professional singer, the camera spun to a young girl, who seemed to be at least half mascara.She gave an&quot;As if!&quot;squeak and smirked. Amanda Holden, the female judge, a woman with improbably raised eyebrows and snail trails of Botox over her perfectly smooth face, chose neutrality. And then Susan sang. She stood with her feet apart, like a Scottish Edith Piaf, and very slowly began to sing Les Miserables&apos;I Dreamed A Dream. It was wonderful.The judges were astonished. They gasped, they gaped, they clapped. They looked almost ashamed. I was briefly worried that Simon might stab himself with a pencil, and mutter,&quot;Et tu, Piers, for we have wronged Susan in thinking that because she is a munter, she is entirely useless.&quot;How could they have misjudged her, they gesticulated. But how could they not? No makeup? Bad teeth? Funny hair? Is she insane, this sad little Scottish spinster, beloved only of Pebbles the Cat?When Susan had finished singing, and Piers had finished gasping, he said this. It was a comment of incredible spite.&quot;When you stood there with that cheeky grin and said,&apos;I want to be like Elaine Paige&apos;, everyone was laughing at you. No one is laughing now.&quot;And it was over to Amanda Holden, a woman most notable for playing a psychotic hairdresser in the Manchester hair-extensions saga Cutting It.&quot;I am so thrilled,&quot;said Amanda,&quot;because I know that everybody was against you.&quot;&quot;Everybody was against you,&quot;she said, as if Susan might have been hanged for her presumption. Why? Can&apos;t&quot;ugly&quot;people dream, you flat-packed, hair-ironed, over-plucked monstrous fool?I know what you will say. You will say that Paul Potts, the fat opera singer with the equally squashed face who won Britain&apos;s Got Talent in 2007, had just as hard a time at his first audition. I looked it up on YouTube. He did not.&quot;I wasn&apos;t expecting that,&quot;said Simon to Paul.&quot;Neither was I,&quot;said Amanda.&quot;You have an incredible voice,&quot;said Piers. And that was it. No laughter, or invitations to paranoia, or mocking wolf-whistles, or smirking, or derision.We see this all the time in popular culture. Do you ever stare at the TV and wonder where the next generation of Judi Denchs and Juliet Stevensons have gone? Have they fallen down a Rada wormhole? Yes. They&apos;re not there, because they aren&apos;t pretty enough to get airtime. This lust for homogeneity in female beauty means that when someone who doesn&apos;t resemble a diagram in a plastic surgeon&apos;s office steps up to the microphone, people fall about and treat us to despicable sub-John Gielgud gestures of amazement.Susan will probably win Britain&apos;s Got Talent. She will be the little munter that could sing, served up for the British public every Saturday night. Look! It&apos;s&quot;ugly&quot;! It sings! And I know that we think that this will make us better people. But Susan Boyle will be the freakish exception that makes the rule. By raising this Susan up, we will forgive ourselves for grinding every other Susan into the dust. It will be a very partial and poisoned redemption. Because Britain&apos;s Got Malice. Sing, Susan, sing - to an ugly crowd that doesn&apos;t deserve you.Hello~I am 24 n Korean.I read an article..by the way, i can&apos;t understand the meaning of&quot;to despicable sub-John Gielgud gestures of amazement&quot;could you explain about that plz?thank you:)What is that mean?We see this all the time in popular culture. Do you ever stare at the TV and wonder where the next generation of Judi Denchs and Juliet Stevensons have gone? Have they fallen down a Rada wormhole? Yes. They&apos;re not there, because they aren&apos;t pretty enough to get airtime. This lust for homogeneity in female beauty means that when someone who doesn&apos;t resemble a diagram in a plastic surgeon&apos;s office steps up to the microphone, people fall about and treat us to despicable sub-John Gielgud gestures of amazement.  more 


Resolved Question: Would you like to run a tea shop?
with lace tablecloths, cream teas, cake stands, doilies, gingham curtains, white painted furniture,and hungry customers.I would.  more 


Resolved Question: My husband and I agreed to not spend money and make Valentines this year, anything cute to say?
I have red paper and heart shaped lace doilies and I want to say something clever.Anything clever aside from the usual stuff?Nothing X rated please, just maybe cute and funny.  more 


Resolved Question: I have an old homemade butterfly that I want to put up for a keepsake, but want to protect it.?
I made a butterfly in a class back in jr. high, you figure I&apos;m 33 now! The butterfly is made out of a firm cut up doily with some lace for bows as well. It&apos;s definitely seen its day and needs to be dusted off but I think it&apos;s time for it to be retired. How can I make sure that it will okay stored in an attic, and what can I store it with or in? Also some ideas on dusting would be great. At its age I think its probably fragile.  more 


Resolved Question: linear life.......................?
Im doing a project called&quot;linear life&quot;this is documenting anything line based in peoples day to day life.i would greatly appreciate input in this.examples of what people may say:Sales Assistant: barcodeOffice clerk: pinstripe suitPostman: railingsOld lady: Lace Doilyanything that springs to mind would be great thank you in advance  more 


Resolved Question: so what&apos;s linear in you life?
Im doing a project called&quot;linear life&quot;this is documenting anything line based in peoples day to day life.i would greatly appreciate input in this.examples of what people may say:Sales Assistant: barcodeOffice clerk: pinstripe suitPostman: railingsOld lady: Lace Doilyanything that springs to mind would be great thank you in advance  more 


Resolved Question: what do you see in your typical day?
Im doing a project called&quot;linear life&quot;this is documenting anything line based in peoples day to day life.i would greatly appreciate input in this.examples of what people may say:Sales Assistant: barcodeOffice clerk: pinstripe suitPostman: railingsOld lady: Lace Doilyanything that springs to mind would be great thank you in advance  more 


Resolved Question: How to clean/restore old lace doilies?
I believe my great grandma made them. They&apos;re in pretty good shape, but need cleaning. Because of age I&apos;m wondering how to clean them without them falling apart.Thanks!  more 


Resolved Question: How can I display antique lace + antique crochet doilies?
I have boxes full of my great grandmothers, grandmothers, and mothers yellowing laceand have accumulated quite a bit in my travels...I guess I&apos;m a&quot;collector&quot;, do you know of any unique ways of displaying them?  more 


Resolved Question: Crocheters, I am thankful for every ounce of info I can collect on crochet, how do you keep up with your info?
I have two books 3 1/2 inches thick, the other is 2 1/2 inches thick and has pages of photographs, I do my own stitch, graph and symbol art in crochet, I put doily or lace and others type patterns into art.I like to see those who crochet and knit, do the same thing using a different way, it is so interesting.  more 


Resolved Question: Does anyone have the recipe for lace cookies?
As they are baked they become flat and bubbles form and pop causing that&quot;lace&quot;effect. Kind of like a doily  more 


Resolved Question: valentine for every sign?
Does February 14 fill you with feelings of cheer or fear? Each Sun Sign has a different way of responding to this romantic holiday. Find out how your Sign handles this much-anticipated day of flowery poems, chocolate hearts and red roses.Aries: You&apos;re determined to receive the most cards, candy and flowers. Who says sending roses to yourself doesn&apos;t count?Taurus: A bouquet of dandelions, dime store chocolates and dinner at a fast food restaurant? Relax, it was just a bad dream!Gemini: You make two dates for the night -- and then backup plans with your friends in case you decide to flake on your original plans.Cancer: Ooh, there&apos;s nothing like candy heart art and lace doilies to get you going! Martha Stewart&apos;s got nothing on you.Leo: You are displeased by the single red rose some admirer left on your windshield. Clearly you are worth at least a dozen!Virgo: You refuse to share the box of chocolates you receive -- what if someone fingers them? What if someone sneezes on your roses?Libra: You send valentines to everyone you know: your hairdresser, your fourth grade teacher, your manicurist, your manicurist&apos;s cousin … You don&apos;t want anyone to feel left out.Scorpio: Why go out for a fancy dinner when you already have dessert waiting at home? Who knew that a Cupid costume could be so sexy?Sagittarius: You can&apos;t commit to sending a card -- what if the recipient reads too much into it? You fake temporary amnesia to avoid acknowledging the holiday.Capricorn: Lacy hearts and syrupy sentiments make you sneeze -- besides, nothing says love like a new electronic organizer!Aquarius: Manufactured holidays aren&apos;t your cup of decaffeinated herbal tea, but consuming a few vegan chocolates doesn&apos;t make you a conformist, does it?Pisces: You live for this stuff! The world would be such a better place if we could all just hold hands and share heart-shaped cookies every day.http://www.astrology.com/fun/valentines.html  more 


Resolved Question: Should there be a blindfold included?
I went in the Pound Shop for some paper doilies and saw they are selling red lace trimmed metal handcuffs c/w with tickling stick for Valentine&apos;s Day. Aren&apos;t you supposed to guess who sent your Valentine?  more 


Resolved Question: do you have a joke like this about your race?
You may be married to a Filipina if . . .your refrigerator is always full but you cannot find any food that you recognize.instead of a dowry, you got the whole bill for the wedding and honeymoon.most of the decorations in your house are made of wicker.you are expected to be able to read her mind just by watching her eyebrows move up and down and which way her lips are pointed.all her relatives think your name is Joe.the instant you are married you have 3000 new close relatives that you can&apos;t tell apart.your house isn&apos;t really on fire, but there is a very charred fish right on top of the stove burner.all the desserts are sticky and all the snacks are salty.she eats her fruit with giant salt crystals and her fried chicken with ketchup.even the ketchup tastes weird . . . very weird.you throw a party and everyone is fighting to chop the leathery skin off a dead pig.all your kids have 4-5 middle names.*your in-laws take 10 years to acknowledge your existence and to call you by something other than&quot;that white guy.&quot;you try to call her up on the phone and someone tells you&quot;for a while&quot;and you want to know&quot;for a while, what??&quot;you are trying to go to sleep and she keeps asking for the comFORT&apos;r, and you ain&apos;t got a clue what she&apos;s talking about . . .your first Christmas present is some funny looking baggy see-thru shirt made out of leftover lace doilies.your phone bills are all international and average 3 hours per call.she sweeps with something that witches usually fly around on.her idea of classy, expensive champagne is Asti Spumantethe rice cooker is on 24 hours a day and uses up 50% of your electric and food budget.on your first trip to the Philippines, you have 18 giant boxes that weigh 1000 pounds each and your&quot;carry on&quot;luggage requires a small forklift truck.the same luggage is over filled with things that cost an average of 15 cents each like old magazines and M&amp;Ms -- the worst part is when you get off the plane, the same stuff you&apos;ve been hauling around half way around the world is available in every store in the airport for half the price!all her pajamas look like they were worn by the Dalai Lama until they got too faded.the first time she&apos;s pregnant you have to go out at 4:00 in the morning looking for some weird type of greasy sausages, green mangoes and bagoong.You buy a new $500 freezer so she can store 200 pounds of SPAM and CORNED BEEF that was on sale.everything in your house was bought on sale, even if you don&apos;t need it .. as long as it was a&quot;bargain&quot;is all that matters.she gets really excited by sucking the fat out of pig knees.your daughter gets her ears pierced when she&apos;s 2 minutes old but your sons are not circumcised until they turn 21.all your postage bills instantly double.you hire a yaya because your wife thinks you clean mirrors with soap and a sponge and the yaya seems cheaper than a divorce.the only&quot;white meat&quot;she likes is You, and that&apos;s if you&apos;re lucky . . .her favorite sauce is called patis, Americans call it turpentine.she actually thinks that bowling and golf and billiards are real sports and are more important than baseball and football.you were married 5 years before she explained to you that&quot;ARAY!&quot;doesn&apos;t mean&quot;ooh, baby!&quot;she prefers bistek to beef steak.her idea of new upholstery is rinsing the bagoong stains out of the slip covers.she can eat and talk at the same time, in fact that&apos;s her especialty!her favorite meal is leftovers, her favorite fancy dessert is Jello mold and for something REALLY romantic, she&apos;ll offer you a halo-halo with 2 straws.you still don&apos;t know what&apos;s the difference between manong and manok.she and the kids are always saying&quot;Daddy made utot&quot;and you still don&apos;t know what it means but they think it&apos;s pretty funny.other than eyebrow raising and lip puckering, her next most expressive form of communication is grunts and pssst&apos;sshe goes to the movies just for the AC.her homeland has more Megamalls than islands.before every holiday and visit, her sisters fax you a 10 page&quot;bilin&quot;list which says&quot;suggestion only.&quot;your kitchen table has a merry-go-round in the middle.all the vegetables she buys at the Filipino store look like they were grown at Chernobyl.your in-law&apos;s first visit lasted 5 years.her friends are named Chinky, Girlie, Boy and Bimbo and you are not allowed to smirk.her home economics course only taught shopping, eating and siesta; cooking, cleaning and sewing were not electives.her idea of edifying reading is gossip magazines.all your place settings has the silverware backwards and there are no knives.she washes her hair with a bucket and her car with a broom.she uses an umbrella even if its not raining.her favorite book (she has 3 copies) is&quot;1001 New Recipes for Pig Parts You Were Gonna Throw Out&quot;you are the only family in a 200 mile radius with 2 VCRs, 3 televisions.she&apos;s done her best job planning a surprise party for you if she manages not to tell you about it until a week or two before.she&quot;cleans&quot;her closet by throwing all the crap into your closet.AND LAST BUT NOT LEAST: you are pretty proud of yourself because you think you snagged up for yourself some unique, rare, tropical goddess type until you go to the Philippines and can&apos;t tell her apart from anyone else in the whole country (unless she&apos;s taller than 5&apos;1&quot;, then it&apos;s a bit easier).BONUS ENCORE: it was your wife&apos;s idea for you to write this cause she thought it was funny . . . for a while though until the list got TOO LONG!!!= = = = = = = =i dont have a wifeim a girl  more 


Resolved Question: Are there any cars or SUV&apos;s with Air Conditioning filters that can be cleaned regularly by owner.?
I want a vehicle with superb Air-Conditioning, with hepa filters and the whole 9 yards. I also want to be able to change the filters myself, preferably wash them instead of having to buy a $99 filter the size of my grandmother&apos;s laced tea doily.any suggestions??Thanks for thoughful answers.No dopey answers please.  more 


Resolved Question: Are there any cars or SUV&apos;s with Air Conditioning filters that can be cleaned regularly by owner.?
I want a vehicle with superb Air-Conditioning, with hepa filters and the whole 9 yards. I also want to be able to change the filters myself, preferably wash them instead of having to buy a $99 filter the size of my grandmother&apos;s laced tea doily.any suggestions??Thanks for thoughful answers.No dopey answers please.  more 


Resolved Question: What is the deal with Walter Mercado?
Really....the guy claims to have a wife, who really appears to be his secretary/assistant, and he wears tons of makeup and these frilly, tacky, getups that can only be described as a cross between Buck Rodgers, Liberace, the Pope, all involved in a terrible explosion in a Lace Doily Factory.Can you tell me...is this guy really eccentric, or is this an act imposed upon him by a crazy producer?Who makes this guys clothing? His wife/assistant? He seems like he is really sexual, in a heterosexual sense, but also looks like he is into crossdressing. I don&apos;t understand his selling point, and tend to ignore what he is saying because I can&apos;t get over what he looks like!Someone please help me with this.  more 


Resolved Question: I made a lace doily for open class competition at the county fair- how should it be displayed?
Should it be mounted on a mat or framed? Or should it just be the doily alone? The rule book didn&apos;t have any guidelines for display.  more 


Resolved Question: Cottage and Victorian, Can they live in harmony?
I am wanting to decorate my house with rose patterned dinnerware, and beautiful mahogany wood table, but I also love painted wainscotting, and big soft couches, lace, vintage floral, granny chic, doilies. Can they all work together? I also love embroidered things, and homemade stuff. And seasonal decorations. Can it work together? Can it be super casual but pretty at the same time?  more 


Resolved Question: Where can I buy lace doilies in London, UK?
I have an aunt who loves them for decoration and furniture protection. I would like to buy some nice ones as a gift. If anybody can help with known retailers in the London area it would be much appreciated.  more 


Resolved Question: Do you know people other than Grandmas like lace doilies?
Lace decor that is considered beautiful, such as Heritage Lace from websites all over the internet, is really gorgeous and easy care for those of us that dont like to do much with laundry. Check out US brand name lace decor, that has nothing to do with Grandmas old world taste in lace! It is of unique quality and style and yet very affordable.  more 


Resolved Question: how can I get candle wax off my my lace doily? Very thick and will not peel off or chip off.?
I placed a candle on my lace tablecloth, and the wax dripped all over it. It is very thick and will not scrape off. I&apos;m afraid to pull on it because it is lace with tiny holes. Does any one have an answer?  more 


Resolved Question: How do I clean my antique linens?
I have a pile of antique doilies/dresser scarves, some are linen, some have a finer weave, most are embroidered, some are trimmed in crocheted lace. All of them are yellowed (which doesn&apos;t bother me so much, they&apos;re freaking old), some have stains, all of them are permanently creased because they&apos;ve been folded so long, but they APPEAR structurally sound. What is the safest way to clean these poor things without damaging the main fabric or loosening the stitching in the embroidery/crochet?  more 
 
Lace Doily News


IMPORTANT: Bing News RSS feed has moved!
	</body>
</document>
