<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002161" url="http://blogs.miaminewtimes.com/shortorder/coming_attractions/" time="2012-07-12-18:03" support="1" score="0.002842923552802361" bingtitle="&quot;Coming Attractions&quot; Archives - Miami Restaurants and Dining ..." webtitle="&quot;Coming Attractions&quot; Archives - Miami Restaurants and Dining - Short Order">
			<query id="000104" bing-rank="185"/>
	<description>... and gift certificates to various dining places. The ... people getting out of work, you look at the number ... Salty American Fast Food; Restaurant No Shows; Eating House&apos;s New ...</description>
	<body>
		Blogs 
 Entire Site Articles&amp;Blogs Restaurants Places Events Music Images Ads Bars Best Of Movies 
 News Home Riptide Strouse Luke&apos;s Gospel Letters Special Reports Archives Search New Times Flipbook Weekly Newsletter Get Mobile Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads New Times Web Awards Music Home Crossfade Concert Calendar Bars and Clubs Brew at the Zoo Submit an Event Music Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurants Home Short Order Find a Restaurant Menus Iron Fork Happy Hours Dining Deals Dining Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurant Ads Arts Home Cultist Visual Arts Theater Welcome to the Future Skrawberry Jam Artopia Arts Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Film Home Showtimes Cultist Film Film Poll 2011 Film Newsletter Get Mobile Free Stuff Best Of Home 2012 2011 2010 2009 Readers&apos; Poll 2012 Best Of Newsletter Get Mobile Best Of Ads Promotions Home Promotional Events Street Team Free Stuff On Sale Promotions Newsletter Get Mobile Deals Post an Ad Jobs Real Estate Advertiser Index Deals Deals Newsletter Virtual Job Fair 
Top

blog

Stories
 
 
 Miami Spice 

 Gotham Steak Hakkasan, Scarpetta Miami Spice 

By Laine Doss
 
 Holidays 

 Bastille Day at Brand New Fabien&apos;s Bistro 

By Lee Klein
 
 Best of Miami 

 Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants 

By Laine Doss
 
 First Bites 

 Iron Side Cafe: Fresh New Lunch Spot 

By Lee Klein
 
 Gastronomic Gatherings 

 Fairchild Makes Mangoes Exciting This Weekend 

By Laine Doss
 
 Chef on the Small Screen 

 Eat St. to Film Food Trucks in Miami 

By Laine Doss
 
 Food Charity 

 Taste of the Nation Celebrates 25th Anniversary 

By Laine Doss
 
 Neighborhood Joints 

 Shack Shack In Coral Gables Opening Soon 

By Laine Doss
 
 News 

 Zeke&apos;s Reincarnated: Rio Station 

By Hannah Sentenac
 
 Fuming Foodie 

 Teacher Nailed for Horrible Behavior With Food&amp;Kids 

By Ily Goyanes
 
   Coming Attractions 
 B Hotel Releases Renderings, Details on Upcoming Downtown Miami, South Beach Locations 
 By Kareem Shaker Mon., Jun. 25 2012 at 8:51 AM Categories: Coming Attractions 
 Pin It 
 
 An artist&apos;s rendering of the planned b2 Hotel in downtown Miami. 
 No, that is not a misspelling in the headline. The folks over at B Hotels and Resorts have a goal -- for the letter &quot;B&quot; to be as familiar in front of the word hotel as the letter &quot;W.&quot;

The company&apos;s Broward location opened just 18 months ago on Sunrise and A1A, but they&apos;ve already become a local favorite. Now the hotel is plotting locations in downtown Miami and South Beach.

&quot;The B Hotel is a brand based on self-expression that seeks to be inclusive and not pretentious,&quot; said B Hotel senior vice president of marketing Chris Tompkins, who spent seven years as a cruise director for Princess Cruises. &quot;A 15-year-old will enjoy staying with us as much as a 30 or 60 year-old.&quot;
 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 B Hotels Write Comment Email to Friend Restaurant News 
 Hooters Swimsuit Pageant Coming to Fillmore Miami Beach June 23 
 By Kareem Shaker Thu., Jun. 14 2012 at 9:16 AM Categories: Coming Attractions , Restaurant News 
 Pin It 
 
 Lindsey Way of Fort Lauderdale won Miss Hooters International in 2011 
 Hooters, famous for chicken wings and hot chicks, will host the 16th Annual Hooters International Swimsuit Pageant at The Fillmore Miami Beach at the Jackie Gleason Theater June 23 at 10 p.m. The event will be broadcast on FX and to all Hooters restaurants live. Competing for a $50,000 first place prize are 101 Hooters girls selected from over 18,000 workers in 430 restaurants worldwide.

Contestants were chosen to represent their markets and home towns by competing in local swimsuit contests.
 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 Hooters , The Fillmore Write Comment Email to Friend Coming Attractions 
 Trump Closes Deal on Iconic Doral Golf Resort, Plans $200 Million Renovation 
 By Kareem Shaker Tue., Jun. 12 2012 at 2:34 PM Categories: Coming Attractions 
 Pin It 
 
 Wikimedia Commons 
 The first mention of the name Trump brings a certain level of respect and expectation. Donald Trump has a knack for turning everything he touches into gold or bankruptcy . Often, other companies buy just the name, and along with it comes the success. A set of esteemed buildings in North Miami Beach is a perfect example.

In October, Trump announced he would pursue the purchase of Miami&apos;s iconic Doral Golf Resort&amp;Spa . The deal closed Monday, and the Trump Hotel Collection (THC) took over operations.

&quot;Every year, my father and mother would take me to Doral for a weekend. It was the ultimate treat for me, it was beautiful,&quot; Trump recalled in a press release .
 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 Doral , Trump Write Comment Email to Friend Coming Attractions 
 All-You-Can-Eat Fried Chicken Returns to Michy&apos;s 
 By Lesley Elliott Wed., Jun. 6 2012 at 11:12 AM Categories: Coming Attractions , Delectable Deals 
 Pin It 
 
 Photo courtesy of Michy&apos;s 
 Starting one week from today, feed your fried chicken frenzy at Michy&apos;s ; it&apos;s officially back on the menu. A summer tradition that began in 2009, the Wednesday night endless fried chicken feast rewards locals for coming out to dinner during the off-season, and in addition to giving hump day cuisine meaning, it&apos;s made Michelle Bernstein&apos;s fried chicken kind of famous.

On one evening, a couple of tourists inquired meekly as to why it wasn&apos;t on the menu. Listening to the server explain that it was a) only during the summer, and b) only on Wednesdays, their expressions changed quickly. It was obviously a great disappointment, &quot;we we&apos;re so excited to try the chicken.&quot; The kitchen whipped up a couple of plates of fried bird anyways, and delivered it with all the fixins&apos; as usual. Satisfied customers and impressed onlookers alike reveled in the chicken. They offered a bite, we took it. We like people who share (and well behaved tourists).
 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 Michelle Bernstein , Michy&apos;s Write Comment Email to Friend Coming Attractions 
 MC Kitchen&apos;s Dena Marino On Modern Italian: Veal Ravioli, Wood-Burning Oven, and Charred Lasagna 
 By Lesley Elliott Fri., May 18 2012 at 9:10 AM Categories: Chef Interviews , Coming Attractions 
 Pin It 
 
 MC Kitchen/Facebook The Chef in her newly acquired kitchen. 
 Chef Dena Marino&apos;s newest restaurant venture, MC Kitchen in the Design District , has a restaurant mantra of &quot;local, seasonal, modern Italian.&quot;

Named for the chef and partner, Brandy Coletta, (thus the M and C in MC Kitchen), the idea simply began with a conversation between the two regarding Miami&apos;s cuisine scene. However, creation of the restaurant and concept was a little more complicated, requiring a six month location scouting process. Why did they ultimately choose the Fratelli Lyon space, and how did MC Kitchen come to be? Keep reading.

 New Times : Is this your first partnership with Coletta? Have you worked together before? 
 Dena Marino: This is our first partnership together, but we have known each other since
 Aspen, since Ajax Tavern. Brandy was the hostess when I first started as 
the chef there, she rocked the door, rocked the house, the place was 
insanely busy and had such a high volume of people coming in and out of 
the door, it was a lot of to handle. She went to school at UM, and 
always had a connection to Miami. We stayed in touch and she was excited 
when I moved here, she said to me, &quot;Let&apos;s do a project here, I feel that 
Miami would love to have your creative style of food and I feel that 
there is a niche for it.&quot;
 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 Dena Marino , Design District , Italian , MC Kitchen Write Comment Email to Friend Coming Attractions 
 MC Kitchen, Dena Marino&apos;s Modern Italian, To Replace Fratelli Lyon Soon 
 By Lesley Elliott Wed., May 16 2012 at 10:14 AM Categories: Coming Attractions , Restaurant Opening 
 Pin It 
 
 MC Kitchen/Facebook 
 Okay, &quot;soon&quot; may be an overstatement, but MC Kitchen is &quot;hopefully opening in early August,&quot; in the former Fratelli Lyon space , says executive chef Dena Marino. This leaves us happily anticipating the modern Italian cuisine of Marino and partner, Brandy Coletta. Their design takeover will replace the current modern aesthetic with a rustic setting. The glass wall will become solid, to create privacy from the surrounding kitchen and furniture stores; other changes include an open kitchen for chef spying, stone floors with wooden inlay, and a more intimate seating layout.

Most importantly, what can you expect to see on the table? We asked Chef Marino for the menu details, and although she was hesitant to give too much away, we cajoled her into revealing a little more information than has been previously released.
 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 Dena Marino , Fratelli Lyon , MC Kitchen Write Comment Email to Friend Coming Attractions 
 New at La Provence: Breads To Go, Salmon, Leek Quiche With Salad for $5.95 
 By Lesley Elliott Mon., May 14 2012 at 8:08 AM Categories: Coming Attractions 
 Pin It 
 
 Lesley Elliott Special orders now being accepting for freshly baked bread at La Provence. 
 La Provence is letting the public in on its commercial business. The bakery and café chain (with 9 locations including Brickell , Coral Gables and Doral ) is offering up the breads they bake daily for hotels and restaurants to their retail customers.

Most breads can be made with 24 or 48 hours notice and sent to any one 
of their retail stores, where buyers can pick them up.
There will be a new &quot;bread book&quot; at each location hat you can peruse -- and then decide upon a plan of attack. It&apos;s going to be hard to choose.

There are sticks shaped like little torpedoes studded with olives, sun-dried tomatoes or walnuts and raisins (we tried these freshly out of the oven, could have eaten a baker&apos;s dozen); and traditional white pave dinner rolls, sourdough, and whole wheat. Buns in both large and small size can be ordered plain, with sesame seeds or onions. Multigrain and white pullman loaves; brioche with and without raisins; ciabatta, French baguettes, focaccia...they&apos;ll even do special items for parties, like flat breads and twisted parmesan sticks.
 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 La Provence Write Comment Email to Friend Coming Attractions 
 Saturday&apos;s Brickell Fest: Luche Libre Wrestling, a Mechanical Bull, and Tequila 
 By Kareem Shaker Thu., May 3 2012 at 9:05 AM Categories: Coming Attractions 
 Pin It 
 
 BrickellFestival.com 
 Brickell is no longer just the largest concentration of international banks in the United States. As one of Miami&apos;s fastest-growing neighborhoods, the area just south of downtown draws many people to live, shop, eat and, or course, drink.

 Brickell Fest looks to take advantage of the area&apos;s growing popularity with a series of holiday celebrations, beginning with Saturday&apos;s free inaugural Cinco de Mayo celebration. It will last from noon to midnight in the parking lot located at 1001 S. Miami Ave.

&quot;We are really excited about working with businesses and members of the community to put together a celebration everyone can enjoy,&quot; says Dina Davis, marketing director for Vitamin C Communications .
 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 Brickell Fest , Cinco de Mayo , Mary Brickell Village Write Comment Email to Friend Coming Attractions 
 From French Toast to Kobe Filet, Villa Mayfair Launches Crazy Good Brunch Deal UPDATED 
 By Lesley Elliott Wed., May 2 2012 at 8:38 AM Categories: Coming Attractions , Delectable Deals 
 Pin It 
 
 Villa Mayfair Lobster and mango salad, one of the apps on the new brunch menu. 
 Beginning this Sunday, May 6, brunch takes on a whole new meaning at Villa Mayfair in Coconut Grove. Every single item on the menu can be mixed and matched to the tune of $28 in total. What does this mean exactly?

Here&apos;s the deal: whether you want french toast or a Kobe burger, you&apos;ll pay $28. In fact, you can have French toast AND a burger, AND a Bloody Mary. Or a Croque Madame. Or a club sandwich. Or tuna tartare. (Note: Since the time of the original posting, they have added an upcharge for menu items like lobster stuffed macaroni and the Kobe filet).

So if you want one entree and two drinks, it&apos;s $28. Three entrees? $28. An appetizer, entree and a cocktail? $28. Okay, you get it, right? We know it sounds redundant, but we love that this menu provides for a personalized dining experience. The deal is sort of a chef&apos;s tasting menu for Sunday brunch lovers, only you design the dish line-up.
 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 Villa Mayfair Write Comment Email to Friend Coming Attractions 
 Today: United Way Miami Wine&amp;Food Festival Kicks Off 17th Annual Edition 
 By Kareem Shaker Wed., Apr. 18 2012 at 9:48 AM Categories: Coming Attractions , Food Charity , Gastronomic Gatherings , News 
 Pin It 
 
 Courtesy of MWFF 
 
It might not have the swag or bravado of its nationally-recognized
cousin the South Beach Wine&amp;Food Festival, but the 17th annual edition of
the United Way Miami Wine&amp;Food Festival definitely has a lot to offer. Best
of all, and unlike SBWFF, proceeds go to a charity that strengthens the
community with programs designed to improve education, income, and health in
Southern Florida.

&quot;The UWMWFF brings together beer, spirits, wine and food
lovers for a spectacular four-day festival,&quot; the United Way said in a statement
on its website. &quot;It kicks off with a Best in Glass Month, top sommeliers,
notable chefs, prestigious wineries and winemakers, breweries and impressive
auction lots, all to benefit the South Florida community.&quot;

The festival runs from Wednesday, April 18 to Saturday,
April 21 in locations across South Florida. Here&apos;s a quick look at this year&apos;s
festivities.

 Best in Glass Month 
 March 12 - April 18 

A two-day full scale graded wine tasting competition was held at Miami Culinary Institute January 8 and 9, 2012 and judged by 18 of South Florida&apos;s top sommeliers. The sommeliers graded the wines and awarded the top entrants gold, silver or bronze medals. Wines are then featured at elite restaurants throughout the South Florida community. A complete list of sommeliers and participating restaurants can be found at the festival&apos;s website .

 More &gt;&gt; 
Tags:
 Fontainebleau , Mary Brickell Village , Merrick Park , United Way Miami Wine&amp;Food Festival Write Comment Email to Friend &lt;&lt;Previous Stories 
Now Trending


 
Sign up for free stuff, news info&amp;more!
 
Slide shows » 

 Closer Look: Villa Azur Closer Look: Josh&apos;s Delicatessen&amp;Appetizing Rock &apos;n&apos; Roll Beer-B-Que 2012 at Seminole Hard Rock Hotel&amp;Casino More Slideshows&gt;&gt; 
 
 Restaurants 
 
 
Lucky Clover
 View Ad | View Site 
Sweet Pointe Bakery&amp;Cafe
 View Ad | View Site 
Montes de Oca Original Pizza Cubana
 View Ad | View Site 
El Bajareque Restaurant
 View Ad | View Site 
 More &gt;&gt; 
Twitter Feed
 
 Follow short_order on Twitter 
 More Twitter &gt;&gt; 
Headlines from our Partners
 

 Summer Gold: Susser Talks Mangoes; London Burger King Installs a Damien Hirst Painting Boulud Hosting &quot;To Live and Dine in Miami&quot;; Balloo&apos;s Summer Additions at Sugarcane &quot;That Glow On The Beach&quot;: The 1950s Restaurants of 22nd Street Whiskey Joe&apos;s Set to Booze on Key Biscayne Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants; Watch an Ad For the Second Cheapest Wine Out There 
 
Links

Choice Eats

 All Purpose Dark ...And The Eggs Be A Wok Star
	</body>
</document>
