<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002820" url="http://www.prospects.ac.uk/types_of_jobs_hospitality.htm" time="2012-07-12-18:53" support="1" score="9.487488457325625e-05" bingtitle="Types of jobs: Hospitality and events management | Prospects.ac.uk" webtitle="Types of jobs: Hospitality and events management
            |
            
            Prospects.ac.uk">
			<query id="000244" bing-rank="244"/>
	<description>Fast food restaurant manager; Hotel manager; Public house manager ... will be able to view the content of this page in your current browser, you will not be able to get ...</description>
	<body>
		Accessibility links 

 Skip to main content Skip to site search Accessibility help 
 The UK&apos;s official graduate careers website 
 Log in to My Prospects 

 Register now to get personalised jobs, courses and careers advice  »
 Site search   Email address Password Remember me 
Not signed up?
 Register now Forgotten password?  »   
Main navigation

 Careers advice 
 Starting out CVs and covering letters Job application advice Interview tips Interview tests and exercises Job hunting Options with your subject What do graduates do? Using your language skills Country profiles Careers fairs Careers services 
 Jobs and work experience 
 Graduate job search Graduate employers Work experience and internships What jobs would suit me? Working abroad Industry insights Self-employment Flexible working Teaching advice Equal opportunities Types of jobs 
 Postgraduate study 
 Search courses and research Latest courses and bursaries Universities and departments About postgrad study Studying abroad Funding my further study 
 Job sectors 
 Armed forces and emergency services IT and information services Banking and finance Law Business and management Marketing, advertising and PR Charities and voluntary work Media and publishing Creative arts and culture Property and construction Energy and utilities Recruitment and HR Engineering and manufacturing Retail and sales Environment and agriculture Science and pharmaceuticals Government and public administration Teaching and education Health and social care Transport and logistics Hospitality, tourism and sport 
 Student life 
 Study advice Money Gap year City guides 
 International students 
 Working in the UK Working outside the UK Studying in the UK Featured courses 
 
 
Navigation trail
 You are in 
 Home page Jobs and work experience Types of jobs Hospitality and events management 
   
Types of jobs : Hospitality and events management 
 
 Accommodation manager Catering manager Conference centre manager Event organiser Fast food restaurant manager Hotel manager Public house manager Restaurant manager 
     
Site links

 Site map Order publications About us Contact us Accessibility information Privacy statement and cookie information Terms of use 
 
Information for other parties

 For advertisers Prospects Software Careers Services’Desk HECSU Research National Council for Work Experience Prospects Press Desk AGCAS - our careers service partner 
     
 
© Copyright 2012 Graduate Prospects Ltd. 
 RSS feeds Follow us on Twitter Follow us on Facebook Back to top 
     
 This website is best viewed in an up-to-date web browser with CSS enabled. While you will be able to view the content of this page in your current browser, you will not be able to get the full visual experience. Please consider upgrading your browser software or enabling style sheets if you are able to do so.
	</body>
</document>
