<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002166" url="http://www.answerbag.com/q_view/1507921" time="2012-07-12-18:04" support="2" score="0.0012510706646575065" bingtitle="Is coffee susceptible to bacteria growth like tea? If my coffee ..." webtitle="Is coffee susceptible to bacteria growth like tea? If my coffee has sit there for a couple of day and I reheat it, will I be drinking bacteria? | Answerbag">
			<query id="000243" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="001157" bing-rank="56"/>
	<description>If you drink from the cup, and save it, there will be bacteria in it. I think you ... Reminds me of a certain fast food restaurant that would not change the coffee until ...</description>
	<body>
		Ask a Question or Create a Poll 
 Home Categories Questions Forums Blog NEW! 
 
 Arts Autos&amp;Motorcycles Business Computers Diet&amp;Fitness Education Electronics Entertainment Environmentalism Fashion&amp;Beauty Finance Food&amp;Dining Games Health Hobbies Home&amp;Garden Kids Legal Life&amp;Society Pets&amp;Pet Care Real Estate Recreation&amp;Sports Relationship Advice Religion Science Social Sciences Transportation Travel&amp;Places Answerbag Outside the Bag 
 
 Home / Questions / Science / Biology / Microbiology / Bacteria 
 
by Meow on June 10th, 2009
 
Question

Help answer this question below.
 
Is coffee susceptible to bacteria growth like tea? If my coffee
has sit there for a couple of day and I reheat it, will I be
drinking bacteria?
 Share your answer here... Want to attach an image to your answer? Click here. 
 
Only upload an image if you have the rights to it,
and ensure that it complies with our terms of use .
 
 Like Report 
 Share: Facebook Twitter Other Sort answers by: Greatness / Likes Date submitted 
Answers. 10 helpful answers below. 
 
 
by holeinthewoods on June 10th, 2009
 
 quite possibly. leave a cup out for too long and it grows mold(3 days or so). Single guy once...been there done that. 
 
Comments

 
I generally do it because I hate...HATE... wasting coffee. I just couldn&apos;t drink it all the other night. I was exhausted and barely got through the half of cup that I did drink.

 Report 
 
by Meow on June 10th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Teller of Truth on June 10th, 2009
 
 I do that all the time, nothing bad has ever happened to me... 
 
Comments

 
I do it all the time as well unless it has a film on the top, then I don&apos;t do it. I just thought I would ask because I was just thinking about it. I actually thought about it before, but just never asked.

Glad to see I&apos;m not the only one who does this though.

 Report 
 
by Meow on June 10th, 2009
 
Of course I have my limitations...A day or two in the pot seems good enough for me but anything after that and I make a fresh pot...I just hate wasting stuff you know, I don&apos;t drink coffee for the taste of it but for the caffeine...Anyways, take care...

 Report 
 
by Teller of Truth on June 10th, 2009
 
Yeah, two days is good for me as well. I can&apos;t have caffeine, so I drink it for the taste only. It&apos;s just a beautiful thing after dinner.

 Report 
 
by Meow on June 10th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 3 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Violet on June 10th, 2009
 
 I use to work at a coffee shop, and the only problem with leaving coffee out, is that it will go&quot;bad&quot;, kind of stale. If you drink from the cup, and save it, there will be bacteria in it. I think you should put it in a leak proof container, and keep it in the fridge. That&apos;s what I do 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by phirad -you can call me Mike on June 10th, 2009
 
 Yes, it will have bacteria in it. the Amounts of bacteria depend on many factors. 
 
Comments

 
K.

 Report 
 
by Meow on June 10th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Anonymous on June 10th, 2009
 
 Reminds me of a certain fast food restaurant that would not change the coffee until (and unless) someone complained. Coffee got kinda gamey after sitting around a bit. 
 
Comments

 
Biggest difference...I&apos;m not a fast food chain and I&apos;m certainly NOT serving it to anyone other than myself...AND I have no problem with reheating coffee myself. Another huge difference is that I am REHEATING this coffee. It&apos;s not sat there on a burner getting an extra&quot;roast,&quot;which is what causes it to become yucky anyway.

&lt;-------So glad I don&apos;t drink restaurant coffee...LOL!!!

 Report 
 
by Meow on June 10th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 1 comment | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Bookworm on June 10th, 2009
 
 Coffee will grow bacteria, and even boiling it will not get rid of any poisonous toxins they may have produced. (remember food poisoning) 
 
Comments

 
LOL...I must be doing something right, then. Maybe it&apos;s the way I hold my mouth while it&apos;s reheating. I doubt the bacteria, if any, really is harmful. Otherwise, I would have a very hefty ER bill by now. Not saying that it can&apos;t happen...it just hasn&apos;t happened yet.

But hey...I reheat eggs and eat other stuff that people claim I shouldn&apos;t and I&apos;m healthy as two blue birds in spring.

 Report 
 
by Meow on June 10th, 2009
 
it&apos;s just something to keep in mind, you may not end up in the ER - just a stomach ache/nausea.

But, hey, if you&apos;ve got the iron stomach - eat on! ;)

 Report 
 
by Bookworm on June 10th, 2009
 
LOL...I actually do have an iron stomach. It&apos;s really weird though because if I see something gross, I won&apos;t be able to eat for a couple of days...it&apos;d just gross me out that bad. But what I eat generally doesn&apos;t make me sick.

 Report 
 
by Meow on June 10th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 3 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Go know thyself is THE RED QUEEN on June 10th, 2009
 
 If you boil the hell out of it...not only will it be absolutely discusting...It will have bacteria in it yes...but they with be dead....


Maybe. 
 
Comments

 
I don&apos;t have to&quot;boil the hell out of it&quot;just to reheat it. I do this all the time, but just was wondering if I am possibly drinking bacteria. If I am, I doubt they are hurting me.

 Report 
 
by Meow on June 10th, 2009
 
The whole&quot;Boiling the hell out of it.&quot;would ensure you that most of the bacteria was killed and couldn&apos;t harm your digestive track, stomach or mouth or throat for that matter. You can grow some nasty things in old coffee. Especially if your water system is un treated and straight out of the tap. You can get strep, yeast infections, virus, anything.

 Report 
 
by Go know thyself is THE RED QUEEN on June 10th, 2009
 
I use filtered watered.

But you think that the untreated water is the problem...sorry but that&quot;city&quot;water is the worst thing people can put in their bodies. I&apos;ll take the bacteria-infested coffee any day over that treated Clorox (and who knows what else) water...LMBO!!!

I did say to someone else in this thread that I have an iron stomach, but that type of water might be what would get me good and quick...LOL!!!

 Report 
 
by Meow on June 10th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 3 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
by Bakebyday still baking.. on June 10th, 2009
 
 Why would you want to drink a cup after a few days. It gets like a scum on time. NASTY. 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by Lazs Mouse on June 10th, 2009
 
 LOL--would not leave it sitting for two days just because it would taste nasty....but OK to leave it sitting for 8 hrs if you turn off the burner and reheat it by the cup in your m&apos;wave... 
 
Comments


 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

No comments. Post one | Permalink 
 
by GuitarPlayer92 on June 10th, 2009
 
 If it were me I probably wouldn&apos;t drink it...I honestly don&apos;t know the answer to this though 
 
Comments

 
Too late...LMBO!!! I do this all the time. I&apos;ve not had any problems yet.

 Report 
 
by Meow on June 10th, 2009
 
hahaha. Here&apos;s to hoping that no problems arise at all

 Report 
 
by GuitarPlayer92 on June 11th, 2009
 
 Add a comment... 
 
 Like Report 

 2 comments | Post one | Permalink 
 
 Share your answer... Want to attach an image to your answer? Click here. 
 
Only upload an image if you have the rights to it,
and ensure that it complies with our terms of use .
 
Did this answer your question? If not, then ask a new question or create a poll . 
 
More Questions. Additional questions in this category. 

 
 Can the same bacteria be different colors? 
by Michael_B9834 on January 30th, 2011
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 Might arsenic loving bacteria be dangerous to your health ? 
by iwnit on December 2nd, 2010
 
 | 3 people like this
 
 Why and how do you test for hydrogen sulfide? 
by jordanaleigh24 on November 22nd, 2010
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 Do I need a microscope to see living bacteria? I need to see the effects of antibiotics on bacteria, but can I see it without a microscope? 
by Michael_B9834 on January 5th, 2011
 
 | 1 person likes this
 
 why should we use thio&apos;s for cultures 
by melindagamble on December 7th, 2010
 
 | 1 person likes this
 More Bacteria See only professionally researched Bacteria questions 
 
You&apos;re reading Is coffee susceptible to bacteria growth like tea? If my coffee has sit there for a couple of day and I reheat it, will I be drinking bacteria?
 
Follow us on Facebook!
 
Related Ads
 
Related Questions

 
 If I eat yogurt and drink coffee, will the heat from the coffee destroy the beneficial bacteria in the yogurt? 
 
 Does urine have bacteria in it? If so, the longer you have the urine in a sealed bottle does that mean the bacteria will be gone or it would grow more bacteria in it? I&apos;m doing an experienment. 
 
 I&apos;m 16 and have the occasional cup of tea or coffee (about twice a week) but lately I&apos;ve been&apos;comfort drinking&apos;coffee. I have depression and coffee makes me feel better. I literally drank 11 mugs of coffee today. Am I addicted? What do I do? 
 
 If I let a glass of water sit on my desk for 9 hours will it start to grow bacteria? 
 
 Can drinking beer kill bacteria that cause vomiting and diarrhea? A friend has been suffering with these symptoms for over 2 weeks. He thinks that drinking beer/liquor will destroy the&quot;bad bacteria&quot;in his digestive system causing these symptoms. 
 
 
Professionally Researched
 
 
 How much bacteria growth occurs in reused water bottles? 
 
 What bacteria are found on school drinking fountains? 
 
 Does chlorine have a bacteria that kills the good bacteria? 
 
 Does the Keurig B140 coffee brewer make tea, too? 
 
 Who started Highland Coffee&amp;Tea? 
 
 
ANSWERBAG BUZZ
 Coffee bacteria Bacteria in coffee Coffee and bacteria Does coffee grow bacteria Bacteria in old coffee 
 About Us About Answerbag Sitemap Professionally Researched Questions   Legal Privacy Policy Terms of Use Disclaimer Ad Choices   Follow Us on Facebook 
 Answerbag.com 
Your favorite Q&amp;A site is on Facebook! Become a fan to connect with the ever-growing community of Answerbaggers, share your thoughts and find out what Answerbag&apos;s up to next!

 Latest Tweet 
 Follow Answerbag on Twitter! 
 
 
Answerbag

 AB4Adults Answerbag UK
	</body>
</document>
