<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002352" url="http://www.ajc.com/business/fast-food-jobs-in-965968.html" time="2012-07-12-18:16" support="4" score="0.012148523994252635" bingtitle="Fast-food jobs in higher demand | ajc.com" webtitle="Fast-food jobs in higher demand| ajc.com">
			<query id="001207" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001380" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000052" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="001201" bing-rank="30"/>
	<description>... ajc.com Shontell Nixon gives a customer a copy of his receipt ... They look sharp, they act sharp and they keep eye contact.” The restaurant industry is the ...</description>
	<body>
		Survey Software 
 CRM Integration 
 ajc 
 Atlanta Weather 

Cloudy

 75° F 

 Pollen 9 

 Air quality 43 

| Traffic 
 
 Customer Care Print/Digital Subscriptions 
 
 ajc.com Archives Services Web 
 
 Home News 
 Metro / Georgia Atlanta / South Fulton Cherokee Clayton Cobb DeKalb Fayette Forsyth Gwinnett Henry North Fulton Georgia Politics Traffic Weather 

 Nation&amp;World News Q&amp;A Photos–News Videos–Local News Videos–Nation/World 
 
Special Reports

 Atlanta Forward CRCT Coverage 

Blogs

 Get Schooled Political Insider More blogs» 
 
Opinion

 Opinion page Letters to the Editor Jay Bookman Mike Luckovich Kyle Wingfield Atlanta Forward blog 
 Sports 
 Braves College Recruiting Dream Falcons Georgia State Georgia Tech Golf Hawks High School AJC Peachtree Road Race UGA Photos–Sports Videos–Local Sports Videos–National Sports 
 
Blogs

 College Recruiting Mark Bradley Jeff Schultz More blogs» 

Topics

 SEC Sports More topics» 

Features

 Scoreboard Sports Vent More features» 
 Entertainment 
 Best of Big A Celebrities&amp;TV Events Food&amp;Restaurants Holiday Guide Movies Music Fashion&amp;Style Games&amp;Comics Photos–Entertainment Videos–Entertainment 
 
Blogs

 Food and More The Buzz Radio&amp;TV Talk More blogs» 

Topics

 Concert Photos Real Housewives of Atlanta Tyler Perry More topics» 

Features

 Find Five Challenge Puzzles&amp;Games TV listings 
 Travel 
 Atlanta Airport Beaches Deals Louisiana Southeast Travel Travel Guide U.S.&amp;International Photos–Travel Videos–Travel 
 
Topics

 Budget Ideas Day Trips Weekend Getaways More topics» 

Features

 Vacation rentals 
 Business 
 Coke Delta Air Lines Georgia Top Stocks Atlanta Top Workplaces Photos–Business Videos–Business At Your Service Graduate/MBA Education 
 
Features

 Find cheap gas Georgia executive pay More features» 
 Lifestyle 
 Celebrations Health Holiday Guide Gardening Home Decor My Style Recipes Photos–Lifestyle Videos–Lifestyle 
 
Blogs

 Atlanta Bargain Hunter Misadventures in Atlanta Momania More blogs» 

Topics

 Private Quarters Photos Weight Loss and Fitness More topics» 

Features

 Living Vent Volunteer Locally More features» 
 Obituaries 
 Funeral Directors Obituary Archives Obituary Help Atlanta Obituary News 
 Homes Jobs Cars Classifieds Shopping 
 Atlanta Business News 7:50 a.m. Friday, June 3, 2011 
 Text size: Decrease Increase 
 
Fast-food jobs in higher demand


 
 Print E-mail 
 
By Jeremiah McWilliams 


The Atlanta Journal-Constitution

In one of the roughest job markets in memory, fast-food positions are proving attractive for job seekers of all ages. Once a workplace ceded largely to teens and part-time workers, fast food is attracting older people with experience, education and marketable skills.
 Enlarge photo Johnny Crawford, Jcrawford@ajc.com Shontell Nixon gives a customer a copy of his receipt inside Popeyes on South Cobb Drive on Thursday. Before coming to Popeyes, Nixon worked in a senior care facility after owning a restaurant. 
 
Related

 Photos: Jobseekers flock to McDonald&apos;s 
 
More business news

 3 options for downtown &apos;Gulch&apos; Committee heads led failed banks Delta dunned for jet&apos;s chipped nose Missing bank director indicted Airport seeking approval for nearly $4 million art project Biz Beat blog Top workplaces: Is your company on this list? Check your stocks 
 
K’wan Banks, 35, went through three rounds of interviews to land a job at a McDonald’s on Riverdale Road. The Everest College graduate has a commercial driver’s license and working experience with Avis Rent A Car. Getting on with McDonald’s, where she is now in training to be a manager, was tougher than she expected.

“Oh my God, yes,”she said.“I didn’t think McDonald’s was that serious.”

Banks said she only recently started thinking of McDonald’s as a potential career. She hopes to become a store manager in the next few months after working in every corner of the restaurant, from cash register to clean-up duty.“You’ve got to learn everything,”she said.

For younger applicants, fast food has been the traditional first job or summer job. Landing that job has become much harder.

Wade Phenicie of Norcross is just beginning his working career and has had a tough job search. He pursued jobs at Papa John’s while on spring break during his freshmen year at Williams College in Massachusetts. For two months, he waited for a callback. On Thursday, he finally got an interview scheduled for a job as a delivery driver.

“I don’t want to get my hopes up,”said Phenicie, 19.

Restaurant owners can afford to be picky as the competition for every opening gets tougher.

Keith Lollis, who operates three McDonald’s restaurants around Atlanta, said his establishments were begging for workers not long ago. Job applicants used to arrive dressed in jeans; he now sees more men in suits and ties or khaki pants and oxford shirts. Women come in dresses. Perhaps one in 10 applicants has a college education, up from one in 30 or 40 less than a year ago.

“The quality of applicant has gotten better,”Lollis said.“They are coming dressed better and presenting themselves better. They look sharp, they act sharp and they keep eye contact.”

The restaurant industry is the country’s second-largest private employer behind health care. Of the industry’s workforce, 42 percent is 24 or younger, and upward mobility is a big draw. More than 90 percent of salaried employees started as hourly employees, according to industry statistics.

Before the recession, Aziz Hashim’s restaurants had trouble finding enough workers. A lot of young people weren’t interested in fast-food jobs, preferring to work at the mall or at Gap rather than Popeyes, Checkers, Rally’s or Domino’s Pizza.

They are interested now, said Hashim, chief executive of Decatur-based National Restaurant Development Inc.

“If we open up even a very modest job opening, it would not be unusual for us to get 50 or 100 applications,”said Hashim, who has restaurants in Atlanta, Los Angeles, Phoenix, Jacksonville and Orlando.

In the Chicago suburb of Aurora, Chick-fil-A operator Doug Lockwood said he has collected hundreds of applications, even though he’s not hiring or advertising positions.

The fast-food segment is the fastest growing corner of the overall restaurant industry, which is pulling out of a three-year slump. In the 12-month period ending in March, fast-food employment rose 2 percent, compared to a 1.3 percent increase in jobs at restaurants that offer table service, according to the National Restaurant Association.

The long queue for available jobs is apparently keeping wages from rising. Fast-food workers have seen their pay stay basically flat for a year. The average hourly wage was $8.93 in March, according to preliminary numbers from the Bureau of Labor Statistics. In March last year, the same jobs paid $8.81 per hour for production and nonsupervisory employees. The national minimum wage is $7.25.

Nelquita Clemmons, 26, got a job at an Atlanta McDonald’s three weeks ago. She had studied to become a medical administrative assistant, and hopes to use the new overnight cleaning job as a stepping stone to something better.“I’m always looking for more opportunities, more benefits, more pay,”she said.

Other factors have attracted people to fast-food openings. The industry has had some success getting rid of the stereotype of the dead-end“McJob,”convincing more people to give it a whirl. Some applicants see the jobs as a long-term opportunity, not just a stop-gap measure.

Matthew Robinson, 16, got a job last summer working the register and cleaning tables at a Chick-fil-A restaurant on Howell Mill Road in Atlanta. He just finished sophomore year at Westminster and plans to work at Chick-fil-A through his senior year. He said he’s looking forward to taking on more responsibility, such as working in the kitchen.

In addition to the attractive applicants, restaurants now find their employees tend to hang onto jobs as long as possible, reducing what used to be a constant churn of departures and hiring.

Arthur Greeno, a Chick-fil-A operator in Tulsa, said his store crews are stable.“I’ve got to be honest, the economy helps,”he said.“When the economy is tough, people with jobs aren’t going to be out looking for jobs.”

“There are plenty of people to choose from,”said John Challenger, chief executive of Chicago-based Challenger Gray&amp;Christmas, an outplacement consulting firm.“There are lots of people who want these jobs, need them and would love to have them.”
 
The Georgia angle

The unemployment rate is 9.7 percent in metro Atlanta. Nationally, it’s 9 percent. The jobless rate is 14.6 percent among people who don’t have a high school diploma; and among teens, unemployment stands at 24.9 percent.
 
More than 1 million people applied for jobs at McDonald’s when it put out the call for applications last month; the chain hired 62,000. That 6.2-percent acceptance rate was lower than Harvard University’s for its class of 2014.
 

 AJC Marketplace 
 Smart Shopping 
starts here!
 This week&apos;s inserts | Today&apos;s Deals | Grocery Coupons 
 
 Grad School / MBA a ticket to success? Earning power | How to pay | Atlanta programs 

 
 Get Travel Ideas from our Budget Traveler - 
Cheap Airfares, Getaways, Today&apos;s Deals
 

 
Inside ajc.com
 
 What&apos;s in Big Mac sauce? 
 
2 all-beef patties, special sauce . . . McDonald&apos;s executive chef shows how to make your own special sauce.
 
 She&apos;s number one! 
 
Baylor basketball star Brittney Griner took home the top female athlete prize at the ESPY Awards.
 
 Can you see the change? 
 
What&apos;s altered in the two photos? See how you score when you play the Find 5 Challenge!
 
 Luckovich: Climate change 
 
Editorial cartoonist Mike Luckovich gives his take on local news, politics, sports and celebrities.
 
 Choose the best produce 
 
It’s time to vote. Just choose your favorite among the Top 5 nominees for best place to get produce.
 
 Girls take on Vogue 
 
Girls demand Teen Vogue follow Seventeen&apos;s lead in declaring an end to digitally manipulating images.
 

 
Share this page with your friends

 

 Tweet 
 
 Business videos 
 
 

Watch more video
 Local sports | Local video from AJC, Channel 2 
 Today&apos;s news Tools and widgets Reprints, Permissions Archives 
 
TRENDING NOW ON AJC.COM
 
 
 
Tell us what you think about the site
 Send us your suggestions about this page. 
Send a feedback technical issue 
 
 Subscribe» 

 
 
 Customer Care» 

Vacation stops, manage subscriptions and more
 
AJC Services

 Staff contacts Reprints and permission Contests Submit event listings Send us news tips Careers at AJC Careers at Cox AJC Store AJC Conversation 
 
Sections

 News Sports Entertainment Travel Business Lifestyle Obituaries 

Other Editions

 Sign up for newsletters Digital Products AJC for iPad Sign up for ajcMobile RSS and Widgets Today&apos;s news | A1 image Archives 
 
Guides

 Best of Atlanta School Guide Neighborhood Guide AJC in Education Atlanta Home Sales Atlanta Topics Travel Guide Atlanta Holiday Guide Atlanta Crime&amp;Safety Find Atlanta Jobs Graduate/MBA Education 
 
Advertising

 Advertise with us E-Sheets 

AJC Sites

 ajc.com AccessAtlanta Atlanta Jobs Atlanta Homes Atlanta Apartments Atlanta Cars Atlanta Classifieds Mundo Hispánico Cars on AutoTrader.com 
 
 Visitor Agreement | Privacy Statement | AdChoices 
©2012 The Atlanta Journal-Constitution
	</body>
</document>
