<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002037" url="http://centralpark.browardschools.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;view=article&amp;id=5662&amp;Itemid=9943" time="2012-07-12-17:56" support="2" score="0.004049980816019246" bingtitle="Central Park Elementary - Welcome to the Central Park Cafeteria" webtitle="Central Park Elementary - Welcome to the Central Park Cafeteria">
			<query id="000713" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000718" bing-rank="10"/>
	<description>Walkers or car riders who wish to eat breakfast ... School policy prohibits parents from bringing fast food/restaurant ... Technology Services . 7720 West Oakland Park Blvd ...</description>
	<body>
		Central Park Elementary 


   
 
 Home Our School Academics Faculty Parents Students Volunteers Business Partners Faculty Contacts 
 
   

 
Cafeteria Information Menu

 School Menu School Meal Prices Paying For Meals Cafeteria Life Applying for Free /Reduced Lunch Inspection Reports 
   
Welcome to the Central Park Cafeteria
 Tweet 
 Cafeteria: 754-322-5710

 Cafeteria Manager: Denise Smith

 Cafeteria Staff:  Daniel Ramirez, Carlton Smith

 Hours Available: 7:30 am to 2:00 pm

The Food and Nutrition Services Department offers a variety of low-cost, well-balanced, nutritious meals. School lunches provide an assortment of foods, including salads and fresh fruit. School meals are healthy, and meet the Dietary Guidelines for Americans. By choosing lunch at school, students learn to make healthy choices, reinforcing nutrition education taught in the classroom. 

 

 Breakfast is served from 7:30 am until 7:55 am. Walkers or car riders who wish to eat breakfast must be in the cafeteria before 7:50 am, and should go directly to the cafeteria serving line.

Breakfast consists of the following:

(1) Cereal or yogurt with biscuit and jelly

(1) Fruit

(1) Milk

(1) Protein (choose from breakfast pizza, breakfast sausage bites, mini pancakes French toast, or other featured items)

The price for breakfast is $1.20.

 

 Lunch times vary by grade. Lunch period is 30 minutes for all grades. The first lunch period is at 10:15 a.m., with the last group of students served at 1:00 p.m.

Lunch consists of the following:

(1) Entrée (A grain is offered as bread or a rice accompaniment)

(3) Fruit/Vegetable/Juice (the three selections must be different)

(1) Milk

Students may enjoy all 5 meal components, or may select 3 or 4 different components. A student may only purchase items ala carte if he or she purchases a school lunch or brings a packed lunch from home.

The price for lunch is $2.00.

 

 Wednesday is Ice Cream Day! Volunteers from the Central Park PTA serve low-fat chocolate or vanilla ice cream every Wednesday. Ice cream is $0.65. Don’t miss out!

 Frozen Juice Fridays! The cafeteria sells frozen juice bars for $0.50 every Friday.

 Eating With Your Child - Parents must follow school policy when having breakfast and/or lunch with their child on campus. School policy prohibits parents from bringing fast food/restaurant food on campus. Parents should only eat with their own child.
   
   
 Advertisement 
   
 Advertisement 
 
     Copyright©2011 Broward County Public Schools | Education Technology Services . 7720 West Oakland Park Blvd. Sunrise, FL 33351.(754) 321-0000 
 Nondiscrimination&amp;Reasonable Accommodation Statement . Privacy Statement Hit Counter : 076423
	</body>
</document>
