<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002780" url="http://kissrichmond.com/1792672/real-talk-mcdonalds-employee-defends-himself-against-violent-female-customers-now-faces-prison-video/" time="2012-07-12-18:50" support="1" score="0.0023438841401546354" bingtitle="REAL TALK: McDonald&apos;s Employee Defends Himself Against Violent ..." webtitle="REAL TALK: McDonald&apos;s Employee Defends Himself Against Violent Female Customers, Now Faces Prison | 99.3-105.7 Kiss FM">
			<query id="001416" bing-rank="58"/>
	<description>That’s when the cashier can be seen on the video going to the back of the fast-food restaurant. ... Social Security Makes Changes: The Check Won’t ...</description>
	<body>
		BP NEXT BP Radio The Urban Daily Hello Beautiful NewsOne Elev8 GIANTLife TV One Jobs Black Doctor 
 Subscribe 
 
 Follow @KissRichmond 
Thursday, July 12
 
Main menu
 Skip to primary content Skip to secondary content 
 Home The 804 
 The Healthy, Wealthy, Wise Expo Stone Soul Music&amp;Food Festival Weather Traffic Sports 
 Contest 
 Girls Night Out With Ledisi 
 Events Photos Videos On-Air 
 Music Playlist Schedule 
 About Us The Healthy, Wealthy, Wise Expo 
 
 Local Traffic Local Weather Listen Live!
 On Blackplanet Radio 
 Home  &gt;  The 804  &gt; REAL TALK: McDonald’s Employee Defends Himself Against Violent Female Customers, Now Faces Prison 
REAL TALK: McDonald’s Employee Defends Himself Against Violent Female Customers, Now Faces Prison
 Oct 18, 2011 1 Comment By Alexx Dupri 
 An argument between a cashier and two irate customers at a New York City McDonald’s turned violent, leaving both customers injured and all three facing charges.

The entire incident, which was captured on video, happened last Thursday morning.

According to CBS News, two female customers argued and yelled obscenities at the cashier when he questioned a $50 bill they gave him.

One of the female customers then slapped the cashier. The first woman is then seen jumping over the counter while the other woman goes behind the register.

That’s when the cashier can be seen on the video going to the back of the fast-food restaurant. He comes back with a metal rod and begins hitting the women.

Other customers watched in horror as McDonald’s workers tried unsuccessfully to stop the violence.

One female customer is later treated for a fractured skull that required surgery and a broken arm. The other has a deep laceration.

Rayon McIntosh, 31, was arrested and charged with two counts of felony assault and criminal possession of a weapon.McIntosh served more than a decade in prison after shooting and killing a high school classmate in 2000. He was being held on $40,000 bail.

The female customers were charged with menacing, disorderly conduct and trespassing.

The owner of that McDonald’s said in a statement that she was“disturbed”by what happened and said the cashier is no longer employed there.

 But the story should not end there. Not only did these women attack Rayon McIntosh, but they jumped over the counter and continued their assault. No other employees stepped-in to help. So was Rayon McIntosh right to defend himself? Should he have been charged (with a crime) at all? And would he have been charged if these were two violent male customers? 
 

 
Tags: alexx dupri &gt; fast food &gt; Irate Cutomer &gt; McDonalds &gt; REAL TALK 
 Newer Post → ← Older Post 
 
More Related Content
 
Daily Links
 Jacque Reid&apos;s&quot;Inside HERStory&quot; —kissrichmond.com 
 Radio One Richmond Teacher of the Week —kissrichmond.upickem.net The Kardashians Get $40 Million Dollars for More Shows —kissrichmond.com Stone Soul 2012 —kissrichmond.com Oprah Honored for Lifetime of Leadership —kissrichmond.com 
 
 
Comments
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. blog comments powered by Disqus 
 advertisement 
Most Popular

 BREAKING NEWS: Usher’s Stepson is Declared Brain Dead by Doctors; Prayer Vigil Held at Hosptial Jennifer Lopez‘Sex’Tape Stolen By Ex- Husband’s Lawyer‏ 
 
Like 99.3-105.7 Kiss FM
 advertisement 
Featured Authors
 
 Miss Community Clovia Profile 
 Presumptive GOP Nominee Mitt Romney Will Address the NAACP in Houston Today President Obama to Hosts Grassroots Events in VA Beach, Hampton, Roanoke and Glen Allen [AUDIO] Miss Community’s Next Voter/Restoration of Rights Rally is July 14 
 Michael Baisden Profile 
 “The View”Co-Hosts Clash Over Komen and Planned Parenthood Are Black People The New Political Orphans of America? Five Things Black People Learned from Don Cornelius 
 Mitch Malone Profile 
 Report: Penn State Officials Hid Sandusky’s Actions From Authorities, The Late Joe Paterno Included KISS–FM’s Celebrity Birthdays For The Week Of July 9th–15th, 2012 (Happy Birthday Bill Cosby!) GOP Nominee Mitt Romney Booed At NAACP Convention In Houston For Vow To Repeal“Obama-Care” 
 99.3/105.7 KISS FM Profile 
 Alfredas Movie Minute: “Savages” [EXCLUSIVE VIDEO] Alfredas Movie Minute: “Savages” R. Kelly Breaks Down “Write Me Back” Track-By-Track [EXCLUSIVE] 
 
 advertisement 
 
 
 Around the Web 

 
 Elev8.com 

 Tia Mowry-Hardrict On Being A Famous Twin: “It Just Feels Magical.” The Center for Disease Control Releases Their “Wedding Day Survival Guide” Did Planned Parenthood Collect $28M In Medicaid Fraud ? Mary Mary’s Erica: ” Love People While You Have Them!” [VIDEO] Presbyterians Reject Redefinition Of Marriage 
 
 iPowerRichmond.com 

 Fat Joe On What Motivated Him To Lose 100 Pounds [EXCLUSIVE VIDEO] Meek Mill&amp;Pastor Jomo K Johnson Argue On Radio Over ‘Amen’ Pastor Calls For Boycott Kirko Bangz On What Happened To Houston Hip-Hop [EXCLUSIVE VIDEO] DJ Khaled Says Don’t Call Him Fat, Call Him… [EXCLUSIVE VIDEO] K. Michelle Release New Mixtape “0 F**ks Given” 
 
 PraiseRichmond.com 

 Bishop Secular: Where’s The Love In Reality TV? [EXCLUSIVE AUDIO] Yolanda’s Points Of Power: Knowing God [EXCLUSIVE AUDIO] Yolanda’s Points Of Power: The Power Of Truth [EXCLUSIVE AUDIO] Yolanda’s Points Of Power: What Has God Established In You Life? [EXCLUSIVE AUDIO] Habakkuk Music Rolls Out an “Incredible” New CD By GERALD SCOTT&amp;CO. 
 
 NewsOne.com 

 From the ‘Too Late’ Files? Steve Harvey Doesn’t Want ‘Think Like a Man’ Franchise to be ‘Buffoonery’ Jesse Jackson Jr. Being Treated for Mood Disorder Bishop Found Guilty of Sodomizing and Molesting 5 Young Boys So Tired! GOP Votes To Repeal Health Care Ho*s To Cops: Let Our Pimps Go! 
 
 
 
 Top Stories 

 Buy Tickets To The Healthy, Wealthy, Wise Expo 2012 Stone Soul Photos&amp;Video Actress Tia Mowry-Hardrict Discusses Reality TV, Being a Sexy Mom and Leaving “The Game” Singer Janet Jackson to Produce Transgender Documentary 
 About Us: 
 About Us Privacy About Our Ads Terms of Service Advertising EEO Careers 
 
 Copyright©2012, Interactive One . All Rights Reserved Powered by WordPress.com VIP
	</body>
</document>
