<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002897" url="http://cleveland.citysearch.com/profile/8049884/wadsworth_oh/kfc.html" time="2012-07-12-18:58" support="2" score="0.003975080998509794" bingtitle="Kfc - Wadsworth, OH, 44281 - Citysearch - Cleveland, OH City Guide ..." webtitle="Kfc - Wadsworth, OH, 44281 - Citysearch">
			<query id="000726" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001481" bing-rank="155"/>
	<description>Take us with you on the go! Download our app ... In Short – Established in 1939, this fast-food restaurant ... She(christina) took my order..got to window and ...</description>
	<body>
		Deals Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Hotels Shopping Best Of Citysearch 

 Mobile Login / Join 
 More More Go! Advertise With Us 
 Citysearch has shed its old skin! In addition to our new look, there&apos;s a boatload of new features. Poke around! Tell us what you think! 
 Cleveland, OH Metro &gt; Wadsworth &gt; Restaurants &gt; Kfc 
Kfc
 (330) 334-0075 
 988 High St , Wadsworth , OH | Directions  
 44281 41.049600 -81.729000 View Website 
 Share Save 
   Own this Business? Recommend this business? Thumbs Up Thumbs Down ? not rated
yet Add a Photo Price: $ Cuisine: Traditional American , Chicken , Fast Food Categories: Restaurants 
 View More 
 Restaurant Special Features: Cheap Eats , Carry Out , Lunch Spot , Family-Friendly Dining Payment Methods: MasterCard, Discover, Visa, American Express, Diners Club 
 View Less 
 Site Feedback 
 Overview Tips (3) Photos (0) 
 Write a Tip for Kfc 
 Sign in to Write a Tip 
 Write a Tip... optional 
 
 
Tips for Kfc
 Doesn&apos;t Recommend columbusmorgan Joined 2 years ago 1.0 January 25, 2010 
 Horrilble Service by the GM !. I waited in the drive thru for 6 minutes on a weekday at 12:50 in the afternoon. She(christina) took my order..got to window and asked why it took so long.reply ...&quot;Its lunch and were busy&quot;was the reply...2 cars in the drive thru.I asked for the corporate number .I then asked for water with my combo to not have to pay taxes.Her responce was she couldn&apos;t do it...I said...&quot;your the GM you can do anything&quot;she said why bother when you are going to call corporate on me anyway.I asked for my money back at that point. If your in a hurry and want chicken.....Don&apos;t go to KFC on route 94 in Wadsworth. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Contributor Joined 9 years ago August 02, 2008 
 For more than 60 years, this all-American institution has been serving its signature chicken and home-style sides.. In Short 
Established in 1939, this fast-food restaurant still makes its legendary fried chicken with the closely guarded blend of 11 herbs and spices originally created by founder Colonel Sanders. Modern additions to the menu include oven-roasted renditions of its chicken sandwiches, popcorn chicken, potato wedges and wraps. Classic sides include flaky, oversized biscuits, steaming-hot mashed potatoes and gravy, smoky-sweet baked beans and crisp, generously dressed coleslaw. Kids and adults love the &quot;little bucket&quot; parfaits of pudding desserts. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart 
 
 
People who viewed this also viewed…
 
 Bob Evans Restaurant 151 Park Ctr Dr 
 Wadsworth, OH 
0.2 mi away Applebee&apos;s Neighborhood… 1020 High St 
 Wadsworth, OH 
0.1 mi away Dairy Queen 835 High St 
 Wadsworth, OH 
0.3 mi away 
 
Things to do near Kfc
 
 Restaurants Movie Theaters Banks 

 Bars Shopping&amp;Malls Hotels 
 
 About Apps Careers Privacy Policy Terms of Use Contact Us Blog FAQs 
 
Partner Sites:

 Ask Kids     Bloglines     Expedia     Hotels     Hotwire     Insider Pages     MerchantCircle     Reference     The Daily Beast     Thesaurus     Urbanspoon 
 ©2011. Citysearch is a registered trademark of CityGrid Media. Data provided by Infogroup. All rights reserved. 
 Popular Categories Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Shopping Hotels Deals Sports&amp;Recreation Cafes Movie Theaters Directory&amp;Services 

 Change City New York City Los Angeles Houston Chicago Atlanta Seattle Portland Philadelphia Austin San Francisco More…
	</body>
</document>
