<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002497" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=1006021507843" time="2012-07-12-18:33" support="2" score="0.0026068130239213514" bingtitle="How do I determine start-up costs for my fast-food restaurant ..." webtitle="How do I determine start-up costs for my fast-food restaurant?...? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="001053" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="001059" bing-rank="38"/>
	<description>Cars &amp; Transportation; Computers &amp; Internet; Consumer ... determine what my start-up cots will be for my fast-food restaurant. This includes equipment, down payments ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Business&amp;Finance &gt; Small Business &gt; Resolved Question 
 ongo_run Member since: December 14, 2005 Total points: 254 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
How do I determine start-up costs for my fast-food restaurant?...?
 I am writing a business plan for a school project. For this, I need to determine what my start-up cots will be for my fast-food restaurant. This includes equipment, down payments, insurance, etc. However, since this is not real... I have no idea how to go about finding this out. Please help. 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 

Additional Details
 I realize that I need to find out what equipment I need, but I do not know how to go about finding out that information either. 
 6 years ago 
 by Richard H Member since: January 31, 2006 Total points: 72,595 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 find out a few things:

1) what you need to start the restaurant
2) where to get the items you need
3) the prices of the items you need

1) what you need should include:

a) property (rent or purchase somewhere)
b) equipment (how can you cook food without a stove, or collect money without at least one cash register?)
c) employees
and with employees, you need to figure out
c)1) how many
c)2) how much money to pay them 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 67% 2 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 
 Action Bar: 1 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (1)
 
 by wanda_ke... Member since: March 14, 2006 Total points: 174 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I am guessing that you are writing one as if you were starting one from scratch and not purchasing an existing fast food restaurant or franchise.

When trying to figure out start up costs you need to consider the following:

One-time expenditures that must be incurred before a business opens its doors, such as buying furniture, equipment, start-up inventory, etc.

Ongoing day-to-day expenses such as payments to employees, rent, utilities, etc.

Figuring out how much money you need involves preparing statements which project your expected net income, cash flow, balance sheet, and completing a breakeven analysis. Based on the projections and your current financial situation, you can then analyze what type of financing you need (debt or equity) and where best to look for it (from within the business or from an outside lender). 
Source(s):
 If you would like a spreadsheet outlining start-up costs in which you can modify to suit your own needs, please go to: http://www.BusinessPlanWorld.com/restaurant

Good luck. 
 6 years ago Report Abuse 
 33% 1 Vote 
 
Discover Questions in Small Business 

 Can I start an online business at the age of 13? How do you start a buisness? Where can I donate home made jewlery? What is the best bank for a small corporation and why? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Business&amp;Finance 
 Advertising&amp;Marketing Careers&amp;Employment Corporations Credit Insurance Investing Other - Business&amp;Finance Personal Finance Renting&amp;Real Estate Small Business Taxes 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

 Richard H 
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
