<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002661" url="http://onlineathens.com/stories/072609/" time="2012-07-12-18:43" support="1" score="0.0010995120016978723" bingtitle="News Archives for 7/26/2009 | Online Athens" webtitle="News Archives for 7/26/2009  | Online Athens">
			<query id="000587" bing-rank="213"/>
	<description>Scholar wants to put it behind him BOSTON ... from shady mortgage lending, abusive credit card fees ... for sale at the North Korean capital&apos;s first fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Login  |  Join Now!  |  Subscribe 
 Site Web Web Search powered by YAHOO! Search 
 
 Home 
 All Today&apos;s Headlines Obituaries Spotted DogBytes AthensTalks Prep Sports Athens Magazine Daily Deals Comics Puzzle 
 Banner-Herald 
 Local News National News Sports Business Opinion Features Marquee Weather 
 AthensLive 
 Live Tonight Tomorrow This Week This Month Art Theatre Classes Kids/Family Other Venue SignUp 
 Barrow 
 Check out AroundhereOnline.com/barrow for more Barrow stories 
 Jackson 
 Check out AroundhereOnline.com/barrow for more Jackson stories 
 Madison 
 Check out AroundhereOnline.com/barrow for more Madison stories 
 Oconee 
 Check out AroundhereOnline.com/oconee for more Oconee stories 
 Customer Service 
 Subscription/Delivery Services Staff Privacy Copyright Wedding Form Engagement Form Weddings / Anniversaries Anniversary Form RSS 
 Classifieds 
 Rentals Garage Sales Pets&amp;Livestock Real Estate Merchandise Transportation Place An Ad FAQ 
 Jobs 
 Need a job? Find it here! 
 Autos 
 Find a new or used vehicle 
 Homes 
 Find a new home 
 
 
 Current weather 
 
 72° Clear sky 
 More Weather 
Sunday, July 26, 2009

 Teresa Edwards joins Hall of Fame 
Already one of the most decorated athletes in basketball history, Teresa Edwards added to her staggering collection of honors on Saturday when the Women&apos;s Basketball Hall of Fame announced her inclusion in its Class of 2010.

 Retailers hope for back-to-school boost 
Like most retailers throughout America, Jody Tanner&apos;s two Bulldog Sporting Goods stores in Athens rely heavily on back-to-school business, especially since it is the industry&apos;s second biggest selling period after the Christmas holidays.

 Nelson: Culpepper very well connected 
Athens lost one of its important connections Monday when E.H. Culpepper died at age 69 after a long fight with cancer.

 Small Biz: Italian roots go deep at eatery 
For the past few years, restaurateur Carl Burdette has been boning up on Italian cooking, buying every cookbook he can get his hands on to learn how to make traditional Italian meals for a new restaurant he and his wife, Kim, started recently in Oconee County.

 Bachtel: Jobs not immediate answer to problems 
From an economic development standpoint, the last thing Athens-Clarke County needs is jobs.

 Mendell: Managers must clarify value of members 
Who is the most important person on your team?

 Carroll: Stages of business decline mimicked by ethical lapses 
Management guru and author Jim Collins, who gave us &quot;Built to Last&quot; (1997) and &quot;Good to Great&quot; (2001) - two of the most popular books written about business performance - now has published a new book titled &quot;How the Mighty Fall&quot; (2009).

 Business Whirl: Brya named young optometrist of year 
The Georgia Optometric Association honored Dr. Meg Brya, clinic director and a partner at Five Points Eye Care Center, as Young Optometrist of the Year at the association&apos;s annual meeting in June. The award recognizes an optometrist who has been practicing less than six years and who shows exceptional leadership, volunteers in the community and maintains high standards in practice.

 Business Briefs: Carroll&apos;s columns form basis of book 
Athens Banner-Herald columnist and University of Georgia professor emeritus Archie Carroll has a new book out, &quot;Business Ethics: Brief Readings on Vital Topics.&quot;

 Brief Cases: Birchmore changes hands 
Birchmore Pool and Spa recently changed ownership. Bob Shields purchased the business, which was started in 1975. Shields has completely renovated the Birchmore Pool&amp;Spa showrooms in its building on Oneta Street and brought in new staff.

 Permits 
Permits issued in Athens-Clarke County the week of July 13 to 17 as reported in the Hunt Letter.

 Licenses 


 Health scores 
Health scores from July 10 to 14, includes scores from Oconee County

 Pedestrian robbed west of downtown 
Four men beat and robbed an Athens man of his wallet and the $10 it contained early Friday as he walked through the Parkview Homes neighborhood off Florida Street west of downtown, Athens-Clarke said.

 City employee finds surprise in envelope 
A Downtown Athens Parking employee was emptying a parking ticket payment box at the corner of East Clayton and North Jackson streets at 8:30 a.m. Friday when he discovered a parking ticket payment envelope filled with vomit, broken glass, a liquid that smelled like alcohol, a note with profanities written on it and the actual parking citation with the vehicle owner&apos;s information on it, Athens-Clarke police said.

 Socket set taken from home&apos;s garage 
Someone broke into a home&apos;s garage in the 200 block of Saxon Woods Drive sometime between July 17 and Friday and stole a Snap-On socket set worth $3,000, Athens-Clarke police said.

 Burglars foil anti-theft effort 
Burglars removed a reinforced door from its hinges and stole a plasma TV valued at $2,000 from a Whitehall Road home between 9 a.m. and 5:15 p.m. Thursday, Athens-Clarke police said.

 Computer, iPod taken from house 
Burglars got into a home in the 200 block of Cleveland Avenue between 10 and 10:30 a.m. Friday through a window at the back of the house and stole a laptop worth $2,000 and an iPod worth $150, Athens-Clarke police said.

 Winder man jailed in shooting case 
Barrow County sheriff&apos;s deputies arrested a 19-year-old Winder man Thursday afternoon on an aggravated assault charge for allegedly shooting a 25-year-old man during an argument over money, deputies said Friday.

 Passenger arrested riding in tagless SUV 
An Athens man who officers said was carrying drugs got a trip to jail Thursday night when police stopped the sport utility vehicle he was riding in because it had no license tag, Athens-Clarke police said.

 Flat-screen TV stolen from home 
Someone busted out a window of a home in the 1200 block of Tallassee Road sometime between 7:40 p.m. Thursday and 3:50 p.m. Friday and stole a flat-screen TV worth $2,000, Athens-Clarke police said.

 Electronics, DVDs, video games taken 
Someone kicked in the front door of a home in the 100 block of Hunters Run between 9 a.m. and 4:30 p.m. Friday and stole a laptop worth $600, a TV worth $200, a Xbox 360 worth $400 and DVDs and video games worth $300, Athens-Clarke police said.

 Burglars take TV through window 
Burglars used an unlocked window to gain entry to a home in the 500 block of Quailwood Drive sometime between 4 and 9 p.m. Friday and stole a flat-screen TV worth $2,800, Athens-Clarke police said.

 Alleged robbery victim changes story 
Police were called to Athens Regional Medical Center between 1 and 2 a.m. Friday to talk with an apparent robbery victim who gave conflicting reports of the incident, Athens-Clarke police said.

 Spurrier: I messed up 
HOOVER, Ala. - Steve Spurrier forced another recount that will be of interest to those in Florida.

 Florida unanimous pick; UGA underdogs in second 
HOOVER, Ala. - It&apos;s unanimous. Defending national and Southeastern Conference champion Florida got all 64 first-place votes by media members as the pick to repeat as SEC East champions.

 Ching: Kiffin trying wrong tactics 
HOOVER, Ala. - Believe it or not, Lane Kiffin could learn a lesson in humility from Steve Spurrier. Spurrier was never known for his modesty in the 1990s, when his Florida teams dominated the Southeastern Conference and he was always quick with vicious one-liners about the Gators&apos; conference rivals.

 Notebook: LSU out to prove last year was fluke 
HOOVER, Ala. - It was quite a freefall for LSU in 2008.

 Kupets enjoys ESPY hoopla 
Even though Courtney Kupets has completed her gymnastics career, she has been consumed by it this summer.

 Ballard Clark fulfills dream with new gig 
In her first week as Georgia&apos;s new assistant gymnastics coach, Julie Ballard Clark arrived at work Thursday morning to an office filled with 20 star-shaped balloons at the Suzanne Yoculan Gymnastics Center.

 Rep. Paul Broun: GOP wants health reform 
Banner-Herald columnist Jonathan McGinty&apos;s misinformed Wednesday column on health care reform assumes I &quot;have no real interest in pursuing any measure of reform (&apos;Broun, GOP ignoring health care problems&apos;).&quot; That couldn&apos;t be further from the truth, something a simple call to my office before printing his allegation would have answered.

 Neil R. Hughes: Single-payer health care works 
A brief letter on the front page of the Banner-Herald&apos;s Sunday opinions section decrying the possibility of a public health-insurance option in this country included the admonition, &quot;To find out what government-run health care is all about, look at the U.K. and Canada ... (Random Thoughts, &apos;Don&apos;t touch health care&apos;).&quot;

 Lisa Majersky: Broun &apos;town hall&apos; a waste of time 
I just wasted an hour of my life waiting in vain in a question queue on one of Congressman Paul Broun&apos;s telephone town-hall meetings. This is just to warn anyone else who ever gets one of his robocall invitations to participate not to bother.

 Dave M. Hudgins: Despite rough economy, Flowerland not stealing ATMs 
On behalf of Caroline&apos;s Flowers Inc., doing business as Flowerland, please be advised that the picture of their delivery van in the Thursday Banner-Herald story headlined &quot;Well-equipped thieves take ATM&quot; gives the owners cause for concern. I&apos;m sure you can understand, as this could be construed by the reading public to imply that they somehow were involved in this Wachovia bank theft. As this could tend to injure their reputation and subject them to ridicule in the community, they are asking that you retract, correct and/or clarify the implication that Flowerland was in any way involved in this matter.

 Whitney Morreau: Toughen anti-bullying laws 
When schools cease to be a safe place for our children to learn, and become settings permitting fear, humiliation and violence, we must take a stand. Nationally, one out of four children is bullied. Consequences of bullying in school include disruptions in learning, absenteeism, physical illness, violence and psychological harm. We must refuse to accept bullying as &quot;just a part of life&quot; and start protecting our children more effectively.

 Spotted®: The focus is on you! 
Athens Academy Middle School student Max Ruston received Grand Recognition from Duke University for his performance on the SAT last fall. The rising eighth-grader scored better than 90 percent of college-bound seniors on the SAT as part of the Duke Talent Identification Program.

 Choir members gather to sing their old songs 
This is a story about the difference good teachers can make. Or maybe it&apos;s about enduring friendship.

 Rich: &apos;Ronda the Chicken&apos; flew the coop 
No sooner had I proudly written the column about the young boy who named his new pet chicken after me than &quot;Ronda the Chicken&quot; proved to be as unpredictable as Ronda the writer.

 Bulletin board 
The Athens-Clarke County Police Department&apos;s Crime Prevention Unit will hold two community meetings to discuss crime problems in the community: 6:30 p.m. Thursday at the Trinity Lutheran Church, 2535 Jefferson Road, and 6:30 p.m. Sept. 2 at Central Baptist Church, 720 Danielsville Road. For information, contact Lt. Terrie Patterson at (706) 613-3358, ext 223, or Nick Aguilar, at (706) 613-3358, ext 237.

 Cedar student offers up several &apos;Gifts&apos; to community 
While most teenagers spend afternoons in front of the TV, Andrew Kim has found a more productive way to pass his after-school time. As the newly elected co-president of Interact Club, a service-based organization at Cedar Shoals High School, the rising junior devotes his free time to working to improve the Athens community.

 Lewis: Summers aren&apos;t what they used to be 
This month, I&apos;ve noticed a trend. Practically every person I&apos;ve run into has commented on how short the summer has seemed.

 From Animal Control: Meet Sadie 
Sweet Sadie is a Hound mix, with a red-and-white coat, light brown eyes and sparkling smile. She is a playful gal who needs a little help walking on lead, so we suggest some obedience training. When outside her pen, she loves her rope toy, but will sit for a back scratch or tummy rub. Sadie is a high-energy dog and suited for a family who loves the outdoors, or has wide open space.

 Smith: Plan a getaway to Callaway 
PINE MOUNTAIN - There are no blooms, no autumn leaves of assorted hues that inspire you to write a hymn or sonnet - or sing one - at Callaway Gardens this time of year. A walk in the woods, however, still refreshes and reminds you that no place in our state has more of nature to enjoy.

 Births 


 Day campers, Sunday drivers, yeah 
Barrow County Emergency Services Fire Station 7 hosted day campers from the Barrow County Leisure Services July 7-9.

 Go West, young man 
Were you spotted at the fifth annual Darius Goes West Day on July 17 at the Presbyterian Student Center.

 New officers named 
The Veterans of Foreign Wars District 4 recently installed new officers for 2009-2010.

 Back to school 
Tad MacMillan, Barrow Elementary principal, meets with parents at last Saturday&apos;s Bethel Homes picnic.

 Boasting serious star power 
Recently, the Athens Chapter No. 268, Order of Eastern Star, hosted guest speaker, James Underwood.

 Above and beyond 
Paramedic Kristine Woodward of Hull was recently awarded the Georgia Society Sons of the American Revolution Emergency Medical Services Medal at the 119th Congress of the National Society Sons of the American Revolution held in Atlanta.

 A wonderful goodbye 
Reginald V. McBride retired from the Griffin-Spalding County School District after 35 years.

 Musical thank-you 
Dennis Luckey of Big D&apos;s BBQ, Court Luckey, Corey Smith, Jason Stewart of Harry Bissett&apos;s and Cassie Tetu hang out before Corey&apos;s sold-out show at Chastain Park on July 18.

 Batter up 
Former University of Georgia softball player Norie Mueller demonstrates proper batting techniques to Wolverine Youth Softball camper Peyton Ricketts during Wolverine Youth Softball Camp on the Prince Avenue Christian School campus.

 Phillips: Catching up with a young Athens artist 
Even just a few months in to writing about Athens arts for this newspaper, I knew in 1997 I was in the presence of something special.

 Mullins talks about sculpture of Dooley 
Athens artist Stan Mullins generally rises early on Sundays and takes a long run around his adopted hometown in perpetual preparation for an upcoming marathon. Although his routes often differ from week to week, there&apos;s a certain location on Lumpkin Street that he rarely, if ever, fails to trot by.

 Polaneczky: Novel says to save the rain forest 
&quot;The Great Kapok Tree: A Tail of the Amazon Rain Forest&quot; by Lynne Cherry (Harcourt and Brace Publishing, 38 pp., $14.95)

 Early American portraits on display at Winterthur 
WINTERTHUR, Del. - Among the rolling hills of Delaware&apos;s &quot;Chateau Country,&quot; a group of guests from Manhattan is being welcomed with open arms at the Winterthur Museum.

 New book sheds light on &apos;patriot&apos; 
ELLISVILLE, Miss. - Newton Knight still haunts the Piney Woods and swamps of Southern Mississippi, 140 years after the Civil War.

 Evil children subgenre can chill moviegoers 
NEW YORK - Evil kids: Can&apos;t live with &apos;em, can&apos;t kill &apos;em. Well, actually, you can. Unless they kill you first.

 Author to have book signing on Tuesday 
Brooks Mendell will have a book signing at 4 p.m. Tuesday at Borders for his book &quot;Beaverball,&quot; a story about the 1993 Massachusetts Institute of Technology baseball team that had the best season in the school&apos;s history.

 Best Bets 
Opening reception: Botanical Fantasy, 1:30-3:30 p.m., State Botanical Garden of Georgia

 Thompkins returns from gold medal run 
Representing his country was more than just an honor for Trey Thompkins, it made him a much more complete player.

 Lobbyists a driving force for reform 
WASHINGTON - A strong force, perhaps as powerful in Congress as President Obama, is keeping the drive for health care going even as liberal and conservative Democrats seem hopelessly at odds.

 Despite Obama, race still a hurdle 
WASHINGTON - President Obama&apos;s summary of the furor over a black Harvard professor&apos;s arrest was so understated, and perhaps obvious, that it barely rose above the cable-news driven din.

 CDC projects 40% in U.S. may get swine flu 
ATLANTA - In a disturbing new projection, health officials say up to 40 percent of Americans could get swine flu this year and next and several hundred thousand could die without a successful vaccine campaign and other measures.

 Feds claim 160 million doses of vaccine possible in fall 
WASHINGTON - The U.S. may have as many as 160 million doses of swine flu vaccine available sometime in October, even though manufacturers worldwide are having serious trouble brewing shots, federal health officials say.

 Scholar wants to put it behind him 
BOSTON - Harvard scholar Henry Louis Gates Jr. says he is ready to move on from his arrest by a white police officer, hoping to use the encounter to improve fairness in the criminal justice system and saying &quot;in the end, this is not about me at all.&quot;

 Flu chief: Epidemic in its early stages 
GENEVA - The global swine flu epidemic is still in its early stages, even though reports of more than 100,000 infections in England alone last week are plausible, the World Health Organization&apos;s flu chief said Friday,

 Ousted Honduran crosses border 
EL PARAISO, Honduras - Ousted President Manuel Zelaya stepped across the border into his homeland Friday, vowing to reclaim his post a month after soldiers flew him into exile.

 U.S. prisons may get some detainees 
WASHINGTON - The Pentagon&apos;s top lawyer said Friday that the Obama administration has not abandoned the possibility of transferring some prisoners from the Guantanamo Bay detention center to a prison in the United States despite strong congressional concerns.

 Democrats forge plan to cut health costs 
WASHINGTON - House Democrats announced agreement Friday on far-reaching steps designed to rein in the relentless growth of Medicare, part of a concerted effort to counter the impression that President Obama&apos;s health care legislation is in deep trouble.

 Even for N.J., graft on a stunning scale 
HOBOKEN, N.J. - Even in the state of &quot;The Sopranos&quot; and &quot;On the Waterfront,&quot; where corruption seems institutionalized, the arrest of a neophyte mayor in office a mere three weeks stands out.

 Making a profit, but not really 
NEW YORK - Corporate America is turning a profit again, but only by spending less, not making more.

 Defense chief wins battles in Senate 
WASHINGTON - Robert Gates is on a roll. Question is, how long will it last?

 As Palin leaves, questions enter 
ANCHORAGE, Alaska - Gov. Sarah Palin gained fame - and to some infamy - since she embarked on a vice-presidential bid less than a year ago.

 Investors upbeat, but not overly so 
NEW YORK - Optimists are back in control of the stock market, but they are cautious optimists.

 Obama prods states on school reforms 
WASHINGTON - Dangling the promise of $5 billion in grants, President Obama pressured states to embrace his ideas for overhauling the nation&apos;s schools, ideas that include performance pay for teachers and charter schools.

 California officials in state of dread 
SACRAMENTO, Calif. - California officials are warily awaiting the next round of state revenue figures, concerned that their latest budget-balancing efforts may not be enough to end a seemingly endless stream of deficits.

 Bush weighed using troops for arrests 
WASHINGTON - The Bush administration in 2002 considered sending U.S. troops into a Buffalo, N.Y., suburb to arrest a group of terror suspects in what would have been a nearly unprecedented use of military power, The New York Times reported.

 As election looms, Taliban stirs strife 
KABUL - Less than a month before Afghanistan&apos;s presidential election, Taliban fighters wearing suicide vests attacked a provincial capital Saturday, triggering gunbattles that killed seven militants. U.S. envoy Richard Holbrooke said it is &quot;extraordinary&quot; to hold a presidential election during a war.

 Ex-adviser: Me and Jackson had &apos;secret&apos; 
LOS ANGELES - A former financial adviser to Michael Jackson said Friday that he was the person who recently turned over to executors $5.5 million, which had been &quot;a secret between Michael and me.&quot;

 Treasury, Fed chiefs squaring off in D.C. 
WASHINGTON - Treasury Secretary Timothy Geithner and Federal Reserve Chairman Ben Bernanke staked out opposing sides Friday in a turf war over who should protect Americans from shady mortgage lending, abusive credit card fees, payday loans and other high-cost or risky financial products.

 Microsoft co-founder wins Indian honor 
NEW DELHI - Microsoft co-founder Bill Gates on Saturday received the Indira Gandhi Prize for Peace, Disarmament and Development from India&apos;s president, a government statement said.

 Senator stays mum on Sotomayor vote 
NASHVILLE, Tenn. - The senior Republican on the Senate Judiciary Committee said he has made up his mind on Supreme Court nominee Sonia Sotomayor, but he&apos;s not ready to make his decision public.

 A &apos;minced beef and bread&apos; - with fries 
SEOUL, South Korea - You still can&apos;t get a hamburger in Pyongyang, but the suspiciously similar &quot;minced beef and bread&quot; is for sale at the North Korean capital&apos;s first fast-food restaurant, a news report said Saturday.

 Winterville Elementary tour a preview of what to come 
Allison Dry had to rush to find some extra time this summer to get her classroom in the new Winterville Elementary School ready for an open house.

 System ails, but what&apos;s the cure? 
Most people agree that the American medical system is broken and costs are out of control, but fixing it is another matter.

 Poultry firm will close plant 
Poultry producer Pilgrim&apos;s Pride will close its Oneta Street chicken processing plant - one of its two facilities in Athens - and an Alabama plant by the middle of October, company leaders said Friday.

 ATM job tied to pro theft ring 
Investigators have linked the theft of an ATM from a bank in Western Clarke County this week to a dozen other ATM thefts since December 2007, mostly in the Atlanta area, Athens-Clarke police said Friday.

 Gas station fined for gouging 
State consumer investigators fined an Athens gas station $1,000 for overcharging people buying gas at the business last September following a supply shortage blamed on Hurricane Ike.

 Fears Atlanta may go hunting for more water 
If Congress is unable to work out a deal to allow metro Atlanta to continue drawing water from Lake Lanier, the region could begin to look elsewhere - including to Athens.

 Sharecropper&apos;s house to be added to Heritage Park 
When Albert Ward started looking for a house, he didn&apos;t go to a local real-estate agent. He went to the Watkinsville postmaster.

 Some question purpose of dramatizing lynching 
Hundreds of onlookers will gather in Walton County today to watch dozens of amateur actors recreate one of the most harrowing unsolved race crimes in North Georgia history.

 Free grants fair scheduled Thursday 
Representatives from state and federal agencies will share tips about getting grants at a Grants Fair U.S. Rep. Paul Broun organized at the Georgia Center for Continuing Education, 1197 S. Lumpkin St.

 Bingo event offers supplies for students 
Students can win school supplies at Back to School Bingo events that the Athens-Clarke Leisure Service Department will hold at three of its community centers in preparation for the new school year.

 Huckaby: Summer spent getting to know Cobern Kelley 
Every year, when I was in school, the first thing we did in English class was write an essay about what we did on summer vacation.

 Sign-ups continue for YMCA programs 
The Athens YMCA is registering students for fall youth activities, including after-school programs that start the week of Aug. 10.

 State&apos;s sales tax holiday starts Thursday 
The state&apos;s back-to-school sales tax holiday will run from Thursday through Aug. 2. People can buy school supplies, clothing and computers without paying the 6 percent state sales tax.

 Shiloh Baptist plans vacation Bible school 
Shiloh Baptist Church, 100 Beaverdam Road, will hold vacation Bible school at 6 p.m. Monday through Friday.

 Madison student schedules come out next week 
Madison County High School officials will distribute class schedules next week to seniors, juniors and sophomores, though freshmen will have to wait until &quot;Freshman Day Back&quot; on Aug. 5 to get their assignments.

 The week in review 
A look back at the top stories of the week in the Athens Banner-Herald and OnlineAthens.com.

 Famous gator still a big draw 
WAYCROSS - Jim Brewer and Don Berryhill have been working nearly two years on what can be best described as a 500-piece three-dimensional jigsaw puzzle.

 Reed seeks redemption after political downfall 
ATLANTA - Ralph Reed was once a powerful force in Republican politics, able to marshal millions of religious conservatives to the polls while leading the Christian Coalition.

 Funerals today 


 Funerals today 


 Death notices 


 Death notices 


 Census sabotage: The plan to end plans 
Pssst. Hey, conservatives - I want to let you in on a devious little plan being hatched by your leaders in the media.

 Sometimes, too much weight assigned to words 
Civil cases litigated in the United States are decided by a &quot;preponderance of the evidence.&quot; In explaining what it means, judges often tell civil jurors to imagine a statue of blindfolded Lady Justice, balancing in her arms competing weight scales. If one side should outweigh the other by so much as a pebble being dropped upon it, that side is said to have met its burden of proof by a preponderance of the evidence.

 Working can be tough job for teens 
It&apos;s 9 a.m. on a Saturday. I&apos;m awakened by the buzzing of the alarm clock. I get up, take my shower, brush my teeth and put on my clothes - not just any clothes, my work uniform - and head out of the house, all before 10:45 and with only 15 minutes to make it to work. By noon, I&apos;m already counting down the remainder of my 12-hour shift, and yearning for the first of two 35-minute breaks I&apos;ll get.

 Lanoue: Everyone has role in education 
Though I have been here for only three weeks, I am compelled to respond to the Banner-Herald&apos;s July 19 editorial on the recent Clarke County Board of Education retreat (&quot;Clarke BOE, super are off to slow start&quot;).

 Editorial: Incentives needed for LEED 
Taking a broad view, there well may be reason to applaud Athens-Clarke County commissioners for working to include a set of environmentally friendly standards in the county&apos;s construction regulations. In their pursuit of that goal, however, they ought to at least consider providing some incentives to developers who might be obliged to comply with those standards.

 Thompson: Reimagining Georgia&apos;s public schools 
The question, occasioned by Flagpole publisher Pete McCommons&apos; entertaining riff on legislative inattention to public school funding during last week&apos;s local public affairs show &quot;Athens News Matters&quot; on WUGA-FM (still available on the station&apos;s Web site), is this:

 Johnson: Harvard prof provides &apos;teachable moment&apos; 
Last week&apos;s arrest of prominent African-American scholar Henry Louis Gates Jr. at his Harvard-leased home by a white Cambridge, Mass., police sergeant has sparked an intense national debate on racial profiling, placing the distrust of minorities toward law enforcement at the center of the dispute.

 Daniel: Obama&apos;s empathy no substitute for the law 
Earlier this year, President Obama described his criteria for choosing nominees to fill appointments to the Supreme Court: &quot;We need somebody who&apos;s got the heart, the empathy, to recognize what it&apos;s like to be a young teenage mom, the empathy to understand what it&apos;s like to be poor or African-American or gay or disabled or old - and that&apos;s the criterion by which I&apos;ll be selecting my judges.&quot;

 Forum: University committed to biosafety, transparency 
The University of Georgia deeply regrets the circumstances that led to the recent issuance of a citation by the state Environmental Protection Division regarding incineration of animal waste without the proper permit at the university&apos;s College of Veterinary Medicine, the Poultry Diagnostic Research Center and the Animal Health Research Center.

 McGinty: Serious study needed for vibrant church 
In 2000, former President Jimmy Carter left the Southern Baptist Convention, citing theological differences with the denomination.

 Forum: Whither your weather depends greatly on your station location 
For years, Atlanta&apos;s Hartsfield-Jackson International and Chicago&apos;s O&apos;Hare airports have competed for the title of nation&apos;s busiest airport. Last year, Atlanta won. As the official temperature stations for their respective cities, however, it seems the two airports tie - for the dubious honor of distorted data. And they&apos;re not the only ones.

 Random Thoughts: New breed of Democrats 
On Jan. 20, 1961, a newly elected Democrat president delivered an inaugural address that included the statement that &quot;the rights of man come not from the generosity of the state, but from the hand of God.&quot;

 No-maintenance living in Oconee County 
Oconee County&apos;s serene Triple Creek neighborhood features the best in beautifully finished patio homes. Beautiful brick and hardiplank exteriors partnered with full landscaping services make Triple Creek the low-maintenance living option that you&apos;ve been looking for.

 855 Parkview Drive 
Buyers looking for an authentic Victorian home with artisan appeal will love this Queen Anne-style estate privately located on 5.5 scenic acres.

 Luxurious Southern-style living! 
For buyers seeking a distinctive Southern lifestyle in a premier golfing community, this home in The Georgia Club’s North Hill neighborhood is a best bet.

 Hannah Heights 
In the heart of the fastest growing area of Madison County is the area&apos;s newest subdivision, Hannah Heights. Drive out and take a look at these new &quot;Everything Included&quot; Craftsman-style homes.

 Hardwood floors throughout! 
Buyers looking for exceptional value on a spacious brick home with hardwood floors throughout will love this four-bedroom home located in the Olde Lexington Gardens neighborhood of eastside Athens.

 The Georgia Club…A Lifestyle 
2018 Trimleston Road 
Helen London, Coldwell Banker Upchurch Realty

 1101 Coday Bluff 
European Style in Oconee County
Judy Payne–Benny Payne Realty, Inc.

 150-year-old home with daylight apartment! 
Located on the edge of downtown and only three blocks from The University of Georgia, this 150-year-old home on Finley Street is the perfect fit for buyers seeking an authentic Athens experience.

 Custom shower curtains create tile match 
Have you noticed that the newest luxury area in a home is the bathroom? In new homes, baths are often huge, having both full showers and jet tubs.

 Big, colorful flowers aren&apos;t that hard to grow 
If you&apos;re a first time homeowner, listen up. If you think you can&apos;t grow fabulous flowers, read on. If past failures have made you throw your hands up and retreat from gardening in general, get ready to rumble. There&apos;s a secret to great big bold flowers.

 Search for Homes for Sale and Real Estate for sale across our Network 
mdRealtyPro + Morris newspapers = the most comprehensive home search across our Morris Newspaper Areas.

 1100 Rowan Oak Circle 
For exceptional value in luxury living, look no further than this five-bedroom beauty located in the exclusive Rowan Oak swim/tennis community.

 1151 Rocky Branch Farm Drive 
Buyers looking for spacious living in an upscale Oconee County neighborhood will love this five-bedroom home with a finished basement that includes a full kitchen.

 1480 Georgia Club Drive–Statham 
Incredible Home Right on the Fairway
Rose Sellers–Prudential Blanton Properties

 ATHENS AREA ASSOCIATION OF REALTORSKICKS OFF CELL PHONES FOR SOLDIERS COLLECTION DRIVE 
The Athens Area Association of REALTORS(AAAR) is holding a drive to benefit Cell Phones for Soldiers. The charity uses monies from the sale of the collected cell phones to purchase calling cards for soldiers.

 JAMES R. &quot;RANDY&quot; FLANIGAN JOINS COLDWELL BANKER UPCHURCH REALTY 
Randy Flanigan has joined Coldwell Banker Upchurch Realty as a licensed REALTOR®, per Charles L. Upchurch, III, President and Broker.

 Kelly Lyn Beasley 
Kelly Lyn Beasley is proud to announce her recent affiliation with Chastain...

 MICHAEL SEGER OF SEGER REALTY, INC. NAMED ONE OF AMERICA&apos;S TOP 200 REAL ESTATE PROFESSIONALS IN RANKING SPONSORED BY THE WALL STREET JOURNAL, REAL TRENDS AND LORE MAGAZINE 
Michael Seger, From Watkinsville, GA, Had an Impressive 343 Transaction sides in 2007 on his Way to Becoming One of the Athens Area&apos;s Top Real Estate Professionals.

 Matt Thomas&amp;Atlas Sponsor Holiday Food/Toy Drive 
Matt Thomas, principal and licensed Realtor with Atlas Real Estate Advisors, is hosting a food/toy drive and pics with Santa at his holiday open house on Sunday December 14th from noon until 5pm at MadiSun Park Subdivision in Danielsville, GA.

 Athens Area Association of REALTORS®Sponsors Toy Drive 
The Athens Area Association of REALTORS®(AAAR) is holding a Toy Drive through December 16, 2008 to benefit Toys For Tots. The Athens Area Association of REALTORS®has supported the Toys for Tots Program for many years.

 Athens Area Association of REALTORS®MEMBERS ATTEND NATIONAL CONVENTION 
The National Association of REALTORS®held its Annual Conference and Expo November 5–10 in Orlando, Florida. REALTORS®had the opportunity to attend a wide variety of continuing education courses, programs, committee meetings, and the trade show.

 Local Real Estate Firms Announce Merger Plans 
Athens, GA - Local real estate firms ERA Classic City Realty and ERA United Realty of Atlanta have announced plans to merge operations, effective January 21, 2009. The combined firm will conduct business as ERA United Realty with offices located in Athens, Roswell, Marietta, Tucker, Conyers and Newnan.

 Realtors®Tell Congress Increased Housing Demand Will Stabilize the Market 
WASHINGTON, November 18, 2008 - In a statement to the House Financial Services Committee today, the National Association of Realtors®recommended a four-point plan to stimulate home sales and stabilize housing valuations.

 Athens Area Association of REALTORSCelebrates 50TH Anniversary 
2008 marks the 50th anniversary for the Athens Area Association of REALTORS Inc. Celebrating five decades which began with 21 founding members representing 14 firms, the organization will hold a commemorative event on August 15th.

 Who Are the Seniors Real Estate Specialists®? 
Elizabeth Thurmond has successfully completed the education program and has received the Seniors Real Estate Specialists®designation. SRES®are REALTORS®qualified to address the needs of home buyers and sellers age 50+.

 Athens Area Association of REALTORS®Present Fundraising Proceeds to Local Fire Departments 
The Athens Area Association of REALTORS®(AAAR) raised approx. $6,500 for the Georgia Firefighters Burn Foundation (GFBF) through Family Fun Day: REALTORS®Help Heal The Burns held October 6, 2008.

 Braves slug way to victory 
MILWAUKEE - Chipper Jones, Martin Prado and Nate McLouth homered to pace a 17-hit effort by Atlanta and Javier Vazquez struck out nine in seven innings, lifting the surging Braves over the Milwaukee Brewers 9-4 on Friday night.

 From soldier to triathlon rene-Gade 
Daniel Gade nestled himself into the seat of his racing wheelchair, positioned his hands on the two large tires at his side and relied on his upper-body strength to propel the contraption forward.

 Athletics deal away Holliday to Cards 
Matt Holliday wanted to join his new team quickly, so he hopped on a train with his wife and two sons and got to the ballpark in plenty of time.

 Andruw Jones on the comeback trail 
ARLINGTON, Texas - Andruw Jones hit as many home runs in one game for the Texas Rangers earlier this month - three - as he did all last season as a high-priced, free-agent bust for the Los Angeles Dodgers.

 Hanson dealt first loss of his career 
MILWAUKEE - Yovani Gallardo scattered four hits in 71/3 scoreless innings and drove in the only run Milwaukee needed off previously unbeaten Tommy Hanson to lead the Brewers to a 4-0 win over the Atlanta Braves on Saturday night.

 A look at the 2009 MLB Hall of Fame class 


 Lance content with third place 
AVIGNON, France - Third place has never felt better to Lance Armstrong.

 Junior on his own today 
INDIANAPOLIS - Dale Earnhardt Jr. had no trouble qualifying Saturday at Indianapolis.

 Martin oldest driver to start from pole at Indianapolis 
INDIANAPOLIS - So excited for last year&apos;s race at Indianapolis Motor Speedway, Mark Martin predicted victory six weeks before the event.

 Norman leads Senior British 
SUNNINGDALE, England - Greg Norman shot a bogey-free 6-under 64 on Saturday to grab the lead by a stroke heading into the last round of the Senior British Open.

 Appeals court rules for NASCAR on Mayfield ban 
INDIANAPOLIS - An appeals court has ruled in NASCAR&apos;s favor, granting its request to keep Jeremy Mayfield off the race track.

 Pirates sweep doubleheader from Windward 
The Athens Pirates took a doubleheader from the Windward Red Braves behind strong pitching from Ryan Poplawski and Justin Earls.

 Jefferson All-Stars roll past Polk County (Tenn.) 
The Jefferson 13-year-old All-Stars advanced to the third round of the Dizzy Dean World Series with a 10-0 beating of Polk County (Tenn.).

 Contador keeps Tour lead; Cavendish wins stage 
AUBENAS, France - Alberto Contador stayed in command with two days of racing left at the Tour de France while teammate Lance Armstrong remained in third place.

 Television 


 Television 


 Former Bulldog Isner loses to Ginepri in semis 
INDIANAPOLIS - Former Georgia tennis player John Isner fell to fellow American Robby Ginepri 6-4, 6-3 in the semifinals at the Indianapolis Tennis Championships on Saturday.

 Math professor brings students into the fold with origami 
A small group of students on the University of Georgia campus has spent its summer making paper models.

 Top flu experts in town for UGA conference 
As area health officials scramble to get ready for what could be the worst flu season in decades, some of the world&apos;s top flu scientists are heading to Athens this week.

 Edwards to join Women&apos;s Hall of Fame 
Already one of the most decorated athletes in basketball history, Teresa Edwards added to her staggering collection of honors on Saturday when the Women&apos;s Basketball Hall of Fame announced her inclusion in its 2010 class.
 
Related Content
 
 Site Web Web Search powered by YAHOO! Search 
 
CONTACT US

 Switchboard: 706-208-2200 Circulation and Delivery: 706-208-2354 Newsroom Tip: 706-208-2211 Obituary Fax: 706-543-5234 Accounts Receivable: 706-549-0123 View the Staff Directory or Send feedback 
 
ADVERTISING

 Contact a Sales Representative Place a Classified Ad Find Athens jobs Buy/Sell Automobile Buy/Sell Homes 
 
SUBSCRIBER SERVICES

 Subscribe to the Banner Herald Set Up a Temporary Vacation Stop Ask a Billing Question Change Delivery Address Report a Delivery Problem 
 
SOCIAL NETWORKING

 Follow us on Twitter Join our Facebook page 
 
Athens Banner-Herald©2012. All Rights Reserved.

 Terms of Service Privacy Policy / About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
