<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002443" url="http://forum.bodybuilding.com/showthread.php?t=845800&amp;page=1" time="2012-07-12-18:29" support="1" score="0.00012081130251883297" bingtitle="Anyone like &quot;Grade D Meat, But Edible&quot; ? - Bodybuilding.com Forums" webtitle="Anyone likeGrade D Meat, But Edible? - Bodybuilding.com Forums">
			<query id="000995" bing-rank="242"/>
	<description>Any Order Over ... of a color or texture that one would not expect. This is the same meat you would find in a hotdog, fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		24/7 Customer Service 1-877-991-3411 Contact Us Need Help? View Cart 
 
 in: Whole Site BodySpace Store SuperSite Reviews BodyGroups BodyBlogs Exercises Videos 
 Free Gift! Any Order Over $ 75 Discounts&amp;Deals - Sign Up! 
 Find A Plan Store BodySpace SuperSite Forum 
 

The Worlds #1 Bodybuilding And Fitness Forum - Save Up To 50% Off Retail Prices In Our Bodybuilding.com Store !

 
 
 
 
 Today&apos;s Posts FAQ Community 
 BodySpace BodyGroups Pictures&amp;Albums Members List BodyBlogs 
 Forum Actions 
 Mark Forums Read 
 Quick Links 
 View Forum Leaders Who&apos;s Online 
 
 
 Advanced 
 
 Forum » More General Categories » Misc. » Anyone like&quot;Grade D Meat, But Edible&quot;? 
 Results 1 to 11 of 11 
Thread: Anyone like&quot;Grade D Meat, But Edible&quot;? 
 
 
 Thread Tools 

 Show Printable Version Email this Page… Subscribe to this Thread… 
 
 Search Thread 
 
   Advanced Search 
 
 Display 

 Linear Mode Switch to Hybrid Mode Switch to Threaded Mode 
 
 
 07-15-2006, 10:41 PM #1 Lethal04 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Aug 2005 Location: Texas, United States Age: 26 Stats: 6&apos;2&quot;, 190 lbs Posts: 2,401 BodyPoints: 3048 Rep Power: 1431 
Anyone like&quot;Grade D Meat, But Edible&quot;?
 Well if you like Taco Bell then you do. A friend when I was in high school worked at Taco Bell and we told him to bring us back some food after his shift. He brought back some Tacos in an empty box that their meat came in&amp;on the side of the box it said&quot;Grade D Meat, But Edible.&quot;Pretty sick, but Taco Bell every once in awhile is pretty good. Comments? 07-15-2006, 10:43 PM #2 GeneticMishap 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Banned Join Date: Dec 2005 Age: 20 Stats: 5&apos;11&quot;, 210 lbs Posts: 587 BodyPoints: 3570 Rep Power: 0 protien is protien 07-15-2006, 10:48 PM #3 mikeslemonade 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Nov 2005 Location: San Francisco, California, United States Age: 24 Stats: 5&apos;9&quot;, 167 lbs Posts: 729 BodyPoints: 573 Rep Power: 12 What makes it grade D? 07-15-2006, 10:50 PM #4 Ruthless4Life 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Ruthless4Life Join Date: Nov 2001 Location: Pennsylvania, United States Age: 25 Posts: 14,231 BodyPoints: 2247 Rep Power: 5633 Behind the Legend
The United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) assigns a letter grade to every cut of meat it inspects, with grade&quot;A&quot;meat being the most desirable (e.g., fillet mignoin) and grade&quot;F&quot;being the least desirable (e.g., something the cat brought in from the garden). The grades are quite broad -- for example, SPAM and baloney are grade B and head cheese is C.

There is really nothing wrong with USDA grade D meat. All the label means is that the meat comes from the less desirable portions (e.g., lips, skin, hair, sexual organs, intestinal contents) of a non-standard food animal (e.g., horse, beaver, rat, laboratory chimp), and that it is of a color or texture that one would not expect. This is the same meat you would find in a hotdog, fast food restaurant, or hobo jungle.

In the 1980s, it was decided that meat of this kind, when it could not be put to a more useful purpose such as feeding hogs, could be sold for use in student lunch programs. The Congressional order that put this rule into effect is the same one that classified ketchup as a vegetable and public education as education.


 http://www.all-lies.com/legends/acad...adedmeat.shtml 07-15-2006, 10:52 PM #5 Lethal04 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Aug 2005 Location: Texas, United States Age: 26 Stats: 6&apos;2&quot;, 190 lbs Posts: 2,401 BodyPoints: 3048 Rep Power: 1431 ^^^ Thanks for explaining that. I guess grade D is standard for fast food 07-15-2006, 10:55 PM #6 mikeslemonade 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Nov 2005 Location: San Francisco, California, United States Age: 24 Stats: 5&apos;9&quot;, 167 lbs Posts: 729 BodyPoints: 573 Rep Power: 12 I don&apos;t like ketchup either, mustard is better. 07-15-2006, 11:46 PM #7 n00bi3 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Free John White Join Date: Sep 2005 Location: United States Age: 24 Stats: 5&apos;4&quot;, 148 lbs Posts: 4,186 BodyPoints: 11390 Rep Power: 1293 Originally Posted by Ruthless4Life Behind the Legend
The United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) assigns a letter grade to every cut of meat it inspects, with grade&quot;A&quot;meat being the most desirable (e.g., fillet mignoin) and grade&quot;F&quot;being the least desirable (e.g., something the cat brought in from the garden). The grades are quite broad -- for example, SPAM and baloney are grade B and head cheese is C.

There is really nothing wrong with USDA grade D meat. All the label means is that the meat comes from the less desirable portions (e.g., lips, skin, hair, sexual organs, intestinal contents) of a non-standard food animal (e.g., horse, beaver, rat, laboratory chimp), and that it is of a color or texture that one would not expect. This is the same meat you would find in a hotdog, fast food restaurant, or hobo jungle.

In the 1980s, it was decided that meat of this kind, when it could not be put to a more useful purpose such as feeding hogs, could be sold for use in student lunch programs. The Congressional order that put this rule into effect is the same one that classified ketchup as a vegetable and public education as education.


 http://www.all-lies.com/legends/acad...adedmeat.shtml Good god. ==================================================
Journal http://forum.bodybuilding.com/showthread.php?t=845762
==================================================

reppin back 1000+ if you ask... 07-15-2006, 11:58 PM #8 marcFE 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Option brah Join Date: Mar 2004 Stats: 5&apos;10&quot;, 202 lbs Posts: 9,913 BodyPoints: 6669 Rep Power: 10884 There is really nothing wrong with USDA grade D meat. All the label means is that the meat comes from the less desirable portions (e.g., lips, skin, hair, sexual organs, intestinal contents) of a non-standard food animal (e.g., horse, beaver, rat, laboratory chimp), and that it is of a color or texture that one would not expect. This is the same meat you would find in a hotdog, fast food restaurant, or hobo jungle.


wtf?

how do you get meat from hair? Anyone over 9000 will receive reciprocation 07-16-2006, 12:03 AM #9 dts1789 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Aug 2005 Posts: 10,381 BodyPoints: 41499 Rep Power: 4859 What the F*CK! Horror movie thread
http://forum.bodybuilding.com/showthread.php?t=1776961 07-16-2006, 12:08 AM #10 Buff Matt 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Banned Join Date: Dec 2003 Location: san antonio Age: 25 Stats: 5&apos;7&quot;, 170 lbs Posts: 12,413 BodyPoints: 10531 Rep Power: 0 Judging by the looks of Taco Bell meat i&apos;m not surprised at all. 07-16-2006, 12:43 AM #11 roshvillian17 
 View Profile View Forum Posts 
 Registered User Join Date: Apr 2004 Posts: 186 Rep Power: 0 officially they use&quot;select&quot;grade beef (acc to their website). which is third in terms of quality on the USDA&apos;s list. the complete list being Prime, choice, select, standard, commercial, cutter, and canner. the usda doesn&apos;t grade beef with a letter, at least not anymore acc to this:
 http://ca.answers.yahoo.com/question...3132223AAMiXn7 Age: 19
Height: 5&apos;9&apos;&apos;
Weight: 200
Squat: 405
Bench Press: 285
Deadlift: 455 
 Quick Navigation Misc. Top 
 Site Areas Settings Private Messages Subscriptions Who&apos;s Online Search Forums Forums Home Forums Main Forums 
 Supplements 
 Supplement Company Transformation Contests And More Product Reviews - Help Out! 
 Supplement Logs Sponsored Supplement Logs Company Promotion Supplement Misc. 
 Supplement Wars! Supplement Science 
 BodySpace Profiles And BodyBlogs Workout Programs 
 Advanced fat loss HELL RAISER TRAINING Workout Journals Derek Charlebois&apos; Contest Prep Section! 
 Exercises 
 Injury Recovery And Prevention 
 
 Specifically For You 
 Teen Bodybuilding 
 Teen Misc. Teen Workout Logs 
 Over Age 35 
 Over 35 Workout Journals Over 35 Misc 
 Female Bodybuilding 
 Nutrition and Supplements Training General Chat Journaling Fat Loss Female Misc. 
 Powerlifting/Strongman 
 Powerlifting Workouts - Training Journals MMA Fighting 
 MMA Training Logs 
 Olympic Lifting Powerlifting Video Library 
 For Personal Trainers 
 More General Categories 
 Post Your Pictures Post Your Own Articles! Sports Training 
 Sports Training Journals Outdoor Recreation 
 Fitness Competitions IFBB Pro Bodybuilding Nutrition 
 Nutrition Logs Nutrition Misc Keto 
 Keto Logs Keto Recipes 
 Advanced Nutrition 
 Contest Preparation 
 INBF-WNBF NPC Contest Prep Journals OCB-IFPA FAME 
 Losing Fat 
 Advanced fat loss Losing Fat Logs 
 Motivation Personals - Meet Other Bodybuilders Misc. 
 Science and Technology Sports 
 Fantasy Sports 
 WWE Wrestling Forum Religion / Politics Music Relationship Help 
 Workout Equipment 
 Latest Bodybuilding Issues 
 Topic Of The Week! 
 Workout Of The Week Wallpaper Of The Week - Create Your Own And Win! 
 BB.com - Give Us Your Ideas! Article Reviews! Careers At Bodybuilding.com 
 
 « Previous Thread | Next Thread » 
Bookmarks
 
Bookmarks

 Digg del.icio.us StumbleUpon Google Facebook Twitter 
 
 Posting Permissions
 
 You may not post new threads You may not post replies You may not post attachments You may not edit your posts 
 
 BB code is On Smilies are On [IMG] code is On HTML code is Off 
 
 Forum Rules 
 -- BBcom Default -- BBcom Black -- BBcom Mobile 
 Contact Us Bodybuilding.com Archive Top 
 Member Login 
 Remember Me 
 
 Forgot Login Info? 
 
 
 All times are GMT -7. The time now is 09:29 AM . Archive Home Store Products Careers Help Contact Us Terms of Use Checkout
	</body>
</document>
