<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002584" url="http://la.eater.com/archives/categories/fairfax_3rd.php" time="2012-07-12-18:39" support="5" score="0.004422437454300918" bingtitle="Eater LA: Fairfax &amp; 3rd Archives" webtitle="Eater LA: Fairfax&amp;3rd Archives">
			<query id="000029" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="000994" bing-rank="216"/>
			<query id="000660" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="001000" bing-rank="248"/>
			<query id="000975" bing-rank="145"/>
	<description>The story -- Bill Chait, then well on his way to ... Requisite condiments like aiolis, mustard, and ketchup ... They&apos;re calling it the &quot;first organic fast food restaurant in LA.&quot;</description>
	<body>
		City 
 National Maine Boston New York Philadelphia Washington DC Charleston Miami Atlanta Chicago New Orleans Houston Dallas Austin Denver Las Vegas Los Angeles Seattle San Francisco Portland, OR 
 
 Top stories Place pages Jobs 
 
Fairfax&amp;3rd
 ACTIVE DISCUSSIONS / NEWEST POSTS Friday, July 6, 2012 Eater Guides 
 Restaurants and Bars in LA With the Hottest Servers 
 
 
The stereotype is somewhat true: Everyone in LA is gorgeous. Sometimes even that server across the dining room ... who&apos;s also a model on the side. These 10 restaurants have the hottest servers in LA. 
 Eye candy &gt;&gt; Loading comment form... Beverly/Fairfax Fairfax&amp;3rd Hollywood Santa Monica Venice West Hollywood   Comments 5:40 PM, Jul. 6 2012 Thursday, June 28, 2012 
 Loteria Grill 
 DEALFEED Loteria Grill 
 The Restaurant : Loteria Grill 
 The Deal : To celebrate Loteria Grill&apos;s 10th anniversary, all locations are offering 10 tacos for $10.
 When/Where : July 1; multiple locations.
 Loading comment form... Fairfax&amp;3rd   Comments Monday, June 4, 2012 
 Expansionwire 
 Expansionwire 
 Peet&apos;s Coffee is building out a new location at Gilmore Station, across the street from The Original Farmers Market, and just across the way from newly opened Mendocino Farms . Farmers Market personnel say the project is at least three months from completion . [ELA]
 Loading comment form... Fairfax&amp;3rd   Comments Thursday, May 31, 2012 Eater Inside 
 Mendocino Farms Gives Gilmore Station Sandwiches 
 
 Click here to view the full photogallery. 
The Gilmore Family, owners of The Original Farmers Market, recently finished construction of Gilmore Station , the newest offshoot of their popular marketplace. Across Fairfax, it&apos;s anchored by Trader Joe&apos;s, and the newest location of LA&apos;s beloved Mendocino Farms , open today . Mario del Pero and Ellen Chen&apos;s gourmet sandwich market has the prime corner spot on the lot, and fills it well.
 Design details. &gt;&gt; Loading comment form... Mendocino Farms 175 S. Fairfax Avenue, Los Angeles, CA 90048 Fairfax&amp;3rd   Comments 9:49 AM, May. 31 2012 Mendocino Farms 175 S. Fairfax Avenue, Los Angeles, CA 90048 USA 34.0721 -118.361 Thursday, May 17, 2012 Plywood Report 
 Mendocino Farms Fairfax&amp;3rd Starts Serving on May 31 
 
 Click here to view the full photogallery. 
 Mario del Pero &apos;s Mendocino Farms is slowly but surely creeping into the best parts of the city, after being a downtown destination for so long . The gourmet sandwich market opened locations in Marina del Rey and West Hollywood in the last couple of years. This month, it adds a new location near The Original Farmers Market on Third and Fairfax. It&apos;s a simple operation, rooted in the tradition of good ingredients, but with playful combinations (Drunk’n Goat on Highway 128, Spicy Lemongrass Steak Banh Mi, Vegan BBQ Torta) that only a California-based business could thrive on. Del Pero is cautiously excited about his expansion plans, which involve opening another location somewhere in LA later this year. Signage was posted on the building earlier this week, and construction is nearly complete. Mendocino Farms on Third and Fairfax opens to the public on May 31 .
· All Mendocino Farms Coverage [~ELA~]
 Loading comment form... Mendocino Farms 175 S. Fairfax Avenue, Los Angeles, CA 90048 Fairfax&amp;3rd   Comments 1:40 PM, May. 17 2012 Mendocino Farms 175 S. Fairfax Avenue, Los Angeles, CA 90048 USA 34.0721 -118.361 Friday, May 4, 2012 Facelifts 
 New Products, New Presentation at Monsieur Marcel 
 
 Click here to view the full photogallery. 
Amidst all of the new marketplace/cafes opening up around town comes news from The Original Farmers Market. Monsieur Marcel is getting a facelift. Owner Stephane Strouk is redesigning his marketplace to flow better, with a new section for registers, a more visible wine selection, and larger tables for confections and candies. Soon, Strouk will also move the cheese and charcuterie counters so that they face the Farmers Market and are visible to passers-by. The whole project should be complete by this summer . All the while, Monsieur Marcel remains open for business. [EaterWire]
 Loading comment form... Monsieur Marcel 6333 W 3rd St., Los Angeles, California 90036 Fairfax&amp;3rd   Comments 3:38 PM, May. 4 2012 Monsieur Marcel 6333 W 3rd St., Los Angeles, California 90036 USA 34.0714 -118.36 Eater Radar 
 Open 
 Graffiti 
 
 Trattoria Neapolis 
 
 Towne Food&amp;Drink 
 
 Vitello&apos;s 
 
 Sycamore Kitchen 
 
 Bon Vivant Market 
 
 Hamburger Hamlet XP 
 
 Kitchen Table 
 
 Laurel Hardware 
 
 Copenhagen Pastry 
 [more] 

 Reviewed 
 The Pikey 
 
 Maison Giraud 
 
 Gusto 
 
 Bizarra Capital 
 
 Black Hogg 
 
 Post&amp;Beam 
 
 Freddy Smalls 
 
 ink. 
 
 Racion 
 
 UMAMIcatessen 
 [more] 

 Closed 
 Fresh East 
 
 The Spanish Kitchen 
 
 Kokomo Cafe 
 
 Doughboys Bakery 
 
 Playa Cantina 
 
 Bodega Wine Bar Hollywood 
 
 Acapulco Restaurante Y Cantina 
 
 Batch Restaurant and Bar 
 
 Cafe Bella Roma 
 
 Chado Tea House 
 [more] 

Radar updated Tuesday, Jul 10 2012 at 3:51PM
 Plywood Update 
 Construction Starts on Gordo&apos;s The Fat Cow at The Grove 
 
 

Just last week, The Farm was still serving The Grove&apos;s mall crowd. Earlier today, a tipster spotted new signage for Gordon Ramsay and Andi Van Willigan &apos;s forthcoming European farm-to-table gastropub, The Fat Cow . A full bar is planned , no word yet on opening date.
· Gordon Ramsay Opening The Fat Cow at The Grove [~ELA~]
· Gordon Ramsay Opening Gastropub at The Grove [~ELA~]
 Loading comment form... The Fat Cow 189 The Grove Dr Los Angeles, CA 90036 Fairfax&amp;3rd   Comments 2:11 PM, May. 4 2012 The Fat Cow 189 The Grove Dr Los Angeles, CA 90036 USA 34.0718 -118.356 Monday, April 30, 2012 ExpansionWire 
 Mendocino Farms to Open at Third&amp;Fairfax on May 22 
 
 
 Four solid locations and counting . Mario del Pero , owner and creator of the popular casual eatery Mendocino Farms , writes in to announce that he will launch his fifth farm-friendly sandwich shop in the new complex at Third and Fairfax, across the street from The Original Farmers Market. The large corner space is next to a stationary store and across from Trader Joe&apos;s, also not terribly far from his newish Santa Monica Blvd location. As with all of del Pero&apos;s recent projects, Poon Design is on board to put the space together by May 22 . Expect the same open floor plan and award-winning design.
· Expansionwire [~ELA~]
 Loading comment form... Fairfax&amp;3rd   Comments 1:12 PM, Apr. 30 2012 Mendocino Farms Third and Fairfax, Los Angeles, CA USA Thursday, April 26, 2012 Eater Inside 
 It&apos;s Okay to Make a Faux Pas Next Week 
 
 Click here to view the full photogallery. 
 Kristofer Keith is just about ready to unveil his newest Spacecraft design creation, Faux Pas . The space near the corner of Third&amp;Fairfax was most recently Rama , and Celadon before that. While the outside remains covered in Spacecraft&apos;s signature black plywood, the interior has been entirely redone.

 Menu and more. &gt;&gt; Loading comment form... Faux Pas 7910 W 3rd St Los Angeles, CA 90048 Fairfax&amp;3rd   Comments 12:34 PM, Apr. 26 2012 Faux Pas 7910 W 3rd St Los Angeles, CA 90048 USA 34.0715 -118.362 Popular 
 Most read Most commented 
 

 Wednesday, April 18, 2012 Eater Tracking 
 Dylan&apos;s Candy Bar Posts Signage at The Farmers Market 
 
 Dylan Lauren , daughter to clothing designer Ralph Lauren and creator of Manhattan&apos;s eponymous candy shop Dylan&apos;s Candy Bar , is in full expansion mode . Last summer, Lauren announced plans to open new locations of Dylan&apos;s Candy Bar across the country and the first of these is coming to fruition in Los Angeles. Earlier this week, Bath&amp;Body Works at the Farmers Market shuttered and the signage over right was posted.

The 1,200 square foot space will house the same selection of candy as the Manhattan store, but may incorporate locally made confections as well. A spokesperson for the Farmers Market said that the store could be open &quot;in a few months.&quot; Signage promises that the store will be complete by Fall 2012 .
· Coming Attractions [~ELA~]

 Loading comment form... Dylan&apos;s Candy Shop 6333 W 3rd St., Los Angeles, CA 90036 Fairfax&amp;3rd Mid-City/Grove   Comments 1:12 PM, Apr. 18 2012 Dylan&apos;s Candy Shop 6333 W 3rd St., Los Angeles, CA 90036 USA 34.0714 -118.36 Friday, February 24, 2012 Good News/Bad News 
 Short Order Falls Short On Service, High in Price 
 
 The hullabaloo surrounding the opening of Short Order reached a fever pitch nearly a month before the place even started serving. The story -- Bill Chait , then well on his way to becoming an empire builder , backed Nancy Silverton (and her burger blend, sold at nearby Huntington Meats ) and (mastermind) Amy Pressman in their humble burger stand endeavor -- was endearing. There was tragedy: The food world&apos;s sadness was palpable when word broke that Pressman had passed. And then vindication: With the project nearly complete, Silverton continued to carry the torch that lit those Short Order griddles, and on Friday, November 18, Short Order opened for dinner. Since then, the bloggers, Yelpers, commenters and critics have created a steady stream of opinion. Here, now, in another Good News/Bad News , we review the written word. As always, additional opinions are welcome in the comments below.

 The Good News: &quot;The first thing I noticed here was the beef... A thick patty was cooked medium-rare, pink/red throughout. Looked like the cross-section of a perfectly grilled steak. Clearly the restaurant wanted to showcase this meat and it didn’t disappoint—beefy and juicy, delicious.&quot; [ DarinDines via Chow ]

 Elizabeth Daniels 2/12 
 MORE &gt;&gt; Loading comment form... Short Order 6333 W. 3rd St., Los Angeles, CA 90036 Fairfax&amp;3rd   Comments 1:07 PM, Feb. 24 2012 Short Order 6333 W. 3rd St., Los Angeles, CA 90036 USA 34.0717 -118.36 Monday, October 10, 2011 Eater Tracking 
 Short Order Opens in Nov, Snag A Pre-Taste of Short Cake 
 
 

Over the weekend those behind Short Order (aka the late Amy Pressman and partner Nancy Silverton ) posted to Twitter the above pictured shot of her soon-to-debut casual burger concept. Short Order&apos;s opening has been slightly pushed back from mid October to the first week of November , at which point Short Cake , Pressman&apos;s nearby seasonally-inspired bakery, will launch as well. In fact, Short Cake might open a few days before Short Order. AND, if you&apos;re looking to score an early Short Cake taste, come by The Farmers Market Fall Festival on October 16 from 3-6PM for sample bites.
· All Short Order Coverage [~ELA~]
· All Short Cake Coverage [~ELA~]
 Loading comment form... Short Order 6333 West Third St. Los Angeles, CA Fairfax&amp;3rd   Comments 1:05 PM, Oct. 10 2011 Short Order 6333 West Third St. Los Angeles, CA USA 34.0714 -118.36 Eater LA Flickr Pool Contribute to the
 Eater LA Flickr pool www. flick r .com Tuesday, August 30, 2011 
 Currywurst Now Open on Fairfax 
 . Currywurst Now Open on Fairfax 
 Phone: 310-204-4450 
 Status: Opened yesterday 
German sausages are invading Los Angeles. After a few months of careful construction, owner Kai Loebach opened Currywurst on Fairfax and 1st to serve his memory of the popular transient fast food. Loebach hails from Wuppertal, Germany and his knowledge of the savory treat is extensive. Unlike the other spots that serve currywurst in town, Currywurst has only a few items on the menu. The namesake link is a pork and veal sausage served mild, medium or hot with ketchup on the side. Also on offer are a pork (Hungarian) sausage and chicken thuringer. The side sauces can get a little crazy (ranch mayonanaise?); sauteed onions, sauerkraut and garlic-y French fries are necessities. Everything on the menu costs under $6.50; beer and wine are not yet served. Open daily, 11AM to 11PM.
 Loading comment form... Fairfax&amp;3rd   Comments 12:19 PM, Aug. 30 2011 Currywurst 109 N. Fairfax Ave., Los Angeles, CA 90036 USA Thursday, July 21, 2011 
 Monsieur Marcel 
 DEALFEED Monsieur Marcel 
 The Restaurant : Monsieur Marcel 
 The Deal : Present your ticket stub from either the Pacific Theatres at the Grove to Monsieur Marcel’s Farmers Market bistro or from the AMC Theatres to their Promenade bistro and receive free hors d’oeuvres with purchase of a glass of wine. Those visiting the Farmers Market location also have the option to present their movie ticket for 20% off a select bottle of wine at Monsieur Marcel’s gourmet market (offer only valid on the same day the movie was viewed, limit one per customer).
 When/Where : Through August 31; multiple locations .
 Loading comment form... Fairfax&amp;3rd   Comments Monday, July 12, 2010 Crucial Updates 
 Nancy Silverton To Open &apos;Short Order&apos; This Winter 
 
 
It&apos;s been a while since the last update on Nancy Silverton and biz partner Amy Pressman &apos;s planned burger joint taking over the former Du-par&apos;s Bakery at the Farmers Market on Fairfax. First off, the name has been changed from the working title of Market Burger to Short Order , and the new expected opening is this winter . As previously reported, the eatery will have two floors (designed by architect Osvaldo Maiozzi) and the overall idea here is a fast casual burger spot . Silverton&apos;s signature burger will be comprised of a beef blend from Huntington Meats, also located within the Farmers Market, but she also plans to serve non-beef burgers made from pork, lamb, fish, even tofu, in addition to a slew of sides, apps, salads, and desserts. Requisite condiments like aiolis, mustard, and ketchup will be made in-house. As for beverages, think custard-based shakes and local beer/wine.
· Nancy Silverton Opening Short Order This Winter [GS]
· New Details on Silverman and Pressman&apos;s Market Burger [~ELA~]
 Loading comment form... Short Order 6333 West Third St. Los Angeles, CA Fairfax&amp;3rd   Comments 11:45 AM, Jul. 12 2010 Short Order 6333 West Third St. Los Angeles, CA USA 34.0714 -118.36 1 2 3 Next&gt; 
Sign up for our newsletter
 
 New Listings at Eater Jobs 
 

 
Follow Eater LA
 
Where to Eat

 Eater&apos;s 38 Top Restaurants Map Heatmap: Where to Eat Now Map Heatmap: Where to Drink Now MAP LA&apos;s Best Chinese Outside of the SGV MAP LA&apos;s Oldest Restaurants Map LA&apos;s Top New Brunch Spots MAP LA&apos;s Best Korean Cuisine in Koreatown MAP LA&apos;s Best Pastry Shops MAP A Guide To LA&apos;s Best Coffee Shops MAP A Guide to LA&apos;s Happy Hour Deals MAP LA&apos;s Most Expensive Restaurants MAP The Pikey New Mercado New Gusto New Bäco Mercat 
 
News by Neighborhood

 Atwater Village Baldwin Hills Beverly Hills Beverly/Fairfax Brentwood Burbank Cahuenga Pass Calabasas Century City Cerritos Chino Hills Culver City Downey Downtown Eagle Rock East L.A. Echo Park Fairfax&amp;3rd Fairfax District Food Trucks Glassell Park Glendale Hancock Park Hermosa Beach Highland Park Hollywood Inland Empire Koreatown LAX Larchmont Las Vegas Leimert Park Long Beach Los Feliz Malibu Manhattan Beach Mar Vista Marina del Rey Melrose Mid-City Mid-City/Beverly Center Mid-City/Grove Mid-Wilshire North Hollywood Northridge Pacific Palisades Pasadena&amp;Environs Pico-Robertson Playa del Rey Redondo Beach San Gabriel Valley San Pedro Santa Monica Sherman Oaks Silver Lake South Bay South LA Studio City The OC The Valley Thousand Oaks Topanga Canyon Torrance Universal City Venice West Hollywood West LA Westlake Westwood Woodland Hills 
 
Tipping is customary
 la@eater.com 
Advertise with us
 sales@curbed.com | Media kit 
Monthly archives
 Select month... July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 June 2007 May 2007 April 2007 March 2007 February 2007 January 2007 December 2006 November 2006 October 2006 All archives 
From our partners






 
Preferences
 Open external links in new tabs? Eater Vegas Dining Confidential 
 Christophe Tassan&apos;s Dangerous Liaison with French Fare 
 Curbed LA Video Interlude 
 Here It Is: Episode One of the K-Town Reality Show 
 Racked LA SaleWire 
 Whitney Port is Having a Sample Sale This Friday 
 
Get daily updates and breaking news alerts from Eater LA delivered straight to your inbox:
 
 Curbed National Curbed Boston Curbed Cape Cod Curbed NY Curbed Hamptons Curbed Philly Curbed DC Curbed Atlanta Curbed Miami Curbed Chicago Curbed Detroit Curbed LA Curbed SF Curbed Seattle 

 Eater National Eater Boston Eater NY Eater Philly Eater DC Eater Charleston Eater Atlanta Eater Miami Eater NOLA Eater Chicago Eater Austin Eater Dallas Eater Houston Eater Denver Eater Vegas Eater Seattle Eater PDX Eater SF Eater LA 

 Racked National Racked NY Racked Chicago Racked LA 

 About Eater LA Privacy policy Terms of service Contest rules Advertising Jobs 

 
 ×
	</body>
</document>
