<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002457" url="http://hamptoninn.hilton.com/en/hp/hotels/index.jhtml?moreDesc=true&amp;ctyhocn=ORFHAHX" time="2012-07-12-18:30" support="1" score="0.0025698643196484777" bingtitle="Hampton VA Hotels - Hampton Inn Hampton-Newport News Hotel ..." webtitle="Hampton Hotels | Hampton Inn Hampton-Newport News | Hampton, VA">
			<query id="000281" bing-rank="105"/>
	<description>Your Confirmation # ... Suites Hotels Enjoy a complimentary cooked-to-order ... Hampton Hotels Count on Hampton to deliver quality ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Content 
 
 My Reservations My Reservations View Promotions 
 Sign In Not a Member? Explore the Benefits       /   My Account Sign Out     Username or HHonors # Password or PIN Sign In   Remember Me Forgot Password? Sign in to view all reservations in your account: Username or HHonors # Password or PIN Sign In   View/change a specific reservation: Your Confirmation # Last Name Find   Existing Travel Reservations: 
 Hotel + Air + Car reservation Air itinerary Car rental details 
 Your Next Stay: See all 
     
 View/Edit 
 Your Last Stay: See all 
     
 View Receipt Book Again 
 Join Hilton HHonors™ Upgrade your account and earn points at over 3,600 hotels in 82 countries around the world. Join HHonors                       
     HP 
 Skip brand navigation 

 Find a Hotel Offers Meetings&amp;Events About Hampton 
 Search 
 skip form 
 
 Where are you going? City, airport, address, attraction, or hotel 
 Arrival You are now focused on a datepicker field. Press the down arrow to enter the calendar table. Once focused on the table, press left or right to navigate days. Press up or down to navigate between weeks. Enter to select. Escape to close datepicker. Your arrival date must be within the next year.   Departure You are now focused on a datepicker field. Press the down arrow to enter the calendar table. Once focused on the table, press left or right to navigate days. Press up or down to navigate between weeks. Enter to select. Escape to close datepicker. Your departure date must be within 4 months after your arrival date.   
 Rooms Adults (18+) Children Rooms 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26+ Adults in Room 1 1 2 3 4 Children in Room 1 0 1 2 3 4 Room 2 Adults in Room 2 1 2 3 4 Children in Room 2 0 1 2 3 4 Room 3 Adults in Room 3 1 2 3 4 Children in Room 3 0 1 2 3 4 Room 4 Adults in Room 4 1 2 3 4 Children in Room 4 0 1 2 3 4 
 
 Use HHonors Points 
 
 Use flexible dates 
 Add special rate codes (AAA, AARP, etc) 
 Promotion/Offer code: 

 Group code: 

 Corporate account: 
 
 Travel agent 

 AAA rate * 

 AARP rate * 

 CARP rate * 

 Government / Military rates * 

* ID required at check-in
 Close Find it   Find it Check Availability Our Best Rates Guarantee 
 
 close tab panel 
 offers Browse our specials and packages to find great deals for your next Hampton stay. see our specials and packages 
 featured offers last minute deals popular offers 
 End of tab panel 

 
 close tab panel 
 groups Taking a trip with a travel sports team or group? Hampton can help you book five rooms or more at a special rate. reserve a group of guestrooms meetings We can help you make your meeting run smoothly when you reserve a meeting room at Hampton. book a meeting social occasions Hampton is the perfect place for your guests to stay during your special event. We can help you organize and plan for your big day. start planning your special occasion End of tab panel 

 
 close tab panel 
 why Hampton? Learn about how Hampton can help you along your journey. see all our amenities locations No matter which one of our locations you visit, you’ll get the full Hampton experience. find a Hampton new hotels Find out about our newest hotels and where we’re scheduled to open soon. see all new hotels End of tab panel 
   Not what you&apos;re looking for? Find Nearby Hotels HHonors Reward Category: 3   

 Hotel Information Check-in: 3:00 pm Check-out: 11:00 am Smoking: Available Parking: Self parking: 
 
 
 (COMPLIMENTARY) Valet: Not Available Pets: Service animals allowed: Yes Pets allowed: No Hotel Policies Where we are 
Find where we are located
 View the Maps&amp;Directions Page 
 Hampton,VA ORFHAHX Local Weather 
This content will open in a overlay
 Five Day Forecast While You&apos;re in Town Restaurant and attraction reviews near this hotel – from travelers like you View Now ORFHAHX 
Hampton Inn Hampton-Newport News
 3101 Coliseum Drive, Hampton, Virginia, 23666, USA TEL: 1-757-838-1400 Book a Room 
 Welcome to the Hampton Inn Hampton-Newport News. Our hotel is located just footsteps from the new Peninsula Town Center, the popular Hampton Coliseum and the new Convention Center. Whatever brings you to town, you&apos;ll feel at home in the place where the past, present and the future come together. /resources/media/hp/ORFHAHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/hx_hotelext_1_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Hampton-Newport News Hotel, VA - Hotel Exterior 0 
 Exterior 
 Our staff will be happy to help you with directions and restaurant recommendations. /resources/media/hp/ORFHAHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/hx_frontdeskguest_2_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Hampton-Newport News Hotel, VA - Front Desk 1 
 Rooms&amp;Suites 
 Of course you&apos;ll sleep on Cloud Nine - the Hampton Bed Experience. Each room also features a 32&quot; LCD TV as well as complimentary high-speed internet access. /resources/media/hp/ORFHAHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/hx_2queen_3_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Hampton-Newport News Hotel, VA - Two Queen Beds 2 
 Rooms&amp;Suites 
 Our lobby provides the perfect area to interact with other guests. /resources/media/hp/ORFHAHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/hx_lobbyguests_4_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Hampton-Newport News Hotel, VA - Lobby 3 
 Rooms&amp;Suites 
 Of course you&apos;ll sleep on Cloud Nine - the Hampton Bed Experience. Each room also features a 32&quot; LCD TV as well as complimentary high-speed internet access. /resources/media/hp/ORFHAHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/hx_kingstd_5_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Hampton-Newport News Hotel, VA - King Standard Room 4 
 Rooms&amp;Suites 
 Welcome to the Hampton Inn Hampton-Newport News. Our hotel is located just footsteps from the new Peninsula Town Center, the popular Hampton Coliseum and the new Convention Center. Whatever brings you to town, you&apos;ll feel at home in the place where the past, present and the future come together. /resources/media/hp/ORFHAHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/hx_indoorpool_6_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Hampton-Newport News Hotel, VA - Indoor Heated Pool 5 
 Amenities 
 You&apos;ll be able to keep up with your exercise program in our fitness center. /resources/media/hp/ORFHAHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/hx_fitcenter_7_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Hampton-Newport News Hotel, VA - Fitness Center 6 
 Amenities 
 The Business Center is available 24 hours for you to print documents and boarding passes, check email messages or surf the web. /resources/media/hp/ORFHAHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/hx_buscenter_8_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Hampton-Newport News Hotel, VA - Business Center 7 
 Amenities 
 The Hampton Inn Hampton-Newport News features two meeting rooms of 575 square feet each. /resources/media/hp/ORFHAHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/hx_mtgroom_9_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Hampton-Newport News Hotel, VA - Meeting Room 8 
 Events&amp;Meetings 
 Our breakfast staff keeps the counters well-stocked with a different hot menu each day. /resources/media/hp/ORFHAHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/hx_bkfstserver_10_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Hampton-Newport News Hotel, VA - Complimentary Breakfast 9 
 Dining 
 
 
 Skip secondary navigation 

 At A Glance Hotel Details Maps&amp;Directions Rooms&amp;Suites Plan An Event Special Offers Dining Things To Do 
   
At A Glance
 

comfort and convenience in Hampton.

Located off I-64, the Hampton Inn Hampton-Newport News is just a short drive from the Jamestown Settlement and Colonial Williamsburg where you can see how the colonists lived when they settled in America. Even closer is the Virginia Air and Space Center where you&apos;ll find a decidedly more modern, yet equally impressive, take on our nation&apos;s history. For a little outdoor adventure, head out to the largest privately maintained park in the country. The 550-acre Mariners&apos; Museum Park is perfect for hiking, picnicking and fishing, not to mention home to an incredible maritime museum. And it&apos;s only one of many local parks just minutes away from our Hampton hotel.

Whether you’re vacationing, just stopping through or here for a long business trip, we want you to feel at home at our hotel in Hampton. That’s why we go the extra mile to make sure you’re well taken care of. The friendly team at the Hampton Inn Hampton-Newport News are ready to help make your stay a fun and relaxing one. If you need anything while you’re here– from an extra pillow to recommendations for a harbor tour—just ask.

 
About The Hotel
 
Hotel Facts
 

 Moments from Jamestown Settlement 109 comfortable guest rooms Accessible rooms available Large indoor pool 1150 sq. ft of flexible meeting space 

 Rooms&amp;Suites 
Included in Every Stay
 

 Free hot breakfast Clean and fresh Hampton bed® Free high-speed internet access in every room Gym/Fitness Center Use 

 Amenities 
 Share Print 
 
 
   
 Skip to top of page 
 
 Hilton HHonors Worldwide Waldorf Astoria Collection The luxury brand offering a unique service experience and world’s landmark hotels. Conrad Hotels&amp;Resorts A world of style, service and connection for today’s sophisticated traveler Hilton Hotels The global leader in hospitality with more than 540 hotels&amp;resorts across six continents. DoubleTree Warm. Comfortable. Smart. The hotel that turns travel into a human experience again. Embassy Suites Enjoy a complimentary cooked-to-order breakfast and more at our upscale all-suite hotels. Hilton Garden Inn Treat yourself with amenities that help you work smarter, eat well, sleep deeply and stay fit. HamptonInn Count on Hampton to deliver quality, value, consistency and service with a smile. Homewood Suites Whether you&apos;re traveling for a few nights or for a few months, you can Make Yourself at Home® Home2 Suites Introducing Home2 Suites by Hilton®-- an all-suite brand of extended stay hotels. Hilton Grand Vacations Enjoy all of the benefits of
owning your own vacation home–with none of the
hassles. About our brands 
 
 Global Sites: 

 Germany Japan United Kingdom 
 
 About Hampton Site Map Hilton Worldwide Careers Development Media RoomKey.com Customer Support 1-800-HAMPTON Privacy Policy (Updated Dec 2011) Site Usage Agreement ©2012 Hilton Worldwide
	</body>
</document>
