<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002467" url="http://www.city-data.com/forum/ohio/30630-tell-me-about-lima-3.html" time="2012-07-12-18:31" support="2" score="0.003607613372819875" bingtitle="Tell me about Lima (Columbus, Defiance: section 8, city hall, rent ..." webtitle="Tell me about Lima (Columbus, Defiance: section 8, city hall, rent) -  Page 3 - City-Data Forum">
			<query id="001188" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="001177" bing-rank="89"/>
	<description>Tell me about Lima (Columbus, Defiance: section 8 ... everyone pays with a credit card, you go to fast food restaurant ... In order for my SO to get certain necessary ...</description>
	<body>
		City-Data Forum &gt; U.S. Forums &gt; Ohio Tell me about Lima (Columbus, Defiance: section 8, city hall, rent) 
 
 User Name Remember Me Password 
 
 
 Register Today&apos;s Posts Search 
 
 
 Search Forums Show Threads   Show Posts Advanced Search Search Blogs Advanced Search 
 
 Go to Page... 
 Welcome to City-Data.com forum! Make sure to register - it&apos;s free and very quick! You have to register before you can post and participate in our discussions with 1 million other registered members. User profiles and some forums can only be seen by registered members. After you create your free account you will be able to customize many options, you will have the full access to over 15,000 posts/day about local topics and you will see fewer ads. 
 
 Jump to a detailed profile or search
site with 
 Search Forums   ( Advanced ) 
 Business Search - 14 Million verified businesses 
 Search for:  near:  
 
 
 
 Page 3 of 6 &lt; 1 2 3 4 5 6 &gt; 
 
 
 
   09-13-2007, 10:45 AM 
 Art1979 American city adventurer   Location: Findlay, OH 630 posts, read 1,169,431 times Reputation: 281 
 Quote: 
 Originally Posted by Crew Chief &quot;Lima; it&apos;s not your average bean town&quot; 
 Ok, that got a chuckle. I didn&apos;t think anyone outside a 50 mile radius knew about that. They even have cookbooks with that emblazoned on the cover. 
 
 
 
 
   09-15-2007, 12:32 PM 
 Crew Chief  Senior Moments!   6,131 posts, read 8,704,127 times Reputation: 9175
	</body>
</document>
