<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002597" url="http://www.ehow.com/credit-card-accounts/" time="2012-07-12-18:40" support="5" score="0.009904779205343434" bingtitle="Credit Card Accounts - How To Information | eHow.com" webtitle="Credit Card Accounts - How To Information  | eHow.com">
			<query id="001177" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="001304" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="000989" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000737" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="001461" bing-rank="48"/>
	<description>Credit Card Accounts how to ... first job at a fast food restaurant or ... may place an order online or over the telephone and forget to tell you what kind of credit card she ...</description>
	<body>
		money section 
 Saving&amp;Spending 
 Budgeting Banking Credit Cards Loans 
 Real Estate 
 Buying a Home Home Loans Selling a Home 
 Careers 
 Career Advice Land the Job Work for Yourself 
 Your Business 
 Starting a Business Managing Employees Running a Business 
 Insurance 
 Insurance Basics Auto Insurance Life Insurance 
 Retirement 
 Get Started Plan Ahead Make It Last 
 
 
 More eHow 
 home mom style food tech money health 
 
 Featured: Allergies eHow Now Blog 
 eHow Personal Finance Credit Cards Credit Card Accounts 
 
Credit Card Accounts

 
 RSS 
 Can a Suspended Credit Card Account Be Reinstated? 
A credit card company can choose to suspend an account for several reasons, including irresponsible spending practices and inability to make timely payments. Reinstating these credit accounts could be as easy as paying a penalty or it could be as difficult as repairing your credit score and developing better strategies for managing your finances.
 How to Separate Credit Accounts During a Separation 
When you and your spouse decide to separate, you deal with splitting both your personal lives and your economic ones. While dividing marital property can be as straightforward as deciding who gets the blender and who gets the toaster, dividing credit-card debt that is held in both names is rarely that simple. It is a necessary, though, to ensure a complete economic separation and to achieve the highest possible level of financial safety.
 Does Each Credit Card Account Show Up on Your Credit Report? 
When you use your credit card, it has the potential to impact your credit score, as your actions with the card will show up on your credit report. When you have multiple credit card accounts, all of the information from the accounts should show up on your credit reports with each bureau.
 What Can a Credit Card Issuer Do for an Unpaid Account? 
When you apply for a credit card, you don&apos;t intend to get in over your head financially. However, excessive use of credit cards can lead to large monthly bills that you may have difficulty paying. This may cause you to miss payments and fall behind on your debt. Your creditor may take several actions if you do not make your credit card payments.
 Does Paying on a Collection Account Reflect on Your Credit? 
According to the Fair Isaac Corporation, collection accounts can negatively affect your credit. If you pay one off, though, it shows as a paid collection on your credit report, changing its date from the past to the date of payment. When you know to whom you should speak and how to pay off a debt that has gone to collections, you can avoid the potentially undesirable impact of keeping it on your report longer than necessary.
 Can Credit Cards Have Joint Accounts? 
If you want to set up a credit card account in such a way that more than one person can use it, you can get a joint credit card account. Each account holder will get a credit card on which he can charge expenses, but all the cards are linked to one account.
 What Is Realistic Budgeting? 
If you have ever wondered where your money goes, or if you would like to make your cash go further, you should construct a budget. A carefully prepared budget is the foundation of sound financial management, helping you to plan for both the expected and the unexpected. It highlights where and when shortfalls are likely to occur and can prompt you to make valuable changes to your financial situation. A budget based on incorrect facts or unrealistic assumptions will see you stumbling at the first hurdle -- but an accurate and realistic budget can significantly improve your financial health.
 Do Overdraft Accounts Show on My Credit? 
Even the best of us may experience an embarrassing moment when our bank account is overdrawn. An account is overdrawn when there is not enough money in the account to pay all of the claims against the account. This is sometimes referred to as an overdraft. While it&apos;s embarrassing, you should understand what will and won&apos;t affect your credit.
 How to Request a Credit Reference 
Whether you are a consumer or in the business of lending money or financing items on credit, know how to request a credit reference. A credit reference provides information about your past borrowing history from other lenders and can be a deterrent to receiving a loan, especially if it indicates many nonpayment or late payment issues. Many companies use your credit scores and references as a method to determine whether you will repay a loan and how good a credit risk you will be.
 How Do I Cancel a NoteWorld Trust Account? 
NoteWorld Trust is a debt management company. The program allows you to enroll in a debt payment plan that partners with the companies to which you are indebted. Your payments are debited from your bank account by NoteWorld each month and dispersed to your creditors on the designated dates. Should you decide to cancel your account at any time, you are free to do so by contacting NoteWorld.
 Harley Davidson Motor Technician Certification 
A person who studies motorcycle technology gains the skills to perform repairs, diagnose motorcycle problems and perform general maintenance. You may learn general motorcycle repair; however, as a certified mechanic you can learn specific skills to work on Harley-Davidson motorcycles. Numerous technical schools offer both general motorcycle technician and Harley-Davidson technician certifications. Some courses can be completed in approximately one year.
 The Salary of a Harley Davidson Mechanic in Arizona 
Harley Davidson motorcycles are one of the most classic of American icons. These motorcycles are often associated with freedom and the open road. However, like any motorized vehicle, Harley Davidson bikes occasionally break down and need to be repaired. Motorcycle mechanics are a specialized field in the broad field of mechanic work as the engines are much smaller and more difficult to repair due to their small size.
 Recurring Bill Agreement 
Recurring bill payments, also called automatic payments, can save time and money. Recurring bill agreements can be established to pay mortgage payments, credit card payments, utility bills and gym memberships. A recurring bill agreement is an agreement that allows a business or company to automatically debit your checking account or credit card on a certain day each month. The payment will be withdrawn until the bill is paid off, or until the agreement is canceled. Before setting up a recurring bill payment, examine your budget to determine when and how much you can pay on a certain day each month.
 How Much Does a Harley Davidson Mechanic Get Paid? 
Harley Davidson is an iconic motorcycle manufacturer that specializes in large bikes, which are ideal for long trips on the highway. Like any vehicle, motorcycles require periodic maintenance to keep the engine, wheels and other parts in good working condition. The U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics provides income data on all motorcycle mechanics, which includes mechanics that repair Harley Davidson bikes.
 How to Set Up a Schwab Visa with Quicken 
Quicken is a well-known personal-finance program that is used by many people. One of the primary functions of Quicken is to link to your bank and credit-card accounts and download your balance and transaction information automatically, allowing you to track your financial activity on a day-by-day basis. Linking your accounts to Quicken just once allows you to manage your money with the program, saving you time and effort.
 Harley-Davidson Mechanic Salaries 
Harley-Davidson is one of the leading names in American motorcycle manufacturing. Learning how to work on Harleys is a highly specialized segment of the overall motorcycle mechanic profession, with the Motor Company&apos;s Twin Cam, Evolution, Revolution and other V-twin engine configurations being proprietary and iconic. For those with a passion for classic American iron, becoming a Harley-Davidson mechanic is a way to work intimately with the big bikes.
 How to Allow Recurring Billing on Sites 
As the Internet continues to weave its web further into the activity of our daily lives and functions, the need for individuals and small business owners to allow recurring billing has grown. Recurring billing saves the consumer the time of logging into their accounts to make payments for services which reoccur each month. Additionally, the benefit to the merchant is an opportunity to lock in customers for a monthly commitment with the ease of pay recurring billing provides. You can allow recurring billing through an online credit card processing site such as PayPal.
 The Average Cost for Car Insurance for an 18-Year-Old Male 
Teenage drivers and drivers younger than age 25 generally pay higher car insurance premiums. Young male drivers under 25 years old often pay the highest rates as insurance companies consider them to be high-risk drivers. Other factors, such as where you live and the type of car you drive, also affect the cost you pay for auto insurance.
 The Average Car Insurance Costs for an 18-Year-Old Boy 
The auto insurance industry assigns a level of risk to drivers based on a number of factors, such as age, gender, location and background. Unfortunately for teenage males, they have among the highest car insurance rates. Insurance companies view them as a greater risk than girls of the same age, or older, more experienced drivers.
 How to Set up a PayPal Plus Credit Card in Quicken 
PayPal offers its customers a number of financial products, including debit and credit cards. The PayPal Plus credit card, now called the PayPal Extras card, is a MasterCard credit card issued by GE Money Bank. Even though PayPal provides access to information about the card balance and charges on the cardholder&apos;s PayPal account, businesses and individuals can also use Quicken to keep track of spending. Since GE Money Bank is a widely recognized institution, adding the card to Quicken is a simple process.
 How to Authorize Recurring Billing 
Recurring billing is a convenient feature that many companies offer, allowing customers to pay their account balance on a regular basis without the hassle of writing a check, making a telephone call or implementing an online transaction. When you sign up for recurring billing, you typically authorize the company to automatically withdraw the payment amount from your bank account or charge it to your credit card each month. A one-time setup process is usually sufficient to begin and maintain recurring billing with most companies.
 Credit Card Help for Seniors 
Seniors on a limited pension may depend on credit cards to help meet unexpected expenses. If the monthly income is already strained, then credit card help may be necessary to restore solvency. A financial plan will help to manage your debt load. You have several choices when looking for credit card help.
 Does an 18-Year-Old Have to Have Auto Insurance in Michigan? 
Most states have laws requiring all drivers to provide some form of auto insurance for their vehicles. Auto insurance applies to vehicles rather than individuals, and covers any authorized driver. Michigan is among the states that imposes specific auto insurance minimum coverage on all resident drivers, regardless of age or experience level.
 How to Re-Open a Closed Credit Card Account 
When you (or your creditor) close your credit card account it is usually a final action. The creditor removes the available line of credit and reports the account as closed to credit bureaus. Closing the account can negatively affect your credit score. If so, in some cases, you may have success in getting the credit card company to re-open the account.
 How Do Banks Handle Inactive Credit Card Accounts? 
Banks typically have a different view of inactive credit card accounts than cardholders do. Banks look at credit accounts in terms of how they affect their business, while cardholders consider the amount of credit card debt they accumulate. The opposing views may cause problems for consumers who suddenly see a change in their credit accounts due to inactivity.
 How to Cancel an IdentityLookout.com Account 
Identitylookout.com is a website designed to protect your identity by monitoring your credit reports on a daily basis. Partnered with Experian, one of the three major credit bureaus in the United States, identitylookout.com enables customers to protect themselves against identity theft by closely monitoring the use of their credit. If you no longer wish to continue with your identitylookout.com account you can cancel at anytime without paying any fees or penalties.
 If a Credit Card Account Is Closed by the Lender Can It Ever Go Into a Positive Status? 
Credit card companies take the closing of an account very seriously, and when they do so the decision is usually permanent. Card companies usually close accounts because of nonpayment, and that process can take several months as the card company waits for the account holder to resume paying as agreed. When that does not happen, the card company closes the account -- with no chance for the account holder to reestablish it as a positive account.
 What Is a Random Credit Card Number? 
Random credit card numbers are either a huge, almost unstoppable risk to a consumer&apos;s account or a tool that keeps an account number nearly entirely concealed. The function of a random credit card number depends on how you use it. The best and legal way to use a random credit card number is as a way to hide a legitimate credit card number.
 Credit Cards Closed Due to Dormancy 
Credit cards are a helpful resource to have in the event of an emergency. If you do not use your account regularly, however, your credit card may not be there for you when you need it the most. Credit card issuers reserve the right to close accounts due to inactivity.
 Credit Card Responsibility Act 
An amendment to the Truth in Lending Act, the Credit Card Accountability, Responsibility and Disclosure, or CARD, Act regulates practices in the credit card industry widely considered unethical by consumers. The CARD Act went into effect in stages, beginning in the summer of 2009 and culminating the following year. Not only does this law protect consumers from dishonest lending practices, it regulates credit card fees, which helps card holders save money.
 How to Know the Date You Are Supposed to Pay Your Fingerhut Payment 
Fingerhut was founded in 1948 by William and Manny Fingerhut. The brothers originally sold automobile accessories but then moved to general retailing in 1952. The company is known for its relatively easy credit-granting process. The company send outs millions off catalogs annually. Fingerhut&apos;s credit program is administered by Meta Bank, which provides different credit options and low monthly payments.
 The Credit Card Accountability Responsibility and Disclosure Act 
The Credit Card Accountability Responsibility and Disclosure Act, or the CARD Act, was passed in May 2009. It increased the protections for consumers from abusive fees, penalties and interest rate changes, and contained the most changes since the Truth in Lending Act was passed in 1968. All of the changes had to be implemented by February 22, 2010, but some went into effect in 2009.
 Seniors With Credit Card Problems 
Many seniors earn fixed incomes and find it difficult to pay the expenses that come with old age and retirement. With limited sources of income, seniors turn to credit cards to cover their living expenses. Credit card can lead to excessive debt accumulation for seniors who can&apos;t effectively manage their debts.
 The Credit Card Accountability, Responsibility and Disclosure Act of 2010 
The United States government enacted the Credit Card Responsibility, Accountability and Disclosure Act (CARD Act) in three phases beginning in August 2009. The second phase began in February 2010, and the third and final phase was effective in August 2010. The CARD Act set forth new laws and regulations in the credit card industry.
 Department Store Credit Card for People With Credit Problems 
Many department and retail stores offer credit cards to qualifying consumers. Users of these cards can make purchases at the store, and pay off the purchase over time. They work much like regular credit cards, allowing you to buy things even if you do not have all the money, and charge interest on your balance until it is paid off. People with credit problems should be wary of opening a department store credit card.
 How to Become a Service Writer for Harley-Davidson 
If you have a love for the Harley-Davidson product and possess the ability to convey information between a customer and a technician, as well as understand the mechanics of a motorcycle, you might consider a career as a service writer with Harley-Davidson. Service writers, also known as service advisers, play an important role in the Harley-Davidson repair and maintenance process. Although there are no formal education requirements for a service writer job, Harley-Davidson does make some recommendations before applying at a dealership.
 Why Is it Important to Raise Your Credit Score? 
The sub-prime mortgage crisis caused lenders to tighten their credit criteria. A credit score that once had lenders beating a path to your door and offering their keenest rates may no longer have the same effect. If you want to obtain low interest rates and the most competitive prices across a range of essential services, you may need to raise your credit score.
 How Are Credit Scores Arrived At? 
Among history&apos;s greatest secrets is the formula for credit scoring developed by the Fair Isaac Corporation. Although we do not known exactly how the FICO formula calculates scores, we know what information it uses to arrive at a score and a general idea of the weights of the most important factors.
 How to Remove Your Property From RealtyTrac 
RealtyTrac is an online service that helps to sell your home without the assistance of a real estate agent, which is a process also called For Sale By Owner (FSBO). RealtyTrac offers you the tools and support you need to make a sale on your home provided you pay a monthly fee for it. Once you have concluded using RealtyTrac, you will want to remove your listed property from the online service.
 If I Paid Off a Credit Card&amp;Cancelled It, Can I Reopen That Account? 
A credit card that is paid off and cancelled is considered closed and cannot be reopened. However, a new account can be opened following a credit check. Your status as a former customer may allow you to accomplish this easily over the telephone. Resuming use of a credit card is easier when you have the account open after paying it off. Some people store cards they are not using in a bank safe deposit box to avoid impulse spending.
 Can a Credit Card Account Closed Due to Delinquency Ever Be Good Again? 
A credit card account closed because of delinquent payments is unlikely to be reopened. However, the card holder is free to apply for a new account. MSN Money reports that credit card companies typically close credit card accounts after payments fall six months behind. The account then is listed as charged off on credit reports and sold or assigned to a debt collector.
 Can I Reopen a Charged-off Credit Card? 
Though most credit card lenders will not re-open an account after charging off a delinquent balance, some lenders will work with capable debtors to re-establish the account. If the debtor cannot re-establish credit, or if the balance remains unpaid, the lender may sell the account and the debtor may endure renewed collection activities.
 Should You Cancel Unused Credit Cards? 
You may have accumulated more credit cards than you need for many different reasons. If you have a wallet full of plastic but you&apos;re not using all those accounts, you may be tempted to close them out. However, closing old credit card accounts can have both negative and positive effects on your credit score. You should be aware of how and when to close accounts if you want to spring clean your wallet without damaging your score.
 Do-It-Yourself Credit Card Debt Settlements 
Credit card debt can follow you for years unless it&apos;s paid or settled. If you&apos;re not in the position to pay off your credit card debt in full, you may be able to settle that credit card for less than you owe. Debt settlement firms charge fees for their services so it&apos;s wise to understand how to settle the credit card debt yourself for free.
 What is a Credit Card Accountability Responsibility Disclosure? 
The Credit Card Accountability Disclosure and Responsibility Act in a federal law that gives consumers certain rights when it comes to credit cards. The CARD Act requires credit card companies to adhere to specific regulations and helps alleviate some of the practices consumers felt were abusive and deceptive on the part of card issuers.
 Credit Card Collection Regulations 
Passed in 1978, the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act, FDCPA, protects consumers against harassment by third-party debt collectors. The Federal Trade Commission enforces the FDCPA. The act covers credit card debt, automobile loans, home mortgages, medical bills and most any other household debts. The FDCPA does not protect against debt collection associated with the running of a business.
 If My Credit Card Account Is Closed Due to Delinquency, Is it a Collection Account? 
A credit card company can choose to close a card account at its discretion after evaluating the account. One common reason for closure is delinquency (late payments). If card closure occurs, it is important to ask about the status of the account and determine whether this will cause collections activity.
 Budget Planning for 18-Year-Olds 
Parents may push their children and teenagers to start budgeting as soon as they get their first job at a fast food restaurant or start having bills, like the monthly cell phone bill. Eighteen-year old teenagers should start making a budget for their money, since 18 marks several milestones, including become a legal adult and starting a prosperous postsecondary educational journey.
 Can an 18-Year-Old Get a Car Loan? 
Turning 18 means you are old enough to apply for a car loan; however, it doesn&apos;t mean you will get one. Lending institutions generally want you to have two years of built-up credit in good standing before they are willing to take a risk on a car loan. At 18, you haven&apos;t had enough time to build a credit history, but there are ways you can still get a vehicle loan approved.
 How to Write a Proposal for Credit Cards 
Credit cards offer consumers a way to purchase items without breaking the bank, but large balances combined with high interest rates can sometimes overwhelm credit card holders and threaten to do just that. The U.S. Census Bureau reports there are an estimated 180 million credit card holders in America in 2011. A percentage of that number will fall behind on payments or worse -- fall into collections. Before this happens, consumers should contact their credit card provider and propose an alternative, including a settlement, a lower interest rate or a smaller minimum balance.
 Can You Reopen a Closed Credit Card? 
While carrying credit card debt is usually a bad idea, closing an account -- even one you do not use -- can be worse for your credit rating. Reopening a closed an account, however, usually does not benefit a credit card company unless it is trying to boost its debt portfolio or you are a highly valued customer. If you have other cards, a closed account won&apos;t matter much anyway.
 A Good Credit Card for An 18-Year-Old 
Teens can begin earning a good credit score early through the responsible use of a credit card. Credit card programs are available to help teens learn how to manage credit card debt while taking advantage of a wide range of perks. Once your child reaches 18, he has the option to apply for an array of cards.
 Credit Card Collection Questions 
If you miss a credit card payment, you can expect to hear quickly from someone in a collections department. Credit cards are unsecured debt, and the only way that creditors have to make you pay is to contact you aggressively to elicit an emotional response, or to threaten you with negative reporting on your credit report. Here are some questions and answers about the collections process.
 What Is a Revolving Credit Card in a Department Store? 
When shopping in a department store, you may be offered a discount on your purchase if you apply for the store&apos;s credit card. This may save you a small amount of money initially, but there may be drawbacks to applying. Understand the terms of a revolving credit card and how it can affect your financial status, both now and in the future.
 How to Fund a Credit Card 
Many banks and financial institutions offer prepaid credit cards or debit cards. These cards function like normal credit cards, but before using the card, you need to fund the prepaid card. When you make a purchase using the card, the prepaid funds are automatically deducted from the card&apos;s balance. Since the prepaid cards are issued by different banks and financial institutions, the exact methods for funding a prepaid card will vary from card to card.
 Important Information on a Credit Card Statement 
Each month, you receive your credit card statement in the mail and depending on your issuer and activity, it can be several pages. Your statement is comprised of several sections and each section has important information about your billing activity, changes in your account status and terms and conditions of using the card, including payment terms.
 How to Check a Visa Number 
The International Standards Organization (ISO) and the American National Standards Institute (ANSI) developed the standards for creating valid credit card numbers. These standards are observed by all major credit card issuers including Visa, Mastercard and Discover. While the ISO and ANSI do not publish their rules and guidelines for public perusal, you can still check and identify whether a Visa card number is valid.
 How Can I Open a Closed Credit Card Account? 
Sometimes consumers will close a credit card account to avoid increasing their debt or because they never use the card. Other times, the creditor itself will close the account due to inactivity, delinquency or failure to pay. In any case, reopening a closed credit card account can benefit a person&apos;s credit rating if the account holder wishes to erase the negative notation of &quot;closed by creditor&quot; from his or her credit report. It can also help cash-strapped individuals who need access to credit. Unfortunately, reopening a closed credit card account ultimately lies at the discretion of your creditor.
 How to Find an Old Fingerhut Account 
Founded in 1948, Fingerhut is a nationally known home shopping company offering the convenience of catalog, phone and online shopping to its consumers. The company offers a free 30-day at-home trial for all of the products it offers. If you have an established account with Fingerhut but are unable to access the account, you can take steps to re-establish your relationship with the company.
 How to Check for a Valid Credit Card Number 
If your business takes credit cards, there may be instances when you want to check whether a customer has given you a valid credit card number. In most cases, a quick swipe through a credit card transaction machine as provided by your bank will do the trick. If this isn&apos;t feasible, then there are ways to manually check the validity of a credit card number.
 How to Reopen an Account that the Credit Card Company Closed 
If you or a credit card company closed one of your old credit card accounts but you now want to reopen the account for the benefits it can have on your credit report and score, you can make a formal request to have the account re-opened. In most cases, an account can be re-opened in a matter of minutes giving you immediate access to your old or new extended line of credit for purchases, withdrawals and balance transfers. The credit card issuer will report your end of billing cycle balance to the three national credit reporting bureaus each month.
 How to Renew a Subscription to the International Herald Tribune 
The International Herald Tribune aims to keep its readers in touch with global issues. It is considered to be the international version of The New York Times. The newspaper also includes business news from around the world. In addition, you will find entertainment information and opinion pieces in it. Ordering your first subscription is simple. Resubscribing is a bit trickier. But with a few pointers, you can renew your subscription online without a hassle.
 How to Buy Harley Davidson Stock 
Harley-Davidson was founded in 1903 and has certainly become one of those iconic brands of the motorbike scene, producing many sought after heavyweight bikes and other merchandise. Harley-Davidson Inc. does not sell stock directly to individuals. As a result, it is necessary to go through a third party, such as a registered stock broker, to make your desired purchase.
 Credit Card Account Number Specifications 
Although credit card account numbers may seem like a string of 15 to 19 digits with little or no rhyme or reason, they actually contain a great deal of information including the type of the card, name of issuer and even a hidden mathematical element to make it harder for people to make up a fake card number.
 Does Opening a Credit Card Account Help Raise Credit Score 
Opening a new credit card account gives you access to additional credit. But opening a new credit card also will affect your credit score. Whether it&apos;s a positive or negative effect depends on your current credit profile.
 Can I Fund a Trading Account With a Credit Card? 
While most traditional stockbrokers will only accept cashier&apos;s checks, personal checks, money orders and wire transfers to fund trading accounts, many Forex brokers will accept those forms of payment as well as major credit cards.
 How to Access a Credit Card Account 
You can usually access your credit card account 24 hours a day to learn your balance, make payments or make changes to the account, depending on which method you use. For any method of accessing your card account, you will need to prove you are the account&apos;s owner. For this, you will need your account number and other personal identifying information as requested by the bank, such as your Social Security number, password, address or mother&apos;s maiden name.
 How to Change Credit Card Information on My Account 
It is easy to shop and pay bills online with a credit card. If you currently use a credit card to make purchases or pay bills, you can change your credit card or billing information at any time. You can also add a new credit card to your online payment account.
 When Is a Credit Card Account Considered a Collection Account? 
If a credit card company does not receive payment on a credit card balance from the account owner, it will eventually charge off the debt. Credit card companies typically sell charged off debts to collection agencies rather than continuing to contact the debtor about the balance.
 How Do I Cancel a Revolving Credit Card Account? 
A revolving credit card account allows a consumer to carry over a balance and make minimum payments each month. Many people enjoy the flexibility and convenience that accompany a revolving credit card account. However, if you no longer need your revolving credit card account, you can close it.
 How to Settle Credit Card Accounts 
Unemployment or health problems can cause people to fall behind on bills, and credit card payments usually become the last priority in such a case. It does not take long for late payment fees and penalties to pile up on credit card balances, making it seem impossible to ever pay the total balance. In such cases, credit card holders have options, including debt settlement. While there are companies that can be hired to reach a debt settlement on your behalf, you can also do it yourself.
 How Long Can I Keep My Credit Card Account Over the Limit? 

 How Can I Find an Old Account Number With a Cato Credit Card? 
Finding an old account number from a Cato credit card should not be difficult--if you owned the account. Privacy laws will prevent you from receiving someone else&apos;s account information. Cato is a women&apos;s apparel specialty store chain with more than 1,300 stores in 31 states. It provides a layaway plan in addition to its own private-label credit card. Most of the company&apos;s stores are located in strip shopping centers. In addition to its Cato-branded stores, the company operates a specialty brand called It&apos;s Fashion.
 How to Make a Credit Card Deposit to a Wells Fargo Account 
Sometimes you need money fast. If your bank account is nearly empty, you may have to turn to your credit card. Wells Fargo bank allows you to deposit money from your credit card into your account. It is advantageous for you to transfer money into your Wells Fargo account from a Wells Fargo credit card. The bank will accept other credit cards, but may charge a service fee, and your credit card company may charge a higher interest rate than a Wells Fargo credit card deposit.
 Does It Affect Your Credit Report if You Settle on a Credit Card Account? 
&quot;Your most powerful wealth-building tool is your income,&quot; says financial guru Dave Ramsey. When attempting to solve your financial problems, consider the effects of solutions such as debt settlement on your credit report.
 Amazon Credit Card Account Information 
The Amazon credit card is a Visa credit card issued by Chase that can be used to make purchases anywhere that Visa cards are accepted, including online retailers. In addition to providing holders with a line of credit, the Amazon Visa card also offers users rewards that they can earn from using the card.
 How to Transfer Money Using a Credit Card From One Account to Another 
Sometimes you may find yourself without enough cash to pay a specific credit card bill. Instead of taking the hefty late fee for missing the payment deadline, one strategy is to use another credit card to transfer money onto the other account. Although it is never ideal to pay debt down with other debt, it can be a good deal in cases where you have a credit card that is offering zero interest for several months. By transferring the credit balance, you save money and buy time to pay off the bill.
 Credit Card Accountability and Disclosure Act 
The Credit Card Accountability, Responsibility and Disclosure Act, often referred to simply as the &quot;CARD Act,&quot; went into effect in stages, ending in February 2010. The CARD Act modified credit card laws to regulate credit industry practices and protect consumers from unethical and unfair charges.
 How Do I Cancel My Credit Card Account or Application? 
It sometimes happens that you apply for a credit card without realizing that some of the terms aren&apos;t favorable. At that point, your application has already been given to the credit card company, so the best thing you can do is cancel that application, or, if it&apos;s too late for that, the account itself. This can help protect you from policies you don&apos;t approve of, and keep you from owning a credit card you don&apos;t want.
 How to Reopen Credit Card Accounts 
Your current credit scores and your previous payment history may be the deciding factors in your ability to reopen old credit card accounts. The credit card companies, while acknowledging your past loyalty, will almost certainly require a new credit check. A good payment history while the accounts were active will be seen as a plus, but current credit problems could trump that and result in denials.
 Questions About Credit Card Collection Accounts 
If your delinquent credit card debt gets turned over to a collection agency, you have a collection account. Collection accounts can appear on your credit report and may influence your credit score. Having a collection account may also result in frequent phone calls from debt collectors. Many consumers have questions about how having a collection account affects them and what debt collectors can and cannot legally do to collect a debt.
 Why Keeping Old Credit Card Accounts Can Raise Your Credit Score 
Each time a person signs up for a new credit card or closes an account, her FICO score is affected. A FICO or credit score is a three-digit number used by credit rating agencies to set interest rates for borrowers. A credit score is based on five factors: payment history, debt owed, length of credit history, new credit and the type of financing used. Unfortunately, consumers sometimes aren&apos;t aware how their actions can raise or lower their credit scores.
 How to Test a Credit Card Account 
When you get a new credit card, you are required to activate it from your home phone. The activation process serves to deter theft of cards from the mail and helps to ensure that only the person who applied for the card can use it. But even though the automated activation process tells you that the card is now active and ready for use, it is still a good idea to test the card to make sure it is active. Trying to use the new card on a date and having it be declined can be very embarrassing, and testing…
 How to Set Up a Credit Card Account in Quicken 
Quicken provides a platform for managing bank account transactions as well as your other financial accounts. You can add credit card accounts to your Quicken application to track your balance, interest accumulation and spending habits. Keeping your credit card records in the Quicken application allows you to identify spending trends and manage your payment history to keep your balance manageable. Reconciling your statement within Quickbooks helps you avoid fees for exceeding your limit by tracking any unexpected charges or fees.
 How to Request a New Account Number for Credit Cards 
Credit card accounts all come with unique account numbers. This allows lenders to track borrowing behavior, locate your account when you send in an inquiry, and properly report your consumer information to the three major credit bureaus--TransUnion, Experian and Equifax. While some companies simply allow you to change this information, others require a significant breach of security before any account information is changed.
 How to Cancel a RealtyTrac Subscription 
RealtyTrac lists foreclosed and lis pendens properties. If you are a member of RealtyTrac and would like to unsubscribe from the service, you can easily do so at their website. You will lose access to the listings at the start of the next billing cycle, but will continue to receive any newsletters to which you are currently subscribed.
 How to Remove a Name From a Shared Credit Card Account 
Removing a name from a joint credit card account is a relatively straightforward process. Once someone is removed from an account, they no longer are responsible for the outstanding balance; the person remaining on the account will have sole responsibility for making the payments on the outstanding balance. Taking someone off a credit card account also reduces their debt load, which may have been preventing them from receiving credit elsewhere.
 How to Create Credit Card Accounts 
Creating credit card accounts is a simple matter of signing up for credit cards and being offered a line of credit on those credit cards from the credit card company. While the application process is simple, deciding whether you should open a line of credit and create a credit account is another matter. Simply put, credit accounts work well if you can afford to pay off the balance every month. Credit accounts can be detrimental if you have too many open accounts and cannot pay the bills.
 How to Settle Credit Card Accounts&amp;Credit Scores 
Settling credit card accounts, and thereby improving your credit score, can be accomplished with only a few short phone calls and letters. Collections agencies and credit card companies tend to use intimidating language that give the impression that the only method to discharge a debt is to pay it in full, but the reality is that all debts are entirely negotiable. Get all agreements with your creditors in writing and you will be well on your way to a high credit score.
 How to Create an International Credit Card Account 
Creating an international credit card account enables easier access to funds while abroad. International business travelers will gain particular benefits from opening such an account, as it can offer automatic currency transfers and discounts on exchange rates relative to retail money changers. Pay close attention to the card holder agreement when ordering an international credit card, as some accounts charge substantial fees for international usage.
 How to Check for Bankruptcy 
Any time an individual files for bankruptcy, that bankruptcy becomes a part of the public record. As such, the case details of the bankruptcy are viewable by anyone who chooses to research it. In the past, if you wanted to review court documents, you needed to go to the courthouse in the county where the public record was originally filed and use the court computer system to track down specific cases. With the release of the U.S. government&apos;s PACER (Public Access to Court Electronic Records) database, however, you can check out your own bankruptcy case or the bankruptcy case of…
 How to Calculate Partial Payments for a Credit Card Account 
If you want to calculate a partial payment for a credit card, there are a number of things you should take into account. The partial payment should be high enough to allow the balance to be reduced by some amount, even if it appears insignificant. A credit card company&apos;s suggested minimum monthly payment can be a percentage of the outstanding balance. Partial payments can be a lesser percentage amount.
 How to Determine if a Credit Card Account Is Delinquent 
A delinquent credit card account is one on which one or more payments have been missed but the credit card company has yet to charge off the debt. Some individuals may be hesitant to call the credit card company to inquire about the status of the account lest their phone number be recorded. This can result in frustrating telephone calls from the creditor regarding the debt. There are ways, however, to discover whether your credit card debt is delinquent without ever contacting the credit card company.
 How to Account for Recurring Credit Card Transactions 
If you have a credit card, it is a good idea to occasionally check your monthly statement to be sure there are no odd purchases or charges. You may discover that recurring charges appear around the same time each month. It is important to look into this matter to make sure you are not being billed for something incorrectly.
 How to Identify a Credit Card by the Account Number 
If you are a merchant, every now and then a customer may place an order online or over the telephone and forget to tell you what kind of credit card she is using. Without that information, you won&apos;t be able to process the order. So, you have to either contact the customer to ask her what kind of credit card she was using or learn how to decipher the account number to determine the issurer.
 How to Contact GE Capital Bank 
GE Capital Bank provides financial services to more than 100 million clients around the globe. Those clients range from everyday consumers and retailers as well as commercial clients. GE Capital Bank is divided into five divisions. The GE Money USA division helps businesses provide more financing options to their customers. GE Money USA also offers credit cards to businesses and consumers. The GE Energy Financial Services division provides financing to businesses in the energy industry. Whichever division of GE Capital Bank you are affiliated with, the company has provided easy ways to contact them if the need ever arises.
 How to Redeem Harley Davidson Visa Points 
The Harley-Davidson Visa credit card allows you to earn one point for every dollar you spend. You can use the credit card anywhere, not solely at Harley-Davidson stores. Once you earn 2,500 points, you can redeem your points for a $25 Harley Chrome cash certificate that can be used at any participating Harley-Davidson dealership. Unredeemed points expired on December 31 three years after they were earned.
 How to Handle Inactive Credit Card Accounts 
Canceling that credit card you haven&apos;t used in years may not be wise. If you are looking to raise your credit score, canceling credit cards will not work. Actually, closing these accounts may very well hurt your score. If leaving them open is tempting you to use them, there are other methods to get rid of them. Keeping an eye on your credit score and being proactive in working to raise it is important for financial success.
 How to Review My Orchard Credit Card Account 
Orchard Bank offers traditional credit cards and secured credit cards to consumers who want to build a good credit history. The company offers traditional paper statements, e-mail and text-message alerts and online account management.
 How to Check My Credit Card Account Online 
Keeping updated with the activities on your credit card account, can prevent your credit card account from going into default. Many credit card companies allows consumers to create online accounts for easier access to their accounts. Using an online account is more convenient than using the phone to check your credit card account. Online credit card accounts allows the user to pay bills, receive monthly statements, check balances and credit limits.
 How Do Merchant Accounts Work 
Merchant accounts are a necessity in today&apos;s business world, because credit cards are a universal form of payment. Understand merchant accounts, their fees and the processes with tips from an experienced financial adviser in this free video.
 How to Make a Payment to a PayPal Plus Credit Card Account 
The PayPal Plus Credit Card is a credit card issued by GE Money Bank provided exclusively to those who are PayPal members. It may be used any place that MasterCard is accepted around the world and is used in the same way as any other credit card. Some lines offer rewards, and most do not have annual fees. The credit card is managed through an individual&apos;s PayPal account, rather than through the lender&apos;s accounts. There are several options for making a payment to a PayPal Plus Credit Card account.
 About Credit Card Merchant Account Brokers 
Society is influenced greatly by economics.This is why much emphasis is placed on how transactions are conducted, and it is the driving force for the creation of new job titles related to commerce. One such position is a merchant credit card broker. If utilized wisely, such brokers can be instrumental to the financial future of your business.
 How Does a Credit Card Merchant Account Broker Spend a Workday? 
A credit card merchant account is an agreement between a business and a bank in which the bank gives the business a line of credit so that the business can accept credit card payments. Accordingly, a credit card merchant account broker&apos;s customers are businesses that do not currently accept credit card payments but would like to do so. The best way to get new clients is to aggressively market. The Internet is a great way to obtain clients by posting advertisements on relevant sites and by using text ads geared toward certain keywords (&quot;credit card merchant account,&quot; for example). Advertising…
 How to be a Savvy Chic Shopper 
Do you hate paying retail for anything? Me, too! So, I&apos;m going to share a few savvy shopping tips that I have learned along the way -- I hope this will help you save some money the next time you go shopping!
 Should I Use My Credit Card or Overdraw My Account? 
Do not use a credit card to make a purchase that would overdraw on a bank account because overdraws often lead to expensive fees. Avoid using credit cards unless it is an emergency with advice from the owner of a debt settlement company in this free video on credit cards.
 How to Collect Donations on the Internet 
This is a time of technology and the Internet promises to reduce your work when collecting donations. Whether you are raising money for a charitable disease or you need funds for the girl&apos;s soccer team, you can collect these donations online.
 How to Buy a Checkbook Calculator 
Checkbook calculators are handy tools in a budgeter&apos;s everyday life. Buying a checkbook calculator can mean the difference between a balanced and an unbalanced checkbook. Read the following tips to learn how to a buy a checkbook calculator that suits your financial needs.
 How to Protect Your Credit or Debit Card and Account Number 
To protect your account numbers, be cautious about sharing them, whether purposely or inadvertently. Know where your cards are at all times, and be suspicious of anyone who requests your number over the phone.
 
 ehow.com 
 About eHow eHow Blog How to by Topic How to Videos Sitemap 
 
Copyright©1999-2012 Demand Media, Inc.
Use of this web site constitutes acceptance of the eHow Terms of Use and Privacy Policy . Ad Choices en-US
	</body>
</document>
