<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002965" url="http://ninewords.com/Fun/The%20Red%20Green%20Show/The%20Red%20Green%20Show%20season%205.html" time="2012-07-12-19:03" support="2" score="0.001002378449899706" bingtitle="Ninewords - The Red Green Show - Season 5" webtitle="Ninewords - The Red Green Show - Season 5">
			<query id="001312" bing-rank="212"/>
			<query id="000404" bing-rank="129"/>
	<description>... hangover :: Handyman Corner – Red makes a trash ... friend are starting Possum Lake’s first fast food restaurant ... :: Adventures with Bill – Bill demonstrates cheese ...</description>
	<body>
		Season:  1     2     3     4    5    6     7     8     9     10     11     12     13     14     15 

 097 Mens Night On The Mountain The 
lodge members go to Rock Reef Point for some male bonding :: Opening Women 
accept what they are. Men prove it. :: Possum Lodge Word Game Harold , Red and Dalton (guest) word 
 sensitive :: Red and Harold sing about Duffys joints :: Red visits Garth Harble , Possum 
Lakes Animal Control Officer. Garth shows how to capture a vole :: Handyman 
Corner Red make s a chair with a built-in snack rack :: Red and Winston help you 
fix it when she wants to be held and you just give a her a hug :: Red visits Buzz and Buzz talks 
about safe bungee jumping :: Adventures with Bill Bill prepares for cliff 
diving :: The Experts Harold, Red and Edgar discuss 
Hollywood.

 098 The Driving Test Red loses his 
license and has to retest. Harold agrees to take the test for him :: Opening 
Women know where theyre going. Men drive. :: Red and Dalton help you explain 
why you arent using instructions :: Red and Harold sing about smell :: Handyman 
Corner Red creates homemade stealth technology :: Possum Lodge Word Game 
Harold, Red and Dougie (guest) word feminine :: Red visits Garth. Garth catches a rattlesnake :: 
Adventures with Bill Bill tries different methods of transportation :: Ranger Gord talks about 
animals in heat :: The Experts Harold, Red and Hap discuss whaling.

 099 The Satellite Dish Red makes a 
satellite dish and the lodge members wont stop watching TV :: Opening Women 
are watching the world. Men are watching television. :: Possum Lodge Word Game 
 Harold, Red and Bob (guest) word marriage :: Red and Harold sing about your head :: Red visits 
Ranger Gord and they talk about fire :: Handyman Corner Red turns a dashboard 
into a TV remote :: Midlife Musings Red defines middle age :: Ranger Gord 
talks about clouds :: Red and Winston help you ease the trouble youre in :: Red 
visits Buzz and they discuss ATVs :: Adventures with Bill Bill rides a pogo 
stick :: The Experts Harold, Red and Dougie discuss romance and cars.

 100 Father and Son Banquet Its time 
for the Annual Possum Lodge Father/Son Banquet :: Opening Women can bear 
children. Men cant :: Possum Lodge Word Game Harold, Red and Mike (guest) word 
friend :: Red and Harold sing about dancing :: Edgar uses hamburger and dynamite 
for home repair :: Handyman Corner Red makes a bedroom suite from tires :: 
Midlife Musings Red talks about your wife getting you new clothes :: Edgar 
gives a demolition safety tip :: Red and Winston tell you how to recover from a 
yawn during a heart-felt talk :: Adventures with Bill Bill makes a tree swing.

 101 The New Doctor Red sends an open 
invitation for a new doctor at Possum Lake :: Opening Women pursue good 
health. Men pursue good doctors. :: Possum Lodge Word Game Red and Ranger 
Gord (guest) word lonely :: Red and Harold sing about fingers :: Handyman 
Corner Red makes a golf caddie :: Midlife Musings Red tells you that you 
drive like your dad :: Red visits Buzz for safety tips :: Adventures with Bill 
Bill barbeques :: Red visits Garth. Garth gets a deer out of a house :: The 
Experts Harold, Red and Dalton discuss a gift for the nth weeding for both the 
bride and groom.

 102 The Vertical Grandstand Red wants 
to turn a transformer tower into a vertical grandstand :: Opening Women enjoy 
good entertainment. Men prefer good seats. :: Possum Lodge Word Game Red and 
Hap (guest) word liar :: Red and Harold sing about fruit :: Handyman Corner 
Red demonstrates soldering, brazing and welding :: Red visits Garth. Garth gets 
rid of a moose :: The Experts Harold, Red and Winston talk about how to spend 
your time :: Adventures with Bill Bill flies rockets :: Red and Dalton get you 
out of trouble after saying I know what Im doing.

 103 The Network Deal A big American 
network is mildly interested in the show :: Opening Women appreciate creative 
input. Men appreciate silence. :: Possum Lodge Word Game Harold, Dalton and 
Red (guest) word sex :: Red and Harold sing about Jersey OBrien :: Handyman 
Corner Red shows how to pack a suitcase :: Red visits Buzz. Buzz flying his 
plane by remote control :: Adventures with Bill Bill, Red and Harold are 
boxing :: The Experts Harold, Red and Hap discuss the greatest rock band ever.

 104 Medieval Times Possum Lodge holds 
a medieval fair :: Possum Lodge Word Game Red and Buzz (guest) word peace :: 
Red and Harold sing about life :: Handyman Corner Red makes a giant crossbow 
:: Midlife Musings Red defines a geezer :: Red visits Ranger Gord. Gords 
building a sprinkler system for the forest :: Adventures with Bill Bill and 
Red fence :: Red and Dalton tell you how to handle We need to talk :: The 
Experts Harold, Red and Edgar discuss one spouse leaving another.

 105 Van Go Buster Hadfield s 
car and Reds van are stolen :: Opening Women protect their feelings. Men 
protect their possessions. :: Possum Lodge Word Game Harold, Dalton and Red 
(guest) word art :: Red and Harold sing about a dog :: Handyman Corner Red 
burglar-proofs a car :: Red and Dougie help you cover the effects of Five-bean 
chili :: Harolds Handy Crafts Harold makes a duck decoy :: Adventures with 
Bill Bill and Red ride a bicycle built for two :: The Experts Harold, Red 
and Winston discuss joining the family business.

 106 Possum Lodge Radio Harold screws 
up the Possum Lake phone lines. The lodge members decide to go back to CB radios 
:: Opening Women like to communicate. Men like to broadcast. :: Possum Lodge 
Word Game Harold, Red and Mike (guest) word responsibility :: Red and Harold 
sing about fishing :: Handyman Corner Red makes a pay phone :: Midlife Musings 
 Red talks about your bed time :: Red visits Ranger Gord. Gord is charging fees 
for ranger information :: Adventures with Bill Bill and Red go bowling :: Red 
visits Garth and Garth talks about geese :: Mail Call Red reads a letter with 
photos of a viewers wife giving birth.

 107 X Marks The Spot Red gets an 
aerial photo of Possum Lake with an X in it. The lodge members think there might 
be treasure in the lake :: Opening Women better themselves. Men better their 
friends. :: The Experts Harold, Red and Dalton discuss the facts of life :: 
Red and Harold sing about going fast :: Handyman Corner Red makes an automatic 
lawn roller from two dryers :: Red visits Ranger Gord. Gords safety rule 
always have a buddy :: Red and Winston help you get out of missing a date with 
your wife :: Adventures with Bill Bill builds a duck blind :: Red and Hap go 
fishing and Hap talks about his days wrestling elephants.

 108 Sedgwick the Thief Old Man Sedgwick is 
stealing from everyone :: Red visits Garth. Garth gets rid of pigeons :: Red and 
Harold sing about an old car :: Handyman Corner Red makes a cable car :: 
Midlife Musings Red suggests you make friends with your new neighbors :: Red 
visits Buzz. Buzz has created a plane trailers :: Adventures with Bill Bill 
shows how to watch for pick pockets :: Possum Lodge Word Game Harold, Dalton 
and Red (guest) word trust.

 109 The Cement Load The lodge members 
are going to buy a submarine and build a submarine pen. When the sub deal falls 
through, Harold forgets to cancel the cement order and the lodge members have 
tons of cement to play with :: Opening - Women have to cement a romance. Men 
have a romance with cement :: Possum Lodge Word Game Harold, Red and Dougie 
(guest) word vacuum cleaner :: Red and Harold sing about fried foods :: Red 
visits Ranger Gord. Gord is listening to land whales (cicadas) :: Handyman 
Corner Red builds a rescue boat :: Midlife Musings Red talks about memory 
loss :: Red visits Garth and Garth talks about controlling skunks :: Harolds 
Handy Crafts Harold weaves a wool blanket :: Adventures with Bill Bill, 
Harold and Red make concrete furniture.

 110 The Gas Shortage The local gas 
station has gone out of business and Possum Lake has a gasoline shortage :: 
Opening Women travel. Men burn gas. :: Dalton and Red help you get out of 
wrecking the inside of your wifes car :: Red and Harold sing about the 
boathouse :: Handyman Corner Red puts a man-sized gas tank in the Possum Van 
:: Midlife Musings Red talks about wrinkles :: Red visits Ranger Gord and Gord 
teaches you how to avoid an attack by a bear :: The Experts Harold, Red and 
Winston discuss getting a job vs. going to college :: Adventures with Bill 
Bill uses railroad hand car technology to run a car :: Red visits Garth and 
Garth talks about catching squirrels.

 111 Trout Season Its the first day of 
trout season :: Opening Women go forward. Men go fishing :: Possum Lodge 
Word Game Harold, Red and Mike (guest) word commitment :: Red and Harold 
sing about a well-armed woman :: Handyman Corner Red makes hip waders that 
hold all his fishing gear :: Red visits Ranger Gord. Gord makes sandwiches for 
missing hikers :: Harolds Handy Crafts Harold makes a clock :: Gord paints 
the watch tower :: Adventures with Bill Bill and Red have a casting contest :: 
The Experts Harold, Red and Dougie give advice to the lovelorn.

 112 The Lost Dog A dog gets lost and 
has the whole area searching for it :: Opening - Women lament lost love. Men 
lament lost pets :: Possum Lodge Word Game Harold, Red and Dalton (guest) 
word feelings :: Red and Harold sing about singing :: Handyman Corner Red 
creates things to keep your dog from running away :: Midlife Musings Red tells 
you how to enjoy your hobbies without sharing your new toys with your kids :: 
Red visits Ranger Gord and tests Gord on the objects around the tower :: Red and 
Winston tell you how to handle I love you from your girlfriend :: Adventures 
with Bill Bill makes a dirigible :: Mail Call Red answers a viewer about 
what makes him laugh :: Red and Hap are fishing. Hap talks about all his 
Hollywood friends.

 113 The New Statue The lodge members 
destroy a town statue and decide to build a replacement :: Opening Women 
build friendships. Men build statues. :: Possum Lodge Word Game Red, Harold 
and Dougie (guest) word cheat :: Red and Harold sing about flying clothes :: 
Handyman Corner Red creates a bug repellant :: Red visits Ranger Gord. Gord is 
tagging house flies :: Adventures with Bill Bill and Red gets Bills car 
started :: The Experts Harold, Red and Winston discuss the secret to getting a 
great job.

 114 One Mans Garbage Red is selling 
the junk around Possum Lodge :: Opening Women throw out garbage. Men catch 
it. :: The Possum Lodge Word Game Red, Harold and Dougie (guest) word loud 
:: Red and Harold sing about a hangover :: Handyman Corner Red makes a trash 
compactor :: Midlife Musings Red persuades you not to look young :: Edgar 
experiments with dynamite :: Red visits Buzz. Buzz loses his plane :: Buzz 
teaches you to navigate by landmarks :: Adventures with Bill Bill plays with a 
Frisbee :: Red visits Garth. Garth captures a badger.

 115 The Big Thing A big thing is 
coming through Possum Lake :: Opening - Women value quality. Men value size :: 
Possum Lodge Word Game Harold, Red and Mike (guest) word remorse :: Red and 
Harold sing about barbequing :: Handyman Corner Red creates an inflatable 
chair :: Ranger Gord talks about forest fire prevention :: Mail Call Red 
answers a letter from a big fan :: Red visits Garth. Garth finds out that Red 
doesnt like spiders :: Ranger Gord talks about three things of nature he 
doesnt understand :: Adventures with Bill Bill and Red make scaffolding :: 
Red and Hap fish and Hap talks about getting into the Guinness Book of World 
Record ::

 116 Bottled Water The local bootlegger 
is arrested and the lodge members take over his still to make his window washing 
fluid :: Opening Women value free spirits. Men bottle them. :: Adventures 
with Bill Bill and Red install an above-ground pool :: Red and Harold sing 
about a canoe :: Handyman Corner Red builds a robot :: Midlife Musings Red 
suggests not dating your old girlfriend :: Red fishes with Hap. Hap talks about 
all the nursery rhymes and sayings he invented :: Possum Lodge Word Game 
Harold, Red and Bob (guest) word promise :: Red and Dougie help you avoid 
trouble when you dont pick up your dirty clothes :: The Experts Harold, Red 
and Dalton discuss selling bad cars

 117 Floating Church Red has a 
near-death experience and promises to go to church. He actually goes when the 
service is held on the lake :: Opening Women enjoy church. Men enjoy Sundays 
:: The Experts Harold, Red and Dalton discuss divorce :: Red and Harold sing 
about your halitosis :: Handyman Corner Red makes a life preserver vest out of 
jelly :: Red visits Buzz for a safety tip. Buzz tells you to visit the hospital 
when you get hurt :: Possum Lodge Word Game Harold, Red and Dalton (guest) 
word job :: Adventures with Bill Bill and Harold demonstrate marital arts :: 
Red visits Ranger Gord and Gord gets a promotion :: Mail Call Red answers a 
letter about Canadians speaking French.

 118 The Not-Chicken Franchise Red and 
a friend are starting Possum Lakes first fast food restaurant :: Red visits 
Ranger Gord. Gord shows how to put out a camp fire :: Red and Harold sing about 
finding a mate :: Handyman Corner Red and Harold make a neon sign :: Midlife 
Musings Red talks about looking good :: Possum Lodge Word Game Hap and Red 
(guest) word friends :: Adventures with Bill Bill and Red play soccer :: The 
Experts Harold, Red and Dougie discuss a birthday gift for mom.

 119 The Compost Heap The lodge member 
decide to grow beer nuts :: Opening Women make compost heaps. Men make 
garbage piles. :: Edgar describes a new version of dynamite :: Red and Dalton 
help you tell your daughter what you think of her new boyfriend :: Red and 
Harold sing about a camp fire :: Handyman Corner Red plants beer nuts :: Red 
visits Buzz and Buzz talks about the safety measures for his long-distance trip 
:: Edgar discusses the proper fuse length to use :: Mail Call Red looks at 
photos sent in by a viewer :: Red visits Ranger Gord. Gord shows Red some of his 
duties :: Adventures with Bill Bill and Red use a chipper-shreader :: Possum 
Lodge Word Game Red and Garth (guest) word control :: Red and Dougie help 
you when you leave the seat down.

 120 Homemade Cheese Junior Singleton makes cheese :: Opening Women mature. Men ferment. :: Adventures with Bill 
Bill demonstrates cheese making :: Red and Dalton help you get rid of your 
in-laws :: Red and Harold sing about friends :: Handyman Corner Red show you 
the signs of animal infestation :: Midlife Musings Red reveals middle-aged men 
know everything :: The Experts Harold, Red and Winston discuss cosmetic 
surgery :: Mail Call Red answers a letter where the Os and Es are backwards.
	</body>
</document>
