<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002759" url="http://www.yelp.co.uk/search?find_desc=nigerian+restaurant&amp;find_loc=London" time="2012-07-12-18:49" support="1" score="0.0019605239967072025" bingtitle="Nigerian restaurant London - London Restaurants, Dentists, Pubs ..." webtitle="Nigerian restaurant London">
			<query id="001473" bing-rank="153"/>
	<description>As the kind old Nigerian lady behind the counter explained to me, &quot;It&apos;s like Kebab, but with Spice.&quot; That&apos;s a good description. Suya is chargrilled meat, and at ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Search Form Skip to Navigation Skip to Page Content 

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 Log In Sign Up for Yelp Friends&apos; Activity 0 Loading... 
 Yelp is using Facebook to personalize your experience. What is this? Not you?
 Log out of Facebook Don&apos;t want to be connected?
 How to turn this off 
 
 Yelp 
 Search for (e.g. pizza, pub, greasy spoon) 

 Near (Address, Area , City or Postcode) 
 Search 
 Welcome About Me Write a Review Find Reviews Find Friends Messaging Talk Events 

 Member Search 
   
nigerian restaurant London 
 Skip to search results 1 to 10 of 55 - Results per page: 10 20 30 40 Hide Filters 
Sort By

 Best Match Highest Rated Most Reviewed 
 
Areas

 De Beauvoir Peckham Walworth Burgess Park 
 …More Areas» 
More Areas»
 
 
 London 
 Select all Deselect all 
 Abbey Wood Abbotts Langley Abridge Acton Addington Addlestone Alderstead Heath Aldgate Alexandra Palace Alperton Anerley Angel Archway Arnos Grove Arsenal Ashford Ashtead Aveley Avery Hill Badgers Mount Balham Banstead Banstead Heath Barbican Barking Barnes Barnet Barnsbury Barons Court Battersea Bayswater Beacontree Beckenham Beckton Belgravia Bellingham Belmont Belsize Park Belvedere Bermondsey Berrys Green Bethnal Green Bexley Bexleyheath Bickley Biggin Hill Blackfriars Blackheath Bloomsbury Borehamwood Borough Botany Bay Bounds Green Bow Bow Common Bowes Park Brent Cross Brentford Brick Lane Bricket Wood Brixton Brixton Hill Broadway Market Brockley Bromley Bromley-By-Bow Brondesbury Buckhurst Hill Buckingham Palace Burgess Park Burgh Heath Bush Hill Park Bushey Byfleet Camberwell Camden Town Canada Water Canary Wharf Canning Town Canonbury Canons Park Carshalton Caterham Catford Chadwell Heath Chalk Farm Charlton Chase Cross Cheam Chelsea Chelsfield Chertsey Chessington Chigwell Chinatown Chingford Chipstead Chislehurst Chiswick Church End Clapham Clapham Common Clapham Junction Clapham Park Clapton Claygate Clerkenwell Cobham Cockfosters Coldblow Coldharbour Lane/ Herne Hill Colindale Collier Row Colliers Wood Coulsdon Covent Garden Cranham Crayford Crayford Ness Cricklewood Crockenhill Crouch End Croxley Green Croydon Crystal Palace Cudham Custom House Dagenham Dalston Dartford De Beauvoir Denham Denmark Hill Deptford Derry Downs Dollis Hill Downe Dulwich Ealing Earls Court Earlsfield East Dulwich East Finchley East Ham East India Dock East Molesey Eastcote Eden Park Edgware Edmonton Elephant&amp;Castle Elm Park Elmers End Elmstead Eltham Emerson Park Enfield Enfield Chase Epping Forest Epsom Erith Esher Euston Ewell Excel Fairlop Farleigh Farnborough Farringdon Feltham Finchley Finchley Central Finchley Road Finsbury Park Fitzrovia Foots Cray Forest Gate Forest Hill 

 Friern Barnet Fulham Fulham Broadway Fulwell Gants Hill Gidea Park Goddington Golders Green Goodmayes Grange Hill Grange Park Green Park Greenford Greenwich Gunnersbury Hackbridge Hackney Central Hackney Downs Hackney Wick Hadley Wood Haggerston Hainault Ham Hammersmith Hampstead Hampstead Garden Suburb Hampstead Heath Hampstead Village Hampton Hangar Lane Harefield Harlesden Harold Hill Harold Wood Harringay Harrow&amp;Wealdstone Harrow on the Hill Hatch End Havering-atte-Bower Havering Park Hawley Hayes Hayes (Kent) Heathrow Hendon Heston Hextable Highams Park Highbury Highgate Hillingdon Hinchley Wood Holborn Holland Park Holloway Homerton Honor Oak Park Hornchurch Hornsey Horton Hounslow Hoxton Hoxton Square Hyde Park Ilford Isle of Dogs Isleworth Islington Iver Joyden&apos;s Wood Kenley Kennington Kensal Green Kensal Rise Kensal Town Kensington Kensington Gardens Kensington Olympia Kentish Town Kenton Keston Kew Kew Gardens Kidbrooke Kilburn King&apos;s Cross Kingsbury Kingsland Kingston Upon Thames Kingswood Knightsbridge Knockholt Ladbroke Grove Ladywell Laleham Lambourne Lee Leicester Square Lewisham Leyton Leytonstone Limehouse Lisson Grove Little Venice Liverpool Street / Broadgate London Bridge London City Airport London Fields Long Ditton Loughton Lower Holloway Maida Hill Maida Vale Malden Manor House Marylebone Mayfair Merton Mile End / Globe Town Mile End (South) Mill Hill Millwall Mitcham Monks Orchard Morden Mortlake Motspur Park Mottingham Mudchute/Cubitt Town Muswell Hill Neasden New Cross New Cross Gate New Southgate Newbury Park Newington Newington Green Nine Elms Noak Hill Noel Park Norbury North Acton North Cray North Finchley North Kensington North Woolwich Northolt Northumberland Heath Northwick Park Northwood Norwood (West&amp;Upper) Notting Hill Nunhead Oakwood Old Kent Road Olympic Village Orpington Osterley Oval Oxshott Paddington Palmers Green Park Langley Park Royal Parliament Hill/Dartmouth Park Parsons Green Peckham Peckham Rye Penge Perivale Petticoat Lane Petts Wood Piccadilly Pimlico Pinner Plaistow Plaistow (South) Plumstead 

 Poplar Potters Bar Pratts Bottom Preston Primrose Hill Purfleet Purley Putney Putney Heath Queen&apos;s Park Queensbury Radlett Rainham Ramsden Ravenscourt Park Raynes Park Regent&apos;s Park Richmond Park Richmond Upon Thames Rickmansworth Riddlesdown Roehampton Romford Rotherhithe Ruislip Rush Green Sanderstead Selhurst Selsdon Seven Kings Seven Sisters Sewardstone Shad Thames Shadwell Shepherd&apos;s Bush Shepperton Shoreditch Shortlands Sidcup Silvertown Slade Green Sloane Square Snaresbrook Soho South Acton South Bank South Harrow South Hornchurch South Kensington South Lambeth South Norwood South Ockendon South Woodford Southall Southfields Southgate Southwark Spitalfields St Helier St James&apos;s St Johns St John&apos;s Wood St Katherines Dock St Mary Cray St Paul Cray Staines Stamford Hill Stanmore Stapleford Abbotts Stepney Stepney Green Stockwell Stoke Newington Stoke Newington Central Stoke Newington Church Street Stonebridge Park Stoneleigh Strand Stratford Streatham Streatham Hill Stroud Green Sudbury Summerstown Sunbury Sundridge Surbiton Surrey Quays Sutton Swanley Swiss Cottage Sydenham Tadworth Tatsfield Tattenham Corner Teddington Temple Fortune Thames Ditton Thamesmead The City The Hyde Theydon Bois Thornton Heath Thorpe Titsey Tolworth Tooting Tooting Bec Tooting Broadway Tooting Graveney Tottenham Tottenham Hale Totteridge Tower Hill Trafalgar Square Tufnell Park Tulse Hill Turnpike Lane Twickenham Upminster Upper Clapton Upper Holloway Upper Tooting Upton Park Uxbridge Vauxhall Victoria Victoria Park Waddon Wallington Walthamstow Walton Heath Walton-on-Thames Walworth Wandsworth Wandsworth Common Wanstead Wapping Warlingham Waterloo Watford Well Hill Welling Wembley Wennington West Acton West Brompton West Drayton West Dulwich West Green West Ham West Hampstead West India Docks West Kensington West Molesey West Wickham Westerham Westminster Weybridge Whetstone White City Whitechapel Whitton Whyteleafe Willesden Wilmington Wimbledon Wimbledon Common Winchmore Hill Woldingham Wood Green Woodford Woolwich Worcester Park Worlds End Yeading Yiewsley 
 
 Search Cancel 
Distance

 Bird&apos;s-eye View Within 5 miles Within 2 miles Within 1 mile Within¼mile 
 
Features

 Good for Groups Good for Children Take Away Takes Reservations …More features» 
 
More Features
 
 General Features 
 
 Accepts Credit Cards Outdoor Seating Waiter Service Wheelchair Accessible 
 
 Alcohol 
 
 Full Bar Beer&amp;Wine Only Happy Hour 
 = No results Search Cancel 
Price

 ££££ £££ ££ £ 
 
Category

 African Restaurants Caribbean Food Stands 
 
 1. Suya Obalende 
 Category: African Area: De Beauvoir 1 review 523 Kingsland Road
London E8 4AR 020 7275 0171 Suya Obalende is a welcome change to Dalston&apos;s many Chinese, Turkish and Caribbean restaurants and take aways. The Nigerian restaurant specialises in tasty traditional seasoned chargrilled meats and fish.   The first 
 2. 805 Restaurant 
 Category: African Area: Peckham 4 reviews 805 Old Kent Road
London SE15 1NX 020 7639 0808 Gorgeous Nigerian food.  Service can be quite hit-and-miss.  Last time I dined here several of my friends waited ages for their food to arrive only to ultimately told that the dish they&apos;d ordered was in fact not 
 3. Spinach&amp;Agushi 
 Categories: African , Food Stands Area: Clerkenwell 4 reviews Exmouth Market
London EC1R 4QE differentiation...London has Nigerian , Senegalese, Ethiopian, Moroccan food and more, and that&apos;s just in one row of stalls at a place like the Sunday UpMarket at Brick Lane.   Anyway. Spinach&amp;Agushi. Yum. Great way to… 
 4. Presidential Suya Restaurant 
 Categories: Caribbean , African Areas: Walworth , Burgess Park 1 review 162-164 Old Kent Road
London SE1 5TY 020 7708 4491 Suya, booyah suckas!  As the kind old Nigerian lady behind the counter explained to me, &quot;It&apos;s like Kebab, but with Spice.&quot;  That&apos;s a good description.  Suya is chargrilled meat, and at Presidential Suya they have meat 
 5. Nigerian Cafe 
 Categories: Caribbean , African , Fast Food&amp;Takeaways Area: Finsbury Park 1 review Station Pl
London N4 2DH Wow, I came home and my coat still smells of grease from this place. I&apos;m not actually sure if that is a good this but this joint is awesome!  Many times when I have been cold and hungry on the bus I have passed by this… 
 6. The Queen of Sheba 
 Categories: Ethiopian , African Area: Kentish Town 6 reviews 12 Fortess Road
London NW5 2EU 020 7284 3947 We wanted to go there already since some time. The first time when we tried to go there the restaurant was packed and unfortunately we didn&apos;t have a booking. This time where smarter and booked ahead.   The food was just 
 7. Zigni House 
 Category: African Area: Canonbury 7 reviews 330 Essex Road
London N1 3PB 020 7226 7418 This is a nice East African restaurant . The food is varied and tasty, service is slow but maybe that means the meals are made from scratch. Staff are friendly, the decor is pretty cool and you can eat with your hands 
 8. Spinach&amp;Agushi 
 Categories: Food Stands , African Area: Notting Hill 3 reviews Stall 65 Portobello Road
London W11 2QB 020 7254 5333 This is my absolute favorite food stand at Portobello Market. Every time I come to this market, I beeline and head straight for Spinach&amp;Agushi&apos;s stand. Every Saturday, they set up shop on the same block as Coffee… 
 9. Merkato Ethiopian Restaurant 
 Category: African Area: King&apos;s Cross 2 reviews 196 Caledonian Road
London N1 0SQ 020 7713 8952 Absolutely perfect! i have been to Ethiopian restaurants in the US, Canada and Uk, but nothing comes close to Merkato!  Located on Caledonian road, it does get some competition from other Ethiopian restaurants , but 
 10. Mosob 
 Category: African Area: Maida Hill 3 reviews 339 Harrow Road
London W9 3RB 020 7289 2288 dish. This is the first Ethiopian/Eritrean restaurant where the lamb wasn&apos;t overcooked! This is probably the 10th restaurant of this style of cooking we&apos;ve eaten at across the globe and we&apos;ll definitely be back. 
 1 to 10 of 55 Go to Page 1 2 3 4 5 6 Previous | Next 
 Less relevant categories omitted. Show all results Got search feedback? Help us improve. 
Related Talk Topics

 
 Naija blues :( 

Does anyone know where I could find a decent Nigerian restaurant? One where you don&apos;t have to wait looong to get the food. I&apos;ve tried Mama Calabar,…
 
 
Related Lists

 
 Meat-eaters dining in London 

Mighty Meaty Meals. Yup... I never thought I would write this list but I have...judge me all you like!
 
 Budget London 

I&apos;m the queen bee when it comes to bargains. Get on the band wagon and spend less of those pennies at these great eat outs.
 
 Take Away and Delivery in London 

Take Out Treats! Indian, Chinese, Pizza...Turkish?!
 

 See more lists» 
 
Not here? Tell us what we&apos;re missing.

If the business you&apos;re looking for isn&apos;t here, add it!
 Add A Business Redo search when map moved Draw Search Area «Mo&apos; Map Less Map» Loading... Please zoom in to get updated search results. Yowza, that is one large search area. Draw something a bit smaller for us, eh? 
About

 About Yelp Yelp Blog Press Investor Relations Terms of Service Privacy Policy 
 
Help

 FAQ Advertise Content Guidelines Contact Yelp Business Support Developers 
 
More

 Careers Yelp Mobile The Weekly Yelp RSS Top Searches 
 
Countries

 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany 

 Italy Norway Republic of Ireland Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United States 
 
Language

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 
 
 London Business Listings # A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z | Newly Added | Talk Archive 

 Site Map | Belfast | Birmingham | Bristol | Cardiff | Coventry | Edinburgh | Hull | Leeds | Leicester | Liverpool | London | Manchester | Sheffield 

Copyright©2004-2012 Yelp
	</body>
</document>
