<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002744" url="http://www.collegehumor.com/video/6579318/hardly-working-business-time-2" time="2012-07-12-18:48" support="3" score="0.002574652852847857" bingtitle="Hardly Working: Business Time 2 - CollegeHumor Video" webtitle="Hardly Working: Business Time 2 - CollegeHumor Video">
			<query id="000198" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000207" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000761" bing-rank="181"/>
	<description>In High School I worked at a fast food restaurant with my best ... 28 black-and-white, four trays ... waist, there are an unreasonable number of ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Videos 
 All Recent Video Playlists Most Viewed Sketch Comedy TV/Movies Originals All Originals Sketch Celebrities Animation Jake and Amir Troopers Hardly Working Very Mary-Kate Dinosaur Office The Six 
 x Pictures 
 All Recent Picture Galleries Most Viewed TV/Movies Categories Animals Art Cars College Epic Facebook Food Foreign Gross Holidays Nerdy People Politics Pop Culture Pranks Relationships Religion Sexy Signs Sports The Internet Words WTF Girls Cute College Girl Hottest College Girl 
 x Articles 
 All Recent Most Viewed TV/Movies Columns CollegeHumor Interview The Graphic Truth Caption Contest TLDNR Exclusive Leaks 420 Special Axe Cop Almost Reading HumorUs 
 x uPick 
 uPick Categories Beach Rants News .GIFs WTF Fail Win Classroom Screencap Rough Love Text Mess Pet Stories Jokes Idiotech Work Sucks Roommate Confessions Polidicks Pranks I Fought the Law 
 x Politics 
 Electoral CollegeHumor Political Timeline Election Cheat Sheet 
 More 
 More CollegeHumor Recent Toplists Surveys Topics CH Live Tour Best of CH CH LiveCast Hotlinks TV/Movies Stalk Us Facebook Twitter Youtube CH Staff Blog Subscribe (RSS) Recent Videos CH Originals Recent Pictures Recent Articles 
 x 
 Submit↑ 
 Sign in | Sign up | 
   Signing in... 
Sign in to CollegeHumor
 

 Use Your CollegeHumor Account Forgot your password? Use Your Facebook Account 
You&apos;ll also be able to post your CollegeHumor activity to your Facebook feed.
 Not registered? Create an account Signing in via Facebook Connect... 
 Business Time 2
 Note: Continuous play is disabled while you read the rest of the page. Scroll back up to enable it. Hide Forever 
Subscribe
   
Subscribe to Hardly Working

Get notified about new episodes via email, SMS and on CollegeHumor.
 Learn More Submit a Video 
They’re photo finished.
 
From CH Staff on September 19, 2011 
 See More Originals Hardly Working office Business Like this Video Share this Video Share on Tumblr 505 Share on Facebook Tweet Email to a friend Embed 
 CollegeHumor’s Favorite Funny Videos 
 Close 
Customize Embed Options
 400 x 225 600 x 338 750 x 563 900 x 507 
Custom Size
 x px 
Other Options
 Use old embed code 

Check out more HardlyWorking episodes at http://www.collegehumor.com/hardlyworking .

 
 Send this page to a friend 
 

 
 Your Name 
 Your Email 
 Friends&apos; Emails (Separate multiple addresses with commas) 
 Send 
 uPick Work Sucks Awful work stories See All» Up +4 Down Vegetarian hot dog. 
I worked at a hot dog stand that stayed open until 3 because the bar across the street let out at 2, and I got all sorts of interesting stories from working with our inebriated clientele. My favorite was probably the man who ordered 5 regular hot dogs, and then one with cheese, onions, saur kraut, relish, ketchup and mustard on it... only, without the hot dog, because it was for ... Read More» his girlfriend who&apos;s a vegetarian. 
 
 July 12, 2012 

 Be the first to comment! 
 Tweet Submit your own picture, video, or story to uPick See all of the uPick Categories» 
 Recommended Videos Comments (50) Script Credits 
 John Mayer&apos;s Hologram 
Unable to tour due to throat problems, John gets a digital replacement just like Tupac’s. Only not.

From CH Staff 
 9,138 likes | 21 comments | May 22, 2012 Seth MacFarlane&apos;s Rejected Pitches 
The creator of“Family Guy”and“Ted”presents some movie ideas the studio passed on, just because they were terrible.

From CH Staff 
 872 likes | 29 comments | June 26, 2012 Call Me Maybe Parody 
Actually, can I have my number back?

From CH Staff 
 6,956 likes | 60 comments | July 05, 2012 Jake and Amir: Reddit 
The host with the most posts.

From Jake and Amir 
 4,144 likes | 94 comments | June 05, 2012 Perfect Fantasy World 
This one goes out to the dreamers. And the perverts.

From CH Staff 
 346 likes | 95 comments | June 27, 2012 The Fall of Pinterest 
The Internet’s only safe-haven for girls comes under attack. From the rest of the Internet.

From CH Staff 
 18,639 likes | 92 comments | June 04, 2012 | +500,000 views Hardly Working: Business Time 2 By Amir Blumenfeld and Patrick Cassels INT. COPY ROOM - DAY

 AMIR, in a suit, walks by the the new xerox machine reading
 DECISION POINTS (by George W. Bush). He notices the machine
 and is floored.

 AMIR
 Sweet Larry, Mother of Pearl...

 Amir takes a step towards the machine.

 PAT (O.S.)
 Xerox Workcentre 7328. Yes, this is
 actual.

 PAT pops up from behind the machine. Amir, still speechless:

 AMIR
 I have a contact at the Xeer&apos; and
 he told me we were on the wait-list
 for one of these bad boys six
 months ago. I thought he was
 pulling my schlong...

 PAT
 He wasn&apos;t. 26 PPM color, 28
 black-and-white, four trays, three
 page layouts, two toner shades, one
 hell of a machine.

 AMIR
 Light production finisher?

 PAT
 Optional (examining) buuut it looks
 like we exercised it.

 AMIR
 Inreal.

 PAT
 Best part, they&apos;re still using the
 7200 series down the hall.

 AMIR
 Well, that&apos;s a quality machine.

 Beat. They both erupt in laughter. Patrick steps towards the
 machine holding a piece of paper. Amir snatches it out.

 AMIR
 Whoa! What are you doing?

 PAT
 Taking this baby for a text drive.

 AMIR
 Are you kidding? You&apos;ve never used
 this machine before.

 PAT
 Nobody has.

 AMIR
 Uncorrect. They debuted this model
 at CopyCon Kansas City 2k10.
 (suspicious)
 Didn&apos;t see you there.

 PAT
 (beat)
 ...Weird. I was.

 AMIR
 So you must have seen keynote
 speaker...?

 PAT
 Mitch Albom. &quot;Handshake Your Way to
 the Top&quot; Very moving.

 AMIR
 Lucky guess. Where&apos;d you stay?

 PAT
 Hampton Inn.

 AMIR
 Me too. Complimentary breakfast?

 PAT
 With monogrammed waffle iron.

 AMIR
 Rental car?

 PAT
 PT Cruiser.

 AMIR
 Regardless, I was loading letter
 when you were an extern at Enron.
 Out of my way.

 Amir tries using the machine. There are some confusing BEEPS
 and MECHANICAL NOISES. It&apos;s clearly not working.

 PAT
 (smug)
 Problems?

 AMIR
 NOPE. It&apos;s just warming up.

 PAT
 I don&apos;t think so. They clocked the
 7328&apos;s warm-up time at 7.5 seconds.

 AMIR
 That&apos;s not official.

 Pat leans close to Amir&apos;s face.

 PAT
 You know, I think I saw an InkJet
 down the hall.

 AMIR
 F*ck you.

 PAT
 Step aside. Let a real eBay power
 seller troubleshoot this bitch.

 Pat presses some buttons.

 PAT
 Your problem is you&apos;re treating
 this like a copy machine when it&apos;s
 a 5-in-one workstation: Copy.
 Email. Fax...

 As Pat talks, a HORRIBLE GRINDING NOISE rises from the
 machine until it&apos;s unbearable. Amir looks concerned.

 PAT
 ...Laminate-- jesus okay I&apos;m
 calling tech support!

 Pat grabs his phone. CU on his waist, there are an
 unreasonable number of BlackBerries, beepers, etc. clipped
 to it.

 Amir grabs the phone, throws it and stomps on it.

 AMIR
 And tell them what? That we took a
 $15,000 dump and we want mommy to
 come wipe it for us?

 PAT
 We&apos;re not qualified to provide
 maintenance on the 7328.

 Amir leans into the xerox machine and points.

 AMIR
 No, I think I&apos;ve located the
 problem. It&apos;s right...
 (points slowly to Pat)
 ...here.

 Pat shoves Amir back. Amir, furious, unbuttons his shirt.

 AMIR
 Thank you.

 PAT
 For what?

 AMIR
 Striking first. Read your HR
 manual. &quot;Employees under attack are
 allowed...

 Pat, accepting Amir&apos;s challenge, unbuttons his shirt.

 PAT/AMIR
 &quot;...to defend themselves with force
 commensurate to the initial blow!&quot;

 Just before they kill each other, Pat and Amir notice each
 other&apos;s shirts. They&apos;re both wearing identical &quot;Sore
 Loserman 2000&quot; tees.

 STREETER enters.

 STREETER
 Hey guys? The bathroom is seriously
 overflowing. Still. So...?

 PAT/AMIR
 Right. Yes. On it, sir.

 Pat and Amir grab buckets and mops and scurry out like rats.

 Streeter removies Amir&apos;s paper from the machine and reads.

 STREETER
 (calling after)
 Is- is this a kill list?

 END. 
 crew Editor Tiffani Johnson President of Original Content Sam Reich Executive Producer Spencer Griffin Director of Post Production Michael Schaubach Creative Director Ben Joseph Production Manager Sam Sparks Post Production Producer Lacy Wittman Production Office Coordinator David Kerns Assistant Editor Drew Nissen Post Production Coordinator Amanda Madden Production Accountant Christine Rodriguez Assistant Production Accountant Daniel Siegel 
 Your Friends on Facebook like Hot links The web&apos;s weirdest 
 The golden age of porn lives on. A good rule of thumb: don&apos;t trust a naked guy unless it&apos;s after you&apos;ve already had sex with him. The theft of BBQ potato chips is the worst crime Canada has seen in 62 years. &quot;Ladies should be seen and not heard, but also not seen.&quot; The only political agenda movies should have is pro-explosion. If these propaganda posters were trying to convince us how weird they are, they&apos;re working. Are the words you are reading right now art? YOU DECIDE. Turns out Adele&apos;s been pregnant for the same length of time Rollin&apos; in the Deep was at number 1: nearly forever. Meet your area&apos;s hottest available douchebags! Another easy money-saving tip: time travel back to the days before inflation and triple your dollars&apos; value. R-Rated Hotlinks More Hotlinks 
   
Newsletter Weekly Roundup 
 
 The best CollegeHumor content delivered directly to your face! 

Enter your email to receive a weekly newsletter of the best videos, girls, and more.
 Subscribe 

 
RSS Subscribe 
 RSS 
 Recent Videos Recent Pictures Recent Articles CollegeHumor Originals 
 
Friends BFF 
 
 Failblog AdultSwim Uproxx HerCampus HollywoodTuna Popoholic BroBible GorillaMask I Am Bored Smosh Caveman Circus The Smoking Gun 
 
 The Stuff Funny Videos / Funny Pictures / Funny Articles / Newsletter / Our Book / Mobile / FAQ 
 
 Seriously About / Site Map / Site Index / Advertise / Jobs / Contact / Privacy Policy / Terms&amp;Conditions 
 
 CH Network Jest / SportsPickle / Dorkly / Hardly Working / Bleep Bloop / Jake and Amir / CH Media 
 
©2012 Connected Ventures, LLC. All rights reserved. | Brought to you by CollegeHumor
	</body>
</document>
