<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002662" url="http://www.activediner.com/fast-food/restaurant/clarksville/tn/us/region-305" time="2012-07-12-18:44" support="1" score="0.002173013680906822" bingtitle="fast food Restaurants in clarksville, tn" webtitle="fast food Restaurants in clarksville, tn">
			<query id="000663" bing-rank="9"/>
	<description>1 - 10 of 75 fast-food restaurant listings found. Next &gt;&gt; ... numerous times, and never have they gotten my order ... was seated, I waited a half hour, the place still ...</description>
	<body>
		CUISINE OR RESTAURANT   CITY/STATE OR ZIP     
 
 
 Destinations 

 Atlanta Austin Boca Raton Boston Charleston Charlotte Chicago Dallas Denver Detroit Fort Worth Ft. Lauderdale Greensboro (Triad) Hartford Houston Indianapolis Kansas City Las Vegas Los Angeles Louisville Miami Minneapolis Nashville New Orleans New York Orlando Philadelphia Phoenix Pittsburgh Portland Raleigh San Diego San Francisco Seattle Washington DC  -------------------------- Browse by Map   
 

 
 Sign Up for Specials 
 

 
 Add Your Restaurant 
 

 
 ActiveDiner Blog 
 
 
Cuisine
 All Restaurants 
 American 
 Chinese 
 Mexican 
 Italian 
 Japanese 
 Burger 
 German 
 Greek 
 American Regional 
 
 more... 
 American American Regional American Traditional Armenian Asian Barbecue Breakfast Brewery/Pub/Tavern Buffet Burger Cafe Cafeteria Cajun/Creole Call Ahead Pickup Candy/Dessert Shop Cantonese style Casual/Family Catering Chicken Chinese Coffee Shop Coffee/Donut Shop Country Deli/Sandwich/Subs Diner Dinner Fast Food German Greek Hunan Ice Cream/Yogurt Shop Indian/Pakistan Italian Jamaican Japanese Kids Friendly Korean Lunch Mexican Pizzeria Seafood Southern Sports Bar and Grill Steak House Szechuan Style Take Out/Carry Out Thai TV/Satellite 
 
 





 
 
 
   
 
 



 
   United States  &gt;  Tennessee  &gt;  clarksville 
fast food Restaurants in clarksville, tn
 1 - 10 of 75 fast-food restaurant listings found. Next &gt;&gt;   
 
 RATING 5.0 
 China King Buffet Corporation 
Chinese, Casual/Family, Fast Food, Buffet
122 Dover Crossing Road, Clarksville
(931) 551-8182   LATEST REVIEW   
GOOD GOOD GOOD
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
 
 RATING 4.0 
 Dairy Queen&amp;Brazier 
American, Fast Food, Ice Cream/Yogurt Shop
1055 South Riverside Drive, Clarksville
(931) 647-1616   LATEST REVIEW   
Good food, good price. Better than their new DQ Grill and Chill stores. Do yourself a favor, stick with the smaller DQ Brazier Burgers. You can&apos;t go wrong with them.
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
 
 RATING 3.5 
 Olive Garden Italian Restaurant 
Italian, Casual/Family, Fast Food
2782 Wilma Rudolph Boulevard, Clarksville
(931) 552-2585   LATEST REVIEW   
I&apos;ve dined here 3 times. Every time I get pasta, there&apos;s enough water in it to take a swim. Not to mention, a couple of times the food had not too much flavor.
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
   advertisements 
 
 
 
 RATING 3.0 
 Jack in the Box 
Fast Food
40 Dover Crossing Road, Clarksville
(931) 648-4401   LATEST REVIEW   
I&apos;ve been there numerous times, and never have they gotten my order right. Their food is ok, but I never get what I order. It would be a great place if they get employees and management that listens to customers.
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
 
 RATING 2.7 
 Red Lobster 
American, Cajun/Creole, Seafood, Casual/Family
2838 Wilma Rudolph Blvd, Clarksville
(931) 645-9872   DESCRIPTION 
We know the secret to great seafood is quality and freshness. That&apos;s why we&apos;ve insisted on the finest seafood the sea has to offer since we opened our first restaurant in 1968. Since then, lots of things have changed. But one thing hasn&apos;t – our relen...
 LATEST REVIEW   
I went one day, and had to wait in an empty restaurant for 15 minutes while the waitresses were talking to each other. When I finally was seated, I waited a half hour, the place still empty, the waitresses still chatting, then I got up and left. Horr...
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
 
 RATING 2.5 
 Mcdonald&apos;s Hamburgers 
American, Fast Food
1644 Fort Campbell Boulevard, Clarksville
(931) 645-6662   LATEST REVIEW   
the food was good and the workers were nice .It did taked a long time to get food.
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
 
 RATING 2.0 
 Jade Dragon Chinese Restaurant 
Chinese, Fast Food
110 Dunbar Cave Road, Clarksville
(931) 647-7711   LATEST REVIEW   
The food we ordered was awfull. We ordered sweet and sour chicken sesame -spelling? and general tsos&apos; chicken and i&apos;ve never tasted this version of chinese food.The items we ordered are the most common ever seen on a chinese menu.It tasted the way a...
 REVIEW RESTAURANT    CHANGE INFO    
 
   Arby&apos;s 
Fast Food
2235 Madison Street, Clarksville
(931) 553-0808   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   Arby&apos;s Roast Beef Restaurant 
Fast Food
3067 Guthrie Highway, Clarksville
(931) 648-3800   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   Arby&apos;s Roast Beef Restaurant 
Fast Food
955 North Riverside Drive, Clarksville
(931) 645-1100   BE THE FIRST TO REVIEW THIS RESTAURANT!    CHANGE INFO    
 
   


 
 Next &gt;&gt; 



 Didn&apos;t find what you were looking for? Try searching here...
 
      Know of a restaurant we don&apos;t have?   Click here to add it. 
 Copyright 1996-2012 ActiveDiner.com All rights reserved.      About Us  |  Contact Us  |  Disclaimer  | Privacy Policy  | Terms of Service
	</body>
</document>
