<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002660" url="http://blogs.miaminewtimes.com/shortorder/2011/08/cream_-_alcohol_infused_whippe.php" time="2012-07-12-18:43" support="3" score="0.005683051376602585" bingtitle="Cream, Alcohol-Infused Whipped Cream Offers Sweet and Creamy Buzz ..." webtitle="Cream, Alcohol-Infused Whipped Cream Offers Sweet and Creamy Buzz - Miami Restaurants and Dining - Short Order">
			<query id="000944" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="001478" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000535" bing-rank="141"/>
	<description>... if we just stumbled across the perfect condiment. ... Follow Short Order on Facebook and Twitter @Short ... Fed&apos;s Primal Zin Wine Dinner; Salty American Fast Food; Restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Blogs 
 Entire Site Articles&amp;Blogs Restaurants Places Events Music Images Ads Bars Best Of Movies 
 News Home Riptide Strouse Luke&apos;s Gospel Letters Special Reports Archives Search New Times Flipbook Weekly Newsletter Get Mobile Calendar Home Top Picks Submit an Event Events Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads New Times Web Awards Music Home Crossfade Concert Calendar Bars and Clubs Brew at the Zoo Submit an Event Music Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurants Home Short Order Find a Restaurant Menus Iron Fork Happy Hours Dining Deals Dining Newsletter Get Mobile Restaurant Ads Arts Home Cultist Visual Arts Theater Welcome to the Future Skrawberry Jam Artopia Arts Newsletter Get Mobile Entertainment Ads Film Home Showtimes Cultist Film Film Poll 2011 Film Newsletter Get Mobile Free Stuff Best Of Home 2012 2011 2010 2009 Readers&apos; Poll 2012 Best Of Newsletter Get Mobile Best Of Ads Promotions Home Promotional Events Street Team Free Stuff On Sale Promotions Newsletter Get Mobile Deals Post an Ad Jobs Real Estate Advertiser Index Deals Deals Newsletter Virtual Job Fair 
Top

blog

Stories
 
 
 First Bites 

 Bloom&apos;s Upscale Fusion Street Food 

By Laine Doss
 
 Miami Spice 

 Miami Spice at Gotham Steak Hakkasan, Scarpetta 

By Laine Doss
 
 Holidays 

 Bastille Day at Brand New Fabien&apos;s Bistro 

By Lee Klein
 
 Best of Miami 

 Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants 

By Laine Doss
 
 First Bites 

 Iron Side Cafe: Fresh New Lunch Spot 

By Lee Klein
 
 Gastronomic Gatherings 

 Fairchild Makes Mangoes Exciting This Weekend 

By Laine Doss
 
 Chef on the Small Screen 

 Eat St. to Film Food Trucks in Miami 

By Laine Doss
 
 Food Charity 

 Taste of the Nation Celebrates 25th Anniversary 

By Laine Doss
 
 Neighborhood Joints 

 Shack Shack In Coral Gables Opening Soon 

By Laine Doss
 
 News 

 Zeke&apos;s Reincarnated: Rio Station 

By Hannah Sentenac
 
   Just Desserts 
Cream, Alcohol-Infused Whipped Cream Offers Sweet and Creamy Buzz
 By Christina Staalstrom Fri., Aug. 19 2011 at 11:43 AM Categories: Booze Hound , Just Desserts 
 Pin It 
 
 Courtesy of Cream 
​ Cream , the alcohol-infused cream that hit the market late last year, is now available in Miami. Even when hidden on the bottom shelf at Grove Liquors (2991 SW 32nd Ave., Miami), the colorful cream canisters grab our attention and have us wondering if we just stumbled across the perfect condiment.

While Cream&apos;s official website suggests adding the stuff atop mixed drinks, shots and coffees, we don&apos;t believe in limiting ourselves. We topped it on our morning bowl of fruit and afternoon latte and no one was the wiser. For those purists in the bunch just squirt it directly into your mouth for a sweet buzz.
 
Comparing it to regular whipped cream seemed like the right thing to do, and we give it a thumbs up. Keep in mind that it contains alcohol, so it&apos;s a bit runnier and not quite as &quot;fluffy,&quot; but serve it immediately and no one will be the wiser -- until they taste it that is. The sweet canned cream taste is there, but there is a definite kick to every bite.

 
 Photo by Christina Staalstrom 
​ Cream offers five flavors: raspberry, chocolate, cherry, caramel and vanilla. We snatched up the 30 proof vanilla for $8.99.

 Follow Short Order on Facebook and Twitter @Short_Order . 
Like this Story?
 
Sign up for the Dining Newsletter: The week&apos;s top local food news and events, plus interviews with chefs and restaurant owners, dining tips, and a peek at our print review.
 Privacy Policy Cancel Continue 
Tags:
 Cream , Grove Liquors Write Comment Email to Friend Print Article 
Related Content
 Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus. 
 
Sounds gross.
 

TotalComments: 1
 
Now Trending


 
Slide shows » 

 Closer Look: Villa Azur Closer Look: Josh&apos;s Delicatessen&amp;Appetizing Rock &apos;n&apos; Roll Beer-B-Que 2012 at Seminole Hard Rock Hotel&amp;Casino More Slideshows&gt;&gt; 
 
 Restaurants 
 
 
Our pizza is simply an honest diversity of all-nat
 View Ad | View Site 
8oz Burger Bar
 View Ad | View Site 
The Corner
 View Ad | View Site 
Bagel Express
 View Ad | View Site 
 More &gt;&gt; 
Twitter Feed
 
 Follow short_order on Twitter 
 More Twitter &gt;&gt; 
Headlines from our Partners
 

 Summer Gold: Susser Talks Mangoes; London Burger King Installs a Damien Hirst Painting Boulud Hosting &quot;To Live and Dine in Miami&quot;; Balloo&apos;s Summer Additions at Sugarcane &quot;That Glow On The Beach&quot;: The 1950s Restaurants of 22nd Street Whiskey Joe&apos;s Set to Booze on Key Biscayne Top Ten Dog-Friendly Restaurants; Watch an Ad For the Second Cheapest Wine Out There 
 About Us | Work for Miami New Times | Esubscribe | Free Classifieds | Advertising | Privacy Policy | Problem With the Site? | RSS | Site Map 
©2012 Miami New Times, LLC. All rights reserved. Browse Voice Nation Most Popular | Most Recent Newsletters | Mobile Log in Sign up 
 New York Village Voice 
 LA Weekly 
 Phoenix New Times 
 Denver Westword 
 Houston Press 
 Dallas Observer 
 SF Weekly 
 Seattle Weekly 
 St. Louis RFT 
 Miami New Times 
 Minneapolis City Pages 
 OC Weekly 
 Broward/Palm Beach New Times 
 

 
 Voice Places 

Discover restaurants, nightlife, travel, shopping...
 
 VOICE Daily Deals 

Get 50 to 90% off every day on restaurants, movies, massages...
 
 Best Of... 

More than 10,000 of the BEST things to eat, drink, and experience
 
 My Voice Nation 

Join the Village Voice community and get exclusive deals and info
 
 Happy Hour 

Your local Happy Hour guide at your fingertips
 
 or 
 Log in or Sign up 
 Social Connect: 
Use your favorite account to access My Voice Nation.
 
 
Use your My Voice Nation account to log in:
 E-mail 
 
 Password 
 
 Forgot password? Remember me or 
 Sign Up or Log in 
 Social Connect: 
Sign up for My Voice Nation with your preferred network.
 
 
Sign up for a My Voice Nation account:
 E-mail 
 
 Privacy policy 
 Settings Log Out
	</body>
</document>
