<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002265" url="http://www.seniorlearn.org/bookclubs/archives/general/CuriousMinds/CuriousMinds2-03.htm" time="2012-07-12-18:10" support="1" score="0.0009874611018692704" bingtitle="Curious Minds ~ 2003 February Export - Bookclubs and Latin on ..." webtitle="Curious Minds ~ 2003 February Export">
			<query id="001084" bing-rank="245"/>
	<description>BARBARA - About your enjoyment in making and giving: I learned long ago the saying about God loving a cheerful giver was designed primarily for the collection of ...</description>
	<body>
		Curious Minds ~ 2003 February patwest January 30, 2003 - 05:07 am 
 










 
 First Kiss 

 
 Curious Minds 
 


 A forum for conversation on ideas and criticism found in magazines, journals and reviews 
 

 


 Every other week we&apos;ll link to a new and noteworthy article of interest for discussion. 
 





 Topic for May 11-24:

Personal Firsts



 We Are All Famous Firsts! 
Click and enjoy! 


 

 

Remember your first day in School? First crush? First time you played &quot;Spin the Bottle?&quot; First time you Flew Solo? Kissed a Snake? Wrestled an Alligator? (for the gals) First time you wore makeup on the Q.T? First time you got caught at it?

What &quot;firsts&quot; in your life that might be memorable, humorous, or just plain fun to remember, that you would like to share with us? Nothing embarassing or intimate, least not TOO. We would love to hear all about them.

Join our discussion and tell all.
 






 Your contributions are most welcome Discussion Leader: Tiger Tom 
 
 patwest February 1, 2003 - 08:49 pm 

 

 
 la balanoire (1876) huile sur toile
Pierre-Auguste Renoir
Muse d&apos;Orsay, Paris, France.

 

 
 Curious Minds 



 A forum for conversation on ideas and criticism found in magazines, journals and reviews 



 Every other week we&apos;ll link to a new and noteworthy article of interest for discussion. 



 THE VALENTINE
WHO GOT AWAY! 
 Click above for our Discussion Link 

 
 
 

 Were you a slave to custom on Valentines day when you were in grade school?
 How do you celebrate Valentines day now? - - Special dinners, flowers delivered, cards mailed/e-mailed, Heart check-up, long distance phone call to a friend or family...
 Did you ever give or receive a mean Valentine?
 Did anyone ever embarrass you by announcing that you had a secret crush on a dreamy girl or boy?
 Did any of your friends move away when you were young. Did you keep up with them after they moved?
 Are you in touch with any of your schoolmates after all these years?
 Are there lost chances in your life that you wish you could turn back time and handle them differently. 
 Your suggestions are welcome
Discussion Leader: Barbara 



 Help Support our Books effort:
 
Buy a book at SN&apos;s B&amp;N Online store:
SeniorNet gets 7% of the purchase price! 

 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 1, 2003 - 09:48 pm New topic and new discussion page - wow all things new...

I do remember those inexpensive bulk Valentine cards but I only remember them when I was a bit older - maybe in the 7th or 8th grade - I remember making Valentines with constructions paper and I remember by Grandmother showing us how to make lace paper by folding and cutting bits off the ends of the folds and then designs like baskets in the larger folded areas so that when it opened it was rather an intricate design. In early grade school I remember lace paper doilies pasted on red construction paper with hearts cut out and added or bits of ribbon tied into bows or if we were lucky we found a cupid or something to cut from a magazine.

Oh yes than the scrapes of fabric that we filled with cotton and some of our moms toilet water that we added to the cards. Oh and do y&apos;ll remember Sweat Heart soap - it was oval in shape and embossed along the edge with curly shapes and it smelled lovely. We either encased the soap in red net with red narrow ribbon tied in a bow at the end or we decorated the soap by piercing beads onto a straight pin and sticking them into the empty spot within the curly embossed area - oh that was a special gift worthy of making in secret for our mothers.

As a kid I do not remember much about flowers or chocolates but then there wasn&apos;t much money so everything was homemade. I do not even remember that we had muffins or cookies in school as my children had during various holidays.

Looking forward to hearing about your memories of Valentine&apos;s day... 
 Bobbiecee February 1, 2003 - 10:20 pm I don&apos;t celebrate Valentine&apos;s Day now, but did when my husband was alive. However, we celebrated it a bit different than most people. We would write a poem to each other rather than send a card, and would buy a live plant from the nursery for each other as we were both keen gardeners. My daughter and her husband have continued that custom. To me, it offers more significance....and doesn&apos;t encourage obesity through eating a box of chockies, etc. Also, Valentine&apos;s Day is in summer here so cut flowers don&apos;t last more than a day or two. A pot with, say, blooming New Guinea Impatiens or other flowering plant that could be planted and nurtured with love was much more significant to us, and is to my daughter and husband too. BTW, we make all of our own cards, complete with a poem, for all occasions, daughter, son&apos;s fiance, etc....they got that from their Mum.

Bobbie 
 TigerTom February 2, 2003 - 08:25 am Barbara,

Valentines day in Grade School:

The most popular girl got the most cards 
and the most unpopular person got hardly 
any.

I understand that today Cards are discourages 
in Grade School because of that. I guess 
Schools these days want to spare the unpopular 
child the embarassment.

Lots of times the upopular child was unpopular 
because the child was &quot;Different&quot; perhaps brighter 
than the rest; Plainer than the rest; not as 
bright as the rest; thinner or more obese than 
the rest. Whatever, many times it was not the 
child&apos;s fault but a matter of genetics. Children 
can be very cruel when in Grade School.

Tiger Tom 
 TigerTom February 2, 2003 - 08:31 am Barbara,

BTW, Happy Groundhogs Day.

Good luck on your discussion. Timely topic.

Tiger Tom 
 Bill H February 2, 2003 - 10:14 am We had Valentine partys in my pre seventh grade school class, and we solved the problem of unfairness in the following way. Each student was assigned a secret Valentine Buddy for whom he/she had to MAKE a valentine card and exchange it along with a small gift. The gift could either be made by the student or purchased for no more than twenty-five cents-after all this was during the great depression.
The Valentine party was held in the home room class and the goodies were made by the parents of the students. The home room teacher would pass out little hats and valentine hearts. The class room was decorated with all kinds of valentine cut outs pinned to the wall and pictures of valentine symbols had been drawn on the blackboard by several of the students. The student who MADE the most unique gift was awarded a prize. This was usually some inexpensive item the class room teacher gave. All in all it was a pretty good time with no one feeling like they had been left out.
Bill H 
 Ann Alden February 2, 2003 - 10:30 am Bill H, you have the most interesting posts about your life! First, your grandmother&apos;s house and now, a very different kind of Valentine&apos;s Day party where fairness was the essence!
All that I remember is the frantic running around to get a Valentine on everyone&apos;s desk before the bell rang.
Now, we(husband and I) exchange really funny Valentines or the very sloppy sweet kind. It depends on our mood the day we stand in front of all those cards at Hallmark!
One far away Valentine&apos;s Day, I found a very funny card which I posted to my husband at work. He nearly fell over when he opened it all the way, as it had on it, a giant female gorilla, pursing her lips and offering him a kiss. He brought it home and I saved it! Sent it to him for almost ten years. 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 2, 2003 - 12:02 pm Ann what a riot - yes bringing fun into the day really takes all the angst out of if you are or not being remembered.

Bill H I can hardly believe that fairness was addressed way back then - amazing - you had a really forward looking teacher didn&apos;t you. Do you think that sense of fairness made into an issue when you were in the 7th grade made a difference in your adult attitude towards fairness?

Tiger Tom were you one of those popular kids? Or I bet you were one of the wise one who just sat back and observed what was happening. Kids can be cruel but I have often wondered if the same kids that are cruel are the ones who grow up to act or think cruel. We assume that as we mature we become more civilized and caring of our fellow man and yet there is an awful lot of cruelty among folks.

Bobbiecee how absolutely wonderful to exchange plants - what a wonderful unique idea - I love it - in fact I think I may borrow it if you do not mind. Up until now except for cards etc. to children and grandchildren I have not done much about the day either.

The other day I turned the big seven O - somehow it was the first time a birthday felt like a milestone - my thought is that I have the next 10 years to really do things that I have always wanted to do or that really make me feel good about my life because after that the chances of me having the physical health or energy is slimmer.

Well I have decided to change all that - the other night seeing on TV those children in Africa living on the streets and the young 12 year old boy who being interviewed at night spoke of having eaten the day before and explaining how the big boys take from the little kids and that when he grew up he was not going to be that cruel to little kids, then he finishes up by saying he misses his mom. (who died of AIDS)

Broke my heart and I wished I could send him a Valentine card along with some money to the orphanage that was featured in the show so they could have taken him but I realized how difficult and impossible that would be to make happen. But what I realized next, there are folks right here that could use some attention. And so I think I will take your plant idea Bobbiecee and bring a plant to a couple of the lesser funded nursing homes in this area, maybe one to the firehouse as well. I would honor teachers but on that day I am sure they are inundated with cards and gifts from their pupils.

I have a couple of long time friends that we have never exchanged greetings on Valentines day and Im thinking why not. 
 Kathy Hill February 2, 2003 - 12:19 pm Barbara - have enjoyed your comments. You make mention of teachers being inundated with cards and gifts. I think that the elementary teachers are, but often those in middle and high school are forgotten. A plate of cookies or a plant would be very welcome in the staff room. So often it is just the parents of the students that deal with the school. When I was with the school system it was always so nice to see just someone from the community recognize us. Maybe I should make some cookies!

Kathy 
 Bill H February 2, 2003 - 01:45 pm Oh, Ann, my life is just chuck full of interesing events some good and others, well, not so good.
Barbara, well, I&apos;m not sure that teacher meant fairness to be an issue per sey. Perhaps she did now that you mention it, but I think she also placed those requirements on the students so that everybody would be involved and also for a class project,i.e. making the gifts and cards to bring out the artist in us ) 
However, I think fairness, other than, race or sex, was practiced more in that era than today. And, yes, I do have a strong sense of fair play although 
 I believe it was family oriented.
Bill H 
 annafair February 2, 2003 - 02:31 pm While I was emptying my pantry , throwing all the stuff the mice got into, washing every shelf and covering with contact , washing all the items in cans and glass jars, moping the floor, washing and putting everything into glass and plastic containers.. The nut curious minds left and here I am thinking of Valentines day ....As long as I can remember ..into Jr High we always celebrated Valentines day in school .. In fact in the 7th grade a dear young man I later dated gave me a heart shaped box of chocolates... He put the box on my seat to surprise me as I was handing out my cards. The real surprise I sat on it .!!!!!!!!! What an uproar...All of his buddies were waiting to see my response&lt;which they didnt expect to be OW what is this ???when I sat on it and the teacher took a dim view of the laughter and explanation ( I was really embarrassed) It seems everyone got cards although in the younger classes we girls would get funny valentines from boys..they were like newspaper with caricatures ...And of course some of the girls gave the boys the same. Now the teacher gives out a list of every student and EVERYONE gets a card ..although it seems to take something away from the whole thing, I know it is kinder and nicer just commenting.

Long ago I told my husband and family I DO NOT WANT CHOCOLATES for Valentine or cut flowers if you are going to get me something make it a plant I can enjoy in the summer ...I hate to see flowers droop an die..unless they come from my own garden. HAppy Valentine day ..anna 
 Bobbiecee February 2, 2003 - 02:58 pm Barbara, you certainly may borrow my idea...plants. I still have some of the live orchids that my husband gave me for Valentine&apos;s Days in the past, plus other plants in pots. Needless to say, I nurture them with love, and they provide memories of the wonderful times we had together. When the orchids bloom, my daughter says &apos;Dad&apos;s saying Hi to us.&apos;

Bobbie 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 2, 2003 - 05:34 pm Hehehe Annafair - oh my - did you end up crushing all the candies - oh I bet he was mortified for you and yet disappointed you didn&apos;t see the box in all its glory before you sat on it - ah youth...

Bill and so your parents are given the credit for your admiration of fairness - interesting - do you have a story that shows us how you picked up on that trait?

How special Bobbie - to see a bloom as the voice of a dear one no longer with you. Sounds like your daughter shares in the memory of your husband - how precious.

Look I just have to tell y&apos;all - I graduated from high school in 1951, a small Catholic High School. I married the following year and didn&apos;t attend collage till my oldest was 12 years old. We moved three times and over the years lost track of everyone except one friend, that all these years we make contact at Christmas. A few years ago she had a niece marry in Austin so I had a wonderful visit with Peggy and her husband who she was dating back when we were seniors in High School.

Well lo and behold - last year my sister told me our old High School had established an alumni newspaper and she mailed it to me. (my sister attended the same High School only 15 years after me) I was delighted and there was a photo that I thought was of our graduating class. They were trying to identify who was in the photo and I shared some of my thoughts along with an experience in school that has meant so much to me in my adult life. Well... the story was printed in the next issue and someone saw it and e-mailed one of my old classmates who had become a nun - she e-mailed me and here after 51 years we have been corresponding by both snail and e-mail.

We have become closer now than all those years ago - we remember one long conversation we had together outside of church one afternoon as we both had been in church praying - at the time she shared with me a nine hour novena that was a phenomenon in those years since novena&apos;s were nine days or nine weeks but none were nine hours with prayers for each hour. I still have that paper after all these years and used it when I was having a difficult time carrying my third baby.

Our lives have changed and I no longer see the Church as the only one true church and therefore, my prayer life is more eclectic - where as Winnie is still a strong church believer. But we do not have to convert each other and we are enjoying the connection after all these years.

I do remember we had a Valentine dance each year and I also remember when we were Juniors being so tired of hearing the same old records that I got a few of my friends and we visited all the classes during home room and asked if each student would donate 10 as a suprise for the seniors - as I recall there was enough for the seniors to purchase 8 new records - yes, remember records not CDs or tapes and not even 45s but records later called 78s.

Have any of you continued a friendship with school chums - tell us about it. 
 annafair February 2, 2003 - 09:54 pm At that time I had reached my full height of 5&apos; and only weighed about 85 pounds ...I didnt crush them because I remember eating them later. It was a surprise to find something on the seat and as I said I make a commotion ...He was a good friend until his death about 3 years ago. He and his wife became good friends of my husband and I and we kept in touch until both he and my husband passed away.

I have kept in touch with many of my childhood friends. Unfortunately our ranks are getting thinner and there are only a few that remain. One friend who lives outside of Atlanta I have known since we were 3 years old and we chat on the phone and via snail mail often. My matron of honor is still alive and lives near where we grew up. We too talk on the phone often. It has been some years since I have seen them but it seems just like yesterday when we talk.

When we had our last reunion I couldnt go but recieved a list of attendees and looked up several and talked with them. Some are disabled and dont go anywhere and others are still very active. But the closest ones whose friendship dated from the first grade have just about died out. I have many good memories of our youth and when we were all young marrieds.

Now I make Valentine cards for my grandchildren and some make some for me...not bad.. anna 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 2, 2003 - 11:03 pm Here is a Valentine Card link that tells us about Making Cards is a Tradition in America - Victorian Valentines 
 Bobbiecee February 3, 2003 - 12:59 am Very interesting site, Barbara. It is truly an old tradition.

Bobbie 
 Bill H February 3, 2003 - 10:39 am &quot;Bill and so your parents are given the credit for your admiration of fairness - interesting - do you have a story that shows us how you picked up on that trait? &quot; 
Not really Barbara. . I seen fairness practiced so often in family life and how unfairness hurt others that a sense of fairness just of grew on me. Although I must admit that what seems unfair to some will seem fair to others. I suppose it&apos;s ones point of view.
Bill H 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 3, 2003 - 02:44 pm Kathy at your suggestion I am adding the Teachers day room to my list - I&apos;m thinking some blooming bulbs rather than a plant that would take some care - hmmm in fact come to think that may be the best idea for the fire station and the nursing home - pretty blooms that will last longer than cut flowers but do not take any care.

Bill it is hard to see someone getting hurt isn&apos;t it - and as a child I remember seeing hurtful behavior that others either ignored or did not realize or did not see - I never knew what to do since the kid that was hurt usually didn&apos;t want anyone to notice.

Hehehe I remember being all of 5 and half and scolding my Dad would you believe - my little sister and I walked the two blocks to meet him where he got off the bus coming home from work. On the way home he swatted my sister on the backside for walking in the tall grass and getting her shoes stained with grass - I just told him he shouldn&apos;t do that - she wasn&apos;t bad she was just little and didn&apos;tknow any better. He was taken back but didn&apos;t answer and he didn&apos;t swat her again either. Golly here I was treating him as if I was the parent - can you believe...oh my.

Bill are you going to do anything special for Valentine&apos;s day this year, and how about you Bobbie - I know you said you hadn&apos;t been doing anything since your loved husband died but what about your neighbor or your daughter for that matter - what could you do...

I wish my grands lived closer - I am all excited this year about making some cards - I&apos;ve a trove of ribbon and lace and paper and frilly fabric - I would love to have some company and spend an afternoon making cards - one of my grands would be such wonderful company - I just do not know about asking another child - somehow that seems like an effort I am not sure I want to get into - now if there was a rec center near by I would take my stuff and set up a childrens after school workshop but the only rec center I know of is clear across town. Because of evening traffic it would take over an hour to get back home. Maybe I will just put Puccini on and have some fun creating cards later this week. 
 angelface555 February 4, 2003 - 11:27 am My school years had class valentine parties with cupcakes in pink frosting and everyone had a valentine or else. You still knew who was in and who was out by the handmade boxes we made and judged which really negated the practice of having to give valentines to all.

My most memorable valentine&apos;s day was getting a plane ticket and a week at a beach resort, my then husband had won it in a radio drawing and it was truly enjoyed!

Nowadays its the custom to go out to restaurants that participate in the &quot;Moonstruck Madness&quot; theme. This is where you go sample flamboyant chocolate desserts at various restaurants that also feature for that one night, various artwork done by local artists. The desserts are judged by patrons and by a local panel of judges who visit each restaurant for the local heart association. There are many donations for heart research by all who participate.

You can judge a decadent dessert and purchase a piece of art at the same time. It is quite an event and we get dressed up to really savor the experience. Then we top the evening off with dancing or going to one of the local comedy clubs. 
 Bobbiecee February 4, 2003 - 02:11 pm Barbara and Angelface, children can indeed be cruel to each other. In re Valentine&apos;s Day, my memories of it as a child were that all children, myself as well, would count the number of Valentine&apos;s we got and would judge our popularity or lack of same by the number we had received. Angelface, I totally approve of the cupcakes, etc, rather than the giving of Valentines, for that exact reason. I am pleased that children do not give valentine cards to each other at school here, so they don&apos;t have the same problem I and my classmates had. Here, children make valentine&apos;s for their parents only, a thanks for being Mum and Dad.

Barbara, I can feel your excitement about making valentines. It gives me a warm feeling...so needed in these worrying times.

Bobbie 
 Lorrie February 4, 2003 - 04:08 pm Some years back, a local magazine published a short short story I did about Valentine&apos;s day. There was some reaction to it.

 HAPPY VALENTINES DAY 
 by Lorrie Gorg 


Valentines Day was approaching and our elevenyear old hearts beat in anticipation. At 
school we had been encouraged to exchange valentines, chum to chum, no sissy stuff like 
sweetheart, or I love you or any other mush. I was delighted. It gave me a chance to 
show off my rhyming skills on my hand-made cards. Rhymes like Roses are red, violets 
are blue, sugar is sweet, and so are you.


I had twenty-one classmates and I liked them all. So I decided to make a valentine apiece, 
each with a simple poem, all cheerful, some of them downright flattering. The night before 
the class party I sat up past my bedtime cutting, pasting, and printing each laborious 
message.
On February 14 I dropped them all in the heart-shaped box our teacher had 
provided, and watched in anticipation as each name was called.


I was not a pretty child, as prettiness went in those days. I was a bit of a tomboy, and my 
parents often said I was healthy-looking with my freckled cheeks and high coloring. Id 
been told I was a lot of fun, and full of high spirits, and I imagine that was true. My 
biggest drawback, I thought, was the fifteen pounds of excess weight I carried self- 
consciously.


Happily, each person collected his or her valentines when their names were called, and 
returned to their desks to open them. When my name was called and I came up to the box 
and saw the hugest card Id ever seen, I was thrilled. It was bigger than anyone elses, with 
elaborate lace and hearts on the front.


When I opened the card, there was no poem or friendly message, only some over-sized 
printing that read HAPPY VALENTINES DAY, YOU BIG FAT PIG! GO FIND A 
HOG-PEN TO WALLOW IN! Beneath that hurtful message was a large cutout of Porky 
the Pig. Of course there was no signature.


Cheeks flaming, I slapped the card shut and looked around to see if anyone had noticed. In 
the back of the room I saw a large group of snickering boys and girls watching to see what 
my reaction would be. Refusing to give them any satisfaction, I stumbled to my feet and 
made my way home, crying in humiliation all the way and hiding my face when I 
approached anyone. 
Luckily no one was home, and I could escape to my room, where I lay in misery for hours.


I never told my parents, only my sister, who was loyally indignant, but I have never 
forgotten the callous cruelty shown on that day so many years ago.


I hate Valentines Day.
 

Lorrie 
 Faithr February 4, 2003 - 04:59 pm Lorrie that is a heart wrenching story about the cruelty of our peers. And the secrecy surrounding that shame made it worse for you. We never know how hurt someone is until they tell us, but stories like this should be read to children so they will build some empathy for others. Faith 
 losalbern February 4, 2003 - 05:17 pm Bobbiecee stated that children can be cruel and I agree. Sometimes deliberately and sometimes just as an oversight. I was never a popular child with my schoolmates, usually disheveled or more than often completely unaware of it. To make things a little bit more uneven, many kids came from well to do families and dressed far better than I did. But in truth, it never really bothered me until one Valentines day when all the kids brought their little cute things for exchanging and I did too, only to learn that none were directed to me. I went home empty handed and of course it hurt. I never was much for Valentines after that until several years later I found a girl who loved to give as well as receive them. Just last week I got my instruction tho, no chocolates this year! Shucks.. Losalbern 
 angelface555 February 4, 2003 - 06:03 pm I think that those types of stories were why we had to give each person in the class a valentine and if there was a birthday and supplies were purchased; it was for the entire class.

I was the tomboy with the perpetually skinned and blackened knees, but luckily my neighborhood was full of little boys. So it was the feminine arts that I was most conscious of in those grade school days. I actually remember trying to practice giggling in my room because a girl named Penny giggled a lot and was very popular in the coatroom. I never did learn how to giggle as my voice has always been low pitched. It was also a number of years before I learned that it wasn&apos;t the giggling that so enchanted my male chums, but the early development instead 
 Bobbiecee February 4, 2003 - 08:18 pm Lorrie, I&apos;m still aching from reading your story. I was never popular in school either. I was a tomboy like you, Angelface, and an additional disadvantage was that I was in the Gifted Child stream, so was called all sorts of nasty names, and shunned by the popular but not so smart kids. It was ghastly. I remember going home in tears, often, saying &quot;I wish I was dumb.&apos; I vowed that my children were never going to go through that. My daughter, Krysti, was also a gifted child, but fortunately, the places she went to school, the emphasis was on excelling, so she was looked up to rather than down on. Here, kids are placed in classes according to which stream they are going to be in, and in mixed grades, ie High 5th/low 6th, etc, so kids like Krysti are always challenged. Also, Krysti was also in the tertiary stream with others who were headed for Uni. I was so relieved that Krysti didn&apos;t have to go through the same things I went through. Krysti was a tomboy as well, although you&apos;d never know it now. All kids in Australia wear school uniforms which, IMO, is a great equaliser. I also remember the pain of wanting the clothes the rich kids had, and Mum and Dad not being able to afford them. Dad cured that by taking me to the poorer areas of LA. However, I got a job when 16, so I could afford to buy my own Spaulding bucks, rather than the Leed&apos;s bucks I&apos;d had before that.

Bobbie 
 Kathy Hill February 4, 2003 - 08:39 pm Spaulding bucks - now there is a memory!

Kathy 
 Bobbiecee February 4, 2003 - 08:47 pm Your age is showing, Kathy.&lt;vbg&gt;I assume you just HAD to have them as well....with the angora socks rolled down below the ankle. How about those horrible skirts with all the scratchy petticoats. And we thought we looked nice and fashionable?

Bobbie 
 pedln February 4, 2003 - 09:53 pm White bucks -- that&apos;s all I wanted for Christmas when I was a junior in high school. And that little thing filled with chalk dust that you patted them with to make them look clean.
And those angora socks -- Bonnie Doones, we called them. Once I was shopping with friends and we ran into an &quot;older&quot; girl who was going to college. She was buying at least 5 or 6 pair of Bonnie Donnes at one time -- somethng unheard of. We just stood and gaped.
And those skirts and crinolines. Now my grandkids wear all that stuff for Halloween. 
 Kathy Hill February 4, 2003 - 11:32 pm Yep, those were the days. That chalk bag was called a buck bag. I was in a Catholic school and the nuns would go into orbit when you would start banging that bag on your shoes and of course it got all over everything. I can just imagine. And those crazy starched and really starched petticoats. What were we thinking? And of course it was neat if you had a felt one with a poodle on it. Poodle? Where did that come from?

Kathy 
 Bobbiecee February 4, 2003 - 11:50 pm A bit of nostalgia time. I actually broke my nose because I was bending down doing my shoes with the buck bag when the driver had to stop quickly. Red blood on white bucks...not good. How about those beehive hairdo&apos;s...my daughter has a picture of me taken on my 21st birthday with one of those hairdo&apos;s. Every time I go to her place, I see that picture...beside the one of me taken last year (boo hoo)&lt;g&gt;.

Bobbie 
 annafair February 5, 2003 - 08:42 am Poodle skirts etc with poodles yet, crinoline petticoats...etc but I suspect we will see them return. Everything seems to be recycled. I have a habit of keeping everything and find that as soon as I throw them out they become fashionable again. I have hats from 30 years ago I am now wearing again!

Valentines...well my father always kept me from getting my nose out of joint as he gave my mother and me corsages and candy for Valentine Day...My brothers just got to help us eat the candy..Now here it is nearing another V Day and I have reached the point where I dont care if anyone remembers me..I remember me and do something special for myself!!!!!!!!!anna who loves being a sassy senior! 
 Bill H February 5, 2003 - 09:48 am Lorrie, the theme of that story was indeed cruel. I suppose the traumatic experience that child went through had a lasting effect all through her life. I read somewhere that the frontal brain lobes of children that age are not fully developed, and that probably explains some of their gross actions.
I suppose the teacher who supervised our class Valentine&apos;s Day party realized this and conducted the party in a fair way.
Bill H 
 MarkS214 February 5, 2003 - 10:30 am I am proud to be here as an ambassador for the day of LOVE. Valentines Day is remembered in my family as my birthdate. 2/14/19**. (No presents expected)

I do remember one valentine from my youth (misspent). It was a handmade one and placed on my school desk. The rest of the valentines were were commercially made and given out at the local stores in bunches to be used by school kids. So they would read, &quot;Make this day a special day, eat Wonderbread&quot; etc. I will never forget my one home made card or Mary Lou Nelson who made the card just for me..Rusty&apos;s Paw.. 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 5, 2003 - 11:05 am Hehehe Poodle skirts and how about broom skirts and halters and the first two piece bathing suits - so very modest compared to today.

Lorrie your story - oh oh oh - I could feel the pain - ohhhh

Rusty hehehe &apos;the ambassador to love&apos;...did you use the phrase as date bait...

I remember one class when I was in around the 5th or 6th grade when a Valentine box was established - I hated the idea because I just knew I would not get many cards or maybe none at all - I dutifully brought my 5&amp;10 store cards, punched out of a cardboard page of cards that came in a booklet of pages of cards and remember being shocked when my name was called out that I received some. Not as many as some and none were special but it was a warming surprise to receive the cards.

It is strange how as children we put so much stock in if we were expectable or not based on receiving cards at Valentine&apos;s Day. It must have something to do with being socially excepted in a community larger than our own families.

I realized something after all these years - I was so sure I was not that acceptable that I buried that thought and decided to have fun &apos;making&apos; - over the years come to think on it - my fun and feeling of satisfaction has always been making gifts or cards or special dinners or creative baked goods regardless the holiday. It feels stranage opening a gift and I never know what to say, as if receiving a gift is just not something that should happen - it takes my seeing the expected looks on my grandchildren&apos;s faces to realize how to them the gift they are giving me is special.

I have a friend who now ownes a beauty shop and was odd man out as a child - leave it to her - she had it figured out - she was a tom boy, had a dark complexion with hair that stuck out all over - not a child beauty - well when Valentine&apos;s came she stuffed the box with all these Valentine cards for herself so that her name was called out over and over or if names werent called she had a pile of cards on her desk - and heheheh in High School she had the florist send her a corsage to the school so that they had to call for her to come to the office over the PA system. We laugh every year as she remembers her stories.

Years ago when my daughter was earning extra money the summer before and first year of collage she worked at a small local card and gift shop that later became a Hallmark shop - we learned that Valentine&apos;s Day has the biggest sales for cards and small gifts, even larger than Christmas. And the day that beat it all, believe it or not, was Mother&apos;s day. Seems not everyone celebrates Christmas nor does everyone have a Valentine. 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 5, 2003 - 01:23 pm Valentine Traditions Around the World 
Check out Scotland and France where the government had to interfere...
 History and Symbols of Saint Valentine Day 
 Coyote February 6, 2003 - 07:10 am BARBARA - About your enjoyment in making and giving: I learned long ago the saying about God loving a cheerful giver was designed primarily for the collection of offerings. What matters more to most hummans, is that we love cheerful receivers. We care most about, and enjoy most, those we do the most for, rather than the other way around.

This theory has a new line of reasoning, now that my valentine and I live in a double-wide with no basement, garage, or attic. Whenever somebody gives us something, we have no place to put it, but if we give something to somebody else, that becomes a favorable balance of trade. 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 6, 2003 - 10:52 am Wow interesting turn Benjamin - need to tuck that one away to call on more often - thanks

Benjamin are you in a moble home park or out on some land...sounds like you had been living in a home with a basement and changed your house for a different kind of lifestyle - how is itworking for you. 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 6, 2003 - 10:57 am Bobbiecee the image of white Bucks so caught our attention and we went off into memory land that I never did ask what does tertiary stream mean - I am assuming Uni is simply short for University but I have no clue what tertiary stream is all about - I can guess it has something to do with the level of ability a child shows doing school work. 
 Bobbiecee February 6, 2003 - 02:20 pm Barbara....I think you use the term &apos;college prep.&apos; College has a different meaning here, two meanings. 1) a place where school leavers can return to to complete or improve their high school grades, and take tertiary prep courses prior to entry into Uni (University); 2) living accomodation and specific tertiary interest within a Uni. ie.. when I earned my GradDip (Graduate Diploma) in my field, plus other additional diplomas (Addictions, etc), plus my MA and Doctorate, I stayed in the one college when I went down for Res (Residential School) as I did all my advanced degrees in external studies. That college housed those taking Psychology. My college had a wonderful resource area with immediate access to psychological literature and studies from within Australia and throughout the world.

My daughter was in the tertiary stream because she intended to go to Uni....and did. My son didn&apos;t want to go to Uni, so he chose the Technical stream, although he had the intelligence to complete the tertiary stream. Interestingly enough, although my daughter is making very good money, my son, with no Uni, is making much more. So, here in Australia, there isn&apos;t the &apos;class&apos; system division between blue and white collar workers that there appears to be in the US. Not only are tech tradesmen highly respected, the dinki-di Aussie, but they usually make as much money, and often, more than the tertiary educated. Interesting cultural difference.

Bobbie 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 6, 2003 - 04:20 pm OK Thanks for the explanation - what you say about salary and education counts here as well - it is according to the job - example my youngest son has only about 15 hours (1/2 year of Collage) and as a manager with Fed. Express makes more than twice the salary as Sally Gale who is a school teacher and the same money as my son-in-law who has his Doctorate and co-owns some computer stores in the South.

The difference isn&apos;t what they read because neither of them read but Gary has had some very interesting jobs in mining and with the LCRA (lower Colorado River Authority) He sits on several boards as a financial advisor.

Where as Paul has a smaller group of friends but that could be personality - Paul is more involved with his family of three boys but still does Rotary and Chamber, playing Racket Ball regularly with folks that run the Bank in town, another who has a string of restaurants and his neighbor, who not only has a large ranch outside of town but is in environmental studies at A&amp;M - they are all collage educated and there is Paul right in with them.

Paul is very dyslexic before there was as much help as there is now and so studying by reading was next to impossible - but true to form they find these dyslexic kids have high intelligence.

I think a lot of it has to do with energy and desire to excel and continue to learn regardless your formal education. I think the ones that give up are often giving up because it seems easier and it is a characteristic of taking the easy road that keeps them from excelling in the work place. 
 Bobbiecee February 6, 2003 - 06:02 pm Barbara...Greg (son) was dyslexic as well. I was fortunate that it was picked up very early, Grade 1, and Greg received mobs of help from the school, including individual sessions to help him to identify when he had words back to front, etc. We also had a very active SPELD (Special Learning Disabilities) group in Alice Springs in which I was active in and which offered considerable help for me and Greg. Greg&apos;s main problem as he got older was when he was having math tests and would transpose the answer. However, the teachers recognised that his answers were back to front, because the numbers were as well, so he was given credit, and able to laugh about it. Yes, dyslexic kids do have very high intelligence...After they developed IQ tests which took dyslexia into account, Greg scored in the genius range. His first test, the standard WISC, of course, showed him as low normal. I&apos;m just fortunate that Greg received so much help, and was therefore able to do well in school...and developed the self-esteem to do extremely well in his career choice. He&apos;s a private contractor to Dept of Forestry...forest harvesting of pine plantations....an extremely choice contract, where he&apos;s essentially set for life now. Krysti is an Accountant Supervisor (middle management) at a large insurance company in Brisbane. Greg, obviously, works in the bush, and has a lovely property just out from a town 2 hours north of me.

Bobbie 
 betty gregory February 6, 2003 - 08:52 pm Lorrie, I&apos;m still thinking about your story and wondering if it has an untold, secret ending. Among the large number of children who received the beautiful, handmade valentines from you, could there have been one miserable, lonely child whose heart was mended as yours was broken?

Betty 
 Lorrie February 6, 2003 - 11:09 pm Betty, what an interesting thought! I never did think about how anyone else would be feeling that day---you have a good point. They were pretty, at that.

Lorrie 
 Coyote February 7, 2003 - 08:18 am BARBARA - I have lived in many different kinds of housing, but had retired to southern Colorado, where I bought an old adobe house with some extra lots, storage, etc. Then my valentine, Ms. E (formerly Winddancer,) emailed me after she had been reading my posts on various sites, then one thing led to another, I sold my place on contract and moved out here to northern California. I misunderstood her comment that she didn&apos;t have very much in the way of household goods (due to a fire several years back,) so bought a two bedroom double-wide in a senior park. I would be happier in a bigger place, but my arthritis plus this location made this a very wise decision for us. But we quickly learned we could have made good use of a large barn for extra storage.

If you are thinking about making such a change yourself, there is a SN site for manufactured housing or somesuch where you might find more opinions and ideas. 
 howzat February 7, 2003 - 11:02 am Bet that taught you to ask what the definition of &quot;very much&quot; is.

Howzat 
 annafair February 8, 2003 - 11:47 am Some how thinking of Valentine Day reminds me of Autograph books..I still have one from the 6th grade //I think .I havent looked at it lately but was remembering some of them...like 
Dont it get you mad 
Dont it get your goat 
When you&apos;re in the bathtub 
Without any soap////I think that is from one of my brothers. 
When you&apos;re old and gray 
And drinking tea 
Burn your lips and think of me.

I could go on but just wanted to mention this...anna 
 howzat February 8, 2003 - 12:05 pm One of my most prized possessions is the autograph book belonging to my mother. I found it in her things after her death. Mother was so shy, I was surprised she could bring herself to offer the book to someone for their autograph. She could hardly bring herself to do anything that brought attention to herself. Lots of folks misunderstood my mother&apos;s shyness for being &quot;aloof&quot;. Nothing could have been further from the truth. She craved being a &quot;part&quot; of something and the society of other humans. She just was too shy to do anything about it.

Howzat 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 8, 2003 - 01:36 pm Ah yes, autograph books - Thanks for the memories - we had them in the 8th grade - our school years were broken, 1 through 8 and then High School so that 8th grade was a significant year because after graduation we would all be going our seperate ways to one of several Catholic High Schools - I remember seeing my mother&apos;s autograph book. I&apos;ve no idea what happened to it but I do remember the sayings to be so many more and much more original.

We received ours in late Spring a month or so before graduation. I remember in a group we often met on the corner under a big tree where there was a rail fense that the boys often sat on and we exchanged book after book, writing our little verses and signing our names. We even would come up to some of the sisters and ask them to write in our books as they walked from school to the convent past that corner. I think the sisters came by early expecting this is what we would do because if we stayed on that corner more than a half an hour we knew we were late for chores and we scattered quickly.

Now in 6th grade I remember many of buying a notebook - the kind that is black with white markings all over and a box in the middle of the hard cover that has a label area where you wrote your name and school and grade. The inside cover often had spelling and English tips and the back cover always had the mutiplication table and other math tips.

We folded the first page into thirds, leaving just a third of that page exposed and on that third of a page we wrote all these questions - what is your favorite color and what is your favorite movie and animal etc. etc. Soem even used a colorered pencil to write the questions. And then we asked all the kids in the class one by one to take a page that was exposed and fill out their answers with their name on top - after they filled out their page we would fold it back under the question page so that a new clean sheet of paper was exposed for the next one.

There were more pages in our notebooks that kids in our class so then we went to the next class up (ahum - never down) and that wasn&apos;t so bad, but it took a real self-assured brave kid to ask a student two classes above who were 8th graders. Someone in our class had a brother in the 8th grade so we asked him and his friends but they treated us like such little kids it was&apos;t fun. Ah what a difference two years made before the age of 16. 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 8, 2003 - 01:50 pm Two sites about Autograph books... Autograph Album / with a collection of versus 

 Memories of Autograph Books 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 8, 2003 - 02:18 pm Did you know February is...
 American Heart Month Black History Month Bird Feeding month Cherry Month -- Oh I remember the bakeries featuring cherry filled log cakes with white icing and an axe as decoration - and Black Forest cakes were also popular as were open cherry tarts Dental Health Month Friendship Month Grapefruit Month - Wow that is a surprise Finally wouldn&apos;t you know Snack Food Month
February 10 is Umbrella Day - The 8th is Boy Scout Day and believe it or not the 9th is Toothache Day - (I guess with it being Snack Food Month) 

 Thomas Edison&apos;s Birthday is on the 11th and of course Lincoln&apos;s Birthday on the 12th and Washington&apos;s on the 22nd with a combination holiday on the 17th. 

The artist Wood Grant&apos;s Birthday on the 13th. Pluto was discovered in 1930 on February 18 and hehehe the 18th is Quiet Day 

 Ansel Adams&apos; Birthday on the 20th and Winslow Homer&apos;s is on the 24th along with Mexico&apos;s Flag Day 

 Renoir who painted the lovely peice in our heading - never noticed before the two couples in the very back chatting with each other under the trees - looks like the whole family is a part of this young man&apos;s courting - well Renoir&apos;s Birthday on the 24th and Daumier&apos;s on the 26th along with the Birthday of Levi Strauss. The 27th is Polar Bear Day 
 isak2002 February 9, 2003 - 11:07 am The mention of autograph books naturally leads to forgotten things such as high school and college yearbooks and writing in them; making your own valentines, and bringing cupcakes to school for one&apos;s birthday. 
I was lucky beyond belief having a Valentine&apos;s Day birthday, and in having two friends who had birthdays 
on the 6th and 12th of Feb. We 3 had an 8th grade-birthday party never to be forgotten....our parents hired the local 
fraternal hall and we invited all of the 7th and 8th graders to the party. My sister played her record player and 
all her best records, and there were Cokes, cookies and Swamp Water!!! (A mix of all sodas over ice)...it sounds 
terrible now, but it was way cool then! In 1952-3 (?) it did not get much better than that! My favorite present that year was a copy of Seventeen Magazine from my favorite (and wisest) teacher. 
isak 
 Faithr February 9, 2003 - 01:52 pm Re February is the month of my birthday, my newest great grand daughters birthday, and assorted other grands and great grands. Also President Reagan&apos;s birthday. I had a calendar once that had a holiday marked on every day in Feb. except the 5th. My Mother said it was reserved for me but I think President Reagan got it instead, hahahah

In 1941 I was invited to the formal Valentine Day Ball at our high-school by a very nice classmate. As we walked in he began introducing me to his friends as I was brand new to this school. Leaning against the wall was an older boy in engineers pants and boots and a corduroy jacket. I thought &quot;That is the man I will marry!&quot; and as quick as the thought came and embarrassed me I swept it under the conscious mind. We were introduced and he pardoned himself for not dancing as he was not dressed for it and soon he left. I had a nice evening. Later I kept meeting this boy at different places, he was 19 and I was 14 and I was not allowed to date him when he asked.Summer came and we did date against my moms wishes. Still at the end of the year we were married, pregnant and living in Reno where he attended college. We had three children and a very good life for a long time then, children up and away and it was over. Funny thing is we didn&apos;t realize it at the time but it was Valentines day again the day we agreed to part. Life is serendipitous for sure. faith 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 9, 2003 - 03:19 pm Oh my Faith, as aching a love story as the famous love stories in History Interesting how most love stories in history ended in dispair or tragedy or in sadness. 
 betty gregory February 9, 2003 - 03:56 pm A beautiful story, Faith, especially that first glimpse of your husband-to-be. My marriage, too, was good while it was good.

-----------------------------------------

Autograph books. If only I still had mine!!!! I still have the memory, though. It was summer time and my mother and the next-door-neighbor mother called together the small gang of my girlfriends to go.....where??.....they wouldn&apos;t tell us. &quot;A surprise,&quot; they said. I think I was between 5th and 6th grades that summer. We were instructed to bring our autograph books.....a big thing at the time.

This was central Texas, late 50s. We drove across town to the section of expensive homes and pulled up to the curb of a non-descript house. &quot;Now we wait,&quot; my mother said. Within minutes, a dark green U.S. Army car came down the street and pulled into the short driveway. That car and our car were the only two cars around. The Army car&apos;s doors opened and 3 or 4 men in army fatigue clothing got out, Elvis Presley among them. Mother and my girlfriend&apos;s mother were rushing us out of the car, waving their arms at the other car and yelling &quot;helloooo!!&quot; Elvis graciously signed all our autograph books, shook hands with our mothers and, as I remember, seemed unhurried and completely at ease.

We were walking back to our car when I turned to run back over to my idol, my obsession, Elvis Presley, and told him, &quot;Bend down, I&apos;m going to kiss you.&quot; He did and I kissed his cheek.

He was stationed at Fort Hood, TX, next door to Killeen, where we lived, and Mother had read that since he had just finished basic training, that he was allowed to live off post. This has been Mother&apos;s story to tell over the years, of how I had a mind of my own and not afraid to demand to kiss Elvis. I just wish I still had that autograph book!!

Betty 
 Faithr February 9, 2003 - 09:05 pm My husband always forgot my birthday and he forgot our real anniversary. But I always got a big box of chocolates in a big red heart with lots of lacy on Valentines day and romantic cards, the kind that made the kids giggle and my son at 7 would turn his head and pretend gag.Yeah We had a good romance and raised some wonderful kids.fp. 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 11, 2003 - 01:21 am There seems to have been many tales that surround St. Valentine&apos;s Day including the concept that birds choice their mate on that day. Valentine History and Customs 

Interesting how we place Romantic Love high on our scale of desirable life time experiences and yet the love that binds families together isn&apos;t really Romantic Love is it - I&apos;ve been working with a young women just going through divorce and typical of what I hear there are all the benign issues that drove her crazy and she still hasn&apos;t caught on that it was all about control -

I look at the many couples that I have worked with since 1980 - buying a house puts their marriage to a test - so many of the marriages that they consider themselves in good working order, typically one dominates with control issues and it is usually the man. Those women who don&apos;t chaff and but who do not experience any abuse were usually quiet with few opinions - hmmm That is certainly the magic pill that traditionalists suggest makes for not only a happy family but also makes for the ultimate, Romantic Love.

In all these years I cannot think of one couple where they equally shared their thoughts and opinions - if the women is vocal in her opinions she is either obvious in her domination over him or on the verge of or just completed a divorce. This can be a strange holiday if we only listen and fantasies based on the advertisements as a day featuring Romantic Love. So far from what I have observed there isn&apos;t much room for equality in Romantic Love.

Well I am looking forward to the day this year - my oldest grandboy turned 14 on Monday the 10th - with the family sick I didn&apos;t drive over on this past Sunday and so I will drive over Friday - with the restaurants all crowded the plan is to have steaks on the grill and I will bring a lucious Valentine/Birthday cake - I am smiling in anticipation. 
 losalbern February 11, 2003 - 09:32 am Barbara, your last posting about &quot;contol and marriage&quot; sounds like a good two week topic at this forum. Losalbern 
 Bill H February 11, 2003 - 10:38 am Barbara, thank you for that interesting link. Those old customs answered a few questions. Maybe that is how my grade school teacher got her sense of fair play for Valentines Day. Good legend about the robin and sparrow. There is another legend about the robin as follows: When you see your first spring robin make a wish and it will be granted.
Bill H 
 annafair February 11, 2003 - 03:59 pm Barbara from a senior lady my feelings seem to be that young women of today feel lucky to find a husband and put up with a lot of &quot;controlling&quot;. My mother did me the best favor when she raised me to believe first, in myself and second I didnt NEED to have a husband to be happy of fulfilled. Her &quot;There are worse things in life than never being married&quot; Now she and my father had a very good relationship and from my view point it seemed equal. He worked, she took care of the house,although he did a lot of the maintenence...and helped with the children. She often told about him changing diapers etc and he was always there for us as children and adults. I was an only girl in a family of five boys and I never so much as ironed a handkerchief for them. We all learned to iron and to cook and to clean a house. It was part of being a family. I passed the same to my children. My daughters are married but are really independent. My sons can do their own laundry and cook and clean house. In thier marriages I see equality. I hope it lasts but all have been married now for from 25 years to ten. They have 6 children between them and have developed a similiar relationship that my brothers and I did and kept it that way. We are one big family now ...

Do I think I had an equal marriage and a romantic one? Yes due partly to the fact my husband was in the service and was away often on missions. He was a pilot and flew everywhere so I was alone a lot and always did what I felt was right. One thing though from the beginning he found I was very independent ..telling him the night before our wedding that I believed in until death do us part and if he felt that was not something he could live up to than we could just cancel the wedding.

We had over 40years together and his death was devastating. I always felt treated as an equal and we made decisions together. We both had strong personalities, which helped and we were both determined to stay together ...regardless. Once some asked if we ever had arguements//Yes in stereo and living color but in the end we always resolved it..sometimes he way and sometimes mine but most of the time it was a mutual.

I see freind who agonize over the fact thier husbands forget anniversaries and birthdays etc..I just put the dates on a large yearly calendar so everyone could see it. Mentioned at least a month in advance what day was coming up and if it was something where I wanted to be remembered I would say IF you are going to do something for that day I would like to go to a specific restaurant, and I would like to have this. It was always gentle not demanding and that way I was never dissapppointed ..I thought that was 1000 times better than being angry and upset because he and the children forgot. In fact it helped everyone to remember birthdays etc and all were great days not days of diasappointments....just a thought ...although I think I went on too long..just remembering what a special marriage I had ....Happy Valentines day to all and if you have no one to remember you&gt;&gt;&gt;REMEMBER YOURSELF&gt;&gt;It is OKAY ... 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 11, 2003 - 05:00 pm Losalbern control is an interesting life style isnt it - my thought is it is based in fear. But another view. I have become interested after all these years in geometry again. It was a favorite subject for me in High School and it really guided me from then on in how I presented my thoughts and arguments - well with this interest. I have been fascinated with Mandelbrots Fractal Geometry which focuses on broken, wrinkled, and uneven shapes.

Fractals is the patterns of Chaos and to further how Chaos is our basic world experience think how land is haphazardly created by volcanoes popping up and weather eroding and continental plates moving and creeks being damned by a wildlife changing the course of rivers. That in order to predict weather using variables as wind speeds, air pressures, humidity, temperature and sunspots wont help increase the accuracy of long range weather forecasting. Since these are all dynamic systems the heat rising from the hood of a car or the wind from the wings of a mosquito in Madagascar is enough to change the behavior of weather.

All to say relationships are the stuff of Fractals. We have considered Chaos as disorder, anarchy, discord, disarray, jumble, disturbed, unsystematic, slovenly, tumultuous rather than the natural order of some things that can not be described and measured as the box, sphere and cone of Geometry. I just think some folks have a greater desire to hang on when things are in order, their order, and must make the world comply ethically and physically surround themselves with order, uniformity, routine, methodical behavior and that includes the behavior of people which they call normal behavior.

I guess it takes someone like Mandelbrot who experienced the concentration camps of Hitler in his youth where he and his uncle survived and all other family perished to see just how Chaotic life really is. I know my own life has been a series of the unexpected with life altering experiences.

I am beginning to accept that chaos is normal and to stop revisiting some of my life experiences as evidence that I needed more order, uniformity, routine in my life. Many will choose to control themselves and those around them believing order and predictability is more valuable.

 Bill I love these old bird legends dont you - there are so many around the Birth of Christ and now to learn about these legends around St. Valentines Day - we have seen our robins over two weeks ago now - so if you live north Spring is really on the way. You would never know it though - the end of last week it was cold and drizzly with a flurry of snow - we have not had a snowflake here since 1996!

 Anna I am so pleased you had the opportunity to reminisce about your marriage and have these pages to do just that. Such lovely memories to have and hold this time of the year. Isnt it lovely to see our children making their marriages work - I know my youngest has an especially good relationship. I think two things, Sally was a tom boy and enjoys the physical activities that having a family of all boys presents and the biggie Sally and Paul were dating since they were Freshman in High School with only a few other dates during those High School years and they knew each other since the 6th grade - they grew up together - established their values together - they are probably more alike in their thinking than a brother and sister. They seem to have a strong marriage. 
 Bobbiecee February 11, 2003 - 07:39 pm ANNA...As I read your post, it was like deja vu. You were saying what I would have said if I was writing on the same topics. The similarities are striking...as are our beliefs, and the beliefs and values we transmitted to our children, as well as the similarities in our own marriages, the equality, the good memories since our husband&apos;s have died...and our current values.

Bobbie 
 angelface555 February 12, 2003 - 12:23 pm It has been an interesting read this morning. I am one whose life has been forged through chaos and I now prefer the quiet and peace of order and methodology.

I am a strong and independent woman who has been married twice and had some other long term relationships. I have learned that I do better on my own, that marriage is a skill I haven&apos;t mastered and I do fine with friends rather then husbands.

My personal life has included many setbacks, family acrimony and deaths. It has taken a strong will to survive and find a measure of contentment in my own preferences and lifestyle. When I am reproached for not getting out more or for taking another class or finding a new electronic gadget; I simply remember that we are all equal but separate.

I have a friend who believes as I do and he and I enjoy our time together. But so many others seek to impose their lifestyle on me. Why don&apos;t we marry? Why do I seem to be more interested in things they are not and why won&apos;t I become more like them? Why do I get so caught up in things that they prefer to ignore or why do I neglect what they find important?

If we were all the same; what a sorry boring place our world would be! 
 losalbern February 12, 2003 - 02:02 pm and needed very much. My wife of 55 years wants me to adjourn to the living room and start a fire in the fireplace and I will do that shortly. Barbara, I have never experienced such a long and thoughtful response to such a simple posting I made earlier. WOW! I would recommend your viewing of the magazine &quot;Discover&quot;, perhaps at a local library, that often deals with subject matter such as chaos and similar matters that interest a science bend such as yours. And to you other ladies who may have had less than desired relationships with men; hey, we are certainly not alike. Not that I ever was a paragon of virtue. I have had plenty of faults and some of them still persist. But our marriage has been one that was always on equal footing, with specialist roles and plenty of personal freedom. She does her own thing with my blessing. She took to motherhood like she invented it. A great Mom. She plays golf and so do I but seldom together. ( We have a little family joke that I introduced her to golf, sex and iced tea!) She has lead a protected life and admittedly loves it that way. She is basically a very good person, a fact that I am grateful for. Needless to say I love her a great deal. I think we have had a fantastic marriage but I still don&apos;t have a clue of what to get her for Valentines day. Except for the no chocolates edict. She wants to lose five pounds. Any ideas? Losalbern 
 Faithr February 12, 2003 - 03:20 pm You are a romantic Losalbern as was my husband. Once he brought me a box of chocolates and inside the wrapping was a picture of us his buddies had taken of us in a boat on the river in San Antonio and we were kissing and willows were hanging over us . It was a sweet picture in which we had been married about 4 years at that time. He had a photography shop blow it up and frame it. He wrote a little bit on his card about still feeling like that all these years later. That was romantic. But I still wanted the chocolates. faith 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 12, 2003 - 03:48 pm Things - things, they never really say much do they and yet it feels so empty not receiving things -

And so Faith you really like your chocolate - did you ever read that book by Joanne Harris or see the movie - I saw the movie and thought it was a delight - now that would be a great movie to rent for a Valentine night with some chocolate and a glass of champaigne - good champaigne like a Cliquot.

Now there is an idea for you Losalbern - get a video - regardless no chocolate this one is a delight - have a card that doesn&apos;t just tell her you love her but what she is that is special that you love - some kind of special drink - if you like champaigne or a good bottle of wine or even if you both prefer Beer than go for some imported special something - rather than the chocolate how about some strawberries or a bit of pate and crackers and of course the room must look festive with some flowers - not necessarily roses - in fact if you like to garden how about the earlier idea suggested where you stop at the nursery and pick up some potted plants or even some bulbs that have been forced and almost in bloom or just a mixed bouquet picked up at the grocery market.

Well I&apos;m off to a my poetry group tonight - toodooles. 
 Bobbiecee February 12, 2003 - 04:39 pm Angelface...Crises in life, when one works through them, and grows, are what make, IMO, a deep person. In contrast, most who have not faced crises and grown, are usually shallow.

Bobbie 
 losalbern February 12, 2003 - 04:48 pm Say Barbara! there has been some good thinking, good planning, good ideas about Valentine evening. Shouldn&apos;t be too hard to carry off, either. I received a bottle of champagne last month for my birthday, and a good dip or pate&amp;some flowers! Actually she came home a couple days ago with three little tiny pots of bulbs ready to bloom, crocus and the like. So maybe a little bouquet of cut flowers. Maybe just a chocolate or two , Faith! And perhaps a little writeup.. And then a video movie. We just saw Fat Greek Wedding yesterday. That would have been perfect! (We are usually behind the curve when it comes to movies. ) We just played &quot;Moonstruck&quot; a couple of weeks ago. I will have to ponder that one for a while! Any more good ideas? Losalbern 
 Coyote February 12, 2003 - 09:09 pm LOSALBERN - Well, you could always tuck a nice gift certificate to her favorite shopping spot into a valentine. Not as romantic as some of the other suggestions, but always appreciated. The suprise is when she tells you what you got her. 
 angelface555 February 13, 2003 - 11:24 am 
 annafair February 13, 2003 - 11:55 am All the suggestions were great...and I think if I can rent it I will get My Big Fat Greek Wedding...I am sure whatever you do will be fine with the missus....I never wanted candy but plants ...something that would last past Valentines day..even now I enjoy some of the plants he gave me and we put out together. That gives me tender memories which are treasures any time of the year.

Angel you live your life and pooh on anyone who tries to throw water on your ideas. I had several female relatives who had long time relationships and never married. They were successful in all areas of thier lives and they died with no regrets.

It is sunny and cold here but oh the sunshine is so welcome. Yesterday it was 50 degrees and I felt sping was just around the corner. I know winter hasnt left but it is February and each day moves us closer to spring...have a great day everyone..anna 
 Bobbiecee February 13, 2003 - 07:36 pm ANGELFACE...&apos; sometimes I feel as deep as the oceans... 

A storm on the surface, but an inner calm in the depths.

Bobbie 
 angelface555 February 14, 2003 - 12:13 pm Bobbie, Thank you. You are so good for all of us. 
 losalbern February 14, 2003 - 01:09 pm And especially to Barbara whose ideas I followed to fulfillment. While my Valentine is out grocery shopping, I did my errands, to wit: the champagne is chilling; found a nice bouquet of mixed cut flowers(Anne, we have so many potted plants now that one more would be a drudge), picked up two Hershey bars just for ambiance. At the deli, got a small container each of shrimp salad and tuna salad that should go well with Ritz crackers-- followed with ambrosia and strawberry parfait. For the movie, I found &quot;Chocolat&quot;. For a guy that didn&apos;t have a clue clear up to yesterday, hey I think I&apos;ve got a winner this year! Thanks loads to everyone! Losalbern 
 Bobbiecee February 14, 2003 - 02:35 pm Angelface....As I believe you&apos;re aware, one of the greatest things about my career is/was that I have been able to see people who have been overwhelmed by crises overcome these crises...grow...in both directions...stature and strength and depth. I see these people, Phoenix Rising...as &apos;miracles.&apos; I view you as one of those people. As I am mainly retired now, I only take on clients via word of mouth, in other words, highly motivated people. Therefore, I am able to see many little miracles, many cases of Phoenix Rising. It is so rewarding and moving.

Bobbie 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 14, 2003 - 02:43 pm losalbern I am smiling at what sounds like excitment for you of having put something different together - hope you have a cozy lovely evening - now don&apos;t forget to tell her not just that you love her but what is special about her that you love...

Is the sun just rising where you are Bobbie - have a great day - it is summer there isn&apos;t it - how wonderful - I really like summer don&apos;t you but it would seem strange to have Valentine&apos;s Day in summer - it was always the holiday that brought color and fun to mid-winter.

Anna - Carol - Faith - Angleface - Bill - who else - have a great day...

Had planned on running over to Collage Station to be with son and grandboys but we are expecting a horrible winter sleet and hail storm tonight and I must come back tonight since I&apos;ve appointments tomorrow so the better part of wisdom came into play - in good weather, and I do have a heavy foot, the trip takes two hours - in high winds with sleet and hail no telling - I just called my son to cancel - Turns out Sally Gale has been home for two days with the flu and Valentine&apos;s is to Fed Ex (he is the manager of the station) like Christmas overnight, so he is pooped and he admitted they wouldn&apos;t have been that much company - and so to surprise all the boys I got on the internet - for a change I sent e-mail cards with a gift cirtificate from Amazon.com to all 5 grandboys - the three in Collage Station and the two in Saluda. Now they can all have fun shopping tonight learning how to navigate amazon.com with their little gift.

Well I&apos;m off with my plants to the nursing home and the fire station before this storm hits. I think I will treat myself to a $12 back massage at Whole Foods on my way Home and then curl up with the latest Agatha Raison Mystery that arrived the other day - Agatha Raison and the Love from Hell I am serious that is the name of it... 
 Bobbiecee February 14, 2003 - 02:59 pm BARBARA...Yes, it is morning...almost 8 am...The sun came up at 5.30 am this morning. I took my dog for a walk in the bush at 5.45, after sitting in my back yard with my cuppa, watching the sunrise. Our summer was quite cool (for us) while in the grip of the big dry. However, the El Nino appears to be leaving us, and the humidity and heat is returning...thus the early walk. I have never been so glad to have a return of humidity which signals a return of our normal summer pattern...afternoon thunderstorms. If you have difficulty with Valentine&apos;s Day in summer, you&apos;d have a great deal of trouble with Christmas in summer, eh? I found it difficult the first two years after I migrated here. I soon learned that a barbeque was best for a summertime Christmas. A summer Valentine&apos;s Day has never bothered me. When my husband was alive, it was always a day when we could go to either the ocean, a lake or waterhole, or out bush, to hold hands and thrill over the beauty of nature...aesthetic intimacy. BTW, Valentine&apos;s Day was yesterday, down under. Happy Valentine&apos;s Day to the northern hemishphere today.

Bobbie 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 14, 2003 - 04:39 pm Well actually no Christmas on the patio are my favorite Christmas&apos; - we have a warm Christmas day about as often as a cold one where as February is our rainy month - as other parts of the country get spring rain in April we get it in February - although the redbud and forsythia and other spring blossoms are a riot of color amid the dreary days with the Robins and Blue Jays hopping around the front lawns -

Christmas can be cold but our wee bit of winter usually starts with some rain in November than blue pretty skies in the high 60s and low 70s in December - than between Christmas and New Year we usually get a blue Norther that lasts for 3 days plummeting the temps into the 30s - we then get these Northers off and on all through January and early February - from mid February on, unless it is a freak storm, it is Spring with temps climbing higher and higher to the &apos;Long Hot Summer&apos; starting in early May with temps in the 100s or upper 90s and they stay that way till at least the end of September dipping into the 90s and 80s in October.

We are not as warm as South Texas or Florida and we do not cool off at night as they do in Southern California but I actually like the heat - the hotter it is the less humidity - to me the 90s are a horror as I drip and drip and drip. 
 Bobbiecee February 14, 2003 - 04:53 pm BARB...Our Christmas temp is in the 30&apos;s as well..Centigrade. Temps on Christmas Day range from 86-100F. Christmas meal is either cold turkey and ham (or barbequed meat and seafood), many salads, entrees of whole prawns (need to be unshelled), fresh fruits (many tropical), sweets are Christmas pudding and Pavlova. Activities: swimming in pools, game of back yard cricket, or spending Christmas Day at the beach. Clothes: minimum possible.&lt;G&gt;Down under, 6 White Boomers (kangaroos) take Father Christmas on his Australian run.

Bobbie 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 14, 2003 - 05:00 pm Bobbie since you are so far south are you temperate to hot even during your winter? 
 MaryZ February 14, 2003 - 05:13 pm Barbara, We love the Agatha Raisin books, too. Thanks for letting us know there is a new one out! I&apos;m reading an older Hamish MacBeth book now (the other M.C.Beaton series) and have just finished a 2001 Hamish Christmas story. What delightful tales she tells! 
 Bobbiecee February 14, 2003 - 05:13 pm We, in Brisbane, are only 500 kms south of the Tropic of Capricorn. Same distance south of the Tropic that Florida is north. Winter here is temperate...normal winter temp varies between 20-25C (68-77F). We usually have a week or so of what we call freezing weather. That&apos;s when the temperature dips to a high of 16-18C (60-64F). We rug up in layers of clothing those days. It is, of course, lower at night, but never gets down to 0C (32). Normal low is 8-12(46-52F), but starts warming up shortly after the sun comes up. North and far north Queensland remains hot during the summer...maximum of 4-5 degrees difference between summer and winter. It gets a lot colder in our southern cities...Sydney, Melbourne, Adelaide. Too cold for me.&lt;G&gt;Sydney is 1200 kms south of Brisbane, Melbourne another 500 kms southwest.

Bobbie 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 14, 2003 - 05:41 pm You know I am almost uncertain sharing this but hay, it is part of my life and my life matters as much as any - The Valentine That Got Away - sort of finds my cry button when I pause -

Back in first grade my mother was pregnant and in those days a women pregnant could not be seen in public and so it was my after school task to shop for the daily needs - every day it was down to Vincintie&apos;s for a quart of milk, two potatoes, a half loaf of rye bread, a half pound of liverwurst to be fried for my father&apos;s breakfast and for our lunch sandwiches. Usually some other not everyday item was on this verbal list that I would often forget the odd item.

My mother would be beside herself as she couldn&apos;t understand how after speaking about the girl with the umbrella and giving me an umbrella to carry I could forget the salt that had a little girl with an umbrella on the label - on and on with her various associations - I would not be able to remember the entire list - Mom could not write it out since I was in first grade and my reading ability was very limited and Mrs. Vincinti spoke Italian with no English and Mom spoke German with little English. Well walking on the way home from school Ralph taught me how to remember things on my fingers and by assigning an item to each finger so that according to how many fingers were needed that was how many items I needed to bring home. We became great friends and by third grade we had a crush on each other.

The news of our crush got out and he was teased and met me under the neighbor&apos;s front stairs to talk it over how he was not going to walk home with me anymore - a week later my friend Chickie came to the back screen door saying Ralph needed to see me under the stairs. I was sure he would be angry again but I went.

Now you must understand, Ralph lived on the next street in a one room basement apartment with his mother since his father had run off years before. This was during a time when there were no social services and so I am not sure what they used for money, maybe the church. The large room had one single bed that they both slept in - one sort of comfortable chair and one table with a wooden kitchen chair at the table and the sink and stove area. No ice box. That was it...I remember he saying after I asked, that they only needed one chair at the table since only one of them ate at a time.

He lived two houses down from my Aunt and Uncle with a very large field behind his house where most of the kids in the area played and the boys had a baseball field that only took up one small area of this field. Next to the field was the house of Chickie&apos;s many Italian cousins with her house next to it and across from ours. We and most of the neighbors all spoke German.

Well when I met Ralph under the stairs, that was a closed in area with a square 3X3 cut out, that we scooted through he was upset - he needed my help - his mother was hanging in their kitchen area and he didn&apos;t want anyone to know since he knew he would be taken to an orphanage. Well we told Chickie and she told her cousins since we needed their help. We kids went over and cut her down. Chickies older cousin stepped up on the sink and reached over with a sharp kitchen knife to cut the rope after we had pushed the chair under where she was going to fall. I remember being so surprised there was newspaper to clean up her mess before we could move the chair since we could not afford a newspaper and my Father had a job. We put her in the chair and covered her with a sheet. Each day I told mom I was hungrier and needed two sandwiches - in the evening he sat at the outdoor table under the grape arbor to eat with Chickie&apos;s cousins aunts uncles grands - there were so many no one knew who was or not at the table and we kids often slipped in and ate with them. He went home each night and slept with his dead mother in the chair - got up, dressed and went to school.

This went on for a week and it was Saturday again. All the boys were playing baseball and all the girls and little kids were out jumping rope or what ever. A neighbor went to investigate and let out a screem not to be believed - every kid stopped and stood silent and so still, we all knew - till finally Ralph slowly walked off 2nd base toward his house.

We kids and most of the neighbors stood silently outside the front of that house. Most of the Women in their black dresses with hair and aprons blowing in the wind as the police had come and taken Ralph away. His head was down as he walked up the path with police behind him. We never got to say goodby. He sort of glanced at me with no expression as he went in the back seat of the car. The police quickly got him in the car and he didn&apos;t turn to look out the back window. Never knew what happened to him but I guess he went to an orphanage. Always wished we could have at least said goodby. And the adults never talked to us kids nor did we share with them what we did so there was no way to learn where he went. 
 Ginny February 14, 2003 - 06:01 pm {{{{{Barbara,}}}}}} what a horrifying, heart wrenching story, and I bet you remember Ralph&apos;s last name, have you tried putting it in google? Wouldn&apos;t it be some kind of valentine if you could find him again? (He&apos;s probably ruling the world and we don&apos;t know it) I would like to know where Ralph is, and what happened to him; it might be some kind of reunion! Stranger things have happened, is everybody who was related to him gone from your own neighborhood?

ginny 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 14, 2003 - 06:09 pm No I don&apos;t remember his last name I remember in second grade he was left back and where he was a grade older when I was in first grade we were in the same class second and third grade - I need to look among my old things and see - I think I may have a class photo or something - I was just always a mixture of tearfilled sadness and anger that the police led him away and didn&apos;t make sure he got to say goodby to us - we were really close friends, even if he could have only said goodby to all of us. 
 GingerWright February 14, 2003 - 06:20 pm Oh Barbara What a sad story. I hope you find out what happen to him and let us know. 
 Faithr February 14, 2003 - 09:25 pm Children can have some terrifying secrets, and adults can be pretty detatched from what children are doing thinking and hiding. Barbara that is the basis for a really good story and maybe you should write it.

Well this is my last chance this year so here goes
 Roses are Red
Violets are Blue
I love Senior Net
And Valentines Too
 
 howzat February 15, 2003 - 12:12 am I&apos;m sure there would have been something about this in the newspaper. You can&apos;t have a woman dead for a week, sitting in a kitchen chair, her child going to school each day as if nothing is wrong without something about it appearing in the paper. There&apos;s where you will find the last name.

Howzat 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 15, 2003 - 02:02 am Dearest I am now 70 - this happened over 60 years ago during the spring when I was in the third grade - like the story in the heading - some things happen that are not resolved - at this stage in my life it would be more valuable for me to learn what Civil War Cemetery my great grandfather is buried since he was paid to fight for someone else we do not even know what name to look for or whatever happened to the parents of my grandfather - my mother&apos;s father - who because they had no more money or food asked for help and before the turn of the century if you asked for help, your children were automatically taken away. He and his brother grew up in an orphanage and hopped the wall one night when he was 14. Met my grandmother&apos;s brothers who took him home - his older brother hopped the rails and they lost each other as well.

Yes, it was an unusual childhood happening when I look at it in light of my own children&apos;s and grandchildren&apos;s childhood. The experience has many sides to it. We kids felt in power - we were taking care of our own for as long as it lasted - yes, we were kids therefore, we had not realized it was all going to come to the end he wanted to put off - but think of it - we pulled off what other kids today can only pull off by hiding the fact that they are drinking or drugging or some other mischief.

Much of what we wanted could not be and the fact he did not get to say goodby was all part of none of us getting what we dreamed should have been &apos;right.&apos; To all of us &apos;right&apos; was getting what our emotions wanted - Ralph wanted to stay there - always, we wanted to help Ralph achieve that and tried to take care of all the contingencies we could think of to allow that to happen, I wanted to say goodby and let him know how much I wish I could have made what he wanted happen.

When the time came, Ralph was probably scared and just wanted to get on with it without feeling and to say goodby meant he may have broken down and cried showing he was scared and feeling his fear and acknowledging the loneliness that a goodby would bring.

Looking at this through an adult eye, I am sure the police did not want some mass prolonged teary goodby - after all mothers, especially Italian mothers, would, given the chance, easily wail calling on the Saints and the ancient gods with hysterical weeping. Also, all the adults were probably in shock themselves - very often when you are faced with something so beyond your imagination you become angry - so the police could have been angry with Ralph for hiding this and yet he was just a little kid (he was small for his age).

The women probably did not want to even ponder what our role in it was - their feelings were probably confused and they were probably feeling quilt since they were not that friendly with his mother.

When you are afraid you could be in someones shoes you put distance between what you are afraid of and so the two of them were a source of fear and tension for the women in the area where we were still remembering first hand the depression. Remember families didn&apos;t have backups then if something happened to the bread winner. Their backup was the same &apos;we will take care of this and each other&apos; that we kids called upon when we were helping Ralph.

We can&apos;t fix what happened so long ago and even if I ever found Ralph - it wouldn&apos;t change anything - he had his trials to deal with in his life as we all have our trials that affect our lives. 
 YiLi Lin February 15, 2003 - 05:21 pm almost want to type &apos;harumpf&apos; barbara- in response to your lead questions, but then again i applaud the discussion leaders who take the time to pose questions to keep us focused... 

so to reveal valentine secrets- my &apos;best&apos; valentine was killed in viet nam- though his runner up gave me nice chocolates that same year- and recently clearing out in my cellar- nope not a basement- a cellar- i found a valentine card from my &apos;grandma katie&apos; addressed to me at age one- i guess now an antique.

but the wonderful news is that my younger son and his wife certainly keep the energy of this day alive and each year they seem to plan some wonderful special valentine for each other- sounds silly, but since i am the mother of &apos;the son&apos; makes me sorta proud.... 
 patwest February 15, 2003 - 07:54 pm 

 
 Curious Minds 

 A forum for conversation on ideas and criticism found in magazines, journals and reviews 

 Every other week we&apos;ll link to a new and noteworthy article of interest for discussion.
The Curious Mind topic for the next two weeks will be about fictional detectives of long ago. 
 Topic Source: Previous Fictional Detectives as Masters 

 Click on the link and let&apos;s talk it over. 



 
 Lord Peter Wimsey 

 
 Nick&amp;Nora Charles 

 
 Sherlock Holmes 

 
 Miss Marple 
 
 

 Your suggestions are welcome Discussion Leader: Bill H 

 
 



 Click here and Help SeniorNet....Buy a book at SN&apos;s B&amp;N Bookstore 
 

 
 Books main page 
 GingerWright February 15, 2003 - 07:55 pm I enjoyed all the posts for Valentines and I thank you for them. 
 Barbara St. Aubrey February 15, 2003 - 08:04 pm Wow slueths it is - - -

Valentine&apos;s was interesting and Lorrie your story was so poigent and Yili Lin we forget - you brought our memory around to how war has permently left holes in our hearts -

Sherlock Holmes considered my many to be a classic - my favorite is the cozy crime stories of Britian and Margerat Rutherford was in my estimation the best actress depicting the Agatha Christie Miss Marple. 
 Bill H February 15, 2003 - 08:19 pm Hello, welcome to the discussion. I&apos;m back on board the trolley for the next two weeks. Barbara, you had a great Valentine discussion. I&apos;m sure everyone who joined in enjoyed all the good posts. It was so seasonal appropriate.
I happened upon the page the link in the heading takes us to while surfing the web. Reading the page gave me idea for this Curious Minds topic. I thought how nice it would be to discuss the old time detectives such as the ones you see in the heading and, of course, others as well. Who of us can forget these super sleuths of yesterday? As Jacky Gleason would say, &quot;they were the greatest.&quot;
As a teen, I would visit the local bookstore a couple of times a week to see if new stories of these sleuths appeared on the shelf of the small bookstore not far from my home. There weren&apos;t any super bookshops then, no comfortable chairs to sink into while you skimmed through the books. Paper backs sold for twenty-five cents. Just think a quarter of a dollar would whisk us away into there fantasy world where we could join the sleuths in solving the case with the clues the author put forth!
As you can see, the Curious Minds trolley in the heading is warming up and is just about ready to take us on our journey to old time detective lore times. So climb aboard, chose your seat, get to know the person sitting in the seat beside you and lets exchange stories about these old time super sleuths, Maybe you will tell us about your favorite old time dectective. I hope so.
I thank the lady techs for assisting me with the heading, if you find anything wrong with it don&apos;t blame the techs I had a hand in making it also. Ladies I hope I didn&apos;t make too much of a pest of myself with the heading.
Pat W built the trolley we are going to ride in so let&apos;s give her a round of applause. Oh, by the way, the trolley ride is free. 
Bill H 
 Harold Arnold February 16, 2003 - 10:12 am Ok Bill I&apos;ll be around for this one though it has been at least 40 years since I went through my &quot;Detective Story&quot; phase. What I&apos;m trying to say is that my posts are from memory not from recent reading and mistakes might be made.

I suppose Sir Arthur Conan Doyle began it all with his creation of Sherlock Holmes. This was certainly true for me as I began reading these stories after I picked up a copy of an anthology of his stories off a &quot;bargain&quot; table in a local bookstore. This was about 1960. When I finished all the stories, including the four long novelettes (like &quot;The Hounds of Baskerville&quot;), I went on to other authors such G.K. Chesterton&apos;s, &quot;Father Brown series and Dorothy L. Sayers, &quot;Lord Peter Whimsey.&quot; Also there was Agatha Christi and Ellery Queen, and a curious series that would not be politically acceptable today about a caricatured black detective named Florian Slappy by Roy Octavius Cohen. ( Click Here or do your own Google search on the string, &quot;Roy Octavius Cohen&quot;).

There were other authors who probably will be remembered for future posts but for now I will conclude with some comments on &quot;Sherlock Holmes, the series that really started it all. I suppose that Sir Arthur as a the creator of the Detective Story had it easy in as much as most of his plots are rather weak and his logic leading to the conclusion is often far from perfect. As an example one of the stories involved a murder in a Turkish bath where the solution of the case involved the finding of the knife that was the weapon used in the killing. All the suspects were those in the bath at the time. None had left the scene and no murder weapon was to be had to the frustration of Inspector Lestrade (pronounce by me less trade, not lastraud as in the movies). But to Holmes it was obvious that since the victim was stabbed to death the murder weapon must have been an icicle that immediately melted after the event occurred. Apparently the physical unsuitability of ice as a substitute for a steel blade did not occur to 19th century readers.

On the other hand I have found at least one of Sherlock&apos;s basic rules of deduction useful in explanation of one of the perplexities of modern life. It is the often-relied upon Holmes axiom that when looking for a lost object, after looking everywhere and there remains only one last place where it might be, It will be found at that place. Finally I will conclude with an all time favorite 1960&apos;s &quot;Playboy&quot; cartoon that showed Holmes and Watson waiting at the ruined gate of the English Country House crime scene. The wrought Iron Gate and its stone pillars were a mass of twisted iron and stone rubble. Standing before the pile Holmes is heard to say, &quot;Perhaps, Watson, this time, we had best wait for Inspector Lestrade.&quot; 
 Faithr February 16, 2003 - 10:34 am These detectives are unforgettable. I adored Nick and Nora Charles in the Thin Man movies. There have been other couples detectives but none so intriquing as these. I even loved their little dog but cant remember his name for the life of me. I some time ago I watched little tv and when I did I was watching pbs Mystery hour . They had a lot of British mystery series. There were a young couple that would get invited to the country, solve a muder and come home. They were in the &quot;Thirties&quot; so I thought they were a mimic of the Charles&apos; and now I cant remember the name of that series or the couple. They were good.

My very favorite detective however is still Nero Wolfe working in his orchids and bossing Charlie around. Many years spent reading at least one detective novel a week. Usually the last thing I did before bed was read my current novel for awhile. Faith 
 Bill H February 16, 2003 - 11:34 am Hi, Harold, I&apos;m happy you are going to join in. Thank you for that great post and thanks for jogging miy mind about about Ellery Queen and Father Brown. There were just so many of them. How lucky we were to have them and their authors.When I was in service I remember carrying an Ellery Queen mystery in my fatigue uniform pocket and whenever I got a chance out it would come for a little bit of reading. Most of my recollection about the old timers are from memory also so maybe I&apos;ll make mistakes too
. I agree Sir Arthur began it all with Sherlock Holmes.(wonder how Doyle come by the name of Sherlock). My interest in this detective began with the Sunday evening radio program with Basil Rathbone and Nigel Bruce. I have two complete works by Doyle but the one I like best is The Illustrated Sherlock Holmes Treasury. The illustrations alone are worth the purchase price of the book This is one book I don&apos;t believe I&apos;ll part with.
Faith, William Powell and Myrna Loye... I believe they were the most debonaire couple of Silver Screen lore. Myrna Loye was so sophisticated and beautiful. I just sat in the theater and watched her and forgot all about Bill Powell
I saw that mystery series you are referring to and I can&apos;t remember the name either. Now I&apos;m going to have to do a google search because I won&apos;t rest till I remember the title. Didn&apos;t you just love the make up the women wore in that series ) 
Bill H 
 Bill H February 16, 2003 - 11:57 am When I think of Dorthy L Sayers, I remember most The Lord Peter Wimsey series especially the &quot;Nine Taylors.&quot; Sayers held my interest in this novel from the beginning. She painted a picture of the wild north England country side in such a fashion it set the tone through out the story. Those of you who read this book know that the &apos;Nine Taylor&quot; were huge church bells named, I think, after the apostles. Anybody caught in the bell tower while these bells were peeling would suffer a horrible death. Isn&apos;t it odd how a book can stay with one for so many years. Have any of you experienced this.
I watched the Lord Peter Wimsey series on PBS some time ago and enjoyed the stories although I feel the role of Wimsey was miscast by the actor who played the role.
Bill H 
 jeanlock February 16, 2003 - 01:26 pm Old tyme detectives--

Most are timeless. Roderick Allyn and all of the British guys by Sayers, Marsh, Christie, Tey, et al. Then there are Gideon Fell and the other one by John Dickson Carr who was actually from Harrisburg PA, the son of a senator or congressman but could create an atmosphere you could cut with a knife. Wrote locked-room stories, as well as some supernatural things (try The Burning Court). 
 TigerTom February 16, 2003 - 01:48 pm Bill H,

I have read that Poe started the Detective Novel 
with his &quot;Murder in the Rue Morgue&quot;

Asta was the name of the Dog in the Thin Man series.

Nero Wolfe bossed around Archie, not Charlie.

Sorry to be so Pickey.

Tiger Tom 
 Harold Arnold February 16, 2003 - 02:02 pm I think the Thin Man began as a radio show. I also remember it as a later TV series. Was it in this one where Nick and Nora sat around in their Manhattan apartment planning their case strategies while Nick chugalugged water glass size shots of presumably 100 proof scotch whiskey? He was not exactly the role model type by present day standards.

There was another very popular private eye type; who was it whose paperback novels were at every checkout counter? Was it Mickey Spillain and his mike Hammer Novels ( Click Here )? I dont ever remember reading one although the novels had a reputation as examples of skillful but really quite innocent risqu prose writing. I see from the Link included above that Mike Hammer character did show up in a long running TV series and also in movies. I must have had better things to do as I have no recollection of ever haveing seen these TV shows or movies. 
 Lorrie February 16, 2003 - 02:21 pm FaithR:

Could the couple you were thinking about on Mystery Theatre be Tommy and Tuppence Beresford? They were a detective couple originated by Agatha Christe and appeared in several of her mysteries.

Lorrie 
 Faithr February 16, 2003 - 02:39 pm Lorrie I belive that is it Tommy and Tupence and I did not know it was Clark who wrote them. I love Mary Higgans Clark novels and have read many. It is peculiar but I cant remember even on or the title and that is not unusual for me regarding mystery or detective novels. I seem to to have a special way of going into the zone while reading them and when I come out I have amnesia...hahahah I can remember the characters though. In these Tommy and Tuppence episodes I loved the open car they drove, the twenties or thirties clothes they wore and of course the makeup was great though somewhat to much white powder!!! They had the same smart repartee as Nick and NOra . Yes the dog was Asta and he was a Terrier with culry hair and he was smart. I think he was the first dog that got a character role.

The books by Arthur C Doyle were family favorites and I think my sybs and I were always reading them and when one would finish anohter would read the book. Now my little sister has some matching volumns containing the complete works of Doyle. I reread The Scarlet Letters just a couple of years ago and had forfotten it was placed in London and USA Utah to be exact. fr 
 Stephanie Hochuli February 16, 2003 - 03:37 pm Mickey Spillane&apos;s novels really were just brag.. Very little plot or anything. The covers were the most risque part of them. 
I used to love Judge Dee.. Philip Marlowe...Ellery Queen (of course)..remember Isaac Asimov&apos;s robot detective. What fun he was. I think the first mechanical private eye.. 
 Bill H February 16, 2003 - 03:39 pm Tom, thank you for the name of the dog
Lorrie, thank you for Tommy and Tuppence. You both saved me from a lot of thought. I enjoyed that series and seeing the styles of that era again. Was it the twenties or thirties.
Stephanie, let&apos;s add Boston Blacky to that list. &apos;member him.
Bill H 
 TigerTom February 16, 2003 - 04:25 pm Bill,

What about Sam Spade? Hercole Proirot (sp),

I can remember a series about an Aborigine Detective 
whose names escapes me right now. Also, I believe, 
one who lived in South Africa and who are a half 
Caste I believe. Both were somewhat in the mold of 
Holmes.

Nick Carter, Master Detective was on the Radio and 
I believe in Books too.

There were a number of Radio Detectives: Mr. Keene 
tracer of lost persons; The Fat Man.

How about Charlie Chan? I believe that character was 
in books and in the Movies.

Tiger Tom 
 losalbern February 16, 2003 - 05:50 pm But I love all those Hercule Poirot plays and the producers could bring all of the old ones back for a second go round and I would watch them all again! David Suchet has a lock on that character part and no one else can come up with a better Hercule. I have seen David in two different American made movies where I didn&apos;t recognise him until half way through the play. A very versatile actor. And Tiger, you hit it on the head with Sam Spade! Can&apos;t quite come up with the name of the author there.. And, Nick and Nora were always favorites. Just saw one last week on TCM. I like Nero Wolf and Archie but some times the clues are overstretched. Nothing like a good mystery story to relax the brain. Losalbern 
 Lorrie February 16, 2003 - 07:00 pm Yes, it was in the 20&apos;s, I believe, that Tommy and Tuppence were written, by Agatha Christie, by the way, FaithR.

I always loved Charlie Chan because of the sassy son he had, (Son #2?)but i changed my mind in later years when I read how the Chinese people in this country were appalled at the ludicrous figure &quot;Charlie Chan&quot; portrayed.

Lorrie 
 TigerTom February 16, 2003 - 07:52 pm Lorrie,

There were two Oriental (I can&apos;t say for sure if they 
were Chinese or not) who played NO 1 Son and No 2 Son. 
There was occasionaly a No 2 Daughter.

The two males appeared in a number of films, One was 
Key Luke and the name of the other escapes me. He, I believe, 
appeared in the David Carradine series &quot;Kung Fu&quot; when 
the main character was a boy called &quot;Grasshopper&quot; and 
the Chinese Actor was his teacher.

I remember Key Luke was in a seriel with Russel Hayden, 
who played in some Hopalong Cassidey Films.

I believe the Chinese Community was irritated because 
Charlie Chan was played by a Swede one time and another 
White. Also the lousy English the character spoke although 
he was a Lt. in the Honolulu Police and was supposedly 
well educated.

Anyone remember Philo Vance?

Tiger Tom 
 isak2002 February 16, 2003 - 10:48 pm Tiger Tom; 
The Aboriginie was Napoleon Bonaparte wasn&apos;t it? I read all of those back in the 70s and then found them again- 
and the author just came floating back into my brain - Arthur Upfield, wasn&apos;t it? A colleague I worked with had just 
begun to read them too, so it was fun to talk about them. 
Now, tho, I am not sure that Upfield did the Boanparte series - will have to check that out. 
I have been re-reading Dorothy L Sayers&apos;s books - the Lord Peter Whimsey books and then found all of the literary criticism books I could about Sayers in the UT Library - what a feast. 
isak 
 Lou2 February 17, 2003 - 06:08 am Only the SHADOW Knows!!!

Remember that one?? On the radio during the 40&apos;s... Oh, the magic of hearing and each one forming their our mental pictures. I think our children and their children lost something in having all their images produced for them on tv.

Lou 
 Ginny February 17, 2003 - 06:28 am How about Johnny Dollar? He was one of the last radio detectives still broadcasting, I remember standing at the sink listening to him in the late 50&apos;s, still going strong.

 I am a huge fan of the Basil Rathbone Nigel Bruce Sherlock Holmes series, on radio and film, have all the movies and they are increasingly rare, and there are many many more radio programs available than you think, most people think you have to get those audio tape sets, and they are nice, with interviews, I&apos;ve got them, but there are tons more of them and now Wal Mart is selling a set of audio tapes with the two actors who took up the series after Nigel Bruce quit. (Basil Rathbone quit the series because he found Holmes taking over his life just like Doyle did and it caused a rift in his long friendship with Nigel Bruce who continued on with Tom Conway).

 If you&apos;re a fan of old time radio you want to know about these people: Crabapple Sound . This is a retirement project of a very nice man and his wife and they have them all, they&apos;re on audio and CD and the CD&apos;s are like $2.95 each and there are two episodes per CD.

 One very nice touch is that if the announcer says next week we&apos;ll hear the story of....then that story is the next CD, they are marvelous!!

 How about Sergeant Preston of the Yukon? &quot;On, KING!!&quot; Was he a detective or just a hero, not sure?

 I&apos;m also fascinated with the old time commercials you can still hear on the programs, Kreml Hair Products, Clipper Craft Suits and of course the famous Petri Wine, (&quot;from father to son, from father to son,&quot;) and that in 1940. If you&apos;ve been idly wondering what happened to that small dynasty you will be glad to learn they flourished, turned into Italian Swiss Colony Wine and Louis Petri became head of the nations largest grape co op in CA. His story, the only interview with him extant, is part of the Berkeley Oral History series and can be ordered, fascinating reading, man is very honest. One of the stipulations OF that interview is that no person can quote from it without written permission of Louis Petri himself first.

 A fascinating time in our history, the development of the wine industry in America in California, and some of the best radio there ever was. I truly think somebody should bring it back, maybe we should make a radio show!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!

 Wouldn&apos;t it be FUN? Hahahahaha

 We could write the script and record it at our Bookfests, what a hoot~ I know how they made lightning, ahhaahahaha how did they do the steps on the floor?

 ginny 
 TigerTom February 17, 2003 - 07:18 am Ginny,

Thanks loads for the Link. I have received an 
advert from a company selling tapes and CD&apos;s 
of old programs but they were expensive, too 
expensive for my taste.

I have the &quot;Encyclopedia of Old Time Radio&quot; 
by John Dunning 745 pages of text and about 
70 pages of index so one can find things in 
a hurry. Brings back a lot of memeories. Will 
have to go through it to dig out the old Detective 
Radio Programs.

Tiger Tom 
 TigerTom February 17, 2003 - 07:26 am Isak2002,

The Detective&apos;s name was Napoleon Bonapart but I 
thought he had a last name and N.P. was his first 
and middle name. What do I know? You are right 
about the name. I only read a few books in the 
series so I am not sure how many books were written 
about the Character.

Tiger Tom 
 Harold Arnold February 17, 2003 - 09:40 am Here are some additional comments concerning the Sherlock Holmes character:

In the 1950s there were several additional Holmes stories sanctioned be the Arthur Conan Doyle Estate. Sir Arthurs son, Adrian Doyle, wrote the first ones. I remember some of them (I think four) were published in a magazine; almost certainly it was Life Magazine. I think there were other Estate sanctioned releases later including one entitled The Seven Percent Solution that I think was made into a movie, perhaps as late as the 1970s. The plot had Holmes traveling to Vienna to consult with Dr Freud about a treatment for his cocaine addiction. I was surprised there was only a bare mention of The Seven Percent Solution from an Internet search and nothing on the plot or a movie. Does anyone remember this? Can anyone provide more Details on the Seven Percent plot?

I agree with Ginnys comment. For me to Basil Rathbone and Nigel Bruce will always be Sherlock Holmes and Dr Watson! I have noted elsewhere on other boards that in 1826 when John James Audubon traveled to England to publish his Birds Paintings, a most interesting Liverpool family named Rathbone assisted him. One of the very young children at that time was named Basil Rathbone. I wondered it this was the actors roots, but if so it was several generations later as I understand the actors origin was South Africa. 
 TigerTom February 17, 2003 - 11:03 am Harold,

Interesting that Holmes Drug addiction has never 
been a concern with most people about the 
Character. Of course, when the stories were 
first written Drug addiction wasn&apos;t a big deal 
as it is today.

Also, with the exception of one female (whose 
name I cannot remember) Holmes seemed to be 
oblivious to women. There is no hint in the 
stories of him being &quot;Unatural&quot; just that women 
were not a part of his life. I believe he considered 
them not up to par in the brain department or at 
least not on a level with males. In the Victorian 
era when this was not considered unusual. Holmes 
was just not subject to males &quot;Beastly Nature&quot;

Holmes and Watson never came across as anything 
but two men living in the same &quot;Rooms.&quot; Interesting, 
because in this day and age there would be commentary 
on it. I always liked that lack of any moralizing 
in the stories other than against crime and criminals.

I wonder how Holmes fares with today&apos;s P.C. world.

Tiger Tom 
 TigerTom February 17, 2003 - 11:07 am Harold,

Do you remember &quot;Michael Shane&quot; Private Eye?

On radio, in movies and books.

A few days ago I saw a movie with Lloyd Nolan 
playing Shane. Not bad. Although Nolan just didn&apos;t 
come across as well as some of the other leading 
men of the day might have.

Tiger Tom 
 Ginny February 17, 2003 - 11:10 am Harold, what a fascinating post, I have Rathbone&apos;s own autobiogaphy, and the only other biography of him, I&apos;ll look that up and report back, how interesting!!!

ginny 
 losalbern February 17, 2003 - 11:13 am To remember names of people and places and things of long ago and far away. There were two or three mystery writers of the &apos;30s who came up with some great stories that became movie classics. Like the Maltese ( sp?) Falcon. Wasn&apos;t that a Sam Spade character? Who wrote that? Daschell Hammett (double sp&apos;s, here) comes to mind but thats just a wild guess. Can anyone come up with other writers of that ilk? Does anybody remember the nickle lending libraries that you could find in drug stores during the Depression? That is where I first became acquainted with some of the books of Agatha Christie. For five cents a day you could rent a best seller. Shucks, where is Katie? She knows all this stuff? Losalbern 
 Lou2 February 17, 2003 - 12:04 pm I recently read Wilkie Collins&apos; a Woman in White and Moonstone. A little wordy but great mysteries. Both of them are told by narrative from the point of view of the different characters. If I remember correctly A Woman in White is credited with being the first mystery novel.

Iosalbern, you are right. The Maltese Falcon is by Dashiell Hammett with Sam Spade. Were Hammett&apos;s the first noir mysteries?

Lou 
 Bill H February 17, 2003 - 01:43 pm These are all great posts and my long term memory bank is going through the shake, rattle and roll process. I must admit I forgot about a lot of the detectives you folks are mentioning. Thank you for all the names.
I loved all those b&amp;w movies of Holmes and Charlie Chan. Nothing like black and white to create the atmosphere needed for these dramas.
The Shadow, one of my all time favorites. I can still here the lead in commentator&apos;s voice as he said: &quot;...the Shadow is in reality Lamont Cranston wealthy young man about town and his fiancee the lovely Margo Lane...&quot; Yes, nothing like radio to stir the imagination.
Losalbern, Any time I hear the name Sam Spade, Humphrey Bogart springs to mind
Tom, the lady Sherlock Holmes admired is Irene Adler. The following quote is from the very first paragraph of Doyle&apos;s &quot;A Scandal in Bohemia&quot;
 &quot;To Sherlock Holmes she is always the woman. I have seldom heard him mention her under any other name. In his eyes she eclipses and predominates the whole of her sex...&quot; 
Ginny, thank you for the link. I intend to get those discs and what a bargain. They&apos;ll make for great listening on a cold winter night.
Losalbern, I do remember those lending libraries. Our corner drug store (and it was on a corner) charged ten cents for three days for paper backs
Bill H 
 Faithr February 17, 2003 - 02:18 pm These memories are great. I saw the Sherlock Homes movie where he goes to Vienna to meet Mr. Freud. It was ok but lacked the 
&quot;real&quot; sherlock ambiance. I have also seen spoofs of Sherlock Homes done by several different actors meant to be funny and I didnt think so. I guess I liked the real stories and characters too much. To this day The HOund of the Baskervilles remains the ultimate terror movie of my childhood. I saw the picture when I was maybe 10 or 11 and was really frightened. I am pretty sure it had Basil Rathbone in it.

I also saw one movie with a different english actor playing the part of Holmes where he was on ship board and had a romance..was this part of where he finds his ultimate woman? or is it one written for his estate after he is deceased. Maybe it was in the Cocain one when he went to Vienna. I am mixed up on it. Lorrie I bet you know. Or Ginny. She has a way of finding out if she doesnt know. Faith 
 TigerTom February 17, 2003 - 03:46 pm Bill H,

Strange, when I hear &quot;Sam Spade&quot; I think of 
Howard Duff who played him on the Radio.

Irene Adler, she bested Holmes at least once 
maybe more times. He admired her mind very 
much. I doubt if he was even aware of her 
as a physical woman.

Tiger Tom 
 pedln February 17, 2003 - 04:45 pm Tiger Tom, interesting that you should mention John Dunning&apos;s &quot;Encyclopedia of Old Time Radio.&quot; I&apos;m reading a recent (2001) mystery by Dunning right now -- &quot;Two O&apos;Clock Eastern Wartime&quot; -- set on the New Jersey coast during World War II and full of radio lore and techniques.
How times change -- as a kid, I wanted to be a secretary to a detective when I grew up. Now I want to be the detective, but can&apos;t remember which one.
I remember Sunday nights, sitting by the radio listening to &quot;The Shadow,&quot; which didn&apos;t scare me to pieces, and then crying because my brother wanted to hear &quot;Inner Sanctum&quot;, which did.
I loved Nick and Nora Charles, and Mr. and Mrs. North. I can still hear Nora Charles at the end of each show, &quot;Goodnight, Nicky darling.&quot; Good grief, what will 10-year-olds remember from today&apos;s shows. 
 Ann Alden February 17, 2003 - 05:35 pm Nothing that nice, Babi!
I loved Jeremy Brett as Holmes. Thought he made the part so interesting. Buuuuut, who could not love Basil Rathbone? They were both good in their time and Brett made the second telling of these timeless tales very enjoyable. I,too, loved Inner Sanctum and Mr&amp;Mrs North. Pam and Jerry? Is that right? And, of course, Nick and Nora Charles! Does anyone remember Jack, Doc and Reggie from &quot;I Love a Mystery&quot;? My husband&apos;s favorite. I would just listen to any mysteries on the radio.
Another good book about radio is Garrison Keilor&apos;s &quot;WLT-A Radio Romance&quot; which is about a new station in the 20&apos;s in a small town. Since my FIL started one of the first radio stations in Ohio, the stories that Keilor&apos;s tales were so familiar to me. Those things actually happened! I will be looking for Dunning&apos;s book, Babi. Thanks for mentioning it. 
 Harold Arnold February 17, 2003 - 05:46 pm To day was a workday at my home office that is in an apartment attached to the garage behind my house. About a quarter to four this afternoon I took a break returning to the house where the TV was still running from this morning. I decided to change the channel to CNBC Business, and while navigating the menu I noticed The hounds of the Baskerville was then in progress on the Turner Classic Movie channel. So I watched the concluding hour and fifteen minutes. I thought it was well done; in particular I thought it told its story well as most old movies, even English ones do.

A Peter Cushing played Sherlock Holmes. My first thought was that he would have been better cast in the Doctor Watson role. By the end however I had to conclude that he did a pretty respectable job. One thing I though was a bit unholmsian, In the climax scene Holmes actually had a pistol in his hand. At this point after a long absence from the literature, I do not recall Holmes himself so armed. It was always Watson who was asked to bring his Pistol. The host at the end of the show mentioned that Peter Cushings is still active today and has had roles in a Star Wars title and other more recent movies. .

To day was a workday at my home office that is in an apartment attached to the garage behind my house. About a quarter to four this afternoon I took a break returning to the house where the TV was still running from this morning. I decided to change the channel to CNBC Business, and while navigating the menu I noticed The hounds of the Baskerville was then in progress on the Turner Classic Movie channel. So I watched the concluding hour and fifteen minutes. I thought it was well done; in particular I thought it told its story well as most old movies, even English ones do.

A Peter Cushing played Sherlock Holmes. My first thought was that he would have been better cast in the Doctor Watson role. By the end however I had to conclude that he did a pretty respectable job. One thin I though was a bit unholmsian, In the climax scene Holmes actually had a pistol in his hand. At this point after a long absence from the literature, I do not recall Holmes himself so armed. It was always Watson who was asked to bring his Pistol. The host at the end of the show mentioned that Peter Cushings is still active today and has had roles in a Star Wars title and other more recent movies. .

 Click Here for The Hounds of the Baskerville 
 Harold Arnold February 17, 2003 - 05:57 pm Tiger Tom The woman was the actress involved in the Scandal in Bohemia. Remember the King of Bohemia was Holmes Client and Holmes devised a rather elaborate stakeout that enabled him to (lets be blunt) burglarize her home to recover the pictures for the errant monarch. Remember the story concludes with Watson saying something like, to Holmes Irene Adler (that name might not be exactly right) was always the woman. Something like that..

Also I found a link to the movie I mentioned this morning. Click Here for The Seven Percent Solution 

And Ginny did we perhaps discuss the Basil Rathbone roots before on another board? 
 Harold Arnold February 17, 2003 - 08:57 pm I did pretty good in remembering the lady&apos;s name and her story but I was wrong about it being in the ending. Actually it was a skilfully concieved opening that read: To sherlock Holmes she was always the woman. I have seldom heard him mention her under any other name. In his eyes she eclipses and predominates the whole of her sex. It is not that he felt any emotion akin to love for Irene Adler. All emotions, and that one particularly, were abhorent to his cold, precise but admirably balanced mind. He was, I take it, the most perfect reasoning and observing machine that the world has seen, but as a lover he would have placed himself in a false position. He never spoke of the softer passions, save with a gibe and a snere. 

I apologize for repeating my earlier message twice. Once said was certainly enough, but aparently I managed to hit the paste button twice. 
 Ginny February 18, 2003 - 06:39 am I have to thank you all! Thanks to this discussion I spent the most wonderful evening last night, just so enjoyable. I managed to find BOTH of the Basil Rathbone books (which itself is a miracle).

 Faith, thank you for that, we may need Lorrie or others here, the only movie I can find in Basil Rathbone: His Life and Films of Basil Rathbone as Sherlock on a ship is Flight to Algiers and it does not mention a love interest (this book has the plot and the cast of every movie he was ever in, so if you all ever need to know somebody I can look it up, but he made a LOT of movies!!). It&apos;s kind of like Tiger Tom&apos;s book, in this case it shows every performance Rathbone did, and boy did he make them, what a career!!!

 

 Apparently he did play in one of Adrian Doyle&apos;s plays, on Suspense on May 26, 1953, in The Adventure of the Black Baronet by Adrian Doyle, but that&apos;s all I can see but it would be easy to overlook one.

 Harold, yes I think I&apos;ve repeated myself in two different discussions, but here&apos;s something new:

 This book mentions the marvelous senses of humor that Rathbone and Bruce both close friends, shared. During the production of the radio broadcasts, each man would try to trick the other and make him laugh. If you listen to the old broadcasts often they both erupt in laughter, it&apos;s quite fun. Once when Bruce turned away, Rathbone mixed up the pages of his script to hilarious result, and Bruce did some fairly unprintable antics which caused Rathbone to leave the stage blushing.

 Rathbone, against the advice of everybody who knew him, gave up the role of Sherlock Holmes and moved to New York to pursue his first love, the theater. He said that Homes was strangling him, typecasting his career, and that the egotism that Holmes displayed and his put downs of Watson made him an unsympathetic character whom it was hard to make likeable. 

 Rathbone apparently was an anomaly in Hollywood, a literate (always with a book in his hand) , kind man who helped everybody he came in contact with, buying clothes for co actors, etc., a devoted husband and father, a poet himself. His will instructed:

 I wish to be buried beside my wife- so close that, if it were possible, we might hold each other&apos;s hand...I wish to be buried above ground, as I look upon death as a gateway to an ascension and an elevationnot a descent. 

 

 Last night I got so caught up in all this I watched &quot;Dressed to Kill&quot; and &quot;A Woman in Green,&quot; and enjoyed them both tremendously and Holmes did have a gun in the second one.

 

 and FINALLY, Harold, here is what I have found about the Audubon reference. You said Audubon came in 1826, Rathbone was born on June 13, 1892, in Johannesburg, South Africa. In his book In and Out of Character he relates that at the age of 4 the family fled Johannesburg for Durban in a boxcar, his father hiding from the Boers under the box his mother sat on. (His mother had a premonition about the ship they were supposed to sail to England on, even to the name of the song sung, &quot;Flowers of the Forest,&quot; so his father humored her, and by George, it sank while the band played that song!) It&apos;s chilling reading! The Rathbones took a later ship to England and arrived when he was 4 years old.

 Rathbone does mention family in Liverpool, and Christmases at his Grandmothers and Grandfathers at Greenbank Cottage, Wavertree, Liverpool, apparently a very fine place. He goes on for pages about it. However after his Grandmother died when he was 10 they never went back till he was, as he puts it, in his &quot;declining years,&quot; and did a nostalgic trip there, to Wavertree and Greenbank Cottage, and encountered the house for sale and an old man who did not recall the occupants. It&apos;s VERY poignant reading, actually quite poetic.

 So it&apos;s apparent, and from his mention of &quot;Uncle William,&quot; that the Rathbones of Liverpool were related and they may have been the very Rathbones that entertained Audubon, at any rate, enjoyed my Rathbone Evening!

ginny 
 TigerTom February 18, 2003 - 06:59 am Ginny,

What an interesting Man is Rathbone. What are the titles 
and ISBN Numbers of the two books you have on him?

I read in one of David Niven&apos;s books that Rathbone 
was the highest paid independent actor in Hollywood. 
Apparently he was not connected to any studio.

I remember the Radio Broadcasts of Sherlock Holmes.

MY oldest brother keeps surprising me, he has taped 
every Sherlock Holmes movie that has been broadcast 
on T.V. I never knew he even LIKED the character. 
He loaned them to me saying &quot;Guard these with your life&quot; 
I watched them and returned the tapes to him in good shape. 
(BTW he was also a Hopalong Cassidey Fan which I also 
didn&apos;t know.)

Tiger Tom 
 TigerTom February 18, 2003 - 07:01 am Bill H,

Two more &quot;Detectives&quot;

Bulldog Drummond and &quot;The Falcon&quot;

Tiger Tom 
 Ginny February 18, 2003 - 07:14 am Tom, the two books are:


 Basil Rathbone: In and Out of Character by Basil Rathbone (a VERY good read) ISBN: 0-87910-119-9, paperback, I think it&apos;s just been reprinted and

 Basil Rathbone: His Life and His Films by Michael B. Druxman ISBN: 0-498-01471-1 harback and out of print.

 

 I forgot also to ask those of you who recommend Nero Wolfe to recommmend what you think his best one was, or a good one to start with? I also grow orchids, I&apos;d like to have what you think is a memorable one, have never read one.

 

 I did notice one thing in the movies last night, Sherlock can&apos;t really play the violin (this is what you learn when you take cello) and the way he throws it around shows that if you couldn&apos;t notice by the playing tho he&apos;s quite good at imitation.

 

 Is Harold right and the first detective WAS Sherlock? Did Doyle start it all? How interesting!

 

 I know a detective I bet you all don&apos;t recall and I would kill, just KILL for one of the books, anybody but me remember the Bonita Granville series? Apparently Bonita Granville was a movie star and somebody wrote a detective series starring her, I read them along with Nancy Drew and Nurse Cherry or whoever she was as a child, anybody remember her?

 Tom, I also love Hoppy, and watching those old shows is really a revelation. Hoppy comes to a saloon, he enters, bad guys within, but it&apos;s always a moral thing, a moral stance, a moral decision, he doesn&apos;t want to fight, the stories were quite powerful in reruns.

 For some reason I know the names of all the cowboy heroes horses, I guess little girls love horses, anyway, yes Hoppy I think was better than Tom Mix.

 ginny showing her age 
 Bill H February 18, 2003 - 10:37 am Ginny, your reference the Hounds...has made me once again aware of the ending of the recent PBS presentation of that story. In that movie, Mrs (Beryl) Stapleton, who was passed off as Stapleton&apos;s sister, was murdered by her husband . So I&apos;m going to view my Rathbone and Watson video cassette of the Hound of the Baskervilles just to see the main difference in the two endings. I haven&apos;t viewed my copy for quite a while, but I thought this movie showed Beryl Stapleton and Sir Henry were to be married at the end. However, the original story told of no such happening.
The Maltese Falcon is reported to have been Sam Spade&apos;s most treacherous and deadly case. I saw the movie but didn&apos;&apos;t read the book. Going to see if my library has it.
I&apos;m trying to remember the actor&apos;s name who played the part of the villain in the Maltese Falcon. He was a huge fat man and co- starred in that movie with Bogart? I believe he and Humphrey Bogart co-stared in other movies as well.
Back in the fifties or there abouts Perer Lawford played in a TV series of The Thin Man, while entertaing enough, I didn&apos;t think it was as good as the William Powell and Myrna Loy movie. They were such a great screen duo. In those days, it was thought that a cigarette in one hand and a drink in the other made for sophistication. When Bill Powell entered his apartment (no house for these two) he would first pour a drink then light up a cigarette. 
 Lou2 February 18, 2003 - 10:53 am Ginny and all, The article in the heading gives a good review of the history of mysteries... The Collins&apos; books I posted about were earlier than Sherlock... and the Moonstone has an interesting detective, whose name escapes me right now. He was modeled after one of the first detectives hired on the London police force. Collins was a good friend of Dickens and wrote these two books in serial form for publication in Dickens&apos; literary newspaper(??)/magazine?? AH! found the book... the detective is Sergeant Cuff. Written in 1868.

Lou 
 TigerTom February 18, 2003 - 11:27 am Bill H,

Fat man was Sydney Greenstreet. A major Character 
actor of the 30&apos;s and 40&apos;s. He was in a number of 
films with Bogart and Peter Lorre.

Tiger Tom 
 TigerTom February 18, 2003 - 11:40 am Ginny,

Thank you for the titles and Numbers.

I did a Google Search on Rathbone and found a site 
in which the site owners says that he is making 
Xerox or some kind of copies of the book: Basil 
Rathbone his life and films. One can order a copy 
for 35 dollars.

Doesn&apos;t this remind you a bit of the Bounty Discussion 
where you had some many wonderful things about Bligh 
and the Bounty and found more?

Tiger Tom 
 Ginny February 18, 2003 - 12:11 pm LOU!! So glad to see you, I DOOO see that, the first &quot;modern&quot; detective story, that&apos;s a GOOD article, Bill, thank you for calling my attention to it but I want to know what the first mystery written was, not modern?

 How old is that genre? I have printed the article and will now happily go read it.

 Bill, I can&apos;t recall the ending! (Shows you how much good it does me to view, huh? Let us know!) hahahaaha

 Tom, yes this is very like the Bounty research, one door leads to another, I was thinking that I paid a whole lot less for that book on his films, I could be wrong, I&apos;ll look it up again!

ginny 
 TigerTom February 18, 2003 - 12:28 pm All,

For those of you who might be interested, the full title 
and ISBN No of the book I cited is:

&quot;On the Air, The Encyclopedia of Old time Radio&quot; 
by John Dunning, Pub by Oxford Universit Press, 
ISBN No. 0-19-507678-8

I guess one can look up Oxoford Univeristy Press 
by doing a Google Search.

I received a Cataloge from them one day in the 
mail and have ordered a number of books out of 
that Cataloge. I would have ordered mor but 
money and lack of room for more books restrained 
me.

Tiger Tom 
 TigerTom February 18, 2003 - 12:30 pm Ginny,

As I said before, it is my understanding that the 
first Mystery was by Poe, &quot;Murder in the Rue Morgue&quot; 
I may be wrong, that has happened before.

Tiger Tom 
 Lou2 February 18, 2003 - 12:51 pm As I said before, it is my understanding that the first Mystery was by Poe, &quot;Murder in the Rue Morgue&quot; I may be wrong, that has happened before.

Tiger Tom

Published 1841 the first time...

Tiger Tom is right. Lou is wrong. The article said the first English mystery. Not the first mystery, which was American. Good for you Tiger Tom... I stand corrected. well, actually set corrected! LOL

Lou 
 Ann Alden February 18, 2003 - 01:06 pm Having written a paper about Poe, back in the olden days, I believe that I remember him being the father of the first American mystery. His first mystery was, &quot;The Mask of the Red Death&quot; published in 1838. Then, came &quot;The Fall of the House of Usher&quot; in 1839. Now that&apos;s on a page from the Poe Museum in Richmond, VA but when I looked elsewhere, I found that they are separated by Detective stories and Horror stories so here&apos;s that list, from another site. Poe&apos;s Works 
I have read both of Wilkie Collins books, back in the 70&apos;s and liked them. There was movie of &quot;Woman in White&quot;. 
 Lou2 February 18, 2003 - 01:16 pm The librarian in me couldn&apos;t let it rest... sorry! I found a great web site...

www.mysterynet.com/timeline

(Sorry, I don&apos;t know how to make this a link here....)

The following is kinda fun info on the first mystery writing... Lots more info there if you are interested.

The fascination with mystery and crime can be traced back to Ancient Greece, where playwrights like Sophocles and Euripides enthralled the local citizenry with their plays combining mystery and drama. In first-century B.C. Rome, Cicero argued passionately in court in defense of accused criminals, captivating Romans with his speeches. 
 While courtroom dramas still enthrall readers, mysteries have taken many other forms, including cozies, locked-room puzzles, and detective pulp novels. Read our evolution of the mystery in Time Line, and you&apos;ll see that the Ancient Greeks and Romans weren&apos;t so different from modern-day mystery fans.

Lou

Edit: Ann I have looked for the Woman in White movie. Do you have any idea when it was made? 
 Ann Alden February 18, 2003 - 01:20 pm Lou, here&apos;s a link, not yours, as they sent me to this one.
	</body>
</document>
