<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002064" url="https://www.viewlondon.co.uk/restaurants/awana-userreview-8859.html" time="2012-07-12-17:58" support="2" score="0.003530420378513619" bingtitle="Awana London - Restaurant User Reviews , 85 Sloane Avenue, Chelsea" webtitle="Awana London - Restaurant User Reviews , 85 Sloane Avenue, Chelsea">
			<query id="001004" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="001287" bing-rank="172"/>
	<description>... food I can&apos;t make on my own or pick up from a fast-food restaurant. ... I could not enjoy my food as the waiters/waitresses ... I felt that we had the worst table. The service was ...</description>
	<body>
		Now on the iPhone Search for 
 (eg. pizza, pubs, Hawksmoor) Where 
 (eg. address, postcode, area) 
 
 
 Log In Sign Up 

 12 July 2012 
 The Londoner&apos;s Guide to London 
 Home View Card Restaurants Pubs&amp;Bars Clubs Cinema&amp;Film Tickets Whats On London 2012 Hotels Experiences Festivals Prizes Parties&amp;Events Site tools Shopping Restaurants The Best Recommended A-Z By Cuisine By Tube By Area By Group Venue Hire Reviews Restaurant Search Restaurant Blog send page print page 
 Home   &gt;  Restaurants   &gt;  Awana 
 
Awana
 Malaysian Chelsea 85 Sloane Avenue,
Chelsea,
London,
SW3 3DX

0871 971 7512
 Note: Calls cost 10p per min plus network extras. 
 add to my map 
 Tweet 
 
Add a User Review for
 Awana Add your own review of this restaurant 
 venue information venue map write a review image gallery (6) book a table 
 
What&apos;s near Awana ?
 Below are the nearest 5 venues within 500 metres of Awana . Restaurants near Awana  (5) (0m) Sushi des Artistes (6m) Gaucho Sloane (6m) Sloanes (92m) Three5 World Tapas (104m) Bibendum More Restaurants Nearby Pubs&amp;Bars near Awana  (5) (0m) Galante (54m) Barts (92m) Three5 World Tapas (146m) Admiral Codrington (168m) Jak&apos;s Bar More Pubs&amp;Bars Nearby Clubs near Awana  (2) (412m) Kings (441m) Dorsia More Clubs Nearby Cinemas near Awana  (1) (491m) Chelsea Cinema More Cinemas Nearby Hotels near Awana  (3) (109m) Myhotel Chelsea (338m) Sydney House Chelsea (441m) Rembrandt Hotel More Hotels Nearby Shopping near Awana  (5) (63m) Jonathan Adler (92m) Joseph (97m) Sainsburys Supermarkets (101m) La Maree (108m) Bobo Kids More Shopping Nearby 
Most Read Today
 Features Whats On Venues Film Free Summer Festivals in London 
Don&apos;t be put off by little things like money, part...
 Olympic Torch Route London 
Check out the Olympic torch route in London
 Olympic Outdoor Screenings 
Catch all the sporting action at one of these gian...
 Bank Holiday London Events 
Make the most of the long weekend with arts, cultu...
 London Exhibitions 2012 
As London gears up for the sporting event of the c...
 Rolling Stones Exhibition London 
A Rolling Stones exhibition London event takes pla...
 Olympic Festival at Hyde Park 
Head to the Olympic festival at Hyde Park for live...
 Ricard Petanque Garden Party 
Get in the spirit of summer and celebrate Bastille...
 Tapas Fantasticas Wine Festival 
The Tapas Fantasticas wine festival comes to Potte...
 London Naked Bike Ride 
Not many people can say that they have cycled nake...
 The Dollhouse 
7-8 Bishopsgate Churchyard, The City, London, EC2M 3TJ
 Reflex 
17 Watling Street, London, EC4M 9BB
 Vue Cinema Acton 
Royale Leisure Park, Park Royal, Acton, London, W3 0PA
 Dorsia 
3 Cromwell Road, South Kensington, London, SW7 2HR
 LJ Coffee House 
3 Winnett Street, Soho, London, W1D 6JY
 Magic Mike 
Channing Tatum, Alex Pettyfer, Matthew McConaughey...

 
 Ice Age 4: Continental Drift 
Ray Romano, Denis Leary, John Leguizamo, Queen Lat...

 
 Salute 
Christopher Kirby, Peter Norman, Tommie Smith, Joh...

 
 Comes a Bright Day 
Craig Roberts, Imogen Poots, Kevin McKidd, Timothy...

 
 Seeking a Friend for the End of the World 
Steve Carell, Keira Knightley, Adam Brody, Derek L...

 
 Content updated: 12/07/2012 16:58 Theo Randall&apos;s Guide to London Read our Restaurant Blog Follow us on Twitter and Facebook 
Restaurant Hire
 Planning a party? 
Find a special restaurant to make your party special here.
 Click here to search 
This Week Try With A View® Card
 Khanage 
2-4-1 food courses Sunday to Thursday with View® Card.
 
Most Viewed Restaurants 
 
 Joes Cafe Lardo Clifton Kitchen Olympic Park Abracadabra Korma Sutra Brasserie Zedel Prince of Wales Comptoir Libanais Cafe de Paris 
 
Latest Restaurants User Reviews
 
 Koto II Japanese Restaurant 
Do not go here, the food is not fresh and their service is appall...
 
 Amandeep1 on 12/07/2012 @ 09:46 Erebuni Restaurant 
I really don’t get the last review. We always order take away fro...
 
 alexb12 on 11/07/2012 @ 18:34 Goode and Wright 
Goode&amp;Wright /definitely got it/ Good&amp;Right!

I&apos;ve been ple...
 
 Jules75020 on 11/07/2012 @ 15:25 Koto II Japanese Restaurant 
I went to Koto yesterday, where I ended up being ill as the food ...
 
 Kha on 11/07/2012 @ 14:52 Everbean 
Amazing salads, tasty cakes, delicious coffee, friendly staff and...
 
 udhr60 on 11/07/2012 @ 14:00 
 
Most Booked Restaurants
 
 Oxo Tower Restaurant, Bar and Brasserie Rainforest Cafe aqua kyoto Proud Cabaret City The Alchemist Big Easy Guanabara Skylon Restaurant Soho&apos;s Secret Tea Room Le Pont de la Tour 
 
 
View London Site Map
 View Card 
 Half price dining at London restaurants London Restaurants 
 Reviews, Venue Hire at London Restaurants London Pubs&amp;Bars 
 Reviews, Venue Hire at London Bars&amp;Pubs London Clubs 
 Club Tickets, Guest Lists&amp;London Club Listings Cinema&amp;Film 
 London Cinema Listings&amp;Film Reviews London Tickets 
 Theatre, Sports, Music, The Arts&amp;Clubs London Whats On 
 Whats On in London, London Events London 2012 
 London 2012 Olympic guide London Hotels 
 Online Booking, Top London Hotels Experiences 
 Gifts, Hen&amp;Stag, Adventures Festivals 
 Summer Festivals, Tickets, Information Prizes 
 London Competitions&amp;Giveaways Parties&amp;Events 
 Venue hire, Christmas parties, Guest Lists Site tools 
 Register, Newsletters, Jobs, List Your Venue Shopping 
 London Shopping 
 
 
Other Cities
 Bath Belfast Birmingham Bournemouth Bradford Brighton Bristol Cambridge Cardiff Edinburgh Glasgow Hull Leeds Leicester Liverpool Manchester Newcastle Nottingham Oxford Sheffield 

 
 
 Auckland Christchurch Dunedin Hamilton Queenstown Wellington 
 
 
Site Links
 Privacy Policy Legal Notices   About View London Corporate Site Contact View London Jobs at View London Our Blog   Get Listed Advertising   Links 
 Hitwise No.1 Award Winner www.viewlondon.co.uk©2012 View London Ltd. All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
