<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002986" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/article/5759528/natural_meats_what_a_difference_at.html" time="2012-07-12-19:04" support="1" score="0.001418131190701752" bingtitle="Natural Meats: What a Difference at Chipotle Restaurants - Yahoo ..." webtitle="Natural Meats:  What a Difference at Chipotle Restaurants - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="000312" bing-rank="249"/>
	<description>... have more animals live to be slaughtered and enter ... right in front of the customer at the counter behind ... wonderful natural meats when eating out at a fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 1 2 3 
 
Natural Meats: What a Difference at Chipotle Restaurants
 Mary Oberg , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
Sep 3, 2010 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: Chipotle Carnitas Au Bon Pain 
 Flag Close Post a comment History 
The first Chipotle restaurant opened in 1993 in Denver, Colorado. Now there are over 1,000 restaurants in this chain and it is was owned by McDonalds Corporation from 1998-2006. Each location is company-owned, and not franchised. The original owner never dreamed his restaurant would expand beyond his first 880 square foot restaurant, but Chipotle restaurants are now located in 36 states in the United States and one location each in Canada and London. Chipotle is the largest purchaser of natural meats in the US.

 Food with Integrity 

There is a growing effort to introduce delicious, healthier food alternatives into America&apos;s busy lifestyles. This is seen in the efforts of the natural meats used at the Chipotle restaurant chain. What does the &quot;Food with Integrity&quot; motto mean at Chipotle? The animals raised for the meats used at Chipotle restaurants are naturally and sustainably raised by local farmers and ranchers, not in factory farms like most of the animals used for meat consumption in the United States. The conventionally raised chickens, pigs and cows are raised in confined quarters. To have more animals live to be slaughtered and enter the food supply quicker, antibiotics and hormones are used in the conventional animal feed. This prevents animal mortality and quickens the growth cycle of the animal so that more animal meat is available quicker for food in the US. Did you know that the animals on factory farms consume over three times the amount of antibiotics as people in the United States each year?

So, what does it mean to raise animals humanely without added antibiotics and hormones?

This is from the Chipotle website: &quot;These are ranchers whose pigs are raised outside or in deeply bedded pens, are never given antibiotics and are fed a vegetarian diet. It&apos;s the way animals were raised 50 years ago before huge factory farms changed the industry. We believe animals that are cared for in this way enjoy happier, healthier lives and produce the best pork we&apos;ve ever tasted. We call this style of ranching naturally raised, and since 2001, we have sourced 100% of our pork from producers who follow these guidelines.&quot;

The other animals raised for Chipotle restaurants are also raised on family farms or ranches, not in factory farms. The chickens used in Chipotle restaurants are 100% naturally raised which means no antibiotics are given. Nationally, no added hormones are allowed for any chickens grown in the United States. In addition, no arsenic is used with the chicken food. Some chicken growers think arsenic causes the chickens to grow faster.

The beef in Chipotle restaurants is 85% naturally raised with the goal to be 100% natural. There are not enough suppliers yet to provide this type of superior meat for this restaurant chain. The goal is to have all beef, pork and chickens to be pasture fed and 100% naturally raised for all Chipotle outlets within a couple of years.

Another product commonly used with cows is Recombinant Bovine Growth Hormone (rBGH). This is used to increase milk production eight times the normal for cows given this hormone. The milk, sour cream and cheese are free of rBGH for Chipotle. Thirty-five percent of the dairy cattle are pasture fed. The black beans are 40% organic with an initiative to increase this amount with organic suppliers.

 The Chipotle Dining Experience 

So, are you ready to enjoy a meal at your local Chipotle? This restaurant offer a wonderful gourmet menu: Burritos, Burrito bowls, Tacos, salads, guacamole and chips. It is a casual dining experience. There are no waitresses. To place an order, people must stand in line (which is often out the door at noon and evening time) but don&apos;t worry as this line moves very quickly. When placing the food order, the food is prepared right in front of the customer at the counter behind clear glass. Rice is offered first, then the choice of beans (black or pinto). Next, it is time to select the choice of meat which has each been braised several hours with special herbs and spices. What is the meat of choice for you today? Will it be barbacoa (beef), carnitas (pork), steak or chicken today? My favorite is the carnitas as I enjoy this wonderful taste. The Cheese, sour cream, guacamole and lettuce are offered next. Next, the choice of sauce for the burrito, salad or taco is offered: mild tomato relish, medium corn relish, medium salsa or hot salsa.

There are also vegetarian items offered for the burritos and tacos for the vegetarians who eat here. The burrito bowl can also be ordered instead of the tortilla for carbohydrate conscious diners. The burrito is then wrapped in foil and is ready to go or the burrito bowl is covered with foil. This meal is a hearty meal and locally costs $6.25 before tax for the carnitas burrito or burrito bowl.

After the order is paid for, it is time to find a table to sit down and enjoy this outstanding food. Dining at the local Olathe Chipotle offers the choice of indoor dining or on an outdoor covered patio. Our family members have been regular customers at the local Olathe, KS Chipotle restaurant for several years. All the meat at our local Olathe restaurant is natural, the beans are organic and much of the produce is local. We enjoy this wonderful food a couple of times each month. We especially like knowing that this food is farmer or rancher raised with attention to no antibiotics and no hormone additives in the meat.

 Future Fast Food Dream 

The health conscious person who does eat meat deserves to have wonderful natural meats when eating out at a fast food restaurant. Customer demand is the key for the other fast food restaurant chains to follow suit and offer naturally grown meats. With restaurant demand, farmers and ranchers may be more willing to forego the antibiotics and hormones use in the normal cattle feed. Wouldn&apos;t it be great if McDonalds Corporation, the former corporate owner of Chipotle, would follow suit and offer naturally raised meats at their fast food restaurants also?

Natural beef is sold at O&apos;Naturals in the North east US, Colorado has Good Times burgers, and Florida has EVOS chain. On the west coast, Burgerville and Burgermeister chains serve naturally raised beef for their burgers. Besides Chipotle, natural chicken is sold at Arby&apos;s, Panera Bread, Chick-fil-A, Chicken Out, and Au Bon Pain national chains. Not all of these chains are available across the US.

My wish is that other fast food restaurant chains will soon follow suit for these naturally raised meats and foods to be offered in an affordable manner at their restaurants. I wonder how many of the regular customers really know how special the naturally raised meat is at the local Chipotle restaurant.

Hormone free and antibiotic free meats are readily available in the super markets in our area. The cost is always more than conventionally grown meat that has added antibiotics and hormones. The taste is outstanding with no additives in the natural meat and I feel it is a healthier choice for our family. For people seeking natural meat and local produce when eating outside of the home, Chipotle has wonderful options for natural meat that is not available at most fast food restaurants. If you haven&apos;t tried it before, check out your local Chipotle restaurant soon.

 Animal Haven and Chipotle 

This Saturday, September 4 th , the Chipotle restaurants in the Kansas City area will donate 50% of the proceeds from your purchase, up to $5000 to benefit Animal Haven. Animal Haven sponsors pet adoptions, provides lost pet reunions, and is the largest no kill animal shelter in the Kansas City area.

 Sources: 

Personal experience

 http://www.chipotle.com/en-US/fwi/fwi.aspx 

 http://www.helpguide.org/life/fast_food_nutrition.htm 

 http://www.motherearthnews.com/Real-Food/Organic-Fast-Food-Restaurant-Chain.aspx 

 http://www.rurdev.usda.gov/rbs/pub/Painter_Report_Small.pdf 

 http://www.animalhavenkc.org/ 
 
Published by Mary Oberg 

Retired nurse with over thirty years of experience. I worked as a Medical-Surgical-Geriatric Clinical Nurse Specialist at a large urban medical center and taught Medical-Surgical nursing for many years at Av...  View profile 
 
 It is Possible to Order Healthy Items at a Fast Food Restaurant Think you have to order 1,000 calorie meals just because you are eating at a Fast Food Restaurant ? Think Again , there are ways to work the menu to your advantage. The Benefits of Working for a Fast Food Restaurant as a Teenager Are you a young person looking to be well prepare for your future career? This article will help explain some of the benefits of working at a fast food restaurant. Charlotte YMCA Health and Wellness Fair The Health and Wellness Fair to be held at Charlotte YMCA will offer health screenings for diabetes, cholesterol and more. Health and Wellness Podcasts to Better Your Life Here are my top 5 health and wellness podcasts available online. Health and Wellness Content Spotlight: The Week of June 5, 2006 This week, some fascinating submissions to the Health and Wellness Category caught my eye. Articles about home safety, the benefits of bee pollen, and two new submissions from a... 

 Salumeria Rosi Restaurant, New York Health Orientated Fast Food Rest... Discover Cipriani Restaurant - S... 
 
 Enjoy Eco-Friendly Dining at Green Restaurants Tomato Ban in All Chipotle Restaurants Chipotle: Fast, Good Mexican Restaurant Chipotle Restaurants Support &apos; Food, Inc. &apos; Film and Humane Farming Restaurant Review: Chipotle Mexican Grill Review of Bluescreek Farm Meats Found at the North Market in Columbus, Ohio Our Health and Wellness is in OUR Hands 
 
 
 
 Takeaways 
 
 Chipotle is an international fast food chain using naturally raised meats in their restaurant foods. Goal of Chipotle is to have 100% of the chicken, pork and beef in their restaurants to be natural More people need to demand that other fast food national chains also provide naturally grown meat 
 
28 Comments
 Post a Comment 
 Sandy James 10/31/2010 
I like Chipotle&apos;s. Great review.
 Jennifer Bove 9/26/2010 
great article and info
 R.C. Johnson 9/25/2010 
A very popular restaurant chain in our area. Learned a lot from your article.
 Rita Oakleaf 9/22/2010 
Great article. I&apos;ve only eaten at Chipotle twice, but it was good. I never knew about their efforts to use natural and local food. Kudos to them.
 Peggy Hazelwood 9/21/2010 
I LOVE Chipotle burritos. Yum!
 Tonya Hillukka 9/10/2010 
I&apos;ve never been there, but this article is full of great information!
 Kristen Wilkerson 9/10/2010 
I found this very interesting. Thanks!
 Carol Roach 9/10/2010 
great read, I don&apos;t have a chipotle here in Montreal that I know of
 Jeanne Baney 9/7/2010 
We love Chipotle! It was a red letter day when they opened a store less than a mile from my home!
 Ali Canary 9/7/2010 
One of my friends introduced me to the local Chipotle and it is great! I am really happy about their environmental practices, too. Great writeup!
 
 Displaying Comments «Prev 1 2 3 Next» 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Shine and Lifestyles Network. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
