<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002433" url="http://shareme.com/details/how-to-operate-a-restaurant.html" time="2012-07-12-18:22" support="1" score="0.00033810675495500836" bingtitle="Tools &amp; Utilities - How To Operate A Restaurant - GoldenStarEbooks.com" webtitle="Tools&amp;Utilities - How To Operate A Restaurant - GoldenStarEbooks.com">
			<query id="000311" bing-rank="237"/>
	<description>How To Buy A Fast Food Restaurant, How To Balance A Check Book, ... in producing, bills, bookings and closing bills ... Enter the computer age and reap the benefits of ...</description>
	<body>
		Categories
 
 Categories | New Software Releases | Popular Downloads | Submit Software | RSS Feeds 
 
 
 
 Business&amp;Productivity Tools Communications Desktop Enhancements Drivers Educational Games Home&amp;Personal Internet Multimedia&amp;Design Network Tools Programming Security Utilities Web Authoring 

 Top Downloads

 Ultimate IP Changer 
Ultimate IP Changer changes TCP/IP settings by...
 FTP Password 
FTP Password is an universal password recovery...
 Scan and Repair Utilities 
Scan&amp;Repair Utilities - 2006 detects, removes...
 Advanced RSS2Web Professional 
Advanced RSS2Web allows you to automatically...
 Active Wall Traffic Monitor 
Active Wall Traffic Monitor is a free real time...
 Easy WIFI Radar 
Look for wireless connections and connect to...
 Broadband Usage Meter 
Real time monitoring of broadband use
 ConceptDraw WebWave 
Web site architecture, diagramming, schematics...
 IDAutomation MICR Check Design Application 
Easily design, create and print MICR bank...
 Lava Lamp 
Displays a mathmos like Lava lamp on your desktop.
 

 New Downloads

 Advanced RSS2Web Professional 3.12.104 
Advanced RSS2Web allows you to automatically...
 CuteHotspot. WiFi hotspot software 3.1 
Charge the customers of your cafe, club, shop,...
 RSS Content Generator Enterprise 3.12.86 
RSS Content Generator is a comprehensive...
 IE Accelerator 3.02 
Accelerate the surfing and downloading speed of...
 Ultimate IP Changer 1.0 
Ultimate IP Changer changes TCP/IP settings by...
 Advanced RSS2Email Premier 3.11.89 
Advanced RSS2Email allows you to automatically...
 Advanced RSS Mixer Personal 3.11.101 
Combines different free RSS feeds (news, press...
 Live Chat Software 4.0.1.5 
Live chat software is best tool useful tool...
 Advanced RSS2Web Personal 3.11.104 
Advanced RSS2Web allows you to automatically...
 Website Monitoring Software 3.0.1.5 
Quality and affordable Website Monitoring...
 

 Related Downloads
 How To Buy A Fast Food Restaurant , How To Balance A Check Book , How To Be A Gangster , How To Be A Nerd , How To Be A Player Soundtrack , How To Be A Virtuoso Pianist , How To Become A Bounty Hunters In Florida , How To Become A Chartered Accountant Canada , How To Become A Criminal Profiler , How To Become A Health Visitor 
 Recent Searches
 Carrier Fs2002 Download , Disc Image Converter , 3gp Movies Watch , Automotive Shop Management , Play Free No Time Limit Hidden Object Games , Code F R Replay Media Catcher , Installing Funshion In Ubuntu Linux , Firefox Web Browser , Asean Country List , Imvu 3d Messenger For Nokia 5530 , Data Center Gantt Charts , Urdu Homeopathy Books , Gigaset 504 Agu , Hyatt Regency Atlanta , Army General Discharge 
 
 
How To Operate A Restaurant 1.0
   

 
 Category: Internet / Tools&amp;Utilities   Author: GoldenStarEbooks.com | Published: Apr 10, 2006
 License: Shareware | O/S: Windows 95/98/Me/NT/2000/XP File Number: 39572 
 Uninstaller: yes 



Despite this growing trend for eating out and a steadily expanding sales volume, the mortality rate in the food service industry is extremely high. What are the causes for failure? This question was asked of many highly successful food service organizations and operators in the country. Invariably they replied that a restaurant operator will fail unless he has a thorough knowledge of food.

 How To Operate A Restaurant Related Tags :
 Ebooks - Home Business - Online Business Opportunity - Package - Profits 100 - Resale Empire - Resell Rights - Ultimate File Size: 438.0 KB   Price: $19.95   Downloads: 124
 Download Now! | Homepage | Screenshot | Report Link Error | Bookmark this page Requirements: n/a User Rating: 
 
 Rate It: &lt;none&gt; Excellent Very Good Good Fair Poor 
 

 
 Editor Rating: Unrated 
 More Software from GoldenStarEbooks.com:
 Classic Dessert Collection - The Path To Prosperity - 101 Camping&amp;Outdoor Recipes - Clairvoyance and Its Powers - 101 Chicken Wing Recipes - Chocolate Recipes For Chocolate Lovers - The Big Book of Cookies - The Science of Getting Rich - Healthy Life Cookbook - Recipes From South of the Border   
 Reviews:
 
Write a review:
 
 

 Your rating  * 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 
 1=poor                                                                          10=excellent Your name  * Email  * Review text  * 




 

   

 
 
 Related Software
 
 
 
 
 How To Do It 1.0 
 Published: Apr 12, 2006 How to talk, read, write, travel and more, How to get into society, Life at school...

 Price: $19.95 Size: 428.0 KB   
 

 
 
 Secret Door To Success 1.0 
 Published: Apr 12, 2006 What is the secret of your success? People never ask a man who is a failure, What is the secret of your failure? It is quite easy to see and they are not interested. People all want to know how to open the secret door to success. For each man there i

 Price: $19.95 Size: 431.0 KB   
 

 
 
 The Secret Of Success 1.0 
 Published: Apr 12, 2006 Success, the book is A Complete Collection of Rules That are Vital to Success. This book was Approved and Formulated by no less than the Successful Men of the World who became acquainted with these Rules only after they had Attained Success.  This bo

 Price: $19.95 Size: 422.0 KB   
 

 
 
 Think and Grow Rich 1.0 
 Published: Apr 09, 2006 In a few minutes, you are about to come into possession of a philosophy which can be transmuted into material wealth, or to bring you peace of mind, understanding, and spiritual harmony.Â  This book explains how to recognize and apply the principles

 Price: $19.95 Size: 438.0 KB   
 

 
 
 How to Study and Teaching How to Study 1.0 
 Published: Apr 17, 2006 How to Study and Teaching How to  Study is a perfect guide on various techniques for quick  and effective digestion of everything that we study. It also includes tips on how one can effectively impart knowledge to any audience.

 Price: $19.95 Size: 450.0 KB   
 

 
 
 As A Man Thinketh 1.0 
 Published: Apr 10, 2006 As A Man Thinketh is a powerful philosophy that will make you achieve perfection through the purity of thought.   More than that this book will help you transform your thoughts into concrete actions that will result in the achievement of anything tha

 Price: $19.95 Size: 420.0 KB   
 

 
 
 Quick and Easy Cooking 1.0 
 Published: Apr 12, 2006 Have you just arrived home from a long work day and want to prepare something simple? You look in the refrigerator and the only thing that looks easy is the not-so-tasty frozen dinners? So instead you hop in the car and it`s off to the fast food rest

 Price: $19.95 Size: 421.0 KB   
 

 
 
 The Path To Prosperity 1.0 
 Published: Apr 06, 2006 It isn`t what most people think that leads to the Path to Prosperity.  Secrets of happiness and prosperity explained in non- frightening terms with examples for the reader.  This book contains principles that on application bring great results no mat

 Price: $19.95 Size: 425.0 KB   
 

 
 
 470 Crock Pot Recipes 1.0 
 Published: Apr 10, 2006 I know that a lot of you have at least one of these efficient and time saving appliances hidden away somewhere in your kitchen collecting dust. You probably thought that the crock pot was just for making soups or stews. Well guess what, you can make

 Price: $19.95 Size: 432.0 KB   
 

 
 
 Recipes From South of the Border 1.0 
 Published: Apr 18, 2006 Among the world`s great cuisines, the foods of Mexico stand out in their diversity. Rooted in a history of ancient Indian civilizations, inspired by the Spanish Conquistadores of the sixteenth century, and influenced by European tastes in the later r

 Price: $19.95 Size: 426.0 KB   
 
 
 
 How To Operate A Restaurant also mentioned on ShareMe
 
 
 1.  Sri Annai Restaurant Billing System - Business&amp;Productivity Tools/Inventory Systems 
... Sri Annai Restaurant Billing System is a new generation of restaurant management software for Windows. It is a complete solution starting from taking orders from clients in producing, bills, bookings and closing bills with different payment options. User interface is carefully optimized for high speed entering of client orders. The system represents rich set of reports that shows whole picture about restaurant operations and life cycles. ...   
 
 2.  Restaurant - Home&amp;Personal/Clocks, Calendars&amp;Planners 
... Cut time, reduce mistakes, improve efficiency and maximise the true potential of your restaurant with this restaurant customer&amp;reservation package. Manage reservation&amp;customer details. Advanced table availability searching. Search for reservations, customers&amp;view customer history. Easily control the flow of customers through the restaurant. Report printing, data exporting plus much more! ...   
 
 3.  Restaurology Restaurant Point Of Sale - Business&amp;Productivity Tools 
... Restaurology The science of running a restaurant
 Full Service, Fast Food, Casual Dining, Walk-up, Drive Thru, Take Out, and Delivery Concepts.
 Scanner / Keyboard Style Track Waiter Sales 
 Print Orders to Kitchen 
 Table layout for your retaurant.
 Touch Screen Operation or Scanner or Keyboard 
 Enhanced Reports 
 Expanded Customer Info 
 Cash Drawer Reconciliation 
 Inventory Control Software 
 Manpower Planning 
 Automatic Tax Rates 
 Automatic Discounts 
 USA, UK Canadian Tax Method 
 Sales ...   
 
 4.  iMagic Restaurant Reservation - Business&amp;Productivity Tools/Organizer 
... Manage your restaurant&apos;s reservations and walk ins. The pen and pad have seen their day!
 
 Enter the computer age and reap the benefits of automating the reservation process. Track customers and more importantly help keep the repeat customers. You can analyse reservation trends and work towards your future needs. Rearrange reservations and allocate tables without an eraser in sight! ...   
 
 5.  Abacre Restaurant Point of Sale - Business&amp;Productivity Tools/Other Related Tools 
... Abacre Restaurant Point of Sales is a new generation of restaurant management software for Windows. It is a complete solution, beginning with taking orders from patrons, and ending with billing and tax reports. The user interface is carefully optimized for high speed input of a patron&apos;s order and the prevention of common mistakes. It&apos;s designed for using on multiple computers, and contains reliable and secure authorization levels. 
 
 The layouts of the guest bill can be customized, and the ...   
 
 

 
 
 a - b - c - d - e - f - g - h - i - j - k - l - m - n - o - p - q - r - s - t - u - v - w - x - y - z - # 
 
 ©1997-2012 ShareMe Last Update: Wednesday, July 11, 2012 shareme | contact | legal notice | privacy | bookmark | link to us 
 
 
Welcome to the ShareMe. Here you can free download windows shareware, freeware and demo versions of commercial software, games, mp3, dvd, audio, video programs. We do not share, host any crack, warez files either from mirrors or file hosting website rapidshare, depositfile, youtube. All software have posted by genuine software authors and we publish them, if you like it, buy the licensed full version or serial keys. Any questions, complaints or claims related to the software should be directed to the appropriate author or company responsible for developing the software, not the staff working for shareme.com
	</body>
</document>
