<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002951" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/article/231732/going_to_hardees_be_careful_what_you.html" time="2012-07-12-19:03" support="1" score="0.00031631091379415394" bingtitle="Going to Hardees? Be Careful What You Wish For - Yahoo! Voices ..." webtitle="Going to Hardees? Be Careful What You Wish For - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="000078" bing-rank="176"/>
	<description>They have more drink selections than any fast food restaurant I ... credit, as they have some of the best seats in the ... They have two soft drink dispensing machines at our ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
Going to Hardees? Be Careful What You Wish For
 Dickie Dingleheimer , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
May 23, 2007 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: Hardees 
 Flag Close Post a comment Hardees brings back a little bit of nostalgia for me, as it used to be the place I would sneak to for lunch, as a high school student. It was a place to smoke a cigarette without having the Principal busting you, and it had better food than the school&apos;s cafeteria.(Not that its a major challenge) Instead of eating their half warmed pizzas and fish, I would spend my lunch hour dining on a chicken sandwich from this restaurant. As a person with a little less hair and more grays for the remaining follicles, my taste in food has changed greatly since those &quot;glory days.&quot; I still go to fast food restaurants, as they are necessary with my unbelievably long work hours. However, I&apos;m a bit more selective now, and the only way I go to Hardees is if its the only place to go.
Unfortunately where I go fishing, it is the only restaurant in town. There&apos;s not one traffic light, but there is a Hardees . It&apos;s nuclear orange sign is hard to miss, and this place can get quite crowded. Before or after spending time on the river, I enjoy going here to see the folks from the movie &quot;Deliverance.&quot; I always walk in and out backwards, and I start sweating if anyone has a banjo. You can buy breakfast, lunch, or dinner here, as their hours on most days are from 6 a.m.-10 p.m. It is open seven days a week, and I&apos;m assuming that it only closes on Thanksgiving and Christmas Day.

I was interested in learning the history of Hardee&apos;s , so after reading one of the store&apos;s napkins, I went to their website for more information.( www.hardees.com. ) They have been around since 1960, and started out in North Carolina. Usually this state is known as a wonderful place for cuisine, and I&apos;ll get to that later concerning this chain&apos;s food quality.Most of their restaurants are still located in the Southeastern United States. You can complain or compliment their locations on the website, or call their corporate line at 1-877-799-STAR. If you want a gift card, which is a wonderful idea for Uncle Jethro&apos;s Christmas stocking, you can order them on line or by calling 1-866-784-9544.

 Breakfast 

They have an extensive breakfast menu, that will rival competitors McDonalds or Burger King for sheer variety. There are pancakes, omelets, biscuit sandwiches, sausages, potatoes, toasts, and other biohazards to chose from. There are about ten value meals to decide from, and you can always order items a la carte as well. Most of the meals cost $4-$6, and come with a soft drink or coffee. The majority of the items purchased separately cost from $1-$3. If you are tired in the morning, this has got to be the easiest place to read the menu with tired eyes. All of the meal signs are lit up with enough light, for a sporting event.

I usually get the Smoked Sausage Biscuit , with a side of their Hash Rounds. This runs for $5, and I get a soda or bottled water with my meal. The Biscuits are really good, as they are warm and fluffy. If you like butter on them, with adds to their healthiness, it will melt as soon as applied. They are slightly browned on the outside, and they might just be the best biscuits of all the fast food restaurants. The sausage inside is pretty good, and has a little bit of spice to it as well. This is a good choice to fill you up, and it provides a lot of energy to start the day. The rounds are small potatoes in a perfect circular shape, and are good with ketchup. They give you a good amount of these too, which is always a plus on a limited budget.

Stay away from the Biscuits and Gravy. While the biscuits are delicious, the gravy that they use ruins them completely. If you like a soggy meal, then you may like this. The country gravy that they use tastes like one would expect from the canned variety, that is served on a submarine. It is nasty, thick, and has a disgusting seasoning that makes it even more abysmal. These cost $3, and I will never purchase them again. Stick with the plain biscuits, and you&apos;ll be quite happy.

How on Earth do you mess up coffee? I didn&apos;t know this was possible, and that I would say 7-11&apos;s formula is gourmet when compared to this stuff. This coffee reminds me of motor oil, and it has a vintage 1983 taste to it. This is pure battery acid, and it will leave your stomach crying for mercy. I had to pop two antacids after having this, and usually they take care of any problem in about half an hour. After drinking this coffee, I had to wait two hours for any relief. Even my buddy who doesn&apos;t care how coffee tastes, admits that this is some terrible stuff that he won&apos;t have again either. This formula is unable to be tamed, even with a ton of creamer and/or sugar.

 Lunch/Dinner 

I have to give this chain credit, as they have a lot of beef items on the menu. You almost have to think that John Wayne would have blessed this place, and brought his cow poke buddies in here to eat. There is a decent sized menu for lunch and dinner selections, and the prices are reasonable as well. Expect to pay $5-$7 for a meal combo, that comes with a sandwich, side item, and a soda. You can also order items here a la carte, and you can decide between regular and curly fries with your meal.

On my most recent visit, I had their new Jalapeno Thick burger. It&apos;s a 1/3 pound burger, with supposedly 100% Angus Beef. I think they were referring to Angus Young of the band AC/DC, as it was a little bit lean on taste and flavor throughout. This burger is topped with lots of Jalapenos, and I think this is an interesting concept if it was done right. There are some positives for it, as the Jalapenos were fresh and had plenty of bite. The vegetable toppings of lettuce, tomatoes, and onions were good as well, and I liked the Jack Cheese that was nicely melted on the beef.

The beef portion itself was undercooked, which I found to be quite revolting. The taste was far from delicious, and I could have sworn that it was made of Soy. For some reason, the roll was stale as well, which is an excellent way to destroy what could be a decent burger. The bun was not of good quality either, and this sandwich was one of the messiest I&apos;ve ever eaten. The ingredients were stacked in a haphazard manner, and the special Santa Fe Sauce isn&apos;t very good. Its a little too sweet in my opinion, and should be removed from the burger altogether. You can buy the meal for this burger at $6, with some additional change going to your Governor. If you want a big burger, they do have a 2/3 lb sized one.

The Big Roast Beef Combo is the best lunch item, and it&apos;s average at best. The bread has the same issues as the Thick Burger did, but at least the slices of roast beef are pretty good. This is what I always get now, when forced to eat here, and its a safe selection. The slices of the beef are always piping hot, and their Horseradish sauce is a winning addition on top of this. The portioning is also above average, and this is a sandwich that will satisfy your hunger after a long day outdoors. Its also $6, and is a good bet for dinner as well.

Do you like fried chicken? I think its the best meal in the world, but Hardees chicken is quite boring. They must raise their birds in a pen, where they are forced to watch Brit Hume all day. It has no real flavor. I like to have spicy chicken, but there&apos;s has none to it. In addition to the lack of refined taste, the breading falls apart easily as well. Its a real thin breading, and for some reason, its also served in real small portions. I&apos;m not sure when they decide to butcher their chickens, but there should be an age requirement. The two piece meal comes with a breast and a thigh, and yes, I&apos;m a breast and thigh man! This meal is served with fries and a biscuit, and costs close to $7 for a combo.

 French Fries or Curly Fries? 

Go with the regular French Fries, as they are hot and crisp. They have a reasonable amount of salt on them, and are usually the most consistent meal on the menu.(I have yet to be served cold/soggy fries here) I think they are really good, and I always up size my meal to get more of them. The Curly edition of fries are okay, but I don&apos;t like the seasoning that they have. I also don&apos;t like how you get fragmented pieces of these, rather than getting large full sized curly potatoes. While they are also served piping hot, they don&apos;t go to well with any of their meals.

 Beverages 

This place must have made a deal with the devil, or at least the Coca-Cola Company. They have more drink selections than any fast food restaurant I&apos;ve ever been to. As per most chain establishments, they have the usual Coke, Diet Coke, Sprite, and Minute Maid Lemonade. However, they also have Hi-C Orange/Fruit Punch, Mr. Pipp, Mello Yellow, and Nestea Ice and Raspberry Tea. If you want a bottled water, which I often purchase, they offer Dasani . This is wonderful filtered water, from a tap that is connected to the Charles River. They also have Hot Chocolate, and Powerade, so you can refresh yourself after running a marathon.

 Milkshakes 

I truly love their milkshakes, as they have the best ones that $2 can buy. Sometimes they offer some rather strange flavors, such as Mark Foley Congressional Page Mix or Al Davis&apos;s Incompetence Bonanza, but usually they have Chocolate, Vanilla, and Strawberry. I almost always purchase the Chocolate one, and I always behave myself by ordering a medium. There is something about the quality of their milkshakes, and they are really thick and delicious. The Vanilla is really good too, and I&apos;ve yet to try the Strawberry one. These are wonderful for dessert, or as a side item.

 Eat In Visits 

I have to give Hardees credit, as they have some of the best seats in the fast food business. Their booths are huge, and allow long legged individuals to be truly comfortable. The backs of the booths have padding, which allow you to forget any back or neck pain temporarily. The tables have plenty of room, and don&apos;t have the annoying advertisements all over them like most fast food places do. There is a salt and pepper shaker on each table, and ashtrays are on the tables at their smoking establishments.

They have a really good condiment island at our location, and I like how it allows for people to get their sauces without causing too long of lines. The sauces and napkins are easy to reach, and they have always been well stocked. They have two soft drink dispensing machines at our Hardee&apos;s , and there&apos;s never been an issue of them running out of ice or the drinks themselves. All of the drink tops and straws are organized, and easy to reach from the metal trays. Their serving cups for the sauces allow for enough portions, so that you don&apos;t have to walk back to the table with four containers of ketchup, mustard, etc.

The signs with the menu items and prices, are easy to read from anywhere in the restaurant. I&apos;ve been pretty impressed with the level of service inside, as the employees have been very friendly. This gives the restaurant a &quot;down home feel,&quot; and I&apos;ve almost wanted to propose marriage there with a shotgun to my back. Each of the employees has been knowledgeable about the menu items, and have had good suggestions about what to purchase. They are also very efficient, even during busy peak periods of business, all while maintaining a pleasant demeanor. Perhaps this is because their name tags are the size of a large index card, so complaints could be easily handled.

As for management, I&apos;ve been impressed that the manager of our location, has been known to participate in a lot of restaurant duties. She&apos;s helped out during busy periods at the register, cooked the food, and has even done some cleaning duties in the dining area. She was also helpful to my friend one time, who had some missing items in a drive thru order. She gave him an extra sandwich and fry free for his trouble, and he was impressed that she took care of him quickly. This personal approach to customers, is one thing that Hardee&apos;s does right.

Generally, the restaurant has also been very clean. The trash cans have never been full, and debris and rubbish is always cleaned off the floors and tables. The windows are kept shining, and I like how the employees focus on keeping the condiment island and serving lines clear of anything. I&apos;ve seen these employees out with cleaning solution on several visits, and they also change it frequently, instead of letting it turn into the Charles River. The bathrooms are sparkling clean, and the supplies are always kept up. Obviously, they don&apos;t lie about their hourly cleaning visits.

 Drive Thru Issues 

I don&apos;t go through the drive thru anymore, because what Joe Pesci said in Lethal Weapon is accurate. They have not given us items that we&apos;ve ordered, or put something incorrect in the bag almost every time we&apos;ve ordered from the car. I think a lot of this has to do with their microphone/speaker system, as its the worst I&apos;ve ever seen. You have to yell to be heard on it, and all you hear from the employee is &quot;Gojgwsnfnvnv.&quot; It&apos;s so hard to understand them, even when they speak perfect English.

I don&apos;t like their sign outside, as the items and prices are in small print. I&apos;m convinced a lawyer had this designed to his taste, and the wait times can be ridiculous! Even if there are only two or three cars in front of you, it can be a 10-15 minute wait for your food. During one visit they said they had to cook my meal, so it would be a few minutes. As soon as I got the sandwich, I discovered that it was cold, and that it was a lie that the employee told me. This is the worst drive thru of any fast food restaurant, and expect a long wait during busy meal periods. The spacing of the lane and the cement barrier, leads to some tricky driving as well.

 Final Thoughts 

I think its okay, in the context that it is the only place in town where I go. However, with all of the fast food chains in most towns, I would go somewhere else if I had a choice. While impressed with their dining room service, the food quality is not enough to get me to go there often. It&apos;s okay for a quick meal, but I&apos;m not that excited about any of their menu items. The best meal overall is probably breakfast, and as long as you pick something safe, it should be okay for general purposes. At least the price is not going to affect your budget, and the milkshakes are fantastic enough for a dessert visit.
 
Published by Dickie Dingleheimer 

I&apos;m a typical suburbanite, with my wife, 2.5 kids, and 1.3 dogs. My interests include hiking, biking, fishing, hunting, and camping. In addition to outdoor activities, I&apos;m most content reading an excellent h...  View profile 
 
 Tips on How to Get the Best Value for Your Money at Fast Food Restaurants Read this informative article and learn some tips on how to get the best value for your money at fast food restaurants! Top Five Fast Food Restaurants that Offer a Diverse Menu Some fast food restaurants are cookie cutter normal, and some have very unique menu&apos;s. Which offer the most choices? Does Fast Food Make People Fat? Los Angeles Considers Banning New Fast Food Restau... Will banning new fast food restaurants help the residents of South LA loose weight and be less obese? One LA City Councilmember thinks so. What do you think? New York City Councilman Has Proposed Limiting Fast Food Restaurants City Councilman and Chair of the Health Committee Joel Rivera has proposed a radical idea that would limit the number of fast food restaurants that can exist in a given area particularly low income areas that house th... Stroke Risk Higher in Areas with Many Fast Food Restaurants New research suggests that there is a link between the number of neighborhood fast food restaurants and risk of stroke for people in the area. 
 
 How to Stay Safe and Clean in Fast Food Restaurants Tips for Making Healthy Choices at Fast Food Restaurants Healthy Choices at Fast Food Restaurants Shopping and Dining Discounts for Seniors Fast Food Restaurants Best Fast Food Restaurants in Antioch, California Top Fast Food Restaurants in Katy, Texas 
 
 
 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Shine and Lifestyles Network. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
