<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002084" url="http://www.city-data.com/profiles/3201" time="2012-07-12-17:59" support="5" score="0.004398195963636483" bingtitle="Crane&apos;s Drive-In, Inc. in Ossian, Indiana - Dining - Business ..." webtitle="Crane&apos;s Drive-In, Inc. in Ossian, Indiana - Dining - Business Profile at City-data.com">
			<query id="001021" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="001026" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="001013" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="000702" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000699" bing-rank="85"/>
	<description>Crane&apos;s Drive-In, Inc. is a fifties style outdoor fast-food restaurant with drive-up eat in you car service or you can park and use the picnic tables for ...</description>
	<body>
		Business Profile for Ossian, Indiana
 
 Login: Password: 
 Business Search 
 14 Million Businesses in
 12,000 Categories 
 Search for: Localization: 
 
 Business name: Crane&apos;s Drive-In, Inc. 
 Address: 410 North Jefferson St

Ossian, Indiana 46777 Phone number: 260-622-7458 Fax number: 260-622-4418 Map: please wait while loading the map... Directions to this business View: Email address: Category: Dining Description: Crane&apos;s Drive-In, Inc. is a fifties style outdoor fast-food restaurant with drive-up eat in you car service or you can park and use the picnic tables for outdoor dining.
They still have carhops who bring the food to your car or table.
Crane&apos;s in known for: Homemade Breaded Tenderloins and Broasted Chicken including homemade Soft Ice-Cream. Rootbeer still served in chilled glass mugs. Over 85 Items on menu. Prices reasonable.
Open April thru October each year. Accept call-in go-orders for pick-up.
Credit Cards accepted.

Call: 260-622-7458 Photos: 
 
 
 
 Last update: 2007-02-19 Visits: 1511 
 
 Add a profile of your own business - it&apos;s totally free. 30,000 businesses already created their profiles! 


 Ossian, IN forum 

 
 City-data Home       Ossian, Indiana 

This page was created by a person asserting to represent this business. This website does not endorse this business or is otherwise affiliated with or endorsed by Crane&apos;s Drive-In, Inc..
	</body>
</document>
