<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002998" url="http://johndlee.hubpages.com/hub/Restaurant-Marketing-6-Low-Cost-Ways-to-Make-More-Money-in-Your-Restaurant-Menu-Optimization--Guest-Check-Average" time="2012-07-12-19:05" support="4" score="0.005940212854880358" bingtitle="Restaurant Marketing. 5 Low Cost Ways to Make More Money in Your ..." webtitle="Restaurant Marketing. 5 Low Cost Ways to Make More Money in Your Restaurant. Menu Optimization, Guest Check Average...">
			<query id="001314" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="001050" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="001063" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="001302" bing-rank="108"/>
	<description>5 easy ways to increase your restaurant profits. ... little scarcer – you&apos;ve got to make every table pay ... Also, check your water bill, check for leaks - they add ...</description>
	<body>
		HubPages 
 explore 
 topics hubs answers forums 
 sign in join now 
 flag 
 Explore  » Food and Cooking (53,824) » Restaurants and Fast Food (2,243) 
 by John D Lee 
932 Followers 
Restaurant Marketing. 5 Low Cost Ways to Make More Money in Your Restaurant. Menu Optimization, Guest Check Average...
 http://www.flickr.com/photos/stuart_spivack/132729710/ 
 There are times of milk and honey and there are times of
peanut butter and jam. Having had a somewhat tourism dependent restaurant business
in a country that has been pretty volatile (with both highs and lows) for the
past many years, I have grown sort of accustomed to both sides of the economic
coin. 

Anyone can make it through in the good times, but the tough times
tend to weed out operations without solid foundations. But tougher times also
force you to revisit your methodology – to tighten things up and to get a
little leaner and a little meaner. And if you can actually do this, you&apos;ll be
in great shape whenever the tide turns, and the guests start flocking back.

I am no &quot;marketing expert&quot; just a guy that has
learned the hard way a number of restaurant lessons. Here are a few relatively straightforward
options for fine-tuning a restaurant business to make the most of its potential.
(Note – none of these &quot;tips&quot; will really cost you anything…).

1. Tighten up

When the dining room is full to capacity you might get away
with bloated food costs, but when guests are a little scarcer – you&apos;ve got to
make every table pay off. Look hard at the food-costs on every dish and
eliminate any that won&apos;t make the grade. The up-side to slower nights is that
your cooks should have more time to prepare foods from &quot;scratch&quot;. Don&apos;t
have anyone sitting around bored when they could be busy and happy and cooking.
It&apos;s more satisfying to make it all yourself (rather than opening a can…) and
it almost always tastes better too.

2. Revisit the menu

The menu mantra I&apos;ve heard throughout the years is that your
menu should be competitive. What this means is that every dish should have to
compete to stay on the menu. If you have a dish that underperforms (even if you
happen to love it) it&apos;s probably time to scrap it in favor of something that&apos;s
actually going to move.

You should also make sure your menus are optimized to induce
the ordering of your most profitable dishes. I won&apos;t get into menu optimization
here, but, placing a dish in the upper right corner of the menu, for example,
is a great way to boost its sales. And if you can boost the sales of a few
dishes that make you a greater profit %, you can really see a difference in the
end of the month bottom line.

3. Extend the hours

This is a big one, but extending your hours of operation to
get an additional service each day can be a great way to increase your sales,
without greatly increasing your fixed costs.

 You have to pay the same rent on the space whether you serve
breakfast or not! 

4. Increase guest frequency

It&apos;s is a lot harder to convince a new guest to try your
restaurant than it is to convince an existing customer at your restaurant to
come back a little more frequently. If you have an existing customer base, work
harder on increasing customer frequency than on encouraging new visits and you will
see a better financial response.

 For example 

 If you get great dinner business, but little lunch trade,
offer your dinner guests a lunch promotion certificate with the dinner check. 

5. Increase guest check size average

If you could get each guest to spend 15% more you&apos;d make a
lot more money each month! And it&apos;s a lot easier to get existing guests to
spend a little more than it is to attract new customers.

Work on the old standbys, appetizers, cocktails, wines and
beer and desserts. Get promo cards on the table advertising your best desserts –
have drink special posters in the hall to the restrooms…

 Nothing groundbreaking here, but like I said, I am not a
marketing guy, I&apos;m a restaurant guy, and so this list of ideas comes from the
point of view of a guy that would rather by in the kitchen than the office, but
that understands the painful truths of the business as well. 

Good luck to you all!
 
Menu Optimization Ideas
 
Make More with Dessert Sales! 5 Easy Ideas

 5 Low Cost Ways to Increase Dessert Sales and Increa... 
5 low or no cost ways to get your guests ordering dessert more often - increasing your guest check average and your bottome line! 
 
Ideas for Building Slow Night Business
 
 Word of Mouth Marketing: How Smart Companies Get People Talking Amazon Price: $12.74
List Price: $24.95 Restaurant Marketing for Owners and Managers (Wiley Restaurant Basics Series) Amazon Price: $14.33
List Price: $30.00 Restaurant Financial Basics Amazon Price: $18.17
List Price: $35.00 The Food Service Professional Guide to Restaurant Marketing and Advertising: For Just a Few Dollars a Day (The Food Service Professional Guide To Series 3) Amazon Price: $3.00
List Price: $19.95 
 
This Hub was last updated on January 15, 2012
 
You can help the HubPages community highlight top quality content by ranking this article up or down.
 Useful  {2} • Funny   • Awesome   • Beautiful   • Interesting   Discover More Hubs Restaurants Near Miller Park: Milwaukee, WI How Healthy is McDonald’s? The Real Story 18 Sauces for Cocktail Meatballs, Cocktails Weenies, and Cocktail Sausage Midsummer Eve, the big summer celebration in Sweden! A Basic Tool Kit For&quot;The Little Lady&quot; And So The Hard Work Pays Off... A Little Bit! 
 Loading... Comments 5 comments 
 Go to last comment 
 Andreas   3 years ago
 
Fantastic Hub, you have nailed the key components of restaurant marketing. Your views are similar to that at the http://www.restaurantmanagementcenter.com 
 
 GmaGoldie   21 months ago from Northern Illinois and Southern Wisconsin Level 6 Commenter 
 
Great Hub! Very intelligent use of time and money. Also, check your water bill, check for leaks - they add up! Water loss, is money out your pocket.
 
 Sun-Girl   14 months ago from Nigeria
 
Excellent hub which really hit the nail on the head, thanks for these well shared article.Am well informed now.
 
 TravelinAsia   10 months ago from Thailand/Southeast Asia Level 3 Commenter 
 
Great Advice John,

I can see that these simple yet effective strategies have contributed to your success at your own restaurant. I have not had the chance to visit lately because I live outside of town, but when I have friends traveling through CM, I will take them to your place.
 

 
 Sign in or sign up and post using a HubPages account.
 8192 characters left. Post Comment 
No HTML is allowed in comments, but URLs will be hyperlinked. Comments are not for promoting your Hubs or other sites.
 working 

 
 Like This Hub? 
Over 50 Million people discover HubPages every month.
 HubPages 
 about us blog advertise faq link to this page copyright 

Copyright©2012 HubPages Inc. and respective owners. All rights reserved.

Other product and company names shown may be trademarks of their respective owners.

HubPages ® is a registered Service Mark of HubPages, Inc.

 terms of use privacy policy (0.1 sec) HubPages Living 
 working
	</body>
</document>
