<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002295" url="http://www.theprovince.com/news/Canadian+Forces+members+appear+Nanaimo+court+knocking+fast+food+restaurant/6422597/story.html" time="2012-07-12-18:12" support="16" score="0.014005455395981633" bingtitle="Two Canadian Forces members to appear in Nanaimo court for ..." webtitle="Two Canadian Forces members to appear in Nanaimo court for knocking off fast-food restaurant">
			<query id="000436" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="000435" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="001305" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="000176" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="001057" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="000429" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="001296" bing-rank="214"/>
			<query id="001309" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000186" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000718" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000717" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="001315" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000311" bing-rank="116"/>
			<query id="001434" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="000711" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000305" bing-rank="106"/>
	<description>Calorie counters fooled by &apos;side-salad illusion&apos; ... string of charges relating to the robbery of a fast-food ... Sign up to receive e-mail alerts on breaking news from ...</description>
	<body>
		17°C Fair Vancouver 
 Detailed Forecast 
   
 Search Search 
   
 Quick Links:    Lotteries | Horoscopes | Obits 
 
 Start  Home  Delivery Subscriber  Services Digital  Edition Mobile Products 

 canada.com network 
 Newspapers 
     
 National Post Victoria Times Colonist The Province (Vancouver) Vancouver Sun Edmonton Journal Calgary Herald Regina Leader-Post Saskatoon StarPhoenix 
 
   
     
 Windsor Star Ottawa Citizen The Gazette (Montreal) DOSE Postmedia Community Publishing Nanaimo Daily News 
   
   
 The Province 
     17°C Fair Vancouver 
 Detailed Forecast 
   
   News 
 In News 
     
 Home Vancouver Fraser Valley B.C. Canada Asia Pacific World Weather Today&apos;s Paper Oddities Your Commute 
 
 Top Stories 
   
 
 
 Charge laid in 299 km/h motorcycle racing spree on... 
 The hunt for a motorcyclist who raced through four municipalities on the Trans-Canada Highway at speeds reaching 299 kilometres an hour in April appears to be over. 
 Raw video: Dangerous Victoria motorcycle ride hits 299 km/h (186 mph) Motorcycle advocate loses bid to overturn traffic ticket given for his loud pipes Motorcyclist reported missing following B.C. road trip Follow The Province on social media: Facebook, Twitter, Google+, YouTube and more Sign up for Province breaking news, sports and Canucks alerts Send us your news tips, photos, videos, eyewitness accounts Download The Province app for iPhone, iPad, Android, BlackBerry and more 
       
 Flag-Bearer 
 
 Olympic triathlon champion Simon Whitfield named Canada’s flag-bearer Christy Clark calls Enbridge&apos;s U.S. oil pipeline spill disgraceful Supreme Court: No tariffs for downloading music Victim identified in fatal two-vehicle crash on Highway 16 outside Prince George (updated) 
 
 Local News 
   
 
 
 Abbotsford Burnaby Chilliwack Coquitlam Delta Kamloops Langley North Vancouver Okanagan Richmond Surrey Vancouver Island 
   More in News     Sports 
 In Sports 
     
 Home Canucks&amp;Hockey Lions&amp;Football Whitecaps&amp;Soccer Baseball Basketball Golf MMA Tennis High School University Olympics&amp;Amateur 
 
 Top Stories 
   
 
 
 Olympic triathlon champion Simon Whitfield named Canada’s flag... 
 OTTAWA—Olympic triathlon champion Simon Whitfield will carry Canada’s flag into the opening ceremonies at the London Olympics. 
 Video: Simon Whitfield Olympic preview with Province Sports Other homegrown elite athletes from Victoria London 2012: Table tennis teen Andre Ho heading to Olympics London 2012: BMX rider Nyhaug loses spleen, wins Olympics spot 
       
 Whitecaps 
 
 Whitecaps suffer last-second defeat in Toronto Gastown Grand Prix gives thousands a thrilling cycling spectacle Davide Chiumiento leaves Whitecaps for FC Zurich I&apos;d make great backup for Canucks&apos; Cory Schneider, says UFA Dan Ellis Photos: Gastown Grand Prix 2012 Many happy returns to B.C. Lions&apos; Tim Brown and other kick receivers London 2012: BMX rider Nyhaug loses spleen, wins Olympics spot Province Sports Podcast 
 
 Sports Academy 
   
 Sports Academy 
 
 Gear to make you feel superhuman One basic principle for greatness: Live for it Sports Academy: Beware the pitfalls of social media... Sports Academy: Teaching skills for soccer and life... Sports Academy: Focus on building in the off-season... 
   More in Sports     Entertainment 
 In Entertainment 
     
 Home Movies Television TV Listings Music Downloads Books Celebrity E-list 
 
 Top Stories 
   
 
 
 Photos: Quasi-celeb Paulina Gretzky returns to Twitter with ... 
 Paulina Gretzky, first-born child of Canadian hockey royalty in Wayne Gretzky and his wife Janet Jones, once shut down her Twitter account in the wake of racy photos that made the rounds on the web -- ... 

       
 Special Event 
 
 Writer’s writer Lucinda Williams headlines Vancouver Folk Music Festival Jerry Springer at home doing live shows in Lower Mainland Lady Gaga launches social network Hot Panda less sweet and cuddly since move to East Van 
 
 Concerts 
   
 
 
 Just announced: The Bright Light Social Hour at the... Just announced: Nneka at the Rio Theatre Just announced: Owl City at the Commodore 
   More in Entertainment     Opinion 
 In Opinion 
     
 Home Blogs Murphy Animations Gordzilla Columnists Editorials Editorial Cartoon Letters 
 
 Editorials 
   
 
 
 Editorial: B.C.&apos;s health system needs huge overhaul 
 A study released yesterday into the decline in the relative availability of health-care services for B.C. seniors should serve as a warning to all of us, but particularly those in government. 

       
 
 
 Letters: Mayor, council had better start listening, readers warn. Guest Column: Finding Higgs Boson: a triumph of our curiosity Letters: Vision Vancouver, seawall, viaducts, RCMP, needle exchange, rents 
 
 Columnists 
   
 Jon Ferry
  » 
 
 Traffic congestion: Metro Vancouver second worst in... Neighbourhoods be damned: High density rules B.C. government too broke for raises — except when... 
   More in Opinion     Business 
 In Business 
     
 Home Money Small Business Markets on FP Mortgages 
 
 Top Stories 
   
 
 
 OAS cost may tally $109B by 2030 
 At a time of ballooning government debt, this is probably the last thing Ottawa wants to hear: According to a new report by Canada&apos;s chief actuary, payments to seniors by the Old Age Security program ... 
 OAS at 67 means we must save more Say goodbye to OAS at 65 Coping with OAS at 67 
       
 
 
 Chorus Aviation to buy 6 Bombardier Q400 planes Corus profit increases, revenue slides in third quarter Cline falls victim to weak coal market 
 
 Local Business 
   
 Business 
 
 Rockstar Games closes Vancouver video game studio Bolivia revoking concession against B.C. mining company... Resource estimate a golden gift for Barkerville 
   More in Business     Health 
 In Health 
     
 Home Women Men Family&amp;Child Seniors Sexual Health Diet&amp;Fitness 
 
 Top Stories 
   
 
 
 Women: anxiety will make you older, faster 
 You really can worry yourself to death, a new study suggests. Researchers who analyzed blood samples taken from 5,243 middle aged and older nurses found women who had a high &quot;phobic anxiety&quot; level had... 
 Factsheet: anxiety disorders When life hands you lemons: the new science of positive thinking Eating disorders can hit at any age: report People who are obese face higher rates of pain: study The age of rage: psychiatrists battle over teen anger diagnosis 
       
 Sexual health 
 
 Gates Foundation to pledge funds for contraception Gene that fights Alzheimer&apos;s may inspire new treatments Cribs more than 10 years old should not be used: Health Canada 
 
 Health Club 
   
 Fitness 
 
 To optimize exercise, heed your heart rate training... Calorie counters fooled by &apos;side-salad illusion&apos; No-nonsense, gimmick-free weight loss strategies that... 
   More in Health     Life 
 In Life 
     
 Home Fashion&amp;Beauty Food Parenting Relationships Education Diversions - Comics&amp;Games Mike Holmes 
 
 Top Stories 
   
 
 
 Weddings: say yes to the stress 
 Weddings are basically all the same thing: ceremony, dinner, speeches (one good, three boring, one incredibly embarrassing), dancing to Kool and the Gang and bam, you&apos;re married. But there are endless... 
 Friendship: brunch and baggage Silence is golden – and unacceptable It&apos;s hard for me to say I&apos;m sorry Decoding online dating: the monkeys are in charge What to expect when you&apos;re 31 and not expecting 
       
 Colour Stories 
 
 Colour stories - Sumptuous brown Summer fashion: affordable, but you can&apos;t be too picky Want beach waves in your hair? Tousled look easy to recreate (video) For chef Seamus Mullen, healthy eating isn&apos;t a concept - it&apos;s a survival strategy 
 
 Live It! 
   
 Diet 
 
 Barbecue smackdown: Hotdog versus hamburger Chloe Moretz: Style ambassador Dr Oz and Dr. Roizen: Meditation, de-stressing can... 
   More in Life     Technology 
 In Technology 
     
 Home Personal Tech
	</body>
</document>
