<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002962" url="http://www.menupages.com/restaurants/yoshinoya/" time="2012-07-12-19:03" support="6" score="0.017459659678256422" bingtitle="Yoshinoya - New York Restaurant - MenuPages Japanese Restaurant Search" webtitle="Yoshinoya - New York Restaurant - MenuPages Japanese Restaurant Search">
			<query id="000350" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="000978" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000987" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="000685" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000852" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="001103" bing-rank="153"/>
	<description>That I would gladly eat. The people behind the ... service was good, got my order in 3 minutes or so, interior was ok, but just like any other fast food place.</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to MenuPages - Please Select a city:

 New York City San Francisco Los Angeles Philadelphia Boston Chicago Washington, DC South Florida 
 New Menupages Desintations London   Paris 
 hide 
 
 Home Blog My MenuPages Restaurateurs Submit a Menu Change City Food Delivery Login 
 
 MenuPages 

Now Serving: 11173 Menus for New York City Restaurants
 
 Search Advanced Find-A-Food 
 
 Areas Neighborhood All Areas Brooklyn East Village/ LES Midtown East Midtown South / Chelsea Midtown West Murray Hill / Gramercy Soho/Trbca/FinDist Upper East Side Upper West Side Uptown Village/ W Village All Neighborhoods Bath Beach Bay Ridge Bedford-Stuyvesant Bensonhurst Borough Park Brighton Beach / Manhattan Beach Brooklyn Hts / DUMBO Brownsville Bushwick Canarsie Central Village / Noho Chelsea / Midtown South Chinatown / Two Bridges Cobble Hill / Carroll Grdns Coney Island Crown Heights Ditmas Park Dyker Heights East 30&apos;s East 40&apos;s East 50&apos;s East 60&apos;s East 70&apos;s East 80&apos;s East 90&apos;s East Harlem East New York East Village Financial District Flatbush Flatiron / Union Square Flatlands Fort Hamilton Ft. Greene / Clinton Hill Gramercy / Kips Bay Gravesend Harlem Kings Highway / Homecrest Lefferts Gardens Lower East Side Marine Park / Gerritsen Beach Midwood Mill Basin / Bergen Beach Morningside Heights Park Slope / Prospect Hts Prospect Park South / Kensington Sheepshead Bay Soho / Little Italy Sunset Park Tribeca Washington Hts / Inwood West 30&apos;s West 40&apos;s West 50&apos;s West 60&apos;s West 70&apos;s West 80&apos;s West 90&apos;s&amp;100&apos;s West Village Williamsburg / Greenpoint Cuisines All Cusines Afghan African American (New) American (Traditional) Argentinean Asian (other) Asian Fusion Australian Austrian Bagels Bakeries Bar Food Barbecue Belgian Bistro Brazilian British (Modern) British (Traditional) Burgers Burmese Cafes&amp;Coffeehouses Cajun&amp;Creole Californian Caribbean Central American Central Asian Cheesesteaks Chicken Chinese Cocktails Crepes Cuban Delis Desserts Dim Sum Diners&amp;Coffee Shops Dutch Eastern European Eclectic&amp;International Ethiopian Filipino Fish&amp;Chips French Gastropub German Greek Haitian Hawaiian Health Food Hot Dogs Indian Indonesian Irish Italian Jamaican Japanese Korean Kosher Latin American Local/Organic Malaysian Mediterranean Mexican Middle Eastern Moroccan New England Noodle Shops Nuevo Latino Other Pakistani Persian Peruvian Pizza Polish Portuguese Puerto Rican/Dominican Russian Salads Sandwiches Scandinavian Seafood Small Plates/Tapas Smoothies/Juice Bar Soups South American Southern&amp;Soul Southwestern Spanish Sri Lankan Steakhouses Sushi Swiss Teahouses Thai Tibetan Turkish Vegan Vegetarian-Friendly Venezuelan Vietnamese Wild Game Wine Bar Wings Street Zip code Cross street Restaurant name 
 
Hold down Control (PC) or Command (Mac) key + mouseclick to select more than one option
 
 
Yoshinoya (CLOSED)
 + SHARE 


 $ 
 Rating Avg. Dinner Entrée $$$$$ Greater than $25 $$$$ $18.01 - $25 $$$ $12.01 - $18 $$ $7.01 - $12 $ Less than $7 
 Japanese 255 W 42nd St , New York   NY 10036 40.7568339 -73.9888051 (Btwn 7th&amp;8th Ave) Subway Directions 

 
 
 Phone: (212) 703-9940 
 
 Profile&amp;Reviews Menu http://www.menupages.com/restaurants/yoshinoya/menu Report Errors Add to
My MenuPages Email 
 Facebook Twitter + MORE 
 
 
User Ratings (Based on 6 reviews) 
 2.56 5 
 Food 2.4 Value 2.8 Service 2.7 Atmosphere 1.7 
 
 Rate and Review this restaurant 
 
Other Restaurant Info
 Phone: work (212) 703-9940 Website: www.yoshinoyausa.com Notes: Delivery Take Out Cash Only Hours: Sun-Thu: 8am-3am Fri-Sat: 8am-4am Serves: Breakfast,
 
 Lunch,
 
 Dinner Features: Open Late,
 
 Delivery,
 
 Take Out 
User Reviews
 
 Yoshinoya 
 Posted by anonymous on 03/17/2011 
 
Disappointing
 
I gave this place several tries but I couldn&apos;t get over how poor the vegetables are. They&apos;re cooked in this goopy clear stuff instead of just steamed or something. I wish they would just give you an easier, more traditional rice bowl with steamed or stir fried vegies, teriyaki (beef or chicken) and rice. That I would gladly eat. The people behind the counter are idiots too, which really doesn&apos;t help. Big FAIL in my book.
 Yoshinoya 
 Posted by anonymous on 05/19/2009 
 
stay away
 
Thought I&apos;d give it a try, should have listened to powermd. Got the beef bowl w/ veg. Beef is really fatty, the veg is steamed to the point of being mushy and tasting all the same. rice is just as way overcooked. service was good, got my order in 3 minutes or so, interior was ok, but just like any other fast food place.
 Yoshinoya 
 Posted by sa on 01/08/2009 
 
yummy fast japanese food!!!!!
 
totally worth the wait. it wasnt even that long. maybe 15minutes. this place is really good for a location in times sq. the beef bowl is under $5 and can fill you up (surprisingly). if youre looking for a nice fast meal this is definitely the place to go! i also highly recommend the desserts! its not made by them, instead its prepackaged from some other distributor but its totally delicious! the cheesecake and the chocolate cake! so good and theyre cheap to add to your meal. $1.50 for each, and you get a slice. a very very decent serving for that price. i love this place. their staff works really slow but thats a goodthing because they dont have enough seating for the line but by the time you get your food you can prob find a seat! a must try!
 Yoshinoya 
 Posted by LT on 06/29/2008 
 
Japanese Fast Food
 
Yoshinoya is like a Japanese Mickey D&apos;s but instead of burgers, they serve beef bowls = thin-cut beef over rice. It&apos;s cheap and the foods good when you&apos;re looking for a quick fix.
 Yoshinoya 
 Posted by powermd on 02/15/2008 
 
Don&apos;t expect much...
 
The food here is truly no good... I&apos;m not sure what more to say. The sauce is generic and chemically, the beef is paper thin and tastes steamed. The vegetables are straight out of a frozen dinner. My expectations were low just walking in, but the food still managed to disappoint terribly.
 Yoshinoya 
 Posted by Anonymous on 01/10/2008 
 
Tasty and cheap!
 
This is 100[%] Japanese fast food. They only serve a [select] few items and all of it is unhealthy, cheap, and delicious.
 
 
 1 
 
 Rate and Review this restaurant 
 
Advertising
 
Movies near Yoshinoya
 Regal E-Walk Stadium 13&amp;RPX 
247 W. 42nd St.

New York
 The Amazing Spider-Man 3D  (PG-13) The Amazing Spider-Man  (PG-13) Brave  (PG) Brave 3D  (PG) Seeking a Friend for the End of the World  (R) Rock of Ages  (PG-13) Show More [+] More Nearby theaters» 
 Ticketing provided by
 
Hot and Fresh Restaurant News Delivered Weekly
 You are signing up to receive: Weekly updates delivered straight to your inbox covering the latest restaurant news, menus, openings, closings, and food events Menupages NYC Newsletter You may also be interested in: Hear about special offers from MenuPages or its partners about future events, promotions and features. Offers&amp;Promotions Sign Up 
Thanks for subscribing!

You will soon begin to receive the newsletters you selected.

To enjoy more benefits and personalization available on MenuPages.com, register now! 
 Checkbox is required 
Advertising
 
 About Us Careers Contact Us Advertise With Us Restaurateurs Privacy Policy Legal Notices Copyright Notice 

©2002-2012 Slick City Media, Inc. All Rights Reserved. MenuPages®is a trademark of Slick City Media, Inc. Disclaimer
	</body>
</document>
