<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002428" url="http://www.ehow.com/tips_1973.html" time="2012-07-12-18:21" support="6" score="0.011680042153795917" bingtitle="Comments on How to Tip a Waiter | eHow.com" webtitle="Comments on How to Tip a Waiter | eHow.com">
			<query id="001312" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000978" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="001292" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000412" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000163" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001449" bing-rank="140"/>
	<description>... if all you get is a simple glass of ... m tipping out %5 of your bill whether you tip me or not. If you don&apos;t want to pay for service, go to a fast food restaurant...we ...</description>
	<body>
		Discover the expert in you.
 
 home mom style food tech money health 
 
 More eHow 
 Featured: Allergies eHow Now Blog 
 eHow Culture&amp;Society Etiquette Tip a Waiter How to Tip a Waiter Comments 
 
 Comments on How to Tip a Waiter 
 
 818545181 Apr 26, 2012 When tipping I tip what ever tax is in my province (Nova Scotia) tax is 15%. I only tip if service is good I will cosider tipping more if I am wowed by service. Kathleen Nov 20, 2011 Just in case you didn&apos;t know...which many of you do not! Elvis De Leon Nov 05, 2009 Good article and advice, thanks 5* ljbinkop Aug 12, 2009 Very basic information on how to tip properly. There is SOOO much more to it. Tipping is expected in most restaurants, but not required. It should be at least 15%, but based on the service received. moleman89 Jun 28, 2009 I tip 20% of the total bill, including the sales tax, and I usually round up. Although I&apos;ve never worked in the restaurant industry, it&apos;s obvious that they work hard for their money, and their hourly rate isn&apos;t significant (and I&apos;m sure they don&apos;t get benefits, either!). Also, it helps to be polite and considerate - why would you want to be rude to someone who is handling your food? Plus, being polite and considerate makes the dining experience better for everyone involved - who knows, you may even make a new friend! graybeard52 Jun 28, 2009 If you can&apos;t afford to leave a decent&quot;tip&quot;(actually the only REAL part of a server&apos;s income) - then order a meal without dessert or have one less glass of wine, etc. Here is a&quot;shocker&quot;to those who don&apos;t work in the service industry - serveres do NOT get all of their tips - they share 20% of their eanrings(more in some restaurants) with the bussers and the bar - even if all you get is a simple glass of wine or a beer with your meal! Personaly, I eat out less due to the economy, but when I do, I almost always tip 20% - I tip more is the service is outstanding. bob52 Jun 27, 2009 Good luck with the cars. Obviously if you hadn&apos;t read the news that&apos;s not going so well. The only secure blue collar job, and for the last fifteen years, has been service. I&apos;m sorry your boss outsourced your job. If you can&apos;t tip, don&apos;t go out and eat then. It&apos;s not my fault your boss was cheap. We&apos;re not a soup kitchen. If if you&apos;d had worked in any type of service industry in the last twenty years you&apos;d noticed the majority of industrial materials are made in China/Taiwan/Vietnam. Sorry, but we don&apos;t serve food in cars and trucks. You have a stove, use it. pleasethink Jun 27, 2009 Keeping all this in mind! Hows about keeping me in mind! I&apos;m a worker here in America. I build car and trucks. I also make shoes,shirts,and pants. There was alot more things i used to make and build. Like Radios,TV&apos;s and most of your Pots and Pans that or used in these Restaurants. But now I&apos;m not able to find a good paying job. So please if everyone would look and make sure...what we buy is&quot;Made In America&quot;&quot;Built In America&quot;maybe i will find a job. I know we can not find certain thing that are not&quot;In America&quot;so then don&apos;t buy it. It will not take long before the message gets back to the&quot;People In Power&quot;(so to speak).I&apos;m not buying unless your product is&quot;Made r Built In America&quot;.Bring back these jobs and i will buy your product. Then i can go out and give that 20% tip to person who is doing a very hard job(dealing with customers). Everything goes&quot;Hand To Hand&quot;as they say. So... farah999 Jun 26, 2009 I agree. It&apos;s 2009. If you&quot;tip&quot;(because we all know by now that it is indeed the servers PAY and not a&quot;tip&quot;, as no one can live on $2.13 an hour...) less than 20%, I would not recommend returning. katia76 Jun 16, 2009 15% is SO outdated. I&apos;ve waitressed for the past 10 years and my tips are almost always at least 20%. I&apos;ve worked in a pub and fine dining and it&apos;s 20% no matter where you are. Chaos1187 May 31, 2009 Most people don&apos;t realize that waiters/esses salaries are only like $2 and thats why we tip. Good article gretad08 May 05, 2009 If you&apos;re a good server you can make a decent living. That is not an excuse, however, to be a lousy tipper. I don&apos;t care whether you tip 15 or 20% but, include the taxes in your figuring. That&apos;s a silly rule that I&apos;ve never heard before and I worked in restaurants all through high school and college. dlturko Nov 17, 2008 Does anyone realize that when server wages haven&apos;t changed in 20 years? That when Minimun wage goes up, that servers wages don&apos;t! That some resteraunts don&apos;t compensate their other employees, (hostest, bus people or bar tenders), that they increase the amount that servers have to tip out. Also, at the end of every year the government expects servers to make at least 10% of their sales and if their $2.and some cents don&apos;t cover the amount state taxes, they will OWE the state money at the end of the year! Yes, it is people decision to work in a resteraunt and it can be decent money, but so often servers are overworked, underpaid and underappreciated. They have to multi-task, deal with the kitchen, customers, the phone and so many things at once and who know what kind of day they might have had before they have to come to work. Keep that in mind next time you or someone your with decid Havyn08 Oct 29, 2008 I&apos;ve never worked in a restaurant for these exact reasons. The pay seems awful. It seems risky to base your income on an optional tip payment that is not guaranteed. Yes, I said it... tipping is optional. So I&apos;m led to wonder, if it&apos;s so terrible, terrible, terrible, and you&apos;re paying out of pocket to serve people meals, WHY DO YOU DO IT? There must be something great about it, or people wouldn&apos;t do it. Don&apos;t talk like you&apos;ve been forced to work in food service and you&apos;re oh so poor because people don&apos;t tip you $20 on a $40 check. If you hate it so much and you&apos;re in such dire financial straits, for God&apos;s sake go work at Wal Mart where at least you know how much money you&apos;re going to make.

For the record, I&apos;m a great tipper when I receive great service. I&apos;ve had servers before who took my order and then never came back. The food was brought out by someone else, the drinks wer lazyboy Sep 19, 2008 At Benihana servers only pocket about $2 every $10 dollars you tip. We have to tip out 8% of our sales to the chefs that gave you the show. So if you tip 10%, we get to split the 2% between 2 servers, 1 busser, bartenders and kitchen helpers. If your check is $200, and you tip $20, about $15 goes to chefs, and $5 splits so many ways I&apos;ll probably keep $1 for serving you for 2 hours. If you leave $0 tip, I have to pay the $15 to the chefs out of my own pocket. Please keep this in mind you benihana goers... waitress Apr 08, 2008 If you&apos;re a bad tipper, it cost me to serve you. I tip out 5% of my sales every night to our bartender, host, busboy , and&apos;temp shift&apos;servers (which covers us when we go on a break)

So if you don&apos;t tip me at all then it cost me to serve you. 15% is courtesy...because even though alcohol is expensive, and you got that free entree coupon, it still means that I&apos;m tipping out %5 of your bill whether you tip me or not. 

If you don&apos;t want to pay for service, go to a fast food restaurant...we get paid the same hourly rate. You don&apos;t tip there because they don&apos;t wait on you and serve you. If you want to go to a sit down restaurant, be prepared to tip. I always have considered gratuity when ordering...even before I worked in a restaurant. 

Some people tip well, 20%...but that extra 5% helps make up for the tips I&apos;ve been stiffed on. Most of the time it&apos;s not because of bad serv waitress Apr 08, 2008 If you&apos;re a bad tipper, it cost me to serve you. I tip out 5% of my sales every night to our bartender, host, busboy , and&apos;temp shift&apos;servers (which covers us when we go on a break)

So if you don&apos;t tip me at all then it cost me to serve you. 15% is courtesy...because even though alcohol is expensive, and you got that free entree coupon, it still means that I&apos;m tipping out %5 of your bill whether you tip me or not. 

If you don&apos;t want to pay for service, go to a fast food restaurant...we get paid the same hourly rate. You don&apos;t tip there because they don&apos;t wait on you and serve you. If you want to go to a sit down restaurant, be prepared to tip. I always have considered gratuity when ordering...even before I worked in a restaurant. 

Some people tip well, 20%...but that extra 5% helps make up for the tips I&apos;ve been stiffed on. Most of the time it&apos;s not because of bad serv waitress Apr 08, 2008 If you&apos;re a bad tipper, it cost me to serve you. I tip out 5% of my sales every night to our bartender, host, busboy , and&apos;temp shift&apos;servers (which covers us when we go on a break)

So if you don&apos;t tip me at all then it cost me to serve you. 15% is courtesy...because even though alcohol is expensive, and you got that free entree coupon, it still means that I&apos;m tipping out %5 of your bill whether you tip me or not. 

If you don&apos;t want to pay for service, go to a fast food restaurant...we get paid the same hourly rate. You don&apos;t tip there because they don&apos;t wait on you and serve you. If you want to go to a sit down restaurant, be prepared to tip. I always have considered gratuity when ordering...even before I worked in a restaurant. 

Some people tip well, 20%...but that extra 5% helps make up for the tips I&apos;ve been stiffed on. Most of the time it&apos;s not because of bad serv waitress Apr 08, 2008 If you&apos;re a bad tipper, it cost me to serve you. I tip out 5% of my sales every night to our bartender, host, busboy , and&apos;temp shift&apos;servers (which covers us when we go on a break)

So if you don&apos;t tip me at all then it cost me to serve you. 15% is courtesy...because even though alcohol is expensive, and you got that free entree coupon, it still means that I&apos;m tipping out %5 of your bill whether you tip me or not. 

If you don&apos;t want to pay for service, go to a fast food restaurant...we get paid the same hourly rate. You don&apos;t tip there because they don&apos;t wait on you and serve you. If you want to go to a sit down restaurant, be prepared to tip. I always have considered gratuity when ordering...even before I worked in a restaurant. 

Some people tip well, 20%...but that extra 5% helps make up for the tips I&apos;ve been stiffed on. Most of the time it&apos;s not because of bad serv tipmehard Jan 14, 2008 This article is WRONG. Yes, it is correct in stating that you calculate the tip based on the pre-tax total, but it is WRONG in stating that you then add this tip to the same pre-tax total to calculate your total payment. You must add your tip to the OVERALL BILL so that the server gets the appropriate amount in his/her pocket. Example:
Your bill at CPK is $100 plus 8% California tax and totals $108. The waitress was hot so you decide to tip her 20%. You calculate the tip as 20% of the
pre-tax total of $100 which is $20( $120 total).
THE PROBLEM WITH THIS is that the waitress only gets $12 to stuff in her bra. $100 goes to CPK and $8 goes to Uncle Sam, leaving her with only $12. She thinks you&apos;re cheap and doesn&apos;t give you her phone number.
Therefore, if you want to do the naked tango with her, you must ADD THE 20% TIP TO
THE OVERALL BILL SO THAT SHE GETS 20% IN HER POCKET. Tuftex23 Nov 11, 2007 If you were un happy with your service , don&apos;t be a smart alik and leave a penny or somthing like that. I would rather get no tip than a smak in the face like that. Tuftex23 Nov 11, 2007 If you were un happy with your service , don&apos;t be a smart alik and leave a penny or somthing like that. I would rather get no tip than a smak in the face like that. Tuftex23 Nov 11, 2007 TO ALL OF THOSE CUSTOMERS OUT THERE: If you go to a restraunt, and it is busy. Remeber that you are not the only table that your server has to take care of, and if you see them walk by the table and do not stop, it is probably beacuse they are doing somthing for another table. Please do not make their tip any less because your server was busy. On the other hand if you see your server standing around doing nothing and they haven&apos;t been to you table they are just being lazy and not doing their job. Tuftex23 Nov 11, 2007 I have been a server for four year, I enjoy my work, I enjoy most of the people. But keep in mind that at most small busnesses(Like where I started serving) You server is not only that, but you cashier, busser and dish washer. I did all of that for 2.63 and hour. So keep in mind that at leats 15% is apreciated. Tuftex23 Nov 11, 2007 I have been a server for four year, I enjoy my work, I enjoy most of the people. But keep in mind that at most small busnesses(Like where I started serving) You server is not only that, but you cashier, busser and dish washer. I did all of that for 2.63 and hour. So keep in mind that at leats 15% is apreciated. 

 1 2 3 4 5 Next 
 
More Articles Like This

 How to Make Sure the Waiter&apos;s Tip Gets to the Waiter When You Leave Importance of Tips for Waiters on How to Treat Customers Tips on Uncorking Wine With a Waiter&apos;s Corkscrew How to Be a Waiter Without Experience How to Determine Tips Allocated for Waiters&amp;Waitresses How to Report Restaurant Tips as Income in Financial Statements How to Estimate Tips for Waiters How to Be a Better Waiter How to ID Customers as a Waiter Knowing Your Alcohol as a Waiter 
 
Related Ads
 ehow.com 
 About eHow eHow Blog How to by Topic How to Videos Sitemap 
 
Copyright©1999-2012 Demand Media, Inc.
Use of this web site constitutes acceptance of the eHow Terms of Use and Privacy Policy . Ad Choices en-US
	</body>
</document>
