<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002751" url="http://www.zazzle.com/krystal_stacked_tshirt-235243716435134917" time="2012-07-12-18:48" support="1" score="0.002023214303087677" bingtitle="Krystal Stacked Shirts from Zazzle.com" webtitle="Krystal Stacked Shirts from Zazzle.com">
			<query id="000726" bing-rank="103"/>
	<description>... just a small sampling of the uncountable number of ... famous krystal, hamburger, fast food, restaurant, southern, ... Track My Order; Safe Shopping Guarantee</description>
	<body>
		Skip to content 
 Sign in  
 My Account Track My Order Order History 
 Wishlist 
 
Loading...
 
 Cart 
 Free Shipping On Orders Over $50 
 Click for Code 
 Shop Departments  
 
Loading...
 
 Create  
 
Loading...
 
 Gift Center T-Shirts 
 Search Today ONLY: 50% Off Stickers , Buttons &amp; Magnets For Zazzle&apos;s Birthday!   Use Code: ZBDAYFLAIR50    See All Birthday Deals Front Back Full Front Full Back 
Basic Dark T-Shirt
 Comfortable, casual and loose fitting, our heavyweight dark color t-shirt will quickly become one of your favorites. Made from 6.0 oz, pre-shrunk 100% cotton, it wears well on anyone. We’ve double-needle stitched the bottom and sleeve hems for extra durability. Imported. 
Dark Grey
 
Adult L
 Read more... 
Promoted in the hamburger shop section on Zazzle, this awesome guys&apos;t shirt idea was created by&quot;krystalburger&quot;. With a t-shirt title of “krystal stacked tshirt”, this darkgrey hamburger tee shirt represents just a small sampling of the uncountable number of beautiful famous ideas offered online at Zazzle. The designer named&quot;krystalburger&quot;appropriately dubbed this basic men&apos;s zazzle dark shirt the krystal stacked tshirt, you can discover other similar tee shirts by searching through the community marketplace for the tags:&quot;famous krystal tshirts&quot;,&quot;hamburger tshirts&quot;,&quot;krystal tshirts&quot;, or&quot;famous tshirts&quot;.

Very long-lasting and affordable, the guys&apos;basic dark tshirt is profoundly adored by our users all over the world. With a basic shape, this t-shirt style offers a very nice look for any guy or gal who is wearing it. In reality, this krystal stacked tshirt will feel positively dynamite to wear as well. If you are unsatisfied by your darkgrey famous krystal t-shirt, Zazzle will take it back, 100% guaranteed.
 In Stock • Ships in 3-5 business days • 100% Satisfaction • No Setup Fees • No Minimum Orders • Highest Quality • No Hassle Returns 
We&apos;re sorry, there are problems with your information.
 Hide all issues 
Krystal Stacked Shirts
 4.2 (939 reviews) 
 Size: Select a size 
 
 Save on Apply Only more on Apply 
 
 Quantity:
	</body>
</document>
