<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002976" url="http://www.catalogs.com/info/bestof/top-10-facts-about-fast-food-and-culture" time="2012-07-12-19:04" support="9" score="0.04511657600889281" bingtitle="Top 10 Facts about Fast Food and Culture - Catalogs.com - Order ..." webtitle="Top 10 Facts about Fast Food and Culture">
			<query id="000776" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000040" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000751" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000353" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000855" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="001317" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000767" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="000189" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="001514" bing-rank="93"/>
	<description>Not if you work in a fast food restaurant! You will spend 8- to 12 ... I could barley carry the tray. I am not joking it ... How to listen to radio online; Making the most of ...</description>
	<body>
		Loading 
 Home Info Library About Us 
 
 Best of Business 
 Advertising Careers Catalog Marketing Education Job Search 
 Celebrate 
 Holidays Parties Weddings 
 Culture 
 Art Books Celebrities Games and Toys Movies Music Offbeat TV Video Games 
 Home 
 Decor Drink Entertaining Food Garden and Lawn Home Improvement Housekeeping Moving Safety 
 Lifestyle 
 Family Fitness Health Parenting Relationships Self Help Spirituality 
 Recreation 
 Crafts Hobbies Outdoors Sports 
 Science 
 Animals Environment Nature Tech and Electronics 
 Shop 
 Beauty Fashion Gift Giving Personal Care 
 Travel 
 Autos Motorcycles Places Vacations 
 
 Browse &gt; Home / Food / Top 10 Facts about Fast Food and Culture 
Top 10 Facts about Fast Food and Culture

Written by: Matt Sherman
October 23, 2008
Filed Under Food  
 
 Tags: food 
Oh, the mixed joys of fast food and culture! Now, those are two guilty pleasures for most people. Fast food culture is sometimes inane, sometimes clever.

I used to work in the retail food industry. May I point out some pitfalls and possibilities for all you fast food junkies (oops, I mean“consumers”) out there?

 

#10 Weight Gain: Fast Food is deadly

Not if you work in a fast food restaurant! You will spend 8- to 12-hour shifts on your feet serving hundreds of ravenous, fast-moving customers. Employees typically earn only one or two meal breaks per shift. Managers grab a mere snack on their feet at times.

When I worked fast food, I lost weight, eating small meals like an athlete in training. 

The truth is you can eat sensible fast food. Check menu and portions—you can go smart as with Taco Bell’s food, getting vegetarian items inside your meal but modest portions of beef or poultry.

#9 Culture Shock: Fast food doesn’t care for culture

Instead, McDonald’s and other chains adapt in their markets to suit local culture internationally. Hamburger joints overseas use only the best beef and freshest vegetables—their European customers wouldn’t tolerate less—though better ingredients drive price and menu upward. I love shrimp salad or fresh pasta with my burger in France or Italy.

In Israel, McDonald’s proffers falafel to win points. It’s in other countries where McDonald’s fast food and culture has promoted anti-Semitic spokesmen and drawn criticism.

#8 Super Size Me: Americans know what fast food to eat

We can’t often justify fast food splurges. I once managed a shift where a man ordered $42 worth of fast food before choosing Diet Pepsi for a drink as he“didn’t need the calories”. Out of sight, the shift workers laughed so hard I thought I’d call an ambulance.

In restaurants food costs is of concern so expect less care taken then at home and choose wisely.

#7 Good Times, Bad Tastes: There isn’t any good fast food

On the contrary, I know fast food chains serving only real sour cream, real beef, fresh ingredients and spices, and controlling portions with customers eating truly healthful and enjoyable meals. Ask for a nutrition guide then let your fingers do the eating.

#6 Slow Food Is Safest: Germs and food

85 percent of food-borne illnesses are transmitted at home, not restaurants! Most restaurants follow codes ensuring frequent washing and sterilization of utensils, and general cleanliness throughout the restaurant, kitchen and food packaging.

There is 24-hour or longer incubation period for food-borne illness. Most sick people assume last night’s local restaurant was to blame, even when it wasn’t.

 #5 Empty Culture:“Losers”work fast food

It was my privilege to work with truly gifted folks in fast food. Collegiates and older folks returning to school late in life, young people working hard apart from teen parties with drinking and drugs, savvy managers who know more about sales and hospitality than most people I know…

…Some fine civic leaders started in fast food. Many went on to manage restaurants or even whole chains of food franchises.

#4 Wants: People choose fast food for quantity and low price

Studies confirm that“fast foodies”are in restaurants for the same reason as others, with service and cleanliness the top priorities. I am thinking“dollars and food”when I go fast, but apparently, two-thirds of consumers are thinking“ambiance”instead. Go figure.

 #3 Iron Chefs: Gourmet diners dine on gourmet fast food

A recent survey of top chefs proved a stunner. The overwhelming choice for top chefs on breaks from a hot stove? The Big Mac . Yup, McDonald’s basic burgers on sugary buns with onions and not other items?

Not In-N-Out Cheeseburgers (I’m drooling into my keyboard right now)? Not tacos from Taco Bell , Del Taco or Jack In The Box ? Not something-or-other with jalapenos and Monterey Jack from Wendy’s ? Not tempting selections from Zagat-rated Chick-fil-A , Dairy Queen or Carl’s Jr. ?

I’m rethinking whether those“top chefs”are indeed top chefs at all.

#2 Nice and Easy: Making fast food is no big deal

It can be easy and pleasant work, until that day when you are scheduled for 8 workers on shift and 3 show up. All the customers will still visit!

A typical fast food restaurant requires two hours only to start all cash and operating equipment, open the kitchen and fry, heat and chop over 40 different food items to plan for nearly 50 menu items plus substitutions.

You also have to be skilled to get a dozen items out a drive-thru window in 45 seconds or less at three in the morning.

#1 America Merges: Fast food is taking over the culture fast

Maybe. Perhaps Starbucks , Wal-Mart and McDonald’s will finally merge together, dominating the landscape with countless food and item stores called“Mc Star-Mart’s”or“Wal-Bucks Donald’s”.

I pray fervently at times for America.
 Tweet 
 
 ( 12 votes, avg: 4.17 / 5)
  Loading ... 
 

 
Suggested Online Food Stores

 Fresh Diet BulkFoods Gourmet Foods Fruit Company® 
 
Comments
 
 10 Responses to“Top 10 Facts about Fast Food and Culture” 

 Laura on
 December 16th, 2008 6:36 pm 
Wow, it’s amazing how many people interpret their personal experience and call it fact as the title of this article demonstrates. In addition, no one seems to question where the person got some other information.
 Cassandra on
 March 23rd, 2009 11:10 am 
what was wrong with the information listed? i am writing a paper on this right now, and it seems pretty acurate.
you cant seriously support fast food..?
 Alex on
 March 26th, 2009 6:44 pm 
Great article, totally loved the last section, and it’s all accurate.
 dumby on
 August 23rd, 2009 7:27 am 
In America everything is nice.
 Mattias on
 November 25th, 2009 8:18 am 
Well while i agree with pretty much everything stated here,“FACT”does tend to come with references, at least thats how it works in my University. So mebbe you should change the title to“Observations”rather than“Fact”. On the other hand howerver i really enjoyed reading it and i Agreed with most everything. Im currently writing a marketing paper where i try to enter the Brittish market with“Healthy”instant microwave meals. On the other hand, theres nothing stopping me from referencing you, seeing as you are“published”on the internet. Who am i to question your sources, plus if it sounds beleivable i doubt my professor is going to go through the trouble of checking out my references. Ironic isnt it. :P
 Dean on
 March 1st, 2010 5:04 am 
I could absolutely ramble for hours about the global fast food chains, though this is not going to achieve anything. I think this site is valuable in that some really good conversations could take place in respect of a“healthy balance towards”that evil food called‘fast food”. What shocked me recently was being asked if I wanted to“up size”to the“super size”I had not heard this from my country. I said yes thinking it was just a slight upgrade. OK, OK I was very hungry and I had not had“Macas”for months. I was so embarrassed when the EXTRA EXTRA large French Fries and the COKE was handed to me. I could barley carry the tray. I am not joking it was disgusting. I have learned one thing though, not all McDonalds in every country is the same, nor is KFC. I will ask for details of sizing the next time I venture into the famous McDonalds.
 Matt Sherman on
 June 17th, 2010 1:57 pm 
I’m the article’s author. Thanks for the comments. My“facts”come from managing five fast food restaurants. :)
 Fast Food Culture«Jude Research Blog on
 August 12th, 2010 7:13 am 
[...] Top 10 Facts about Fast Food and Culture By MATT SHERMAN–October 23, 2008 http://www.catalogs.com/info/bestof/top-10-facts-about-fast-food-and-culture [...]
 stylo mont blanc on
 April 24th, 2011 8:07 pm 
you have a nice blog your blog is very nice。
 sean on
 January 13th, 2012 8:54 am 
awesome survey about fast food
 http://www.kwiksurveys.com?s=OCDNOG_a1b4d3da 
 

 Got something to say? 
 
 Name (required) 
 

 Email Address (required) 
 

 Website 
 

 Speak your mind 
 

 

 Notify me of followup comments via e-mail 
 
Suggested Online Food Stores

 Fresh Diet BulkFoods Gourmet Foods Fruit Company® 

 
 
Most Recent Tops 10s

 Best of…finishing touches in fashion Top 10 Weird Vocabulary Words Best of…creative water gardens Top 10 Things To Do During Summer Best of…feeding a crowd Top 10 Clothing Tips for Men Best of…first apartment checklist Best of…how to fix bra problems Best of…decorating with style Best of…efficient computer setups 
 
Latest Info Articles

 How much exercise does a dog need? How to accessorize office fashion Is it dinner or supper Scrapbook ideas for couples What to wear the first day of school 
 
 
Copyright©1997-2012
 
 catalogs.com  |  whowhatwherewhenwhy.com  |  About Us  |  Privacy Policy  |  Terms&amp;Conditions  |  Site Map  | BLOGS: Blog - e-Marketing  |  Let&apos;s Talk Style  |  IWantItDaily.com  | 
 RSS Feeds  |  onlinecatalogs.com  |  Email Catalogs.com  |
	</body>
</document>
