<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002932" url="http://www.insiderpages.com/b/15239995854/fazolis-italian-resturant-huntington" time="2012-07-12-19:01" support="15" score="0.05813222874848393" bingtitle="Fazolis Italian Resturant - Huntington - Insider Pages ..." webtitle="Fazolis Italian Resturant - Huntington">
			<query id="001004" bing-rank="48"/>
			<query id="000358" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="001009" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="001488" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="000891" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="000608" bing-rank="10"/>
			<query id="000221" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000234" bing-rank="17"/>
			<query id="001519" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000226" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000595" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="001016" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="000108" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000096" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="001111" bing-rank="69"/>
	<description>What other fast food Restaurant gives anything away free, besides drinks? I am a marathon runner so my food selections are always ... stand and hope to see an empty table ...</description>
	<body>
		join sign in 
 Find Near Browse Categories 
recommendations that matter most 
 Health&amp;Medical Home&amp;Garden Hair&amp;Beauty Auto
 Services Pets follow us Advertise With Us 
 Huntington, WV &gt; Restaurants &gt; Italian Restaurants &gt;Fazolis Italian Resturant 

 

 

 

 
Fazolis Italian Resturant
 ★★★☆☆ 3 Reviews Write a Review 
304-697-9908
 1310 Third Ave. Huntington , WV 25701 

 
 Add Photo Edit Business Claim Business 
 
About Fazolis Italian Resturant
 Categories 
 Italian Restaurants 
 
Food
 More choices in Huntington: 
 Rocco&apos;s Ristorante 
252 Main St Ceredo, WV
 
 Tascali&apos;s Decades Pasta&amp;Grl 
6007 Us Route 60 E Barboursville, WV
 
 Reviews 
 
Insider Pages Reviews for Fazolis Italian Resturant

Have experience with this business? Write a Review. 
 ★★★★★ The Other Reviewers Are Crazy! Great Food and Free Internet Access. 
 Sara G. 5 Fazolis Italian Resturant 
 
What other fast food Restaurant gives anything away free, besides drinks? I am a marathon runner so my food selections are always made based on health. This Restaurant Chain home cooks their pasta and the customer can choose any entree with or with out meat. Vegetarians do not have to be limited to salads! This location also offers a gourmet Italian Espresso Coffee Bar! While other fast food locations try to catch up to Fazoli&apos;s forward thinking, I love the &apos;extra&apos;s&apos; given to me at no charge. Free drinks and unlimited breadsticks offered in an modern setting. Everyone who wants healthy choices finally has a place to dine!
 February 17, 2007 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★★☆☆☆ Not a Happy Customer 
 Meg R. 2 Fazolis Italian Resturant 
 
Today I went to Fazoli&apos;s a FAST food place and the service was unexceptable. They messed up my order charged me too much and then I had to wait 15 minutes for them to credit me back $2.00. They couldn&apos;t just add on another item and let me call it even. The whole event really didn&apos;t make me mad until I was leaving and they didn&apos;t even say&quot;I&apos;m so sorry about that you have a great day&quot;They said nothing but&quot;we voided the first transaction and charged you for your original order. Keep your reciept to make sure it went through your bank.&quot;The weren&apos;t friendly at all and I really don&apos;t think they even had a clue what was going on. I will never go there again.
 January 29, 2007 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 ★★☆☆☆ Poor Service 
 Barbara S. | Insider Expert
| Rank: 2,845 2 Fazolis Italian Resturant 
 
The food at this restaurant is fairly good for quick Italian food. The problem is one of seating. The building has limited seating, and there is no arrangement for orderly service. You just stand and hope to see an empty table you can grab. There is no place to sit while you wait, and there&apos;s a series of small rooms. It is very hard to find someone leaving before another takes advantage of this opportunity. One time we waited until we scored a table, but the next time we got tired of the game and left to eat elsewhere. We never returned.
 November 29, 2006 
 Report Abuse 



Was this review helpful to you?
 Write a Review Get Map&amp;Directions 
Modify or Try Another Search For:
 
Italian Restaurants - Huntington, WV
 Find Near Home | About Us | FAQ | Blog | Help/Contact Us | Feedback | Store Finder | Doctor Finder | Sitemap | Privacy Policy (updated) | Terms &amp; Conditions ©2004–2012 Insider Pages. All rights reserved. Partner Sites: MyAutismTeam | Ask Answers | Ask Kids | Life123 | Citysearch | MerchantCircle | Urbanspoon
	</body>
</document>
