<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002942" url="http://www.ciao.co.uk/sr/q-dominos+pizza" time="2012-07-12-19:02" support="6" score="0.01997685314235929" bingtitle="Dominos Pizza - Prices, Offers &amp; Tests of Dominos Pizza" webtitle="Dominos Pizza - Prices, Offers&amp;Tests of Dominos Pizza">
			<query id="000808" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000981" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="000790" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="000996" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000999" bing-rank="204"/>
			<query id="000811" bing-rank="248"/>
	<description>Fast Food Restaurant, Pizzeria, Take-away (On Ciao since: 02/2003) Offers by eBay &gt; ... We have about 4 or 5 different Dominos pizza places in this town, and some are ...</description>
	<body>
		Join Ciao | Login | Help | Mobile 
 
 Browse by category 
 Appliances 

 Books 

 Cameras 

 Cars 

 Computers 

 Electronics 

 DVDs 

 Music 

 Phones 

 Travel 

 More 
 
Ciao - for people with opinions

 
 Latest reviews Write a review 
 
 Latest questions Latest videos 
 
 
 
 ALL RESULTS Shopping Offers Reviews FILTER BY CATEGORY 
 Travel (66) 
 Europe (66) 
 France (21) 
 Paris (13) 
 Paris Restaurants (13) 
 Lyon (3) 
 Lyon Restaurants (3) 
 Toulouse (3) 
 Toulouse Restaurants (3) 
 Bordeaux (2) 
 Bordeaux Restaurants (2) 
 
 United Kingdom (33) 
 Manchester (8) 
 Manchester Restaurants (8) 
 Glasgow (7) 
 Glasgow Restaurants (7) 
 Leeds (6) 
 Leeds Restaurants (6) 
 Edinburgh (5) 
 Edinburgh Restaurants (5) 
 Belfast (3) 
 Belfast Restaurants (3) 
 Birmingham (2) 
 Birmingham Restaurants (2) 
 Other Destinations in United Kingdom (2) 
 United Kingdom Restaurants (2) 
 
 Ireland (11) 
 Dublin (5) 
 Dublin Restaurants (5) 
 Limerick (2) 
 Limerick Restaurants (2) 
 Galway (1) 
 Galway Restaurants (1) 
 Cork (1) 
 Cork Restaurants (1) 
 Other Destinations in Ireland (1) 
 Ireland Restaurants (1) 
 Waterford (1) 
 Waterford Restaurants (1) 
 
 Spain (1) 
 Madrid (1) 
 Madrid Restaurants (1) 
 
 
 
 Education&amp;Careers (1) 
 Careers&amp;Placements (1) 
 Employers (1) 
 Employers C-F (1) 
 
 
 Food&amp;Drink (1) 
 Food&amp;Health (1) 
 Chain Restaurants (1) 
 
 
 ALL RESULTS &gt; Shopping &gt; Results for &quot;Dominos Pizza&quot; 
Shopping»
 
 
 Results on ciao.co.uk Results in online shops Special Offers 
 

 1 - 20 of 68 results for &quot;Dominos Pizza&quot; sort by: Popularity | Price | Rating | Date 
 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza 
 
(+) Very tasty food, consistantly high quality, ability to order online ... more 
 (+) Very tasty food, consistantly high quality, ability to order online too. (-) Somewhat more expensive than some other places. (*) (On Ciao since: 06/2001)
... less 
 




 
 
 User reviews (50) 
 
 Food&amp;Drink &gt; Food&amp;Health &gt; Chain Restaurants 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza 
 
(+) Flexability of working hours, Tips, Not being stuck in one working ... more 
 (+) Flexability of working hours, Tips, Not being stuck in one working environment, Mates can come to work (-) Wear and tear on car, Delivering to some dodgy areas, Average Pay, Mistakes come out of your own pay check, Some rubbish managers (*) (On Ciao since: 12/2006)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (7) 
 
 Education&amp;Careers &gt; Careers&amp;Placements &gt; Employers &gt; Employers C-F 
 
 Dominos Pizza , Manchester 
 
(+) Great food. Good delivery- Always hot and on time (Unlike pizza hut). ... more 
 (+) Great food. Good delivery- Always hot and on time (Unlike pizza hut). Meal Deals (-) The internet ordering facility doesn&apos;t yet allow you to do meal deals. (*) (On Ciao since: 02/2006)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (2) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Manchester &gt; Manchester Restaurants 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza , Chelmsford, Essex 
Fast Food Restaurant, Pizzeria, Take-away (On Ciao since: 02/2003)


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (1) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Leeds &gt; Leeds Restaurants 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza , Colchester 
Take-away, Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant (On Ciao since: 02/2002)


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (1) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Other Destinations in United Kingdom &gt; United Kingdom Restaurants 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza , Guistey 
Take-away, Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant (On Ciao since: 03/2004)


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (1) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; United Kingdom &gt; Other Destinations in United Kingdom &gt; United Kingdom Restaurants 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza , Limerick 
 
Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: 56 The Orchards, Castletroy, ... more 
 Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: 56 The Orchards, Castletroy, Limerick (On Ciao since: 04/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; Ireland &gt; Limerick &gt; Limerick Restaurants 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza&apos;s , Limerick 
 
Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: 2 Mount Kenneth pl Henry Street, ... more 
 Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: 2 Mount Kenneth pl Henry Street, Limerick (On Ciao since: 04/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; Ireland &gt; Limerick &gt; Limerick Restaurants 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza , Alsia, Paris 
 
Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - 23 Rue Sarrette, 75014 Paris, ... more 
 Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - 23 Rue Sarrette, 75014 Paris, FranceAddress: (On Ciao since: 04/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; France &gt; Paris &gt; Paris Restaurants 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza , Auteuil, Paris 
 
Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - 1 Rue Bosio, 75016 Paris, FranceAddress: ... more 
 Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - 1 Rue Bosio, 75016 Paris, FranceAddress: (On Ciao since: 04/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; France &gt; Paris &gt; Paris Restaurants 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza , Monceau, Paris 
 
Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - 58 Rue Legendre, 75017 Paris, ... more 
 Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - 58 Rue Legendre, 75017 Paris, FranceAddress: (On Ciao since: 04/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; France &gt; Paris &gt; Paris Restaurants 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza , Commerce, Paris 
 
Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - 134 Rue Thtre, 75015 Paris, ... more 
 Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - 134 Rue Thtre, 75015 Paris, FranceAddress: (On Ciao since: 04/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; France &gt; Paris &gt; Paris Restaurants 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza , Tallaght, Dublin 
 
Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: The Square, Tallaght, Dublin (On ... more 
 Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: The Square, Tallaght, Dublin (On Ciao since: 04/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; Ireland &gt; Dublin &gt; Dublin Restaurants 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizzas , Ennis 
 
Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: Parsons Quay, Ennis (On Ciao ... more 
 Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: Parsons Quay, Ennis (On Ciao since: 04/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; Ireland &gt; Other Destinations in Ireland &gt; Ireland Restaurants 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza , Washington Street, Cork 
 
Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: 26a Washington Street, W, Cork ... more 
 Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: 26a Washington Street, W, Cork (On Ciao since: 04/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; Ireland &gt; Cork &gt; Cork Restaurants 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza , Prospect Hill, Galway 
 
Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: Prospect hill Eyre sq, Galway (On ... more 
 Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: Prospect hill Eyre sq, Galway (On Ciao since: 04/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; Ireland &gt; Galway &gt; Galway Restaurants 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza , Reuilly Picpus Garden Center, Paris 
 
Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - 204 Rue Charenton, 75012 Paris, ... more 
 Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - 204 Rue Charenton, 75012 Paris, FranceAddress: (On Ciao since: 04/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; France &gt; Paris &gt; Paris Restaurants 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza , Porte De Vanves, Paris 
 
Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - 97 Rue Didot, 75014 Paris, FranceAddress: ... more 
 Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - 97 Rue Didot, 75014 Paris, FranceAddress: (On Ciao since: 04/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; France &gt; Paris &gt; Paris Restaurants 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza , Level 1 The Square, Dublin 
 
Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: Level 1 The Square, Tallaght, ... more 
 Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: Level 1 The Square, Tallaght, Dublin (On Ciao since: 04/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; Ireland &gt; Dublin &gt; Dublin Restaurants 
 
 Domino&apos;s Pizza , 2 Roseville Terrace, Dublin 
 
Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: 2 Roseville Terrace, Dundrum, ... more 
 Pizzeria, Fast Food Restaurant - Address: 2 Roseville Terrace, Dundrum, Dublin (On Ciao since: 04/2010)
... less 
 


   Offers by eBay &gt; 

 
 
 User reviews (0) 
 
 Travel &gt; Europe &gt; Ireland &gt; Dublin &gt; Dublin Restaurants 
 
 
(*) Reviews by Ciao members
 
 1 2 3 4 



 Next page 
 
Offers»

 1 - 4 of 4 results for&quot;Dominos Pizza&quot; sorted by: Popularity | Price 

 
 AMERICAS BEST VALUE INN, Tomball 
AMERICAS BEST VALUE INN, Tomball
 
 
WELCOME TO AMERICAS BEST VALUE INN AND SUITES TOMBALL,CONVENIENTLY LOCATED ONE MILE WEST OF HIGHWAY 249 ON FM2920.KNOWN FOR BEING THE HOMETOWN WITH A HEART,...... more 
 WELCOME TO AMERICAS BEST VALUE INN AND SUITES TOMBALL,CONVENIENTLY LOCATED ONE MILE WEST OF HIGHWAY 249 ON FM2920.KNOWN FOR BEING THE HOMETOWN WITH A HEART, TOMBALL OFFERSALL OF ITS VISITORS FRIENDLY HOSPITALITY WITH PLENTY TO SEEAND DO. OUR TOMBALL, TX HOTEL IS NEAR THE LONE STAR COLLEGEAND TOMBALL COLLEGE. LOCAL MUSEUMS INCLUDE THE PEARL FINCHERMUSEUM OF FINE ARTS, WOODLANDS CHILDRENS MUSEUM, SPRINGHISTORICAL MUSEUM, AND CIVIL WAR MUSEUM. ENJOY SOME SHOPPINGAT THE VINTAGE PARK SHOPPING CENTER, WILLOWBROOK MALL, ANDHOUSTON PREMIUM OUTLETS. HARRIS COUNTY SMOKEHOUSE,CHICK FIL A, AND DOMINO S PIZZA ARE JUST A FEW OF THERESTAURANTS LOCATED A MILE FROM OUR HOTEL. START YOUR DAYRIGHT WITH OUR FREE CONTINENTAL BREAKFAST. APPRECIATE THECONVENIENCE OF OUR ON SITE GUEST LAUNDRY FACILITY. STAYCONNECTED WITH FREE WIRELESS HIGH SPEED INTERNET ACCESS INOUR COMMON AREAS AND GUEST ROOMS. RELAX AND UNWIND IN THEPRIVACY OF YOUR OWN GUEST ROOM WITH AMENITIES INCLUDING AMICROWAVE, MINI FRIDGE, COFFEEMAKER, FLAT PANEL SATELLITE TVWITH HBO AND ESPN, HAIRDRYER, IRON, IRONING BOARD, DESK WITHLAMP, CLOCK RADIO, FREE LOCAL CALLS, AND WAKE UP SERVICE.UPGRADE YOUR STAY BY BOOKING ONE OF OUR SUITES ORKITCHENETTE GUEST ROOMS. CHILDREN AGE 11 AND YOUNGER STAYFREE IN THEIR PARENTS ROOM WITH EXISTING BEDDING. OUR FRONTDESK AND LOBBY ARE OPEN 24 HOURS/DAY. AT AMERICAS BEST VALUEINN AND SUITES TOMBALL, WEVE GOT YOU COVERED FROM THE TIMEYOU HIT THE ROAD UNTIL YOUR HEAD HITS THE PILLOW..
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  refer to website 
 Availability :  Price is per double room per night and may vary depending on date booked... £ 34.08 Visit Shop  &gt; hotels.com 
 AMERICAS BEST VALUE INN, Canton 
AMERICAS BEST VALUE INN, Canton
 
 
WELCOME TO THE AMERICAS BEST VALUE INN OF CANTON,MISSISSIPPI. WE ARE EASILY ACCESSIBLE VIA INTERSTATE 55. OURHOTEL IS LESS THAN TWO MILES FROM THE CANTON FLEA...... more 
 WELCOME TO THE AMERICAS BEST VALUE INN OF CANTON,MISSISSIPPI. WE ARE EASILY ACCESSIBLE VIA INTERSTATE 55. OURHOTEL IS LESS THAN TWO MILES FROM THE CANTON FLEA MARKET,ANNUAL HOT AIR BALLOON FESTIVAL, CANTON MISSISSIPPI TRAINMUSEUM, AND THE CANTON MULLTICULTURAL CENTER AND MUSEUM. OURPROPERTY IS ALSO NEAR SEVERAL OTHER POPULAR ATTRACTIONSINCLUDING THE CANTON MOVIE MUSEUM, UNIVERSITY OFMISSISSIPPI, AND NORTH PARK MALL. WHILE VISITING THEAMERICAS BEST VALUE INN CANTON, BE SURE TO TAKE ADVANTAGEOF THE NUMEROUS RESTAURANTS IN THE SURROUNDING AREAINCLUDING EL SOMBRERO MEXICAN RESTAURANT, TWO RIVERSRESTAURANT, WESTERN SIZZLIN OF CANTON, BLUES FISH HOUSE,DRAGONS GARDEN, AND STONE PONY OYSTER, BAR ALONG WITHSEVERAL OTHER FAST FOOD FAVORITES SUCH AS MCDONALDS, KFC, PIZZA HUT, AND DOMINO S PIZZA . .AMERICAS BEST VALUE INN OFCANTON, MISSISSIPPI FEATURES 40 SPACIOUS EXTERIOR CORRIDORROOMS. ALL GUEST ROOMS ARE GENEROUSLY EQUIPPED WITH HI SPEEDINTERNET ACCESS, CABLE TV WITH HBO, MICROWAVES,REFRIGERATORS, HAIRDRYERS, IRONS, IRONING BOARDS, ANDCOMPLIMENTARY LOCAL CALLS. ALL OF OUR GUESTS ARE INVITED TOENJOY A VARIETY OF AMENITIES INCLUDING OUR DELICIOUSCOMPLIMENTARY CONTINENTAL BREAKFAST, COMPLIMENTARYNEWSPAPER, FAX/COPY SERVICES, VENDING MACHINES, AND ICEMACHINES. OUR HOTEL ALSO FEATURES A SEASONAL OUTDOOR POOL.OUR FRIENDLY STAFF, AFFORDABLE RATES, AND COMFORTABLEACCOMMODATIONS ARE SURE TO PLEASE EVERYONE. COME SEE US THENEXT TIME YOU VISIT THE HISTORIC CITY OF CANTON. ..
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  refer to website 
 Availability :  Price is per double room per night and may vary depending on date booked... £ 37.86 Visit Shop  &gt; hotels.com 
 AMERICAS BEST VALUE INN, Rifle 
AMERICAS BEST VALUE INN, Rifle
 
 
AMERICAS BEST VALUE INN WELCOMES YOU TO PICTURESQUE RIFLE,COLORADO, NESTLED AT THE BASE OF THE BOOKCLIFFS, NAMED FORLINES OF SEDIMENT AND SHALE THAT RESEMBLE...... more 
 AMERICAS BEST VALUE INN WELCOMES YOU TO PICTURESQUE RIFLE,COLORADO, NESTLED AT THE BASE OF THE BOOKCLIFFS, NAMED FORLINES OF SEDIMENT AND SHALE THAT RESEMBLE THE PAGES OF ABOOK. WE ARE CONVENIENTLY LOCATED OFF OF I 70 EXIT 90 IN THEHEART OF THE GROWING RIFLE, COLORADO COMMERCIAL AREA. THECITY IS ALSO A HAVEN FOR NATURE ENTHUSIASTS AND OUTDOORSMEN.ENDLESS RECREATIONAL OPPORTUNITIES INCLUDE HUNTING FOR ELKAND DEER, FISHING, CAMPING, HORSEBACK RIDING, HIKING, ANDMOUNTAIN BIKING. COME SEE WHY RIFLE, COLORADO IS RANKED 17THOF THE TOP 200 TOWNS FOR SPORTSMEN/OUTDOORSMEN AND 27TH OFAMERICAS BEST HUNTING AND FISHING TOWNS. OR EXPLORE RIFLEFALLS, VOTED 6TH OF THE TOP WATERFALLS TO VISIT. WE AREWITHIN WALKING DISTANCE TO RESTAURANTS, FAST FOOD, ANDSHOPPING. THE HISTORIC DOWNTOWN AREA, MUNICIPAL AIRPORT, ANDCOMMUNITY COLLEGE ARE ONLY MINUTES AWAY. WHETHER HERE FORBUSINESS OR LEISURE, YOULL APPRECIATE THE OLD WEST FEEL ANDSCENIC WONDERMENT THAT IS RIFLE, COLORADO. .WAKE UP EARLYAND ENJOY A HEARTY CONTINENTAL BREAKFAST COURTESY OFAMERICAS BEST VALUE INN RIFLE. SERVED BETWEEN 5AM 9AM, OURCONTINENTAL BREAKFAST FEATURES CEREAL, DONUTS, MUFFINS,BAGELS, ENGLISH MUFFINS, TOASTER WAFFLES, AND COFFEE. LOCALRESTAURANTS INCLUDE DOMINOS PIZZA , RIB CITY GRILL, BASECAMP CAFE, THAI CHILI BISTRO, AND FIESTA GUADALAJARA..AMERICAS BEST VALUE INN RIFLE OFFERS EXCEPTIONAL VALUE ANDQUALITY SERVICE IN THE PERFECT SETTING. YOU WILL ENJOY THEQUAINT ACCOMMODATIONS AND OUR FRIENDLY STAFF. ALL ROOMS AREEQUIPPED WITH FREE WIRELESS INTERNET ACCESS ALLOWING GUESTSTO STAY CONNECTED IN THE PRIVACY OF THEIR OWN ROOM. GUESTROOM AMENITIES INCLUDE MICROWAVES, MINI FRIDGES,COFFEEMAKER, AND SATELLITE TV WITH SHOWTIME. PLEASE CALL USDIRECTLY TO RESERVE OUR KITCHENETTE ROOMS AND VISIT OURWEBSITE AT WWW.REDRIVERINN.COM. AT AMERICAS BEST VALUE INNRIFLE, WEVE GOT YOU COVERED FROM THE TIME YOU HIT THE ROADUNTIL YOUR HEAD HITS THE PILLOW..
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  refer to website 
 Availability :  Price is per double room per night and may vary depending on date booked... £ 48.28 Visit Shop  &gt; hotels.com 
 Jane&apos;s Games Fraction Dominoes (ages 6-11) 
Jane&apos;s Games Fraction Dominoes (ages 6-11)
 
 
These games familiarise children with fractions, and reinforce what fractions mean. The dominoes are played the same way as conventional...... more 
 These games familiarise children with fractions, and reinforce what fractions mean. The dominoes are played the same way as conventional dominoes . Instead of matching the same number of dots, these dominoes involve matching different examples of the same fraction. A given fraction is illustrated in different ways: as a number; as a picture of a familar object, such as half an apple or pizza for example; or as a diagram. There are four games in the box, each at a different level of difficulty. Set 1: Halves, quarters, thirds and fifths (age 6-7). Set 2: Sixths, eighths and twelfths (age 8-9). Set 3: Equivalent fractions: halves, quarters, thirds and fifths (age 9-11). Set 4: Equivalent fractions, percentages and decimals: halves, quarters, fifths, eighths and tenths (age 10-11). The equivalent fractions help to explain how the same value may appear in different forms. So, in set 3, 1/2 can be matched with 2/4, 3/6, 4/8 and 5/10, for example. Set 4 introduces the idea that the same value can appear as a fraction, as a decimal or as a percentage. So, 1/2 can be matched with 0.5 and 50% as well as with half a chocolate bar, for example.
... less 
 

 



 Postage&amp;Packaging :  £2.75 
 Availability :  Usually dispatched within 1-2 business days... £ 6.50 Visit Shop  &gt; amazon marketplace toys 
 
(*) Reviews by Ciao members


 
Related tags for Dominos Pizza»
 domino&apos;s pizza domino&apos;s pizza ireland domino&apos;s pizza europe domino&apos;s pizza france dominos pizza uk domino&apos;s pizza uk dominos pizza glasgow domino&apos;s pizza takeaway 
Reviews»

 
 Roll the Dice and land here (Domino&apos;s Pizza) 

 Advantages: Very tasty food, consistantly high quality, ability to order online too.
 Disadvantages: Somewhat more expensive than some other places.


...Dominos pizza has got to be my favourite way of indulging in a pizza. I don&apos;t know what it is that they do which is so different to everyone else, but I honestly can say I&apos;ve not eaten a better pizza from anyone else ever. 

We have about 4 or 5 different Dominos pizza places in this town, and some are definitely better than others in terms of service and speed, however the quality of the pizzas is almost (I have to say this as we did have one that was a bit problematic) always the same really good high standard. 

Dominos stores are all take away. They do deliver too, recently bringing in new hours so that they will deliver all the way through the night till 5am which is a crazy time to want to eat pizza unless you&apos;ve just been out clubbing, and sadly my clubbing days are well and truly over lol, but I can imagine back in the past I...

 vialdana 
 01.01.1970 Read review 
Ciao members have rated this review on average very helpful 
Review of Domino &apos;s Pizza 
 
 overpriced pizza 

 Advantages: easy to order
 Disadvantages: expensive


...Domino&apos;s Pizza has over 8,700 stores in over 60 countries. 
Tom Monaghan opened the first Domino&apos;s Pizza place in 1960 in the USA. The first store opened in the UK in 1985. This surprised me as I thought they had been around the UK longer than this as people rave so much about the pizza&apos;s. 
Tom joined forces with his brother and together they opened a pizza delivery store in Michigan. They named it DomiNicks. A year later, Tom traded his Volkswagen Beetle car for his brother&apos;s share of the store and later renamed his business Domino&apos;s Pizza. 

I have to ask are they worth the money? A small basic cheese and tomato pizza costs 8.99 which is 6 slices and I think around the 9-10 inch size. If I order this from a local takeaway I expect to pay around 3.50. 

So why is Domino&apos;s so special that people will pay more than twice the cost? 
My...

 rojm 
 01.01.1970 Read review 
Ciao members have rated this review on average helpful 
Review of Domino &apos;s Pizza 
 
 Dominates my pizza experience (Domino&apos;s Pizza) 

 Advantages: Extremely tasty
 Disadvantages: Location of stores


...~~~Domino&apos;s Pizza~~~
Im not sure about you but I love a good slice of pizza. We don&apos;t actually eat a lot of takeaway unless we have had a bad day at work and can&apos;t be bothered cooking or we fancy a nice night in on a weekend.

Our personal favourite has to be Domino&apos;s and here&apos;s why:


~Location:
Unfortunately for us we have never had a Domino&apos;s nearby that would deliver, if you have a Domino&apos;s nearby its worthwhile checking if they deliver instead of just presuming they do.

Our nearest was in StHelens which is 3.9 miles from our home but we are out of their delivery scope, were not lazy so driving there is not a problem but the location of the shop is for parking etc.

Within the last year Domino&apos;s opened in Widnes which is 5.9 miles from our home however even though the distance is much greater they include our area in their delivery...

 clumsy221 
 01.01.1970 Read review 
Ciao members have rated this review on average helpful 
Review of Domino &apos;s Pizza 
 
 
 About Us - 
 Jobs
 - 
 Advertise with Us
 - 
 Press
 - 
 Become a Partner
 - Ciao Quality Seal Ciao Deutschland - Ciao France - Ciao Italia - Ciao España - Ciao Nederland - Ciao Sverige Site Index - Ciao Charts - Most searched products - Data Protection 
 ©2012 Shopping Guide GmbH
	</body>
</document>
