<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002189" url="http://www.kidsparkz.com/food.html" time="2012-07-12-18:05" support="14" score="0.07218018243372494" bingtitle="Food preschool theme" webtitle="Food preschool theme">
			<query id="000252" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000896" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000167" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000430" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="000413" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000176" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000425" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000181" bing-rank="154"/>
			<query id="000164" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="000170" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000264" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000416" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000419" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000261" bing-rank="137"/>
	<description>Food. Here is a collection of activity pages and games ... order_by_size_2_cookies.pdf ... You will receive a confirmation email - just click on the ...</description>
	<body>
		KidSparkz Home 
 
 Preschool for the Year 
 
 Toddler for the Year 
 
 What&apos;s New? 
 
 Monthly Curriculums 
 
 Jumbo Pack 1 Collection 
 
 Jumbo Pack 2 Collection 
 
 Compare Collections 
 
 Theme-a-Pedia Printables 
 
 Learning Focus Printables 
 
 Alphabet 
 
 Numbers 
 
 BIG Theme Units 
 
 Skillbuilders Collection 
 
 Games and Flashcards 
 
 The Power of Reading! 
 
 Log-in Resource Room 
 
 Subscribe Resource Room 
 
 Preschool Sings Index 
 
 FAQ 
 
 Links 
 
 About Us and Contact 
 
 
 Food 
 

 

    
 
 Food 

 Here is a collection of activity pages and games to make that co-ordinate with the early childhood theme Food, and can be used when planning activities and curriculum for young children.    Download instantly, in Adobe PDF format. Print using the fast draft setting if you wish to save colored ink. 
 
   

 Flashcards_vegetables.pdf 

  24 large photo flashcards/color  
 
  

   Flashcards_fruit.pdf    

 20 large photo flashcards/color 
 
 

 Bread_Flashcards_Set.pdf 

24 large photo flashcards/color   
   Food pictures for sorting .   Cut out large pictures for dairy; meat chicken and fish; fruit and vegetables; bread rice and pasta. use for sorting, discussion etc. Also included a set of&quot;junk&quot;food to compare.    This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
 Preschool Sings!    

 - a HUGE free collection of the words to many familiar and new songs to use when creating curriculum activities for young children 
 order_by_size_2_cookies.pdf 3 pages     Food_theme_poster.pdf    
   

which is different?

 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
 
 

     Food backgrounds   

  7 pages to cut up and use for art collage and other projects 
 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room         
border shopping.   
 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
   

tracing.   

 Trace the bag; draw food or glue packet and can labels 
 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
   

puzzle.   

 6 pieces - print 2 copies, cut up one and match to the other 
 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
   

Food predicting

 What will happen? 
 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
   

Food predicting 2   

 Tell the story 
 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
   

predictable list fave foods   
 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
      

poster - coloring fruit.

 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
 
   

poster - coloring vegetables

 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
 
      

pie making

 Create a filling - cut out top crust and cover pie 
 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
      

picture story starter   
 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
 
 
  math mats table

  2 pages - make sets of food on the table 
 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
   

large pictures for games

 10 pages 
 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
   

Emergent readers

 What Tastes Delicious? 2 readers, one with pictures. Each reader has 5 full pages, 9 reader pages. 
 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
   

eating together

 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
 
   

discussion - breakfast.

 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 

 
 
   

creative coloring broccoli

 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
 
     

Food chant
 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
    

complete the pattern.   
 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
    Food conversations

 This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room 
     Connect the dots   This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room   
     
 Food tracing 2. This activity is in the KidSparkz Resource Room   Food_flashcards.  general   (general) 5 pages Use for matching, sorting, vocab, recognition, sight reading etc 
   

 Food_alphabet.  7 pages 
   
 
   
 
 If you like this category you might also like:   Fruit   Vegetables Farms APPLES Preschool Theme Curriculum 
  Basic Skills - PUMPKINS Cookies 
  Complete Curriculum for the Year (download)    - this is our most popular curriculum, and is also available recorded on a CD (over 2100 pages)
 
 
 
 Tons of additional activity pages in the KidSparkz Resource Room – new pages added every week. 

 Member Log-in&gt;&gt;&gt; 

 New subscribers and more information&gt;&gt;&gt; 
 

 
 
 
     
 
 
     KidSparkz Sitemap 
 Main Categories  Popular Themes Popular Themes     Popular Themes Popular Themes Popular Activities   Customer Service    Home Preschool Curriculum  by month Themes  Theme-a-Pedia Printables  by Learning Focus Alphabet Numbers Jumbo Pack 1 Jumbo Pack 2 Collection  (BIG!) ChildCare Providers Literacy Activity Packets Skillbuilders Collection Yearly curriculum   for Preschool Yearly curriculum for Toddlers Preschool Theme Units Art,Scienceand  SongBooks  The Power of Reading! Games and Flashcards    Compare curriculum collections Subscribe to Resource Room Log-in to Resource Room What&apos;s new? HUGE Song Collection 
   
 5 Senses Action Heroes African Animals   Air  Airplanes Amphibians Animals  Alphabet Ants    Apples   Arbor Day    Arctic Animals 
 Australian 

 Animals 

 Babies 
 Back_to_School Baking    Ballet Baseball   Bats    Beach    Bears    Bicycles    Birds Birthdays    Boats    Bubbles    Butterflies   Camping    Cars    Castles    Cats Chickens    Chinese Lunar Christmas Cincode  Mayo    Circus    Cityand  Country  Clowns Colors Community  Helpers Construction Workers Cookies Cooking Corn    Costumes Cows Dinosaurs   Dogs Ducks Earth_Day Easter Eggs Elephants Fairy Tales Fall Family Father&apos;s Day Farms Favorite Book Favorite Things Fire Safety Fish Flowers Food Forest Animals Friends Frogs Fruit Gardens Gingerbread Grandparents Groundhog Halloween     
 Hands 

 Hanukkah 

 Harvest 

 Health&amp;Nutrition 

 Hibernation 

 Homes 

 Horses 
 
 Ice Cream 
 
 Insects 
 4th_of_July Kangaroos Koalas Ladybugs Leaves   Light Lions Living Things Magic Magnets Maps M_L_King Masks Mice Mittens Money Monkeys Mothers Day    Neighborhood New Year Night Sky Numbers Nursery Rhymes Nuts Ocean    Owls Pancakes Patterns Penguins Pets Picnics Pigs Pizza Popcorn Pumpkins Puppets Quilts Rain Rainbows Rainforest Restaurant   
 

 Rocks 
 Scarecrows Seasons Shadows Shapes Shells Shoes Signs (neighborhood ) Snakes Snow Space Spiders Spring Squirrels St Patricks Day Strawberries Summer Sun Supermarket Teddies Teeth Thanksgiving Tools&amp;Machines Toys Trains Transportation Treasure Hunting Trees Umbrellas   Vacations  Valentines   Vegetables   Water   Watermelons Weather Whales Wheels Wind Winter   Winter Olympics Zoo 
   
 Story Starters      Emergent r eading Cut and Paste Poems and RebusRhymes   Dot to dots Mazes Cut and Paste Puppets Creative coloring pages Bookmarks Lotto cards Sequence creating patterns Flashcards Word walls Large flashcards Page Borders Masks&amp;Stick Puppets Math Mats    Tracing   Puzzles  Categorizing  Pre-Writing Number Grids Alphabet activities Alphabet Cut and Paste Addition math mats Art templates Visual Discrimination   
 
 FAQ   Links   About Us Contact Us Return Policy   Articlescurriculum   Compare curriculums Newsletters   Privacy Policy     Book List 
 
 
 If you would like to receive an email whenever we add NEW printables, manipulatives and other teaching tools to the site, please fill in your email address, read the Privacy Policy and click send.  You will receive a confirmation email - just click on the link given in the email and you&apos;re set. You can unsubscribe at any time. Subscribe to the Newsletter I have read and agree to the Privacy Policy 
   

   This is a BIG site. Use this form to find whatever you are looking for on the KidSparkz site . 

 Search the KidSparkz website for: 
 
        Share this page to Facebook 

 Tweet 

 Email 

   Copyright 2006-2012 KidSparkz.com
	</body>
</document>
