<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002867" url="http://wrestlegirl.com/diet.htm" time="2012-07-12-18:56" support="12" score="0.02512192606797498" bingtitle="The Wrestler Diet" webtitle="">
			<query id="001100" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="000849" bing-rank="151"/>
			<query id="000859" bing-rank="243"/>
			<query id="001257" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="000367" bing-rank="217"/>
			<query id="000347" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="000856" bing-rank="221"/>
			<query id="000723" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="001254" bing-rank="162"/>
			<query id="001120" bing-rank="213"/>
			<query id="000869" bing-rank="144"/>
			<query id="001277" bing-rank="213"/>
	<description>CONDIMENTS, FATS, AND OILS Avoid the use of oils and products packed ... It is difficult to choose a high-carbohydrate meal at a fast food restaurant. Beware or you can eat ...</description>
	<body>
		The
Wrestler Diet 

 AGuide
to Healthy Weight Control 

Follow safe and effective ways of controlling your weight by
incorporating HCG into
your diet.

Wrestlers who cut weight often
deny themselves the very nutrients they need to perform well. Many
wrestlers either don&apos;t care about proper nutrition or they simply do
not know any better. Wrestlers often think of food and water only in
terms of gaining weight. They forget that food provides nutrients to
fuel their bodies. However, the scientific facts are simple: poor
nutrition will hamper performance. The body cannot function at its best
when it lacks vital nutrients. Consider these points:


* Concentrating on wrestling
rather-than on cutting weight will make you a better wrestler.


* To grow naturally and
increase strength, wrestlers need the same nutrients as other
teenagers, but need more calories to meet the demands of daily training.


* Fasting causes the body to
use muscle proteins for energy even if fat is available. This limits
muscle growth and strength development.


* A proper diet will help
wrestlers&apos; lose fat weight without sacrificing muscle tissue or
becoming dehydrated.


* Dehydration is a major cause
of losses in strength and endurance.

 * Losing weight rapidly results
in a loss of both muscle tissue and water.


* Losing weight gradually (2-3
Ibs/week) is the best way to lose fat and keep muscle.


* Proper training includes
practicing proper nutrition eve/y day.


* Practicing good nutrition and
proper weight control methods is vital to achieving peak physical
performance.

 wrestlers
who cut weight oftendeny themselves the very nutrients they need to
perform well, The body cannot function at its best when it lacks vital
nutrients. 

 PRINCIPLES OF GOOD
NUTRITION 

 Cutting
and Maintaining Weight 

Once you&apos;ve determined your
weight class, you should next develop a. plan for making and maintaing
the weight. Plan your diet to lose not more than 2-3 poun~ each week.
For example, if you determine you want to lose 10 pounds, allow at
least 5 weeks (2 Ibs.lweek) to accomplish your goal. If you plan ahead,
the gradual reduction in weight can be easily accomplished. Also, to
achieve your goal, you must understand the principles of good nutrition.

 Food
Pyramid 

Wrestlers can achieve a
balanced diet by following the. dietary guidelines provided in the food
pyramid. The training table guidelines listed below indicate the
minimum number of servings from each food group for each day. The menus
in Appendix A show examples of these recommendations.

The pyramid is divided into 4
levels according to the needs of your body. The base of the pyramid
contains foods &apos;including grains such as oats, rice and wheat, and the
breads, cereals, noodles and pasta made from them. Try to choose 6-11
servings of these products each day io ensure a solid. foundation for
your diet. Foods from this group are high in complex carbohydrates,
which are the main energy source for training and other body functions.

The next level of nutrition in
the food pyramid includes foods from the vegetable and fruit groups.
These foods. include all fresh,&apos; frozen, canned and dried fruits and
vegetables and juice. These groups are loaded with vitamins and
minerals, carbohydrates and fiber. It is recommended that.your diet
consists of 3-5 seryings of vegetables and 2-4 servings of fruit each
day to ensure an ample supply of vitamins, minerals and carbohydrates.

The next level of nutrition in
the food pyramid consists of 2 food groups: the dairy products,
including milk, yogurt and cheese; and the meat products, including
meat, poultry, fish, dry beans, eggs and nuts. These groups are rich in
proteins, calcium, zinc, iron, and vitamins, and are essential for
healthy bones and muscles. Choose low fat dairy products and lean (low
fat) meat products to get the full advantage of these foods without
excess&apos; fat calories. Your diet should include 2-3 low fat servings
from the dairy group each day, as well as 2-3 servings from the meat
group each day. Appendix A give some examples.
The top of the food pyramid includes nutrients that should be used
sparingly in your diet, including fats, oils, and sweets. Many of these
nutrients are already present in foods previously discussed and are
often added in processed foods. Be careful in your selection of foods
and check food label for added sugars and fats that can add calories to
your diet without significantly
increasing their nutritional value.
 


 Determining.
Your Wrestling Weight 

 Figure
1 . 
 Determine the minimum number of
calories for your goal weight. 


 

 NUTRIENTS 

Your body depends upon a
constant supply of nutrients to keep it functioning. There are six
essential groups of nutrients your body needs everyday: water,
carbohydrates, protein, fats, vitamins, and minerals. These nutrients
work together to build and fuel for your body.


 WATER 

The most important nutrient for
any athlete is water. Your body is 60-70% water. Water is absolutely
essential for optimal health and peak performance. You may be surprised
to know that dehydration is a major cause of decreased performance.
Some wrestlers are more sensitive to dehydration than others. A fluid
loss of 2-3% of your
weight can quickly occur during intense training. Even modest levels of
dehydration . should be avoided because dehydration harms performance.
It is important to drink plenty of fluid during practice and between
matches. Not only will you feel better, but you may also find you have
more endurance. During physical activity, thirst is not an adeqiJate
signal ofneed for fluid. Follow the fluid guidelines listed below:


 * Weigh-in
before and after training to monitor fluid loss. Drink two cups of
fluid for every pound of body weight lost.


 * Drink 2 1/2 cups of fluid 2 hours before training or competition.


 * Drink 1 1/2 cups of fluid 15 minutes before competition.


 * Drink
1 cup of fluid every 15-20 minutes during training and competition.


 * Avoid beverages containing alcohol and caffeine, as they promote
dehydration.

 


 EATING BEFORE
TRAINING
OR COMPETITION 

When you eat can often be as
important as what you eat before competition and between. matches in a
tournament. When you eat a regular meal, it takes about three hours for
the food to be completely digested and absorbed. As a result, meals are
best eaten three to four hours before competition. For athletes too
nervous to consume solid foods before competition, special sports
nutrition supplements may be an option. Carbohydrate supplements and
liquid-nutrition supplements can be taken up to one hour before
training or competition, but you should experiment with such products
to make certain that you do not experience discomfort. A
properly-formulated sports drink can be qonsumed before, during, and
following training or competition to help minimize dehydration and
provide a source of energy to working muscles.

 METHODS
OF WEIGHT CONTROL THAT SHOULD BE AVOIDED 

 Dehydration 

Weight loss in wrestling
usually occurs in a short period of time and consists primarily of
water loss. If you lose weight faster than 2-3 pounds per week, you are
likely losing water (and perhaps muscle tissue). Unfortunately, when
you rehydrate after weigh-in, your body absorbs water at a relatively
slow rate: only about 2 pints per hour, and it takes up to
48 hours for the water balance in your tissues to be restored. The ill
effects of dehydration
include a decrease in muscular strength and endurance, a decrease. in
blood flow to mu.scle tissues, &apos;and an impaired ability to properly
regulate your body temperature. Therefore, it is recommended that:

* Wrestlers should limit weight
loss by dehydration to a bare minimum.


* Use of diuretic drugs (&quot;water
pills&quot;) to help lose water weight should be avoided. These drugs can
cause disorders in the way your heart and kidneys function.


* Wrestlers should not rely
upon sitting in a steamroom or sauna to cut.weight. Exercise in a
plastic suit should also be avoided. These practices are strongly
discouraged because they can cause rapid dehydration and heat stroke,
which may be fatal.

 Weight loss in wrestlers usually occurs
in a short period of time and consists primarilly of water loss. If you
lose weight faster than 2-3 pounds per week, you are likely losing
water (and perhaps muscle tissue). 
 
 

 SUGGESTIONS TO
REDUCE
BODY FAT 


 BEHAVIOR
MODIFICATION 

1. Diets dont work. If any one
diet worked, there wouldn&apos;t be any fat people. A lifesyle of exercise
and a balanced diet are the key to maintaining a good muscle-to-fat
ratio.


2. Reduce the total number of
calories eaten by eating smaller portions at meals.


3. Do not skip meals. This will
only slow your metabolism down and make it more difficult to lose fat.


4. Reduce the total number of
calories eaten by eliminating snacks.


5. Eliminate eating late at
night; because you will be inactive these calories will only be stored
as fat.


6 A large person can
successfully lose approximately 2-3 pounds of fat per week. If&apos;you lose
weight any faster than that, you may begin to lose muscle, as well as
strength. Losing fat needs to be a slow, gradual process.


7. For each pound of fat you
want to lose, you have to eliminate 3500 calories. You should do this
with a
combination of diet and exercise.


8. The fastest and perhaps the
easiest way to lose weight is with a combinaitori of diet and exercise.
If you eat 500 calories less and exercise 500 calories more, you could
burn up 1000 calories per day.
At this rate, you could lose two pounds in a week.


9. Drink 4-6 eight ounce
glasses of water a day.


10. Omit or limit
alcoho!consumption.


11. Read labels when shopping.
Low fat does not always mean low or no fat. Look for nonfat or fat free.


 FOODS
TO EAT. FOODS TO AVOID.&amp;PREPERATION 


 MEATS 
Buy lean cuts of red meats (flank steak, venison and diet lean
hamburger)
Keep servings to moderate size (4-6 oz)
Only consume red meat once or twice a week
For lunch meats use turkey, chicken, tuna (no oil), and 96% fat free
ham and turkey ham. Don&apos;t fry meats: bake, broil, boil, grill, poach,
steam and barbecue/grill


 CHICKEN
AND FISH 
Remove skin from chicken before cooking and grill or bake. Do not fry.
Use white meat (breast) instead of dark meat (legs and thighs)


 DAIRY
PRODUCTS 
Use nonfat milk instead of whole, 2%, and 1%.
Use kraft fat free cheese instead of regular cheddar cheese Use egg
whites and nonfat egg beaters instead of egg yolks Use nonfat yougurt
instead of regular yogurt


 CONDIMENTS,
FATS, AND OILS 
Avoid the use of oils and products packed in oil (I.e. tuna) .
Use Kraft fat free mayonnaise and miracle whip instea of regular or
light
Use Kraft fat free salad dressings instead of regular or low fat
stir frying or sauteing use water, chicken or beef broth instead of oil.
 
 Rev Up Your
Metabolism 


 Ways
to speed up your metabolism to burn more calories: .
 

1.) Always eat-breakfast
Skipping breakfast sends the message to your body that you&apos;re
starving because you haven&apos;t had food in 18 hours or so: As a
protective measure, your
metabolism slows down. Food fuels your metabolism.


2.) Eat earlier in the day.
Reseach has demonstrated that you can lose weight and boost your
metabolism simply by eating a substantial breakfast and lunch and a
light dinner. Dinner
should be eaten as early as possible, preferably at least 4 hours
before bedtime.


3.) Never eat less than 1,200
calories a day. Fewer calories are usually not enough to support
your base metabolism, so your metabolism slows down.


4.) Snack frequently. Choose
fruits and vegetables for snacks and boost you fat burning capability
Also, snacking prevents you from becoming too hungry. The hungrier you
are, the less control you have oyer what-and how much you eat.


5.) Eat food in it&apos;s simplest
form. The less processed food is, the fewer calories it will have and
less of the Galories come from fat.


6.) Do some type of aerobic
exercise.


7.) Look for opportunities to be active. Park as far from the store as
you can. Use the stairs.

8.) Avoid alcohol. Alcohol depresses your metabolsim and stimulates
your appetite.


9.)Drink more water than you
have to. Your metabolism needs plenty of water to function properly.
Carry a bottle with you and sip frequently throughout the day.


10.) A void the three Ps:
Pills, Powders, and potions. People who try quick fix weight loss
usually end up devastating their metabolism. There are no quick fixes.


 


 EATING OUT WISELY 

You can maintain your training
diet when eating at a restaurant if you are careful about
what you order. Pay attention to how foods are prepared. Choose food
that is baked, broiled, boiled, or poached. Avoid food that is breaded,
fried, or served in gravy. Limit your use of butter, margarine,
mayonnaise, sour cream, cream cheese, and regular salad dressings.
Instead, use barbeque sauce, ketchup, mustard, relish, and vegetables
for toppings. Do
. not be afraid to ask for food served &quot;your way;&quot; ask for extra
vegetables in sandwiches or on pizza, skip the extra cheese or extra
meat, request skim or 2% milk, and specify the topping you want.
When you know you will be eating out, carefully choose low-fat foods
for your other meals that day. Also, take along your own fresh fruit to
munch on after the meal instead of ordering desserts.
When eating a meal at a fast food restaurant, don&apos;t make it a dietary
disaster. A typical fast food meal is high in fat and low in calcium,.
vitamin C, and vitamin A. It is difficult to choose a high-carbohydrate
meal at a fast food restaurant. Beware or you can eat half of your
caloric allotment in one meal.

 

 HOW TO CALCULATE YOUR
MINIMUM BODY WEIGHT 

1. To Calculate Your Fat
Weight:
Multiply your weight in pounds by your percent fat (as a decimal). For
example, if
you weigh 140 Ibs. and are 12% fat:
140XO.12=16.8 lbs of fat

2. To Calculate Your Lean Body
Mass:
Subtract your fat weight from your body weight:
140-16.8=123.2 Ibs. of lean body mass (LBM)

3. To Calculate Your Minimum
Wrestling Weight:
Divide LBM by .93:
123.2divided by.93=132~5 Ibs. of body weight at 7% fat

4. To Calculate Your Maximum
Fat-Weight Loss:
Subtract your calculated body weight from your present weight:
140-132.5=7.5 Ibs. of fat weight to lose

 Appendix A- sample
menus and snacks
: 2000 Calories 

 Nutrition
Page 2 
 

 Copyrighted by: RogerV. Landry, M.A.
Robert A. Oppliger, Ph.D. Ann C. Shetler, R.D., L.D. Gregory L. Landry,
M.D. 


 Distributed
by:
State CIF Office
664 Las Gallinas Ave.
San Rafael, CA 94903 415-492-5911/FAX 415-492-5919 www.cifstate.org
	</body>
</document>
