<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002499" url="http://www.jmr-marketing.com/user/705/Fast_Food_Sales/" time="2012-07-12-18:33" support="1" score="0.0009702040696071549" bingtitle="Fast Food Sales - March 2010 - JMR Japan Consumer Marketing Research" webtitle="Fast Food Sales - March 2010">
			<query id="001107" bing-rank="70"/>
	<description>Japan&apos;s Non-consuming Consumers ... Fast Food Sales Japan Fast Food Restaurant Sales ... new data on the fast food market in Japan. According to the data, the number ...</description>
	<body>
		日本語 Chinese 

 
 Search 
 Strategy Development&amp;Consultancy - Applying Marketing Research 
 Home Services Strategy Market Data Trends In the Media Real Asia Contact 
 50 years of marketing Strategic marketing focus Think tank activities JMR Publications Consumer Data Economic Data Think Tank Activities Strategic Marketing Focus 50 Years Japan Marketing 100 Years of Marketing H. Matsuda discusses strategy Strategy 100 Cases Japan Consumer Life Survivors and Thrivers Multi-sided Markets Leadership Theory JMR/PNWA Alliance Solutions&amp;Results Global Promotions Study Eye-tracking Internet Surveys J marketing.net Contact Us Map / Access E-mail Form Internships Eyetrack&amp;Cultures Eye-Tracking Shelf Placement Shelf Placement (Japanese) Eye Movement&amp;Buyers Applications JMR on Eye-Tracking Latest hits Hot Words Japan Consumer Trends Media&amp;Advertising Distribution Channels Gizmo Nipponica Monthly Product Watch Weekly Business Guide J Shoppers Youth Culture Japan Pop beat Recent More articles More by H. Matsuda Anime&amp;Manga Global Impact Peer-to-Peer Driving the content Robot dreams Online gaming 3 sacred treasures Guys just wanna be girls Japanese Magazines Shibuya Fashion China Korea Taiwan JMR in Japanese Media JMR in Overseas Media JMR Books JMR Journals Curry Powder Market B2B Food Trends Instant Noodle Soups Cosmetic Foundation Consumer Must-Buy List 2010 March April 16 - 22 April 9 - 15 Toyo Suisan NIDEC Circle K Sunkus Morinaga Ajinomoto Fast Retailing (UniQlo) Sharp Honda House Foods Seven&amp;i Corp. Bridgestone Canon Corp. Asahi Beer Sapporo Holdings Internet channels Home Centers Teaser Ads Print alive in Japan Japan is Back Japan Consumers - Slides Third Beer in Japan Onigiri - Rice Balls in Japan i Pod lives on Latest on J-smartphones Manga in English Yen10 Trill. market Japan CPI Mobile Phones Monthly Indicators LCD TV Production Fast Food Sales PC Production Housing Starts Media Spending Family Restaurants Chain Restaurant Ranking Online Supermarket Ranking Overtime Hour&amp;Monthly Salary METI Trade Statistics New Japanese Car Sales Family Income Household Spending Unemployment Consumption 2006-2008 Double Income Consumption Drive High Rollers Affluent Middle Kingdom Household Spending Movie Studio Tourists K-Pop Tops Billboard Charts Watami in Taiwan&amp;China 
 

Market Data

 
 Consumer Data 
 Japan CPI Mobile Phones Monthly Indicators LCD TV Production Fast Food Sales PC Production Housing Starts Media Spending Family Restaurants Chain Restaurant Ranking Online Supermarket Ranking 
 Economic Data 
 Overtime Hour&amp;Monthly Salary METI Trade Statistics New Japanese Car Sales Family Income Household Spending Unemployment Consumption 2006-2008 
 
 
 Richard&apos;s Eye 

 Japan&apos;s Zen-Like Consumer 
 Steady-state economy&amp;Japan&apos;s reluctant consumers 
 
 Japan&apos;s Seasonal Factors 
 Seasonal income flow&amp;impact on consumer spending
 
 
 Arbitrage&amp;Consumers 
 Law of&quot;One Price&quot;in consumer product markets 
 
 Japan Viewed from the Outside 
 &quot;Gai-jin,&quot; outsiders, views of Japan uncover new insights 
 
 Mobile phone usage habits -- Japan, China, U.S. 
 JMR study finds culturally influenced patterns 
 
 Richard May -- interview on iTV 
 Video clip -- marketing research
trends in Japan now 
 
 Software-as-a-Service 
 SaaS changes how you acquire software 

 more 
 
 Case Studies/Japanese Market 

 Private Brands in Japan 
 
 

 more 
 
 JMR in Print 

 1. Japan&apos;s Non-consuming Consumers 

 2. Economic Weather Chart of 47 Prefectures 

 3. JMR on Economics of Marketing 

 more
	</body>
</document>
