<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002301" url="http://health.yahoo.net/experts/eatthis?page=14" time="2012-07-12-18:13" support="1" score="0.0003421171113044971" bingtitle="Eat This, Not That - Yahoo! Health" webtitle="Eat This, Not That">
			<query id="000875" bing-rank="208"/>
	<description>... intrigue of the runaway best-selling book, the Eat ... alternatives, so you can still enjoy your meals and ... A dollar or two at a fast-food restaurant can buy a lot of ...</description>
	<body>
		HOME HEALTH TOPICS A-Z 

 Most Common Conditions Acne Allergies Anxiety Arthritis Asthma ADHD Bipolar Disorder Breast Cancer Depression Diabetes GERD High Blood Pressure Menopause Migraine Multiple Myeloma Osteoarthritis Pregnancy Prostate Cancer Sleep Disorders Stroke 3D Body Maps Health Experts News Videos 

 HEALTHY LIVING 

 Aging&amp;Longevity Beauty&amp;Skin Care Exercise&amp;Fitness Health Care Men&apos;s Health Mental Health Nutrition Oral Care Parenting Pregnancy Relationships&amp;Sex Sleep Weight Loss Women&apos;s Health Daily Tips 

 CHECK YOUR SYMPTOMS 

 Most Common Symptoms Abdominal Pain Back Pain Blood In Stool Chest Pain Cough Dark Urine Diarrhea Dizziness Fatigue Fever Frequent Urination Gas Headache Joint Pain Loss of Appetite Low Grade Fever Nausea Rash Swollen Feet Vaginal Discharge Vertigo 

 DRUGS&amp;TREATMENTS FIND A DOCTOR DR. OZ   
 
 Featured on Yahoo! Health: Sleep Positions for Sciatica The Worst Health Habit Parasite Linked to Suicide Women&apos;s Health Risks Chemo Brain or Just Stress? 
 Health Search 
Health Experts
 Health Experts Main 
Blogs List
 The Doctor Oz Prescription All in Your Mind Breast Cancer Chronicles Day in Health Dr. Mao&apos;s Secrets of Longevity Eat This, Not That Fitness for Real Life Happier, Healthier You Healthy Kids, Healthy Family Healthy Living and Your Weight Joy&apos;s Healthy Bite Living With Diabetes Losing It With Liz Men&apos;s Health The Family Dentist The Skin Guru Women&apos;s Health Today Your Best Fitness Your Best Heart Health Related Topics 
 Autism Avoidant Personality Disorder Schizotypal Personality Disorder Social Anxiety Disorder 
 Health Topics» 
Eat This, Not That
 By David Zinczenko with Matt Goulding Provided by
 RSS | View Profile» 
 Show All Results Aging Alzheimers Blood Pressure Children Cholesterol Fitness Heart Men&apos;s Health Mental Health Nutrition Obesity Sexual Health Sleep Weight Loss Women&apos;s Health 
 of 19 
 8 Worst Restaurant Starters 

A funny thing has happened to America&apos;s restaurant appetizers, starters, and sides: They&apos;ve started growing bigger than the main meals. It&apos;s now common for a diner to wolf down 500 or 600 greasy calories before even starting on the ...  More» 
 David Zinczenko - Dec 10, 2009 
 America&apos;s Cheapest Health Foods 

Eating well has never been so expensive. Over the past two years, the cost of vegetables, meat, fruit, and other high-nutrition, low-calorie foods has increased by an average of 19.5 percent.  More» 
 David Zinczenko - Dec 01, 2009 
 Best&amp;Worst Ice Cream in America 

The writers of Eat This, Not That! 2010 have uncovered the 7 worst ice creams in America. Avoid them and choose their equally delicious--but much healthier--counterparts, and you&apos;ll be able to indulge and enjoy while losing weight too!  More» 
 David Zinczenko - Nov 18, 2009 
 8 Perfect Stay-Young Foods 

You’re only as young as you feel—so add these eight nutritious powerhouses to your daily diet, and start feeling (and acting and looking) years younger!  More» 
 David Zinczenko - Nov 09, 2009 
 The Worst Movie Foods (and What to Eat Instead) 

traditional movie munchies can turn any film into a horror flick. The truth is that all that mindless snacking during your show can add hundreds of calories to your daily intake.  More» 
 David Zinczenko - Oct 22, 2009 
 Health Food... or Health Fraud? 

Beware of packaging propaganda: Food-industry health claims can be misleading. Use this guide to learn the science behind the sales pitch. Call it the Eat This, Not That crib sheet for helping you to beat Big Food at its own game--and be ultimatel...  More» 
 David Zinczenko - Oct 12, 2009 
 Best&amp;Worst Vending Machine Foods! 

Diapers, iPods... even shoes. You can buy almost anything out of a vending machine these days—so why is it so difficult to find a healthy, satisfying snack?  More» 
 David Zinczenko - Oct 05, 2009 
 8 Perfect Sleep-Better Foods 

Nothing makes it harder to fall asleep than knowing how important it is to fall asleep. So when the pressure&apos;s on, try chowing down on one of these snacks before bedtime to ensure some serious shut-eye.  More» 
 David Zinczenko - Sep 21, 2009 
 Hidden Calories in &quot;Healthy&quot; Menu Items! 

Take a close look at chain restaurant menus, and you&apos;ll glimpse the occasional section devoted to supposedly &quot;healthy&quot; fare. But are these special items really guiltless, trim, or the healthiest on the menu?  More» 
 David Zinczenko - Sep 15, 2009 
 The Best and Worst Pizzas in America 

Somewhere between the brick ovens of Italy and the delivery cars of America something went horribly wrong. The traditional pizza, made with just bread, cheese and tomatoes, is now tricked out with inflated crusts, four-cheese toppings, and a surpl...  More» 
 David Zinczenko - Aug 28, 2009 of 19 
Follow Yahoo! Health on Twitter and become a fan on Facebook 
 
Sponsored Links
 Nutrition Experience Kaplan University With No Tuition Obligation. Try Today! 
 www.Kaplan.edu nutrition Find nutrition Here. Online Specials on Popular Items! 
 HealthBeauty.DealTumbler.com Healthy School Lunches Join A Debate About Nutrition. What Is The Healthiest Option For Kids? 
 LibertyMutual.com/Responsibility Follow @YahooHealth on Twitter Related Videos   Play Video HER Week In Health Feburary 3, 2012 
 By Empowher More Videos» Related Health News 
 Healthy eating may help ADHD kids: US study 
 Jan 09, 2012 - AFP 
 Health spending eclipses growth in rich countries: OECD 
 Jun 29, 2010 - AFP 
 Pass child nutrition bill: Michelle Obama 
 Aug 01, 2010 - Reuters 
Sponsored Links
 Nutrition Experience Kaplan University With No Tuition Obligation. Try Today! 
 www.Kaplan.edu by nutrition Find by nutrition Here. Online Specials on Popular Items! 
 HealthBeauty.DealTumbler.com Healthy School Lunches Join A Debate About Nutrition. What Is The Healthiest Option For Kids? 
 LibertyMutual.com/Responsibility 
More on YAHOO! Health

 Health Topics A-Z Healthy Living Symptoms Checker 

 Drugs&amp;Treatments Find a Doctor Health Experts 

 Tip of the Day Health News Videos 
 
Also on YAHOO!

 Answers Local Mail 

 Messenger News Shine 
 Yahoo! Health is for informational purposes only and is not a substitute for professional medical or health advice,
 examination, diagnosis, or treatment. Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Lifestyles Network | Terms of Service | Copyright/IP Policy | Help 
We collect personal information on this site. To learn more about how we use your personal information, see our Privacy Policy | About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
