<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002698" url="http://nz.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20120324021856AARG8y9" time="2012-07-12-18:45" support="7" score="0.016395529160308255" bingtitle="It took me 20 minutes to receive my order at McDonald&apos;s. Remind me ..." webtitle="It took me 20 minutes to receive my order at McDonalds. Remind me again, why is it calledFast Food? - Yahoo! Answers NZ">
			<query id="001103" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000990" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000226" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000600" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000995" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="001178" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000883" bing-rank="115"/>
	<description>Consumer Electronics; Dining Out ... took me 20 minutes to receive my order ... Answer Questions in Fast Food. Poll-What is your favorite fast food restaurant?</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! New Zealand Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Fast Food &gt; Resolved Question 
 Misplaced Apostrophe&apos;s Member since: 04 March 2009 Total points: 12,823 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
It took me 20 minutes to receive my order at McDonald&apos;s. Remind me again, why is it called&quot;Fast Food&quot;?

 4 months ago Report Abuse 
 by ? Member since: 11 March 2012 Total points: 1,651 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 hey you&apos;re an alien, you guys eat mcdonalds too huh 
 4 months ago Report Abuse 
 19% 7 Votes 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; It took me 20 minute… &quot;was originally asked in Yahoo! Answers Australia 
 
 Other Answers (8)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Will Member since: 21 May 2010 Total points: 977 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Most likely because you were a difficult customer who didn&apos;t know what they wanted so they had to re-make your order multiple times. We are not ALL idiots at McDonald&apos;s, the majority of us are students in high school or college, trying to pay for our education. 
Source(s):
 I work at McD&apos;s. 
 4 months ago Report Abuse 
 11% 4 Votes by Catman Member since: 17 December 2010 Total points: 3,736 (Level 4) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Fastest time on a meal at Chick-Fil-A for a regular combo was about 5 seconds.


Don&apos;t believe me? They have chutes for regular sandwiches so they can just take them and give them to you. 
 4 months ago Report Abuse 
 3% 1 Vote by Spike Member since: 18 March 2012 Total points: 1,256 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Because the meat is actually just processed pink slime. 
 4 months ago Report Abuse 
 16% 6 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Sean Member since: 17 March 2012 Total points: 127 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 It&apos;s probably opposite day ^.^ 
 4 months ago Report Abuse 
 8% 3 Votes by peggy b Member since: 21 February 2008 Total points: 5,872 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Morons work at McDonalds 
 4 months ago Report Abuse 
 14% 5 Votes by royce Member since: 17 March 2012 Total points: 342 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 because its fast to eat the food, but service can vary. 
 4 months ago Report Abuse 
 16% 6 Votes by Fyfe Member since: 24 March 2012 Total points: 81 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Because the workers are crap 
 4 months ago Report Abuse 
 5% 2 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by David Member since: 05 November 2011 Total points: 541 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 I would have told them give me my money back and left 
 4 months ago Report Abuse 
 5% 2 Votes 
 
Discover Questions in Fast Food 

 Interview questions for McDonalds? ? What time does Mcdonalds stop serving apple pies UK? New at working at Sonic Drive-Inn? Any Tips? Will i get hired at McDonald&apos;s ? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! New Zealand Limited. All Rights Reserved.

 Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines
	</body>
</document>
