<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002913" url="http://twincitiesrestaurantblog.typepad.com/tcrb/roseville/" time="2012-07-12-18:59" support="5" score="0.004111434417163258" bingtitle="Twin Cities Restaurant Blog: Roseville" webtitle="Twin Cities Restaurant Blog: Roseville">
			<query id="000251" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="001002" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000562" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="001285" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000688" bing-rank="224"/>
	<description>... are so good and the 2-for-1 happy hour drink ... and is about the same size as a typical fast-food restaurant. ... There is a beverage station near the front counter with ...</description>
	<body>
		Twin Cities Restaurant Blog 

A detailed account of different restaurants around St Paul, Mpls and surrounding areas
 Home 
 Home Archives Profile Subscribe 
 
Roseville

January 18, 2010
 
 Davanni&apos;s Pizza ~ Arden Hills, Bloomington, Brooklyn Center, Burnsville, Coon Rapids, Eagan, Eden Prairie, Edina, Golden Valley, Minneapolis, Minnetonka, Plymouth, Richfield, Rogers, Roseville, Savage, St Paul, Woodbury 
 
 Cuisine: Pizza, Delicatessen (hoagies)

 Restaurant Features: Catering, Counter-Service, Delivery, Kids Menu, On-Site Parking (at many locations)
 Locations: Arden Hills, Bloomington, Brooklyn Center, Burnsville, Coon Rapids, Eagan, Eden Prairie, Edina, Golden Valley, Minneapolis, Minnetonka, Plymouth, Richfield, Rogers, Roseville, Savage, St Paul, Woodbury
 Addresses: (Click here for Maps of Davanni&apos;s Locations) 
Arden Hills: 3673 Lexington Ave N Arden Hills, MN 55126 651-481-7100 

Bloomington: 8605 Lyndale Ave S  Bloomington, MN 55420  952-888-6232 

Brooklyn Center:  5937 Summit Dr  Brooklyn Center, MN 55430 763-566-8220 

Burnsville:  14639 CR 11  Burnsville, MN 55337  952-431-1500 

Coon Rapids: 3430 129th Ave NW Coon Rapids, MN 55448 763-712-1000 

Eagan:  1960 Cliff Lake Rd Eagan, MN 55123  651-688-6111 

Eden
Prairie:  8061 Flying Cloud Dr Eden Prairie, MN 55344   952-941-4444 

Edina: 5124 Gus Young Ln Edina, MN 55436 952-920-9090 

Golden Valley:  663 Winnetka Ave N  Golden Valley, Mn 55427 763-398-0303 

Minneapolis: 1242 Hennepin Ave Minneapolis, MN 55403  612-338-0000 
 

Minnetonka:  15200 Highway 7 Minnetonka, MN 55345 952-938-4243 


Plymouth:  3015 Harbor Ln N  Plymouth, MN 55447 763-550-0003 

Richfield: 2312 W 66th St Richfield, MN 55423   612-866-3324 

 Rogers:  14165 James Road Rogers, Mn 55374 763-428-2990 


Roseville, 1905 W Perimeter Dr Roseville, MN 55113 651-636-3411 

Savage: 14125 Highway 13 Savage, MN 55378 952-440-1200 
 

St Paul:  310 White Bear Ave St. Paul, MN 55106 651-738-6992 


St Paul:  41 Cleveland Ave S St. Paul, MN 55105 651-690-4848 

Uptown Mpls: 1414 W Lake St Minneapolis, MN 55408 612-822-3111 
 

Woodbury: 1905 Donegal Dr Woodbury, MN 55125 651-739-1010 

 Links: Davanni&apos;s Website 
 

 


 Atmosphere: The East St Paul Davanni&apos;s location is just off I-94 and White Bear Ave. Like all other Davanni&apos;s location, customers order at a counter and then wait for their name to be called when order is ready.

 

There are several different seating areas, each with booths that can accommodate up to four people. There are also a couple of tables in the very back section of the dining room. There are many windows throughout the restaurant, leaving it very well lit during the day.

 


 Menu:  Appetizers include Potato Chips, Breadsticks and Garlic Cheese Bread.

Salads at Davanni&apos;s are the Garden Salad, Side Garden, Chicken Cobb, Italian Chef, Oriental Chicken, Southwestern Chicken, Spinach Chicken, Chicken Caesar, and Side Caesar.

Hoagie sandwiches are served on either white, whole grain, or ciabatta roll with lettuce, tomato, onion and mayo. Options include Southwestern Chicken, Chicken Bacon Honey Mustard, Chicken Breast, Turkey/Bacon/Cheddar, Turkey, BLT w/ Cheddar, Club, Roast Beef, Pastrami, Ham, Salami, Tuna Melt, Veggie, and Three Cheese. Hot subs made with meat, marinara and cheese only include Chicken Parmigiano, Meatball, Sausage, and Pizza.

Davanni&apos;s Pizza can be ordered with a choice of three different crusts (thin, traditional and deep dish) and two sauces (red and white). Sizes pizzas come in are Solo, Medium and Laqrge. Toppings choices are Pepperoni, Italian Sausage, Sliced Chicken Breast, Canadian Bacon, Hamburger, Red Onion, Green Pepper, Garlic, Mushrooms, Hot Peppers, Green Olive, Black Olive, Pineapple, Bacon, Gorgonzola Cheese, Anchovies, Roma Tomatoes, Cheddar Cheese, and Jalapeños. 

Davanni&apos;s also has Penne Pasta (with chicken, meatballs or sausage), Lasagna and Stuffed Calzones.

Kids menu items include Hlaf Pasta, Solo Cheese Pizza, or Half Ham Hoagy.

Desserts include Brownies, Rice Crispy Treats, and Chocolate Chunk Cookies.
 Price guide: Hoagies $3.25-7 Salads $4-7  Pizzas $5-20 Calzones $5.50+

 What We ordered: My companions and I ordered a variety of pizzas, including this large Chicago-style deep dish pizza with pepperoni and sausage. Davanni&apos;s deep dish is a treat for those who like real Chicago-style pizza and has been my one of family&apos;s favorites for many years. The buttery brown crust is at least 1&quot;deep yet it is light. The lightness of the crust is deceiving because the pizza is actually very filling. The cheese and meats were baked directly on top of the crust with pizza sauce spread out on the very top to prevent the crust from getting soggy. The large pizza had 10-12 wedges.

  

Our party also ordered a Large Thin Crust Pepperoni Pizza. The crust on the thin crust pizza was also pretty good, crispy but slightly chewy. It was loaded with melted mozzarella and a fair amount of pepperoni (although I personally like more).

 c and olive oil)

This is a solo deep dish pizza with pepperoni, mushrooms and&quot;pink&quot;sauce. Pink sauce simply means that it has both white sauce (garlic and olive oil) and red sauce. If you like garlic, you would love either the white or the pink sauce. This pizza was also very good, the mushrooms were fresh and there was a lot of pepperoni. The light and buttery deep dish crust practically melts in your mouth.


  

One of my companions ordered a half pizza hoagy on whole grain with a special request for the sauce to be served on side. This is a good sandwich but it doesn&apos;t have much substance, just a thin layer of pepperoni and a thin layer of melted cheese on one half of the bread. You better order the whole sandwich if you&apos;re hungry!

  

Another companion ordered a pepperoni and veggie calzone to-go. Safe to say that this thing was loaded with melted cheese, meat and veggies.

 

 Service: You can call ahead for pick up or delicery, otherwise Davanni&apos;s offers standard counter-service. There are typically 2-3 cashiers taking orders during the lunch and dinner rush but you can still expect to wait a few minutes before placing your order. It was fairly busy during my visit and it took about 30-40 minutes for our pizzas, which seems a reasonable amount of time for the deep dish pizzas to bake.
 Overall Impression: Davanni&apos;s has excellent deep dish pizza and is conveniently located in several places around the Twin Cities. Service is reasonably fast and menu prices aren&apos;t going to break the bank. Jan 18, 2010 5:14:57 PM | Arden Hills , Bloomington , Brooklyn Center , Burnsville , Catering , Counter-Service , Delicatessen , Delivery , Dessert , Downtown Minneapolis , Eagan , Eden Prairie , Edina , Golden Valley , Kids Menu , Minneapolis , Minnetonka , On-Site Parking , Pizza , Plymouth , Richfield , Roseville , Savage , St Paul , Woodbury 
 Comment 1 Reblog It 0 
 
December 27, 2009
 
 Ol&apos; Mexico Restaurante&amp;Cantina~ Roseville, MN 
 Cuisine: Mexican, Kids Menu
 Restaurant Features: Banquet, Bar, Catering, Happy Hour Specials, On-Site Parking,
 Location: Roseville, MN
 Address: 1754 Lexington Ave North St Paul, MN, 55113 (651) 487-2847
 Hours:  Kitchen: 11a-Midnight Bar : 11a-2a
 Links: Ol&apos;Mexico Website    Google Map 

 




 Atmosphere: Located just off Hwy 36 in Roseville, Ol&apos;Mexico is easy to get to from either Mpls or St Paul. Ol&apos;Mexico has been open since 1979 and is an enchanting restaurant that is quite reminiscent of its namesake. The restaurant itself is quite large with many different seating areas, the center if which is a beautiful indoor courtyard complete with a fountain at its center.

  

In the areas surrounding the central courtyard there are two tiers of additional seating. The lower level has large round tables within semi-private alcoves that are perfect for parties of eight. The lighting is dim and romantic throughout the entire restaurant.

  

Ol&apos;Mexico also has a large open bar area with great Happy Hour drink specials and a taco bar every Friday. There is also Karaoke ever Thursday night from 9p-1a and nightly Buzztime Interactive Trivia. There are also several HD TVs that play local games and ALL NFL Football games, as well as Nascar races.

 


The Bar also has a Dining area with tables to seat around fifty or so. The lighting is just as dim as the rest of the restaurant but it just doesn&apos;t have the same ambiance as the more formal dining room.

 


 Menu: Appetizers at Ol&apos;Mexico include Nachos, Black Ben Nachos, Fresh Guacamole&amp;Chips, Shrimp Cocktail, Mexi Wings, Chile Verde with Flour Crisps, Taquitos and Chile con Queso.

Salads offered are the Taco Salad, Tostada Salad, Grilled Chicken with Raspberry Walnut Vinaigrette, Caesar, Santa Fe Chopped Salad, and Dinner Salad.

Ol&apos;Mexico has a&quot;Eating Fit&quot;menu as well that includes Spinach Salad (with chicken or salmon), Grilled Marinated Salmon with Steamed Asparagus, Grilled Chicken Breast with Steamed Vegetables, and Lettuce Burger Wrap.

Burgers and sandwiches at Ol&apos;Mexico are Cheeseburger, BBQ Bacon Cheddar Burger, Mexican Sandwich and Veggie Sandwich.

Entrees include Four Cheese Quesadilla, Steak or Chicken Fajita Quesadilla, Pocket Taco Enchilada Style, Pocket Taco Platter, Chimichangas (choice of ground beef, ground chicken, spicy seafood, shredded beef and bbq beef), Sizzling Fajita Platter, Southwestern Spicy Seafood Enchiladas, Diablo Shrimp tacos, Pollo Fundido, Grande Burro, Macho Burro, Fajita Burro, Bean&amp;Veggie Burrito.

There are number of combination Mexican dinners and you can also create your own combo.

Grilled Entrees include 14 ox t-Bone Steak, Fresh Grilled Salmon with Mango Salsa, Fresh Grilled Tilapia covered in Jumbo Shrimp, Grilled steak, Chicken, Shrimp or Vegetable Skewers.

Desserts at Ol&apos;Mexico include Mexican Fried Ice Cream, Brownie Sundae, Fresh Strawberry Shortcake, Chocolate Caramel Lava Cake, Fresh Fruit Plate, and Fresh Strawberry and Banana with sweet cream, walnuts, raisins and coconut.

Kids Menu includes Chicken Strips, Chhese Melts, Taco, Mexi Dog and Hamburger.

 Price guide: Appetizers $4-8 Salads $9-13 Sandwiches $10 Entrees $10-16  Grilled Entrees $15-17 Desserts $ 7-8 Kids Menu $5
 What I ordered:  My visit to Ol&apos;Mexico was during Happy Hour so I took advantage of the 2-for-1 special and ordered peach margaritas. These are so amazing!!! They are the best peach margaritas I have had anywhere. They use some sort of fruit syrup for all of their fruit margaritas (other choices include strawberry, raspberry, watermelon, wild berry, blue raspberry, pomegranate, banana, melon) and they are packed with tartness and flavor. The chips were also very good, warm and freshly fried to a crispy golden brown. I am not sure if my taste buds were off on this visit, but I did not care for the salsa as it tasted way too salty and not very spicy. The chips and the margaritas made up for the salsa though!
 
For dinner I made my own combo with a Chile Relleno, a Cheese Enchilada and Mexican Rice. This was a great choice! The Chile Relleno was stuffed with shredded beef and cheddar cheese then breaded and fried and baked with cheese on top. The beef was tender and was seasoned to give it a lot of flavor, especially when paired with the spice of the pepper. The enchilada was stuffed with cheddar and topped with enchilada sauce and even more melted cheese. Rice was decent.

  

My companion had the build your own combo as well, with ground beef hard corn taco and ground beef enchilada. The ground beef was only slightly seasoned and very boring, and had several pieces of onion mixed in with it. Would rather have had the shredded beef than the ground beef. The beans were good.

 

 Service:  My companion and I met at Ol&apos;Mexico around 3:30 on a snowy Tuesday afternoon and the happy hour crowd was only just beginning to arrive. We were seated in the bar area although had we been given the option, I would have preferred any of the tables in the courtyard or formal dining room. Our server was nice and was great about letting us know that the Happy Hour specials included 2-for-1s on all their drinks. Food came really fast.
 Overall Impression:  Ol&apos;Mexico is one of the few restaurants I ate at while growing up and it was always considered my family&apos;s&quot;favorite&quot;Mexican restaurant in the 80&apos;s and 90&apos;s. In the past decade I have come to eat better Mexican food at other restaurants, but I still love the charm and atmosphere of Ol&apos;Mexico in Roseville. The fruity margaritas are so good and the 2-for-1 happy hour drink specials are a pretty good deal. Dec 27, 2009 12:56:51 PM | Banquet Room , Bar , Catering , Dessert , Happy Hour , Kids Menu , Mexican , On-Site Parking , Roseville 
 Comment 4 Reblog It 0 
 
May 18, 2009
 
 Grumpy&apos;s Bar&amp;Grill ~ Roseville&amp;Minneapolis, MN 
 
 Cuisine: American
 Restaurant Features: Bar, Banquet Room, Pull-Tabs, On-Site Parking, Patio
 Locations:  Roseville, Northeast Mpls, Downtown Mpls, MN
 Addresses&amp;Maps: 
 Northeast Mpls - 220 4th St NE Mpls, MN 55413 (612)789-7429

 Downtown Mpls - 1111 Washington Ave Sp. Mpls, MN 55415 (612) 340-9738

 Roseville - 2801 Snelling Ave No. Roseville, MN 55113 (651)379-1180

 Link: Grumpy&apos;s Website 

 
 Atmosphere: The Roseville location of Grumpy&apos;s Bar&amp;Grill is in a very large building that was first the home of K-Fan Restaurant and then served as Majors Sports Cafe until Grumpy&apos;s took over the location early in 2008. Within the large space there is a large bar area with several bar-height tables placed around the centrally-located bar, an upstairs seating area, and an enclosed space for playing darts.

  

The Dining Room contains both booths and wooden tables, contemporary decor.

  

There is also a large Patio Area that can be accessed through the bar area.

 

 Menu: Appetizers at Grumpy&apos;s include Chicken Drummies, Chicken Tenders, Popcorn Chicken, Quesadilla Gordo, Potato Skins, Mozarella Sticks, Tepanyaki Beef Tidbits, Mac n Cheese, Mac N Cheese Bites, Beer Battered Onion Rings, Nachos El Grumpy, Lil&apos;Grumpy Burgers, Mini Corndogs, Tex Mex Queso Rolls, Sausage Pizza Dip, Gazillion Cheese Dip, Walleye Fingers, and Pepper Jack Spinach Dip.

Grumpy offers the following salads: Grumpy&apos;s Chop, Ty Cobb, Aztec Chicken, Bleu Bayou, Greek, Caesar, and Chicken Spinach Flatbread. Soup choices include Chicken Wild Rice, Chili and a Soup du Jour.

Grumpy&apos;s has the largest selection of potato choices I have seen including Grumpy Fries, Tater Tots, Wedge-Style, Shoe String, Criss-Cut Fries, Mashed, Baked and Hash Browns.

Sandwiches include Chicken Cordon Bleu, Buffalo Chicken, BBQ Chicken, Cajun Chicken, Hawaiian Chicken, Build Your Own Chicken Sandwich, BBQ Chicken Wrap, Honey Mustard Chicken Wrap, Chicken Salad, Southwestern Turkey, Walleye, Tuna Melt El Paso, Mock Duck BBQ, Grilled Cheese, Ham N Cheese, Hell on Whells, Grilled Reuben, Grumpy&apos;s Rachel, Roast Beef or Chicken Philly, Hot Beef, B.L.T., French Dip, Clubhouse, Pork Tenderloin, BBQ Pork, The Cuban, and St Paul Style Coney Dogs. All sanwiches come with choice of potato.

All Burger Choices are a 1/2 lb of lean Black Angus and come with a choice of potato. Options include Southern Style&quot;The Elvis&quot;(beef patty topped with peanut butter and bacon), American Burger, Pepper Burger, Burgermeister, Chili Burger, Veggie Burger, Cream Cheese Burger, Patty Melt, The Wyoming, Juicy Lucy, and Build your Own Burger.

Pizzas are made with homemade dough and include choices such as the Straught Up Sausage, Attsa Cheeseburger, BBQ Chicken, Pepperoni, Northern Italian, Aloha This! and Build Your Own Pizza.

Entrees include Ribs, T-Bone Steak, Top Sirloin, Country Fried Chicken or Pork, Homemade Meatloaf, Pork Chops, Fish&amp;Chips, Penne Diablo, Gnocchi, Manicotti, Chicken Penne Carbonara, Shrimp or Chicken Fettuccine, and Tater Tot Hotdish.

Desserts include S&apos;Mores, Home Baked Apple Pie, Chocolate Cake, Carrot Cake, New York Cheesecake, and Chocolate Chip Cookie Sundae.

 Price guide: Appetizers $7-10 Sandwiches/Burgers $7-12 Entrees $10-16

 What I ordered: I really couldn&apos;t decide what I was in the mood for- I just knew I didn&apos;t want to get a burger or sandwich which is usually what I get at a bar&amp;grill. The server said the manicotti was good so I tried that. I would say it was decent, but nothing to write home about. The portion was HUGE, with several large tubes of pasta filled with a ricotta cheese mixture. It was very mild and I could only detect maybe a slight hint of garlic and oregano in the mixture, otherwise it was just plain old ricotta. The red sauce was tasty but there just wasn&apos;t much of it, so I asked for a large side of it so I could adjust it to my liking. There was a lot of mozzarella baked on top. It was supposed to come with bread of some kind, but they forgot to bring it to me.

  

One of my companions had the Country Fried Chicken. The chicken was good, covered with gravy and served with a side of mashed potatoes, variety vegetables, and toast.

  

Another companion had the Quesadilla which comes stuffed with cheese and tomatoes and onions. My companion ordered it with black beans and peppers added (which was charged an additional $3). It was an excellent quesadilla but very expensive at $11.

 

Another Companion (who happened to be the Guest of Honor) originally ordered the Fish&amp;Chips but it had been fried so long that it was hard as a rock. Since it was inedible it was sent back to the kitchen.

  

Instead of Fish&amp;Chips my companion had the Tepanyaki Beef Teedbits at the suggestion of the server. These looked and smelled delicious

  

Two of the people in our group shared the Grumpy&apos;s Nachos, which was a HUGE order of tri-colored chips piled with melted cheese, tomatoes, jalapenos, black olives, green onions and served with sour cream and salsa on the side.

 

 Service : My party had a reservation (made 3 days in advance) for 15 people at 6pm on a Saturday night. At 6:10 when the entire party had been assembled, we were told that they could only accommodate us in the dining room for one hour and then we would have to leave so they could set up for another big party who had a reservation at 7:30pm. Say what?! My companion who had arranged the dinner in honor of a birthday celebration was very upset, as we all were. Apparently they had overlooked our reservation but could accommodate us all in the bar area with taller tables pushed together. We were fine with that, as we weren&apos;t given much choice. Our server was nice but not overly friendly and was not very helpful with suggestions on the menu- she told us she only ever eats appetizers. It also took a considerable amount of time to bring little things when asked, although we did have a large party.
 Overall Impression: I was not at all impressed with the food at Grumpy&apos;s Roseville and the service was pretty bad. It is very unlikely I&apos;d ever go back
 May 18, 2009 7:26:36 PM | American , Banquet Room , Bar , Burgers , Downtown Minneapolis , Minneapolis , On-Site Parking , Patio Dining , Pull-Tabs , Roseville 
 Comment 2 Reblog It 0 
 
February 05, 2009
 
 Dino&apos;s The Greek Place - Coon Rapids, Edina, Lakeville, Roseville, Plymouth, West St Paul,&amp;Woodbury MN 
 
 Cuisine: Greek, Mediterranean, Middle Eastern

 Restaurant Features: Counter Service, On-Site Parking
 Locations: Coon Rapids, Edina, Lakeville, Roseville (Falcon Heights), Plymouth, West St Paul, and Woodbury, MN
 Addresses&amp;Maps: 


 Coon Rapids - 

 3179 Northdale Blvd. Coon Rapids, MN 55433 
 (763) 422-2003
 Edina - 
 6539 York Ave. S Edina, MN 55435 (612) 866-6363
 Lakeville - 
 17701 Cedar Avenue (Cedar Avenue&amp;Dodd Road) Farmington, MN 55024 952) 431-3466

 Roseville - 
 1700 Snelling Ave. Falcon Heights, MN 55108 (651) 645-8800
 Plymouth - 
 3355 Plymouth Blvd. Plymouth, MN 55447 (763) 553-2040
 West St Paul - 
 1221 South Robert St. West St. Paul, MN 55118 (651) 450-6976

 Woodbury - 

 10060 City Walk Drive Woodbury, MN 55129 651-738-9757

 

 Links: Dino&apos;s Website 
 Hours: Daily 10am-10pm

 Atmosphere: Dino&apos;s offers counter-service and is about the same size as a typical fast-food restaurant. The entire restaurant is furnished with your basic hard-top tables set close together, without a booth in sight. There is a beverage station near the front counter with two large soda dispensers. A couple of TVs hang from the ceilings and there are also some paintings adorning the walls.

 

 Menu: Side Items include French Fries, Seasoned Fries, Pita Bread, Pita Chips, Hummus, Greek Olives, Pepperoncini Peppers, Falafel, Spanakopita, Onion Petals, Spinach Puffs and Greek Meatballs.

Dino&apos;s offers a Greek Salad ( lettuce, feta, Greek olives, cucumbers, peppers, onion, pepperoncini peppers, and Greek dressing) with choice of meat.

The Sandwiches at Dino&apos;s are served on fresh pita bread and include the Gyro (meat with raw onion, tomato and tzatzini sauce), Jr. Gyro, Spicy Gyro, Chicken Gyro, Jr. Chicken Gyro, Greek Chicken Breast, Greek Philly (sauteed peppers and onions and melted Swiss), Greek Meatball, Falafel (deep-fried patties made of a mixture of ground chick peas and seasonings), Steak Souvlaki, and Chicken Mushroom Swiss . **Any sandwich can be mega-sized for an additional charge.   Any sandwich can be ordered as a Value Meal, which comes with soda and either fries or side salad. 

There are also a couple of Wraps including Greek Chicken Caesar, Hummus, and the Gyro Bacon Cheddar Wrap.

Entree Plates offer meat choice with Fries, Greek Salad or Rice, and Grilled Pita. Meat choices are the Gyro, Chicken Gyro, Steak or Chicken Souvlaki (kabobs), or Spanakopita (spinach, onions, feta and ricotta cheese wrapped in filo dough and baked). Combination Plate includes each of the meat choices.

There are also two Family Packs available. The Family Pack comes with 1 lb gyro meat, sauce, toppings, and 5 pitas. The Mega Family Pack is the Family Pack with an additional two orders of Fries and 1 large Greek Salad.

Desserts include Baklava, Cookies, or Ice Cream.

 Price guide: Side Items $1-2 Sandwiches and Wraps $5-6 Value Meals $8-9 Salads $6-9 Plates $7-9
 What I ordered: The Greek Chicken Breast Sandwich with Spicy Feta and side of Seasoned Fries. Normally this sandwich comes with regular feta cheese, but I LOVE the spicy feta and have them substitute the regular feta for the spicy. This particular sandwich came with both, which was a little too much. The chicken breast was marinated and tender, cut into strips. The sandwich was big and messy, so I opted to eat it most of it with a fork. The onions were plentiful, sliced thin and the spicy feta had a nice kick to it and was full of flavor. The Seasoned Fries were delicious! Dino&apos;s adds their own Greek Seasoning which is pretty salty and garlic-y, but so so SO good!

 One of my companions ordered the Spicy Gyro Sandwich. It is similar to a regular gyro except the spicy comes with the spicy feta instead of tzatziki sauce and also has romaine lettuce. My companion enjoyed it but prefers the traditional gyro.

 Another companion ordered the Souvlaki Plate, with one chicken and one beef kabob, Pita Triangles and Onion Petals. The meat was very good, but there were just five bites of meat on each skewer. The Onion Petals were crispy brown and the portion was rather large.

 

 Service: Ordering is done at the Counter and it usually takes less than ten minutes for the order to be ready, at which point they will either call your name or bring the food out to your table, depending on how busy they are. There are often staff members who will walk around to bus tables or ask you if you&apos;d like a drink refill or anything else. Definitely a step above most other fast-food type restaurants.
 Overall Impression : I really enjoy Dino&apos;s, it is fast and the food is good (especially anything with spicy feta!). The seasoned fries are AWESOME. Dino&apos;s is more expensive than other fast-food restaurants but less expensive than most sit-down restaurants. I wish there was a Dino&apos;s in Hugo or Maplewood!
 Feb 5, 2009 1:54:12 PM | Coon Rapids , Counter-Service , Edina , Greek , Lakeville , Mediterranean , Middle Eastern , On-Site Parking , Plymouth , Roseville , West St Paul , Woodbury 
 Comment 2 Reblog It 0 
 
September 24, 2008
 
 House of Wong- Roseville, MN 
 
 Cuisine: American, Chinese,
 

 Restaurant Features: On-Site Parking, Counter-Service for Take Out
 

 Location: Roseville, MN
 

 Address: 1163 Larpenteur Ave W St Paul, MN
 55113-6382 (651) 488-6687 

 Links: Google map 

 
 

 Atmosphere: House of Wong is a large restaurant located within a large strip-mall in Roseville. The restaurant is long and narrow shaped, with several high-backed booths that run all the way to the back of the restaurant. The taller booths give you a sense of privacy and the way they are placed might make you forget the restaurant is as big as it is. The decor of the House of Wong is more casual and homey than sophisticated Asian, but the hand-carved wooden doors and handful of Asian vases serve to remind you this is indeed, a Chinese Restaurant.
 

 
 

 Menu: Appetizers include Egg Rolls, Cantonese Chicken Wings, Fried Potstickers, Szechuan Wings, Chinese Barbeque Pork, Crispy Chicken Fingers, Jumbo Golf Shrimp, Meat Wontons, Cream Cheese Wontons, Shrimp Toast, Fried Chicken Livers, and Onion Rings. 

 The House of Wong has several variations of Chow Mein including Meat, Diced Chicken, Sliced Mushroom, Subgum, Chicken Mushroom, Chicken Subgum, Shrimp, and Barbeque Pork. Lomein entrees are made with either Chicken, Barbeque Pork, Beef, Shrimp, or the House of Wong Special Lomein.
 

 Fried Rice specials include Chicken, BBQ Pork, Beef, Fresh Shrimp, Special Fried Rice, and Meatless.   

 
 

 Chinese Chicken dishes include Sweet&amp;Sour, Sesame, Orange, Moo Goo Gai Pan, Chicken and Broccoli, Chicken Almond Ding, Kung Pao, Szechuan, Chicken in Garlic Sauce, General Tsao&apos;s, and Curry Chicken. 


 

 Beef Dishes include Beef&amp;Broccoli, Beef&amp;Snow Peapods, Beef Pepper Steak, Mongolian, Kung Pao, Szechuan, and Mandarin Beef. Pork entrees include Sweet&amp;Sour and Sesame. 

 Vegetarian and Seafood plates include Gulf Shrimp&amp;peapods or Broccoli, Szechuan Shrimp, Kung Pao Shrimp, Triple Kung Pao, Hunan Triple Crown, Szechuan Vegetarian Tofu Stir Fry. 

 You can also get a Noodle or Rice Bowls topped with either Mandarin beef, Teriyaki Chicken, Szechuan Garlic Chicken, Pepper Steak, Chicken Almond Ding, Kung Pao Chicken, Beef and Broccoli, and Szechuan Vegetarian Tofu. 

 There are a number of combination plates as well. 

 
 

 Besides the large amount of Chinese dishes, House of Wong also has several American Items on their menu with Entrees such as Hamburgers, Fresh Roasted Turkey, Grilled or Breaded Pork Chops, Leg of Pork, Pork tenderloin, Frilled Round Steak, Cod Filet, Baby Beef Liver, Sauteed Chicken Breast, Breaded Pork Cutlet, Jumbo Golf Shrimp, Hawaiian Ham Steak and Fried Chicken. 

 Sandwiches include Triple Decker Club, Grilled Cheese, Cold Turkey, Hot Turkey, Grilled Chicken, Grilled Ham and Cheese, Chicken or Tuna Salad, and Fish&amp;Chips Basket. 

 You can even order Italian entrees like Spaghetti, Meat Lasagna, Mostaccioli, Chicken Parmigiana, and Fettuccine with Chicken and Broccoli.
 

 The homemade pies at House of Wong include Banana Cream, Coconut Cream, Chocolate Silk, Apple, Custard, Pumpkin, and on Sundays there is also Carrot Cake.
 

 
 

 Price guide: Prices vary depending on whether you dine-in or order take-out. Take out prices seem to be a couple $$ less. Appetizers $5-10 Chinese Entrees $8-14 American Entrees $10-16
 

 What we ordered: We started with the Shrimp Toast, which was fabulous! The bottom was made with a piece of cocktail-sized bread and then large pieces of shrimp were butterflied, seasoned, and then placed on top and then battered and deep-fried. What a delightful combination of textures! The toast was crispy yet the top was light, fluffy and crunchy. Served with hot mustard and a mild sweet and sour sauce. I have only had shrimp toast at a handful of restaurants and I think House of Wong has the best :)
 

 
 

 We also ordered the Barbeque Pork appetizer. Unbelievably good!  The pork was so tender you could cut it with a fork and the outside was glazed with a sweet sauce, complimenting the natural flavor of the pork. This is a must-have every time I visit the House of Wong!

   

 We also had the Pork Fried Rice, which had large pieces of the Barbeque Pork that I like so much. The rice was so hot it was steaming and my photo ended up turning out blurry. Sorry I didn&apos;t take a better one! The rice was deliciously flavorful with green onions, scrambled egg, mushrooms and bean sprouts and the portion was very generous. 
 

   

 We also tried the Egg Foo Young with shrimp and mushrooms. I am not typically a big fan of egg foo young, but this was really good! There was a nice mix of both vegetables and shrimp. The sauce was on the mild side.
 

   

 We also ordered the Beef Tenderloin Lomein. This was a generous portion of thin, pan-fried noodles with stir-fried pea pods, onions, carrots, bean sprouts, and thin slices of beef tenderloin. This is a mild dish that compliments each of the individual flavors of the ingredients.
 

   

 We also had the Orange Chicken. The portion was pretty large with several pieces of crispy, batter-fried chicken. The sauce was very thick and tasted very strongly of orange.
 

 
 

 Service:  Our visit was right at the beginning of the dinner rush and we were lucky enough to get a table immediately- (You can almost always expect a short wait during the dinner rush because the House of Wong is very popular! ). Our server was very nice and very busy attending to us as well as her other tables, she was very attentive to getting refills
 

 Overall Impression: House of Wong has been one of my all-time favorite Chinese restaurants since I was just a toddler. You get large portions for the money the food is consistent and the quality of the meat is always very good.
 
 Sep 24, 2008 11:19:00 AM | American , Chinese , Counter-Service , On-Site Parking , Roseville 
 Comment 9 Reblog It 0 
 
September 15, 2008
 
 Khan&apos;s Mongolian Barbeque- Richfield, Roseville, Coon Rapids, MN 
 
 Cuisine: Asian, Mongolian, On-Site Parking
 Restaurant Features: Bar, Lunch Buffet, Dinner Buffet , On-Site Parking 
 

 Locations: Coon Rapids, Richfield, Roseville
 Addresses and Maps: 

 Coon Rapids - 2085 Northdale Blvd NW Coon Rapids , MN 55433 (763) 767-3018
 Richfield - 500 E 78th St Richfield , MN 55423 (612) 861-7991 
 

 Roseville- 2720 Snelling Ave N. Roseville, MN 55113 (651) 631-3398 



 
 Atmosphere:  There are several small dining areas situated around the restaurant, made a little more private with the creative use of live plants. The dining areas all surround the centrally-located meat and vegetable buffets. All seating is limited to tables, but there is at least one dining space that allows for tables to be pushed together for larger parties.

  

Within the restaurant there is a small bar area to accommodate patrons who may have to wait for a table on a busy night, or for those who would like to try one of the specialty tropical drinks or wines.

 

 Menu:  The concept of Khan&apos;s is one that allows diners to customize their own stir-fry dishes. Patrons choose from a buffet containing a variety of sliced frozen meats (beef, chicken, pork, lamb, shrimp and imitation crab). You take a bowl, fill it with the meats and noodles of your choosing, and then move down to the vegetable line where you can choose from a large selection of fresh vegetables to be used in your custom stir-fry.

  

After filling your bowl with your preferred meats and vegetables, you then add sauces to flavor your stir-fry, such as Garlic Sauce, Cooking Wine, House Sauce, Dragon Sauce, Teriyaki, Curry, Lobster Sauce. There is a sign over the sauce bar that suggests which sauces and flavorings you should choose, depending on how spicy you would like it. After you have your bowl filled with meats, noodle, vegetables and sauces, you take it to the Barbeque Area, where your stir-fry is cooked right in front of you.

 

 Price guide: $15 All-You-Can-Eat Buffet or $10 for a single plate
 What I ordered:  Everyone receives an appetizer as part of the cost of the buffet. There is Hot and Sour Soup, a Fried Wonton, and a tender BBQ Marinated Chicken Wing.

  

My first plate consisted of beef, thin noodles, peppers, zucchini, broccoli, onion, carrot, and pineapple. I love spicy and flavorful food, so I used a ton of the garlic sauce, fresh cilantro, several scoops of the dragon Sauce, cooking wine, house sauce and teriyaki. It was delicious!! I have been to Khan&apos;s several times and have finally figured out the amount and combination of sauces that I like the best. One thing i have noticed is that it seems safe to go a little overboard with the sauces, because a lot of the moisture is cooked out and the noodles also absorb a lot of sauce. Despite how much spicy Dragon Sauce I added, it wasn&apos;t as hot as I like it. The best part is that if you don&apos;t care for your stir-fry, you can always go back to the Buffet line and start over with a new combination!

  

Sticky Buns are also served with dinner, a dough-like pastry filled with a buttery cinnamon/sugar sauce. I did not try this because I was already too full from the other good stuff!

 

 Service:  Our server was very friendly and prompt, kept drinks refilled and removed dirty plates in a very timely fashion. It can get extremely busy on weekend evenings, so it is a good idea to call-ahead for a reservation, especially if you plan to have a party larger than four.
 Overall Impression: If you enjoy stir-fry, Khan&apos;s is your place! The endless trips to the buffet for only $15 is a great deal.
 Sep 15, 2008 9:59:00 PM | Asian Variety , Bar , Coon Rapids , Dinner Buffet , Lunch Buffet , Mongolian , On-Site Parking , Richfield , Roseville 
 Comment 1 Reblog It 0 
 
March 13, 2008
 
 Good Earth- Roseville, MN&amp;Edina, MN 
 
 Cuisine: Healthy Eating, American
 Restaurant Features: On-Site Parking

 Locations: Roseville, MN Edina, MN
 Addresses&amp;Maps: 
 Roseville - 1910 West Highway 36 Roseville, MN 55113 651-636-0956                          
 Edina- Galleria 3460 Galleria Edina, MN 55435 952-925-1001
Hours: Monday-Saturday 7am-10pm Sunday 7am-9pm

 Links: Good Earth Website 

 
 Atmosphere: The inside of the Good Earth has an natural feel to with earth-colored decor. There are booths around the outside of the restaurant and several wooden tables and chairs in the middle, easy to combine for larger groups.

 

 Menu: Breakfast foods include fresh juices&amp;smoothies, Organic Oatmeal, Granola, Ten-grain Hotcakes, Buttermilk Pancakes, Corn Cakes, Cinnamon French Toast, Wild Mushroom Omelette, Veggie Omelette, Tomato Basil Omelette, Turkey Sausage Scramble, Grilled Salmon Hash, Good Earth Huevoa, Breakfast Quesadillas, Black Bean Roaster, Breakfast Wrap, Bacon&amp;Eggs, and the Heartland Breakfast.

Woks&amp;Steamers include Coconut Curried Shrimp, Szechuan Chicekn, Steamed Veggies&amp;Brown Rice, Mandarin Orange Beef, Thai Chicken Noodles, Steamed Salmon&amp;Veggies, Seared Shrimp.

Sandwiches include Thai Chicken Wrap, Harvest Wrap, Grilled Shrimp Club, Cashew Chicken Melt, Almond Tuna Salad, Turkey Club, Grilled Veggie, Smoked Turkey and Provolone, Turkey Burger, Planet Burger,and Bison Burger.

Entrees include Teriyaki Chicken, Thai Chicken Satay, Scallops and Penne, Chicken Quesadillas, Whole Wheat Tostada, Salmon Cakes, Vegetarian Enchiladas, Lemon Caper Tilapia, Grilled Salmon and Mango Salsa, Turkey Meatloaf, Black Beans&amp;Rice, Wild Salmon with Root Vegetables, Greek Pizza and Thai Chicken Pizza.

Good Earth also has a large selection of fresh soups and salads.

 Price guide: Breakfast $7-10 Woks&amp;Steamers $11-15 Sandwiches $9-11 Entrees $9-15
 What I ordered: To start with, we were given a nice basket of breads, including crispy, flat crackers and fresh multi-grain bread, served with a side of fresh hummus.

 

I was torn between getting the chicken quesadilla, veggie enchilada, or Thai chicken wrap, so I asked my server his opinion. He said that of the three, the Thai Chicken wrap had the most flavor and was on the spicy side, so I went with his suggestion. I thought the wrap was good, but it wasn&apos;t packed with as much flavor as I was hoping, although I could taste each individual vegetable and the only spice I detected was cilantro. The peanut sauce was good, but very thin.

 My companion ordered the veggie enchilada. I wish I would&apos;ve gone with this entree! It was loaded with sauteed veggies including a variety of peppers, so it was packed with flavor! I am not positive, but I think the rice was cilantro-lime.

 

 Service: We were able to be seated immediately. Our server was very knowledgeable about the menu and helpful (although I was disappointed with his suggestion). 
 Overall Impression: The restaurant filled up very quickly by 6pm with people eagerly awaiting healthier food choices. Good Earth is a good choice for the health-conscious on a reasonable buck for fresh and organic ingredients.
 Mar 13, 2008 9:49:00 AM | American , Edina , Healthy Eating , On-Site Parking , Roseville 
 Comment 0 Reblog It 0 
 
August 06, 2007
 
 Big Bowl Fresh Chinese&amp;Thai ~ Roseville, Edina,&amp;Wayzata, MN 
 
 Cuisine: Chinese and Thai 

 Restaurant Features: Bar 
 

 Locations: Roseville (site of this review), Edina, Wayzata 

 Addresses: 

 Roseville (Rosedale Center) 1705 Highway 36 West Roseville, MN 55113 (651) 636-7173 

 Edina  3669 Galleria Edina, MN 55435 (952) 928-7888 

 Minnetonka (Ridgedale Center) 12649 Wayzata Blvd Minnetonka, MN 55305 (952) 797-9888 

 Links: Big Bowl Website   Google Map 

 





































































































 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 Atmosphere: Located inside Rosedale Mall, Big Bowl is a large restaurant with a trendy Asian flair. There are several booths around the edges of the dining area and in the bar area, with many smaller tables within the middle. At the back of the restaurant near the kitchen is an area for make-your-own stir-fry. 

 



















































































 Menu: Appetizers include steamed Chinese dumplings, veggie or chicken pot stickers, hot buns filled with pork, chicken satay, egg rolls, Thai-beef lettuce wraps, shrimp summer roll, teriyaki spare ribs, calamari, and a few soups and salads. Thai curry dishes include yellow curry with chicken or veggies, panang curry chicken, scallop and shrimp citrus curry, thai green vegetable curry. Chicken dishes include kung pao, orange peel, lemon chicken, chicken with vegetables, and Thai hot pepper chicken. Beef dishes include Mongolian, Kung pao, and beef with broccoli. Seafood dishes include crunchy sichuan cashew shrimp , T hai hot pepper shrimp with basil and peanuts ,  crunchy sichuan scallops , sweet ginger sea scallops and shrimp , and teriyaki glazed fresh salmon. Pad Thai is Big Bowl&apos;s signature dish, try it with vegetables/tofu, chicken, shrimp or salmon. Big Bowl also has a make-it-yourself stirfry bar option. You choose your vegetables, meat, sauce, and noodles and they will cook it for you. 

 Price guide: Appetizers $6-9 Entrees $8-15 

 What I ordered : My companion and I started with an order of the veggie pot stickers (Classic pan fried northern Chinese dumplings stuffed with cilantro, green onions, crushed peanuts) It was also served with three dipping sauces, sweet and sour, plum and sesame mustard. Excellent choice! These pot stickers had a ton of flavor and excellent texture. 

 

















































































































 I wanted to try a curry dish and decided to go with the P anang Curry Chicken 
(chicken, light peanut-coconut curry, peas, snow peas served over jasmine rice). This dish was packed with flavor! The sauce was indeed&quot;light&quot;if they mean&quot;thin&quot;. It was delicious, but I think would prefer it with a little more peanut flavor and if it were a tad bit thicker. The vegetables were very good, but the texture of the chicken was kind of slimy. I enjoyed the first ten bites or so and then got kind of bored with it. 

 



















































































 My companion ordered pad Thai with vegetables. This seemed to be a hit! I tried a little bit of it and thought the noodles had good flavor. As you can see, there were a lot of veggies in the dish. 

 





















































 Service: The host staff was very friendly, as was our server. I think the server may have been new though, as he was not as knowledgeable about the menu as he could&apos;ve been. 

 Overall Impression: Great ambiance and decent food. 
 Aug 6, 2007 12:50:00 PM | Asian Variety , Bar , Chinese , Edina , Minnetonka , Roseville , Thai 
 Comment 2 Reblog It 0 
 
July 15, 2007
 
 Keys Cafe&amp;Bakery ~ Minneapolis, Roseville, Spring Lake Park, St Paul, White Bear Lake, and Woodbury, MN 
 
 Cuisine: American, Breakfast, Bakery
 

 Locations: White Bear Lake(site of this review), Minneapolis, Roseville, Spring Lake Park, St Paul , and Woodbury 

 Addresses: Locations with a * serve dinner 

 *Minneapolis 114 S 9th St   Minneapolis , MN 55402-3308 612-339-6399 

 *Roseville 1682 Lexington Ave N Roseville , MN 55113-6514 651-487-5397 

 *Spring Lake Park 8299 University Ave Ne Spring Lake Park , MN 55432-1867 

 St Paul   500 Robert St N Saint Paul , MN 55101-2246 651-222-4083 

 St Paul 767 Raymond Ave  Saint Paul , MN 55114-1522  651-646-5756 

 *White Bear Lake   2208 4th Street White Bear lake, MN 55110 651-426-2885 

 *Woodbury 1750 Weir Dr  Woodbury , MN 55125-2252 651-731-5397 



   Links: Keys Cafe Website   

 Atmosphere:  Family dining and a local hot spot, especially at breakfast time! 

 



















































































 Menu: Lets start off with breakfast :) Signature breakfasts include a variety of egg/meat combos as well as The&quot;Two Guys&quot;breakfast (named because it is enough food for two!), potatoes with sauteed veggies and cheese, drilled Denver sandwich, egg sandwich, roast beef or Italian hash. Keys is also known for their giant pancakes, french toast and Belgian waffles. There is also a large selection of omelets, including a&quot;build your own&quot;. Specialty sandwiches include Cajun chicken, BBQ chicken, fish fillet, Monte cristo, grilled Reuben or Rachael, meat loaf, steak, roasted turkey or the club house. Grilled sandwiches such as the tuna, turkey, bacon&amp;cheese, chicken and BLT are also quite good, as are the homemade soups and salads. Dinner items include the oven roasted turkey, meat loaf, roast beef, roasted pork, walleye, pork chops and spaghetti. All dinners are served with mashed potatoes, gravy and bread. 

 Keys is also famous for their bakery....pies, cakes, scones, muffins, cookies. 

 Price guide: Breakfast $ 4-9 Sandwiches $ 6-9 Dinners $ 9-11 

 What I ordered: Combo #2 (two eggs with Italian hash). Keys famous Italian sausage with mushrooms, onions, green peppers, tomatoes and hash browns. This is my favorite breakfast! I love the spiciness of the sausage with the texture of the sauteed veggies and hashbrowns. The thick sliced homemade bread toasted with keys homemade strawberry jam is also delicious 

 























































































 My companion ordered the farmer&apos;s omelet (ham, onions and cheese) with a side of hashbrowns. This was a very large omelet, stuffed full of ingredients. 

 









































 Service:  Our visit was at a non-peak hour and was kind of slow. Took awhile for the hostess to see us and then seat us. 

 Overall Impression: Large selection of breakfast dishes, reasonably priced. Good place to meet a group for breakfast (as long as you don&apos;t mind waiting to be seated, as it is very busy on Sat-Sunday mornings.) 
 Jul 15, 2007 3:07:00 PM | American , Bakery , Breakfast , Downtown Minneapolis , Minneapolis , Roseville , Spring Lake Park , St Paul , White Bear Lake area , Woodbury 
 Comment 2 Reblog It 0 
 
July 06, 2007
 
 Romano&apos;s Macaroni Grill ~ Burnsville, Edina, Minnetonka, Roseville, MN 
 
 Cuisine: Italian, Pizza
 

 Restaurant Features: Bar , On-Site Parking (for all but Rosedale Mall location) 
 

 Location: Burnsville, Edina, Minnetonka, and Roseville, MN
 

 Addresses&amp;Maps:   

 Burnsville - 1025 Country Road 42 Burnsville, MN 55337 (952) 898-4366 
 
 Get Directions 

 Edina - 7651 France Ave S Edina, MN 55435 (952) 844-0084 
 
 Get Directions 

 Minnetonka - 11390 Wayzata Blvd Minnetonka, MN 55305 (952) 417-9880 
 
 Get Directi Roseville - Rosedale Mall 1705 Highway 36 W Roseville, MN 55113-3011 651-633-2148 

 Links: Macaroni Grill website    

 



















































































 Atmosphere: Dimly lit and somewhat romantic, you might not even realize that you are situated within the Rosedale Mall. There is a mix of tables and booths underneath a wooden faux-gazebo structure. 

 



















































































 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 

 Menu: Appetizers include bruschetta, fried mozzarella, shrimp&amp;artichoke dip, calamari, crab-stuffed mushrooms and parmesan crusted artichokes.
 

 Pasta dishes include the Pasta Romano, penne rustica, shrimp portofino, vodka rustica, seafood linguine or create-your-own pasta from a choice of pastas and sauces. Stuffed pastas include lobster ravioli, chicken cannelloni, and chicken marsala ravioli. 
 

 Classic dishes include chicken or veal marsala, chicken, eggplant or veal Parmesan, fettuccine Alfredo, spaghetti with meatballs, chicken and shrimp scaloppine and twice baked lasagna.
 

 Meat entrees include chicken portabello, steak, grilled halibut or salmon, grilled porkchops, and honey balsalmic chicken There are also a selection of brick-oven pizzas, salads and soups. 

 Price guide : Appetizers- $5-10  Pastas- %9-16 Meat Entrees- $12-21 







































 What I ordered : Macaroni Grill always provides free loaves of their fresh, hot bread. Break off a piece and dip it in the olive oil provided. Delish! The texture is light, similar to ciabatta. 

 











































 For my entree I ordered the Mama&apos;s Trio, a sampler of the chicken parmesan, chicken canneloni, and twice baked lasagna. The chicken parmesan was very good, as was the lasagna (however the lasagna was warm at best, not hot). The cannelloni had nice flavor, but the outer shell was pretty dry and crunchy. 

 



































 My companion ordered the chicken parmesan entree, served on a bed of angel hair pasta. The size of this chicken was magnificent! The combination of textures with the chicken and angel hair pasta was a big hit. 

 







































 Service: The hosts and serving staff were very friendly and pleasant. Drinks and food served in a timely fashion. 

 Overall Impression: Decent Italian food if you like chain-style restaurants. Prices are comparable to other Italian restaurants of the same caliber, good service. 
 Jul 6, 2007 8:16:00 PM | Bar , Burnsville , Edina , Italian , Minnetonka , Pizza , Roseville 
 Comment 1 Reblog It 0 
 » 
 Twin Cities Restaurant Blog 


 2 Following 125 Followers 
Search
 
My Other Accounts
 
 Twitter | TwinCitiRestBlg 
 
Recent Comments
 
 Mr. Venetian Plaster: I love CRAVE restaurant but had NO idea they di... | more » On Monday Night Wine Classes at CRAVE Pizza Lieferservice Munchen: Those pizza slices are looking very delicious, ... | more » On Pizza Luce ~ Minneapolis, St Paul&amp;Duluth, MN Traci: Try POP! in St.Paul or Minneapolis.
Very good f... | more » On Restaurant Recommendations, please! 
 
 Subscribe to this blog&apos;s feed Powered by TypePad
	</body>
</document>
