<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002133" url="http://ca.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20080519181110AAFiUtS" time="2012-07-12-18:02" support="1" score="0.0010944618487798846" bingtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - How do they make vanilla milk shake at ..." webtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - How do they make vanilla milk shake at Burger King?">
			<query id="001119" bing-rank="127"/>
	<description>Consumer Electronics; Dining Out; Education ... if the cup is facing the wrong way your cup ... Discover Questions in Fast Food. Healthy fast food restaurant names?</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Canada Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog (USA) 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Dining Out &gt; Fast Food &gt; Resolved Question 
 Bela Member since: January 27, 2008 Total points: 576 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
How do they make vanilla milk shake at Burger King?

 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by Clarissa S Member since: May 11, 2008 Total points: 794 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 You have a vanilla mix that comes in this plastic type of bag/carton and you dump in into the machine which keeps it at a certain temperature and depending on what flavor you want you have different syrups that mix in with the vanilla flavoring.. but your just asking about vanilla.. PS. you press the vanilla button, put the cup on the holder and pull the lever down but you have to be careful if the cup is facing the wrong way your cup can fall of.. the cups are automatically measured to know how much to fill it up with

haha sorry I think I just got a little carried away but you get the point ;) 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 33% 3 Votes 
 2 people rated this as good 
 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; How do they make van… &quot;was originally asked in Yahoo! Answers United States 
 
 Other Answers (5)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by Mommie in September Member since: May 14, 2008 Total points: 230 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 They don&apos;t it comes from a large metal machine just like soft serve icecream. Most fast food establishments choose this method because making a hand-dipped milkshake is a little more expensive and a little more time consuming. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 22% 2 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Bad Habit Member since: April 25, 2008 Total points: 658 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 squeze a vanilla cow same with chocolate. But imagine the peanut butter and cookies and cream. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes by Bigdog Member since: March 30, 2006 Total points: 7,739 (Level 5) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Not trying to be sarcastic, but with a vanilla milk shake machine and their mix that comes in a carton. So do all the other fast food joints. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 22% 2 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by Frenchie Member since: May 09, 2008 Total points: 525 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 As disgusting as it is to say, most fast food places have lard in their milk shakes. Yeah... lard... in a milk shake... ew. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 11% 1 Vote 
 1 person rated this as good 
 by reneethe... Member since: April 19, 2008 Total points: 127 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 with the milkshake machine. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 0% 0 Votes 
 1 person rated this as good 
 
 
Discover Questions in Fast Food 

 Interview questions for McDonalds? ? What time does Mcdonalds stop serving apple pies UK? New at working at Sonic Drive-Inn? Any Tips? Will i get hired at McDonald&apos;s ? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
Related Questions

 how many calories does the chocolate milkshake from burger… Is a Burger King vanilla shake made with real ice cream? How much does the biggest chocolate shake at burger king cost? what should i do if i found an acrylic nail in my burger king… How far are you from the nearest Burger King? 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Dining Out 
 Argentina Australia Austria Brazil Canada Fast Food France Germany India Indonesia Ireland Italy Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Other - Dining Out Philippines Singapore Spain Switzerland Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Sponsor Results
 Best Burger Recipes Chef Tested Burger Press, fast and easy to create burgers www.chefdepot.com Vanilla Milkshake Get Answers Faster at Ask.com. Try It Now! Ask.com SanRe Organic Skinfood Vanilla Sensation - 100% USDA Organic -OR- SPF 30 Body... www.sanreorganic.com See your message here... 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Canada Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Canada Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines
	</body>
</document>
