<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002747" url="http://www.nachas.org/BethYehuda/kosher.html" time="2012-07-12-18:48" support="6" score="0.00902956589493542" bingtitle="New York State Kosher Restaurants by Location" webtitle="New York State Kosher Restaurants by Location">
			<query id="000392" bing-rank="167"/>
			<query id="001156" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="001309" bing-rank="35"/>
			<query id="001145" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="001459" bing-rank="205"/>
			<query id="001157" bing-rank="27"/>
	<description>Disclaimer: The restaurants below are listed for informational purposes only. ... Nosh World Ice Cream. 845 794-1854. 121 Broadway, Monticello. Dairy R&apos; Yechiel Babad ...</description>
	<body>
		We detected that your JavaScript seem to be disabled. 

You must have JavaScript enabled in your browser to utilize the functionality of this website.
 
 

 Skip to Main Content» 
 Search Site Welcome to Nachas Unlimited
 
 My Account My Cart Checkout Log In 
 
 Home About Us Zecher L&apos;Churban Artwork Books Past Projects Kosher Restaurants 
 By Location By Name Kosher Symbols 
 
 
You&apos;re currently on:

 Home / New York State Kosher Restaurants by Location 
 
 Disclaimer: The restaurants below are listed for informational purposes only. This does not imply an endorsement of the kashrut of any of the establishments. Some restaurants are open on shabbat, some have supervision in name only or may have other aspects of their supervision that might bring their kashrut into question. If you are interested in visiting any of these restaurants, you must first verify that they are still open, as well as investigating the legitimacy of the hashgacha. If you have any questions regarding the kashrut supervision, please consult your local orthodox rabbi.

This page provides a list of the restaurants in New York state, sorted by region and proximity one to the next. In Manhattan they are sorted from downtown to uptown, east side to west side, and acsending street address.


 Price guidelines: (the column headed &apos;$&apos;) 

1 - lowest price range: fast food, pizza parlors, Chinese take-out, etc. Generally under $10/person. A rating of &apos;1&apos; indicates that it is low priced for the type of food that it is serving, even though a Chinese place might charge twice as much as a pizza place.
2 - mid-range prices: cafes, delis, lunch/dinner, etc. Generally $10-$30/person
3 - high price range: Restaurants in which you are paying a premium for ambiance. Generally over $30/person.

Starting in 2010, I am highlighting my updates, for a few weeks so that you can see what has changed or has been added.


This is intended to be as up-to-date as practical. If you have information about any of these establishments that is more correct than what you see here, or if you know of any restaurants not listed here, then please contact me with the information that you see in the headings. Please email to DFriedman613@gmail.com or contact me by phone at (home) 718 983-6415 or (work) 212 339-2862 with updated information, deletions, additions or corrections.

One other thing: It might be wise to check out any restaurant that you are interested in, with the City Department of Health, Restaurant Inspection Information web site (follow the &quot;Inspection Results&quot; link). Keep in mind that this reflects only a moment in time, and that many if not most restaurants have some type of violation against them.

 



 Downtown Manhattan | Upper East Side | Upper West Side | Queens | Brooklyn | Bronx 
 Staten Island | Long Island | Monsey | Elsewhere in New York | Resorts | Stadiums 
 
 Manhattan (212 or 917) 
 
 
 Name 
 
 Phone 
 
 Address 
 
 Category 
 
 $ 
 
 Hashgacha 
 
 Updated 
 
 Dovid&apos;s Kosher Food Stand 
248-9008 
27 William St. (Beaver&amp;Exchg Pl.) 
Meat 
1 
Kosher-K R. Avrohom D Katz 
2/12 
 Crumbs 
480-7500 
87 Beaver (Hanover&amp;Wall) 
Dairy 
 
OKS - R&apos; Harry Cohen 
3/08 
 Cravings 
334-1111 
17 Trinity Place (Morris&amp;Exchange) 
Dairy 
 
 OU , Udvary 
6/12
	</body>
</document>
