<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002975" url="http://www.livedash.com/transcript/anthony_bourdain__no_reservations-(venice)/6630/TRAVP/Tuesday_March_23_2010/232981/" time="2012-07-12-19:04" support="3" score="0.004365700781314013" bingtitle="Anthony Bourdain: No Reservations - Venice - Tuesday, Mar 23, 2010 ..." webtitle="Anthony Bourdain: No Reservations - Venice - Tuesday, Mar 23, 2010 - mReplay Livedash TV Transcript - Livedash - Search what is being mentioned across national TV">
			<query id="000643" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="000018" bing-rank="185"/>
			<query id="000566" bing-rank="102"/>
	<description>... SCARED TO TELL You I&apos;ve got this amount of credit card ... So, why would a fast-food restaurant be on the same list as the ... have to look very long to find our next pick. 00 ...</description>
	<body>
		Enterprise users, login for video or API access&gt; 
 
 
Anthony Bourdain: No Reservations - Venice

TRAVP

 Aired on Tuesday, Mar 23, 2010 (3/23/2010) at 07:00 PM 
 
 View other episodes View more from this channel View all transcripts from (3/23/2010) 
 
Video and Thumbnails
 
Transcript
 
 00:00:28 ]sayit&apos;s really hard to save for the futureand they&apos;ve come to a point where it&apos;s overwhelming. 00:00:33 [ Advisor 2 ] OH GEE, I&apos;M SCARED TO TELLYouI&apos;ve got this amount of credit card debtor I&apos;ve got a 15-year-oldand we never got around to saving for theircollege. 00:00:42 That&apos;s when I go to work. 00:00:43 We talk, we start planning. 00:00:45 We can fix this. I know we can do it. 00:00:48 When clients walk out of my officethey feel confident about their retirement. 00:00:52 [ Male Announcer ]VISIT AMERIPRISE.COMAnd put a confident retirementmore withinreach. 00:02:41 [ Indistinct whispering ][ gulls calling ][ bell tolling ]Man:&quot;To romano, a patron of the arts --&quot;they are rare in these days --&quot;from his friend ernest hemingway&quot;24 bound volumes in the life of a restaurant. 00:03:18 De Mori: Volumes of guest books from whenthey first opened,signed matisse and miró. 00:03:25 Man #2: From maria callas, enrico fermi. 00:03:28 Artists, statesmen, authors, musicians. 00:03:32 So, here&apos;s some music. 00:03:34 Somebody wrote a little ditty. 00:03:36 Scribbled drawings, expressions of gratitude,poetry, and prose. 00:03:44 Philip of habsburg came and had the riceand loved the rice and said,&quot;i&apos;ll have more,&quot;and he said,&quot;i&apos;m not gonna give you anymore. 00:03:51 &quot;what is it about this placeon the fairly remote, isolated outer islandof burano? 00:04:09 Traditionally an island of fishermen,row after row of bright, pastel-colored houses,so the fishermen could see themback in the day when returning from sea. 00:04:21 The women of the island were once masterlace makers --today, not so much. 00:04:29 But what is left is well wortha 45-minute boat ride to this tiny island,or at least that&apos;s what lori de mori says. 00:04:36 She&apos;s an american cookbook author and foodwriterwho&apos;s been living in italy for decades. 00:04:40 There are two principal groups who come toburano --those shopping for the famous laceand people like me and lori,who are looking for one thing --a perfected dish that can be found at thisplace, da romano. 00:04:53 Local painters, it started out with,elected this place, you know -- this wastheir hangout. 00:04:58 Ah, right. 00:04:59 This was the place they came to, and youknow the way it goes. 00:05:02 Then visiting artists find outthat that&apos;s where all the artists go,and then, suddenly, that&apos;s where everybody&apos;sgoing. 00:05:11 FROM THE 1800s,Five generations of a single family haverun this place,handing down recipes from parents to children,never deviating from simple, good things. 00:05:21 The walls are covered with the work of long-deadadmirers,and their signatures fill the guest book. 00:05:27 But life and cooking go on. 00:05:29 Hemingway and matisse and miró are gone,but keith richards comes straight here whenin venice. 00:05:35 Keith richards? he&apos;s right about everything. 00:05:37 Fourth-generation proprietor luigi santo. 00:05:41 [ Santo speaking italian ]tony, you&apos;ll like this. 00:05:45 He says this is heroic cooking. 00:05:48 A lot of people who don&apos;t know muchabout traveling in a certain way --they want to have spaghetti and meatballs. 00:05:54 And, actually, he says to stay steadfastand say,&quot;you know what? this is good enough. 00:06:00 &quot;It&apos;s not only good enough, it&apos;s perfect. 00:06:01 &quot;does he agree? 00:06:05 Does he feel a compulsion to innovate? 00:06:09 No. 00:06:09 [ Speaking italian ]the fifth generation -- his son luca. 00:06:13 De Mori: He&apos;s for simplicity, and he thinksthat this tradition is the right road. 00:06:18 What if a bunch of really hot girlsstart showing up here every night --it&apos;s like&quot;sex and the city,&quot;but youngerand hotter --and they all want cosmos? 00:06:26 [ Speaking italian ]he says he thinks he can make them stay,even if he keeps offering the same thingthey&apos;ve been offering for the last hundredyears. 00:06:41 That would include stufflike this assortment from the lagoon --cuttlefish roe, sea snails,baby octopus, and mantis shrimp,all cooked in the only restaurant kitchenin veniceallowed to still use a wood fire. 00:06:53 It&apos;s a lot of work. 00:06:55 Bourdain: The wood has to be brought in. 00:06:55 Bring in the wood. 00:06:57 It&apos;s also bloody hot in there. 00:06:59 It&apos;s summertime, and they&apos;ve still got thisthing raging. 00:07:01 And a lot of people say to them, like,&quot;and, you know, the flavor is not the same. 00:07:05 Tastes good. 00:07:07 Yeah. yeah. 00:07:08 And this is something.. 00:07:13 The polenta -- grilled polenta? 00:07:14 Grilled polenta, white. 00:07:15 Polenta is a fundamental staple of venetiancuisine --usually, but not always white cornmeal,usually, but not always grilled. 00:07:23 And then the sardine is cooked in vinegar. 00:07:26 And so you have this sort of sweetness from.. 00:07:28 Right. and the vinegar, which preserves it. 00:07:30 That&apos;s delicious -- one of my favorite fish,by the way. 00:07:33 Sardine? yes. 00:07:35 A lot of flavor for your money, no? 00:07:37 But, really, if there&apos;s one dishworth crossing the lagoon for, if not halfthe world,it&apos;s this. 00:07:43 It&apos;s a dish that, all alone,makes venice, and burano in particular,a place you just have to visit --go risotto. 00:08:08 Fish risotto needs to beds.. 00:08:13 Right. in order to behave. 00:08:15 In the brilliant film&quot;big night,&quot;there&apos;s a painful moment where an ignorantcustomer looksat an authentic, perfectly prepared orderof seafood risotto&quot;and, yes, go risotto is rice, but what rice. 00:08:32 So, this is what we&apos;re having, which they&apos;rereally famous for. 00:08:35 [ Speaking italian ]oh, so this is a real classic fisherman&apos;s.. 00:08:40 OF THE EARLY 1900s, MADE WITH A FISH CALLEDGo. 00:08:45 Go is not a prized fish. 00:08:46 It&apos;s one of those fish that burrow down --ugly, little, fat fish. 00:08:51 A lot of bones, so it&apos;s not a fishyou&apos;d want to eat as a fish,but it&apos;s a fish you&apos;d want to use for flavor. 00:08:56 So, they make this broth out of it. 00:08:58 They have to simmer it really, really gently,because if they break it up,it lets out this black, bitter --and it really isn&apos;t nice. 00:09:07 The way they handle the broth --&quot;simmer the broth. in goes the rice. 00:09:24 Mix it, and that&apos;s all that happensis they keep adding the broth. 00:09:28 An amazing confluence of physical forcesof the universecome together into a substancethat can only be described as otherworldly. 00:09:37 And that just goes slowly, slowly, slowly. 00:09:39 The fats and essences of the fish,the textural magic of arborio rice,a miracle of gradual, gradual absorption. 00:09:48 .. [ speaking italian ]they&apos;re trying to make it creamy withoutadding cream. 00:09:53 A kind of alchemy --movement altering texture, texture enhancingflavor. 00:09:58 Sort of hits the pan and flips the rice soit&apos;s creamy. 00:10:02 There is risotto, and then there is greatrisotto,and then, once in a very, very long time,there is truly great risotto. 00:10:10 It&apos;s just that go. it&apos;s just the broth. 00:10:13 It better really be good, or there&apos;s nothingelse. 00:10:15 This is what they mean when they say trulygreat,and I guess two centuries of artists recognizedthat, too. 00:10:23 It looks so plain. it&apos;s just white. right. 00:10:26 And then you taste it. 00:10:27 It&apos;s like the distilled essence of the adriatic. 00:10:29 It&apos;s absolutely full of flavor. right. 00:10:31 Oh, man, that&apos;s beautiful. 00:10:33 This is absolutely fantastic, by the way. 00:10:36 The flavor is superb. 00:10:37 And look at how these are like little pearls. 00:10:39 They&apos;re definitely all keeping their ownpersonality. 00:10:42 I absolutely agree. 00:10:45 To heroic cooking. mmm. 00:10:47 [ Speaking italian ].. 00:10:52 Always slowly, slowly, slowly. 00:10:54 ...There&apos;s more to venice than humping gondolasup and down the canals, like moving hugetankers around. 00:10:59 Bourdain: That line breaks, it&apos;ll whip your.. 00:11:02 And as always, I find myself pitching in. 00:11:05 ...Which means that, if we stay here,we&apos;ll be crushed like a proverbial pancake. 00:11:11 )♪♪♪♪ 00:11:21 Mmm... HOT FUDGE SUNDAE. 00:11:24 ♪♪♪♪ 00:11:25 !? 00:11:28 ♪♪♪♪ 00:11:31 over 25 flavorsof kellogg&apos;s pop-tarts®®. 00:11:33 And they&apos;re all for funand fun for all. 00:11:37 Pop-tarts®®. made for fun. 00:11:40 coversamericans. 00:11:44 That&apos;s right, 97%. 00:11:45 Which means you can talk, text, email orgo onlinefrom almost anywhere. 00:11:50 So whether you&apos;re in portland, oregon,.. 00:11:54 , or seattle, washington,or somewhere in between,at&amp;t has the coverage you need. 00:12:02 Hopefully that sheds a little light on thesubject. 00:12:06 ♪♪ ♪♪ 00:12:11 warms,makers.. 00:12:13 Want to make sure allergies don&apos;t alwayshave to keep you cooped up inside. 00:12:15 That&apos;s why we&apos;re making it easier for everyoneto find allergy solutions. 00:12:19 By offering products likenew zyrtec liquidgels. 00:12:22 Zyrtec, the fastest 24-hourallergy medicine,is now availablein a liquid gel. 00:12:26 .. 00:12:29 Indoors and out. 00:12:30 You&apos;ll also getthe expert advice of yourwalgreens pharmacist. 00:12:33 So you&apos;ll feel freerto love the air. 00:12:36 Walgreens.there&apos;s a way to stay well. 00:12:41 madduxloveseveryonehow drivers can get discountsup to 40 percent. 00:12:44 I --your neighbors can tell you, too. 00:12:46 Chances are they&apos;re some ofstate farm&apos;s 40million drivers. 00:12:49 My --so talk to them. 00:12:50 Then cl a state farmagent like carrie. 00:12:53 Call me. 00:14:26 De Mori: The truth is, we feel ourselvesto be a bit superior to everybody else,&apos;cause we have an ancient culture,and most people who come here -- they don&apos;thave that. 00:14:37 What is a venetian? 00:14:39 What are venetians like? 00:14:41 And what do they do? 00:14:42 To the casual visitor,it&apos;s the guy who pilots the gondola aroundtownor some wealthy mummyfrom an old and impeccably despotic familystill living in a corner of one of the grandpalazzos. 00:14:53 But there are other venetians and, in fact,another venice. 00:14:59 [ Air horns blowing ]morning. 00:15:06 This is lori&apos;s friend stefano benedetelli,born and bred venetian. 00:15:11 And this is venice, too. 00:15:13 Stefano is a mooring man,and he makes his money, as does much of venice,from the vitally important commercial industrialcomplexof porto marghera,a place they don&apos;t show you in the tourismfilmsbut as vital to venice&apos;s everyday life andsurvivalas the grand canal. 00:15:30 [ Speaking italian ]we wouldn&apos;t live just selling postcards. 00:15:33 Chemicals here, energy -- oil and coal --over here, and cargo thataway? 00:15:39 Yeah. 00:15:40 [ Speaking italian ]85% of the economy of venicepasses through this port. 00:15:47 Looks like new jersey, which is where I grewup,and so far, it smells a lot better. 00:15:53 [ Air horn blows ]hey! 00:15:58 Stefano&apos;s job --to get big freaking ships, like this one,tied up and safely docked. 00:16:04 Always slowly, slowly, slowly. 00:16:06 Bourdain: How many ships this size come ina day? 00:16:10 About 55, 40. 00:16:11 [ Air horn blowing ]first, the tugs do their job. 00:16:14 The tug sort of receives the boat from thesea to come in. 00:16:17 Right, and they turn -- I saw it turn themaround. 00:16:20 Helps it turn it around --I mean, it&apos;s like being a big bull in a smallchina shop. 00:16:23 So this is, like, really delicate work, youknow? yeah. 00:16:26 And it&apos;s kind of like lassoing the world&apos;slargest bull,only lots biggerand filled with highly flammable toxic chemicalsand slower-moving and, like, floating. 00:16:37 Okay, bad metaphor. 00:16:40 The ship&apos;s mates drop their mooring linesto stefano and his crew, who dart around,threading the needle, as it were, again andagain. 00:16:47 Gulliver and the lilliputians come to mind. 00:16:49 Ready to hitch up the mule train and pullthem in, right --which means that, if we stay here,we&apos;ll be crushed like a proverbial pancake. 00:16:54 Yeah, you would. 00:16:55 That line breaks, it&apos;ll whip your head cleanoff. 00:16:58 [ Rope snaps ]be a little pink mistand a nubbin left where your head used tobe. 00:17:04 I hate when that happens. 00:17:05 They&apos;re really good. 00:17:06 I mean, you know, there&apos;s some real choreographygoing on here. 00:17:09 It&apos;s sort of like ballet or a japanese bondagefilm --not that I&apos;ve seen any of those. 00:17:14 I hooked this up myself, by the way. 00:17:16 Just doing my bit to help the economy. 00:17:18 Come on, little fella. come on into port. 00:17:21 Bring her on in, boys. 00:17:23 Good job. I think it&apos;s miller time. 00:17:31 [ Benedetelli speaking italian ]so, like good italians, pasta is fundamental. 00:17:36 Bourdain: Pasta&apos;s fundamental. 00:17:37 Is lunch the big meal of the day or is dinner? 00:17:40 [ Speaking italian ] lunch. lunch. 00:17:42 Lunchtime -- in this case,when our planned scene falls through,a last-minute choice at any old place. 00:17:48 Stefano picks trattoria borgi in historicvenice,and naturally, it turns out to be perfect. 00:17:53 Now, ordinarily, most of the time, in thecafeteria? 00:17:56 Often, they go onboard of the boat. 00:17:58 How are the cooks? 00:17:59 Finissimo. really? 00:18:01 [ Speaking italian ]basically, those guys are on the boat formonths,and if the food is no good, the cook&apos;s thrownoverboard. 00:18:07 Man: Ciao. ciao. 00:18:08 We&apos;re joined by some of stefano&apos;s colleagues,.. 00:18:14 Ooh. bello. 00:18:15 ...Which works out just fine for everybody,&apos;cause there&apos;s lots of it. 00:18:18 Sardines and onions -- typical, ubiquitous. 00:18:22 Got to have the baccalàà mantecatoand some seafood, maybe some grilled vegetables. 00:18:27 What is the common personality type? 00:18:29 Is there a common personality type? 00:18:31 [ Speaking italian ]slightly dissident, not quick to hand outthe friendship. 00:18:38 If you earn it, it&apos;s for life and a surething. 00:18:42 Everybody seems to know each other here. 00:18:44 You know everybody at least by sight,and if not, by -- you know, you actuallyreally know them. 00:18:49 Next up -- pasta, because without pasta,the meal is a sin against godand everything that is good and decent inthe world --in this case, some clams and mussels fromthe lagoonand not too much garlic and some good oliveoil,spectacular in its simplicity, in its beingunspectacular. 00:19:07 Who are the worst [bleep] tourists thereare? 00:19:10 [ Speaking italian ]it&apos;s not a nationality. it&apos;s a sort of tourist. 00:19:15 It&apos;s the day-tripper. 00:19:16 Ah, so they come in on the cruise ship? 00:19:19 Or just on the train. 00:19:20 It&apos;s kind of this difficulty,&apos;cause rushing does not exist in the venetianculture. 00:19:26 And the tourists need to rush. 00:19:27 And so it&apos;s one thing that creates this instantdivide. 00:19:31 Go rush. run, if you want. 00:19:33 You know, there is no rushing. 00:19:39 [ Speaking italian ]the truth is, we feel ourselves.. 00:19:44 &apos;cause we have an ancientculture,and most people who come here -- they don&apos;thave that. 00:19:49 I think that&apos;s a completely reasonable attitude. 00:19:52 [ Speaking italian ]I mean, you know, look around. 00:19:55 So the world has to learn to adjust to venetiantime. 00:20:00 Yes. 00:20:03 Pasta and time --ordinary things, birthrights --another day in venice. 00:20:11 .. 00:20:12 What&apos;s kept an eccentric bohemian artistfrom englandfrom ever leaving venice? 00:20:16 Humphries: I found myself in a differentdimension and couldn&apos;t get out. 00:20:19 As one might guess, venice isn&apos;t such a badplaceto be an artist -- starving or otherwise. 00:20:24 Enlightened view of extending credit? 00:20:26 A lot of these paintings are extended credit. 00:21:22 its1936and now we&apos;re insuring over 18 million drivers. 00:21:25 Gecko: quite impressive, yeah. 00:21:28 Boss: come a long way, that&apos;s for sure. 00:21:29 And so have you since you started workinghere way back when. 00:21:40 Gecko: ah, I still have nightmares. 00:21:44 15 minutes couldsave you 15%or more on car insurance. 00:21:51 Announcer:.. 00:21:52 Reservations under griswold. 00:21:54 .. 00:21:56 Oh. 00:21:57 We have you in the napoleon suite. 00:22:01 .. 00:22:03 .. 00:22:06 What the? 00:22:07 And hidden charges. 00:22:08 You even charged mefor the complimentary bottle of water? 00:22:10 It&apos;s complementary with an &apos;e&apos;. 00:22:13 The water complements the room. 00:22:14 It&apos;s not free. 00:22:15 Bad, sparky. 00:22:16 See the filmat homeaway. com. 00:22:18 Rent a house for halfthe cost of a hotel. 00:24:44 [ Bell tolling, clock ticking ][ bell chiming ]time -- venice&apos;s seeming timelessness,the assumption that, well, she&apos;s been here,she surely always will be -- is a centralirony. 00:25:10 Tourists and short-time visitorscan never fully grab venice. 00:25:14 Staying is difficult and increasingly pricey. 00:25:17 Costs rise. the number of natives shrinks. 00:25:20 The buildings themselves slowly crumble --a living museum of millennium-old masterworksinexorably dying. 00:25:27 Artists and poets from elsewherehave always been transfixed by her noblerot. 00:25:32 Humphries: You must remember, looking outof the windowis probably the biggest waste of time inlife,but what else can one doif one has to do nothing with it whatsoever? 00:25:42 Following in the footstepsof fellow englishmen besotted with venicelike lord byron,artist geoffrey humphries came to venice40 years ago --coming, for instance, for what one sees fromhis window. 00:25:53 I found myself in a different dimensionand couldn&apos;t get out of it. 00:26:03 There was an artistic community here anda feeling. 00:26:08 Maybe I was going back in time,but I&apos;ve wanted to always go back in time. 00:26:12 Don&apos;t we all? 00:26:13 All that, and the natural light makes painting,like the city itself, a slowly passing thing. 00:26:19 Geoffrey lives on the giudecca,the large island saddling venice proper. 00:26:24 Nobody would touch the giudecca. 00:26:25 .. [ speaking italian ]once a kind of low-rent refugefor the broke and bohemian classes,now, as with so many other formerly industrialdistricts,all the tics -- posh hotels,the scourge of hipness spreading like chlamydia. 00:26:40 Geoffrey, unsurprisingly,is not too happy about the change. 00:26:45 Geoffrey paints portraits,often casting contemporary venetiansas figures from the past. 00:26:50 Today, he arrests timeby capturing his wife and daughter,even while the late-afternoon daylight --his favorite source of illumination --fades and slowly dies. 00:27:01 With a few strokes, he freezes this momentin time --woman with child, late afternoon, venice--never to happen precisely like this again. 00:27:16 There it is. there it was. 00:27:24 Well, we came here one lunchtime and atein the garden. 00:27:28 It was totally empty. wooden chairs and benches. 00:27:31 Geoffrey leads me back in timeto a favorite restaurant of his younger,hungrier days. 00:27:35 The atmosphere was so rickety -- it was wonderful. 00:27:38 The meal cost a thousand lira. 00:27:40 Geoffrey&apos;s venice can never be the sameas the venice of those born to it. 00:27:44 He knows it. 00:27:45 Yet he&apos;s part of a grand tradition --a world of misfits for whom venice is a stage. 00:27:49 And that, too, has nostalgia, rites of passage,and special entrée for certain professions. 00:27:55 Bourdain: One of yours? yes, that&apos;s in there. 00:27:56 There was always a table here for artists--tavolo d&apos;artista. mm-hmm. 00:28:01 And all these wonderful artists -- they usedto come in and sit. 00:28:03 This is a place with a payment plan not uniqueto these parts. 00:28:07 Enlightened view of extending credit? 00:28:09 A lot of these paintings are extended credit. 00:28:14 Locanda montin -- an old, very old-schooltrattoria --simple classics made well, a place aboutwhich venetiansand particularly longtime ex-patstend to be sentimental,very likely because of their onetime viewthat art was acceptable as legal tender. 00:28:29 The world was very different. 00:28:30 There were no credit cards,but there was credit in a funny way. 00:28:34 My bill got so heavy,so I picked up my paintings from an exhibition,and I told him to select one for himselfto pay my -- cover my bill. 00:28:42 &quot;and I said,&quot;how&quot;&quot;[ laughs ]this is mantis shrimp. 00:28:50 I&apos;m afraid you have to eat this by hand. 00:28:52 Bon appétit, huh? 00:28:53 Oh, boy. they&apos;ve gone overboard. 00:28:56 Pasta in red sauce. 00:28:57 Very happy with this. 00:28:58 [ speaking italian]just -- that&apos;s the tomato, garlic, and pasta. 00:29:04 Mm-hmm. mmm. 00:29:05 As we settle into our meal,I ask geoffrey what he remembers mostabout coming to venice as a young artist. 00:29:11 When I came here, everybody,even the vegetable salesmen, whatever --they all know art. 00:29:17 It&apos;s their life -- michelangelo, the bignames. 00:29:20 But you kind of can&apos;t help it. 00:29:21 You know, you walk down the street,and you&apos;re tripping over stuff. 00:29:25 I learn a lot from the street. 00:29:27 People look at my work, and they say,&quot;ugh,&quot;I said,&quot;sir, you&apos;re just following the sun,&quot;you know, meaning I keep moving the shadow,which is right. 00:29:36 &quot;&quot;&quot;wait, you just hear this from passersby,from venetians? 00:29:42 I&apos;ve picked up a lot of education from thestreet. really? 00:29:45 In a city where art is a birthright,everywhere you lookthe street&apos;s a gallery and everybody an artcritic,this artist has found a venice of his own. 00:29:56 .. 00:29:57 Benelli: Okay, this is forbidden wine. 00:30:00 Why? methyl alcohol. 00:30:01 And if you get drunk with that, probablyyou have some problems. 00:30:04 Yeah, like going blind,but when was the last time I let petty healthconcernsget in the way of a good buzz? 00:31:01 kids! 00:31:01 guys! 00:31:01 Even responsible peopleget into accidents,which is why we do all we canto help you move on after one. 00:31:09 [ Engine turns over ]and when you insureboth your home and car with us,we do it for even less. 00:31:25 Liberty mutual insurance. 00:31:27 Responsibility. 00:31:27 What&apos;s your policy? 00:33:26 Benelli: The venetians --they lasted more than the roman empires --a thousand years. 00:33:32 What constantly surprises about venice iswhat lies beneath --that, all along, she&apos;s been self-sufficientin seafoodand still produces just like the old days,that some things other than the buildingshave decidedly not yet disappeared. 00:33:45 The same wonderfully dysfunctional systemwhich allows her to crumblealso keeps her gloriously unchanged. 00:33:51 And one thing that hasn&apos;t changed erasmoremains,to a great extent, venice&apos;s private greenmarket. 00:34:00 Ciao, tony. good to meet you. 00:34:02 Nice meeting you. yeah. nice meeting you. 00:34:04 So, where we going? 00:34:05 erasmoto see the islands and gardens and this friendof mine. 00:34:10 We&apos;ll taste some forbidden wines and --forbidden? oh, I like it. 00:34:14 St. erasmo -- that&apos;s the garden of venice. 00:34:16 It&apos;s a proper garden. 00:34:18 Which boat&apos;s yours? 00:34:20 Nice. all right. 00:34:22 &apos;60s. 00:34:23 That was my era. 00:34:24 Also mine. 00:34:25 erasmo -- cesare benelli,chef, restaurateur, and a true venetian. 00:34:31 It&apos;s always been sort of the vegetable basketof venice? 00:34:35 It&apos;s been the garden since the 15th century. 00:34:39 But, I mean, I&apos;m surprised even nowthat so much of the food still is sourcedhere. 00:34:45 Yeah. 00:34:46 That&apos;s really -- that&apos;s remarkable. 00:34:48 You&apos;re right. that&apos;s it exactly. 00:34:49 I&apos;m surprised myself. 00:34:58 I&apos;m famously not exactly thrilledby fruits or vegetables,but perhaps that&apos;s because I wasn&apos;t bornvenetian. 00:35:07 erasmo is an isolated ecosystemunique in the world,a metaphysical mix of soil and salinitywhich famously producessome of the best fruits and vegetables foundanywhere. 00:35:19 We take a short trip around the islandwith cesare&apos;s friend massimo. 00:35:23 .. 00:35:26 Mmm, man. 00:35:29 That&apos;s one of life&apos;s great treats. 00:35:31 [ laughs]you know, they drip like that, too -- notthat I&apos;d know. 00:35:35 ...Ethereal grapes... a perfection of eggplant... 00:35:39 Benelli: oh,that&apos;s great. 00:35:41 That&apos;s a professional basil-slicing job there. 00:35:43 ...Tomatoes which convince youyou&apos;ve never actually had a tomato before--.. 00:35:49 It&apos;s nice to be reminded of how good a tomatocan be. 00:35:54 Yeah. 00:35:55 ...It&apos;s a near-religious experience. 00:35:57 [ Choir vocalizing ]of course, there&apos;s the holy trinity --some nice sliced salami, some good cheese,and fresh country bread. 00:36:10 And don&apos;t forget the local beverage,a wine known as fragolino. 00:36:14 [ laughs ]okay, this is forbidden wine. 00:36:18 it&apos;s done with --we call it american grape -- I guess it&apos;sconcord, right? 00:36:22 During the fermentation,.. right. 00:36:27 In very small percentages,but it&apos;s above the percentage admitted. 00:36:32 Right. 00:36:32 For years, people loved this humble localwinefor its delightful taste of strawberries. 00:36:38 The problem, though, is that too much,allegedly, makes one go blind. 00:36:41 And if you get drunk with that every dayfor 30 years, 40 years,probably you have some problems from themethyl. 00:36:47 I don&apos;t think it&apos;s more harmfulthan a martini or a straight vodka. right. 00:36:52 Salute. cheers. salute. 00:36:54 A la vita. 00:36:54 And I love rough local winesthat taste of the earth you drink them on,so the whole possible-blindness thing --not really a concern. 00:37:02 [ Laughter ] love it. perfect with this. 00:37:04 I think it goes very well with this. 00:37:06 Do you ever take this for granted? 00:37:07 I haven&apos;t met anyone in italywho takes their food for granted. 00:37:11 I&apos;m just amazed by that and envious, frankly. 00:37:13 This is the mark of a great food culture. 00:37:14 Right. 00:37:16 Despite an afternoon of much wine,cesare and I survived to dineat his well-known and much-loved ristoranteal covoin venice&apos;s arsenale neighborhood. 00:37:24 Between lunch and dinner, he scoured thelagoon,hopping from island to island, looking forthese --the first moeche of the season --tiny, tender, baby soft-shell crabs. 00:37:35 Not a huge fan of soft-shells --you know, when they&apos;re tiny or relativelysmall and soft. 00:37:40 Those big leatherbacks -- not for me. 00:37:42 You cut in the middle of the eyes,because when you fry them,otherwise, they explode and they absorb theoil. 00:37:49 It&apos;s a popular kitchen accident --the exploding-soft-shell-crab trick. 00:37:53 [ Laughs ].. 00:37:58 ...Or send sizzling soft-shell-crab juiceinto your face -- oh, man. 00:38:03 That hurts, let me tell you. 00:38:04 But, then again, soft-shell-crab juice,when deep-fried, oh, baby, it hurts so good. 00:38:09 So, how long have you been open here? 00:38:12 Since &apos;86. 00:38:12 Did venetians accept this place immediately,or did it take some time? no. 00:38:32 I&apos;m speaking to more and more chefs in mytravelswho have come to this crossroads in theirlife that you seem to have,&quot;simplicity -- the pure ambition to take greatingredientsand try very, very hard to just not screwthem up. 00:38:47 It&apos;s illustrative hereto compare and contrast with the french. 00:38:50 In france, the chef is the star. 00:38:52 Here, it&apos;s all about the ingredients. 00:38:55 Really great. so delicate. 00:38:58 Our first dish is a carpaccio of wild seabasswith pink peppercorn, chives, and basil oil. 00:39:05 This is -- this is really, really good. 00:39:07 Next dish -- spider crab served with itsown roe. 00:39:12 This is very elegant food. 00:39:15 Our third dish --fried zucchini and soft-shell crabs withwild fennel,lying on a bed of crispy fried potatoes. 00:39:22 Oh, they&apos;re so cute. fantastic. 00:39:25 Oh, man. 00:39:27 These are very nice, yes. 00:39:29 You see the menu. 00:39:30 It&apos;s written,&quot;no salt and without lemon,&quot;in order to invite the customer not to askfor lemon,because lemon here ruins everything to me. 00:39:41 Tony, do you really need lemon here? 00:39:43 No. no, you don&apos;t. 00:39:44 And as is always the case in italy,it seems they know when to say when. 00:39:49 Well, if you want to eat something --uh, I --you&apos;re --well, okay, maybe not. 00:39:55 [ speaking italian ]yeah, some --[ laughter ] yeah. 00:40:02 I think we&apos;re just about done. 00:40:04 Okay, we&apos;re not eating all of this. 00:40:06 [ Woman speaking italian ]oh, man, look at that. oh, man. 00:40:08 Koh, ma, enough! 00:40:11 .. 00:40:12 OH, MAN. De Mori: Oh, wow. wow. 00:40:14 That looks hot. 00:40:15 That&apos;s the creature from the black lagoon. 00:40:16 Yes. 00:40:17 ...Inky, teeth-blackening, sea-creature goodness. 00:40:21 Anytime you findthe italians and the chinese doing the samething,it&apos;s probably because it&apos;s a really goodidea. 00:40:29 ♪♪♪♪ 00:40:30 the usual? yes, please. 00:40:32 Anything else? 00:40:34 ♪♪♪♪ 00:40:35 when you&apos;re tryingto be good,tempting treatscan be wicked. 00:40:42 No thanks, I&apos;m good. 00:40:44 New special k fruit crisps. 00:40:46 .. 00:40:49 It&apos;s the delicious, new wayto stay on track. 00:40:53 Now, being good&apos;s a cinch. 00:40:55 With new special k fruit crisps. 00:41:04 welcome to the olive gardencooking school in tuscany. 00:41:06 Where our chefs learn the secrets of italiancooking. 00:41:08 .. is key. 00:41:11 But then, you have to balance the flavorsjust right. 00:41:13 secrets like how to blend four artisanalcheesesto create our new creamy fonduta saucethat perfectly enhancesseasoned steak medallionsin our new grilled steak fonduta. 00:41:24 And grilled chickenin our new chicken fonduta. 00:41:25 Everything we learn here we&apos;re bringing backto you. 00:41:28 share their experience tonightwith our new fonduta dishes. 00:41:31 At your olive garden. 00:42:04 astigmatism. 00:42:05 So my old contact lenses wouldsometimes moveout of placeand blur my vision. 00:42:08 My eye doctor saidthere&apos;s great newsfor people with astigmatism. 00:42:12 Acuvue oasys for astigmatism. 00:42:14 They work with the way my eyesmove and blink,which helps them stay in place. 00:42:17 And this is the only lens of itskind madewith hydraclear plus. 00:42:21 I&apos;m seeing more clearly, crisply, comfortably,all day long. 00:42:26 Now life doesn&apos;t have to be a blur. 00:42:27 [ Male Announcer ] FOR A FREE TRIAL PAIRCertificate,go to getacuvue.com. 00:42:31 Acuvue oasys for astigmatism. 00:42:34 outdinnercan sometimes get out of hand in a hurry. 00:42:39 [ screaming ]Hey. pbht! 00:42:41 [ Luke ] UNLESS, OF COURSE, YOU&apos;VE GOT AT&amp;T,The nation&apos;s fastest 3g network,which means you can surf the weband downloadvideos in a snap. 00:42:49 There you go, dad. 00:42:50 Hey. 00:42:51 ♪♪ ♪♪ 00:42:54 thanks. 00:42:54 [ chuckles ] THIS IS GOOD. 00:42:56 [ Male Announcer ]AT&amp;T. A BETTER 3G EXPERIENCE. 00:42:58 Get 50% offall messaging phonesafter mail-in rebate,like the pantech reveal. 00:43:02 Only from at&amp;t. 00:43:30 Lido island -- an 11-mile-long sandbarprobably most famous as the settingfor thomas mann&apos;s classic novelof homoerotic longing and terminal illness,&quot;real upbeat film, too --lots of yuks in that one, I can tell you. 00:43:44 The grand seaside resorts of another agestill attract a who&apos;s who of internationaldouchedom. 00:43:49 But me -- I&apos;d sooner be seen at a crackheadrodeothan set foot on the beach here in cabanaland. 00:43:57 [ Birds chirping ]but this being venice,just a couple of blocks back from the infernolives our friend stefano, the mooring man,and his family,a decidedly different, more low-key setting--a house, a backyard,kids running around, grandma in the kitchen. 00:44:28 You know this is gonna be good, right? 00:44:32 De Mori: E la mama, she&apos;s the head chef inthis house. 00:44:35 Bourdain: Does everybody&apos;s mother make thisdish the best? 00:44:38 Benedetelli: Si. si. 00:44:40 [ Speaking italian ]the family matriarch --still apparently happy to stand for hourson end,painstakingly making family meals from heirloomrecipes. 00:44:52 She says she wouldn&apos;t have it any other way. 00:44:55 Venice&apos;s great restaurants --to a great extent, italy&apos;s --succeed or fail to the degreethat they evoke this kind of cooking. 00:45:05 To my mind, certainly,italian cooking is home cooking. 00:45:10 And today, I&apos;m really happy it&apos;s stefano&apos;shome. 00:45:13 What had been a heavy, suffocating, late-summerheatlifts with a nice, sustained breeze off theadriaticthrough the curtains of this tiny familykitchen. 00:45:23 Onions start to cook. 00:45:24 [ Sizzling ]family members help out. 00:45:27 A little of this, a little of that --ingredients measured out in practiced incrementsby hand. 00:45:36 [ Speaking italian ]salute e grazia. 00:45:44 Do you know that rule? yeah? 00:45:46 Bad manners to let pasta get cold. 00:45:48 All right. it&apos;s so pretty. 00:45:52 We start with bigoli,a thick, tubular, long-cut pasta,like a hollow spaghetti,in a sauce of slow-melted, salt-cured anchovies. 00:45:59 As with nearly everything on the menu,it&apos;s labor-intensive. 00:46:04 [ Speaking italian ]so, when you know that you want to have thispasta,you have to start three days ahead. 00:46:10 Three days ahead? 00:46:11 [ Conversation in italian ][ laughs ]so, she said,&quot;you have to kill the onions. 00:46:17 &quot;The onions have to die. 00:46:17 .. 00:46:22 &quot;oh, you mean during the cooking process. 00:46:26 Yeah. so you melt them. 00:46:27 You say melt, and she says kill. 00:46:29 Lots of pepper and white wine. 00:46:32 Does everybody&apos;s mother make this dish thebest? 00:46:34 You know what I mean? 00:46:35 Si. si. 00:46:37 It&apos;s indescribably flavorfuland is just the right balance of sauce tostarch --sauce more condiment than main event,as my friend mario might say. 00:46:47 Mm-mm-mmm. 00:46:47 Oh, man, that&apos;s the best. 00:46:49 Oh, man. oh, wow. 00:46:51 Wow. that looks hot. 00:46:52 That&apos;s the creature from the black lagoon. 00:46:55 Yes. exciting. 00:46:58 Cuttlefish from the lagoon, cooked in itsown inkand served with fresh, slow-cooked polenta. 00:47:06 The polenta, still steaming,is cut at the table with a thin thread,and then all that goodness luxuriatesin an inky bath on your plate. 00:47:13 Does anything else that turns your teethblack taste as good? 00:47:18 Anytime you findthe italians and the chinese doing the samething,it&apos;s probably because it&apos;s a really goodidea. 00:47:28 Oh, yeah. 00:47:29 We&apos;re having pretty muchall of the greatest hits this afternoon. 00:47:31 Pretty much the best. 00:47:33 And the most famous of venetian dishes,the classic liver-and-onions fegato veneziana--sweat the onions, sear the liver,deglaze with wine, cook through, and serve. 00:47:45 It&apos;s just a wonderful, wonderful flavor. 00:47:49 Onions are miraculous things. 00:47:51 You can make an onion taste so many differentways,depending on how you treat it. 00:47:55 No mystery here --only a delightfully sweet, sour, savory symphonyof offal. 00:48:01 [ Bird chirps ]I&apos;d like to ask both moms here --when you go out to a restaurant, what makesthem angry? 00:48:09 [ Conversation in italian ]passion -- if there&apos;s no passion, it&apos;s --passion and then another&quot;p&quot;word,.. patience. 00:48:17 Which there&apos;s -- it abounds in venice. 00:48:21 She likes to eat her own food. 00:48:23 If she&apos;s home by herself,she makes herself a lovely meal all by herself. 00:48:26 I don&apos;t think she&apos;s going out very often. 00:48:28 And quite simply, it&apos;s easy to see why. 00:48:31 This is one of those&quot;lucky to be alive,&quot;&quot;i like my job&quot;moments. mm. 00:48:36 A perfect afternoon, the kind of afternoonI wait for, hope for, and live for --an italian family at a backyard picnic table,grandma cooking, a scene from a past notmy own,from a movie I never lived but always wantedto be in. 00:49:00 All things must pass. day turns to night. 00:49:04 Art is long, life is short, as the sayinggoes. 00:49:08 But in the end,even art grows old, crumbles into nothingness. 00:49:12 Nothing lasts forever,however hard we try and hold it close. 00:49:16 Maybe that&apos;s what&apos;s heldour gaze year afteryear,since thvenetianempire ended. 00:49:21 It&apos;s the slow decline,the long and gloriousdeath,the rising damp,the sinking walls --beautiful, truly beautifulthings in peril. 00:49:32 And yet, look now,one thinks of venice --a city millions of touristshave yet beenunable to ruin. 00:49:41 Look now. 00:50:00 Narrator:... 00:50:02 .. 00:50:03 It&apos;s one of our favorite pastimes when wetravel. 00:50:07 It can be slow and luxurious or fast. 00:50:10 And if it&apos;s fast, there&apos;s one restaurantchain we all know. 00:50:15 It&apos;s the one that changed how we eat aroundthe world. 00:50:20 The restaurant? 00:50:21 McDONALD&apos;S. 00:50:26 Remember this? 00:50:27 ♪♪ McDONALD&apos;S IS OUR KIND OF PLACE ♪♪ 00:50:29 Narrator: If you vacationin one of the more than 100 countries aroundthe globeTHAT HAS a McDonald&apos;s,you&apos;ll probably hear that tune and see thisface. 00:50:40 ♪♪ Your kind of place ♪♪ 00:50:43 Narrator: Today, over 46 million people sitdown and chow downAT ONE OF OVER 30,000 McDONALD&apos;S TO GET THEIRBreak every day. 00:50:53 And while you might thinkevery McDonald&apos;s is the same anywhere youtravel,WE found McDonald&apos;s restaurantsunlike any you probably have ever seen. 00:51:01 Get ready to supersize your travel adventure,BECAUSE THE MOST unique McDonald&apos;s in theworldare next. 00:51:11 --Captions by VITAC--www.vitac.comCaptions paid for bythe travel channel, l.l.c. 00:51:19 Burgers, fries, shakes. 00:51:22 What we know today as fast food all startedwith these two brothers, dick and mauriceMcDONALD,In san bernardino, california. 00:51:30 In 1948, they decided to open a restaurantthat served mass-produced, hot food quicklyfor the masses. 00:51:38 Some of you might even recognizetheir logofrom those days. 00:51:42 His name is speedee. 00:51:45 Little did dick and mac knowthey were creating a whole new way of eatingfor the entire world. 00:51:53 Ron piazza is the franchise ownerOF ONE OF THE VERY first McDonald&apos;s everbuilt. 00:51:58 We took your order, we hadour products readyto go,and you were out the window,and it wasn&apos;ta carhop,it wasn&apos;t sit-down, and it was the firstof its kind. 00:52:07 Narrator: We enlisted the help of a mcdonald&apos;sfanaticwhen we went looking for the 10 best. 00:52:12 ...A big mac today. 00:52:13 And peter holden told us everything we neededto knowABOUT WHAT MAKES a McDonald&apos;s different forgood reason. 00:52:20 He claims to have been to nearly 12,000 ofthem. 00:52:25 Holden: As of the last trip that I just cameback from,I&apos;VE BEEN TO 11,928 differentMcDonald&apos;s innorth america,and no two are exactly alike. 00:52:40 Narrator: Peter collects mcdonald&apos;s diningexperienceslike some people collect baseball cards. 00:52:46 His first criteria? 00:52:47 I will look at the menu, look for anythingnew and strange,especially when I&apos;m traveling,try to find something different, if I possiblycan. 00:52:57 Narrator: Peter took us to our first uniqueMcDONALD&apos;S. 00:53:02 To find it, we traveledto downey, california,just east of los angeles. 00:53:09 Before there were big macsor McNuggets to dip in honey-mustard sauce,there was this. 00:53:16 Holden: From a historical standpoint, myfavorite McDonald&apos;sperhaps of all time is in downey, california. 00:53:22 Narrator: Built in 1953,would you believethat this golden arches restaurant is soimportant,it&apos;s listed on the national register of historicplaces? 00:53:33 So, why would a fast-food restaurantbe on the same list as the white house? 00:53:37 THERE ARE 30,000 McDONALD&apos;SRESTAURANTS AROUNDThe world. 00:53:41 We are the oldest operating one. 00:53:43 They all came after us. 00:53:45 Narrator: This mcdonald&apos;s is the granddaddyof an american institution,and that&apos;s why it&apos;s the world&apos;s oldest operatingMcDONALD&apos;S. 00:53:54 But how did the golden archesbecome the gold standard for all fast food? 00:54:00 Think milkshakes. 00:54:02 [ Slurping ]DICK AND mac McDonald ownedEIGHT thriving McDonald&apos;s restaurants inTHE &apos;50s. 00:54:09 Business was so good, in fact,they needed to order eight new milkshakemixers. 00:54:14 Piazza: The multimixer is the key ingredientIN the McDonald&apos;s story. 00:54:19 And when ray kroc received the order foreight multimixers,couldn&apos;t believe it. 00:54:24 He knew heded to be part of this historiceventTO spread McDonald&apos;s across the country. 00:54:31 Narrator: Ray kroc, the multimixer salesman,IMMEDIATELY LICENSED the McDonald&apos;s nameand speedee service. 00:54:38 An empire was started. 00:54:40 It&apos;s truly the american success story. 00:54:43 Ray kroc comes up with an idea -- franchises,one restaurant that leadsto thousands and thousands of restaurantsthroughout the world. 00:54:52 The very first arches were built to holdup the roof,not to advertise the restaurant. 00:54:59 the McDonald&apos;s logo actually startedfrom the architecture developed at this restaurant. 00:55:04 If you look back from an angle, you can seethe McDonald&apos;s logobuilt in on the side of the building. 00:55:12 TODAY, that McDonald&apos;s logois easily the most recognizable icon in theworld. 00:55:18 Narrator: Step in here. 00:55:20 If you love big macs,then you&apos;re walking on seriously sacred territory. 00:55:25 IT&apos;S the McDonald&apos;s museum. 00:55:30 You can check out a cash registerfrom the very first restaurant. 00:55:36 But this might be the most important itemin the museum --THE MILKSHAKE MIXER THAT STARTED the McDonald&apos;sempire. 00:55:47 If you want to run one,just sign up for hamburger university,because that&apos;s where they train you to runand own a franchise. 00:55:54 THE OLDEST operating McDonald&apos;s might beone thing,BUT FOR OUR NEXT MOST unique McDonald&apos;s,we found one that will really surprise you. 00:56:07 Got a passion for supersized fries? 00:56:11 Or a true talent for eating quarter pounderswith cheese? 00:56:16 Don&apos;t worry. 00:56:17 Take a trip hereto new york city,and you&apos;ll be living your dreamin no time,BECAUSE WITH ALMOST 600McDONALD&apos;S TO CHOOSEFrom,you&apos;re not gonna have to look very long tofind our next pick. 00:56:31 We headed to the heart of manhattanto one of the most famous corners on earth--TIMES SQUARE, 42nd STREET AND BROADWAY. 00:56:41 It&apos;s here that megahit musicalslike&quot;phantom of the opera&quot;and&quot;the producers&quot;wow audiences from around the world. 00:56:49 Every year, the bright lights of this famousintersectiondraw people with big dreams and big appetites. 00:56:58 NO, ronald McDonald is not starring in hisone-man show,but it does look like a theater,starting with this -- an authentic broadwaymarquee. 00:57:08 Man: First time we walked by, all the lightswere on,and it was in the summer, and we were burningup. 00:57:13 We couldn&apos;t believe how hot it wasunderneath the wattage there. 00:57:17 It&apos;s more wattage than a lot of broadwayshows. 00:57:20 It&apos;s kind of scary. 00:57:23 This thing glows, and it rocks,and when yougo down 42nd streetAND YOU TAKE A LOOKAT the McDonald&apos;s sign,you can&apos;t help but stopand say,&quot;wow! 00:57:32 LOOK AT thatMcDonald&quot;Narrator: With 7,500 glittering bulbs,this showstopping sign soaks up a lot ofwatts every dayand demands more attention than a broadwaystar. 00:57:48 So, we actually have to go out and get ourown boom truck,and one of our people on staff is actuallyup therechanging bulbs every day. 00:57:56 Narrator: If you think this place lookslike a theater on the outside,
 
Word Map
 pasta speaking time well dish cooking look italian There first family restaurant like people venice long sauce found What place help different mean rice came Yeah Bourdain make world stay This life wine good risotto great always island know come kind Speaking venetian venetians think slowly order flavor credit find food makes right want Narrator probably days fish work lagoon 
Tag cloud of show
 pasta speaking time well dish cooking look italian There first family restaurant like people venice long sauce found What place help different mean rice came Yeah Bourdain make world stay This life wine good risotto great always island know come kind Speaking venetian venetians think slowly order flavor credit find food makes right want Narrator probably days fish work lagoon 
Livedash is ad supported
 About Us | Help | DMCA | Terms of Use 
 Privacy Policy mReplay Livedash is a registered trademark of mReplay Corporation. The information provided with
 mReplay Livedash is for informational purposes only. For more
 information, please see our terms of use.
 
 The network logos used on mReplay Livedash are registered trademarks of
 those respective companies, including Fox, NBC, CBS, PBS, ABC, FX,
 TNT, ESPN, ESPN2, TBS, USA, MTV, VH1, Spike, A&amp;E;, Bravo, AMC, TLC,
 Animal Planet, ABC Family, Cartoon Network, Disney, CNN, CNBC, Fox
 News, MSNBC, Comedy Central, Entertainment, TV Land and Oxygen.
 
 These networks, Fox, NBC, CBS, PBS, ABC, FX, TNT, ESPN, ESPN2, TBS,
 USA, MTV, VH1, Spike, A&amp;E;, Bravo, AMC, TLC, Animal Planet, ABC Family,
 Cartoon Network, Disney, CNN, CNBC, Fox News, MSNBC, Comedy Central,
 Entertainment, TV Land and Oxygen, are not affiliated with mReplay
 Livedash, or mReplay Corporation. 
 
 
 loading...
	</body>
</document>
