<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002730" url="http://martaguide.com/category/n1-peachtree-center/" time="2012-07-12-18:47" support="4" score="0.01344671667005789" bingtitle="N1 Peachtree Center « MARTA Guide" webtitle="N1 Peachtree CenterMARTA Guide">
			<query id="000783" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="000807" bing-rank="53"/>
			<query id="000811" bing-rank="183"/>
			<query id="000808" bing-rank="16"/>
	<description>The Martin Luther King Jr. March and Rally takes place ... northbound train at the Five Points Station, or exit at ... include Santa, a light show, family activities, food and ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to navigation Skip to main content Skip to primary sidebar Skip to secondary sidebar Skip to footer 
 
 MARTA Guide 
 Atlanta Walking and Transit Directions 
 Home Attractions Festivals Hotels Shopping Station Map Station Guides App Contact 
 Twitter Facebook RSS Feed 
Category Archives: N1 Peachtree Center 
 
 MARTA to CVS Pharmacy 
 
 Jul 1 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
If you are traveling on MARTA and need to get to a CVS Pharmacy, there are several of them located near MARTA stations.  They are listed below,  with the locations closest to a rail station listed first.

 Five Point Station 
There is a CVS directly above the Five Points MARTA Station, but the area is a little sketchy.  After exiting the train, follow the signs to street level, then look for the MARTA Ride Store/Peachtree Street exit.  Turn left by the Ride Store to go up an escalator to the Broad Street Plaza.  The CVS is located there.

 Peachtree Center Station 
There is also a CVS above the Peachtree Center Station.  Take the Harris Street/John Portman Blvd. exit off the train platform, then follow the signs to Peachtree Street East.  CVS will be just outside the station in the Peachtree Center North tower.

 Decatur Station 
Take the Swanton Way exit out of the station and walk straight through the bus bay.  Turn right on Commerce Street.  CVS is a block up.

 Midtown Station 
Take the Peachtree Place exit out of the station and turn left.  One block up at Peachtree Street turn right.  CVS is located about two blocks down at Peachtree and 6th Street.

 North Avenue Station 
If you regularly travel on or live near Ponce de Leon Avenue, bus 2 that departs the North Avenue Station stops at a CVS across from Ponce City Market, in the Whole Foods/Home Depot shopping center.

 Georgia State Station 
On the blue/green rail line, exit at the Georgia State Station and board bus 99 .  The bus travels through the Atlanta Medical Center, and there is a CVS on Boulevard near Freedom Parkway.

 For more information, see: 
 MARTA Maps 
 How to Ride MARTA Buses 
 Best of MARTA: Services 
 Using Google Maps for MARTA Directions 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like One blogger likes this. 
 
 
Posted in Bus 2 , Bus 99 , Business , E1 Georgia State , E6 Decatur , Five Points , Medical , N1 Peachtree Center , N3 North Avenue , N4 Midtown , Service 

 Leave a Comment 
 
 MARTA to Holiday Inn Centennial Park 
 
 Jun 26 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Holiday Inn at Centennial Park is located at 101 Andrew Young International Blvd.  It is next to Centennial Olympic Park and near attractions such as the Georgia Aquarium, World of Coca-cola, Imagine It! Children’s Museum, AmericasMART and the CNN building.  It also features an outdoor pool, laundry facilities, free meals for kids and a fitness center. The closest MARTA station is the Peachtree Center Station on the red and gold rail lines. All trains departing the airport stop at this station.

After exiting the train, follow the signs to the Harris Street/John Portman Blvd exit. Walk through the fare gates and follow the signs again to Peachtree Street West. Go up the escalator to street level and turn right on Peachtree Street. At the first intersection, turn right on Andrew Young International Blvd. and walk about two blocks.

 

 You can also get to the hotel via the Dome/CNN/Philips Arena Station on the blue/green rail line. Take the Philips Arena exit out of the station and walk straight ahead down Centennial Olympic Park Drive. Bus 1 travels next to the hotel on Centennial Olympic Park Drive. Stand on the park side of the street to take the bus to Five Points/Underground Atlanta/Braves Shuttle. The park features free outdoor concerts on Wednesday evenings from April -September, from roughly 5:30-8 p.m. 

 

 For more information, see: 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 Peachtree Center Station Restaurants 
 Dome Station Restaurants 
 Top 5 Most Walkable Stations 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Bus 1 , Hotel , N1 Peachtree Center , W1 Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena 

 Leave a Comment 

Tags: Andrew Young International Blvd. 
 
 MARTA to Holiday Inn Express Downtown Atlanta 
 
 Jun 26 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Holiday Inn Express in downtown Atlanta is located at 111 Cone Street near the Tabernacle and Centennial Olympic Park. The hotel features a free hot breakfast and 24-hour fitness center. The hotel itself is located in a historic building, with the closest MARTA station Peachtree Center on the red/gold rail line. All trains departing the airport stop at this station.

After exiting the train, follow the signs to the Ellis Street exit. Walk through the fare gates and keep right to Peachtree Street West/public library. Go up the tall escalator and walk straight out of the station on to Forsyth Street. Walk past the public library and turn right on Luckie Street. The hotel is about two blocks down at the corner of Luckie and Cone Street. Turn right on Cone Street for the entrance.

 


 Ted’s Montana Grill is one block beyond the hotel off of Luckie Street. Walk the Fairlie-Popular district and (especially Broad Street) for historic street fronts and inexpensive food options. Within a 15-minute walking radius you can get to the Imagine It! Children’s Museum, World of Coca-cola, Georgia Aquarium, Centennial Olympic Park, Philips Arena and the CNN building. 

&lt;
 For more information, see: 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 Peachtree Center Station Restaurants 
 Top 5 Most Walkable Stations 
 10 Popular Atlanta Tourists Attractions and How to Get There on MARTA 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like One blogger likes this. 
 
 
Posted in Hotel , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Leave a Comment 

Tags: Cone Street 
 
 MARTA to the Quality Hotel 
 
 Jun 24 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Quality Hotel is located in downtown Atlanta at 89 Luckie Street, near the Rialto Center for Performing Arts and the Georgia State University campus. The hotel features free WiFi and breakfast bar.

The closest MARTA station is Peachtree Center on the red/gold rail line. After exiting the train, take the Ellis Street exit off the train platform, then follow the signs to Peachtree Street West/public library after going through the fare gate. Walk straight out of the station on to Forsyth Street past the public library and turn right at the second intersection on Luckie Street. The hotel will be about a block down on the right.

 

 The Sidebar is a cozy, local bar nearby on Popular Street. Not much is open as far as restaurants on the weekends, especially around Five Points. You’ll have better luck finding open restaurants around the Peachtree Center Station or the 24-hour Landmark Diner across from the Rialto. Head up to the top of the nearby Westin hotel for a birds-eye view of the city. 



 For more information, see: 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 Peachtree Center Station Restaurants 
 Peachtree Center Attractions 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Hotel , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Leave a Comment 

Tags: Landmark Diner 
 
 MARTA to Motel 6 Atlanta Downtown 
 
 Jun 22 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
One of the most affordable hotels in downtown Atlanta is Motel 6 located at 311 Courtland Street. The nearest MARTA station is Peachtree Center on the red and gold rail line.  After exiting the train, follow the signs to the Harris Street/John Portman Blvd. exit. Walk through the fare gates and follow the signs again to Peachtree Street East, walking partly through the Peachtree Center Mall. At street level, turn right on Peachtree, then right again on Baker Street. Walk two blocks and turn left on Courtland Street. The hotel will be on the right.

 


 For inexpensive dining, check out the food court inside the Peachtree Center Mall. 



 The Hilton is located next to Motel 6, and in the basement you’ll find Trader Vic’s , a fun tiki bar/restaurant. 


 Bus 16 has a stop outside the hotel on Courtland Street that will take you to the Five Points MARTA Station and Underground Atlanta. 



 For more information, see: 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 Peachtree Center Station Restaurants 
 10 Popular Atlanta Tourists Attractions and How to Get There on MARTA 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like One blogger likes this. 
 
 
Posted in Bus 16 , Hotel , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Leave a Comment 
 
 MARTA to the Atlanta Marriott Downtown 
 
 May 25 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Atlanta Marriott Downtown is located at 160 Spring Street NW, closest to the Peachtree Center MARTA Station in downtown Atlanta.  Rates start from $99 and go over $200 depending on the date of stay.  The hotel features paid Internet access, valet and off-site parking for a fee, fitness center and outdoor pool.

From MARTA, take a red or gold line train to the Peachtree Center Station.  If coming from the airport or Greyhound, board a northbound train.  From the Megabus , board a southbound train at the Civic Center Station.  Once exiting the train, follow the signs to the Harris Street exit, go through the fare gates, then follow signs again to Peachtree Street West.  At street level, turn right along Peachtree Street (passing Ray’s in the City and Fire of Brazil restaurants).  The first stoplight is Andrew Young International Blvd. (Hard Rock Cafe on the corner).  Turn right on Andrew Young International and walk about one block to reach the hotel, which is near a small park.

Nearby attractions include the Peachtree Center offices and mall, Centennial Olympic Park, Imagine It! Children’s Museum, Georgia Aquarium and the World of Coke.

 For more information, see: 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 Peachtree Center Station Restaurants 
 Top 5 Most Walkable Stations 
 Top 5 Hotels Closest to MARTA 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Hotel , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Comments Off 
 
 MARTA to the MLK March and Rally 
 
 Jan 15 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Martin Luther King Jr. March and Rally takes place annually on Martin Luther King Jr. Day in downtown Atlanta.  Open to all, the march assembles at Peachtree and Baker Streets at 1:15 p.m. and begins at 2 p.m. down Auburn Avenue to the King Center.

The Peachtree Center MARTA Station on the red/gold rail line is right next to the starting point of the march.  If you are coming from the east-west rail line, you will need to transfer to a northbound train at the Five Points Station , or exit at Five Points and take the Peachtree Street exit out of the station and turn left.  The march route will be about two blocks up.

If arriving at the Peachtree Center Station, follow the signs to the Harris Street exit for closest access to the start of the march.  See MARTA directions to the King Center for information on getting to the rally at the end of the march.

 For more information, see: 
 Exploring the King Memorial Station Area 
 King Memorial Station Restaurants 
 How to use Google Maps for MARTA directions 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Festival , Five Points , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Leave a Comment 

Tags: Martin Luther King March 
 
 MARTA to the Chick-fil-A Bowl Parade 
 
 Dec 29 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The 2011 Chick-fil-A Bowl Parade takes place Dec. 31 from 12:30–2 p.m. just outside the Peachtree Center MARTA station on the red/gold rail line.  All north/soundbound trains stop at this station, and all station exits will take you to street level where you can view the start of the parade. Or if coming from the blue or green rail line, exit at the Five Points Station and follow the signs to the Northbound train platform and get on the first train that arrives and go one stop to Peachtree Center.

The other option is to exit at the Dome Station on the blue/green rail line and follow the signs to the Philips Arena exit.  Go up the escalators and keep walking straight ahead along Centennial Olympic Park Drive (Philips Arena will be on your left).  A few blocks up the parade route travels on Andrew Young International Blvd. through the park (see walking map ).  If you are coming from the north or south rail line, be sure to exit at Five Points and follow the signs to the Westbound platform for the correct train.

The Chick-fil-A Bowl Fanfest will take place next to the Dome Station at the Georgia World Congress Center after the parade and the football game will take place in the Georgia Dome next door.

 For more information, see: 
 MARTA to the Chick-fil-A Bowl 
 New Year’s Eve Weekend MARTA Schedules 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 Dome Station Restaurants 
 Peachtree Center Station Restaurants 
 Top 5 MARTA Stations to Park and Ride 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Art, Music and Culture , Festival , Holiday , N1 Peachtree Center , Sports and Outdoors , W1 Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena 

 Leave a Comment 
 
 MARTA to Hampton Inn Atlanta Downtown 
 
 Dec 16 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Hampton Inn in downtown Atlanta is located at 161 Spring Street NW in a historic building. Features include complimentary breakfast and a business center.

The Peachtree Center Station is the closest MARTA station to the hotel.  Take any red or gold line train to the station and follow the signs to the Ellis Street exit then to Peachtree Street West.  At street level,  immediately turn right on Carnegie Way and walk about two blocks to Spring Street and turn left.  Walking time is about five minutes.

Nearby attractions include the Hard Rock Cafe, Peachtree Center businesses, Centennial Olympic Park, Tabernacle, Imagine It! Children’s Museum, Georgia Aquarium, World of Coca-Cola, CNN and the Rialto Center for Performing Arts.

 For more information, see: 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 Peachtree Center Attractions/Directions 
 Top 5 Most Walkable Stations 
 Using Google Maps for MARTA Directions 
 10 Popular Atlanta Tourists Attractions and How to Get There on MARTA 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like One blogger likes this. 
 
 
Posted in Hotel , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Leave a Comment 
 
 MARTA to Days Inn Atlanta Downtown 
 
 Dec 15 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Days Inn in downtown Atlanta is located at 300 Spring Street, closest to the Peachtree Center MARTA Station ( see map ). The hotel features a complimentary breakfast and newspaper along with an outdoor seasonal pool.

Take any red or gold line train, including any train from the airport, to the Peachtree Center Station.  Follow the signs off the train platform to Harris Street, then take the Peachtree Street West exit after walking through the fare gate.  At street level, turn left on Baker Street and walk about two blocks.  The hotel is on the corner of Baker and Spring Streets.  The entrance is actually on Baker.  Walking time is less than 10 minutes.

Nearby attractions include AmericasMart, Georgia Aquarium, World of Coca-Cola, Imagine It! Children’s Museum and Centennial Olympic Park.

 For more information, see: 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 Peachtree Center Attractions/Directions 
 Peachtree Center Station Restaurants 
 Top 5 Most Walkable Stations 
 Top 5 Hotels Closest to MARTA 
 10 Popular Atlanta Tourists Attractions and How to Get There on MARTA 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Hotel , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Leave a Comment 

Tags: Atlanta Downtown , Atlanta Hotel 
 
 MARTA to the Peach Drop 
 
 Dec 15 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Peach Drop is Atlanta’s New Years Eve event that takes place just outside Underground Atlanta. Activities and live music take place much of New Years Eve day, and at night, a large peach drops in countdown to the new year.

The Five Points Station is right next to the Peach Drop and Underground Atlanta. All trains stop at Five Points, making it an easy destination. The Peachtree Street exit out of the station will be closed Dec. 31, but there will be clear directions to other other exits. If you exit on Alabama Street, turn left on Alabama Street. Or take the Broad Street plaza exit out of the station near the ride store, walk through the plaza and turn right on Marietta Street.

For those who wish to avoid some foot traffic, you can also exit at the Peachtree Center Station (follow the signs to the Ellis Street exit off the train platform) and walk a few blocks south on Peachtree Street to reach the Peach Drop. The Georgia State Station is also in walking distance, though a little further. If you exit at Georgia State, take the Piedmont Avenue exit out of the station and turn right. At Decatur Street, turn left and walk about three blocks (see area map ).

MARTA trains will have extended service on New Years Eve. The last trains in all directions will depart Five Points at 2 a.m.

 For more information, see: 
 Navigating the Five Points Station 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 New Year’s Weekend MARTA Schedules 
 Top 5 MARTA Stations to Park and Ride 
 Using Google Maps for MARTA Directions 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in E1 Georgia State , Five Points , Holiday , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Leave a Comment 

Tags: Atlanta New Years Eve , Atlanta Peach Drop 
 
 MARTA to Hyatt Place Atlanta/Downtown 
 
 Dec 11 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Hyatt Place Atlanta/Downtown is located near two MARTA stations at 330 Peachtree Street NE.  Nearby attractions include Hard Rock Cafe’, Peachtree Center mall and offices, Georgia Aquarium, Centennial Olympic Park, World of Coca-Cola and the Imagine It! Children’s Museum. With daily parking at the hotel $22/day, consider taking MARTA from the airport or other destination and walking to the hotel.

The closest MARTA station is  the Peachtree Center Station on the red/gold rail line.  Follow the signs to the Harris Street exit and then to Peachtree Street West.  At street level, turn left along Peachtree Street and walk just over two blocks.

Or, exit at the Civic Center Station, also on the red/gold rail line. Exit the station and head south (toward the skyscrapers) on West Peachtree Street.  When you get to the edge of the small park, turn left on Simpson, then left on Peachtree Street.  The hotel will be near the corner (see walking map from both stations).

All trains departing the airport stop at both Civic Center and Peachtree Center, so merely get on the first train that arrives.  The MegaBus also stops at the Civic Center Station.

 For more information, see: 
 Civic Center Station Guide
 Civic Center Attractions/Directions 
 Top 5 Hotels Closest to MARTA 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Bus 110 , Hotel , N1 Peachtree Center , N2 Civic Center 

 Leave a Comment 

Tags: Atlanta Hotel 
 
 MARTA to the Children’s Christmas Parade 
 
 Nov 30 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Children’s Christmas Parade takes place every year in downtown Atlanta along Peachtree Street.  For 2011, view the parade at 10:30 a.m. on Saturday, Dec. 3  just outside the Peachtree Center MARTA Station near the intersection of Baker and Peachtree Street.  Attendees can take any exit out of the station to see the parade or exit at the Five Points Station and turn left out of the Peachtree Street station exit to view the parade near the middle of the route.

 For more information, see: 
 Navigating the Five Points Station 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 10 Atlanta Attractions and How to Get There on MARTA 
 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Art, Music and Culture , Five Points , Holiday , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Leave a Comment 

Tags: atlanta christmas parade , Atlanta Parade 
 
 MARTA to Christmas on Peachtree 
 
 Nov 29 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
 Christmas on Peachtree is an indoor holiday festival in the former Macy’s department building in downtown Atlanta ( see area map ).  Highlights include Santa, a light show, family activities, food and shopping.  The closest MARTA station is Peachtree Center on the red/gold rail line, which is less than a block to the building.  For the shortest walk,  after exiting the train, follow the signs to the Ellis Street exit.  After going through the fare gates, keep to the right and go up the tall escalator.  Look for signs pointing to the Atlanta Public Library and Peachtree Street West.  At street level, turn left along Peachtree Street and the building will be just a couple doors down next to the Westin Hotel at 200 Peachtree Street NE.

 For more information, see: 
 MARTA Breeze Cards Explained 
 Peachtree Center Station Restaurants 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 5 Most Walkable MARTA Stations 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Festival , Holiday , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Leave a Comment 

Tags: Atlanta Christmas , Atlanta Holiday Festival , Downtown Atlanta 
 
 MARTA to Downtown Restaurant Week 
 
 May 24 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
 Atlanta Downtown Restaurant Week features special three-course meals at fine dining restaurants for a discounted price.  The 2011 dates are May 28-June 5.

Below is the list of restaurants along with the closest MARTA station. Click here for the full list of participating restaurants with map links. Three of the restaurants require a bus route, and those have been left off the list below.

 Peachtree Center Station 
Atlanta Grill (Ritz Carlton Hotel)
Azio Downtown
Benihana
Meehan’s Public House
Pittypat’s Porch
Ray’s in the City
Sun Dial Restaurant and View (Westin Hotel)
Terrace on Peachtree (Ellis Hotel)
Truva

 Civic Center Station 
BLT Steak (W Hotel)
Max Lager’s Wood-Fired Grill&amp;Brewery
ROOM at Twelve

 Five Points 
 Georgia Peach Restaurant&amp;Lounge (Underground Atlanta) 
 Thrive 
 

 Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena Station 
Dantanna’s Downtown
Der Biergarten
Legal Sea Foods
Peasant Bistro
Rise Sushi Lounge
Ruth’s Chris Steak House (Embassy Suites Hotel)
STATS

 For more information, see: 
 Peachtree Center Station Restaurants 
 North Avenue Station Restaurants 
 Midtown Station Restaurants 
 Lindbergh Station Restaurants 
 Buckhead Station Restaurants 
 Dome/Philips Arena Station Restaurants 
 Top 10 Fine Dining Restaurants Near MARTA 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Five Points , N1 Peachtree Center , N2 Civic Center , Restaurant , W1 Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena 

 Comments Off 
 
 MARTA to the Hilton Atlanta 
 
 Apr 30 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Hilton Atlanta is located downton at 255 Courtland Street near the Peachtree Center MARTA Station .  All trains leaving the airport stop at this station on the red and gold rail line.

After getting off the train, take the Harris Street (not Ellis) exit off the train platform then follow the signs to Peachtree Street East after walking through the fare gate.  At street level turn right on Peachtree Street then right on Harris Street/John Portman Blvd.  The hotel is about two blocks down at the intersection of Harris Street/John Portman Blvd. and Courtland Street (see walking map ).

Trader Vic’s, a tiki bar and restaurant, is located in the lowest level of the hotel and Nikolai’s Roof is at the top.  Other nearby restaurants include Sear, Pacific Rim Bistro, Benihana Japanese Steakhouse and Morton’s the Steakhouse.

 For more information, see:
 Tips for Riding MARTA to/from the Airport 
 Top 5 Hotels Closest to MARTA 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 Peachtree Center Station Restuarants 
 Using Google Maps for MARTA Directions 
 10 Atlanta Attractions and How to Get There on MARTA 
 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Bus 110 , Hotel , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Comments Off 

Tags: Atlanta Downtown Hotel , Atlanta Hotel , hilton atlanta , Nikolai&apos;s Roof , Trader Vics 
 
 MARTA to the Ellis Hotel 
 
 Apr 19 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Ellis Hotel is a luxury hotel located in downtown Atlanta at 176 Peachtree Street.  It is conveniently right next to the Peachtree Center MARTA station.  Take a red or gold line train to Peachtree Center and be careful to follow the station exit marked “Ellis Street” when you get off the train.  This exit is at the far south end of the station.  After going through the fare gates, turn right and at street level turn left.

The hotel features Terrace, a sustainable restaurant.  Area attractions include the Georgia Aquarium, Centennial Olympic Park, Tabernacle, World of Coke, Imagine It Children’s Museum and Underground Atlanta.

 For more information, see: 
 Top 5 Hotels Closest to MARTA 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 Tips on Riding MARTA to/from the Airport 
 10 Atlanta Tourist Attractions and How to Get There on MARTA 
 10 Easiest Destinations to Get to on MARTA .
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Bus 110 , Hotel , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Comments Off 

Tags: Downtown Atlanta Hotel 
 
 MARTA to the Ritz Carlton Downtown 
 
 Apr 17 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Ritz Carlton in downtown Atlanta is located at 181 Peachtree Street, a short walk from the Peachtree Center MARTA station.

Take any red or gold line train to the Peachtree Center station and take the Ellis Street exit off the train platform, which is at the south end of the station.  After going through the fare gates, turn left and follow the signs for Peachtree Street East.  Go up the elevator or escalator and at street level, turn right and walk to the first intersection.  Approximate walking time once out the station is about one minute.

For more information, see tips on riding to/from the Airport on MARTA and 10 popular Atlanta tourist attractions and how to get there on MARTA .
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Hotel , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Leave a Comment 

Tags: Downtown Atlanta Hotel 
 
 MARTA to the Hard Rock Cafe 
 
 Apr 15 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
Atlanta’s Hard Rock Cafe is located downtown at 215 Peachtree Street NE, near the Peachtree Center MARTA station (see area map ).

To get there on MARTA, take a gold or red line train to the Peachtree Center station and look for the“To Harris Street”exit off the train platform. After going through the fare gate, follow the signs pointing to Peachtree Street East.  Once you get to street level, turn left and walk to the first intersection.  Hard Rock is on the corner.

Bus 110 also runs up and down Peachtree Street from Five Points to the Lenox station.  Exit at the intersection of Peachtree and Andrew Young International Blvd.

For more information, see 10 popular Atlanta tourist attractions and how to get there on MARTA and the top 5 most walkable MARTA stations .
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Bus 110 , N1 Peachtree Center , Tourist Attraction 

 Comments Off 
 
 MARTA to Atlanta Fulton County Public Library 
 
 Mar 27 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
There are several public libraries accessible via MARTA and the main central library is conveniently located across the street from the Peachtree Center MARTA station.

Take a red or gold line train to Peachtree Center and follow the signs to the Ellis Street exit after getting off the train.  After going through the fare gates, keep right to follow the signs pointing to Peachtree Street West.  At the top of the tall escalator, walk straight ahead to reach the library.

There are also three other branches that are fairly easily accessible:

 Ponce de Leon Library–Take  bus 2 from the North Avenue station and exit at Ponce and Fredrica Street. Peachtree Library–Exit at the Arts Center station and follow the signs to the exit pointing to Arts Center Way.  Go up two sets of escalators then turn left at street level alongside the back of Woodruff Arts Center.  Turn right at 16th Street and walk a block to Peachtree Street (see walking map ). Buckhead Library–Take bus 110 from the Buckhead or Lenox station and head south on Peachtree Road.  Exit at Buckhead Avenue, which is between E. Paces Ferry and Pharr Road (see area map ). 

For more information, see MARTA Maps and how to use Google Maps for MARTA directions .
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in N1 Peachtree Center , N3 North Avenue , N5 Arts Center , Service 

 Leave a Comment 

Tags: atlanta fulton county public library , Atlanta Library , atlanta public library 
 
 MARTA to the Georgia Marathon 
 
 Mar 18 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Georgia Marathon takes place every year in early spring.  This year the race takes place on Sunday, March 20, 2011.   The marathon and the half-marathon start and end at Centennial Olympic Park in downtown Atlanta (see area map ) and go through intown neighborhoods, including Inman Park, Virginia Highland, Decatur, Midtown and Druid Hills.

 From the North or South (red/gold rail lines)
 Take a red or gold line train to the Peachtree Center station .  Take the Harris Street exit off the train platform then follow the signs pointing to Peachtree Street West after going through the fare gate.  At street level, turn right on Peachtree Street then right at the first light on to Andrew Young International.  This street will go right to the park.

 From the East or West (blue/green rail lines) 
Take a blue or green train to the Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena station , which is one stop away from Five Points.  Follow the signs pointing to Philips Arena after exiting the station.  After going up an escalator and flight of stairs, walk straight ahead past Philips Arena (the arena will be on your left).  The park is about two blocks down.

For more information, see see Using Google Maps for MARTA directions for specific time schedules and the top 5 MARTA stations to park and ride .
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in N1 Peachtree Center , Sports and Outdoors , W1 Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena 

 Leave a Comment 

Tags: georgia half marathon , georgia marathon , publix marathon 
 
 MARTA to the Greenprints Conference 
 
 Mar 4 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Greenprints Conference and Trade Show takes place in Atlanta every year and focuses on  sustainable construction and design.   The 2011 conference is March 14 and 15 at the Sheraton Hotel in downtown Atlanta, 165 Courtland Street NE (see area map ).

If you are coming from the airport, take any northbound train to the Peachtree Center MARTA station.  Follow the signs pointing“To Harris Street”after exiting the train, then after going through the fare gate, follow the signs“To Peachtree Street East”.

At street level turn left on Peachtree and walk to the first intersection and turn left again on Andrew Young International Blvd.   The entrance to the hotel is two blocks down at the intersection with Courtland Street.

For more information, see how to use Google Maps for MARTA directions and the 10 easiest destinations to get to on MARTA .
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in N1 Peachtree Center , School/Education 

 Leave a Comment 

Tags: greenprints conference , greenprints tradeshow , sheraton hotel atlanta , sustainability atlanta 
 
 MARTA to the Sheraton Hotel Downtown Atlanta 
 
 Mar 2 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Sheraton Hotel in downtown Atlanta is located near the Peachtree Center station on the red/gold rail line at 165 Courtland Street NE (see area map ).

If you are coming from the airport, take any northbound train to the Peachtree Center MARTA station.  Follow the signs pointing“To Harris Street”after exiting the train, then after going through the fare gate, follow the signs“To Peachtree Street East”.

At street level turn left on Peachtree and walk to the first intersection and turn left again on Andrew Young International Blvd.   The entrance to the hotel is two blocks down at Courtland Street.

For more information, see how to use Google Maps for MARTA directions and the 10 easiest destinations to get to on MARTA .
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Hotel , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Leave a Comment 

Tags: Atlanta Downtown Hotel , Atlanta Hotel , sheraton hotel , sheraton hotel atlanta 
 
 MARTA to the Children’s Healthcare Christmas Parade 
 
 Dec 3 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
Saturday, Dec. 4, 2010 is the Children’s Healthcare of Atlanta Christmas Parade.  The parade kicks off at 10:30am in downtown Atlanta, from Peachtree Street south to Marietta and on to Centennial Olympic Park .  The park also offers an ice skating rink in winter months if you want to combine the parade with more winter activities.

The start of the parade will take place just outside the N1 Peachtree Center station on the north/south rail line.  Take any north/south train and any exit out of the station for the parade at street level.

The Five Points station is another option on the parade route.  Ride any train to Five Points and take the Peachtree Street exit out of the station and turn left onto Peachtree.  Walk about one block to reach Marietta Street to view the parade.

For more information, see the 10 easiest destinations to get to on MARTA and the Top 5 MARTA Stations to Park and Ride .
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Art, Music and Culture , Five Points , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Leave a Comment 

Tags: atlanta christmas parade , atlanta holiday , centennial olympic park , Children&apos;s Healthcare of Atlanta 
 
 MARTA to the Atlanta Marriott Marquis 
 
 Aug 31 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
Image via Wikipedia
 
The Atlanta Marriott Marquis is located in downtown Atlanta at 265 Peachtree Center Avenue (see area map ).  The closest MARTA station is Peachtree Center on the red/gold rail line.  All trains departing the airport stop at this station, and all trains coming from the north stop here as well.

From the Peachtree Center station, follow the signs to the Harris Street exit after getting of the train.  After walking through the fare gates, follow the signs again to the Peachtree Street East and at street level, turn right to walk north along Peachtree Street.  Turn right at the first intersection on to Harris Street, then left at the next block on Peachtree Center Avenue.  The hotel is a short walk down on the right.   Approximate walking time from the fare gate is only 3 minutes.

If you don’t want to walk outside, you can also exit the station into the Peachtree Center mall and walk through for an indoor connection.

 For more information,  see: 
 Top 5 Hotels Closest to MARTA 
 Peachtree Center Station Restaurants 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 How to use Google Maps for MARTA Directions 
 Top 10 Easiest Destinations to Get to on MARTA 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Hotel , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Comments Off 

Tags: Atlanta Downtown Hotel , Atlanta Hotel , atlanta marriott , Downtown Atlanta 
 
 MARTA to the Hyatt Regency 
 
 Aug 30 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Hyatt Regency Atlanta hotel is located at 265 Peachtree Street, in close walking distance to the Peachtree Center MARTA station on the red and gold rail lines ( see area map ).  The hotel is the location of the 2011 Downtown Countdown inclusive New Years Eve party and also features an outdoor pool, 24 hour gym and three restaurants: Market, Sway and Twenty-Two Stories.

For the shortest walk, exit the train at Peachtree Center  and follow the signs pointing to the Harris Street exit.  After exiting the fare gate, follow the signs again to Peachtree Street East.  Once you reach street level, turn right to walk along Peachtree Street and walk about a block to reach the Hyatt.  You can also reach the hotel through the Peachtree Center Mall without having to go outdoors.  Follow the signs to the mall via the Harris Street exit and there is a skybridge as the far end of the building away from Peachtree Street.

 For more information, see: 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 Peachtree Center Station Restaurants 
 Peachtree Center Attractions 
 Top 5 Most Walkable Stations 
 Tips for Riding MARTA to/from the Airport 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Bus 110 , Hotel , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Comments Off 

Tags: Atlanta Hotel 
 
 MARTA to the German Bierfest 
 
 Aug 22 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The annual German Bierfest takes place in Woodruff Park  in downtown Atlanta, about half-way between the Five Points and the Peachtree Center stations on the north-south rail line (see area map ).

If you are coming on the east-west, blue/green lines, exit at Five Points and follow the signs to street level then to the Peachtree Street exit.  Turn left onto Peachtree Street and walk about two blocks to get to Woodruff Park.

Otherwise, if you are coming from the north or south, you can also exit at the Peachtree Center Station.  Follow the signs pointing to the Ellis Street/public library exit.  After exiting the turnstiles, turn left and either take the elevator or escalator up to street level. At street level, turn left to walk along Peachtree Street.  The park is about 1.5 blocks down on the left.

For more information, see how to use Google Maps for MARTA directions and other easy destinations to get to on MARTA .
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Art, Music and Culture , Bus 110 , Bus 16 , Bus 3 , Five Points , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Comments Off 

Tags: atlanta festival 
 
 MARTA to the Westin Peachtree Plaza Hotel 
 
 Aug 12 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Westin Hotel in downtown Atlanta is very easy to get to from the Peachtree Center Station on the north-south rail line, which connects to the airport.  Follow the signs to the Harris Street exit after exiting the train, then after exiting the fare gate, follow the signs  pointing to Peachtree Street West.  This exit will put you on the same side of the street as the hotel (see area map ).

Once you’ve reached street level, turn right and walk about a half-block to the hotel.  This entrance is a side one, and the main entry is in the rear of the building should you care to walk around on the street.  To do this, turn right onto Centennial Olympic Park Drive and walk a block.

Area attractions include the Georgia Aquarium, World of Coke, CNN, Centennial Olympic Park.

 For more information, see: 
 Top 5 Hotels Closest to MARTA 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 Peachtree Center Station Restaurants 
 Tips on Riding MARTA to/from the Airport 
 10 popular Atlanta Tourist Attractions and How to Get There on MARTA 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Bus 110 , Hotel , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Comments Off 

Tags: Atlanta Downtown Hotel , Sundial Restaurant and View 
 
 MARTA to the Carter Center 
 
 Jun 6 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Carter Center is just outside downtown in a residential area and features a permanent Jimmy Carter exhibit as well as rotating exhibits.  There is a bus stop right next to the Carter Center, making it fairly easy to get to.

 Bus 16 is the route that goes to the Carter Center, which you can board at the Five Points station on Alabama Street as well as any stop on Peachtree Street from the Five Points station north to Auburn Avenue along Woodruff Park.  You can also catch the bus about  a block away from the N1 Peachtree Center station ( see area map ).

The recommended route would be to take  a north/south line train to the Peachtree Center station and follow the signs to the Harris Street exit.  After exiting the fare gate, tap your Breeze Card and follow the signs to Peachtree Street east.  At street level, turn right to walk along Peachtree Street then make the first right onto Harris Street and walk one block to Peachtree Center Avenue.  Look for any bus stop sign on Peachtree Center Avenue and wait there for the bus.  It is best to check schedules ahead of time as routes can be upwards of 20-30 minutes apart.

Once on the bus, you can let your driver know your destination.  You will know you are getting close to the Carter Center when it looks like the bus is getting on an interstate ramp.  Once the bus goes around a large curve and enters the residential area, the stop for the Carter Center is next.  To return, you’ll have to wait for bus 16 on the opposite side of the Carter Center (see bus stop map ).

For more information, see 10 Popular Atlanta Tourists Attractions and How to Get There on MARTA and how to use Google Maps for MARTA directions to get specific bus times and route information.
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Art, Music and Culture , Bus 16 , Five Points , N1 Peachtree Center , Tourist Attraction 

 Comments Off 

Tags: jimmy carter 
 
 MARTA to the Rialto Center for Performing Arts 
 
 May 26 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Rialto Center for the Performing Arts is a music and performance venue in downtown Atlanta on the Georgia State University campus.  It is an easy walk from the N1 Peachtree Center MARTA station, and is also accessible via Five Points (see area map ).

The most direct route is to exit at Peachtree Center, which is on the north-south rail line, and follow the signs to the Ellis Street exit.  After going through the fare gate, keep to the right and go up the escalator to street level.  Keep walking straight ahead to enter Forsyth Street, walk past the public library and the Rialto will be at the next intersection at 80 Forsyth Street.

The other option is to take the Forsyth Street exit out of the Five Points station and turn right and walk about three blocks, but the area is a little less safe.

If you are coming from the east or west and plan to exit at the Peachtree Center station, you must exit the train at Five Points and follow the signs to the Northbound train platform.

For more information, see how to use Google Maps for MARTA directions and the Top 5 Most Walkable MARTA Stations .
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Art, Music and Culture , Five Points , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Comments Off 

Tags: atlanta central library 
 
 MARTA to Fiesta Atlanta 
 
 Apr 30 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Fiesta Atlanta event takes place over Cinco de Mayo weekend in Centennial Olympic Park, which is in walking distance from both the W1 GWCC/Dome station and the N1 Peachtree Center station .  If you are coming from the north or south lines, exit at Peachtree Center so you can avoid transfering trains.  Likewise, if you are coming from the east or west rail line, get off at the W1 stop.

After getting off the train at W1, follow the signs to the Philips Arena exit out of the station.  Go up the escalator and stairs and keep walking straight ahead and you will reach the park.

If you exit at Peachtree Center, take the Harris Street exit out of the station then follow the signs to Peachtree Street West.  At street level, you can walk west down Andrew Young International Blvd., Harris Street or Baker Street and end up in the park (see map ).

For more information,  see how to use Google Maps for MARTA directions .
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Art, Music and Culture , N1 Peachtree Center , W1 Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena 

 Comments Off 

Tags: centennial olympic park , fiesta atlanta 
 
 MARTA to Imagine It Children’s Museum 
 
 Mar 12 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The Imagine It! Children’s Museum is located at 275 Centennial Olympic Park Dr. near the Peachtree Center Station on the red and gold rail line.

To get there on MARTA, take a red or gold line train to Peachtree Center and take the Harris Street exit off the train platform. Follow the signs to Peachtree Street West and turn left at street level. Walk one block north to Baker Street, turn left (west) on Baker and walk about three blocks (see walking map ).

Those who are sight-seeing might also want to consider exiting at the Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena Station on the blue/green rail line and take the Philips Arena exit out of the station.  From there, walk straight ahead on Centennial Olympic Park Drive that runs along the side of the station.   On the way to the museum you can also visit CNN and Centennial Olympic Park.

 For more information, see: 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 Peachtree Center Station Restaurants 
 Dome/Philips Arena Station Restaurants 
 10 Easiest Destinations to Get to on MARTA 
 10 Popular Atlanta Tourist Attractions With MARTA Directions
 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Art, Music and Culture , N1 Peachtree Center , Tourist Attraction , W1 Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena 

 Comments Off 

Tags: atlanta chidren&apos;s museum 
 
 Peachtree Center MARTA Station 
 
 Feb 28 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The N1 Peachtree Center MARTA Station is located in downtown Atlanta near many hotels and the AmericasMart (see area map ).  The station is famous for having some of the longest escalators in the Southeast, and is the furthest underground out of all the other rail stations.

 What’s Nearby 
As one of the most walkable MARTA stations , you can walk to attractions like the Georgia Aquarium , World of Coke and Centennial Olympic Park in addition to many office buildings and Georgia State University .

There are also several restaurants in close proximity to the station, including Ray’s in the City, Hard Rock Cafe’, Hooters, Il Mulino and Durango on the Harris Street end and Quizno’s, Landmark Diner off of the Ellis Street exit.  Plus most all of the area hotels have restaurants.

 Directions 
All trains departing from the airport and all trains going southbound go to the Peachtree Center Station.  If you are coming from the east/west rail line, then you must exit at the Five Points Station and transfer to a northbound train.

 Buses/Parking 
Because the station sits right along busy Peachtree Street, there are no MARTA bus routes that connect to this station.  However GCT 101 , GCT 102 , GCT 103 and GRTA Xpress 418 stop outside the station.  There is  no parking.

 Commute Time 
It takes 17 minutes to get to/from the airport and only 1 minute to the Five Points Station.

 More on the Peachtree Center Station 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 Peachtree Center Station Restaurants 
 5 Most Walkable MARTA Stations 
 10 Easiest Destinations to Get to on MARTA 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in MARTA Station , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Comments Off 

Tags: gct 101 , gct 102 , gct 103 , grta xpress 418 
 
 MARTA to the World of Coke 
 
 Feb 26 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
The World of Coke is one of more popular Atlanta tourist attractions you can get to on MARTA . There are several options to get there:

 Take any red or gold line train to the Peachtree Center Station and follow the signs to the Harris Street exit then to Peachtree Street West.  At street level, turn left along Peachtree Street and walk to Baker Street and turn left (west) on Baker.  The World of Coke is about 4 blocks down (see walking map ) and about 12 minutes of total walking time. Take the train to Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena stop on the blue and green rail line.  Take the Philips Arena exit out of the station and more or less walk straight ahead on Centennial Park Drive and through the park to reach the museum. Ride bus 32 from the Civic Center Station.   This a great route because it will also take you to the Atlanta zoo , so you can hit both attractions on the same bus line. 

 

 Walking time from either station is just under 15 minutes, so if you have small children with you, consider having strollers or wagons. The walk back to the Peachtree Center Station is uphill, but going to the Dome Station is fairly flat.  You could see the attractions around World of Coke (Georgia Aquarium, Imagine It! Children’s Museum) and walk through Centennial Olympic Park to the CNN building/tour/food court then board the train at the Dome/CNN Station. Nearby restaurants, just beyond the Georgia Aquarium, include Legal Sea Foods, Johnny Rockets and Baja Fresh Mexican Grill.  There is also a Hard Rock Cafe near the Peachtree Center Station you can eat at before or after your visit. 

 For more information, see: 
 10 Popular Atlanta Tourists Attractions and How to Get There on MARTA 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 Peachtree Center Station Restaurants 
 Navigating the Dome/Philip’s Arena Station 
 Using Google Maps for MARTA Directions 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in N1 Peachtree Center , N2 Civic Center , Tourist Attraction , W1 Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena 

 Comments Off 
 
 MARTA to the AmericasMart 
 
 Feb 8 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
A buyer and sellers showroom of the latest fashions and products, the AmericasMart is located next to the Peachtree Center MARTA station .

Take any red or gold line to the Peachtree Center Station and take the exit marked“To Harris Street”off the train platform.  After walking through the fare gate, follow the signs again to“Peachtree Street West”.  At street level, turn left alongside Peachtree Street and the Mart will be just ahead on the left.  Total walking time is approximately five minutes.

 For more information, see: 
 Top 5 Hotels Closest to MARTA 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 Peachtree Center Station Restaurants 
 Using Google Maps for MARTA Directions 
 10 Easiest Destinations to Get to on MARTA 
 10 Popular Atlanta Tourists Attractions and How to Get There on MARTA 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Business , N1 Peachtree Center , Shopping 

 Comments Off 

Tags: americas mart , americasmart 
 
 MARTA to Bank of America 
 
 Feb 8 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
If you need to do some banking or use an ATM, there are several Bank of America’s near train stations:

 S2 West End
 This Bank of America branch is directly across from the station entrance.

 E6 Decatur
 Take the Church Street exit out of the station and turn left onto Church Street, left onto Ponce and a right onto Clairemont.

 Five Points
 Take the Peachtree Street exit out of the station and immediately after exiting the fare gates, turn left and go up the escalator to the Broad Street plaza.  Walk across the plaza and keep walking straight on Broad Street.  The bank will be on the left.

 N1 Peachtree Center
 Exit at Peachtree Center and take the exit marked“To Harris Street”from the train platform.  Exit the fare gates and follow the signs to Peachtree Street East.  At street level turn right.

 N3 North Avenue 
The Bank of America tower sits next to the North Avenue station, with an ATM directly across the street from the station entrance.  Follow the signs to the West Peachtree Street exit out of the station and walk across North Avenue to get there.

 N4 Midtown 
Exit the station onto 10th Street and turn right.  Turn left at the first stoplight onto Peachtree Street and walk about block.

 N6 Lindbergh 
Take the northernmost exit out of the station and walk straight ahead on Lindbergh Lane for about two blocks.  Turn right when the street comes to a T (Main Street/Sidney Marcus).  The bank is on the next corner.

 N7 Buckhead 
After exiting the fare gates, take the first set of stairs, or the escalator, out of the station and turn left at street level.  Walk about two blocks and the bank will be on the left across from Lenox Mall.

 N9 Dunwoody
 This branch is a little bit farther to get to–at least 15 minutes.  Exit the Dunwoody fare gates and turn right.  Walk down the corridor and down the stairs.  At street level turn right and follow the sidewalk between the parking garages to reach the Perimeter Mall entrance.  Walk all the way through the mall, exit the mall and turn left along Ashford Dunwoody Road and walk about a block.
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Business , E6 Decatur , Five Points , N1 Peachtree Center , N3 North Avenue , N4 Midtown , N6 Lindbergh , N7 Buckhead , N9 Dunwoody , S2 West End 

 2 Comments 

Tags: bank of america , bank of america marta 
 
 MARTA to Georgia State University 
 
 Jan 14 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
There are three MARTA stations that can get you to the Georgia State University campus: Peachtree Center, Five Points and Georgia State .  Here are the major campus buildings ( view campus map ) and a recommendation of what rail station you should exit at:

 Business School:  Five Points School of Policy:  Five Points Natural Science Center: Five Points University Commons: Peachtree Center (Harris Street exit) Aderhold: Peachtree Center (Ellis Street exit) Haas Hall/Standard Building: Peachtree Center (Ellis Street exit) Law School: Georgia State Rec Center/Sports Arena: Georgia State Student/University Center: Georgia State Alumni Hall: Georgia State Classroom South: Georgia State Lofts: Georgia State Library: Georgia State One Park Place: Five Points College of Education: Five Points Sparks/Kell Hall/A&amp;H: Five Points or Georgia State General Classroom Building: Five Points or Georgia State 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in E1 Georgia State , Five Points , N1 Peachtree Center , School/Education 

 Comments Off 

Tags: Aderhold Learning Center , georgia state university , gsu , gsu business school , gsu commons , gsu general classroom building , gsu law school , GSU Rec Center , GSU School of Policy 
 
 MARTA to the Tabernacle 
 
 Jan 7 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
One of Atlanta’s music venues, the Tabernacle is located downtown near the Peachtree Center Station on the red/gold rail line (see area map ).  When exiting the station, be sure to take the exit marked“To Harris Street”.   After going through the fare gate, follow the signs to Peachtree Street West.

At street level turn right to walk along Peachtree Street.  At the first intersection, turn right onto Andrew Young International (Hard Rock Cafe will be across the street).  Walk one block then turn left onto Spring Street, then make a right on Luckie Street just after you walk by Ted’s Montana Grill.  The Tabernacle is less than a block down on the left.

You can also exit at the Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena Station , take the Philips Arena exit out of the station and walk straight ahead on Centennial Park Drive then turn right on Luckie Street.  The walk is slightly longer on this route and can be more isolated, especially if there aren’t any events going on around Philips Arena and the Dome.

 For more information, see: 
 Music Venues Near MARTA 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 Peachtree Center Station Restaurants 
 How to Use Google Maps for MARTA Directions 
 Georgia Dome/Philips Arena Station Restaurants 
 Navigating the Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena Station 
 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Art, Music and Culture , N1 Peachtree Center , W1 Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena 

 Comments Off 

Tags: tabernacle 
 
 MARTA to Dragon*Con 
 
 Sep 3 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
Image via Wikipedia
 
Over Labor Day weekend, Atlanta hosts the science fiction Dragon*Con conference downtown.    There is a full- costumed parade on Peachtree Street and many other events  that take place  at the hotels surrounding the N1 Peachtree Center MARTA station.

The Peachtree Center station is located on the north-south rail line, and you can take any northbound (or southbound depending on your starting point) train to the N1 Peachtree Center station.  The Ellis Street/public library exit at the south end of the station will take you up to the start of the parade and also has an elevator.  The Harris Street exit will put you closer to the event hotels, including the Hyatt Regency and Marriott Marquis .

 For more information, see: 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 Top 5 Hotels Closest to MARTA
Using Google Maps for MARTA Directions 
10 Popular Atlanta Tourists Attractions and How to Get There on MARTA .
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Art, Music and Culture , Festival , N1 Peachtree Center 

 Comments Off 

Tags: festival 
 
 MARTA to the Georgia Aquarium 
 
 Jun 15 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
Image via Wikipedia
 
The Georgia Aquarium is one of most popular tourist attractions in Atlanta,  and there are several options for getting there on MARTA:

 Take a red or gold line train to the Peachtree Center Station and take the Harris Street exit off the train platform then follow the signs to Peachtree Street West.  At street level turn left on Peachtree Street then left again on Baker Street.  The aquarium is about four blocks down ( see walking map ). The area is generally safe with mostly office buildings. Take a blue or green line train to Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena Station .  Take the Philip’s Arena exit out of the station after going up the tall escalators, keep right and walk straight ahead on Centennial Park Drive and through the park to reach the aquarium. Take bus 32 from the Civic Center Station on the red/gold rail line.   This a great route because it will also take you to the Zoo Atlanta , so you can hit both attractions on the same bus line. 

For more information, see 10 Popular Atlanta Tourists Attractions and How to Get There on MARTA and how to use Google Maps for MARTA directions to get specific bus times and route information.
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Five Points , N1 Peachtree Center , N2 Civic Center , N5 Arts Center , Tourist Attraction , W1 Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena 

 Comments Off 

Tags: Atlanta Aquarium , Georgia Aquarium , marta bus 32 
 
 MARTA to Centennial Olympic Park 
 
 Jun 4 
 
Posted by MARTA Guide 
 
 Centennial Olympic Park features water fountains, greenspace and regular events throughout the year including ice skating , Fourth Saturday Fun Days (summer months), Wednesday WindDowns, Fourth of July fireworks and more.

There are two MARTA stations that are close to the park: Peachtree Center on the red/gold line and the Georgia Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena Station on the blue/green rail line.

From the Peachtree Center Station, take the Harris Street exit off the train platform, then follow the signs to Peachtree Street West.  At street level, turn right or left on Peachtree Street and at the first intersection you come to, walk west down Andrew Young International Blvd. or Harris Street to reach the park (see walking map ).    These streets will also put you closer to the ice rink as well as the Children’s Museum, World of Coke and the Georgia Aquarium.

From the Dome Station, follow the signs pointing to Philips Arena to exit the station.  Go up the tall escalators and keeping walking straight ahead up the stairs and along Centennial Olympic Park Drive to reach the park.  Philips Arena will be on your left.

 For more information, see: 
 Georgia Dome/Philips Arena Station Restaurants 
 Navigating the Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena Station 
 Navigating the Peachtree Center Station 
 5 Most Walkable MARTA Stations 
 How to Use Google Maps for MARTA Directions 
 
Share this:
 
 Email Print Facebook Twitter 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
Posted in Art, Music and Culture , N1 Peachtree Center , Sports and Outdoors , Tourist Attraction , W1 Dome/GWCC/Philips Arena 

 Comments Off 

Tags: 4th saturday family fun day , centennial olympic park , film , fountain of rings , Georgia Aquarium , museum , olympic park , olympic park ice skating , park , screen on the green , Wednesday Winddown 
 
 Search for: 
 News and Updates 

 Weekend MARTA accessible events up! Street Food Festival, Braves, Avengers. fb.me/X58m9n8h 1 hour ago 
 Follow @MARTAGuide 
 MARTA Information 

 Breeze Cards How to Ride MARTA Buses How to Ride MARTA Trains MARTA Maps MARTA Park and Ride MARTA Trip Planning Megabus and MARTA Train Schedules and Frequency 
 
 Upcoming Events 

 Braves Games Outdoor Movies @ Atlantic Station (Thursdays) Summer Films at the Fox Unplugged in the Park (Sundays) 
 
 Most Popular 

 Station Map Hotels MARTA to the Megabus MARTA to Atlantic Station North Springs MARTA Station MARTA to Turner Field Doraville MARTA Station Welcome MARTA to the AmericasMart Station Guides Civic Center MARTA Station MARTA to Cumberland Mall 
 
 Recently Added 

 MARTA to the Shakespeare Tavern MARTA to Hyatt Atlanta Midtown MARTA to CVS Pharmacy 
 
 
 
 Facebook 
 
 
 
 Email Sign Up 
 
Enter your email address to follow this website and receive notifications of new posts by email.

 

 
 
 
 
Popular Tips

 10 Easiest MARTA Destinations 5 Walkable MARTA Stations MARTA to/from the Airport Using Google Maps for MARTA Directions 
 
 
 
 Latest Articles 

 Weekend MARTA destinations: Street Food Festival; Braves vs. Mets; Avengers MARTA destinations: Ringo Starr; Collective Soul; Heritage Arts Festival 10 Frugal summer activities on MARTA 
 
 
 Blog at WordPress.com .
 Theme: Mystique by digitalnature .
 Follow 
 Follow“MARTA Guide” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com Send to Email Address Your Name Your Email Address Cancel Post was not sent - check your email addresses! Email check failed, please try again Sorry, your blog cannot share posts by email.
	</body>
</document>
