<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002481" url="http://www.bizbuysell.com/washington/ellensburg/restaurants-for-sale/?q=/wEFA249YQ==" time="2012-07-12-18:32" support="3" score="0.0021225541288393737" bingtitle="Ellensburg, WA Restaurants For Sale - BizBuySell.com" webtitle="Ellensburg, WA Restaurants For Sale - BizBuySell.com">
			<query id="000807" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="000808" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="000802" bing-rank="224"/>
	<description>Find your ideal Ellensburg Fast Food Restaurant, Indian Restaurant, or other ... Exit Equity ~ for 17 years we have advised ... best place to list used car lot and rental ...</description>
	<body>
		Already a BizBuySell Member?

Log In to Continue
 


Invalid log in. Check your user name and password.
 Email Address (Member ID): Password: 
 Verifying... 
 
 Forgot Your Password? 

 Note : The email address you provided matches an existing account. Please log in using this email address and your original password. If you don&apos;t recall your password, click the &apos;Forgot Your Password?&apos; link.
 
 Are you new to BizBuySell? 
 
 
BizBuySell - The Internet&apos;s Largest Business for Sale&amp;Franchise for Sale Marketplace
 
 Welcome! Sign In Register For Brokers 

 My BizBuySell BrokerWorks 
 My Listings My Watch List My Saved Searches My BizAlerts My Ad Responses My Ad Inquiries My Valuation Reports My Community Questions My Community Answers My Profile 
 Sign Out For Brokers 
 
 
 
 

 Properly valuing small, family owned businesses and larger companies. Determining which businesses offer the greatest financial return. How to value a business and negotiate the price. And much more... 

 Enter email address: 
 Please note that you can opt out of the BizBuySell Bulletin at any time. 


 Ellensburg, WA Restaurants For Sale 
 0 Ellensburg Restaurant Businesses for Sale Found. 

Below are the Ellensburg Restaurants currently available for sale on BizBuySell. Find your ideal Ellensburg Fast Food Restaurant , Indian Restaurant , or other Ellensburg Restaurant opportunity. If you don&apos;t find what you are looking for, try our advanced search or consider setting an email alert to be notified any time new Ellensburg Restaurants
	</body>
</document>
