<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002002" url="http://sarahtigertree.wordpress.com/2011/07/23/fast-food-conspiracy/" time="2012-07-12-17:55" support="3" score="0.0009261102400017916" bingtitle="Fast food conspiracy « sarahtigertree" webtitle="Fast food conspiracysarahtigertree">
			<query id="001489" bing-rank="227"/>
			<query id="000955" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000452" bing-rank="105"/>
	<description>At one fast food restaurant, it was suggested that I order the value meal, have them ... Or what if it would be cheaper to get a couch for the price of a love-seat?</description>
	<body>
		Home About 
 
sarahtigertree

Just another WordPress.com site
 July 23, 2011 
Fast food conspiracy
 By bjarnetree 
Okay, I am not much of a conspiracy theorist, but I definitely believe there is a conspiracy in the fast food industry.  I went to a certain fast food restaurant and ordered a fish sandwich, a bottled water and a small fry.  I was told that it was cheaper to get a super value meal which includes the sandwich, a large fry and a gigantic sugary pop.  I told the worker that I didn’t want that much food and I didn’t like pop.  She frowned and said,“suit yourself…it’s just going to cost a lot more.”A lot more?!  Why?  Wouldn’t it be logical that the less food you have, the cheaper it would be?  And it was more expensive…insanely more expensive in fact.  I started paying attention to menus and realized that all fast food restaurants do this insane practice; they charge immensely for those who do not want to be in a fat-induced coma by the age of 25.

I am by no means a health-nut, as my friends would attest to, however, why are those of us who are trying to be frugal and eat in moderation penalized.  At one fast food restaurant, it was suggested that I order the value meal, have them trade out the pop for water and just not eat it all.  Um…okay…wasteful much?  I supposed I could feed the extra fries to the birds, but really…I just want a small fry!

My frustration with this phenomenon has turned encouraged me to stop going to fast food restaurants all together…which is good.  I just hope that other businesses learn from the fast food chains.  Wouldn’t it be great if it was cheaper to get all of your groceries for $20.00 if you bought them all at the same time?  Or what if it would be cheaper to get a couch for the price of a love-seat?  Even better, a King size bed would be cheaper than a twin.  This conspiracy has been going on for a long time; I think it is time for other businesses to pick up on the trend.  Momma needs a king-size bed!
 
Share this:
 
 Twitter Facebook 
 
Like this:
 Like Be the first to like this. 
About bjarnetree
 I am a unique and eccentric individual with a penchant for saving bugs, talking to trees and singing aloud (even when there is no music playing). I am the mother of two intelligent, wonderful toddlers who both think they are going to be rock stars, but haven&apos;t quite developed the skills to sing in tune (a gift from their Mother, perhaps?). I am a case manager and have a passion for working with the underprivileged. I am socially inept as I do not fit into any category of human being that I have found. View all posts by bjarnetree This entry was posted on Saturday, July 23rd, 2011 at 8:27 pm and tagged with business , fast food , french fries , value meals and posted in I&apos;m confused . You can follow any responses to this entry through the RSS 2.0 feed. « Idiot Clause Cold Coffee » 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 Enter your comment here... 
Fill in your details below or click an icon to log in:

 
 Email (required) (Address never made public) Name (required) Website 
 You are commenting using your WordPress.com account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Twitter account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 
 You are commenting using your Facebook account. (  Log Out  /  Change  ) 
 Cancel 
Connecting to %s
 
 Notify me of follow-up comments via email. 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
Pages

 About 
 
Archives

 August 2011 July 2011 
 
 Subscribe RSS Blog at WordPress.com .
 Theme: Elegant Grunge by Michael Tyson . Follow 
 Follow“sarahtigertree” 
 
Get every new post delivered to your Inbox.



 
 
 
 Powered by WordPress.com
	</body>
</document>
