<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002286" url="http://voices.yahoo.com/6-tips-working-fast-food-8012972.html" time="2012-07-12-18:11" support="3" score="0.0017418921286111622" bingtitle="6 Tips for Working in the Fast Food Industry - Yahoo! Voices ..." webtitle="6 Tips for Working in the Fast Food Industry - Yahoo! Voices - voices.yahoo.com">
			<query id="000935" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="000932" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="001466" bing-rank="73"/>
	<description>... employee can do to waste ... you walk out of the store ... with working at a fast food restaurant as a first job or if you have no other options, but you should get out of ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Voices 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
6 Tips for Working in the Fast Food Industry
 Errick D. Williams , Yahoo! Contributor Network 
Mar 14, 2011 &quot;Share your voice on Yahoo! websites. Start Here .&quot; 
 More: Fast Food Food and Beverage 
 Flag Close Post a comment Most young people and uneducated adults end up in the fast food industry in some form or another. Of course, these people prepare hundreds of burgers or sandwiches per day for people that want a quick, cheap meal. The job isn&apos;t that great and doesn&apos;t come with a ton of perks. Still, it&apos;s a good way to start out your job history if you don&apos;t have any or if you lack an education. Most of the jobs are extremely easy - if not boring. So then, here are some tips for working in the fast food injury.
 Always look busy rather than standing around doing nothing. 
Obviously, your job is going to go nowhere if your supervisor always thinks that you do nothing while at work. You should make it a chore at work to always look busy, even if you aren&apos;t. This can help you get raises and get a better position. Of course, there are plenty of different things a fast food joint employee can do to waste time. Supplies of ketchup packets and cups are always dwindling, so going to the back is actually necessary quite often. No matter what, don&apos;t ever get caught doing nothing on the job or you could face some consequences.

 Never eat the fast food that you serve (or any other fast food). 
Without a doubt, eating the fast food that you prepare is an extremely bad idea. It&apos;s unhealthy, and you have pretty easy access to all of these foods. You should always take your lunch break away from the fast food restaurant that you work for or it could start to affect your health. Sure, it might seem ultra convenient to pick something off the heating area before you walk out of the store, but that&apos;s only going to lead to regret and health issues later on. Therefore, you should always eat healthy, non-fast food when you work in a fast food restaurant. Do your body and health some favors.

 Be a great employee to earn more money and climb the employment ladder. 
You should display courtesy and kindness at all times while on the job. First of all, this can directly lead to a raise or a promotion. Employees that are regularly complimented upon by customers to management are almost always rewarded in some way or another. An employee that constantly gets praise is likely to be in line for some raises and maybe even a promotion. So then, you can&apos;t let the boring job get to you at any time because it pays much more to suck it up and exhibit excitement and friendliness on the job. Just think about what you could do with a raise!

 Shower after work to avoid that constant grease smell. 
Unfortunately, working in a fast food restaurant means that you will constantly smell and feel greasy after work or whenever you are wearing your uniform. It&apos;s always a good idea to shower as soon as you get off work to avoid these smells and feelings. Also, you should purchase two work uniforms so that you aren&apos;t stuck in a single, smelly uniform all week. You should wash both of them two times per week to keep them relatively clean and grease-free. For some people, the greasy environment of a fast food restaurant&apos;s kitchen is their least favorite part of the job.

 Keep your drawer balanced to keep your job. 
As with any job that involves money handling, you need to be accurate and efficient with money. Failing to balance your drawer each day can get you fired or accused of stealing from the company. Don&apos;t make careless mistakes when handling money because it could cost you your job after a few incidents. Without a doubt, you should work on quick efficiency when it comes to dealing with a cash register, receiving money, and giving change. Doing a lazy job with money handling can leave your drawer short on money and could get you kicked out of the fast food restaurant. Obviously, nobody wants to lose their job for something so simple.

 Don&apos;t stay in the industry too long. 
Without a doubt, the fast food industry is one of the worst industries to work in. There is very little room for income improvement, even if you get constant raises and promotions. You still won&apos;t be earning that much money - whether you&apos;re a fry cook or a manager. So then, you should enter the fast food industry as your first job, spend a year or two there to get some experience or cash, and then you should switch jobs right away. Honestly, job loyalty to a fast food joint doesn&apos;t pay well and it won&apos;t get you very much else aside from a dead-end job. Get out of the fast food industry and stay away from it at all costs after that.

 The fast food industry isn&apos;t for you...or anyone. 

Still, plenty of people end up working at fast food restaurants, whether they have no education, other job opportunities, or something else. There is nothing wrong with working at a fast food restaurant as a first job or if you have no other options, but you should get out of there as soon as you have enough experience to qualify for a better job. Either way, you have to make the best of the job while you work there, so you should remember these tips and do whatever you can to earn raises or promotions.

 More Information 

Fast Food Careers
 www.kelloggforum.org/fast-food-careers/ 

Making a Fast Food Job Better
 www.wikihow.com/Make-the-Best-of-Working-in-a-Fast-Food-Restaurant 

Food and Beverage Occupational Outlook
 www.bls.gov/oco/ocos162.htm 
 
Published by Errick D. Williams 

 View profile 
 
 Could Living Near a Fast Food Restaurant Be as Bad as Second Hand Smoke? A study at the University of michigan showed that the risk of a stroke in a neighborhood increased by 1 percent for every fast food restaurant that was located there. Things to Avoid Saying to Fast Food Workers Here are some of the many things that you will want to avoid saying to someone who works in the fast food industry. &quot;Healthy&quot; Fast Food: America&apos;s Biggest Oxymoron Seldom today can one go anywhere without being bombarded by food advertisements. Whether it&apos;s a high-rise billboard or a ten second radio commercial, food has worked its way into the everyday lives of Americans. Five Ideas to Create Sustainable Fast Food Chains How can fast food restaurants be sustainable? They may never be 100% sustainable but here are a few solutions to bring them closer. Surviving in the Food Service Industry More and more of us these days find ourselves in one of the most stressful industries of all: food service. Here&apos;s some survival tips from a 15-year veteran. 

 UBS Raises McDonald&apos;s Target Pri... Health To Go: How To Order Wisel... Fast Food Restaurant Salads Expo... 
 
 Getting a Job at the Fast-Food Restaurant 20 Fun Facts About Fast Food Kevin Federline&apos;s Nationwide Commercial Offending Fast Food Employees Consumers Taking a Legal Stand Against Fast Food Fast Food Nation and Fast Food&apos;s Effect on American Society The Fast Food Industry - You Pay Them to Kill You, While Still Making Hefty Profits What High School Students Should Know Before Interviewing for a Job Any Other Fast... 
 
 
 
To comment, please sign in to your Yahoo! account, or sign up for a new account.
 
Yahoo! Voices

 Entertainment Auto Business Creative Writing Health Home Improvement Lifestyle 

 News Sports Tech Travel Slideshow Library Video Library 
 
Also on Yahoo!

 Autos Finance Games Groups Health Mail 

 Maps Movies Music My Yahoo! News Shine 

 Shopping Sports omg! Travel TV Contributor Network 
 All Yahoo! Services» 
Yahoo! Contributor Network

 Join / Sign in Help 

 Community Resources Blog Forum Promotional Tools Contests User Search Featured Contributors 
 Copyright©2012 Yahoo! Inc. All rights reserved. | Yahoo! Finance and Yahoo! News Network. 
 Questions or Comments Privacy Policy About Our Ads
	</body>
</document>
