<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002320" url="http://www.contactmusic.com/movie-review/scotlandpa" time="2012-07-12-18:14" support="1" score="0.000811936936528629" bingtitle="Scotland, Pa Review (2001) | Movie | Contactmusic.com" webtitle="Scotland, Pa Review (2001) | Movie | Contactmusic.com">
			<query id="001028" bing-rank="174"/>
	<description>... LeGros) is the brains behind the thriving fast-food restaurant ... Pat McBeth (Maura Tierney), who works the tables. ... By turning all actors of the play into white-trash ...</description>
	<body>
		Home &gt; Film &gt; Reviews &gt; Scotland, PA James Legros | Pictures | Video | Movies 
Scotland, Pa Movie Review

 
 
 
 
Cast&amp;Crew

 Director : Billy Morrissette 

 Producer : Richard Shepard , Jonathan Stern 

 Screenwriter : Billy Morrissette 

 Starring : James LeGros , Maura Tierney , Kevin Corrigan , James Rebhorn , Christopher Walken , Amy Smart , Andy Dick , Timothy &quot;Speed&quot; Levitch
 
Fueled by gritty Bad Company songs, enough plaid to keep all residents of 
Alaska warm for winter, and Pabst Blue Ribbon on tap–Scotland, PA blasts onto 
the silver screen with the reckless intent of Patty Hearst during a bank 
robbery.

The last place I’d expect to see a Shakespearean adaptation of Macbeth to occur 
would be in a backwater town in the middle of Pennsylvania circa 1972. But it 
provides a dark and menacing backdrop to this loose–and do I mean loose–adaptation of Shakespeare&apos;s ever-popular tragedy of a incompetent husband and 
power-hungry wife weaving murderously toward power and riches.

The story revolves around the sordid tale of disillusioned fast-food workers 
vying for the power of the drive-thru window, set to butt-rocking seventies 
metal. Joe“Mac”McBeth (James LeGros) is the brains behind the thriving 
fast-food restaurant -- Duncan’s -- along with his conniving and sultry wife 
Pat McBeth (Maura Tierney), who works the tables. His boss, Norm Duncan (James 
Rebhorn), is a schmuck of a boss who constantly overlooks the abilities of Mac 
and his brilliant ideas for expanding the business.

One night while walking home drunk, Mac encounters three hippies (Andy Dick, 
Timothy &quot;Speed&quot; Levitch, and Amy Smart)–the three witches of Fate–who 
foretell Mac’s future and plant the seeds of revenge against his employer. Mac 
and Pat concoct a plan of thievery and murder, and after depositing the‘king’into the French fryer, Mac and Pat reign supreme in greasy food distribution 
until chief inspector McDuff (Christopher Walken) comes a-calling to find the 
murderers of the slain king.

As tensions mounts and the body count slowly rises, the slain king’s son comes 
screaming out of his homosexual closet, and Mac and Pat slowing descend into 
1970s decadence (complete with a wood-paneled basement and red muscle cars) as 
well as the madness of their own treacheries.

Director Billy Morrissette has produced the first concise parody of the classic 
Macbeth. It’s unbelievable that Morrissette’s previous forays into film 
production include stints as a bit part actor in Ghoulies 3: Ghoulies Go To 
College and as Paramedic #1 in the awful Vegas Vacation. By stripping away all 
of the fancy dialogue and introspective diatribes of the original text, 
Morrissette has produced a quirky noir film crammed full of wonderful 
characters made memorable by excellent acting. Strong performances by indie 
favorites James LeGros and Kevin Corrigan bring merit to the roles of Mac and 
Banko and the sultry Maura Tierney as Pat McBeth could cause even me to gun 
down my boss for her love. [You&apos;re fired. -Ed.]

By turning all actors of the play into white-trash hicks, small-town folks with 
simpleton minds, and thick guys with thick suntans–the original story 
virtually slips away. Everything about the production–from the set designs 
to the revolting fashion and hair designs–perfectly fits the scene. Between 
Mac throwing back Jack and Tabs at the local bar to Pat’s endless smoking of 
extra slim cigarettes, the 1970s haven&apos;t been this vivid since Linklater’s 
Dazed and Confused.

The glue that holds all these elements together resounds in the standout 
performances by Christopher Walken as McDuff–a vegan cop who drives a small 
German automobile listening to inspirational tapes–who manages to rival 
Frances McDormand’s character from Fargo as most memorable cop. Whenever 
Walken enters the scene, he no longer resembles a supporting actor but a force 
of nature commanding response from all parties involved. His intrepid snooping 
brings out the biggest laughs I’ve ever had in any Shakespearean tragedy.

Despite the loads of laughs and great acting, the film serves more as a Pyrrhic 
victory for Morrissete. By stripping away all of the meat of the original 
story and turning it into a linear tale of revenge and murder, the story loses 
its muscle. The ending is sadly no better than your average direct-to-Showtime 
action flick.

The Scotland DVD includes a commentary track and a couple of minor extras.

The waitress doth protest too much.
 
 Tweet 
 
 More From Contactmusic.com 
 
 More From The Web 
 

 Write for us 
 
 
 
Comments
 Enter your comment here... Post to my Facebook wall (Facebook Connect users). 
James Legros Newsletter

Subscribe to this news alert service to receive news and reviews on James Legros

 Unsubscribe 
 
 Films by Artist: A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z 
 
Scotland, Pa Rating
 
 &quot; Excellent &quot; 

Rating: R, 2001
 
James Legros Photos
 
 James Legros Gallery 
 
James Legros Film Reviews
 
 The Last Winter 
 
 Trust the Man 
 
 November 
 
 Sexual Life 
 

 More James Legros Movies 
 
James Legros Videos
	</body>
</document>
