<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002606" url="http://www.tripadvisor.com/Restaurant_Review-g32827-d854709-Reviews-Adalberto_s_Mexican_Food-Orangevale_California.html" time="2012-07-12-18:40" support="5" score="0.025809241666843646" bingtitle="Adalberto&apos;s Mexican Food, Orangevale - Restaurant Reviews ..." webtitle="Adalbertos Mexican Food Reviews - 5 Restaurant Reviews - TripAdvisor">
			<query id="000883" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="001511" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000037" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="001103" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000350" bing-rank="58"/>
	<description>Just went through the drivethru and placed my order. All was ... eat this side of Mexico for quality authentic mexican food. Set up like a fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Adalberto&apos;s Mexican Food, Orangevale
 
 Home Orangevale 
 Orangevale Tourism Orangevale Vacation Rentals Flights to Orangevale Orangevale Restaurants Orangevale Travel Forum Orangevale Photos Orangevale Travel Guide 
 Flights Vacation Rentals Restaurants Best of 2012 More 
 Travel Guides Travel Forum Apps Cruises 
 Write a Review 
 
 Sign in with Facebook Sign in Register Now! FREE Mobile App 
 
 Home 
 &gt; United States &gt; California (CA) &gt; Orangevale &gt; Orangevale Restaurants &gt; Adalberto&apos;s Mexican Food 
 
 All 21 Orangevale Restaurants» 
Adalberto&apos;s Mexican Food
 8844 Greenback Ln , Orangevale , CA 95662-4019 916-988-6508 Got a photo? 
 Add it. Ranked #8 of 21 restaurants in Orangevale 5 Reviews Cuisines: Mexican Restaurant details Update restaurant details Write a Review 
5 reviews from our community
 60% Recommend 
 Excellent 2 Very good 1 Average 1 Poor 0 Terrible 1 
 Rating summary 
 Food Service Value Atmosphere 
 5 reviews sorted by Date Rating English first Any gfales Orangev 1 review “disgusting!” Reviewed August 2, 2011 
I have been here three times and have always ordered a carnitas burrito. Just went through the drivethru and placed my order. All was good until I took my first bite and had a mouthful of cartilage. I took my chances and kept eating, and about every third bite had the same. The whole burrito was full of cartilage.
I... More 
 
 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? TifLaf Eureka, CA Contributor 13 reviews Reviews in 2 cities 7 helpful votes “Almost always makes me sick yet I keep going back for more!!!” Reviewed March 12, 2010 
My dear friend Adalberto&apos;s: why does something so good have to be so bad? It almost always seems to make my tummy hurt, but they are always open, the food is cheap and tasty, the portion size is, well huge.
There is nothing like an Adalberto&apos;s egg, bacon and potato burrito at 3 A.M.!!
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? RPF49 Davis, California Top Contributor 193 reviews Reviews in 32 cities 174 helpful votes “Great Mexican fast food” Reviewed July 2, 2009 
Adalberto&apos;s is the best Mexican fast food around in an old-style drive-in (i.e, not counting some of the newer taquerias, although it&apos;s better than a lot of those too). Great taste, huge portions, definitely not for the diet conscious!! Budget prices.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? Ramblingrochelle California Reviewer 3 reviews Reviews in 2 cities 2 helpful votes “Amazingly authentic quality mexican food at fast food prices” Reviewed July 30, 2008 1 person found this review helpful 
There is no better place to eat this side of Mexico for quality authentic mexican food. Set up like a fast food restaurant with fast food ordering, an optional drive up window for on the go travelers and small tables to eat inside , it isnt meant to keep you lingering. They also have a small mexican store on site.... More 
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? A TripAdvisor reviewer on Facebook 1 helpful vote “Yummy #24.” Reviewed February 7, 2008 
Yummy #24.
 Was this review helpful? Yes Problem with this review? 1-5 of 5 reviews 1 
Also consider these other restaurants near Adalberto&apos;s Mexican Food
 Donut Spot 
 1 Review &quot;Soft and tasty doughnuts&quot; 
 0.0 miles from Adalberto&apos;s Mexican Food 
 Annie&apos;s Breakfast&amp;Steaks 
 3 Reviews &quot;Only the locals know how good this place Is&quot; 
 0.1 miles from Adalberto&apos;s Mexican Food 
 Mountain Mike&apos;s Pizza 
 1 Review &quot;Great pizza&quot; 
 0.1 miles from Adalberto&apos;s Mexican Food 
 All restaurants in Orangevale (21) 
Been to Adalberto&apos;s Mexican Food? Share your experiences!
 Write a Review Add Photos Add Videos 
Owners: What&apos;s your side of the story?

If you own or manage Adalberto&apos;s Mexican Food, register now for free tools to enhance your
listing, attract new reviews, and respond to reviewers.
 Manage your listing 
Browse nearby
 Restaurants (21) Adalberto&apos;s Mexican Food 8844 Greenback Ln Orangevale, CA 95662-4019 Get Directions What&apos;s Nearby: Hotels Restaurants Things to Do Click map pins for more information. You are zoomed out too far to see location pins. Please zoom back in. Interactive map 
Traveler Photos&amp;Videos
 
 Cartilage By gfales Orangev 
 All Photos | Add photos | Add videos 
Free Orangevale Guide
 Get your quick guide to the top hotels, restaurants and things to do.   Get it now 
Popular Orangevale restaurants

 Blue NAMI Sushi&amp;Sake House Lupita&apos;s Authentic Mexican Restaurant Donut Spot Mountain Mike&apos;s Pizza Annie&apos;s Breakfast&amp;Steaks Asheley&apos;s Country Kitchen L&apos;Orchid Wa-Me Restaurant LA Placita B J Bakery Don Pancho Wonder Hostess Thrift Shop Jeff&apos;s Mesquite Barbecue Pik A Deli Kolbeh Kabob Jack&apos;s Donut Wheel New York Pizza Spice Tiki Hut Cafe 
 
Hotels around Orangevale

 Red Roof Inn Rancho Cordova - Sacramento 3.5 out of 5, 55 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 BEST WESTERN PLUS Sutter House 4.0 out of 5, 78 reviews Last reviewed Jul 10, 2012 Hilton Sacramento Arden West 3.5 out of 5, 95 reviews Last reviewed Jul 10, 2012 Hampton Inn&amp;Suites Folsom 4.5 out of 5, 46 reviews Last reviewed Jul 10, 2012 Heritage Inn Express Roseville 2.0 out of 5, 23 reviews Last reviewed Jul 9, 2012 BEST WESTERN Expo Inn&amp;Suites 3.0 out of 5, 37 reviews Last reviewed Jul 3, 2012 BEST WESTERN Golden Key 4.5 out of 5, 59 reviews Last reviewed Jul 3, 2012 Heritage Inn Express Rocklin 3.0 out of 5, 26 reviews Last reviewed Jun 28, 2012 Holiday Inn Rancho Cordova 3.5 out of 5, 24 reviews Last reviewed Jun 24, 2012 Extended StayAmerica Sacramento/Roseville 2.5 out of 5, 11 reviews Last reviewed Jun 16, 2012 Comfort Suites 3.5 out of 5, 14 reviews Last reviewed Jun 12, 2012 Extended StayAmerica Sacramento/Arden 4.0 out of 5, 16 reviews Last reviewed Jun 12, 2012 Homestead South Natomas 4.0 out of 5, 25 reviews Last reviewed Jun 7, 2012 Crossland Economy Studios Sacramento-Point East Dr 3.5 out of 5, 13 reviews Last reviewed Jun 5, 2012 Extended StayAmerica Sacramento-Rancho Cordova 3.0 out of 5, 9 reviews Last reviewed Apr 26, 2012 
 Explore the world Restaurants 
 Mi Cocina in San Jose del Cabo 4.0 out of 5, 35 reviews Le Casier a Vins in Paris 4.0 out of 5, 5 reviews Nobu in Nassau 4.0 out of 5, 121 reviews The Mint in Raleigh 3.5 out of 5, 35 reviews Benedict in Tel Aviv 4.5 out of 5, 196 reviews Marlowe in San Francisco 4.5 out of 5, 11 reviews 
 Hotels 
 Hotel Melantrich 4.0 out of 5, 243 reviews Last reviewed Jul 9, 2012 Star Hotel in Nice 4.0 out of 5, 191 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Eden Village Hotel 4.5 out of 5, 295 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 Coral Sands Hotel in Harbour Island 4.0 out of 5, 191 reviews Last reviewed Jul 11, 2012 
 About TripAdvisor® TripAdvisor®features reviews and advice on hotels, resorts, flights, vacation rentals, vacation packages, travel guides, and lots more. Reviews and advice on hotels, resorts, flights, vacation rentals, travel packages, and lots more! Select a TripAdvisor site: 
 
 About Us | Write a review | Careers | Site Map | Top Cities | Owners | Help Center | Business Listings | DMO/CVB | Investor Relations © 2012 TripAdvisor LLC All rights reserved. TripAdvisor Terms of Use and Privacy Policy . Some photos provided by VFM Leonardo. * TripAdvisor LLC is not a booking agent and does not charge any service fees to users of our site... ( more ) TripAdvisor LLC is not responsible for content on external web sites. Taxes, fees not included for deals content.
	</body>
</document>
