<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002610" url="http://v2.ksl.com/index.php?nid=443&amp;sid=733005&amp;tab=images" time="2012-07-12-18:41" support="2" score="0.0035312905943067517" bingtitle="Car Classifieds for Utah, Idaho, and Wyoming | ksl.com" webtitle="Car Classifieds for Utah, Idaho, and Wyoming | ksl.com">
			<query id="000959" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="000113" bing-rank="221"/>
	<description>Utah&apos;s Fastest Growing Car Website: Search for a ... Buyer/Seller offers to pay with a money order or cashiers ... Seller explains that a third party or service will pick ...</description>
	<body>
		Login    Feedback    Contact Us KSL TV       KSL Newsradio       iWitness    » Classifieds all of KSL Classifieds Local Web Keyword 
 Utah Page Two U.S. World Sports Weather Traffic Biz Entertainment Shows More 
 
 Deals Local Jobs Homes Cars Classifieds 
 
 Classifieds Cars Homes Jobs Services Construction Center 

 Advanced Search Help My Ads Place an Ad 
 Classified 
 Car 
 Business Job About this ad 
Cars&amp;Trucks
 (10,609,167 Served) See Also:   Auto Parts , Motorcycles, Dirt Bikes , Motorcycles, Road Bikes , Snowmobiles , Camp and Travel Trailers , Wheels and Tires , Auto Parts 
 Body: Click Here Year: Click Here Make: Click Here Price: Click Here Model: Click Here Dealer: Click Here State: Click Here Zipcode: Click Here Mileage: Click Here Int-Color: Click Here City: Click Here Ext-Color: Click Here Trans: Click Here Drive: Click Here Fuel: Click Here Seller: Click Here # Doors: Click Here Clear search... Show advanced search... 
 
  List View Photo View My Car Ads Sell A Car Coupons 
 List Newest to Oldest List Oldest to Newest List Price High to Low List Price Low to High Utah&apos;s Fastest Growing Car Website: 
 Search for a specific car by clicking on the attributes above: 2005 - Toyota $2,900 00 2004 - Dodge $12,900 00 1997 - Honda $2,200 00 2005 - GMC $2,900 00 1993 - Toyota $1,800 00 2001 - Mercury $3,200 00 2005 - Toyota $2,900 00 2002 - Volvo $4,800 00 1951 - Studebaker $13,500 00 1977 - Ford $4,000 00 1998 - Jeep $3,999 00 2006 - Mazda $2,900 00 1994 - Geo $1,500 00 2009 - Ford $19,250 00 1999 - Volvo $2,300 00 2004 - Ford $4,700 00 2002 - Infiniti $4,900 00 2009 - MINI $20,999 00 2003 - Jeep $7,200 00 1991 - Chevrolet $9,450 00 2002 - Ford $4,500 00 1997 - Mitsubishi $7,000 00 2003 - Chevrolet $7,995 00 1993 - Ford $9,800 00 1996 - Volkswagen $900 00 1963 - Ford $6,500 00 1991 - Chevrolet $1,200 00 2006 - Mitsubishi $8,950 00 1969 - Chevrolet $7,300 00 1997 - Honda $2,900 00 2007 - Chevrolet $32,000 00 2002 - Chevrolet $9,700 00 2000 - Ford $3,995 00 2000 - Toyota $3,700 00 2000 - GMC $2,900 00 2001 - Chevrolet $9,400 00 1997 - Nissan $1,460 00 1994 - Ford $1,900 00 1999 - Pontiac $1,500 00 1969 - Chevrolet $7,300 00 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 Beware of Classified Ad Fraud! 
KSL Classifieds is meant to be a local service for those in Utah and the immediately surrounding areas. However, individuals outside of the country will frequently contact sellers or post their own fraudulent ads. Do not be misled! These are not honest people with exceptional deals, but criminals trying to take your money. Watch for the following signs:

 Buyer/Seller explains that they are currently out of the country. Buyer/Seller offers to pay with a money order or cashiers check for significantly more than the asked for price. Buyer/Seller explains that a third party or service will pick up or deliver the item. Email inquiry is poorly written, generic, or strange sounding. Offer is simply too good to be true. 

 For more information on how to protect yourself: CLICK HERE. 
 About this ad About this ad Most Popular 
 Read Video Commented Sports Deseret News 
 
 
 1. Thief steals camera, pictures of ... 
 
 2. Jordan: 1992 Dream Team better than 2012 ... 
 
 3. Lightning starts new fire in Tooele County 
 
 4. Charges filed against man for sexually ... 
 
 5. Families of both victim and suspect in ... 
 
 
 
 1. Thief steals camera, pictures of ... 
 
 2. Families of both victim and suspect in ... 
 
 3. Long-sought national fugitives arrested ... 
 
 4. Salt Lake computer repair business ... 
 
 5. Juan Diego athlete dies in accident 
 
 
 
 1. Romney faces NAACP, booed for hitting ... 
 
 2. Slap to Obama: GOP House votes to kill ... 
 
 3. Family sues Bountiful, Woods Cross police ... 
 
 4. Families of both victim and suspect in ... 
 
 5. Photos show progress of LDS temple in Rome 
 
 
 
 1. Utah wants to help more kids at home and ... 
 
 2. State report: Red Butte Creek is now safe ... 
 
 3. Louis Freeh: Penn St. disregarded ... 
 
 4. Sierra Newbold&apos;s family thanks police, ... 
 
 5. &apos;Water footprints&apos; and how much water is ... 
 
 
 
 1. Jordan: 1992 Dream Team better than 2012 ... 
 
 2. Inquiry: Penn St. officials concealed ... 
 
 3. Juan Diego athlete dies in accident 
 
 4. Watch Me Now 
 
 5. Golf News 
 
 About this ad About this ad Site Index 
 
 News 

 Utah 
 News Investigations Tough Times Survival Bank Staying Safe Statecraft Sunday Edition 


 Page Two 
 Motherhood Matters Happy Living Pic&amp;Flix Science&amp;Innovation Tech&amp;Gadgets Gamer&apos;s Guide Religion Odds&amp;Ends Have you seen this? Video of the Day 

 National World Entertainment Biz/Finance Consumer Sci/Tech Health Education 
 KSL Schools 

 
 Weather 

 Forecasts Current Conditions VORTEX Microcast Water Watch 
 Snowpack totals Ramp reports Lawn Watering guide Flood/Water Flow 
 Photo Galleries Weather Planner Weather Lab Ask the Meteorologist Ski Report Weather on 5.3 


 Traffic 

 Traffic Cams 


 Special Features 

 General Conference Mission Guide 


 Opinion 

 Sunday Edition 
 
 Sports 

 BYU 
 Schedule / Stats / Standings Coach&apos;s Show Cougar Tracks My Cougar Stories CougarNation Polls/Rankings 
 U of U 
 Schedule / Stats / Standings Crimson Corner Polls/Rankings 
 USU 
 Schedule / Stats / Standings Polls/Rankings Blog 
 Jazz/NBA 
 Schedule / Stats / Standings Blog 
 RSL 
 Schedule / Stats / Standings Blog 
 Prep 
 Schedule / Scoreboard / Standings KSL Coaches Poll 
 NFL Golf Utah Stats/Scores 
 
 Shows 

 Studio 5 KSL Outdoors w/ Adam Eakle Sunday Edition Mormon Times Utah&apos;s Morning News Doug Wright Show The Browser Utah&apos;s Afternoon News Nightside Project KSL Movie Show KSL Outdoors KSL Greenhouse Show Matt Townsend Show KSL Travel Show 


 Classifieds 

 General Homes Cars Utah Jobs Help 


 Movies 

 Movie/Theater Listings 
 
 TV 

 Bios Schedule Contests More on the Web Studio 5 


 Radio 

 Listen LIVE Podcasts Lineup Bios Staff Blog Shows Features 
 Speaking on Biz Teacher Feature Metro Business Reports 
 Contests Events 
 
 Advertise with KSL 


Other Resources

 Contact Us / Phone Numbers Careers with KSL Careers with DDM Web Resources Charity Account Form 


Wireless

 ksl.com mobile text alerts 


Legal

 Terms of Use Privacy Statement DMCA Notice EEO Public File Report DTV Quarterly Activity Closed Captioning Assistance 


Sister Sites

 FM100 / Arrow 103.5 Deseret News Deseret Book 

 
 KSL&apos;s public inspection files, including the Children&apos;s Television Programming Reports and the DTV Quarterly Activity Station Report, are available for viewing during regular office hours at the KSL Broadcast House. ©2012 ksl.com | KSL Broadcasting Salt Lake City UT | Site hosted&amp;managed by Deseret Digital Media - a Deseret Media Company  v10
	</body>
</document>
