<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002359" url="http://www.barcop.com/bar_and_restaurant_software.php" time="2012-07-12-18:17" support="8" score="0.011252129407940122" bingtitle="BAR AND RESTAURANT SOFTWARE, Inventory Control Software, POS SOftware" webtitle="BAR SOFTWARE, Restaurant POS, Liquor Inventory Control System">
			<query id="000300" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="001218" bing-rank="118"/>
			<query id="000303" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="001216" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000394" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="001405" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="001398" bing-rank="129"/>
			<query id="001209" bing-rank="91"/>
	<description>The bar management software program allows you to enter ... Cop&apos;s merchant account provider specializes in credit card payment processing solutions for bars and restaurants.</description>
	<body>
		Bar software, restaurant POS and liquor inventory control system! 
 
 USA/Canada Toll Free: (888) 783-7038 | Email Us 
 
Office Hours: Monday - Friday | 9 AM - 5 PM CST
 

 
 Secure Order: Shopping Cart | Checkout Order 
 
 

 

 BAR COP: Inventory Software | POS Software | Liquor Scale | Keg Scale | Point Of Sale System | Surveillance System | Card Processing 

 
 Why spend $1000&apos;s on your bar and restaurant inventory control system? Bar Cop is simplifying the way bars, hotels, restaurants and nightclubs manage and control their liquor, wine, beer and food inventory. Our bar inventory.... Read More 
 
 
 
Our bar and restaurant inventory control software is affordable, feature packed and was designed to be simple to use right from the start, even with zero bar inventory control experience. Working in conjunction with our bar POS software and point of sale systems - our bar inventory control software will help raise your bottom line profits by controlling employee theft and liquor inventory abuse. Take back control of your employees and recover lost profit, by implementing our bar and restaurant inventory software and our POS systems in your establishment today. Our bar inventory control system will help you monitor and track your entire liquor, wine, beer and food inventory accurately and efficiently. This gives you a close insight to where your retail profits are really going. Using our restaurant inventory software will keep your employees honest and profits where they belong. Control your bar employees; do not let your employees pocket your retail sales. Our bar and restaurant inventory control software is the best solution for your bar, if you want to take your profit potential to a higher level. Bar Cop makes you more money!
 
 
 

 Bar And Restaurant Theft Prevention Solutions 

 
Bar Cop specializes in bar and restaurant POS systems, bar POS software, liquor inventory control software and surveillance systems. We carry a full line of bar management products to help you maximize your retail profits daily. Do not let profits slip through your hands and into your employees pockets, by not using POS software designed for the bar and restaurant industry by people in the industry. Utilizing our bar POS system, bar POS software and inventory control software will streamline your business and put more profits into your cash drawer. Running the proper point of sale system in your bar or restaurant is smart business and will return big savings to your bottom line.
 

 

 

 
 
 
 
 
 Bar Cop offers - bar and restaurant inventory control software, POS software with employee management features to help control... 
 
 VIEW - INVENTORY | POS 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Bar Cop offers - top quality weigh scale to track your bar and restaurant liquor, wine and food inventory accurately helping control... 
 
 VIEW - LIQUOR SCALE 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Bar Cop offers - a heavy duty and durable keg weighing scale in two sizes for small inventories in tight spaces&amp;large for heavy... 
 
 VIEW - BEER KEG SCALE 
 
 
 

 

 
 
 
 
 
 Bar Cop offers - top of the line bar and restaurant POS and point of sale system at an affordable price to help manage your sales and... 
 
 VIEW - POINT OF SALE 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Bar Cop offers - a 4 to 16 camera bar surveillance system to help protect your bar investment, your customers, your staff&amp;... 
 
 VIEW - SURVEILLANCE 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Bar Cop offers - the best bar and restaurant credit card processing with the lowest rates, NO contracts, NO application fees, NO... 
 
 VIEW - CARD PROCESSING 
 
 
 

 

 

 

 BAR COP: Inventory Software | POS Software | Liquor Scale | Keg Scale | Point Of Sale System | Surveillance System | Card Processing 

 
 Bar Cop is your leader in theft prevention products for bars, restaurants and hotels. We carry a full line of bar inventory control software, bar&amp;restaurant POS software, liquor and food scale, beer keg scale, point of sale system and security camera system. All of our bar and restaurant products are the highest quality and designed for your business. Ordering: Shopping Cart | Checkout Order 
 
 Store Policies | Return Policy | Lease Info 
 
 Bar Articles | Free Bar Management Forms 
 
 

 

 

 

 1998-2012 Bar Cop - Bar and Restaurant Inventory Control&amp;Software Solutions
	</body>
</document>
