<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002988" url="http://answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20080903215908AATUbLD" time="2012-07-12-19:04" support="2" score="0.00546114064334555" bingtitle="Average number of customers per day at fast food / fast casual ..." webtitle="Average number of customers per day at fast food / fast casual restaurant.? - Yahoo! Answers">
			<query id="000354" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="001515" bing-rank="21"/>
	<description>Best Answer: Not really...I live in a very small town now and the fast food restaurants and other restaurants vary so much, but one fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Make Y! My Homepage   
 Close this window For the most captivating daily read, Make Yahoo! your Homepage
 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Business&amp;Finance &gt; Small Business &gt; Resolved Question 
 Pete Member since: April 18, 2008 Total points: 479 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
Average number of customers per day at fast food / fast casual restaurant.?
 Hi, I am doing a research for a school project and I need to get a rough estimate of customers a fast food or a fast and casual restaurant in a large or large to medium city. The restaurant could either be in residential areas such as neighborhood centers or in business places. Can anybody from food industry give me any estates? 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 by aliciali... Member since: April 30, 2008 Total points: 31,472 (Level 7) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Voters
 Not really...I live in a very small town now and the fast food restaurants and other restaurants vary so much, but one fast food restaurant has tons of customers yet in a large city I used to live in...same kind of fast food restaurnat hardly had any customers and in general all restaurants varied to extremes. The best suggestion I can give is to actually call a variety of local restaurants to you and ask them.

Truthfully, I think you are just trying to get others to do your homework...you won&apos;t learn if you don&apos;t put the effort in yourself....I&apos;ve already told yo what to do and you should have takent initiative to do it yourself. 
 4 years ago Report Abuse 
 100% 1 Vote 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
 Other Answers (0)
 
No other answers.
 
Discover Questions in Small Business 

 Can I start an online business at the age of 13? How do you start a buisness? Where can I donate home made jewlery? What is the best bank for a small corporation and why? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Business&amp;Finance 
 Advertising&amp;Marketing Careers&amp;Employment Corporations Credit Insurance Investing Other - Business&amp;Finance Personal Finance Renting&amp;Real Estate Small Business Taxes 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Answers. Send Feedback 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! Inc. All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - About Our Ads - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines - Safety Tips
	</body>
</document>
