<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002726" url="http://drflynndmd.blogspot.com/" time="2012-07-12-18:47" support="1" score="0.0009725765630949406" bingtitle="Flynn-Flippin-Tastic" webtitle="Flynn-Flippin-Tastic">
			<query id="000569" bing-rank="241"/>
	<description>... Microsoft form, you had to give them a credit card ... But she processed my order without further incident ... Wow and this is just one sandwich at one fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Flynn-Flippin-Tastic
 
 Robert&apos;s thoughts, opinions and experiences. 
 
 July 7, 2012 
 
 Secret Beach 
 I know I do not post about my family or our families adventures, due to a promise I made with Sandra when I first said I wanted to blog-- &quot;That&apos;s my thing, that&apos;s what I blog about&quot;, she said. So I haven&apos;t, until today. So let me start off with an apology for not only blogging about the family, but preemptively posting about our Kauai trip before she gets to. Please do check out her blog in the following days for a much better blog than mine, as it will be I am certain--spectacular, as always.

I love to play in the waves and never in my entire life have I been able to play like we played this week. The sea was unreal. The waves literally massive and towering which crashed down with violent beauty.

While the younger kids played in safe near the shore, Christian and I ventured out into the larger waves and as fun as it was we took a beating, as wave after wave pummeled over us, spinning us in summersaults under the water. Of those waves we were able to dodge by diving under the wave before it took us out, we would only be greeted by the subsequent incoming swell that was trying to crest. You look up  at this two-story mountain of water in front of you and think to your self,“Oh crap!”  
 
 The following are a few of the photos Sandra and I took of us playing in the waves at a secluded beach on Kauai&apos;s north shore called Secret Beach (Note: that these waves were typical of what we swam in, however, when the weather turned sour and the rains came down the waves nearly doubled in size, but we couldn&apos;t take photos at risk for ruining our camera, but non the less these waves are impressive):

 
 

 
 
 


 
 


 
 
 
 
 
 
 






 Posted by DrFlynnDMD at 2:21 PM 1 comment: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Links to this post 
 May 27, 2012 
 
 The Gay Dilemma 
 Disclaimer: I know that same-sex-attraction is a hot political and religious topic and one that is becoming increasingly so. With diametrically opposed movements building support and momentum on either side the war cry is sounded, &apos;which side of history will you be on&apos;? This is not the intent nor conclusion of this post. I am not writing today with the intent to prove either side right or wrong as pertaining to same-sex-attraction or their desire for equal marriage rights. This post, however, is a meager attempt to elaborate a perplexity of mine as to the seemingly disproportionate amount of emphasis and blame which is focused on those who are gay as to the perceived denigration of marriage and rampant immorality of society (as opposed to those who are not gay, but whose actions, I believe, actually cause far more reaching social and moral harm). 



Over the past several decades, the gay rights movement has moved from the hidden outskirts of acceptable society to the center of American politics. I believe the real momentum that sparked it&apos;s evolution occurred fifteen years ago when Ellen DeGeneres publicly came out in 1997. She subsequently used her hit show &apos;Ellen&apos; to further propogate gay-right issues and it&apos;s acceptance. While her show soon tanked and was cancelled, the seed was planted and a media metamorphisis was initiated. I remember at first, television shows displayed large warning signs that &apos;inappropriate and possible offensive adult material&apos; was included in it&apos;s episode, but as society acclimated they stopped displaying warnings. Eventually they introduced the first gay kiss on TV. The conservative mainstream went berserk and protests were held with fists in the air and anti-gay signs and slogans were everywhere. Soon the fervor dissipated and homosexuals in our living room became common place as one show after another introduced gay characters into their popular television series. Today there is hardly a show on TV that doesn&apos;t have some connection to a gay character or couple. The media paints an alluring picture of acceptance. They endear us with charming characters with witty lines and compassionate hearts free from social and moral consequences. This pervasive movement into our lives through social media has changed our social perception and acceptance of gay individuals. Just a few weeks ago, the President of the United States publicly declared that he is supports gay marriage and that our nation should be more accepting of the gay lifestyle, which would have been unheard of just years before.
 
 In consequence to this social evolution, we have been hearing a lot of hype and media chatter about the &apos;War on Marriage&apos; or more specifically the &apos;War on Traditional Marriage&apos;. I understand the offense and threat of redefining the definition of marriage and it&apos;s moral implications as acceptable normalcy into our society, but in my opinion the real war on marriage has been raging for much longer and it&apos;s current poster-child, the inclusion of gay couples into marriage, is but a small diversion from the actual evil behind the fight. I think the real war on marriage is found in the mass frequency and acceptance of premarital heterosexual immorality and flagrant extramarital ease in which spouses so easily break their sacred marriage covenants by embracing sexual interactions outside of their marriage whether through pornography, filthy literature, perversions, inappropriate relationships or actual physical infidelity (Adultery). Never before in history are adulterers and fornicators more accepted than they are today. It is as if immorality has become so common place that society cannot even imagine a life with standards and virtue. Honor, faithfulness, sacrifice, delayed gratification and integrity can likewise be said to be lost in marriage expectations. As I see it, the morals of our society at large can be compared to the continuous melting of a hot wax candle till there is nothing left but a lone moral wick standing in a puddle of molten promiscuous wax!  
 With the horrendous onslaught of moral decrepitude in this world, what makes homosexuality a worse sin than all other sexual aberrations? In my view there is nothing more evil, divisive and destructive than adultery. Not only are they engaging in sexual acts outside of wedlock (which by Christian definition is morally reprehensible), but they are also breaking their marriage covenants, shattering their family and destroying the intimate trust of their loved ones. This selfish act of unbridled lust can permanently devastate and fracture an entire family with unmeasureable harm. Nothing that two gays can do to each other can ever result in the far reaching outbreak of chaos and pain that adultery can cause. Yet, adulterers can live respectable lives in our society. They are seldom persecuted or discriminated against. In fact, in some situations they are even praised for their conquests! On a similar note, fornication whether casually or as a result of a deepened relationship account for nearly 60% of all babies born (with 89% of those babies conceived by 15-19 year old girls)!!! Where is the social outcry for all of this? Yes, there is some, but nothing on the scale of the outcry about gay marriage in my opinion. Certainly if families are falling apart because of the lack of faithfulness within their &apos;traditional&apos; marriages and out-of-wedlock pregnancies are leading to more than half of all children being born, the result is a vast multitude of children left to grow up without the support and stability of a &apos;traditional family&apos; and thus the world is forced to carry the inevitable weight of these social burdens and their ever increasing consequences! Are these not tremendous casualties of war--the real war on marriage?   
 So I am left to wonder why are the gays, those whose sexual actions account for the least amount of real harm or consequences to society, left taking the brunt of the moral burden? Are the gays just a convenient scapegoat to distract the world from the real moral decay that pervades our society or are they simply the ominous yellow canary indicating how close we are as a society from becoming completely morally bankrupt? 

The gays are asking for equal rights and social legitimacy. Social conservatives respond citing further moral degradation. I therefore ask, Will gay marriage somehow lessen the sacredness of traditional marriage? Personally, I do not think so. Let me clarify, either it may be seen as a continuation of the erosion of social morals that already make a mockery of the sanctity of marriage or it can be seen as I would see it: That no other person&apos;s marriage or relationship effects who I am or what I have. The success, sacredness and happiness of my relationship and marriage is not based on a comparison of others, nor is it based on another&apos;s perceptions and beliefs or lack thereof. I have made covenants between my wife and God and no one else matters.  I see it similar to baptism. The validity and sacredness of my baptism is not diminished because others of different faiths or beliefs also baptize. Their beliefs and baptisms do not lessen my baptism, neither do other&apos;s marriages of whatever level of sacredness lessen my marriage.

Secondly, will the inclusion of gay marriage in society be the tipping point that will lead to rampant immoral promiscuity as so many conservatives fear? Hard to say. I feel that society has already plummeted off a proverbial moral cliff decades ago and has been accelerating towards Hell with ever increasing incident by heterosexual misconduct already, although I would imagine that any accelerant would increase it&apos;s breadth and pace.

There is a war on traditional marriage, but I do not feel it is all about the gays. While I myself am not threatened by gay marriage and I feel great empathy for those who struggle with same-sex-attraction, I do feel that it&apos;s inevitable inclusion to normalcy in society is a manifestation of societies general descent of traditional values and morals.  This is the real glossed-over issue--the mainstream loss of morality . As is often said, we are free to choose, but not to choose our consequences. The world is on a slippery slope of immorality from so many fronts and it&apos;s consequences are at our door. 

In an associated note:
The LDS church has created a wonderful pamphlet entitled,&quot; God loveth his children &quot; (2007) which eloquently elaborates the LDS church&apos;s position toward same-sex-attraction. It is well written and expresses a greater understanding, sympathy and empathy for those who struggle with this than is often portrayed across the pulpit. See link below: 
 http://www.lds.org/manual/god-loveth-his-children/god-loveth-his-children?lang=eng 

 
 Posted by DrFlynnDMD at 1:53 PM 2 comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Links to this post 
 April 1, 2012 
 
 Relative Perspective 
 
 Reality is based on one&apos;s perspective, surroundings and experiences. This reality however, is not necessarily the reality or perspectives of others who enjoy different perspectives due to their differing surroundings and experiences. Einstein illuminated the world with the introduction of the Theory of Special Relativity which in simplicity states that it is impossible to determine whether or not you are moving unless you can look at another object. Think about that. If you were in the middle of outer space far from any other objects, how would you know whether or not you were moving? All movement is relative to other objects. For example, right now relative to your computer you are not moving at all, but relative to the distant quasars you are moving at nearly the speed of light. Relative to the Earth, most meteorites move at about 25,000 miles an hour (40,233 km), but if you were standing on a meteorite looking at another meteorite going in the same direction as you and at the same speed, it would not appear to move at all. Imagine a girl riding due west in a train traveling 60mph while a boy stands on the ground watching the train go by. Each feels like they are motionless until they compare themselves to their surroundings. Which one is moving the boy or the girl? Is the train moving 60mph or is the train standing still while the ground with the boy actually moving? Reason exclaims, &quot;it&apos;s the train that is moving&quot;. However, perspective is everything, what neither can see from their point of perspective is that the earth itself is rotating in it&apos;s orbit at 1070mph and the fact that the train is traveling west against the direction of the earth&apos;s rotation the girl is actually slowing the speed she is traveling in space/time slowing her speed to 1010mph, 60mph slower than the boy who is standing still! Wow-that&apos;ll blow your mind. In that same example, if that same girl on the train drops a ball to her the ball travels straight down with gravity hitting the floor directly beneath her, while the boy not on the train does not see the ball fall in a straight line but in an arc moving in direction of the train so that in the time the girl lets go of the ball the ball continues to travel east at the speed of the train. So which is truth: does the ball fall straight or does the ball fall in an arc? They are both true, a different reality for each. What does all this physics mean in our lives?  That our life and everything that we think is reality is relative.  For example: We read the story of Lehi who is instructed of God to get the brass plates. His sons try to get them but are rejected. Then while guided by the spirit Nephi comes across Laban (who owns the plates) passed out drunk in the street. The scriptures proceed to walk us through Nephi&apos;s perspective on the events that followed. Nephi is ultimately congratulated for his righteousness. However, from a different point of view, whose &apos;reality&apos; is different from Nephi, say a bystander watching the SAME events could presume Nephi as a murderer for killing Laban, a thief for stealing his clothes and sword, a liar for impersonating him and deceiving his servant Zoram all to selfishly and illegally acquire another person&apos;s family heirloom (the brass plates). So which reality is correct? We only think that Nephi was righteous because we have the background and God&apos;s perspective of his actions. Without this insight what would you really think about what he did? If you saw someone else do the same things that Nephi did (kill a person, take his things, assume his identity, lie and steal from his home and then make any witnesses vow an oath of loyalty and force them to leave with them forever) would you not call the police? If caught, would you not testify at his trial against him? And, would you not esteem yourself as being more righteous than that murderer, liar and thief? Perspective is everything. But whose perspective is correct? Perspective defines who we think we are and who we THINK others are. The problem is that our perspective of others is not THEIR perspective of themselves. Their realities are different than our realities. Their perspectives are not our perspectives. How can we then think to judge another? Or to push and insist that our perspective and reality is more correct than another&apos;s? Perspective is what can make a person a saint or a villain, a traitor or revolutionist, a visionary or a lunatic.  Perspective is what makes a republican a republican, a democrat a democrat.   Perspective is what lends one to dispense mercy and another to dispense justice. Perspective is what helps one sleep soundly at night while another dealing with the same trial has a sleepless night. So which perception is right? Like the ball that drops from the train--they may all be right within the confines of their own reality--which reality may be vastly different than our own. There is a difference between different and sin. Sometimes in life we confuse the two. Perspectives often changes over time as one&apos;s reality changes through time. Our basis of judging reality alters as deeper understanding of the varying angles of perspective illuminate our vision enabling a clearer or broader view of reality opens up to us. Villains are rewritten as saints, traitors are called founding fathers, and lunatics are herald as visionary geniuses. Einstein has taught us that we can only judge ourselves by comparing ourselves to others, but how can we do this correctly when we do not have all the facts and perspectives to judge correctly? Are we good? Are we successful? Are we happy? Are we righteous? Each can be answered yes or no to varying degrees as we compare ourselves to others. From one moment to another we can feel good about ourselves, esteeming ourselves to be successful, happy and righteous when compared to one person and then in a following instant feel like we are a worthless, wretched and failed soul as compared to somebody that we perceive to be superior to ourselves. Nothing has changed, just our perception of our reality. What we do not see is God&apos;s reality, God&apos;s perspective and evaluation of us. Through this life we have but our own perspectives, experiences and perceived reality. We must be humble enough to realize that we do not know everything. We do not always know the perspective and reality of others and how different they may be from our own. Paul once illuminated, &quot;For now we see through a glass, darkly ; but then face to face: now I know in part ; but then shall I know even as also I am known (1 Corinthians 13:12).  The day will come that we will know all truth, all perspectives, all realities. But that day is not today. How do we stand today? Do we offer mercy and consideration or do we rashly deliver judgement and justice? We all come from different backgrounds, experiences, and expectations. We all have different perspectives and realities.  God works through each of us to help us achieve our best selves . He molds and prepares us today to be ready for the trials of tomorrow. We may have trials and difficulties in our lives that others are not required to suffer. We also have blessings that others may not receive.  I believe that our lives fit our exact eternal needs, whether to further perfect our own souls or the souls of those around us. That is why it is so damaging to judge others or to envy their lives, accomplishments or blessings.  We all live in the reality of our own perspective that may drastically differ from the reality and perspective of others.  Comparing ourselves to others only skews the divinity of our own life&apos;s path .  How futile are we as limited humans to cast judgment on ourselves or others. Only God can fairly judge our life, the intentions of our actions, and the correctness of our course. While we are free to evaluate the correctness of our own lives and correct our own course through the inspiration of the holy ghost, we are entirely unprepared to evaluate and judge the life of another. Until the day comes that all darkness is removed and we are allowed to be seen as we are seen and see others as they are seen by God let us attempt to be kinder, more forgiving, more openminded and accepting. May we see the beauty that others can offer us and the world and not just see our own preconcieved assumptions of prejudicial short comings and failures.   
 
 
   “Don’t judge me because I sin differently than you.”    (President Uchtdorf, CR, April 1, 2012). 
 
 Posted by DrFlynnDMD at 4:24 PM 3 comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Links to this post 
 January 1, 2012 
 
 Resolution 
 
 It&apos;s that time again when the world makes shallow and unrealistic goals to improve themselves in the new year. Last night we stayed up late with our relatives playing games, making noise and shooting off fireworks welcoming in 2012. I said to myself--This is going to be a great year! It may even be our last? There is a lot of hullabaloo claiming the Mayan&apos;s predicted that the world would end on December 21, 2012. The reality is that a major celestial cycle (a multi-hundred year planetary rotation cycle) ends on the Mayan&apos;s calendar on that date. What the ruckus fails to mention is that on December 22, 2012 the calendar starts a new cycle. Not quite the cacophony of doom! 
 
 
 Well wether the world ends or not this year, we are still culturally obligated to make new year&apos;s resolutions. Year after year I write down two or three goals and mostly complete some of the them. Last years resolutions were to--Run a half marathon, See my Chiropractor and get a Massage (due to work related strain) every month, and to Paint my dental office. The results: I never ran even once-especially a half marathon. I saw the chiropractor about 8 of 12 times and had about 3 massages. However, instead of just painting my office, I completely remodeled it--new flooring, resurfaced the cabinets, new counter tops, everything repainted, I blew up huge beautiful photos that Sandra took for wall decorations, expanded the front desk, updated the electrical, added additional computer hardware and modernized my recall software which now sends emails and text messages to my patients. Actually, it is only mostly done, it won&apos;t be completely finished till late March, but it&apos;s a heck of a lot better than just &apos;repainting&apos; as my resolution asked for. So in the end I completely and embarrassingly failed one goal, partially and haphazardly completed another and totally annihilated the last.  
 
 
 There is two ways to look at this. The first I&apos;d like to call &apos;My Dad&apos;s Method of Success&apos;, based on a conversation Sandra and I had with him after having Hunter (our third of five children). My dad (who had 9 children) said, &quot;The more kids you have the greater the chance that one of them will turn out!&quot; So in light of this, one could argue--the more goals one makes for yourself, the greater the odds are that you might actually accomplish at least one of them. The second is the simple, &apos;Less is More&apos; principle that by focusing on just one clearly defined goal you won&apos;t be overwhelmed and distracted with too many areas of improvements thus facilitating yourself to dedicate enough time and attention to that resolution that you accomplish it. 
 This year I am going with the latter in a sink or swim mentality. Acknowledging the reality that I will probably never consistently run, bike or endure any extended duration exercise, but wanting to improve my overall health, I have decided to DAILY do 100 push-ups, 100 sit-ups and 10 pull ups. 2012 is the year of the core! If the world does ends, I want to go out with a six pack! 
 
 
 So I went downstairs this morning, stretched and assumed the position. 15 push-ups later I was in a panting heap on the floor. I then slid my feet under the couch and begin curling upwards, 13 sit-ups later I was spent, out of breath, collapsed on the floor. Several intermissions later and only in sporadic spurts I was able to fight my way through 25 push-up&amp;sit-up and 3 (non-consecutive) pull-ups. I decided to call that day one. I knew if I pushed myself any harder I wouldn&apos;t be able to move let alone repeat this for the rest of the week, so I&apos;m going to ease into this resolution. I haven&apos;t already failed, I like to think of it as I am just gracefully achieving! It will come in time, and I will be working towards it every day. 
 
 
 Even more embarrassing than my complete lack of physical strength and stamina was having my son Hunter walk into the room and exclaiming, as he sees me laying in a heap panting for my life, &quot;What&apos;s going on here!&quot;? Not my most proud father-n-son moment. 
 
 
 So what will you resolve to resolute? 
 
 
 
 Posted by DrFlynnDMD at 9:55 AM 5 comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Links to this post 
 November 11, 2011 
 
 The exceptionally blessed 1% 
 A few weeks ago a member of our ward who has a PhD in statistics gave a very interesting talk about how very very very very very…did I mention VERY blessed we all are. He continued to pummel how our privileged lives are the exception not the normal to how the rest of the world lives. The enjoyment of electricity, access to food and clean water, air conditioning, television, and refrigerators. Our world boasts standards of comparative luxury surrounded in freedom and wrapped in safety. He referred to us as the exceptionally blessed 1%. He said, the world population today is over 7 billion. Image a single filed line of 7 billion people. How big is that line? If this line was at the equator and everyone stood shoulder to shoulder that line would wrap around the earth 106 times! If you stacked each other on top of each other&apos;s shoulders their would be enough people to reach and touch the moon 26 times! That&apos;s a long line. Well when you look back at this enormous line, you should realize that 99% of that line, at least 6,300,000,000 people, are standing behind you in that line. In other words you are very blessed.

Now expand that further. How many have freedom of religion? How many have heard of Jesus Christ? How many have heard of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints? How many are members? Approximately 14 million or .002% of the world. How many are active LDS (world-wide)? Realistically the estimates are only around 35% or 4.9 million or .0007% of the world! When it comes to the blessings of the restored gospel of Jesus Christ at least 6,995,100,000 people are standing behind you in line.

Why do I make this point? To boast our great fortune for being LDS? Our clearly obvious magnificent pre-earthly performances? Hardly. No, but rather how we waste the opportunities and possibilities of these blessings. How we live beneath our potentials and God&apos;s expectations of us. One of my greatest pet-peeves are LDS members who pontificate how chosen and clearly spiritually superior we are over the rest of the world solely on the fact that we are members of the church. They speak as if salvation comes from membership alone. That exaltation arrives if we just wait long enough as members. If you were to describe the type of being that God is (or that Jesus is to make it more comprehensible), what type of being would you describe? Would you be describing the members of your ward? If so how many really would you be describing? Would you be describing yourself? To be fair--no one is already like God, or they wouldn&apos;t be here. What I am trying to say is how many of us are truly trying to be like God? The fact remains, to be with God, one must become like God.

How then are we doing here in Utah? The statistics range from 60-70% of the state are members of the church, if 50% of those members are active that would be approximately 1 million of the nearly 3 million people who live in Utah are considered active LDS. With this comparatively extraordinary saturation of active LDS members scattered throughout the state (1 in 3 people) we should be living in a utopian society, enjoying the law of consecration, bathing is the waterfalls of modern revelation and playing dodgeball with arc angels! Yet in stead we find that Utah boasts the award for the highest number of subscriptions to pornography websites, one of the highest occurrence of underage drinking, gambling and prescription pill addictions and abuse. Continually, year after year, Utah also reports some of the nations highest bankruptcy rates, as well as the percentage of population suffering from depression and anxiety. Utah was also recently touted as one of the highest per capita use of plastic surgery in the nation. Basically, what Utah is telling the world is not that were Mormons, but that we are stressed out, insecure, envious, stiflingly horny, and a rebellious people!

The world is a messed up place. Why isn&apos;t it better here than it is? I think it is because somewhere along the way we lost perspective of how truly blessed we really are. Not just as LDS members, but as humans on this planet. We got spoiled. We grew spiritually weak, and pleasure fat. We live unrealistic lives and care too deeply how others perceive us. Our lives are too full of stuff and things that we do not need, yet we work tirelessly to obtain. We lost sight of what really is important and replaced it with things that don&apos;t last--things that are not even real: Cars, homes, beauty, pleasure, trips, comparisons, achievements, degrees, financial statements, etc. What we&apos;ve lost along the way real family relationships, true friends, integrity, honesty, patience, enjoyment of small&amp;simple things, time, opportunities, conversations, innocence, love, real priesthood authority, and unshakable testimonies.

We need to slow down. Get back in tune with God. Learn to feel the Holy Ghost again. Listen to what he is saying and then have the courage to do what he says. We need to cast off the artificial burdens we&apos;ve placed on ourselves and stop worrying what everyone else thinks (remember they are just as messed up, insecure, and lonely as we are). We need to get back to the basics. I do not believe that this life is a &apos;test&apos;, I believe that we are here to learn, not be graded (yes in the end, but not along the way). We are blessed beyond belief -- why? who knows? But we have been nonetheless. It is then left for us to act proportionally to the blessings we&apos;ve received. We need to act well our part.

Ask yourself are all your daily frantic doings and priorities making you more like God or more like Utahns? 


 Posted by DrFlynnDMD at 11:02 PM 4 comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Links to this post 
 September 11, 2011 
 
 The Three Travelers 
 
During scout camp the camp director had shared a brief folk tale that I really liked. So I decided to expand the simple story into a more developed and meaningful story, to which I entitled,

 &quot; The Three Travelers &quot;  
 There once were three travelers who were on a long journey. One night while sitting around the campfire an angel appeared in the smoke of the fire and said unto the three men, &quot;you have journeyed long and hard and now you will be rewarded with riches and wealth the likes of which you have never seen&quot;. Hearing this the men declared, &quot;how is this done?&quot;. The angel replied, &quot;pointing to a spot far on the horizon, tomorrow when you awake ride to that spot before the sun sets and there you will enjoy your reward, however, along the way as you ride replace the earthly contents of your satchels on your horses with pebbles and stones&quot;. With that the angel disappeared and the three men marveled.

The next morning the three men eagerly awoke and prepared their horses. The first, in his zeal to gain his reward disregarded the angel&apos;s requirement to gather pebbles and stones along the way, but left his campsite uncleaned and sped away without stopping toward the promised location. Nearing the end of his journey the first traveler began to remember the admonitions of the angel and fearing he might not get his reward stopped just before arriving stopped and gathered a small handful of pebbles and one rock and placed them in his satchel. A few moments later in a feeling of triumph for being the first to arrive, supposing he had gained an advantage, began searching for his reward.

The second, also awoke in haste and made ready his horse and saddle and galloped west towards his anticipated reward. Unlike the first rider, he did remember and took heed of the Angel&apos;s request, and occasionally stopped along the way to gather pebbles and stones, but not wanting to part with the majority of his valuable earthly belongings was only able to fit a few handfuls of pebbles and three or four stones into his satchel.

The third, arose early with the rest, but unlike the other two took time to savor the morning, cleaned up the campsite, readied his horse, and watched the sunrise. As he travelled slowly, but steadily towards the horizon he gave full heed to the Angel request. Knowing he had more than required sunlight to arrive at his destination, he spent his time looking and picking up unique rocks and interesting pebbles of all sizes and shapes until he had eventually removed all of his personal belongings and replaced them with stones and pebbles. Burdened under the weight of these rocks the third rider finally arrived at the promised location just as the sun was beginning to set.

Upon arriving he saw the first two riders in a panicked state, all covered in dirt and sweat as they were frantically still searching for the treasure before the sun set. We have looked everywhere they exclaimed, turned over every rock, searched in every hole and cave, but nothing--no treasure! With that the sun had set.

Disappointed, the three travelers made a fire and sat in silence reflecting on the day&apos;s events. While gazing into the flickering flames suddenly again the angel appeared in the smoke of the fire. The angel spoke, &quot;congratulations, your journey is through, now take joy in the rewards of your journey&quot;. The first man replied, &quot;what rewards? I was the first to arrive and have spent the majority of the day searching this area and have found no treasures!&quot; The second then exclaimed, &quot;I was the second to arrive and having looked to the point of exhaustion and madness have not found the riches you promised--the likes of which we have never seen!&quot;. The third traveler humbly, replied, &quot;I didn&apos;t have time to search for treasures, I had spent my time gathering pebbles and stones along the way that upon my arrival the sun had set and my journey was over&quot;. To this the Angel, replied, &quot;Treasures are enjoyed, not found, at a journey&apos;s end, but collected along the way. Did I not instruct you to gather pebbles and stones along the way? Go and take joy in the treasures you&apos;ve gathered&quot;. The angel then disappeared.

The three travelers then went to their satchels to find the pebbles and stones they had gathered and to their astonishment the pebbles had turned into precious gems--diamonds, sapphires, emeralds and rubies and the rocks had turned into pure gold.

The first rider pulled out his one rock of gold and small handful of precious gems was now more wealthy than anyone in the town in which he lived. While overjoyed with his new found riches, he knew that in his haste to finish the journey, he had missed priceless opportunities along the way.

The second rider pulled out four large gold rocks and a few handfuls of precious gems and was immediately the wealthiest person in the region in which he lived. While overwhelmed with his new found fortune, he knew that if he would have been willing to have parted with his now comparably worthless earthly belongings he could have had unfathomable wealth.

The third rider discovered his satchels were filled to overflowing with gold and gems, he was now the richest person in the whole world. Free of regret his joy was full.

Let the lesson of the three travelers be a warning in our lives that we need to slow down and enjoy our journey, seeking out new and old friends in which to share experiences and our abundance. In so doing we will find rest and joy at the end of our lives savoring the priceless memories and relationships we have gathered along the way.

-- Robert M. Flynn
 Posted by DrFlynnDMD at 9:16 PM 3 comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Links to this post 
 August 28, 2011 
 
 Microsoft Blows! 
 My son Hunter, who is obsessed with playing Halo on the xbox, wanted to be able to play Halo online through a feature in the xbox called xbox live. I was dubious at first letting my ten year old into the online world, but I soon found out that most of our neighbors had xbox live and felt it was safe, so we said yes to the free trial to check it out.

I have to admit the technology was really cool. Hunter could enter this vast connected world of friends and kids playing halo. Instead of playing against predictable computer generated opponents by yourself, you could play against really thinking similarly obsessed kids. This is definately a step up from Pacman and Asteroids that I played when I was ten.

When the free month was up for all practical purposes so was Hunter&apos;s &apos;purpose&apos; in life. It was the begining of summer time and he did a lot of moping and complaining--&quot;there&apos;s nothing to do, it&apos;s to hot to play outside, none of my friends can play, no I don&apos;t want to read a book or play with my sister, and you won&apos;t let me watch any more TV, please, please, please, let me get xbox live again&quot;!!!! After enough tears and promises Sandra and I agreed to sign Hunter up. [And before you think that we are terrible parents who let our kids waste away their lives playing computer games--He only is allowed to play for an hour or two every other day and only after his chores and summer homework are done].

In typical Microsoft form, you had to give them a credit card number with the only option of automatic renewal. It was my responsibility to remember the renewal date and proactively cancel it before that date if I didn&apos;t want it to renew for another year. If I forget I will automatically renew even if I didn&apos;t want to. Frustrating, but I had no choice. It took forever to register because I had to enter everything on a game controller through the xbox. Scrolling through the entire alphabet, number pad and symbol pages picking one character at a time like old school texting. Eventually he was in and life was great again. His summer finally had meaning!

Two months had gone by and all was well. Hunter could play but only for short spells and after his daily chores and study time. Then, yesterday morning I received an email stating that $19.95 was charged to my credit card for purchases made on xbox live. &quot;This must be an error&quot;, I thought, &quot;there is no way that Hunter could know my password to have purchased anything&quot;. At the time I received this he was away at a friend&apos;s birthday party so I couldn&apos;t ask him about it. So I contacted xbox live support.

I was greeted by Josh who was ever so friendly and empathetic. &quot;I can certainly understand your frustration&quot; he said, and &quot;I&apos;ve helped a lot of people with similar complaints, let&apos;s see what I can do to help resolve your concerns&quot;. After about going through 7 layers of security including identifying my name, address, phone number, xbox serial number, last 4 digits of my credit card on file, my User name, and answers to my secret questions that I filled out when registering, Josh was finally able to get access into my account.

We discovered the purchase was for Microsoft Points. These points were like tokens used at Chucky Cheese that could be spent at will at the various money traps in xbox live. Apparently, Hunter was able to purchase these Microsoft points and then spent all of them on different outfits and accessories for his avatar figure on xbox. So he spent $20 on digital clothes to dress a cartoon!!! Josh just oozing with empathy apologized, but regrettably he was helpless in refunding the money because it was already spent.

I then said, how is it possible that xbox allows 10 yr old boys to have access to spend money on their parent&apos;s credit card? Is there no security, no pop up for a password or way to validate that the owner of the credit card is authorizing the purchase? It took me twenty minutes of security validation to talk to a representative at xbox live, yet my son and apparently anyone who has access to our xbox can freely spend all the money on my credit card!? Again, he excreted his obviously well trained, &quot;I can certainly see how that would be frustrating, let me transfer you to a technical support specialist to adjust your settings on your xbox and see if they can help you prevent this from happening again&quot;.

I was put on hold for nearly ten minutes and was transferred to Tristian who quickly apologized, but he specialized in another area of security and could not help me, but that he would transfer me to another specialist who would be able to help me. Another five of six minutes later Joan connected and apologized for the wait. She explained that parental controls are not set as a default and needed to be set by the user. She then walked me through the labyrinth of screens to where the settings were supposed to be. &quot;Huh&quot;, she exclaimed, when the setting option was not there. Not only was it not set as a default to protect my credit card from frivolous non-authorized purchases, apparently my xbox was missing the setting all together!

She then exclaimed--&quot;there is no way to block access to purchases on your xbox. The only way to prevent future unwanted purchases is to remove the credit card, which would subsequently cancel Hunter&apos;s xbox live account&quot;. Fortunately for Hunter there was a way around that, by way of gift cards. Apparently you can buy short term 1-3 month xbox live membership time. All you have to do is redeem the code 16 digit number on the gift card to extend your membership. Joan sent me 4 sixteen digit codes that I had to go into the xbox and once again with a control pad old school painstakingly text them in. Eventually, after over an hour trying to figure out and correct this mess the xbox was finally safe and Hunter could keep his precious xbox live, however, he will be doing so major chores to pay us back!

I just can&apos;t believe how purposefully dishonest and predatory Microsoft is! How many millions they must earn everyday by enticing and allowing children to purchase electronic content at their whim on their parent credit cards with no security or restrictions of any kind. How is that even legal? Shame on Microsoft. Posted by DrFlynnDMD at 9:53 AM 2 comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Links to this post Labels: Halo , Microsoft , Xbox live 
 July 31, 2011 
 
 Kick the Can 
 Walls up on every side--such is the case with Washington yet once again.  As a country we have moved decisively into political party division. It no longer is about the issues or the people or the inevitability that we are about to fall off a cliff, it&apos;s about which party wins. 

I heard a recent interview on Fox News where a prominent Republican boldly stated that he hoped things would not go smoothly in the debt crisis debates so as to assure that Obama would not be able to be elected to a second term. He then went further to say he is and will do everything in his power to see that that happens! How absurd! How myopic and partisan, that he would risk plunging our economy into further travail and free fall just so he could point blame and destroy the other party. &quot;Yeah, you messed up and now the world is broken, ha ha we were right&quot;. Only to then realize, &quot;oh the world is broken and now it&apos;s too late to fix the damage!&quot; 

I believe Washington is corrupt on both sides of the aisles. Both hold much blame. Both are to blame for where we stand as a nation today. The debt crisis of today was not created by only one party. Yes we can blame Obama for the latest hemorrhaging of new debt, but every president before him spent and spent. Each acted like a teenager with a credit card, some more responsibly that the others, but ultimately, everyone spent more than they had to pay it back. Each raised the debt ceiling multiple times, each expanded programs and agencies and made promises that can&apos;t be paid for. I get sick and tired of the one-sided bantering and attacks. Each party talks as if they were innocent and all the ills of society are the other parties fault. Yet when the Republicans had full control of Washington they didn&apos;t use their power and influence to fix the problems, they too kicked the can down the road just as the democrats are trying to do on their watch. The difference is we are getting near the end of the road where an enormous economic cliff is looming. 

How much longer can we keep kicking the can? 

This is the problem: When news reports, emails or blogs voice extreme opinions and are clearly filled with biased partisanship comments immediately all credibility and debate is lost as rational discussion is inherently impossible. Throwing out vicious accusation and narrow minded comments will automatically cause a reactionary wall blocking communication and progress. This happens on both sides. No one is listening to each other, no one is willing to truly see the other&apos;s opinion and compromising is futile. Whatever the debate, it is not about the issue, it is about what party side your fighting for. You want your side to win, regardless.

The path we are on as a country looks grim and I am pointing to both sides.  I feel that Obama has made a bigger mess of our country, although it wasn&apos;t in very good shape when he inherited it. I believe that Washington needs to come together and invoke real change. But I don&apos;t expect to see any. While I think the tea party folks are a bit extremist, they are the only ones really serious about change. Everyone else is just trying to come up with new ways to kick the can down the road a little farther but make it look like the didn&apos;t.

Please click on the link below -- it&apos;s a visual representation of our nation&apos;s debt and worse what is coming. It is mind blowing!                 
                                      http://usdebt.kleptocracy.us/ 

Please leave a comment--Thanks for listening Posted by DrFlynnDMD at 11:01 AM 6 comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Links to this post 
 July 14, 2011 
 
 Our future with an extra side of bacon 
 Last night on The Daily Show with Jon Stewart they ran a bit on the rampant pandemic of obesity in America. With every state in the country reporting that a minimum of 20% of their residents were obese, except Colorado who reported 19.8%, thats 1 out of every 5 people. Worse in some southern states they averaged over 30%, thats 1 out of every 3 people who are not just overweight but medically lopping over into the aisle OBESITY!!!.
	</body>
</document>
