<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002407" url="http://www.wholesale.com.au/" time="2012-07-12-18:20" support="31" score="0.10784432007720102" bingtitle="Wholesale Direct – Restaurant Supplies – coffee cups, napkins ..." webtitle="Wholesale Direct – Restaurant Supplies – coffee cups, napkins, thermal rolls, toilet paper, garbage bags">
			<query id="000392" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000601" bing-rank="8"/>
			<query id="000243" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="001129" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000126" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="000151" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="001371" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000149" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="001152" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000557" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000610" bing-rank="20"/>
			<query id="001156" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000399" bing-rank="5"/>
			<query id="000547" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000400" bing-rank="29"/>
			<query id="000154" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="001145" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="001490" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="000617" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000142" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000054" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000150" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="000559" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="001528" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000622" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000554" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="001500" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000900" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000383" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000152" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000133" bing-rank="3"/>
	<description>A cafe and restaurant supplier of a range of hospitality products including cutlery, plastic containers, napkins, coffee cups, toilet paper and garbage bags.</description>
	<body>
		Shopping Cart (0 items) Check Out Home Fast Shop Register Login 0 item(s) 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Products How To Order Contact Us FAQs About Us 
 1300 586 246 Bags Catering Supplies Coffee Beans Cold Cups Drinking Straws Docket Books Food Wraps Garbage Bags Gloves Napkins Paper Coffee Cups Paper Tablecloths and Doyleys Plastic Containers Plastic Cutlery Portion Cups Register Rolls Takeaway Food Packaging Washroom and Cleaning 
Clients&amp;Corporate Partners
 

 

 
 8oz Black Paper Coffee Cups, 500/ctn Code CRW8BLK (GST excl.) 500 $52.75 Black Lid to suit 8oz Paper Coffee Cups, 1000/ctn Code CSL8BLK (GST excl.) 1000 $34.95 &quot;MIO Espresso&quot; Coffee Beans, 5kg Code CME (GST excl.) 1 $135.00 Coffee Cup Carry Trays - 100/ctn Code CT4 (GST excl.) 100 $18.95 1-Ply Luncheon Napkins, 3000/ctn Code NL1P (GST excl.) 3000 $20.95 Plastic Teaspoons, 1000/ctn Code CUTTSPNW (GST excl.) 1000 $8.95 
 
 ONLINE 
 Need help ? MAIL ORDER 
 Download form CALL US 
 1300 586 _ 246 
 Last Name Last Name is required Email Address Email Address is required Email Address is invalid We do not give out your
information. See our
 Privacy Policy for details 
 Low Shipping
Rates * available to capital city metro areas on the east coast,&amp;major town centres. Click here for more details. 
 
 
Wholesale
Direct
Restaurant
Supplies
 
We supply a large range of food service, packaging&amp;washroom products to restaurants, cafes, hotels, take away shops, fast food outlets, clubs&amp;pubs. Our brands are well recognised in the industry,&amp;include Solo cups, Merino napkins&amp;much more.

 Our success is based on a simple philosophy: providing wholesale prices direct to restaurants. This means that restaurants&amp;cafes of all sizes have access to prices that were once only available to large restaurant chains&amp;franchises. 
 
As a result, restaurants can enjoy huge savings on all their disposable packaging products, including garbage bags, toilet rolls, plastic containers, plastic cutlery, straws, paper bags, napkins, paper tablecloths, restaurant docket books,&amp;register rolls.

All of these items are available online,&amp;can be purchased using our secure platform. We also offer a Fast Shop option - the industry leader in fast&amp;convenient stock replenishment. It allows customers to view past orders online, update relevant details&amp;checkout.

We hope you find our site easy to navigate, but if you get stuck, please don&apos;t hesitate to contact us on 1300 586 246.
 
 
 1300 586 246 
 
 
 
Top Sellers

 8oz Black Paper Coffee Cups 
 12oz Black Paper Coffee Cups 
 Luncheon Napkins 
 Thermal Rolls 
 Coffee Cup Carry Trays 
 Cling Wrap 
 Plastic Teaspoons 
 8oz/225ml Clear Plastic Cups 
 
Top Categories 

 Garbage Bags 
 Coffee Beans 
 Drinking Straws 
 Paper Coffee Cups 
 Plastic Cutlery 
 Register Rolls 
 Takeaway Food Packaging 
 Washroom and Cleaning 
 Sitemap 
 2011 Wholesale Direct Restaurant Supplies Pty Ltd. ABN: 99 879 219 916. All prices are listed in Australian dollars and excludes GST. Privacy Policy About Fast Shop Benefits of Shopping with Us Shipping Refunds and Returns Terms and Conditions Netstarter - Ecommerce Solutions , Digital Strategy &amp; Search Marketing {1} ##LOC[OK]## {1} ##LOC[OK]## ##LOC[Cancel]## {1} ##LOC[OK]## ##LOC[Cancel]##
	</body>
</document>
