<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002373" url="http://www.city-data.com/va-restaurants/China-Panda.html" time="2012-07-12-18:17" support="4" score="0.00366993183826624" bingtitle="China Panda, 8970 Quioccasin Road, Richmond, VA - Restaurant ..." webtitle="China Panda, 8970 Quioccasin Road, Richmond, VA - Restaurant inspection findings and violations, food safety">
			<query id="001204" bing-rank="250"/>
			<query id="001213" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="001150" bing-rank="232"/>
			<query id="001216" bing-rank="178"/>
	<description>0820 - Critical Fried rice in steam table was 112 degrees. ... Keep open so it can be used easily. 3045 - No handwashing ... Employee that provided refund receipt to customer did not ...</description>
	<body>
		China Panda, 8970 Quioccasin Road, Richmond, VA - Restaurant inspection findings and violations 

 
 
 
Back to Virginia Restaurants , Virginia , VA smaller cities , VA small cities , All Cities .
 Restaurant: China Panda 
Address: 8970 Quioccasin Road, Richmond, Virginia 
Phone: (804) 754-8822 
Total inspections: 30 
Last inspection: Jul 29, 2009 
 
 
Violation code
 
Inspection Date
 
Inspection Type
 
Critical violations
 
Non-Critical violations
 
Details / Comments
 
 0140 - Corrected During Inspection Critical After handling raw shrimp 2 employees rinsed their hands. 1890 - Critical Employee washed a container that had rice in it and did not sanitize before putting more rice in it. (Note: rice was from previous day and had been in the walk-in cooler). 1770 A - Corrected During Inspection Critical Dried chicken was found on the slicer. 
 July 29, 2009 Risk Factor Assessment 3 0 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. May 04, 2009 Risk Factor Assessment 0 0 - No violation noted during this evaluation. February 02, 2009 Risk Factor Assessment 0 0 - 
 0160 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Employees not washing hands after hands have been contaminated. 0220 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Employee was eating while preparing food. 1750 - Repeat Single use containers being reused. 3080 - Repeat Light intensity low (25 foot candles). 
 December 16, 2008 Follow-up 2 2 Details / Comments 
 3045 - Corrected During Inspection No handwashing signs in restrooms. 1770 A - Corrected During Inspection Critical Slicer was dirty behind guard. Knives stored on wall were dirty. 1900 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Knives were not sanitized after being cleaned. 0480 - Labels have worn off corn starch bins. 0550 - A soup container was being used to scoop rice. 1750 - Single use containers were being reused. 2020 A (single-service/single-use) - Corrected During Inspection Unwrapped eating utensils were in a container for the customers with eating surface presented. 1570 - Shelf in refrigerator was broken. 3080 - Light intensity low 25 foot candles. 
 November 03, 2008 Routine 2 7 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. July 15, 2008 Risk Factor Assessment 0 0 - 
 1570 - Repeat 1/15/08-Refrigerator shelf broken. 1570 - Repeat Refrigerator shelf broken, shelves rusty and cinder blocks being used to hold rice cooker. 1750 - Repeat Single use containers being reused. 3080 - Repeat 1/15/08- Light intensity low. 3080 - Repeat Light intensity low (25 foot candles in kitchen. 
 January 15, 2008 Follow-up 0 3 Details / Comments 
 0160 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat Employee returned from lunch and did not wash hands before starting to work. 0220 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Open employee drink in kitchen. 0470 - Critical Containers not covered in walk-in. 0610 - Food containers stored on floor in walk-in. 0830 - Critical Precooked meats and egg rolls not date labeled. 1570 - Refrigerator shelf broken, shelves rusty and cinder blocks being used to hold rice cooker. 1750 - Single use containers being reused. 2020 - Single use utensils were not displayed so that the handles were at one end. 2310 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Handsink was blocked. 3045 - No handwashing signs in restroom. 3080 - Light intensity low (25 foot candles in kitchen. 
 December 28, 2007 Routine 5 6 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. November 07, 2007 Follow-up 0 0 - 
 0160 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Employee came in through back door and started cutting chickens with washing hands. 0480 - Containers of flour, sugar and corn starch not labeled. 0820 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Eggs and gravy in sandwich unit were 45 degrees. 1570 - An old refrigeration unit was found outside the back door. 1770 A - Critical Can opener was dirty. 3340 - Corrected During Inspection Critical A container of gasoline was stored on top of boxes of duck sauce. 
 October 03, 2007 Routine 4 2 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. September 19, 2007 Complaint 0 0 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. August 09, 2007 Other 0 0 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. August 06, 2007 Follow-up 0 0 Details / Comments 
 0060 - Critical Expired demonstration of knowledge. 0160 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Employees were not washing hands before starting to work and in between tasks. 0220 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat Open employee drinks in kitchen. 
 July 30, 2007 Critical Procedures 3 0 Details / Comments 
 0470 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Raw duck and raw chicken were over RTE sauces in walk-in. 0800 - Critical Pan of cooked chicken on counter is 88 degrees, was cooked this a.m. 1890 - Critical Employee washed food container and did not sanitize container before placing on drying rack/storage rack. 
 April 23, 2007 Critical Procedures 3 0 Details / Comments 
 0160 - Critical Observed employee &quot;wash&quot; hands without using soap after meal break. 0170 - Observed employee wash hands and face in 3 compartment sink. 0220 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat Employee drank from open soda can in kitchen. 0470 - Critical Bag of carrots and open container of sliced cabbage on walk-in floor. 0820 - Critical Fried rice in steam table was 112 degrees. 
 January 22, 2007 Critical Procedures 4 1 Details / Comments 
 0220 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat Observed employee drinking can of soda in food prep area. 0960 2 - Repeat Thank you bags used as food containers. 1060 - Repeat Using cardboard on shelf as divider. 1750 - Repeat Chicken seasoning containers reused as food containers. 
 January 22, 2007 Follow-up 1 3 Details / Comments 
 0220 - Critical Repeat Observed partially consumed coffee cup in kitchen over prep area. 0220 - Critical Observed partially consumed container of hot and sour soup on shelf over prep area (photo on file). 0470 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Observed raw meat over vegetables in walk in. 0820 - Critical Pan of fried chicken on counter is 101 degrees and egg rolls in refrigerator are 51 degrees (had been on counter). 0960 2 - Using &quot;thank you&quot; bags for food storage containers. 1060 - Using cardboard for divider in singel serve utensil storage container. 1570 - Wire shelves in walk in are rusted. 1750 - Reuse of plastic chicken seasoning container for food storage. 1770 C - Some gaskets not clean. 1770 C - Hood not clean, not scheduled for cleaning until 1/07. 1770 C - Exterior (handle) of pan not clean. 3150 - Damaged cans not segregated from ok cans. 3170 - Walk in floor is rusted. 3240 - Drain plug for handsink sticks. 
 November 01, 2006 Routine 3 8 Details / Comments 
 0220 - Critical Repeat Twist top water bottle and open containers of hot tea in food prep areas. 1890 - Critical Repeat Metal pan in clean storage area had food residue on it. 3340 - Critical Spray bottle of garden fungicide on food storage shelf. 
 August 07, 2006 Critical Procedures 3 0 Details / Comments 
 0220 - Critical Employee drank from open cup in kitchen. Open &quot;pepsi&quot; can in kitchen. 0470 - Critical Jugs of bleach are used to hold down strainer in container of hot peppers-bottoms of jugs that had been on floor are in contact with food. 0800 - Critical Pan of cooked chicken approx 6&quot; deep in refrig is 75 degrees. 1890 - Critical Pans/food containers not clean. 3340 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Can of carpet adhesive, pesticide sprayer, draino and bleach next to or over food. 
 May 03, 2006 Critical Procedures 5 0 Details / Comments 0470 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Raw meat over RTE food in walk in. February 06, 2006 Critical Procedures 1 0 Details / Comments 
 0960 1 - Critical Repeat Thank you bags used as food contact surface/container. 1570 - Repeat Some shelves in refrig are rusted. 
 January 26, 2006 Follow-up 1 1 Details / Comments 
 0160 - Critical Employee preparing raw chicken rinsed hands in 3 compartment sink before preparing order. 0820 - Critical Container of cooked rice out at 100 degrees. Container of cooked egg rolls out at 60 degrees. 1620 - Employee preparing raw chicken rinsed hands in 3 compartment sink before preparing order. 2310 - Critical Handsink not accessible-bags of cabbage, containers of prepared food, etc. block access to sink. 
 January 20, 2006 Follow-up 3 1 Details / Comments 
 0160 - Critical Employee preparing raw chicken changed duties and prepared orders at work without washing hands. 0240 - Food prep employees without hair restraints on. 0560 - Cloth towel in contact with/covering egg rolls in refrig. 0610 - Corrected During Inspection Bag of raw chicken on floor. 0610 - Corrected During Inspection Container of cooked rice stored in splash zone of handwash sink. 0640 - Fly glue strips over food prep area. 0960 1 - Critical Thank you bags used as food containers. 1570 - Rusted shelves in prep refrig. 1750 - Reuse of chicken seasoning container as food storage container and reuse of cardboard boxes as single use sauce containers. 1770 A - Critical Encrusted food debris on sugar container. Scoop in clean storage area had food on it. 1770 C - Gasket on prep refrig not clean. Exterior of homestyle refrig is not clean. 1940 - Aprons washed on site with no mechanical washer available. 1960 - Wiping cloths washed on premises were outside to dry. 2660 - Women&apos;s restroom waste container cover is missing. 2720 - Dumpster door and grease barrel open. 3170 - Walls behind handsink and prep table not clean. 3270 - Flies present-back door open. 
 November 09, 2005 Routine 3 13 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. October 05, 2005 Complaint 0 0 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. August 04, 2005 Critical Procedures 0 0 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. May 24, 2005 Complaint 0 0 Details / Comments 0220 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Employee had RTE chicken wings in prep area. April 27, 2005 Critical Procedures 1 0 Details / Comments 1890 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Pan not sanitized before reuse. January 25, 2005 Critical Procedures 1 0 Details / Comments 
 0640 - Corrected During Inspection Employee placed hot rice in bus pan &gt;4&quot; deep. 1530 - No chlorine test papers. 1900 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat Employee washed pan bun but did not sanitize before reuse. 
 January 25, 2005 Follow-up 1 2 Details / Comments
	</body>
</document>
