<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002430" url="http://www.entrepreneur.com/franchises/kfccorp/282495-0.html" time="2012-07-12-18:22" support="1" score="0.001006529888986178" bingtitle="KFC Corp. Franchise Information | Entrepreneur.com" webtitle="KFC Corp. Franchise Information | Entrepreneur.com">
			<query id="000180" bing-rank="229"/>
	<description>Franchises for Sale: Food | Health Care | Retail | Sports | ... agreement stipulated that the corporation would receive a ... Filed Your Taxes? You Deserve a Cup of Coffee</description>
	<body>
		Business&amp;Small Business Follow Entrepreneur on Facebook Follow Entrepreneur on Twitter Follow Entrepreneur on LinkedIn Subscribe | Mobile | Bookstore 
 Entrepreneur Homepage Startups Starting a Business Home How-To Guides Startup Basics Business Ideas Business Planning Startup Financing Success Stories Home-Based Business Run&amp;Grow Run and Grow Your Business Home Human Resources Leadership Innovation Growth Strategies Business Management Travel Automotive Money Money Home Financing Taxes Accounting Basics Personal Finance Money Management Payments&amp;Collections Marketing Sales&amp;Marketing Home Marketing Basics Sales Online Marketing Finding Customers Social Media Branding Technology Technology Home Your Website Apps&amp;Software Security Mobile Office Tech SEO Franchises Franchises Home Franchise 500 Homebased Low Cost Top New Fast Growing Top Global Biz Opportunities Franchises for Sale Franchises for Sale: Food | Health Care | Retail | Sports | Travel | Part Time | More» The &apos;Treps The &apos;Treps Home The Innovators ’Trep Talk Profiles Lifestyle Productivity Young Entrepreneurs Answers Ask Entrepreneur Home Starting a Business Franchises Sales&amp;Marketing Technology Money Home Based Business Online Business Legal Issues Human Resources Grow Your Business Have a Burning Buesiness Question? Ask Your Question Now Magazine Current Issue Subscribe Tablet Edition Past Issues Startups Magazine Video 
 Franchise 500 Homebased Low Cost Top New Fast Growing Top Global Biz Opportunities Franchises for Sale Franchises / Food / Chicken Next 17/500 Back 
KFC Corp.
 
 #17 
At a Glance
 
 Products&amp;Services: Chicken

 Number of Locations: 16,853

 Total Investment: $1.31M - 2.47M
 
 Founded: 1930

 Began Franchising: 1952

Public Owned
 Tweet 
About KFC Corp.
In 1930, Harland Sanders opened Sanders Court&amp;Cafe in the front room of a gas station in Corbin, Kentucky. He was named an honorary Kentucky Colonel in 1936 for his contributions to local cuisine. Colonel Sanders began franchising in 1952 and awarded the first franchise to Pete Harman in Salt Lake City, Utah. Their handshake agreement stipulated that the corporation would receive a royalty of one nickel for each chicken Harman sold.
His recipe is still a secret, but billions of Colonel Sanders&apos; chicken dinners are served annually in more than 80 countries. KFC is now part of Yum! Brands, which also includes A&amp;W;Restaurants, Long John Silver&apos;s, Pizza Hut and Taco Bell. 
Franchise Units

 Year U.S. Canadian International Company Owned 2011 4,275 0 8,353 4,225 2010 4,307 0 7,676 4,281 2009 4,297 0 7,482 3,801 2008 4,387 0 7,166 3,339 
 Where Seeking Franchisees: Franchisor is seeking new franchise units worldwide. 
Startup Costs, Ongoing Fees and Financing
 Total Investment: $1,308,800 - $2,469,000 
Franchise Fee: $45,000 
Ongoing Royalty Fee: 5% 
Term of Franchise Agreement: 20 years, renewable 
 
Financial Requirements
Net Worth: $1,500,000 
Liquid Cash Available: $750,000 
 
 Financing Type In-House Third Party Franchise Fee Startup Costs Equipment Inventory Accounts Receivable Payroll 
 
Franchise Ranking History
 Franchise 500®: #17 (2012) , #16 (2011) , #24 (2010) , #14 (2009) , #7 (2008) , Fastest-Growing: #48 (2008) , America&apos;s Top Global: #16 (2012) , #14 (2011) , #19 (2010) , #13 (2009) , #2 (2008) , 
Related Stories
 
 From Small-Town Day Spa to Flourishing Franchise A Franchise Grapples with Hypergrowth Waxing for Young Girls? Franchise&apos;s Promotion Draws Heat Top 10 Franchises for Veterans How One Health Care Franchisee Overcame Growing Pains and Found Success 
 
Related Franchises
 
 Bojangles&apos; Restaurants Inc. Brewster&apos;s Chicken Buffalo Wild Wings BullChicks Chester&apos;s 
 
Franchise Search
 Find Franchise Opportunities for Sale Select Industry Automotive Franchises Business Services Children Related Commercial Cleaning Education Franchises Financial Services Food Franchises Fitness and Beauty Healthcare Home Based Franchises Home Improvement Internet&amp;Technology Low Investment Franchises New Opportunities Part Time Franchises Retail Franchises Restoration Services Senior Care Sports Related Franchises Travel Service Franchises 
 Featured Franchises For Sale 
 
 
 More Franchise Opportunities» Advertisement 
 Fund Your Franchise Today 
Use your existing IRA or 401k funds to purchase a franchise—with no tax penalties.
	</body>
</document>
