<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002733" url="http://www.ukjobsnet.com/packers-pickers-jobs" time="2012-07-12-18:47" support="2" score="0.003659381428655669" bingtitle="Packers / Pickers Jobs" webtitle="Packers / Pickers Jobs">
			<query id="000949" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000966" bing-rank="22"/>
	<description>... Quality Picker you will be responsible for picking various ... Exp. Order Pickers needed to work in a busy warehouse ... work in a packhouse environment packing fruit into trays ...</description>
	<body>
		Updated every day with the latest job vacancies from across the UK! 
 UK Jobs Part Time Jobs Graduate Jobs Job Categories Local Jobs Advertise Here Contact Us 
 
Packers / Pickers Jobs

Here are the latest packers / pickers jobs. This list of packers / pickers jobs is updated every day with the latest vacancies, so don&apos;t forget to check back regularly or bookmark this page.
 
 Packers / Pickers Jobs Packers / Pickers Jobs in Birmingham Packers / Pickers Jobs in Bristol Packers / Pickers Jobs in Chelmsford Packers / Pickers Jobs in Cheshire Packers / Pickers Jobs in Coventry Packers / Pickers Jobs in Crewe Packers / Pickers Jobs in Gosport 

 Packers / Pickers Jobs in Hemel Hempstead Packers / Pickers Jobs in Kent Packers / Pickers Jobs in Kettering Packers / Pickers Jobs in London Packers / Pickers Jobs in Merseyside Packers / Pickers Jobs in Middlesbrough Packers / Pickers Jobs in Milton Keynes Packers / Pickers Jobs in Nottinghamshire 

 Packers / Pickers Jobs in Oldham Packers / Pickers Jobs in Reading Packers / Pickers Jobs in Rochdale Packers / Pickers Jobs in Southampton Packers / Pickers Jobs in Stoke-on-Trent Packers / Pickers Jobs in Swansea 
 
 NO. JOB TITLE&amp;DESCRIPTION - CLICK THE JOB TITLE TO VIEW THE JOB DETAILS AND SUBMIT YOUR APPLICATION 1 Order Picker 
 Location: Kettering - Salary: From £6.25 to £6.50 per hour - Posted: Today 
Our client urgently requires order pickers. This work is temporary on going.Experience is essential for this role. Must have order picking experience using hand held scanning guns. Main duties will involve operating a hand held scanning gun to ord...
 2 Picker / Packers Required 
 Location: Sherburn In Elmet - Salary: £6.08 per hour - Posted: Today 
Aqumen Recruitment required experienced picker packers to join a busy team. working monday to friday 8am-5pm Duties:- Re work Packing Picking to set targets and deadlines
 3 QA Manager 
 Location: Chippenham - Salary: 40000 - Posted: Yesterday 
Our client is an excellent example of how vertical integration can create business growth. As one of the top farming businesses in the UK they are farmers, packers and supermarket suppliers and its their supply chain that puts them in a unique pos...
 4 Co - Packers 
 Location: Oldham - Salary: £6.08 per hour - Posted: Yesterday 
We are looking for experienced co packer to work for our client based in oldham. full time hours temporary on going work. warehouse experience is desirable but not essential.
 5 Picker/Packer 
 Location: Swansea - Salary: 6.08 - 7 per hour - Posted: Yesterday 
We are currently looking for experienced picker/packers in the Swansea area. They will be working Mo
 6 Pickers Packers 
 Location: Chelmsford - Salary: 6.2 - Posted: Monday 
Immediate Start. We are looking for hard working, flexible, reliable pickers packers for busy warehouse based in Chelmsford. Ideally you will have previous experience but we will consider people from a variety of working backgrounds that required ...
 7 Pickers and Packers 
 Location: Brigg - Salary: 6.08 - Posted: Monday 
Due to expansion over the coming months our client will be looking for production operatives to work within the food production environment. We are looking for operatives to work Monday to Friday 40 hours per week. Due to the location of the clien...
 8 Picker/Packer 
 Location: London - Salary: 6.08 - Posted: Monday 
Picker / Packer 6.08 per hour Based in North London Ongoing - Long term Our client is looking for picker / packers to join their team. You will be required to work to strict picking deadlines - If deadlines are not met contracts will be terminated...
 9 Cold Store Supervisor 
 Location: Kent - Salary: 25000 - Posted: Monday 
Excellent opportunity in the food industry. The Company Located in Kent, the Garden of England, The company is one of the largest growers and packers of top, stone and soft fruit with over 40 years of experience. The family run business is the big...
 10 Warehouse Picker / Packers 
 Location: Hemel Hempstead - Salary: £6.45 per hour - Posted: Monday 
We urgently require warehouse pickers for our customer based in Hemel Hempstead.Working in a clothing warehouse you will be hanging garments, order picking, packing garments, scanning boxes, sealing and moving boxes and all other duties required.A...
 11 Warehouse Pickers 
 Location: Milton Keynes - Salary: £6.08 - 6.08 per hour - Posted: Monday 
Warehouse Operatives required for a busy Warehouse in Milton Keynes Applicants must have experience picking in a fast paced environment Duties will include picking, packing, replenishment and stock control as well as other associated tasks. Immedi...
 12 Pickers Packers 
 Location: Chelmsford - Salary: £6.20 per hour - Posted: Monday 
Immediate Start. We are looking for hard working, flexible, reliable pickers packers for busy warehouse based in Chelmsford.Ideally you will have previous experience but we will consider people from a variety of working backgrounds that required a...
 13 Prod Ops&amp;Packers 
 Location: Middlesbrough - Salary: 6.08-6.08 h - Posted: Friday 
Prod Ops&amp;Packers required for Stokesley Early morning starts. 12 hour shifts. Long term tempo
 14 Order Picker 
 Location: Bathgate - Salary: £6.10 per hour - Posted: Friday 
Manpower UK Ltd is recruiting on behalf of our client for Order Pickers to work within their Bathgate site. Candidates will be required to locate and pick items and work towards targets. Candidates should be hardworking, motivated with good commun...
 15 Cumberland Meat Packers 
 Location: Birmingham - Posted: Friday 
Vacancy&apos;s available at CUMBERLAND MEAT PACKERS in a range of departments. Forklift and HGV2 License
 16 Forklift and HGV2 License Holders, Butchery and Meat Packing 
 Location: Birmingham - Posted: Friday 
Vacancy&apos;s available at CUMBERLAND MEAT PACKERS in a range of departments
 17 Order Pickers 
 Location: Southampton - Salary: £6.08 - 6.08 per year - Posted: July 5th 
ORDER PICKERS - Southampton, Hedge End, Nursling Starting at £6.08per hour . Various shifts - 6am to 2pm / 7am to 2.30pm / 9.30am to 6pm / 8am to 4.30pm / 2pm to 8pm / 8pm to 6am Temporary ongoing work available to join the order picking teams. Pr...
 18 Website Order pickers 
 Location: Start Point - Salary: wrapping and packing goods ... - Posted: July 5th 

 19 Order Pickers 
 Location: Cheshire - Salary: £6.08 per hour - Posted: July 5th 
Order Pickers - Crewe£6.08 per hourTemporaryExperienced Order Pickers required to work for our client in Crewe. They are a well established successful company.Good levels of literacy and numeracy are required, with keen attention to detail and a c...
 20 20X Order Pickers 
 Location: Coventry - Posted: June 29th 
20 X Order Pickers New Contract Magna Park, Lutterworth Temp to Perm, 6.75ph Must have 5 years
 21 Food Production Packers 
 Location: Merseyside - Salary: From £6.08 to £6.08 per annu - Posted: June 27th 
My large client in the St Helens area are recruiting for food production packers.Must be available to work shifts 6am - 2pm and 2pm till 10pm.Must be able to get to St Helens for these times.Experience working in a food environment would be advant...
 22 Refuse loaders/ Refuse HGV Drivers/ litter Pickers 
 Location: Chichester - Salary: £6.25 per hour - Posted: June 26th 
Refuse loaders are required for temporary work for Chichester District Council. They are holding a training inducation on Tuesday 26th&amp;Thursday 28th June at 1.30pm, and you will be required to attend this and once you have completed th...
 23 Order Packers / Goods In&amp;Out, Eccles 
 Location: Eccles - Salary: £6.08 per hour - Posted: June 21st 
Order Packers / Goods In&amp;Out Pay: £6.08 per hour Working Hours: 5.30am-2pm Order Packers / Good In&amp;Out wanted for expanding company in Eccles. Candidates will be required to work together in a team environment to weigh and pack the produce. T...
 24 Packer/ Bow tier 
 Location: Avonmouth - Salary: £6.08 per hour - Posted: June 20th 
An exciting opportunity to join one of our well established clients as a part of a packers/bow tiers team. We are looking for dedicated and reliable candidates with a background in a warehousing environment, who can be flexible on the hours worked...
 25 Packers 
 Location: Corby - Salary: £6.08 per hour - Posted: June 14th 
Our FMCG Client requires packers who are available at sometimes short notice to work in their busy production/packing plant. You will have previous experience of working in a fast moving environment and be willing to work at the Corby location at ...
 26 food packers x 40 
 Location: Winsford - Salary: Upto £6.08 per hour - Posted: June 13th 
Assist are looking for packers for the Winsford area, candidates will be packing meat on a production line. Work is ongoing and the environment is fast paced.Various shifts;7am-2.30 pm2.30pm-2.30am5 days out of 7 which will include some weekendsCo...
 27 Order Pickers 
 Location: Corby - Posted: June 13th 
Order Pickers wanted for Local Based Client in Corby areaMonday to Friday (Mornings and Afternoons)Min Wage £6.08 p/hrImmediate StartIf you would like to apply for this position please email your CV to natalie-hardwick@industria-northampton.co.uk
 28 Order Picker 
 Location: Didcot - Salary: From £6.08 to £10.64 per hou - Posted: June 13th 
Order pickers required for busy distribution centre in Didcot, Oxford.The job entails picking goods ready for delivery.Experience of working in a warehouse and chilled environment an advantage but not essential.Candidates must be available to work...
 29 Packer/ Bow tier - Temporary 
 Location: Bristol - Salary: From £6.08 to £6.08 per hour - Posted: June 13th 
An exciting opportunity to join one of our well established clients as a part of a packers/bow tiers team.We are looking for dedicated and reliable candidates with a background in a warehousing environment, who can be flexible on the hours worked....
 30 Food Packers X 40 
 Location: Winsford - Salary: £6.08 per hour - Posted: June 13th 
Assist are looking for packers for the Winsford area, candidates will be packing meat on a fast paced production line. Work is ongoing and shifts are 4 on 4 off.Various shifts;7am-2.30 pm2.30pm-2.30am5 days out of 7 which will include some weekend...
 31 Food Packers - Nights 
 Location: Wandsworth - Salary: £7.00 per hour - Posted: June 8th 
Our client, a truly innovative food design company, are looking for Production and Packing staff to work on their prestigious Upper Class Airline Catering contract. You will be resposible for the basic preperation and packing of the products so ex...
 32 Fruit Packing Operatives 
 Location: Linton - Salary: £6.08 per hour - Posted: June 7th 
Go Produce are urgently seeking 40 x Fruit Packers who would be available for work immediately on the outskirts of Maidstone in Kent on both day and night shifts. The work is based on the outskirts of maidstone to the location, own transport or ca...
 33 Warehouse Staff / Pickers&amp;Packers 
 Location: Rochdale - Salary: 6.08ph - Posted: May 31st 
Our clients offers various shifts inc days and nights over a 7 day period, 40 - 48hrs per week
   
 
 Agriculture Worker Jobs CNC / Machine Operators Jobs Cabin Crew Jobs Cleaning Jobs Contract Manager Jobs Courier Jobs 

 Driving Jobs Gardener Jobs Groundkeeping Jobs HGV Driving Jobs Hairdressing Jobs Housing Jobs 

 Latest Jobs Mechanic Jobs Operations Manager Jobs Packers / Pickers Jobs Public Sector Jobs Royal Mail Jobs 

 Salon&amp;Beauty Jobs Transport&amp;Logistics Jobs Travel&amp;Tourism Jobs Travel Agent Jobs Veterinary Jobs Youth Worker Jobs 
 ©2012 Online Classifieds Limited. Privacy Policy . Terms&amp;Conditions . Advertiser Login . Information for Job Seekers . International Careers . Useful Websites .
	</body>
</document>
