<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002637" url="http://tokyoexpert.blogspot.com/" time="2012-07-12-18:42" support="1" score="0.00010191637991267763" bingtitle="Japan Travel Tips" webtitle="Japan Travel Tips">
			<query id="000400" bing-rank="225"/>
	<description>... money, eat like the locals do, don&apos;t go out and waste your ... So in case you need to make a order at a fast food restaurant. A yes, and let&apos;s not forget SUSHI! You can find ...</description>
	<body>
		skip to main | skip to sidebar 
Japan Travel Tips
 
 Tokyo, Kyoto, Osaka, it doesn&apos;t matter where in Japan, I hope to provide you with as much assistance as possible in planning your trip to Japan. 
 
 Monday, February 16, 2009 
 
 BUDGET: FOOD&amp;DRINK 
 Food and Drink 
 Where to eat good and save money .

Now of course you probably have read about the $10 dollar cup of coffee you can find in Ginza, and if you have an unlimited budget, well go for it.

But not all of us are right right?

For your morning coffee, there&apos;s nothing wrong with going to McDonald&apos;s or smaller shops. McDonald&apos;s coffee is pretty good and quite popular in Japan. You can get it as low as 100 Japanese Yen.

As for food, people often ask me this question. You don&apos;t need a high food budget to eat good. Someone asked me once &quot;Is $100 USDollars good enough for ONE DAY?&quot; My answer to them was &quot;The average Japanese person doesn&apos;t spend $100 USDollars a day on food, why should you?&quot;.

If you want to save money, eat like the locals do, don&apos;t go out and waste your money on fancy restaurants for breakfast, lunch and dinner, that&apos;s a silly waste of money!

 Local Restaurants 

Noodle shops are common everywhere, and you have all types of noodles, Ramen, Udon, Soba etc etc. And noodles are cheap, you can get a good bowl that will fill you up for less then $5 USDollars.


Gyudon &quot;Beef Bowls&quot;, Gyudon is another popular Japanese dish. Gyudon is a bowl of rice, topped with beef and onions. The most famous brand named store is YOSHINOYA, pretty much the McDonald of fast food Gyudon. Another famous fast food Gyudon place is Matsuya. You can get a bowl of gyudon for around 380 Japanese Yen (about $4 USDollars).

Curry restaurants also provide good cheap food. There&apos;s Japanese Curry and a large amount of Indian Curry restaurants as well. Again you can get yourself a nice good meal for about $5 USDollars.

 Izakaya - is a type of Japanese style bar.
At Izakaya you can usually find cheap drinks and good small fingerfoods. Any fingerfood you can imagine, chicken, pizza, french fries etc. at cheap good prices.


 

 Fast Food - Hamburgers etc.
Of course Japan is not short of your typical fast food places like McDonald&apos;s and Tokyo has (but very few) Burger Kings and Wendy&apos;s. McDonald&apos;s is king in Japan.
Now you&apos;re asking yourself, &quot;I just traveled 6,000 miles to Japan, why should I eat at McDonald&apos;s??&quot;
My answer is, for the experience. Japanese McDonald&apos;s do have some interesting menu items that are not found in other countries. Give them a try! Plus it is cheap, they have a 100 yen menu which is similar to the US Dollar menu.

Another recommended Japanese fast food place is MOS BURGER, though a little more expensive then McDonald&apos;s, MOS BURGER is Japanese, and they make EXCELLENT burgers. I suggest you give them a try.


PS. In American English &quot;FRENCH FRIES&quot;/ &quot;CHIPS&quot; in British English, In Japanese it is translated as &quot;FRIED POTATO&quot;. So in case you need to make a order at a fast food restaurant.
 A yes, and let&apos;s not forget SUSHI! 
You can find many cheap Sushi places, including 99yen Sushi restaurants all over the place. Just remember to keep track of how much you are eating!
 
Vending Machines and Convenience Stores 
There are more 7-11 (Seven Eleven) Stores in Japan, then there are in the ENTIRE United States. Convenience stores in Japan and in Tokyo are EVERYWHERE and they are all competing against each other. Popular stores are:
LAWSON, 7-11, AMPM and FAMILY MART.
Also in Japan Vending Machines are EVERYWHERE, Japan has the highest vending machine to person per capita then any country in the world.

 Markets/Grocery Stores 
My advice to you, if you find a grocery store or market near your lodging place SHOP THERE! Usually the prices here are cheaper then vending machines and convenience stores for things like drinks. Also, if you shop at the market before it closes, many times, perishable items will be marked on sale for upwards of 50%. This is a little known secret to travelers, so take advantage of it!

Restaurant Tips:
Please see my section below on tips when visiting a restaurant. 
Restaurant Tips

A few tips and cultural points
 First things first, in Japan, they don&apos;t TIP. In Japan it might be seen as a sign of disrespect as you have to pay someone extra to do their job correctly.
So DON&apos;T TIP in Japan.

When eating with chop sticks don&apos;t leave your chop sticks sticking out of the rice, this practice is only done at FUNERALS.

When eating noodles, it is ok to slurp!

Some restaurants might be a tatami mat, or require you to take off your shoes (if you see a bunch of people with no shoes on, it is a good idea to take yours off too). Though this is usually for higher end restaurants, and you usually don&apos;t have to worry about in fast food restaurants. However there are Izakaya&apos;s that are designed that way. So just pay attention to the other customers if you are not sure.

Language Barrier:

Now a restaurant most likely won&apos;t have an English translation, but don&apos;t worry!
Many shops have plastic displays of their food outside the shop, just point at the one you want.


Here are some basic Japanese food terms:

Chicken- TORI NIKU
Pork - BUTA NIKU
Fish - SAKANA
Egg - TAMAGO

Drinks:
Water - MIZU
O&apos;sake - ALCOHOL
Don&apos;t be afraid of the language barrier, you are visiting another country for a reason right? To explore! So have fun and enjoy your time. The staff would probably try to help you as much as possible.

Just don&apos;t be rude and arrogant!!
Remember speaking English louder won&apos;t make the other person understand it any clearer if they don&apos;t understand it to begin with. 
100 Yen Shops

Great Discount Items
 
100 Yen shops are shops where all items (unless otherwise noted) costs 100yen (with tax it is really 105 yen).

At 100 yen shops you can find virtually anything you might need for a traveler and daily living. Food, snacks, drinks, notebooks, paper, envelopes...pretty much any daily necessities you might need can be found at 100 yen shops.

100yen shops are a good alternative to convenience stores when you need to buy snacks or drinks on the go. Posted by tokyosbuway at 8:54 AM 1 comment: Older Posts Home Subscribe to: Posts (Atom) 
Japan Expert Pages
 
 ▼  2009 (8) 
 ▼  February (8) 
 BUDGET: FOOD&amp;DRINK KODAMA PURATTO ECONOMY PLAN - Discount tickets Tok... NARITA AIRPORT LAYOVER INFORMATION TOKYO STUDIO GHIBLI MUSEUM DIRECTION JAPANESE ATMs&amp;MONEY JAPAN AIR PASS INFORMATION USING THE JAPAN RAIL PASS Japan Travel Information 
 
 
 
Favorites
 Tokyo Subway
	</body>
</document>
