<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002518" url="http://www.vendscreen.com/category/blog/" time="2012-07-12-18:35" support="3" score="0.0037762107728993664" bingtitle="Blog | VendScreen | VendScreen" webtitle="Vending Technology Blog | VendScreen.com">
			<query id="000576" bing-rank="62"/>
			<query id="001020" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="001272" bing-rank="215"/>
	<description>... nice poster of us, and we put our business cards on our little table (this is like claiming a table at a fast food restaurant). ... tape to remove the existing credit card ...</description>
	<body>
		Meet Jen Products About Operators Advertisers Blog Media Press Contact 
 
 
Meet the Founders:
 
 Paresh Patel 
 Founder and CEO 
 
 Glenn Butler 
 Co-Founder and CTO 
 
Follow us on:
 
Search:
 
Recent Posts:

 Crunch Time Part Two [VIDEO] Bootstrapping a Startup is a State of Mind Two Vending Industry Veterans Join VendScreen 
 
Categories:

 Entrepreneurship Glenn NAMA OneShow News Paresh Staff and Talent Vending Technology VendScreen Products 
 
 
Vending Technology Blog
 
 Crunch Time Part Two [VIDEO] 

By: Glenn Bulter | July 2, 2012

 Back in April, I wrote a post called“ Crunch Time! ”as we were getting ready for our public launch at the NAMA One Show , the vending industry’s annual trade show. Our team stepped up and met that goal (and I totally appreciate our team for this!). We won 5 Gold awards and, by any measure, hit a home run.

 But now, a newer and bigger Crunch Time is upon us – we are currently putting devices into the field–and they actually have to work. 

Anyone reading this blog who has experience launching a M2M / Hardware / Cloud / Consumer / Customer experience knows that this is a vastly complicated thing. There are hardware issues, software issues, and firmware issues–and that’s just on the engineering side. As founders, we are also dealing with investors and customers. With VendScreen it is even more complicated than that because our customers are: 

 consumers who use vending machines; operators and bottlers that want to install VendScreen devices; and partners–like the big bottlers or consumer brands in vending–that want to promote their brands on our devices 

Paresh and I are a dynamic team and we always try to do a“divide and conquer”so we can stay nimble and move faster.  Faster is critically important to us because, unlike most software startups, we have a hardware supply chain that ties up funds at an enormous and scary rate. A two-week problem in engineering can translate into a 6-figure tie-up of funds in the supply chain.

 So I always ask myself,“How well we are executing? What could we be doing better?” 

I give us an honest startup rating of A-. We suffered a few inevitable setbacks, but we’ve also made some major achievements and I think overall we’ve executed very well. I am proud to say that we have devices in the field and our field trials are progressing nicely. This video shows one accomplishment that I am particularly proud of:

 

 Two seconds or less! But–we have a lot of work to still do. So, we continue building an all A+ team to help us meet our challenges. Where we are today is remarkable considering how young this company is! Yes, we can always do better, and every day, Paresh and I and the VendScreen team strive to do just that.
 
 Bootstrapping a Startup is a State of Mind 

By: Paresh Patel | June 1, 2012
 
Unassuming Glenn digitally signing our $12MM Series A documents from a Starbucks in Las Vegas
 
Startup Funding Strategies: Bootstrapping vs. Venture Funding

Recently Glenn and I were  speaking with a fellow entrepreneur regarding funding startups and bootstrapping . I said, “Glenn and I have done it both ways. We have bootstrapped prior startups and now we’ve gotten outside capital with VendScreen.”

Spending Other People’s Money

I started thinking about this considerably because while I was saying we have done it “both ways” it really didn’t feel any different to me in this startup as compared to my bootstrapped startup.  Glenn still shows up with his 3 year old, scratched up, and beaten up Mac, and I still use the same computer I used at Courtesy Vending before VendScreen.

As I thought about this more, I realized actually there was little difference. Yes, this company’s capital needs are different than the other companies we started. But our attitude and the way we are building the business is very similar. We still spend money as if it were our own. In fact, we are even more judicious because now we feel a sense of greater responsibility and accountability than if it were our own funds or internally generated cash. We don’t lose sight of the fact we are spending “other people’s money.”

 Spending Money in the Right Places 

Don’t get me wrong – I’m not saying the two scenarios are exactly the same. Of course having the capital allows us to staff up, prime the supply chain, and scale the company much faster than we would be able to do otherwise. Arguably, this company could not seize the market opportunity without outside funding due to the unique capital needs.

Nonetheless, if we look at HOW we are building the company, we still act as if we are bootstrapping. I would argue it is more about the spending side than the capital side. Different businesses have different capital needs, but bootstrapping may better be used to characterize how money is being spent. In that regard, bootstrapping may be universally adopted by startups regardless of how they are actually funded.

In other words, bootstrapping is a state of mind. It is more about how we entrepreneurs go about building the business and how we set the priorities for the business.

Bootstrapping at VendScreen

A clear example is the day we received the first tranche of our Series A funding. While we were certainly pleased and relieved, there was no celebration. We did not go out that day, nor were there any high-fives. In a way, it wasn’t really a sense of accomplishment for us; the funding simply signified the beginning of additional hard work to be done and the responsibility we owed to our investors. We didn’t miss a heartbeat by celebrating and continued working as if it was just another busy day in the startup. Our priority was not the funding, but the business we are building.

In fact, we were so immersed in our work, the first emails that went out were not to our employees, but to our suppliers and contractors who were waiting for the funding green light so they could proceed in helping us build the business.

Perhaps the single best example that our state of mind is still focused on “bootstrapping” is that when Glenn is in town for business, he still stays in a small room at the motel my parents own so we can save on hotel rent! While he could legitimately consider it a business expense to stay somewhere else, we know in a bootstrapped company you don’t spend any dollar you don’t have to. And that’s our mindset still.
 
 Two Vending Industry Veterans Join VendScreen 

By: Glenn Bulter | May 11, 2012
 
Stephen Pasker
 
We’re excited to formally announce that we’ve added two full-time members to our stellar team: Stephen Pasker and Erich Markee , who bring more than three decades of combined vending experience to VendScreen.

Stephen was most recently an industry consultant following his departure from Crane Streamware, where he served 11 years. He worked in customer support, documentation and quality assurance, most recently presiding over the implementation team. He has spent more than a decade working with hundreds of vending operators, helping them realize operational efficiencies and improvements.

Stephen learned about the vending machine industry from the bottom to top. He understands the needs of vending machine operators, the challenges they face, and what it takes to improve the profitability of their businesses.”

Erich brings more than 19 years of industry experience to VendScreen. Prior to joining VendScreen, he consulted for several operators, focusing on process development,
 
Erich Markee
 
data analysis, and cash and inventory accountability.

Prior to working as a consultant, he was general manager for Next Generation Vending, based in Stoughton, Mass., systems implementation manager for Sodexo Vending Services, and operations manager for A&amp;B Vending in Saugus, Mass. He rolled out Crane Streamware’s vending management system to item level for more than 130 routes, and implemented pre-kitting, dynamic scheduling and various cashless systems for numerous vending operators.

Both Erich and Stephen add immense depth to VendScreen, Inc. with their tribal vending knowledge. We are delighted to have both of these A players on our team as we work to commercialize VendScreen Revolution .

 

 
 
 Photos from VendScreen at NAMA Part 3 

By: Paresh Patel | May 1, 2012

Wow, these are some nice shots! Thanks to Jon over at Rains Marketing for some great perspective from the conference floor!
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 VendScreen REALIZE Demo [Video] 

By: Paresh Patel | April 30, 2012

Our super developer Gary Gause shows off the VendScreen Realize at the NAMA One Show in Vegas. The Realize is a resident device built into the OEM machine that handles purchasing,  cashless, nutritional data, ads, coupons, and telemetry (data back to customer VMS). It Directly synchs to an existing VMS systems (MEI, Streamware, and Cantaloupe now, more to come) with very little done outside of the VMS. Take a look…

 
 «Older Articles 
Copyright 2012|VendScreen, Inc.|(888) 748-4249|Patents Pending
 
 Designed by Rains Marketing
	</body>
</document>
