<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002145" url="http://www.singleservecoffee.com/archives/026722.php" time="2012-07-12-18:02" support="7" score="0.007852804489472946" bingtitle="Making Iced Coffee and Tea with the Keurig Platinum B70 | Single ..." webtitle="Making Iced Coffee and Tea with the Keurig Platinum B70 | Single Serve Coffee">
			<query id="001152" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="001142" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="001154" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000399" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="001153" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="001057" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="001148" bing-rank="100"/>
	<description>... 50 for an iced coffee or iced tea at a coffee shop or fast food restaurant when you can make your own at home? Over the past few weeks, we&apos;ve been testing various K-Cups ...</description>
	<body>
		Select Archive Complete Archive List July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 June 2007 May 2007 April 2007 March 2007 February 2007 January 2007 December 2006 November 2006 October 2006 September 2006 August 2006 July 2006 June 2006 May 2006 April 2006 March 2006 February 2006 January 2006 December 2005 November 2005 October 2005 September 2005 August 2005 July 2005 June 2005 May 2005 April 2005 March 2005 February 2005 January 2005 December 2004 November 2004 October 2004 September 2004 August 2004 July 2004 June 2004 May 2004 Site Navigation Home Complete Archive List About Single Serve Coffee Advertising Breville Bunn My Cafe Caffeine and Coffee CBTL Classic Coffee Makers Coffee Concentrates&amp;Extracts Coffee Cups&amp;Travel Mugs Coffee Gadgets&amp;Accessories Coffee Pod Reviews Coffee Pods Coffee Tables Coffee Visits Cuisinart Espresso Pods Flavia General News Grindmaster Holiday Shopping Guides Home Cafe K Cup Reviews Keurig&amp;K-Cups Keurig Reviews Keurig Vue&amp;V-Cups Krups Nescafe Dolce Gusto Lavazza Mailing List Mailing List Promotions Melitta One:One Monthly Round-Up Nespresso Portable Single Serve Coffee Reviews RSS Senseo Simplehuman coffee pod brewer Single Serve Coffee Deals Single Serve Coffee Europe Single Serve Coffee Machines Single Serve Coffee Rumors Single Serve Coffee Tips&amp;Tricks Single Serve Tea Starbucks Single Serve Coffee Submit News Super Automatic&amp;ESE T Disc Reviews Tassimo&amp;T-Discs Tea Pods The Single Serve Coffee We&apos;re Drinking Whole Bean and Ground Coffeee 
 
 Get Seen Advertise Here 
 

 

 

 

 

 



 

 
 
 
 «Coffee Cup Power To Go - Car Powered One Cup Inverter | Main | NexPod - Refillable Coffee Capsule for Nespresso» 


June 8, 2009
 
 Making Iced Coffee and Tea with the Keurig Platinum B70

 


Whether it&apos;s gathering round the patio after a hearty BBQ or heading out for a drive on a lazy Summer week-end, those of you who purchased the new Keurig Platinum B70 this past year can cool off by taking advantage of a neat little feature which has yet to appear on other Keurig models: you can now make iced coffees/teas which you can customize to your own flavor preferences.


Why pay upwards of $2.50 for an iced coffee or iced tea at a coffee shop or fast food restaurant when you can make your own at home? Over the past few weeks, we&apos;ve been testing various K-Cups to see which ones were best suited to be &quot;iced&quot; vs. prepared in their usual manner. Let’s take a quick look at some of our favorite varieties along with flavoring suggestions for each.


 

It should be noted that we used unflavored 10% blend cream and all-natural Stevia sugar substitute to achieve some of the sweeter iced latte drinks. We realize most of our readers may not have easy access to specialty coffee flavoring syrups, so we decided not to use any during our testing. Feel free to use half&amp;half or 1% skim milk and whatever sweeteners/flavorings you prefer.
 
 Single Serve K-Cup Iced Coffees 

 
 
 
 
 Dark Roasts&amp;Extra Bolds – This variety will yield the strongest taste and will obviously be favored by those who prefer these types of K-Cups. We suggest a generous blend of cream&amp;sweetener to prevent things from becoming too bitter. This type of K-Cup would probably hold up well with added flavor syrups. In our opinion, this is the best choice if you’re attempting to make a flavored iced latte drink. The truly adventurous can take this straight-up on the rocks. We liked Tully’s French Roast&amp;Green Mountain’s Extra Bold Dark Magic.




 
 
 Medium Roasts&amp;Flavored Roasts – Best paired with cream&amp;sugar. Some flavored roasts might have a strong enough flavor which will not require addition of any sweeteners or syrups. Our favorites so far have been Green Mountain’s fruit flavors such as Fair Trade Raspberry Rhapsody, Fair Trade Wild Mountain Blueberry&amp;even their Southern Pecan. We also enjoyed Timothy’s Caramel Vanilla Nut&amp;Gloria Jean’s Butter Toffee. Fruit flavors seemed ideal straight-up on the rocks (the raspberry was amazing)&amp;anything with hints of caramel or nut notes always goes well with cream, sweeteners and perhaps the occasional touch of flavor syrup.


 Light Roasts – This one was a little too weak for our liking. Once we added creamer&amp;the ice started to melt, any remaining flavor became too diluted. Maybe some syrups might help, although those who prefer lighter-tasting drinks might actually enjoy this.


 Single Serve K-Cup Iced Teas 


 
 
 
 
 Herbal Teas – We tried Timothy’s Lemon Blueberry Passion Tea and were quite surprised by the results. It was like drinking a mild blueberry lemonade. The fact that this tea was colored added a nice visual touch. We’re still on the lookout for more herbal teas to try and can only imagine they would probably also go well over ice.


 Traditional Teas (White, Green&amp;Black) – Timothy’s Orange Indulgence White Tea yielded a very light tasting drink with very faint hints of orange (the ice diluted the taste), while their Cranberry Twist Green Tea resulted in a nearly identical flavor as when it’s prepared hot. Bigelow’s English Breakfast Tea was best served with several lemon wedges and a splash of sweetener.




 
 
 Specialty Teas – What kind of review would this be if we didn’t try the obvious… a chai latte! We took Timothy’s Chai Tea and fine-tuned the mix of cream&amp;sweetener until we hit the perfect balance. It was almost like an iced version of Tassimo’s Twinings Chai Latte without the shelf-stable milk aftertaste.


 Making Iced Teas and Iced Coffees with the Keurig Platinum B70 

So how does the new Keurig Platinum B70 go about making iced beverages anyway? Simple, the “iced beverage” setting has a max output of 3oz which yields VERY strong “shots” of coffee (depending on the roast)&amp;tea from a K-Cup. As the hot coffee/tea hits the ice cubes, the ones in the center of the cup start quickly melting, immediately diluting the strong taste by turning into water while also forcing the temperature of the drink to drop. The ice cubes near the wall of the cup melt at a slightly slower rate and further help cool down the temperature of the drink. Once brewing is complete, a quick stir will completely chill the drink to normal “iced beverage” levels and slow down the melting rate of the remaining ice cubes. Our tests showed ice remaining in our drinks for as much as 1 hour after brewing (when using a double-walled glass)


This got us thinking… couldn’t you use any Keurig model to make iced beverages? Yes, but not without a bit of a hassle. We tested with a B50 as well as the Mini B30 and found out the hard way that there’s no easy method to halting a Keurig machine mid-brew unless you yank out the power cord. Both models overflowed (due to larger default brew sizes) or yielded severely watered-down beverages which didn’t have much taste. To be honest, we preferred to take the lazy way out and simply use a machine that had the proper preset. Hopefully Keurig will start introducing their 3oz iced beverage setting throughout their entire line-up instead of limiting it to one of their premium models.


As we’ve noted earlier, iced beverages can be enjoyed at home or on the go. Any heat/cold resistant mug or glass will do at home but we suggest getting a small insulated travel mug (in the 5 or 6oz range) when heading out. The insulation should prevent the ice from melting too quickly and you’ll be doing your part to help the environment by using a washable mug vs. a paper or plastic cup usually favored by various coffee shops/restaurants.


With the hundreds of K-Cup flavors available at stores and online, the possibilities for iced K-Cup beverages are almost endless. The key thing is to have fun and experiment… a lot. Also, don’t get too disappointed if you end up throwing away a few bad batches as it took us a few trial&amp;error runs before we figured out what worked best.


So grab some ice cubes, brew-up a cup, sit back&amp;relax… because Keurig B70 fans, you just got one more reason to look forward to Summer each year.


Read our full review of the Keurig Platinum B70 ...


Read More in: Keurig&amp;K-Cups 

Share this Article with others: 

Related Articles:

 Keurig VUE Brewer V700 and V-Cups Announced - Feb 15, 2012 Swiss Miss K-Cups Now at Green Mountain Coffee - Jan 25, 2012 Mr. Coffee Single Serve Coffee Maker Looks Great in White - Jan 17, 2012 

Came straight to this page? Visit Single Serve Coffee for all the latest news.
 Posted by Jay Brewer at June 8, 2009 7:58 AM
 Recent Comments 
 
 
If you put a stainless steel spoon in the glass with the ice it will keep almost any glass from cracking when adding hot water ... waitressing secret ...

 Posted by: dmfarino at December 22, 2010 6:50 PM 
We have the original version of the B70 (without the iced beverage serving size) and I&apos;ve been using it to make iced coffee since my espresso machine called it quits. I use The Roasterie (http://www.theroasterie.com)Espresso, My K-Cup and the smallest brew setting. I brew the coffee and usually let it cool slightly before adding it to a glass with ice, chocolate syrup and sweetener. It&apos;s topped off with skim milk and, occasionally, whipped cream. This makes a generous 20 oz serving and has become my favorite drink during our current heatwave.

 Posted by: Kathleen at June 24, 2009 2:11 PM 
Yes, I forgot to note that. With double-walled glassware, you indeed have to careful when using spoons/ice cubes. I usually insert the cubes gently vs. throwing them in there like any other single-walled cup/mug. I also refrain from using spoons and use plastic stir sticks anytime I need to stir in creamers, etc. That&apos;s probably why I haven&apos;t had any Bodums break on me yet... either that or just uncanny good luck.

 Posted by: SH at June 10, 2009 10:27 AM 
Ha, well really I was thinking the ice cubes would crack the inner wall themselves unless you carefully laid them in the cup. Guess not!

 Posted by: jbviau at June 8, 2009 9:45 PM 
Bodum glasses are made to handle the temperature extremes. You can have extremely hot or cold beverages. One would think the temperature extreme would cause the glass to break, but I&apos;ve been using the same cup for the past few months without any problems. No cracking, but now you&apos;ve gone and made me paranoid :-P

 Posted by: SH at June 8, 2009 12:27 PM 
Make that &quot;ice&quot; cubes, not &quot;iced.&quot;

 Posted by: jbviau at June 8, 2009 9:08 AM 
Iced cubes in a Bodum double-walled glass? Now that takes nerve! How many have you broken so far? :)

 Posted by: jbviau at June 8, 2009 9:07 AM Post a comment Name: 
 

 Email Address: 
 

 URL: 
 

 Remember personal info?
 
 Comments: 
 

 Please enter the letter &quot;b&quot; in the field below: 
 Please press Post only once. Submission of comments takes up to 20 seconds because of Spam Filtering. 
 
 
 Email This Entry: Making Iced Coffee and Tea with the Keurig Platinum B70 Email this entry to:
 

Your email address:
 

Message (optional):
 

 
 

 

 

 

 
 Mailing List Enter your Email
	</body>
</document>
