<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002194" url="http://www.abdo.ca/blog/tag/best-food-in-montreal/" time="2012-07-12-18:06" support="4" score="0.014288641425535974" bingtitle="Best Food In Montreal | Restaurants in Montreal-Montreal ..." webtitle="Best Food In Montreal | Restaurants in Montreal-Montreal restaurants-Montreal food-Montreal accountants-Montreal Bank-Montreal car dealers-Car dealers in Montreal-Montreal events organizer">
			<query id="001335" bing-rank="175"/>
			<query id="001317" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="001263" bing-rank="237"/>
			<query id="000886" bing-rank="237"/>
	<description>These are the real places to try out. Most of them ... specialty stores, guests take tongs and a tray and ... every local street vendor, neighbourhood fast food restaurant or ...</description>
	<body>
		French 
Menu
 
 Home Abdo, history&amp;facts Submit Listing Compare Memberships Login Now Advanced Search Contact Us Jobs Sitemap 
 
Categories
 
   Automotive 

   Banking&amp;Finance 

   Business 

   Food&amp;Beverage 

   Health Services 

   Media&amp;Publication 

   Services 

   Real Estate 

   Education 

   Travel&amp;Tourism 


 
 



 
 Links 
 Free Web hosting 
 Send huge files for free 
 Social Bookmarking 
 Website design 
 Over 23000 recipes online 
 free tv channels 
 Real estate in Lebanon 
 submit articles 
 movies trailer 
 website traffic tips 
 pepsi coupons 
 huggies coupons 

 

 
Posts Tagged‘best food in Montreal’
 
 Food in Montreal’s Chinatown 
 Thursday, September 30th, 2010 
Chinatown is a cultural point of Montreal offering standard fast food fare on budget. Travelers get a lot to taste in Chinatown. Food in Montreal ’s Chinatown is delectable and mouth-watering. While you are in Montreal, make sure to visit Chinatown to savor its culinary delights which come within your budget.
 
 

Travelers can easily find out a variety of fast food chains within Chinatown offering their usual bites. However, there are several restaurants in Montreal’s Chinatown . These are the real places to try out. Most of them are popular to provide unusual savory treats which are served quickly and at affordable prices.

The St.Urbain and de la Gauchetiere streets are some of the best places in Chinatown , Montreal to look for the most wonderful alternatives. Walk along this area and you can find plenty of eateries lined out to allure people passing by the street.

 Chinese Specialty Pastries 

Want to taste some Chinese specialties? Stroll along the de la Gauchetiere and you will come across a range of Chinese bakeries. The wonderful window displays will attract you to get in and have some lip-smacking Chinese delicacies.

Try Patisserie Harmonie located at 87 de la Gauchetiere. It’s a specialty Chinese bakery offering a wide selection of dishes to the visitors. In most of these specialty stores, guests take tongs and a tray and then selects from the slices of the delicate green tea cake or the sweet pastries. Some of them may be filled with sweet custard or red bean paste. Then there are pleasant buns which comes filled with barbecued pork, chives among the other ingredients used to prepare them.

 Dim Sum 

Near Patisserie Harmonie you will find Jade Garden. It is the take out counter of the Poon Kai Restaurant located at 87 de la Gauchetiere. This counter provides a wide variety of dishes to make your selection. Especially succulent and tempting are the dim sum which is removed from bamboo steamers. In addition to Dim Sum, this well-known restaurant provides a great variety of Chinese pastries. This restaurant offers reasonably priced delicacies and tasty treats which make this place worth a visit. However, it may take time to get served during the peak hours.

 Barbecue Treats 

Going towards east you can find the St. Laurent Street. This is another popular area to offer you some refreshing and fulfilling treats. Here you can find A Lam Kee Grocery Store and Barbecue located at 1065. St. Laurent. It might seem to be a plain and small establishment, but it serves some of the best crispy roast pork, chicken, barbecued duck, and a host of other tempting meats.
 
Across the St. Laurent Street there is another popular must visit food outlet. It’s the Patisserie Cao Thang Binh. This particularly specializes in serving you some fresh taste of the Vietnamese submarine sandwiches. They even serve you other excellent choices like exotic desserts, alluring spring rolls, cold noodle dishes. You can taste them are at reasonable prices. During the peak hours, it usually takes a bit of time to serve, but it’s worth a wait due to its affordable rates and tasty results.
 
Tags: best food in Montreal , budget food in chinatown , chinese bakery , Chinese restaurant , chinese restaurants in montreal , food in montreal , food in Montreal chinatown , food outlet 
Posted in Food in Montreal | No Comments» 
 
 Food in Montreal- Affordable and Cheap Places to Note 
 Monday, September 27th, 2010 
Like the most standards sights, food in Montreal happens to be the greatest charm of the city which should never be missed. There is much more to your tour when it comes to touring Montreal . Visitors coming to Montreal should not be missing out the greatest charm of the city. Instead of having your breakfast, lunch and dinner at your hotel, choose to check out the food outlets and various other restaurants within the city.

 

When touring Montreal, most travelers are quite certain to watch out the regular sights, like the Olympic Stadium, Notre Dame de Montreal Basilica, the Botanical Gardens and Parc du Mont-Royal. These are sights which are well-worth your time. However, you need to spend some time satisfying your appetite as well. Here’s the most cheapest and affordable way to get most out of the edible pleasures in Montreal. Given below are few suggestions for fulfilling your appetite on a budget while in Montreal.

 Breakfast in Montreal 

You must order a heavy breakfast. Why? Because a lot of biking and walking needs to be done, if at all you want to check out each and every corner of the city. This is where the Dusty’s stands out. Nestled at 4510 Avenue Du Parc, you can expect a range of western breakfast and staples at the Dusty’s. Be sure to get the best of large breakfast specials.

Chez Cora located in 1396 Rue Mont- Royal is another great option, popular for omlettes and other egg preparations. The Peggy’s Poached and Cora’s special dishes are great choices. People who love French toasts can be sure to get the best treat.

 Lunch in Montreal 

Whether its summer or spring, it’s the ideal time to go for picnics at Montreal baskets. Don’t worry about food. You can visit Parc Lafontaine, Parc du Mont-Royal and the other stunning parks in Montreal . Spread a blanket and get started with an enjoyable picnic feast. If you are looking for some grocery stores, then Supermarche PA located at 5029 du Parc will most arguably be your first choice. With quality produce and affordable rates, you can always get the best.

If you are seeking something more, then you can look beyond a standard supermarket. Visit La Maison Du Roti, situated at 1969 Avenue Du Mont-Royal Est. This is where you can get appetizing baguettes, pre-made meals and a wide variety of cheeses. Not only this, this place is a great choice to meet your barbeque requirements.

 Coffee Breaks in Montreal 

Want to test the best coffee in the heart of Montréal? Your choices are Café Olympico, Club Social and Laika. The Club Social is a stylish place that you may be looking for, providing good java. Another choice can be Café Olympico providing stylish ambiance and big TV offering some Italian soccer entertainment. You can choose to try out the latter which is served in glass and even sweetened with brown sugar.

 Dining in Montreal 

In the year 2009, Marconi Bar was voted as the best Montreal restaurant by the readers of a Montreal newspaper-Mirror. This restaurant in Montreal offers food which is reasonably priced and delicious.

If you are in mood to try out some fries and burger, then you may go for Patati Patata. Not only does it serves great burgers but the prices are much low. You may even choose to try out poutine, the city’s best dish here. For chocolaty treats you may choose Juliette Et Chocolate and for desserts there can be nothing like the tasty cupcake served at Petits Gateaux.
 
Tags: best food in Montreal , best Montreal restaurants , food in montreal , restaurants , restaurants in montreal , touring montreal 
Posted in Restaurants in Montreal | No Comments» 
 
 Finding Delicious Chinese Food in Montreal 
 Wednesday, August 18th, 2010 
Montreal can be termed as the melting pot for different culinary cultures. When you are on a trip to Montreal, you will find the best of any cuisine because people in Montreal just love to eat and that too healthy food. If you are worried about finding a good Chinese food joint in Montreal, then relax. There are several of them across the city. All of these restaurants promise to take you through the most exclusive of Chinese dishes, the taste of which you will savor for a lifetime. Chinese food is considered to be healthy with a distinct taste of its own. You will get authentic Chinese as well as innovative Chinese food in Montreal. Some of them also provide either take out and home delivery facilities. You just only need to know where to find them.

 

You will find the tastiest of chop sueys, rice rolls, noodles, mantous and Chicken soo guys in Chez Chine in Downtown Chinatown. To taste the Orient in its best, you have to visit Downturn Chinatown while touring in Montreal. The restaurant specializes in Cantonese preparations, but it also serves several Continental menus. You will get the best Dim Sum, lobster and duck dishes in Chez Chine. Their Cantonese lobster is hailed among the best in entire Montreal. The shellfish dish available here is one of a kind. After you have had your fill, sit at the Lotus Blue bar and enjoy your favorite drink.

Niu Kee is among the best Chinese food joints in Montreal. It earned its reputation over the years by delivering some of the most delicious Chinese items to its customers. Moreover, it will serve the food in an absolutely Oriental environment. Climb the stairs and take your place in front of one of the disposable plastic wrapped tables. The staff is friendly and can suggest the best item to you. Treat yourself to the scrumptious spicy fish with peanuts, eggplant with peppers and spicy beef with onions and cumin.

Qing Hua is situated inconspicuously in Lincoln Street. Though the place might be a little difficult to find, the food is absolutely marvelous to savor. The Dumplings is another popular pick and they offer the best taste in entire Montreal. These dumplings are juicy because they are filled with soups and have the perfect taste. You have to be meticulous while having it or you might just spurt the soup. Try their lamb with coriander and beef with spring onion and you will rave about the taste.

China Grill is another premier Chinese restaurant located in Downtown. It operates from 11am to 10pm throughout the week and serves exquisite Chinese preparations making it worth your visit. The setting is modern and the food is of high quality available at affordable rates. Their presentation is artful and quantity is substantial. Their special dish baby back ribs is delectable. Their rice rolls, noodles and seafood platter is mouth watering. If you love oriental dishes, do not forget to check out the Chinese restaurants in Montreal.
 
Tags: best chinese food in Montreal , best food in Montreal , chinese food , chinese food in Montreal , Chinese restaurant , food in montreal 
Posted in Restaurants in Montreal | No Comments» 
 
 Picking One of the Best 24/7 Montreal Restaurants 
 Friday, August 6th, 2010 
Want to cherish the pleasure of late night dining? The city of Montreal which has always been known to offer a congenial and pleasurable ambiance together with exotic flavors when it comes to dining has decided to bring you something different and happening this time around. Wondering what is it? Then you must know that you can now explore the opportunity of dining late at the best-known 24/7 Montreal restaurants.

 

There can be noting as special as checking out the 24×7 Montreal restaurants to perk up your late night adventures which offer you the room to spend the night in a new way possible. Bringing a new dimension in partying late night, you get the chance to taste some good food while sipping some fresh drinks and giggling with your group.

Setting your mood to party all night long with friends, the 24×7 Montreal restaurants bring you an absolute delight at all forms. The 24/7 Montreal restaurants know your needs and keep up to meet your expectations when it comes to serve food while ensuring full entertainment. Whether you are visiting with a group, some French fries, a burger and soda makes you ready to spend the night out with closed ones. Not only has this, the carbs and fat from the neon-bathe dining aid to absorb the over-consumption of the evening. This is what reduces the possibility of an untimely hangover.

Another interesting fact indicates that poutine includes restorative properties which have also been proved by scientists. The contribution of scientists stands integral in formulating an idea of having a perfect partying experience at night. However, your partying can’t be an enjoyable without picking up the Montreal restaurants which offer 24-hour service.

Not all Montreal restaurants allow you to dine the whole night. Hence, you have to know those special ones which make your night an enjoyable one. In this article, you will find 3 most happening outlets. These are few of the favorite 24/7 eating and party joints which help you to keep all your desires and adventures fired up throughout the night.

 Rapido 

Located at 4494 St. Denis, you find this restaurant in Montreal to be spacious enough to accommodate a group comfortably. The pink, brown and orange booth offer just right cocoons to those who are just feeling a bit over-stimulated from the excess of techno music. You can expect to get unlimited coffee with your selected menu from the 24-hour breakfast menu.

 Le Club Sandwich 

The Le Club Sandwich is one of the popular 24/7 Montreal restaurants which promise a classic style dining arrangement. Situated at 1578, Sainte-Catherine East, the restaurant features a lot of table spaces and cheering dance remixes. During summer, you can enjoy a romantic dinner under the stars on the patio enjoying club sandwich for sure.

 Al-Taib 

Situated at 2125 Guy Street, the Al-Taib is a hot-favorite among the 24×7 party people and students. This Lebanese bakery is a favored choice for its delicious eats and reasonable price. Explore the Arabic taste right way by ordering the mainstay- Manakish. You also get fresh salads and pizza. Order the fresh baklava and finish up for the day. Well, you need to keep some to explore any another night.
 
Tags: best food in Montreal , food in montreal , montreal restaurants , restaurants , restaurants in montreal 
Posted in Restaurants in Montreal | No Comments» 
 
 Restaurants in Montreal 
 Monday, December 21st, 2009 
For people who love to travel, there is one golden rule about the food in foreign countries – always eat like locals! That is a great recommendation, and you should keep it in mind. Whenever you travel, try to blend in as much as possible, learn about tradition and culture and of course – taste the domestic, local cuisine. If you go to Montreal eat like Quebecois do!

 

Their traditional, domestic food is actually traditional French, with local additions and ingredients. Restaurants serve French specialties but with domestic “flavour” so they add wild vegetables (for instance mushrooms, fiddleheads or ramps), maple syrup etc. Fish they eat is fresh, and the most popular kinds are freshwater salmon and trout. People in Montreal restaurants mostly eat healthy meals, based on fish and vegetables and the best meals are served in restaurants like Chez L’Epicier, Toque…

Montreal also offers a huge variety of fast food restaurants where you can try all sorts of not-so-healthy but very tasty dishes. These small corner restaurants serve poutine (that means you will get frites with strong gravy and cheese curds that are melting), an interesting combo known as pizzaghetti (pizza/spaghetti mix) and very popular sandwiches with smoked meat. Basically every local street vendor, neighbourhood fast food restaurant or take out corner offers this fast food selection.

Apart from local, traditional food, Montreal has a big number of restaurants serving international (foreign) cuisine. That means that if you have a craving for certain cuisine, in Montreal you will have no trouble finding what you want. For those who like American food – Cosmos Snack Bar, Beaver Club and Beauty’s will be the perfect choice. If you are more into delicious Asian food, then visit Chao Phraya, Chu Chai, Ginger or Ganges, they are all excellent. Canadian food (described above) is served in fantastic restaurants like Chez Noeser, Aix Cuisine du Terroir, Chez L’Epicier, and Bronte. Of course, since Canadian cuisine presents a mixture of French food and local ingredients, there is a huge variety of French restaurants all over Montreal. Ones you need to check out if you travel there are: Bonaparte, legendary Au Pied de Cochon, L’Express and Decca 77. Italian food is loved and accepted all over the world, and Montreal is no exception. There are many great Italian restaurants all over town where you can taste tasty pastas and marvellous wine, just like Italians do. Casa Napoli, Café via Dante, Amelio’s and BU Bar a Vin are among the best Italian restaurants in Quebec, so check them out if you visit Montreal.

If you prefer desserts and sweets more than regular meals, then you have to try maple sugar sweets, which are the best Canadian sweet brand. Crepes or pancakes, maple syrup toffee and coffee with maple syrup are traditional desserts in every restaurant in Canada. If you have a sweet tooth, these are restaurants in Montreal you shouldn’t skip: Bilboquet, Premiere Moisson Boulangerie, la Maison Cakao, Brulerie Saint – Denis…

No matter what your favourite cuisine is, or what kind of sweets you prefer, restaurants in Montreal will certainly offer you a variety of good tastes and excellent food to choose from. Enjoy!
 
Tags: best dishes in mntreal , best food in Montreal , Montreal cuisine , Montreal restaurant , montreal restaurants , montreal traditional food , restaurant in Montreal , restaurants in montreal , tradional food in montreal , what to eat in Montreal , where to eat in montreal 
Posted in Restaurants in Montreal | No Comments» 
 
 Fusion cuisine in Montreal 
 Friday, December 11th, 2009 
Fusion cuisine is a huge hit around the world. This cuisine is a mixture of elements of various culinary approaches combined together, and it was implemented in restaurants during the 70’s. Fusion cuisine became very popular again in the last decade. In Montreal, fans of fusion have more than 20 restaurants to choose from, depending on the price range, cooking and serving styles, and restaurant locations.

 

Asian Fusion restaurants are among the most popular ones. They feature and combine Chinese food, Indian cuisine and Singapore dishes. In Asian Fusion restaurants, you will probably recognize meals and names, but here they have a little twist – which means they have been prepared in a modern way and not traditionally. Montreal offers excellent Asian fusion restaurants and the best thing is – they are not expensive!

Another fusion approach means that the cook is using original traditional dishes but changing main ingredients, making them fresh, new and original. This is a more eclectic approach. Basically, these restaurants serve regional cuisine with new ideas and twists. Restaurants from this group are bit more expensive, and their interior is usually very modern and NY-inspired (marble, glass, monochromatic materials and colours). Worry not – Montreal has 3 in the city centre.

The third Fusion type is when a chef makes traditional food with ingredients from other cuisine. Here is an example: pizza with cheddar, salsa, pepper jack cheese, beans etc (ingredients for Mexican food). If you are up for experiments, this fusion will be your perfect choice. Winning combos include a crossover between Italian and Mexican food, between Indian and French cuisine and between Greek and Asian food.

As we have mentioned, these restaurants can be cheap or very expensive, depending on the part of the city they are located in, the cuisines which are mixed, and the reputation the restaurant has. Everything connected to Asian food guarantees huge portions, spicy but tasty food, lower prices and cosy authentic ambient. Fusion of French, Italian and American food can cost you more. Fancy restaurants usually have high prices, offer an amazing variety of drinks and tasty, but smaller portions of food.

Montreal gathers a lot of tourists every year and its settlers are from all over the world. That is why the offer is so rich, and you really need a lot of time and will taste every cuisine there, and feel their real hospitality. If you plan to go out on a dinner, cruise the web to find the best possible offer. Fusion cuisine is very popular so the choice will not be easy. Decide which mixture (fusion) works best for you, then decide how much money you would like to spend, and then select from the offers, where you want to eat.

Since fusion is the no.1 trend at the moment, Montreal, being a big city, certainly has a lot to show and offer. We suggest brave combinations: where Mexican food meets Italian, but that is only for the bravest hedonists!
 
Tags: Asian cuisine in Montreal , Asian food in Montreal , Asian restaurants in Montreal , best food in Montreal , eating chinese food in Montreal , Fusion restaurants in Montreal , Montreal fusion restaurants 
Posted in Restaurants in Montreal | 1 Comment» 
 
 
Search Blog
 Search for: Follow Us 
 
Categories

 Accommodation (4) Accountants in Montreal (4) Amusement Parks (2) Apartments (1) business (7) Business Directory (4) car dealer (11) Cardiologists (1) cars (22) Clubs (4) Companies (11) dentist in Montreal (8) Dentists (8) Doctors in montreal (11) Financial Translation Services (1) Florist Services (4) Food in Montreal (5) Graphic Design (2) Health Care in Montreal (2) Hotels (8) Italian Restaurants in Montreal (2) Jewelry (4) Limousines service (2) Montreal Downturn restaurants (1) Moving Company (4) Music (1) Photographers (6) Restaurants in Montreal (51) Saunas in Montreal (2) Services (2) Shopping (8) Student Housing Facilities (1) Translation Company (2) Travel (18) Web Design (2) Wedding Photographers (11)
 Real Estate (10) 
 X Medical Translation Services (1) 
 
Archives

 March 2012 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 June 2010 March 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 
 
 
 Subscribe in a Reader 
 
 Entire (RSS) 

 Comments (RSS) 
 
 
 
 
 Home   -   Contact us   -   Advertise 
 with us   -   Submit your Business -   Login Now   
 

 
 ©2006-2009 ABDO.ca - All Rights Reserved.

All logos and trademarks in this site are property of their respective owners.
This Site is powered by Point Multimedia Design
	</body>
</document>
