<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002121" url="http://thecompanyofextraordinary.com/franchises/" time="2012-07-12-18:01" support="3" score="0.017932824804131213" bingtitle="Outstanding Services for the Retail and Food &amp; Beverage Industry" webtitle="the Company of Extraordinary: Outstanding Services for the Retail and FoodBeverage Industry">
			<query id="000501" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000516" bing-rank="128"/>
			<query id="000189" bing-rank="181"/>
	<description>Pivano, Snack Gastronomique, is a high quality fast food ... Pivano has a clear competitive advantage thanks to its ... is also a large delivery service of hampers and trays ...</description>
	<body>
		the Company of Extraordinary 
 Outstanding Services for the Retail and Food&amp;Beverage Industry 
 Home The Team The Services Concept Bank Affiliates Contact 
 

 Pivano, Snack Gastronomique 
 
 

 Pivano, Snack Gastronomique, is a high quality fast food restaurant&amp;deli concept 

 

Pivano is a unique fast food concept serving gastronomic French/Mediterranean food, using the freshest ingredients and seasonal products.

 

Their quality commitment is written down in the base line: “Snack Gastronomique” .

Each day their employees are proud to carry out this message by delivering quality services and products to each customer.

They have set the foundations of the concept on outstanding quality and innovative grounds. Since the opening, they have been leading this new market by a continuous flow of creativity.

 

The creator, Pascal Ducros, is a former 3 stars Michelin Executive Chef, who has been exposed to the international markets for the past 15 years.

His strong background and business acumen, and his outstanding ‘cuisine’ skills and passion, contribute to the success of the concept in this new emerging market segment.

Today, Pascal Ducros is ready to develop Pivano with a unique business strategy: create a network of passionate quality franchisees in the major cities of the world to establish an international brand, and give the opportunity to these outstanding franchisees to be associated with the growth and success of the brand in becoming a potential country master-franchisee…

Pivano has been recognised by national food industry magazines as one of the most innovative and quality concepts of the year 2005.

 

Pivano has a clear competitive advantage thanks to its exceptional quality, taste, freshness, nutritional approach and innovation that make the experience a unique one, yet affordable.

Pivano is also a large delivery service of hampers and trays for business lunches and corporate or private functions.

The Company of Extraordinary is a network partner of Pivano and its sole regional agent for the Asia Pacific (except Japan and Korea).

We are involved in the development of the concept as well as the support and technical assistance to franchisees.

———
For more information about Pivano please visit their website or contact the Company of Extraordinary .

For information about franchises in Asia, please contact the Company of Extraordinary .
 


   
 
 The Services 

 Brand Representation Franchise Set-up and Management F&amp;B Concepts and Solutions Product Strategy and Development Training for Excellent Customer Management Procurement for the Hospitality Industry 


Email

 Pascal Hequet Lara Jay Sachdev 
 
 Franchises 

 
Premium French Fast Food and Traiteur 


 Food Manufacturing Brands 

 
French Bakery 


 Preferred Partners 

 


 The Company of Extraordinary is an affiliate of... 

 



 and a member of the... 

 
 Disclaimer / Website Credits 

All rights reserved©2005 - 2007 The Company of Extraordinary (Co. Reg. No. 53049536L)
	</body>
</document>
