<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002112" url="http://www.thekitchn.com/mystery-oil-wha-162241" time="2012-07-12-18:00" support="2" score="0.0024121392746537565" bingtitle="Mystery Oil: What&apos;s Really Inside This Box? | The Kitchn" webtitle="Mystery Oil:  What&apos;s  Really  Inside This Box?  | The Kitchn">
			<query id="001246" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="001247" bing-rank="72"/>
	<description>... as used in many fast food restaurant ... then you just throw it out &amp; start fresh next time? why not reuse the oil? i&apos;m sure you can find *some* kind of container. and ...</description>
	<body>
		Main Recipes Advice Supplies Kitchens Drinks Gatherings 

 Apartment Therapy Login 
 
 Mystery Oil: What&apos;s Really Inside This Box? 
 
 My husband and I were given a countertop fryer for a wedding present. It&apos;s been a fabulous piece of equipment but it does have one drawback. The oil. It&apos;s wicked expensive and the fryer requires a great deal of it. To make the most of things we throw fry parties where friends and family bring veggies to tempura, french fries or fish to throw in and possibly candy bars. Hey, I never claimed it was a healthy event.

We&apos;re always on the lookout for inexpensive oil and this time of year with all the turkey frying that happens, peanut oil goes on sale every week—somewhere. So when we happened upon this green box (on sale for $18.99 at the time) we were excited and then suddenly confused. Can you guess why?

For the most part, the oil found in bulk quantities intended for turkey frying will be peanut oil. It has a smoke point between 320 and 450 depending on if it&apos;s refined or not. So when we checked out this package we suddenly realized we didn&apos;t really know what kind of oil it was. It didn&apos;t say!

After reading the (super) fine print, it was determined that the contents were cottonseed oil. What is cottonseed oil? It&apos;s exactly what it says it is. The oil extracted from the cotton plant and seeds. It has a smoke point of 420 degrees which is pretty perfect for frying most things.

This trip to the store was an adventure in making sure you read the label and is a good reminder that great packaging and marketing can lead you to buy anything if you don&apos;t have your super sleuth detective glasses on. Have you ever purchased something, got it home and realized it wasn&apos;t what you thought it was?

 Related: How To Make Tempura Fried Vegetables At Home 

 (Image: Sarah Rae Trover ) 
 12 comments 12.05.11 3:00PM Sarah Rae 
Categories:
 Cooking Methods 
Comments (12)
 
Personally I&apos;d be cautious about cottonseed oil and check it out further--as a knitter I know that cotton is a heavily treated plant. Does anyone know if the refining process strips away the chemicals present in or on the plant?
 posted by nionon on 12.05.11 at 03:28PM 
Cotton seed oil is just another form of vegetable oil but it actually has some health benefits. This article will explain....
http://www.purematters.com/herbs-supplements/c/cotton
 posted by smithrobin86 on 12.05.11 at 03:38PM 
That was certainly an interesting series of pages, however they do not address my primary concern. I&apos;m not trying to be contentious, I&apos;m really interested in the answer. I&apos;m not reassured on the issue of if chemicals used to treat the plants are eliminated in the refining process. I believe that heating liquids often concentrates chemicals as evaporation occurs. I am not qualified to make any judgements, I&apos;m
curious....
 posted by nionon on 12.05.11 at 04:13PM 
I use peanut oil for frying if lard isn&apos;t available. most of my recipes don&apos;t get anywhere close to 400, so the extra high smoke point isn&apos;t worth the extra cash.
 posted by kcunning on 12.05.11 at 04:34PM 
Every time I go to Popeye&apos;s for fried chicken (my husband is semi-addicted), I always toss any of the so-called &quot;honey&quot; away. If you read the fine print, it says &quot;honey&quot; in big letters and &quot;sauce&quot; in smaller ones -- it&apos;s mostly made with high-fructose corn syrup with honey flavoring. Blech!
 posted by Lorena in SD on 12.05.11 at 04:59PM 
@nionon - I would speculate that, like most other seed crops, they seeds are washed before processing, so a fair amount of chemical residue on the surface of them will be removed. Also, since the seeds are pressed to extract the oil and the husks don&apos;t actually make it into the product, that will reduce the amount of contamination as well.

HOWEVER

after reading this: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cottonseed_oil and following the Gossypol link, I&apos;d have serious questions about consuming cottonseed oil at all. It sounds like it&apos;s not really fit for human consumption without some serious post-processing.

Finally, I have to say though that debating the health implications of which oil you use to deep fry your food is kinda like rearranging the deck chairs on the Titanic. You&apos;ve got bigger health concerns going on.
 posted by qhartman on 12.05.11 at 05:12PM 
Another warning about cottonseed oil: I started getting a rash on my upper lip every time I ate certain fast food items. I called a fast food HQ and spoke to a nutritionist who told me cheaper vegetable oil blends, as used in many fast food restaurant, contained largely cottonseed oil, because of how cheap it was and that it wasn&apos;t usually for people to be irritated by it.
 posted by sloanbuller on 12.05.11 at 06:54PM 
I have been frying turkeys for about 8 years and I have been using soybean oil. I get it at samsclub for about $14. Everybody prefers it to peanut oil. I used Peanut oil one year, and was asked to change back.
 posted by chepnut on 12.05.11 at 11:36PM 
i agree with the comment above. that or check your local restaurant supply store (because walmart/sams is an evil empire)
 posted by joeys on 12.06.11 at 12:04AM 
I don&apos;t understand - are people deep frying entire turkeys?? I thought the US Thanksgiving/Christmas tradition was roast turkey?
 posted by RosieGreenie on 12.06.11 at 07:26AM 
RosieGreenie - oh yeah, deep frying turkeys is a big thing, especially in parts of the country where the weather is likely to cooperate and be pleasant.
 posted by abcornwell on 12.06.11 at 07:51AM 
it sounds like you have a frying party to use up as much of the oil as you can because then you just throw it out&amp;start fresh next time? why not reuse the oil? i&apos;m sure you can find *some* kind of container. and not to gross you out (but it will), we had a fryer when i was growing up. we just put the metal lid on it&amp;put it back in the basement until next time my mom wanted to fry something. five of us kids, all still alive decades later.
 posted by loislane on 12.06.11 at 08:49AM 
Post a comment
 Comment 
 &lt;a href&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;are allowed, and line breaks are automatic. Please be aware of our comment policy . Seeing spam? Let us know . 
    

Logged in as  |  Sign out . 
Please sign in or register to comment.
 The Kitchn 
 Small Cool Kitchens 2012 Tours 
 Cook&apos;s Kitchen Grower Maker 
 Meals 
 Breakfast Lunch Supper Snack Sweets 
 How To 
 Meat Tutorials Baking Tutorials 
 Questions 
 Ingredient Questions Recipe Questions Dinner Party Questions Health Questions Product&amp;Shopping Questions 
 Food&amp;Ingredients 
 Beverages Type of Dish Ingredients 
 Kitchen Tools 
 Small Electrics Bakeware Cookware Knives&amp;Cutlery Tools&amp;Utensils Kitchen Gadgets Food Containers&amp;Storage Aprons&amp;Clothing Towels&amp;Linens 
 Cookbooks 
 Cookbook Review Cookbook Recipe 
 Life in the Kitchen 
 Projects Gardening Organizing Housekeeping&amp;Cleaning Lifestyle 
 Season 
 Winter Spring Summer Autumn 
 Sweets Quick Budget All Categories 
 
Top Recipes

 How to Cook Moist&amp;Tender Chicken Breasts Every Time How to Make Kombucha Tea at Home How To Make Cake Pops Summer Recipe: Zucchini Boats with Mozzarella and Olives How To Cook Perfect Steak in the Oven 
 See more recipes 
Top Posts

 What Do You Serve Fussy&amp;Picky Eaters? 10 Recipes to Help Meet the Challenge Garlic Sprouting Too Fast? Preserve It for Later With This Tip! 15 Ways to Eat a Cold Salad for Supper The Most Popular Dish for Olympic Athletes in Summer 2012: Can You Guess? Freeze&amp;Preserve Fresh Herbs in Olive Oil 
 
Email Updates
 
Submit a Story

Got a tip, kitchen tour, or other story our readers should see?
 Tell us about it 
Follow Us
 @TheKitchn Like us on Facebook RSS Feed Our reading list See more options 
Read Our Books

 Good Food to Share (2011) The Big Book of Small, Cool Spaces (2010) Apartment Therapy Presents (2008) The Eight-Step Home Cure (2006) 
 
Faith’s Daily Find
 
 Home Cooking: A Wri... Sombrero Juicer fro... TANGKORN Seaweed To... 
 Go to Apartment Therapy Marketplace Inspiring cooks, nourishing homes 
 About Us Our Team Contact Us 
 
Email Updates
 
Apartment Therapy
 
Top Posts

 15 Crazy Ideas to Make Your Life Saner Before&amp;After: Updated Bamboo Etageres 10 DIY Wall Art Ideas That Anyone Can Do Before and After: A Real Life LEGO Bridge Over-Sharing and Over-Caring: Decorating Our Homes in the Digital Age 
 
Top Tours

 Kristina&amp;Tyler&apos;s Whitley Heights Home Myles&amp;Grace&apos;s La Cañada Light House Long Island City: Modern Living at the View Joshua&apos;s Vintage Daydream Eva&apos;s Eclectic&amp;Elegant Pad 
 
The Kitchn
 
Top Posts

 What Do You Serve Fussy&amp;Picky Eaters? 10 Recipes to Help Meet the Challenge Garlic Sprouting Too Fast? Preserve It for Later With This Tip! 15 Ways to Eat a Cold Salad for Supper The Most Popular Dish for Olympic Athletes in Summer 2012: Can You Guess? Freeze&amp;Preserve Fresh Herbs in Olive Oil 
 
Top Recipes

 How to Cook Moist&amp;Tender Chicken Breasts Every Time How to Make Kombucha Tea at Home How To Make Cake Pops Summer Recipe: Zucchini Boats with Mozzarella and Olives How To Cook Perfect Steak in the Oven 
 ©2012 Apartment Therapy Advertising Jobs Legal Privacy Policy Comment Policy
	</body>
</document>
