<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002317" url="http://www.niuzer.com/Avon-IN/" time="2012-07-12-18:14" support="1" score="0.0003036194265122897" bingtitle="Events, news and articles from Avon, Indiana :: Niuzer" webtitle="Events, news and articles from Avon, Indiana :: Niuzer">
			<query id="000798" bing-rank="189"/>
	<description>... year with a solid 15-8 record but had an early exit ... A popular California-based fast-food restaurant chain is opening ... has forced the board of directors for Susies Place ...</description>
	<body>
		Login with Facebook Join Niuzer Login 
 
 Home Business 
 Economy&amp;Finance Stock Markets Automotives Real Estate 
 Politics Entertainment 
 Celebrity Television Music Movies 
 Technology 
 Internet Gadgets Security Software Hardware Mobile&amp;Telecom Gaming 
 Science 
 Space&amp;Astronomy Energy Environment 
 Lifestyle 
 Travel Culture&amp;Arts Fashion&amp;Beauty Family 
 Health Sports 
 NFL Football Baseball Basketball College Sports Soccer Hockey Tennis Golf Fighting News Motor Sports Others 
 Education Pets U.S. Local News 
 Germany Set My Locations US Local News 
 
 Avon, IN News / World / US / Indiana / Avon, IN / 
Avon, IN
 
 Sort by: Date Most read 
 42 hours ago — WIBC News More Charges Against Accused Sextortionist Discuss 
U.S. Attorney Joe Hogsett has added extortion charges onto a growing list of allegations related to Richard Finkbiner&apos;s child pornography case. Listen:  Hogsett says Finkbiner, from Clay County, is o... 44 hours ago — Hendricks County Flyer Alleged sextortionist now facing charges Discuss 
United States Attorney Joseph Hogsett announced on Tuesday that charges will be formally brought against Richard L. Finkbiner, 39, of Brazil, for a &quot;sextortion&quot; ring that involved 10 boys and two girls in... 7 days ago — WIBC News Allcare Targeted By Attorney General Discuss 
The attorney general&apos;s office has filed an administrative complaint against Allcare Dental and Dentures President Robert Bates, alleging multiple licensing violations. Allcare, a national chain of denti... 03 Jul 2012 — Hendricks County Flyer Avon youth baseball squad finishes sixth in nation Discuss 
A small, Indiana baseball team made waves this past week in Orange Beach, Ala., as the 8-under Avon Orioles accomplished something no other Indiana team has ever done - advancing to the World Series in th... 21 Jun 2012 — WIBC News Miller to Take Lawson&apos;s Place on November Senate Ballot Discuss 
Pete Miller was sworn in as State Senator in April to replace Connie Lawson (WIBC.com file photo: Eric Berman) State Senator Pete Miller (R-Avon) will replace Secretary of State Connie Lawson on the Rep... 20 Jun 2012 — WIBC News No Evacuations Necessary for Avon Rail Yard Leak Discuss 
(photo courtesy of RTV6) A railroad fuel tanker car sprung a leak early Wednesday morning. Hazmat crews responded to the CSX Rail Yard about 4 a.m. A bad valve on the tanker is responsible for the h... 20 Jun 2012 — WIBC News Picks for Lieutenant Governor, Secretary of State Mean Ballot Shuffle Discuss 
Indiana precinct leaders are meeting over the next several days to find replacements for officeholders taking aim at state office. Listen:  Avon Republican Pete Miller already won a nine-way caucus t... 17 Jun 2012 — Indiana Hoosiers Basketball Indiana camp was a productive one for Daniel Discuss 
After a weekend of individual camps the IU coaching staff began three days of team camp on Monday afternoon. One of the schools that made the trip to Bloomington was Avon (IN) Avon H.S. The Orioles have... My Locations My Categories Change Germany [Europe] Remove Type your City , Country or US State   Home About Niuzer Help&amp;FAQ News Widget World News US Local News Contact Us 
©2009-2012 Niuzer - Terms of Service Privacy FaceBook Twitter
	</body>
</document>
