<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002757" url="http://www.gazette.com/articles/font-100297-style-lingo.html" time="2012-07-12-18:49" support="1" score="0.0002526622467894361" bingtitle="Fountain Police Chief Corsentino resigns | font, style, lingo ..." webtitle="Fountain Police Chief Corsentino resigns | font, style, lingo - Breaking News - Colorado Springs Gazette, CO">
			<query id="001301" bing-rank="173"/>
	<description>Pay Your Bill Online; Vacation Stop; EZpay Program; Purchase ... adds to the legacy of turnover the seat has seen ... spring of 2008 after leaving his gun in a fast-food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Gazette 
 Get Email&amp;Mobile Alerts | Classifieds | Green Edition | Subscribe to Paper 
 
 78° 
 Fair 5-Day Forecast 
 Home Local 
 News Crime&amp;Justice Government Photos Military&gt; 
 SpringsMilitaryLife.com 
 Education&gt; 
 PikesPeakParent.com Graduation 
 Infocenter&gt; 
 Databases Community Links Special News Reports 
 Side Streets Barry Noreen 2012 Vote Nonprofits Traffic Homicide Map Leave a News Tip CSFreshInk.com Around Town Did You Ever Wonder? School Closings 
 Obits 
 Obituaries, Guest Books Submit a Death Notice Place a Paid Obituary 
 Entertainment 
 ColoradoSprings.com Best of the Springs Event Calendar Dining Guide Cinema Guide Around Town TV Listings Travel Books Pets Games Comics Puzzles Horoscopes 
 Life 
 Travel Gardening 
 Sports 
 News David Ramsey Air Force Academy Colorado College Hockey gazettepreps.com&gt; 
 Peak Performers 
 OutThereColorado.com Broncos Olympics Rockies/Sky Sox Where Are They Now? Area Golf Course Guide 
 Business 
 News Local Stocks Local Gas Watch Pikes Peak Shopping Local Home Values Economic Indicators 
 Opinion 
 Views&amp;Letters Guest Columnists Submit a Letter Contact Elected Officials Freedom Politics The Broadside Blog 
 Customer Service 
 Contact Customer Service Subscribe Pay Your Bill Online Vacation Stop EZpay Program Purchase Back Issues Sales Locations Green Edition FAQ Coupons 
 Matress Img Jobs Auto Real Estate 
 
 Don&apos;t Miss: HOW TO DONATE | FIRE COVERAGE | Aerial fire pics | FIRE PHOTOS | FIRE VIDEO | VOTERS GUIDE | LIVE TRAFFIC 
 
 Local 
  &gt;  
 News 
 Font Size 

 

 
Related Stories/Links
 

 
Fountain Police Chief Corsentino resigns
 

 June 16, 2010 11:00 AM | Print Story | E-Mail Story CARLYN RAY MITCHELL THE GAZETTE 
Citing more opportunities and bigger pay in the private sector, Fountain Police Chief Dan Corsentino submitted his resignation to the city manager Tuesday, 16 months after taking the job.

The former longtime Pueblo County sheriff has taken a private security job that will send him all over the nation planning event security and consulting on homeland security. He would not identify the company that hired him.

His last day as police chief, a $95,000-a-year position, will be June 30.

Corsentino said that even if the job had not come up about three weeks ago, he would have considered leaving Fountain because of his increasing frustration with a constrained budget.

“There’s a lot of issues financially with all of us in the recession. For a chief of police, we want to make the biggest impact possible. I wasn’t able to move as quickly as I wanted to,”Corsentino said.

He gave the example of an aging fleet of vehicles and computers that the department needs but the city can’t afford as one of his frustrations.

“I don’t think the frustration was as much of a factor as the ability to enhance my career in the private sector,”Corsentino said.

Corsentino started his law enforcement career with the Pueblo County Sheriff’s Office in 1987, serving four terms as Pueblo County sheriff before leaving office in 2007. He ran unsuccessfully in 2004 for the Republican nomination for the 3rd Congressional District. Before taking the Fountain chief job, Corsentino taught at Colorado State University in Pueblo, served on a Homeland Security National Advisory Board subcommittee and ran a private business, Corsentino Group, in which he advised businesses and churches.

Corsentino admitted that his resignation adds to the legacy of turnover the seat has seen in the past century. The city has had 97 police chiefs in 105 years. Corsentino is the fifth Fountain chief in the past 10 years. Larry Baldonado served as police chief from 1989 to 2000, followed by Dave Moore, John Morse, now a state senator, and Charles Crawford who resigned in Oct. 2008.

Crawford, a veteran Florida lawman, was put on administrative leave in the spring of 2008 after leaving his gun in a fast-food restaurant bathroom.

“(Turnover) destabilizes an organization,”Corsentino said.“The chiefs that are coming in the future will have somewhat of a difficult time.”

Corsentino has been living with his daughter, a Fountain resident, to fulfill the city’s requirement that the chief live in city boundaries. He will now return to living full-time at his home in Pueblo with his wife, he said.

The city will soon begin the process of finding Corsentino’s replacement but has not finalized what that process will look like, Deputy City Manager Dave Smedsrud said.
 
 

 See archived &apos;Local&apos; stories» 
  
 
 Day Lily Salon&amp;Spa 70% OFF - ONLY $30 for a Cut, Partial Highlights and Style at Day Lily Salon&amp;Spa ADVERTISEMENT  Most Viewed 
 SIDE STREETS: Flying W owner ponders future (with video) Peyton Manning buys Denver area mansion for $4.5M BREAKING NEWS: Penn State officials concealed abuse, report says Body&apos;s condition makes identity difficult to discern Velasquez makes explosive new allegations in lawsuit 
 Things to do in the Pikes Peak region 
 
 Events Dining Venues Movies 
 
 Featured Events Event Listings 
 Click for More Events Add Your Events   
 Find an Event 
 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT  Latest Obits 
 Anderson, Anthony R. &quot;Tony&quot; Favela, Patricia Kendall, Dorothy Lee Kostelc, Carolyn A. Floryancic Sipe, Debbie 
 Click here for more Local Business Websites 
 Name: City: SELECT AN AREA ALL Air Force Academy Black Forest/Gleneagle Briargate North Broadmoor/Cheyenne Mountain Colorado Springs Downtown Falcon/Peyton/Calhan/Eastern Plains Fountain/Security/Widefield/Fort Carson Manitou Springs Old Colorado City Other Teller County/Lake George Peterson AFB/COS Airport Powers Corridor Rockrimmon Tri-Lakes Ute Pass Woodland Park 
 Featured Categories 
 Arts&amp;Entertainment Autos Beauty&amp;Wellness Financial Health Care Home Improvement 

 Hotels&amp;Lodging Legal Real Estate Restaurant Shopping View All» 
 Poll National Top Videos 
 » U.S. news 
» Entertainment 
» Business 
» Lifestyle 
» Sports 
» Health 
 powered by
          Search: Web   Site 
 Advertising Info Place An Ad Today&apos;s Ads Place an Announcement Interactive   

 About Us Contact Us Facebook Comments FAQ Contact the Newsroom Advertise Gazette Speakers&apos; Bureau Work For Us Copyright and Reprint Information 

 Subscriber Services Subscriber Services Manage Print Subscription Pay Your Bill Online Vacation Stop Archives Newspaper Ads Buy Our Photos Single Copy Locations 

 Online News Environment The Street Green Edition E-Newsletters/ Alerts RSS Feeds Mobile Article Map AP Terms&amp;Conditions 

 Related Sites Dreamcity2020.org Coloradosprings.com Gazettepreps.com PikesPeakParent.com Best of the Springs FreedomPolitics.com CSFreshink.com OutThereColorado.com SpringsMilitaryLife.com 
 


 Privacy Policy | User Agreement | Site Map 

 Autos | Homes&amp;Real Estate | Jobs | Classifieds | ColoradoSprings.com 

 Local Business Directory | Webmaster 
 
 Freedom Communications, Inc.
	</body>
</document>
