<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002215" url="http://www.yelp.com/biz/in-n-out-burger-santa-rosa" time="2012-07-12-18:07" support="1" score="0.0010529152422588013" bingtitle="In-N-Out Burger - Santa Rosa, CA" webtitle="In-N-Out Burger - Santa Rosa, CA">
			<query id="000710" bing-rank="13"/>
	<description>Bottom line: This is a FAST FOOD restaurant. If greasy, unhealthy food ain&apos;t your cup o&apos; tea, then don&apos;t eat ... They had staff out there helping cars to park and back out ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Search Form Skip to Navigation Skip to Page Content 

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 Log In Sign Up for Yelp Friends&apos; Activity 0 Loading... 
 Yelp is using Facebook to personalize your experience. What is this? Not you?
 Log out of Facebook Don&apos;t want to be connected?
 How to turn this off 
 
 Yelp 
 Real people. Real reviews. ® 
 
 Search for (e.g. taco, cheap dinner, Max&apos;s) 

 Near (Address, City, State or Zip) 
 Search 
 Welcome About Me Write a Review Find Reviews Find Friends Messaging Talk 

 Member Search 
   
In-N-Out Burger
 39 reviews Rating Details 
 Category: Restaurants Burgers Burgers   [Edit] 
 2131 County Ctr Dr 
 Santa Rosa , CA 95403 
 (800) 786-1000 http://www.in-n-out.com 
 
 Add Photos Price Range: $ 
 Accepts Credit Cards: Yes
 Parking: Private Lot
 Attire: Casual
 Good for Groups: Yes
 Good for Kids: Yes
 Takes Reservations: No
 Delivery: No
 Take-out: Yes
 Waiter Service: No
 Outdoor Seating: Yes
 Wi-Fi: No
 Good For: Late Night, Lunch, Dinner
 Alcohol: No
 Drive-Thru: Yes
 Noise Level: Very Loud
 Ambience: Casual
 Has TV: No
 Caters: No
 Wheelchair Accessible: Yes
 First to Review Mike I. 
 Edit Business Info Work Here? Unlock This Business Page 
 Send to Friend Bookmark Send to Phone Write a Review 
39 reviews for In-N-Out Burger
 Reviews Matching: Search Reviews 
Review Highlights  
 
 &quot; Double double animal style your my only friend.&quot; In 2 reviews &quot;Best damn fast food joint ever.&quot; In 8 reviews &quot;...a lot closer instead of having to drive to Rohnert Park .&quot; In 3 reviews 
   Loading... Sort by: Yelp Sort | Date | Rating | Elites&apos; | Facebook Friends&apos; 
Facebook Friends


 
From Reviewers You&apos;re Following 


 
Reviews from Your Friends


 
39 reviews in English

 
Review from Roland F. 
 
 27 friends 73 reviews 

 Roland F. 
 
Petaluma, CA
 6/4/2012 1 Check-in Here 
A much needed addition to Santa Rosa.  Since A&amp;W departed (the REAL A&amp;W, not the KFC/A&amp;W crap), Santa Rosa hasn&apos;t had a decent fast food burger.

This In-N-Out gets considerably more busy than your average fast food (or even In-N-Out), especially around lunch.  The parking lot arrangement doesn&apos;t help.  Orders can take forever, and although it&apos;s not the hardworking employees&apos; fault, it can throw a serious kink in what you hoped would a quick, greasy lunch.  Beyond that, it&apos;s In-N-Out.  It&apos;s cheap, delicious, and Animal-ly.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from John w. 
 
 0 friends 12 reviews 

 John w. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 6/3/2012 
After years of driving to RP to get In n Out I was happy one came to town.

I think the RP one is better (they give you more veggies in your burger and when you as for extra everything it&apos;s exploding with veggies - in SR it&apos;s hard to tell the difference) but it&apos;s still a deliciuos in n out experience.

I think they are better (and better value) than 5 guys and love the toasted bun.

The only downside is that, as expected, having one so close to home has taken some of the specialness out of having an in n out...

On the plus side it&apos;s on the way home from the gym so I can indulge in a protein style burger, have a delicious snack and feel only mildly guilty about it!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Matthew W. 
 
 8 friends 38 reviews 

 Matthew W. 
 
Clearlake, CA
 3/31/2012 
After hearing so much about I-and-Out burger AND getting one in Reno finally (back when I lived there), this was the first of this franchise I have ever tried out, and I have to say it was disappointing compare dot the hype.

While still the best of the fast-food burgers, it still seems sub-par to most any local bar-and-grill location.

Now, don&apos;t take it to mean I dislike this food, I was just hearing so much about how good it was, that it was a large disappointment to finally eat here and taste what seemed like the best of the low-quality burgers (McDonald&apos;s, Burger King, etc).

The establishment was fine enough with clean surfaces and courteous staff. I think the largest thing that would keep me from coming back in the future is how busy it usually is.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Michelle C. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 1377 friends 870 reviews 

 Michelle C. 
 
Philadelphia, PA
 3/25/2012 1 Check-in Here 
In-N-Out is a west coast staple for me, and this was one of my better experiences. Animal-style with cheese and an order of cheese fries were devoured rather quickly.

Head inside to avoid the drive-thru line.
 
 Listed in: The Chain Gang , The Burger List , California Wine Country 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (6) Funny (2) Cool (5) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Murphy O. 
 
 82 friends 304 reviews 

 Murphy O. 
 
San Francisco, CA
 1/14/2012 5 Check-ins Here 
The burgers are good.

But the parking situation sucks here! I always get blocked in by people waiting in the drive through, and that&apos;s WHEN I find a spot.
 
 Listed in: In Pursuit of a Better Burger 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Nick B. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 14 friends 163 reviews 

 Nick B. 
 
Boca Raton, FL
 1/9/2012 
This is your standard In-N-Out.

I went here on a Saturday night and the line of cars in the drive through wrapped around the building; that didn&apos;t matter because I ate inside. My order was ready in under ten minutes, and it tasted just like the delicious In-N-Out I&apos;ve loved as a CA native!

In-N-Out, that&apos;s what hamburgers are all about! (Just not the fries - avoid those, you can get better ones elsewhere. :P).
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Lorenzo L. 
 
 0 friends 5 reviews 

 Lorenzo L. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 5/26/2012 
I&apos;m a total fan of vanilla milk shakes and french fries.  Dipping those fries into that vanilla milk shake makes my day better and I find myself being nicer to other people when I treat myself to this indulgence.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jeremy H. 
 
 2 friends 58 reviews 

 Jeremy H. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 11/10/2011 
This review is for the Santa Rosa one since that&apos;s the one I got dragged to recently. But I&apos;ve been to the one at Fisherman&apos;s Wharf, the one in Rohnert Park, one down in the Peninsula somewhere and one somewhere in Nevada. Exact same experience at all of them.

Look, I understand about regionalism, and nostalgia for chains where you grew up. I&apos;m from western PA and I salivate a little thinking about Eat N&apos; Park, but if I took you there, you&apos;d wonder why I was going off about some marginally-better-than-Denny&apos;s diner chain.

Native Californians, please try and understand that you *may* be overrating In-N-Out just a *bit* due to childhood nostalgia/brainwashing. The burgers are decent, but they aren&apos;t the amazing experience everyone always carps on about them being. The fries are downright below-average, limp and doused in too much salt. The prices are pretty good, and the burgers are good enough that that alone might make the place worth the trip ... if it wasn&apos;t for the constant 2-mile lines in both the restaurant and the drive-thru at every location, every minute that they are open. The food does not even come close to meriting the wait. Anyone who insists that this is a &quot;quality&quot; burger better than something at a sit-down restaurant with steak fries, or even a place like Pearl&apos;s or Five Guys, is legitimately out of their mind.

The vibe if you eat in is also weird. This place makes people act shifty and bizarre. Everyone gives you a Clint Eastwood look when you come in, like you just strolled into the wrong saloon. People eyeball you constantly like you&apos;re gonna try to steal their place in line or swipe their Animal Style right off the table in front of them. Watch where you put your hands when you go to get more napkins or some concealed-carryin&apos; granny might quickdraw on you.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Kevin J. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 1796 friends 683 reviews 

 Kevin J. 
 
San Francisco, CA
 5/31/2011 2 Check-ins Here 
I&apos;d like to know who doesn&apos;t like In-N-Out?  Vegetarian/Vegans don&apos;t coutn.  I&apos;m talking to the meat people.  Whether you&apos;re a health nut (don&apos;t get fries and opt for a bun-less burger with &quot;Protein Style&quot;) or a Quarter pounder freak(grab a &quot;Double Double&quot;, Triple Triple, or whatever number your heart desires) In-N-Out burger will do you right.

Animal style adds mustard, diced grilled onions, and pickles onto your burger or fries(sans pickles/mustard) while grilled cheese sandwiches, protein style burgers and I&apos;m sure others don&apos;t quite make the menu.  Some secrets have to remain, but who says you can&apos;t have it &quot;your way&quot; at this burger joint?

5 Guys who?
 
 Listed in: Burgers-A-Hoolanhan 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (3) Funny (1) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Corey G. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 109 friends 1460 reviews 

 Corey G. 
 
Richland, WA
 5/1/2011 1 Check-in Here 
Can I buy stock in In N Out?  Man, they always have lines warranting traffic control.  City Planners must have a hissy-fit when In N Out announces intentions of opening a space in town.

Do I care?  Heck no.

I just want me a burger, fries, and  a pink lemonade.  I don&apos;t care if I need a sleep air traffic controller to guide my pony to the drive-thru window.

There&apos;s not much to say about the food.  It&apos;s the same deliciousness as with any In N Out experience.  This is one of the northernmost stands on the 101 though.  So if you&apos;re heading northward, it&apos;s your duty to stop on by!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (4) Funny (2) Cool (7) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from kainoa r. 
 
 33 friends 173 reviews 

 kainoa r. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 2/4/2011 ROTD 3/8/2011 
Big fan of the In-N-Out. Love the burgers, the shakes, the sauce, grilled onions, chili peppers, all of it.

Almost all of it.

I can&apos;t get into the fries unless they&apos;re animal style. Not sure if it&apos;s the Kennebunk potatoes they use, or the fact they aren&apos;t double-fried, or that they use vegetable oil...  but something ain&apos;t right. Smack them up and down with sauce and cheese and all is fine. Without? The horror.

Everything else at this location is your standard In-N-Out fare, with one exception. For some reason, they go light on the sauce. And the sauce? I like it. I want it. I NEED it. Not on every burger everywhere, but if I&apos;m there... I gots to have me some. So don&apos;t go skimping my sauce.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (3) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Hasan T. 
 
 1 friend 59 reviews 

 Hasan T. 
 
Rohnert Park, CA
 4/28/2011 
Honestly, I don&apos;t really see the purpose of reviewing In-N-Out. If you&apos;re from California, and you don&apos;t currently live under a rock, then you pretty much should know what you&apos;re getting. Ah screw it...

I&apos;ll say this about In-N-Out. It is without a doubt, the best fast food restaurant around. The food is fresh (which by itself puts it above most of its brethren), and the service is always top notch. The location of this particular In-N-Out is terrible, though. I don&apos;t know what they were thinking...

Bottom line: This is a FAST FOOD restaurant. If greasy, unhealthy food ain&apos;t your cup o&apos; tea, then don&apos;t eat here. If you&apos;ve got a hankering for a quick, filling burger and some fries then give &apos;em a shot.

P.S: The best time to go is at night, when the line isn&apos;t halfway to Windsor. When it&apos;s midnight and you&apos;ve just got done enjoying you&apos;re favorite, ahem &quot;herbal remedy&quot;, there&apos;s nothing like a double-double to vanquish your munchies.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jenn H. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 22 friends 39 reviews 

 Jenn H. 
 
Dunedin, FL
 12/30/2011 
Best fast food burger and menu(s) EVER! Nom nom nom!! Double double protein animal style! =)
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from alice k. 
 
 7 friends 14 reviews 

 alice k. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 12/14/2010 
This location forgot one of my burgers that I paid for through the Drive-Thru a couple of weeks ago.

It hurt my feelings. And I had to pretend I wasn&apos;t hungry and let someone else eat mine. I live 20 mins away from Santa Rosa, but in-n-out is seriously the only drive-thru place closest to me that is open past midnight. And I did not feel like driving back and waiting in the HUGE line to see if they would give it to me or not. I&apos;ve learned to check my bags, though I do grudgingly point out this has never happened in Rohnert Park.

Well.. I&apos;ve forgiven you. Just don&apos;t let it happen again please.
Because I do love your animal-style fries like crazy.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (2) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Susan L. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 100 friends 434 reviews 

 Susan L. 
 
San Jose, CA
 11/7/2011 
Drove all the way to Santa Rosa for InNout. Just kidding! It was a mini detour on the way back from OR/WA and I was having huge cravings for their burgers. Believe it or not, there&apos;s not that many on the way back to NorCal. It was this or eating in downtown Santa Rosa again and I can&apos;t believe I chose fast food!  Sure hit the spot...
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Wally W. 
 
 49 friends 353 reviews 

 Wally W. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 10/29/2010 1 photo 16 Check-ins Here 
Awesome stuff!

I can&apos;t wait until the lines die down, though.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (2) Funny (1) Cool (2) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Mark B. 
 
 4 friends 24 reviews 

 Mark B. 
 
San Francisco, CA
 12/12/2011 2 Check-ins Here 
I&apos;m happy to say that the SR In-n-Out crew has really gotten their act together over the last several months. Once green, they have taken the initiative and brought one of the chain&apos;s newest locations up to brand standard. Fantastic work indeed.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Sheri M. 
 
 11 friends 84 reviews 

 Sheri M. 
 
East Boston, MA
 11/5/2010 
My favorite fast food joint, now only 5 minutes away! We were in Europe during the grand opening and went for some grub the day we returned... after flying over 12 hours, and getting stuck in the damn Giants parade trying to catch the bus home. Needless to say, we were ravenous. The food was amazing as usual (I had a 3x3 for the first time). I would have been forgiving if they had messed up somehow, but they didn&apos;t! But there was one thing that irked me...

I&apos;m not sure what the designers were smoking when they planned it, but the drive-thru set-up sucks. The queue runs right through the parking lot. What the hell?! They had staff out there helping cars to park and back out, but I doubt they&apos;ll have them out there permanently. This is the first In-N-Out I&apos;ve been to that doesn&apos;t have a dedicated area for cars to queue up. I smell a potential disaster.
 
 Listed in: SoCo under $10 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (2) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Michael j. R. 
 
 4 friends 24 reviews 

 Michael j. R. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 1/16/2012 1 Check-in Here 
Luv It...Double Animal Style...
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Tom M. 
 
 Elite &apos;12 81 friends 226 reviews 

 Tom M. 
 
Glenside, PA
 9/17/2011 1 photo 
Great like all other In-N-Outs. One word of caution: older GPS units will not find it. Ask for directions at your hotel like I did if your GPS was not bought yesterday.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Adam K. 
 
 0 friends 3 reviews 

 Adam K. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 10/22/2011 
Thank God for Harry Snyder and for Having In-N-Out in west coast
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Nikki W. 
 
 38 friends 234 reviews 

 Nikki W. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 6/20/2011 
We are at 3 stars here because we all know the food is Delicious and you can count on it to be the same everywhere, what you can&apos;t count on is parking/time to order. This place has the most ridiculous parking and &quot;waiting in line for the drive up&quot; that I&apos;ve ever seen. Sooo poorly designed! You are waiting with your car hanging out in the street, the drive through spits you out where the other cars are trying to come in, it is a total mess- it really deters me. I&apos;d rather drive to petaluma then this location. Sorry In and Out but you should have hired a better engineer to make this run smoothly, for now it really bites!
 
 Listed in: Burgers 
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Heather J. 
 
 9 friends 31 reviews 

 Heather J. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 5/19/2011 1 Check-in Here 
Best damn fast food joint ever. Enough said.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jim T. 
 
 8 friends 107 reviews 

 Jim T. 
 
GEYSERVILLE, CA
 4/26/2011 
Pretty much a &quot;what are they thinking&quot; experience when you eat here.  There must be 50 places nearby with better burgers---it&apos;s like getting excited about a Big Mac---BLECH !!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ron m. 
 
 7 friends 75 reviews 

 Ron m. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 12/22/2010 
The grilled cheese with onion is great . The reason in-n-out gets 3 star from me ....first off- fast food is not worthy of 4 , and secondly the fries here don&apos;t taste good . I prefer frozen fries with lots of grease on them like McD or BK . this place is doing very well for fast food and has received my highest rating for fast food of 3 star .
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Tracey R. 
 
 1 friend 13 reviews 

 Tracey R. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 7/29/2011 
This place is fantastic. Incredibly fresh food, simple menu that accommodates gluten free very well. (Double-double protein style!) Very reasonable prices. Fresh potatoes in the fries, watch them cut them in front of you! Beef from their own source too, not the giant, nasty, mega slaughter bin the other chains use. They treat their employees well too.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Tom B. 
 
 41 friends 17 reviews 

 Tom B. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 4/22/2011 
I don&apos;t understand why this place is so popular. They have a mediocre burger and a long wait to get it. I will say the staff is extremely courteous and attentive to their customers and their specific job assignment, but in the end, isn&apos;t it all about the burger?
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Valerie S. 
 
 0 friends 11 reviews 

 Valerie S. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 10/31/2010 
I was disappointed after hearing  so much hype. The burger was fresh tasting and seemed less calorie laden than other burgers, but next time I&apos;ll order the double, because the meat patty was so thin.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (1) Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from rich m. 
 
 16 friends 71 reviews 

 rich m. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 2/22/2011 4 Check-ins Here 
A nice new restaurant.  Friendly staff and great food.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Reed P. 
 
 1 friend 21 reviews 

 Reed P. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 Updated - 5/12/2011 
three good burgers in a row...and very good service too.

floor was pretty dirty, though.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
2 Previous Reviews: Show all» 

 12/6/2010 
second time here was not as good.

my dubl-dubl must&apos;ve been handled a bit heavily because the bun was… Read more» 
 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Rhita B. 
 
 18 friends 25 reviews 

 Rhita B. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 3/3/2011 1 Check-in Here 
who doesn&apos;t love the neopolitan shake! AND if you are celiac, order the flying dutchman!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Jena D. 
 
 4 friends 41 reviews 

 Jena D. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 3/1/2011 
wow- so clean, great service, food was so yummy! Tasted like  fresh burgers&amp;fries from a nice restuarant! Go inside, waited maybe 5 minutes. Sweet deal!!! 10 bucks 2  burgers, 2 shakes&amp;fries!
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Mike I. 
 
 15 friends 217 reviews 

 Mike I. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 10/26/2010 
The same In-N-Out burgers you already know and love. Now, right here in town. What&apos;s not to love?
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Dan N. 
 
 4 friends 92 reviews 

 Dan N. 
 
San Antonio, TX
 11/7/2010 
Food is still the same awesome quality and price and the best part is it&apos;s a lot closer instead of having to drive to Rohnert Park. Naturally the lines are extremely long, could it be because its only been open for a little over a week? Nah! LOL
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from amanda l. 
 
 2 friends 10 reviews 

 amanda l. 
 
Forestville, CA
 5/4/2011 
if only all fast food was this good!! they dont mess around. fresh lettuce and tomatoes on top of real beef, never frozen. their walls and uniforms are imaculet white, fit for surgery if you ask me. you can see them prepare your food fresh through the big stretch windows. they got nothing to hide. service was excellent. you can tell these people are proud to be a part of such a wonderful place. for their best burger ask for it animal style (its not on the menu). aside from here i dont touch fast food.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Pixie D. 
 
 4 friends 17 reviews 

 Pixie D. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 11/22/2010 
Why is there so much hype about this chain? It sucked! First, hubby got the burger, although I don&apos;t know why he&apos;d take his life in his hands by eating that, but he said he has gotten better burgers at McDonalds and Burger King, and this one made Wendy&apos;s burgers seem gourmet. And I don&apos;t know why someone yelped that here they don&apos;t use &quot;wonder bread style&quot; buns, because they absolutely were just as gummy and disgusting as wonder bread. The cashier was really dumb. First he told me I could get a bun with lettuce&amp;tomato, but they don&apos;t have veggie burgers, or I could get  &quot;grilled cheese,&quot; which is really a cheeseburger with no burger - nothing grilled about it. But when I found out that the kind with just cheese costs MORE than a hamburger (!??!), he said I could get a veggie burger for $1.30. So I said how do I change my order and get my money back for the difference between a veggie burger and a &quot;grilled cheese.&quot; Of course he didn&apos;t know, but when a &quot;manager&quot; finally came over, he reiterated that there was NO veggie burger, just a nothing sandwich. So of course I kept the cheese, and it sucked. This was after I had to repeat my order half a dozen times because he kept saying he only rang up one cheeseburger. When I could not get through to him (having repeated my order of one cheeseburger and one &quot;grilled cheese&quot; a few times already!), and finally said excuse me, I was sure you said I could order one with just cheese, the other two cashiers burst out laughing. I don&apos;t even know if they were dissing me or him, but even a dimwit should have been able to ring up that order properly. And he forgot it was not to go - although who would get out of their car in the rain when they could use the drive-through if they actually wanted it to go? This place does not foster common sense! Btw, why do they say they have good fries? There is such high turnover in this place they should have been freshly made and hot, but they weren&apos;t! I do think the fries may have been cut from real potatoes, as I heard they were, because I could see several black, rotten spots that they had not taken the care to pick out. Disgusting, and so disrespectful to the customers!!! P.S. the decor was very generic and cheaper than typical McDonalds.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny (2) Cool (1) 
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from ROBERT H. 
 
 0 friends 8 reviews 

 ROBERT H. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 12/23/2010 
at this in  n&apos; out,  the drive through entrance must be approached from the southbound lane of county center drive, as there is a center island. i came from steele lane
and took the first entrance to then loop around into the drive through lane. about 3 cars in front of me did the same thing. well they had this guy telling people not to come in this way. so i when he talked to me , i explained to him this is a situational inconvenience. he became agitated and lectured me about next time i come to pull in the other way, wow.  so it&apos;s bad enough that it&apos;s poorly designed and if you have to go out of your way to go there but i never made it in without in n&apos; out employee&apos;s confronting me. i turned around and left. i will never return.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful (1) Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Ham B. 
 
 12 friends 4 reviews 

 Ham B. 
 
Sonoma, CA
 5/30/2011 
Double double animal style your my only friend! : ) though I love the burgers I think the fries need work.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
Review from Gavin L. 
 
 0 friends 3 reviews 

 Gavin L. 
 
Santa Rosa, CA
 2/1/2011 
I&apos;ve been a loyal fan of double -double animal style for at least 10 years. Burgers are always outstanding but on this visit my fries were only OK. I would return more often if the drive through didn&apos;t take the fast out of fast food. Perhaps I shouldn&apos;t go there at 12:30 lunch rush.
 
Was this review…?

 Useful   Funny   Cool   
 
 Add owner comment Bookmark    Send to a Friend Link to This Review 
 
 ( 8 Filtered )  
 
 Write a Review View Larger Map/Directions 
Browse Nearby:
 
 Restaurants | Nightlife | Shopping | Movies | All 
 
Deals Nearby
 
 $40 for $75 Deal Sizzling Tandoor Santa Rosa, CA $15 for $20 Deal Betty&apos;s English Fish &apos;n&apos; Chips Santa Rosa, CA 
 
People Who Viewed This Also Viewed...
 
 In-N-Out Burger  75 reviews &quot;Animal Style is probably the best.&quot; Five Guys Burgers and Fries  98 reviews &quot;Kicks In n Out in the Double Double if you get my drift.&quot; In-N-Out  43 reviews &quot;oh and don&apos;t forget to get your burger animal style.&quot; Foster Freeze  12 reviews &quot;...walking there to get chocolate dipped cones in the summer...&quot; Superburger  103 reviews &quot;the onion rings are really good too.&quot; 
 
Related Lists
 More» 
 Burgers-A-Hoolanhan 
Only the best of the best beef (or non-beef) around.  Check em out and see how they rate to you.
 Best Burger Joint for a Burger (not… 
Best Places to go for a Burger if you&apos;re intention is just to eat a good Burger and you don&apos;t care who else is…
 
 
People Viewed This After Searching For...
 
 Restaurant Santa Rosa 
 
About

 About Yelp Yelp Blog Press Investor Relations Terms of Service Privacy Policy 
 
Help

 FAQ Advertise Content Guidelines Contact Yelp Business Support Developers 
 
More

 Careers Yelp Mobile The Weekly Yelp Yelp Apparel RSS Top Searches 
 
Countries

 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany 

 Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom 
 
Language

 English 
 
 Dansk (Danmark) 
 
 Deutsch (Deutschland) Deutsch (Schweiz) Deutsch (Österreich) 
 
 English (Australia) English (Belgium) English (Canada) English (Republic of Ireland) English (Switzerland) English (United Kingdom) English (United States) 
 
 Español (España) 
 
 Français (Belgique) Français (Canada) Français (France) Français (Suisse) 
 
 Italiano (Italia) Italiano (Svizzera) 
 
 Nederlands (België) Nederlands (Nederland) 
 
 Norsk Bokmål (Norge) 
 
 Suomi (Suomi) 
 
 Svenska (Finland) Svenska (Sverige) 
 
 
 
 Santa Rosa Business Listings # A B C D E F G H I J K L M N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z | Newly Added | Talk Archive 

 Site Map | Atlanta | Austin | Boston | Chicago | Dallas | Denver | Detroit | Honolulu | Houston | Los Angeles | Miami | Minneapolis | New York | Philadelphia | Portland | Sacramento | San Diego | San Francisco | San Jose | Seattle | Washington, DC | More Cities 

Copyright©2004-2012 Yelp Inc. Yelp logo and related marks are registered trademarks of Yelp. All rights reserved.
 
 Email Address Step 1 of 2 Zip Code 
 
Hey , you can use Facebook to make signing up for Yelp even faster . Yes, use Facebook to sign up 
 Already have an account? Log In Now 
 Email Address Password Zip Code Birthdate (Optional) --- Jan Feb Mar Apr May Jun Jul Aug Sep Oct Nov Dec --- 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 --- 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 2000 1999 1998 1997 1996 1995 1994 1993 1992 1991 1990 1989 1988 1987 1986 1985 1984 1983 1982 1981 1980 1979 1978 1977 1976 1975 1974 1973 1972 1971 1970 1969 1968 1967 1966 1965 1964 1963 1962 1961 1960 1959 1958 1957 1956 1955 1954 1953 1952 1951 1950 1949 1948 1947 1946 1945 1944 1943 1942 1941 1940 1939 1938 1937 1936 1935 1934 1933 1932 1931 1930 1929 1928 1927 1926 1925 1924 1923 1922 1921 1920 1919 1918 1917 1916 1915 1914 1913 1912 1911 1910 1909 1908 1907 1906 1905 1904 1903 1902 1901 Country 
 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom United States 
 
 United States Change 
 
By clicking the button below, you agree to the Yelp Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .
 
 
 Cancel Sign Up 
 
 Use Facebook to sign up faster! 
 Already have an account? Log In Now 
 First Name Last Name Email Address Password City / Town: Zip Code Birthdate (Optional) --- Jan Feb Mar Apr May Jun Jul Aug Sep Oct Nov Dec --- 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31 --- 2012 2011 2010 2009 2008 2007 2006 2005 2004 2003 2002 2001 2000 1999 1998 1997 1996 1995 1994 1993 1992 1991 1990 1989 1988 1987 1986 1985 1984 1983 1982 1981 1980 1979 1978 1977 1976 1975 1974 1973 1972 1971 1970 1969 1968 1967 1966 1965 1964 1963 1962 1961 1960 1959 1958 1957 1956 1955 1954 1953 1952 1951 1950 1949 1948 1947 1946 1945 1944 1943 1942 1941 1940 1939 1938 1937 1936 1935 1934 1933 1932 1931 1930 1929 1928 1927 1926 1925 1924 1923 1922 1921 1920 1919 1918 1917 1916 1915 1914 1913 1912 1911 1910 1909 1908 1907 1906 1905 1904 1903 1902 1901 Gender (Optional) Male Female Country 
 Australia Austria Belgium Canada Denmark Finland France Germany Ireland Italy Norway Spain Sweden Switzerland The Netherlands United Kingdom United States 
 
 United States Change 
 
By clicking the button below, you agree to the Yelp Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .
 
 
 Cancel Sign Up 
 No account yet? Create an Account 
 Email Password 
 
 Cancel Log In 
 
Add a Profile Picture

More people will read your reviews and you will be one step closer to the Yelp Elite Squad if you have a profile picture.
 Import Facebook Photo You don&apos;t have Flash installed, Facebook Connect requires the latest version of Flash
	</body>
</document>
