<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002051" url="http://caloriecount.about.com/protein-bars-love-hate-relationship-b548298" time="2012-07-12-17:57" support="6" score="0.00893905373731684" bingtitle="Protein Bars: A Love Hate Relationship" webtitle="Protein Bars: A Love Hate Relationship">
			<query id="001130" bing-rank="218"/>
			<query id="001318" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="000190" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000752" bing-rank="246"/>
			<query id="000502" bing-rank="244"/>
			<query id="000211" bing-rank="202"/>
	<description>1/2 cup water or coffee if you want more of an ... I also track my food daily and rarely get enough ... than skip dinner altogether, or stop at a fast food restaurant on ...</description>
	<body>
		-- Calorie Camp Logging Community Foods Exercise Tools Advice Blog 
 FOODS ACTIVITIES RECIPES FORUMS ASK MARY GROUPS FOODS   
 Blog Home Tips&amp;Updates Dieting&amp;You Success Stories Recipes Healthy Eating 
 Existing users: Log in 
 
 Subscribe Expand Browser 
 x 

 
 Receive updates by email 
 Your name: Email address: 
   
 

 Blog: Healthy Eating Blog &gt; Healthy Eating &gt;Protein Bars: A Love Hate Relationship 
 Archive Categories 

 Tips&amp;Updates Dieting&amp;You Success Stories Recipes Healthy Eating Site Highlights 
 Archive Dates 

 July 2012 (25) June 2012 (58) May 2012 (73) April 2012 (53) more... 
 Newsletters 

 July 12th, 2012 July 11th, 2012 July 10th, 2012 July 9th, 2012 more... 
 
 
 « Experts Reveal: Small Diet Changes for Weight Loss (Part 1)   Experts Reveal: Small Diet Changes for Weight Loss (Part 2) » 
 

 
Send Email
 

 Your Name* *Required Your Email* Friends&apos; Emails* 
 (Enter emails seperated by commas) Message I found this article on Calorie Count and thought that you might be interested. 144 characters left 
 
 
 
Protein Bars: A Love Hate Relationship
 
 By carolyn_r on Jan 11, 2012 10:00 AM in Healthy Eating 
 
It used to be that food in small rectangular form was called candy and relegated to a section next to the checkout line in the grocery store. Not so these days. There’s a whole aisle of bars now, but they aren’t the Snickers or Crunch bars you’re used to, we’re talking protein bars, also called energy, nutrition, cereal - well you get the point. These are the fast food items of the health and fitness industry. Touted as good on-the-go snacks or post-workout meals, protein bars are perceived by many as part of a healthy lifestyle. But are they any better than candy bars in the way of nutrition?

 What We Don&apos;t Love

 According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), most Americans get more than the recommended amounts of protein daily. So if you don’t need the additional protein, what do you get? Protein bars are generally around 150 to 250 calories of sugar, fiber and whey or soy protein. It&apos;s not ideal that you’d be replacing a hearty snack of fresh fruits and vegetables and nuts with a processed food. Yes, there are some that are minimally processed, but for the additional price, consider if you could’ve gone for a small well-balanced meal instead. Another not so good thing about many protein bars is their use of sweeteners. Whether it’s listed as brown rice syrup, agave nectar, evaporated cane juice, high fructose corn syrup or sugar alcohols, it’s still an added sweetener.

 What We Love

 If you’re a newbie to eating healthy and you need an alternative to eating a candy bar, protein bars are generally a better option. We love those with a short ingredient list of dried fruit, nuts, and oats as they are a good source of fiber and can stave off hunger between meals when compared to their candy cousins. A study found that replacing a high fat, high carbohydrate candy bar, with a high fiber, high protein bar could reduce food intake in subsequent meals. Just remember the resulting difference in lower glucose peaks and more stable insulin levels holds for any meal that replaces refined sugars with more fiber and protein. Be sure not to replace meals with a protein bar because of the lack of vegetables in many of them, and remember if you’re sedentary or don’t workout hard everyday, protein bars may end up as extra calories. 

 The Convenience Issue

 For those of you who opt for protein bars out of convenience, use an extra 30 minutes a week to cut up fresh fruit and vegetables and separate nuts and seeds into single serving baggies for snacks. Many protein bars that have good nutritional value run upwards of $3-4 dollars. If you just can’t see a way around eating them, consider making your own or creating your own trail mix. That way you know exactly what’s in it, and you save the extra dollars that’s spent on pictures of muscular men doing pushups and really nice packaging. An added bonus: you’re not stuck in that darn energy bar aisle, where you feel obligated to read the ingredients of each one to make the healthiest choice. If ever you feel trapped, make a beeline for the produce section - no nutrition label reading required.


 Your thoughts... 

 If you eat protein bars, when do you eat them and how many calories do they account for in your day? 
 
 Tags: energy bars , protein bars , cereal bars , nutrition bars , healthy snacks 
 
Comments
 ( last ) 
 
 cazir - Jan 11, 2012 11:19 AM New Comment 
 
I&apos;m a protien bar fan - I tend to have one a day and as I have a sweet tooth it prevents my craving for chocolate. I also find that they are very filling and I often do not need lunch after eating one. So I&apos;d rate them pretty highly!
 

 
 cornejansenvanvuren - Jan 11, 2012 11:50 AM New Comment 
 cornejansenvanvuren 
I LOVE Maxilean high protein bar or USN protein bar.

I found it a great support since i am on a high protein diet,
and its way better than your average chocolates.



Its also great if you exercise with weights.
 

 
 misslavey - Jan 11, 2012 11:56 AM New Comment 
 
I&apos;ve kept a food log since the beginning of the year and realized that I don&apos;t get nearly as much protein as I thought I did, so it&apos;s not exactly true that everyone gets enough protein in their diet. It&apos;s easier for me to carry a protein bar in my purse to have as a lunch at school rather than a bag of fruit that&apos;s been rotting since morning.
 

 
 ttommyunger - Jan 11, 2012 11:57 AM New Comment 
 
Considering I work out seven days a week (including pull-ups, sit-ups and push-ups) at home and twice a week at the gym (for 3.5 hours each) I consider myself an active male. I incorporated Clif Bars into my daily diet about a year ago. I&apos;ve gone from 185 to under l65 (my weight at discharge from the Army at age 21, in l962). I consider them a &quot;meal&quot; rather than a snack, due to their high calorie content. I eat a &quot;Body&quot; Bar at mid-day and either a &quot;Mojo&quot; Trail Mix Bar or a regular Clif Bar late afternoon. You don&apos;t want to know the rest of my diet, it is too depressing, but it works for me. ;)
 

 
 coachtod - Jan 11, 2012 12:26 PM New Comment 
 coachtod 
P90X protein bars have been one of my go to snack in my 100 lb weight loss. I usually have them as snack or a portion of a small meal with fruit when I&apos;m on the go.
 

 
 coffeetx - Jan 11, 2012 12:48 PM New Comment 
 
I found Quest bars to be the only ones that are both high fiber, low carb and high protein. Plus they are all natural ingredients. I have to special order them b/c you can&apos;t find them in the stores.
 

 
 33abol - Jan 11, 2012 12:52 PM New Comment 
 
I try to get 5-6 servings of food a day and having a protein bar at times fills one of those spots. I try to stay away from them as they are processed and don&apos;t really count as a meal, but in a pinch, better to have one than go without. It ends up I have one or two a week depending on family activities.

 
 

 
 sllverchild - Jan 11, 2012 01:23 PM New Comment 
 
About a year ago, I found a really simple protein bar recipe that doesn&apos;t cost a whole lot to make (one of the downfalls of protein bars for me is how expensive they are). Nutritionally Luna Bars aren&apos;t that bad but as someone on a low sugar/ high protein diet, I definitely prefer to make my own.

For six bars I blend:

1/2 cup lowfat cottage cheese

1 cup quick oats

4 scoops protein powder- vanilla or chocolate

five packets of stevia

1/2 cup water or coffee if you want more of an espresso taste

2 TBS Flax Meal

Pour the batter in a greased 8X8 glass pyrex and bake for 15-20 minutes.

Each bar has about 170 calories, 4 grams of fat. 21 grams of protein, 3 grams of fiber, 14 grams of carbohydrates and only 2 grams of sugar.

These aren&apos;t going to taste nearly as candy-bar like as the store brand, but they&apos;re more suited for me nutritionally and financially.
 

 
 tsultrim - Jan 11, 2012 01:25 PM New Comment 
 
As an active person, and a vegan, I rely on Clif Bars (Clif and Clif Mojo) and Vega Whole Food Vibrancy bars, consuming several bars daily. Both are all natural and mostly or completely organic. After a vigorous work-out one does need replenish stores of glycogen in the muscles (by consuming carbohydrate), and muscles need protein to rebuild. That&apos;s what the energy bars offer, in palatable form. Their durable and compact packaging works well. The Clif bars, purchased at &quot;case lot&quot; prices from a discounter, aren&apos;t particularly expensive. 
 

 
 tdirpincess - Jan 11, 2012 01:41 PM New Comment 
 Tdiprincess 
My favorite bars are Element bars and Larabars. Once in a while I&apos;ll eat a Clif bar, but I honestly don&apos;t really like them.

If I&apos;m at a convenience store and super hungry I&apos;ll see if they have any fruit and some nuts before grabbing protein bars.

The ones I do eat are basically a treat or when I&apos;m super hungry and need something completely on the go.
 

 
 andijomom94 - Jan 11, 2012 01:53 PM New Comment 
 
I enjoy protein bars before I exercise. I can&apos;t exercise on a full stomach, but I don&apos;t have energy if I exercise on an empty stomach. A protein bar 30 min before workout is perfect. On days when I take a long run, I eat one when I&apos;m finished. They account for less than 200 calories in my daily diet, and are only consumed about 3 times a week. I, too, prefer a banana or apple for a quick fix.
 

 
 edie1109 - Jan 11, 2012 02:06 PM New Comment 
 Edi 62 yrs young - no dust gathers on me 
The oven temp is ? Does the protein powder have gluten, usually?
 

 
 rachelwert - Jan 11, 2012 02:32 PM New Comment 
 Rachelwert 
I&apos;m not much of a protein bar eater. I used to try to find really high protein bars because I figured I wasn&apos;t getting enough protein since I don&apos;t eat much meat. Come to find out that consuming protein for 30% or more of your diet causes a buildup of ketones that are difficult for your kidneys to process and doing so can also lead to dehydration. Now if I&apos;m in a huge rush and have nothing else to grab, I&apos;ll eat a protein bar. But usually I opt for a yogurt or portable fruits and veggies instead.
 

 
 __katie__ - Jan 11, 2012 02:38 PM New Comment 
 Don&apos;t get me wrong, I love protein bars- they are quick, convenient, and better for you than a candy bar. I use them as a meal replacement when too fatigued to make a meal. Here&apos;s the but.... They set me up behaviorally to reinforce instant gratification to my emotional eating. I have an emotional eating disorder and protein bars are one of my trigger foods/ go-to foods. I also have chronic fatigue syndrome and fibromyalgia - those conditions give me a good excuse to grab a bar instead of make a meal but.... they aren&apos;t a good enough excuse to keep enabling my sweet tooth or feeding myself a well balanced diet.
Bad choice in general for me behaviorally, emotionally, and physically.....even though I love them. They have a double edged sword all the way around. 

 
 fatboog - Jan 11, 2012 02:39 PM New Comment 
 I&apos;d stay away from those lara and clif bars. Those are mostly designer bars for the hip crowd, which means they&apos;re little more then snickers in a different packaging. Protein bars were built for those mister universe types who had hit the wall and needed to build a bridge in their nutrional gaps. A 200 lb body builder needs 400 grams of protein a day. Whey and creatin just doesn&apos;t cut it after a while. If you need a snack, try a boil egg or some almonds or even an apple. If you must have a protein bar, get away from the grocery aisles and try gnc to start. Meso tech is a basic choice and you can go from there. 

 
 fatboog - Jan 11, 2012 02:46 PM New Comment 
 Also, forgot to add. If you are trying to do that weight lifting thing or just taking in more protein bars, you&apos;ll need alot of water. And stay away from soda and juice. Most bars have enough sugar as it is and a glass of oj will mess you up. The liver and kidneys can start to fail with too much protein and other supplaments so you&apos;ll need a lot of water rinsing through them. 

 
 artdeptsecretary - Jan 11, 2012 02:55 PM New Comment 
 
I love CLIF Bars, especially the oatmeal raisin walnut. I eat one every day for breakfast with a cup of coffee.

This is not labeled a protein bar but an energy bar . This particular bar has 240 calories, 5 g of fat, 43g carbs, 5 g dietary fiber, and 10 g of protein.

The CLIF Bar keeps me full for at least 4-5 hours. I find when I eat a bowl of oatmeal I get hungry in less than 3 hours.

I will continue to eat them!

 

 
 

 
 __katie__ - Jan 11, 2012 03:06 PM New Comment 
 Good point Fatboog!! 
It&apos;s essential to replace fluids with bar consumption since it sucks the fluids out of you. I was in the dr&apos;s office this week for abnormal renal functions found in my blood work -all due to dehydration. Not enough fluid intake in ratio to coffee consumption was my issue. 

 
 iulizbug - Jan 11, 2012 03:15 PM New Comment 
 
I eat the Optimal Diet Protien bars that I buy at Mass Nutrition or GNC. They are very low carb and high protein, fairly-low calorie but fill me up for awhile and tase &quot;ok&quot;. Not near as tasty as regular protein bars but they shouldn&apos;t be--they aren&apos;t packed with sugar like the others. I have lost almost 90 lbs in just over 5 months using them daily with my exercise and diet regimen.
 

 
 nyxiefly - Jan 11, 2012 03:18 PM New Comment 
 nyxiefly 
I have found that Luna Bars are a great alternative to candy bars! And for several reasons too!
1. They have less sugar.
2. 8 to 9 grams of protein depending on what bar you get.
3. Less then 200 calories.
4. Low glycemic index (digests slower and keeps you full longer).
5. 3 grams of fiber.
6. Taste flipping awesome! :D
7. One bar runs around the same price as a candy bar.
 

 
 carik1945 - Jan 11, 2012 03:20 PM New Comment 
 
I bought a slew of these bars at Costco--nature valley almond granola bar or something like that. I thought they were delicious and I put them in my backpack for emergencies. Well, now the date has expired, and I am sick of them. I like your idea of just bagging up nuts and dried fruit to have on hand for emergency hunger situations, when you are on a train and can&apos;t get lunch. I won&apos;t buy these again. They really are like candy bars, actually.
 

 
 brity235 - Jan 11, 2012 03:24 PM New Comment 
 
So often I read that Americans consume too much protein, but I&apos;d really like to know the study that came to this conclusion. Over a year of keeping track of my diet showed that just about every day was a struggle to get enough protein, and I&apos;m not a vegetarian; I could probably count the days on one hand where I actually got &quot;too much&quot; protein, and even then, it wasn&apos;t an obscene amount by any means. 

Now I might be generalizing, but I would hypothesize that American women (trying to eat a balanced diet, like myself) don&apos;t overdo the protein, and there&apos;s probably even a sizeable percentage that would qualify as deficient.
 

 
 brity235 - Jan 11, 2012 03:25 PM New Comment 
 
And I probably do eat a high protein bar once a day to reach my recommended amount of protein.
 

 
 smithteamracing - Jan 11, 2012 03:27 PM New Comment 
 smithteamracing L love Luna Bars&amp;Mojo Bars. Working 12 hr shifts they really help. You can&apos;t replace fresh fruit&amp;veggies with them but I think they a much better snack than a candy bar. But I will be careful to drink more fluids with them, probably ice tea. 

 
 spunkoney - Jan 11, 2012 03:30 PM New Comment 
 Sarah 
I&apos;m doing the P90X high protein, low carb diet, so the extra protein I get from a bar is important to rebuilding my muscles. My bar of choice is Premeir Nutrition High Protein, mostly for the convenience of buying in bulk at Costco. I eat one, every other day. Since each bar is almost 300 calories, I eat half for my morning snack at 10, and then eat the second half for my afternoon snack at 3. It&apos;s a great boost on the days I lift with P90X.
 

 
 tammyspies - Jan 11, 2012 03:49 PM New Comment 
 Tammy Wanting to get back to my 20year size Original Post by: sllverchild 


About a year ago, I found a really simple protein bar recipe that doesn&apos;t cost a whole lot to make (one of the downfalls of protein bars for me is how expensive they are). Nutritionally Luna Bars aren&apos;t that bad but as someone on a low sugar/ high protein diet, I definitely prefer to make my own.

For six bars I blend:

1/2 cup lowfat cottage cheese

1 cup quick oats

4 scoops protein powder- vanilla or chocolate

five packets of stevia

1/2 cup water or coffee if you want more of an espresso taste

2 TBS Flax Meal

Pour the batter in a greased 8X8 glass pyrex and bake for 15-20 minutes.

Each bar has about 170 calories, 4 grams of fat. 21 grams of protein, 3 grams of fiber, 14 grams of carbohydrates and only 2 grams of sugar.

These aren&apos;t going to taste nearly as candy-bar like as the store brand, but they&apos;re more suited for me nutritionally and financially.
 

You could add coco powder to this recipe to give it a chocolaty flavour. It would take much.
 

 
 carik1945 - Jan 11, 2012 03:53 PM New Comment 
 
I am with the person who said &quot;who said americans get too much protein&quot; I belong to Sparkpeople.com and I have been tracking what I eat. They give you a report at the end of the day, and I never get enough protein. 
 

 
 1bigfatgirl - Jan 11, 2012 03:56 PM New Comment 
 1bigfatgirl 
If you have sugar cravings after meals, I highly recommend (as an alternative to an entire protein bar) having a Viactiv chocolate (or caramel) chew instead! You can freeze them so they last longer. They have a very good chocolatey taste, and are calcium! Very good for women. I keep them in my desk as my office has a candy bowl at the front so instead of getting the Hershey&apos;s kisses after lunch, I work on a couple of these. Give it a try.
 

 
 zdietrich - Jan 11, 2012 04:04 PM New Comment 
 
I like to find protein bars that are low in carbs and high in protein. I think this helps keep me full longer and is an added benefit. &quot;OhYeah&quot; makes different sized bars. I choose the smaller ones and keep one with me at all times. So I have one in my lunch box, one in my school bag and one in my gym bag. That way whenever I miss a meal, or the appropriate time for that meal, I have the bar to eat instead of doing what I used to do and grab something fast food.
 

 
 LtotheN - Jan 11, 2012 04:12 PM New Comment 
 LtotheN 
I wish there was such a thing as a healthy protein bar! I simply can&apos;t afford the 20g of added sugars in a Clif Builder Bar, which is the lowest-sugar choice I can find.

I eat roasted soybeans as a pre- or post- workout protein source instead. but this is very inconvenient because they aren&apos;t sold on or around my college campus, so I have to have my mom ship them to me!

you&apos;re overlooking the point of convenience. protein bars can be bought on the go and carried around easily. Fruits and veggies can&apos;t.
 

 
 carolyn_r - Jan 11, 2012 04:47 PM New Comment 
 Carolyn_R Health and Fitness Writer and CC Success Story Original Post by: brity235 


So often I read that Americans consume too much protein, but I&apos;d really like to know the study that came to this conclusion. Over a year of keeping track of my diet showed that just about every day was a struggle to get enough protein, and I&apos;m not a vegetarian; I could probably count the days on one hand where I actually got &quot;too much&quot; protein, and even then, it wasn&apos;t an obscene amount by any means. 

Now I might be generalizing, but I would hypothesize that American women (trying to eat a balanced diet, like myself) don&apos;t overdo the protein, and there&apos;s probably even a sizeable percentage that would qualify as deficient.
 

Hi Brity235, Thanks for your question about protein intake in America. What you may see in your intake is a discrepancy between the recommended percentage of 10-35% of daily calories from protein, however we are referring to Americans daily intake of protein grams as being more than recommended. The CDC publishes the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHANES) which reflects both in 2005-2006 and 2007-2008&apos;s survey that Americans get much more than the Institute of Medicine&apos;s recommended daily allowance of protein which is 56 grams for men between ages 19-70 and 46 grams for women in the same age range. The source of the Recommended Daily Allowances for Macronutrients is:

 http://www.iom.edu/Global/News%20Announcements/~/media/C5CD2 DD7840544979A549EC47E56A02B.ashx 

If you cannot open the pdf files that are linked above, the source of those files can be found by clicking on the Nutrient Intake From Food by Gender and Age at http://www.ars.usda.gov/Services/docs.htm?docid=18349 

Great question!

 
 

 
 kc_mom - Jan 11, 2012 04:49 PM New Comment 
 
I agree with the many posts regarding &quot;too much protein&quot;. I also track my food daily and rarely get enough protein. Sometimes I add a protein bar, however, don&apos;t like the added sugar in so many of them. I tend to add more protein with Non-fat Greek Yogurt and egg whites.
 

 
 mischiefdm - Jan 11, 2012 04:50 PM New Comment 
 MischiefDM Achieve a healthy low weight Original Post by: tammyspies 

 Original Post by: sllverchild 


About a year ago, I found a really simple protein bar recipe that doesn&apos;t cost a whole lot to make (one of the downfalls of protein bars for me is how expensive they are). Nutritionally Luna Bars aren&apos;t that bad but as someone on a low sugar/ high protein diet, I definitely prefer to make my own.

For six bars I blend:

1/2 cup lowfat cottage cheese

1 cup quick oats

4 scoops protein powder- vanilla or chocolate

five packets of stevia

1/2 cup water or coffee if you want more of an espresso taste

2 TBS Flax Meal

Pour the batter in a greased 8X8 glass pyrex and bake for 15-20 minutes.

Each bar has about 170 calories, 4 grams of fat. 21 grams of protein, 3 grams of fiber, 14 grams of carbohydrates and only 2 grams of sugar.

These aren&apos;t going to taste nearly as candy-bar like as the store brand, but they&apos;re more suited for me nutritionally and financially.
 

You could add coco powder to this recipe to give it a chocolaty flavour. It would take much.
 

Search the recipe section for protein bars. There are pages to look at and some of them are no-bake types. Good recipe for me to add to my book as I make all my own.
 

 
 healthyfoundations - Jan 11, 2012 05:21 PM New Comment 
 
Funny all the ideas about high sugar. All protein bars I eat have about 5 grams or less ... I think protein bars are a great snack (and I try not to go over any that are 200-250 cal, which isn&apos;t that much) when I crave something proteiny and sweet at the same time, but yeah, obviously not the healthiest choice given its long ingredient list. But sugar&apos;s not the issue, it&apos;s all the other stuff I don&apos;t know how to pronounce.
 

 
 marauder - Jan 11, 2012 05:27 PM New Comment 
 
I use &quot;energy bars&quot; when away from home -- before or during sports events, such as tennis or bicycling, or prior to a gym workout. Favorites are performance vanilla crunch, and clif bar the mini size. However, if starting from home, the tried and true oats &apos;n honey bars with teaspoon of &quot;naturally more&apos; peanut butter works great. Not into the &quot;protein bars&quot; as they seem to have high sugar, and also high protein isn&apos;t what I need prior to or during an athletic event.
 

 
 terrikh - Jan 11, 2012 05:58 PM New Comment 
 I have used protein bars for years. They are great for travel. I always have some in the car so I never have to stop for fast food. Since they&apos;ve stopped serving free meals on planes I carry bars and fruit. I use it as a meal with fresh fruit, never as as a snack. Protein is filling and lasting. As for which bars to choose, I pick the ones with the most protein and the lowest calories. There is a supermarket brand called Snackwells, previously South Beach Diet Bars that are tasty and always on sale Costco sells a few brands that also reasonably priced. There is always a compromise between price and quality but generally if you add a piece of fruit and a bottle of water it&apos;s a pretty decent meal. 

 
 karentr75 - Jan 11, 2012 06:42 PM New Comment 
 
I was using Clif Bars and Pure Bars and realized that I was eating WAY too many calories. I have since switched to 100 Calorie Clif Bars just prior to a workout and that works really well. They are small and you may be a bit taken aback by the small portion size, but they are packed with sugar and protein and are a perfect pre-workout snack. 
 

 
 mm92 - Jan 11, 2012 07:14 PM New Comment 
 
I eat a protein bar at least once a day. I will usually have one after a high intensity morning work out in lieu of breakfast and sometimes I will have a bar as my 3pm snack. I like pure proteins and luna protein bars. Both are about 200 calories.
 

 
 janecwolfe - Jan 11, 2012 07:51 PM New Comment 
 Jane Wolfe Entrepreneur 
I just tried Diabeteze Bars at Costco yesterday and loved them. There are two flavors Chocolate Peanut Butter and Chocolate Mint. Each has only 180 calories and 4 grams of Sugar and 10 grams of Protein. I got them to take the edge off between meals and like that they are meant to support blood sugars. A reasonable alternative to the high-sugar bars and very convenient. 
 

 
 dianemar - Jan 11, 2012 08:07 PM New Comment 
 
I think for most it is an healthier alternative to a candy bar. If I want a candy bar I will opt for a 72% or more dark chocolate bar. Maybe if I know I am going to skip a meal, maybe a protien bar will work then too. But a small bag of nuts or trail mix would probably do the same thing, with a glass of milk.
 

 
 tammyspies - Jan 11, 2012 08:11 PM New Comment 
 Tammy Wanting to get back to my 20year size 
Thanks I will do that :)

 
 

 
 catharsisx101 - Jan 11, 2012 09:33 PM New Comment 
 Catharsisx101 Trying to maintain a balance 
I&apos;m a high protein / high fiber bar advocate. I have digestive issues and can&apos;t eat nuts and I have a number of reasons to avoid bringing raw veggies with me.

I eat two types of bars primarily: Gnu Fiber bars (Cal 140, Pro 4g, Carb 30g, Fib 12g, Sug 9, Fat 4) and Think Thin Protein bars (Cal 200, Pro 20g, Carb 25g, Fib 1g, Sug 0g, Fat 9g). I will typically eat the Gnu bars as a breakfast replacement or about a half hour before a workout so that I&apos;m not overfull and I still have energy. The Think Thin bars are either a lunch/dinner replacement or a half is used as a bridge between meals. Gnu bars are organic and taste amazing. They&apos;re like very moist oatmeal cookies. Think Thin bars are &quot;natural&quot; and also taste very good. They come in a variety of flavors, ranging from 15-20g of protein. I have trouble digesting most protein sources, yet I have found that these give my sensitive stomach no issue. These bars have been a life saver at a job where if I need a snack, I have to sneak it in between customers.
 

 
 imia345 - Jan 11, 2012 09:40 PM New Comment 
 imia345 
I like to eat 150 calories of Almonds before working out and after, it keeps me satiated but whatever works for you! I use to eat protein bars as well, if it&apos;s there and I&apos;m hungry/convenient I&apos;ll eat it but I prefer almonds or nuts for the energy.
 

 
 ther71apy - Jan 11, 2012 11:05 PM New Comment 
 RubyGirl I&apos;ve recently started to make my own &quot;recovery&quot; bars which have a moderate amount of protein in them. I race my bike competitively and clock over 500km per week along with a couple of runs - I&apos;m also vegan, so protein intake is a hot topic in my life! However, I wasn&apos;t happy with the chemicals commonly found in the commercial products so switched to making my own batch once a fortnight - and they&apos;re delicious and jam-packed full of wholesome ingredients. 

 
 mewlkitten - Jan 12, 2012 01:14 AM New Comment 
 
I don&apos;t do the meal replacement bars or protein bars (Even though I hardly ever get the recommended amount of protein in my diet). All those bars have way too many calories and most of them have too much sugar as well.

If I absolutely need something (Especially when I&apos;m out of the house and there is no gluten free options for me) I will have a KIND bar. I also buy them for my fiance to eat for breakfast sometimes. It&apos;s hard to get her to eat breakfast, so I&apos;d rather she have a KIND bar then nothing.
 

 
 anaesperanza - Jan 12, 2012 02:07 AM New Comment 
 
I love them. They help me get protein (I&apos;m a vegetarian) and am trying to reduce carbs. I use coupons to buy them, so it helps me keep my budget down to use them as a meal.  I like Clif and other brands. The other day I had one and then had snack cake, and the cake did not compare to the taste of the bar.
 

 
 imia345 - Jan 12, 2012 02:45 AM New Comment 
 imia345 Original Post by: ther71apy 

I&apos;ve recently started to make my own &quot;recovery&quot; bars which have a moderate amount of protein in them. I race my bike competitively and clock over 500km per week along with a couple of runs - I&apos;m also vegan, so protein intake is a hot topic in my life! However, I wasn&apos;t happy with the chemicals commonly found in the commercial products so switched to making my own batch once a fortnight - and they&apos;re delicious and jam-packed full of wholesome ingredients. 

That sounds yummy! Would u mind sharing the recipe? :)
 

 
 ther71apy - Jan 12, 2012 03:20 AM New Comment 
 RubyGirl 
Recipe for an energy bar from my cycling pal James! Feel free to toy with it to suit your needs - it is yummmm.
Ingredients
250g rolled oats

125g seeds e.g. pepitas or linseeds

125g nuts e.g. almonds, hazlenuts

125g dried fruits e.g. cranberries, sultanas, orange peel

50g dessicated coconut

1 can condensed milk (I substitute for soy milk)

Sesame seeds and choc-chips ( I don&apos;t use the choc-chips)

nb. I also put in a scoop of non-dairy protein powder. Currently using pea protein powder. But you may need to adjust the milk amount to get the right mixture consistency.

 
Method
 Pre-heat oven to 140°C Chop nuts&amp;dried fruits to desired consistency Warm condensed milk(or your substitute) slightly by placing the can in a bowl of hot water for 5-10mins Mix all ingredients together–should be sticky and clumpy Sprinkle sesame seeds on the bottom of a baking tray Place mixture on top of sesame seeds and sprinkle with choc-chips Bake for 45mins-1hr, until top is browned 

You may have to adjust the ingredients to suit your taste and practice with quantities until you get the appropriate consistency.

 
 

 
 ther71apy - Jan 12, 2012 03:27 AM New Comment 
 RubyGirl 
This is another recipe for energy bars that I&apos;ve adapted from Brendan Brazier&apos;s Thrive diet plan.

 Ingredients 

I cup fresh dates

1/4 cup almonds

1/4 cup raspberries

1/4 cup carob powder

1/4 cup flax seeds

1/4 cup sesame seeds

1/4 cup protein powder (he uses hemp protein but I use pea protein and it&apos;s fine)

1 teaspoon lemon juice

1/2 teaspoon lemon zest

sea salt to tase

 Method 

Process all ingredients in a food processor. You can then either roll tablespoon fulls into balls or I flatten the mixture on a clean surface, place plastic wrap on top and roll out to the thickness I like and cut into bars. The mixture is a bit sticky to handle but gets easier as it dries.

NB. if the mixture is too wet to make a solid bar, just add more dry ingredients e.g. more almonds and visa versa if it&apos;s too dry!

These don&apos;t freeze solid so I wrap them individually and put into the freezer and grab one as I&apos;m heading out for a ride. 
 

 
 miztremblay - Jan 12, 2012 12:39 PM New Comment 
 I&apos;ve been using the Special K Protein bars as an on-the-go meal on days when I don&apos;t get home until late due to Civil Air Patrol meetings after work (teaching, then tutoring). Rather than skip dinner altogether, or stop at a fast food restaurant on the way, I&apos;m getting a fairly filling meal substitute for 180 calories. As often as possible I try to bring along an apple or something as well, and drinking plenty of water. 

 «previous 1 2 next» 
Post Your Comment
 To post comments to this article, please log in or create a free account below. Join Calorie Count - it&apos;s easy and free!
 Advertisement 
 Advertisement 
 Eat for Better Health 
 Watch What You Eat with RA Can You Eat to Beat Psoriasis? Diet Do&apos;s and Don&apos;ts with Neutropenia Chronic Headaches Linked to Caffeine 
 
 Advertisement Free Coupons 
 $1.00 off U.S.A. Kids Cups Product
 Claim Coupon 
 Popular Items 
 advice american appetizers asian beans blog bmi breakfast calcium calories chicken children chocolate coffee confidence cooking craving dessert diabetes diet dieting dietsinreview dinner eggs emotionaleating exercise faddiet family fiber fish fitness fruit goals healthyeating healthysnacks holidays hunger inspiration italian mediterranean mindset motivation nuts obesity party plateau portioncontrol portions protein recipe recipes salad self-esteem shaysorrell sleep snack snacks soup spinach stress successstory sugar support tbl thebiggestloser tips travel tv vegetables vegetarian vitamind water weightloss workout yogurt 

 
 
 home | about us | press | help | mobile | bookmark | contact | advertise | tell a friend 

 ©2012 About, Inc., A part of The New York Times Company . All Rights Reserved. 

 Subscribe to our feeds: RSS | Twitter | Facebook User Agreement | Privacy Policy | Your Ad Choices | Mobile Privacy Policy&amp;Terms 

 
 
 Dashboard Calcamp Home Customize Goals Dietitian Support 
 
 Food Log Activity Log Weight Log Analysis Tagged Items Account Settings 
 
 Overview Forums Groups Journals Profile Supporting Mailbox 
 
 Overview Food Browser Recipe Browser New Recipe My Recipes Unit Converter Suggest Food Coupons 
 
 Overview Activity Browser Exercise Plan Workout Center Beginner&apos;s Corner 
 
 Overview Diet Profile BMI Tool Burn Meter Calorie Target Go Mobile Toolbar Challenge 
 
 Ask Mary Experts Members Videos Q&amp;A Books 
 
 Blog Home Tips&amp;Updates Dieting&amp;You Success Stories Recipes Healthy Eating Site Highlights
	</body>
</document>
