<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002945" url="http://www.principlesofaccounting.com/chapter22/chapter22.html" time="2012-07-12-19:02" support="1" score="0.0008325561312313976" bingtitle="Principles of Accounting" webtitle="Principles of Accounting">
			<query id="000992" bing-rank="186"/>
	<description>Out to Lunch is a rapidly growing fast-food restaurant chain. ... Some overage and waste is expected due to the need ... proportion of total production, time from order receipt ...</description>
	<body>
		Principles of Accounting.com : 
  Home  Chapter Summary 
 

Chapter 22 provides insight into ways in which a business can evaluate performance. The chapter begins with an exploration of the concept of responsibility centers and management by exception. Consideration must be given to whether an operation is to be evaluated according to cost control, profit generation, or investment returns. Examples are used to show how reporting methods should align with the affixing of responsibility.

Previous chapters introduced budgets. This chapter extends those concepts by showing how flexible budgets can be adjusted for changes in business volume. This logic also gives rise to the concept of standard costs, which in turn allow for careful analysis of variances. Variances can be prepared for various facets of performance related to material, labor, and overhead.

In addition to financial performance measurement, many businesses assess other aspects of operations. These goals and outcomes are often expressed in the form of a balanced scorecard concept.


 
 Exercises 
 

To aid in your understanding of this chapter, exercises with solutions are available for free download at Bookboon.com. You will find these exercises very helpful in providing models and guidelines for solving all of the problems at principlesofaccounting.com.

 

 Click here to go to Bookboon. 


 
 
 Problems Goals Achievement Fill in the Blanks Multiple Choice Objectives  Key Terms  
 


 Chapter Twenty-Two: Tools for Enterprise Performance Evaluation 
 
 Your goals for this “evaluation” chapter are to learn about: 


 Concepts in responsibility accounting and management by exception. Using flexible budgets to adapt outcome assessments to variable scenarios. Developing and using standard costs. Traditional variance calculations for monitoring cost and efficiency. The balanced scorecard approach to measuring business performance. 
 Now Available:
	</body>
</document>
