<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002823" url="http://www.health002.com/diet/what-fast-food-restaurant-is-the-most-hea.html" time="2012-07-12-18:53" support="6" score="0.03270161118140973" bingtitle="What fast food restaurant is the most healthy food to eat-Weight ..." webtitle="What fast food restaurant is the most healthy food to eat-Weight Loss Questions answered-Health002.com">
			<query id="000372" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="000360" bing-rank="171"/>
			<query id="001113" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="001125" bing-rank="143"/>
			<query id="000383" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000620" bing-rank="96"/>
	<description>Answers for What fast food restaurant is the most healthy food to eat-No fast food restaurant is &apos;healthy&apos;. The best you can do is order a salad from the menu. ChaCha!</description>
	<body>
		Health QA Find Your Best Health Questions&amp;Answers Online Health Home &gt; Weight Loss &gt; 
What fast food restaurant is the most healthy food to eat
 Question in topics Diet Nutrition Dining Out .We found some answers as below for this question &quot;What fast food restaurant is the most healthy food to eat&quot;,you can compare them. 
 No fast food restaurant is &apos;healthy&apos;. The best you can do is order a salad from the menu. ChaCha! ( Source: http://www.chacha.com/question/what-fast-food-restaurant-is-the-most-healthy-food-to-eat ) More Answers to &quot; What fast food restaurant is the most healthy food to eat &quot; How to Eat Healthy at a Fast Food Restaurant http://www.ehow.com/how_4917424_eat-healthy-fast-food-restaurant.html ･1 Almost all fast food restaurants have salads now. But eating healthy doesn&apos;t stop there. Many of the...･2 If you aren&apos;t like me and regularly eat fast food, there are ways to cut down on the junk you&apos;re eating...･3 Avoid any foods t... Is it possible to eat healthy at a fast food restaurant?? http://www.weight-loss-consultant.com/2008/05/dining-out-tips-on-how-to-dine-out.html The best advice is to check out the nutritional information on-line to see what your best options are if you have to resort to fast food. Pay particular attention to the salt and fat content as well as the ingredients. How to Eat Healthy at Arby&apos;s Fast Food Restaurant http://www.associatedcontent.com/article/455906/how_to_eat_healthy_at_arbys_fast_food.html As life becomes more hectic, you may have less time to cook your favorite, healthy meals at home. Sometimes dinner needs to be something chosen quickly from a local fast food restaurant. If you have an Arby&apos;s fast food restaurant nearby, yo... 
Related Questions Answered on Y!Answers
 What is the healthiest fast food restaurant to eat at? Q: What place has overall the healthiest food food to eat. From the ingredients, how they cook it, and how it tastes? A: I would have to say Subway....they incorporate lots of vegetables on their sandwiches and also have the low calorie menu. They also have low calorie sides like apple slices, yogurt and raisins.Wherever you go to, whether its mcdonalds or wendy&apos;s or taco bell, there will be at least one item on the menu that are low calorie. Subway probably has the most variety and&quot;bang for your buck&quot; What are the most healthy fast food restaurants? Q: Also, what is the healthiest choice at fast food restaurants?I&apos;m trying to eat as healthy as possible, even when i go to fast food restaurants. Thanks in advance! A: Polo Tropical and Chicken Kitchen in Miami are rated the healthiest.....just to bad they only local and nationwide!! Would you eat at a vegetarian healthy fast food restaurant? Q: A: YES!!! I am a meat eater and never could quit because I really love the taste of it but sometimes, I get in a vegetarian mood, and would love to have a place like that around. It would be great! In fact, over the summers when it is sooo bloody hot, we do eat more vegetarian suppers than meat. TOP 
 
 Prev Question: How many calories are in an order of onion rings 
Next Question: Is there glass in chewing tobacco 
 People also view What is the best post workout supplement for you to take Does the skin on a cucumber have any nutritional value How much is a girl 12 year old that is 5 don&apos;t 3 supposed to How many calories are in a small sonic strawberry banana smo What is the best way to detox without pills What do you get vitamin C from and what does vitamin c do fo What can I eat for breakfast to help me gain weight What are negative side effects of caffeine What is the best way to slim down What makes you gassy 
 Categories 

 Weight Loss Female Health Fitness Alternative Medicines Beauty Health Drugs Illness Symptoms Psychological Health Eat Health Home&amp;Garden Hot Topics 

 Topics 

 Diet Pregnant Yoga Calories Average Weight Recipes FLU&amp;Cold ADHD Cancer Blood Pressure Average Height Disease 

Advertising
 
Hot Questions Answered

 What is healthier brown rice or jasmine rice What foods make you gain weight What does vitamin C do for my body Is weed good How many calories are in Wendy&apos;s chili What does honey do to your body How do apples help your body How many calories are in a wheat pita bread How many calories should the average person have in a day What should I eat if my potassium is low 
 
QA Tags

 Treatment Medicine Addiction Drug Abuse Womens Health Conditions Illness Style Beauty Psychology Diet Nutrition Food Drink Fitness Garden Home Conversational Definitions Health 
 

 Copyright©2009 The health questions answered online Health002.com 
 About Browse Contact Disclaimer
	</body>
</document>
