<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002524" url="http://billoreilly.com/show?action=viewTVShow&amp;showID=2261" time="2012-07-12-18:35" support="3" score="0.001611876622937172" bingtitle="Bill O&apos;Reilly: The O&apos;Reilly Factor - Tuesday, February 10, 2009" webtitle="Bill O&apos;Reilly: The O&apos;Reilly Factor - Tuesday, February 10, 2009">
			<query id="001063" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="001302" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="001310" bing-rank="93"/>
	<description>But Immelt has no shame - GE stockholders pay him ... man who called 9-1-1 to complain that a fast food restaurant had ... Steve Pooly, Las Vegas, NV: &quot;Bill, I thought you ...</description>
	<body>
		Hello. Would you like to register or log in ? 
 
 
 
 Your shopping cart is empty. Start shopping in The O&apos;Reilly Store... 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Videos Audio TV&amp;Radio Books&amp;Print Opinion&amp;Analysis Fun Stuff About Bill Help/Contact Us Free Newsletters 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 The O&apos;Reilly Factor Tuesday, February 10, 2009 
 
 Email this entry Print this entry The O&apos;Reilly Factor Archive 
 
 Talking Points Memo: President Obama and financial corruption Top Story: Is Obama using fear to drive the stimulus package? Culture Warriors Segment: Responsibility times eight: What should happen to octo-mom? Impact Segment: A-Rod admits to using performance enhancing drugs Body Language Segment: Body language: Octuplet mom, John McCain, more &apos;Is it Legal?&apos; Segment: Chris Brown arrested for assaulting girlfriend Rihanna Back of Book Segment: Great American Culture Quiz: Funny folks edition Pinheads and Patriots: Salma Hayek&amp;Florida whiner Factor Mail 
 
 
 
 

 
 
 
 Talking Points Memo   President Obama and financial corruption &quot;Millions of Americans are refusing to put their money back in the stock market because they believe it&apos;s rigged. Some companies are so corrupt, so poorly run that it&apos;s staggering. The best example Talking Points can give you is General Electric, which we have been investigating for years. In 2001, legendary GE boss Jack Welch retired and Jeffrey Immelt took over. On his watch, GE stock has declined an astounding 75%. In addition, Immelt continued to do business with Iran, even as that country was sending roadside bombs into Iraq. But Immelt has no shame - GE stockholders pay him about $20 million a year in compensation. The reason the guy has not been fired is that he has GE&apos;s board of directors in his pocket because he gives them lavish perks. This is why Americans can no longer trust the stock market - it is not based on performance, it&apos;s based on cronyism. And, by the way, guess who appointed Jeffrey Immelt as one of his economic advisers? Hi there, President Obama. And guess which network used its power to get President Obama elected? That would be NBC News, owned by General Electric. Does that sound like &apos;change we can believe in?&apos;&quot;

 News Link: Tarnished GE CEO named to Obama team 
 
 Top Story   Is Obama using fear to drive the stimulus package? President Obama, who denounced President Bush for employing the &quot;politics of fear,&quot; has been casting this recession in the most starkly ominous terms. The Factor asked political analysts A.B. Stoddard and Ken Vogel about the apparent contradiction. &quot;That was then and this is now,&quot; Stoddard quipped. &quot;The president&apos;s job to maintain confidence, but jobs are being lost at such a rapid clip that government action is the last thing in the arsenal, and that&apos;s why he&apos;s talking with such urgency.&quot; Vogel agreed that President Obama has dramatically shifted his tone. &quot;The rhetoric of the campaign trail was lofty and hopeful, but this is the rhetoric of governing. He&apos;s using the bully pulpit to pressure Congress to pass his stimulus package, and the left is going to cut him a lot of slack on this.&quot; The Factor complained about the left&apos;s apparent double standard. &quot;After 9/11 the Bush administration used fear to get their programs through, and the left in this country screamed and yelled, and so did Barack Obama. It&apos;s the same thing now.&quot;

 News Link: Obama paints dire picture of US economy 
 
 Culture Warriors Segment   Responsibility times eight: What should happen to octo-mom? Culture Warriors Margaret Hoover and Monica Crowley scrutinized the case of Nadya Suleman, who gave birth to octuplets and now has fourteen children. &quot;The state should come in,&quot; Crowley declared, &quot;and take those children into their custody. The mother should be put under psychiatric observation, she has some serious mental illness, and the doctor should be suspended.&quot; Hoover focused on Suleman&apos;s recent interviews. &quot;She uses all this psychobabble to rationalize her actions, how she wants to fulfill her childhood dream. What really needs to happen here is that people who can afford to raise these children should adopt them.&quot; The Factor urged authorities to take immediate action. &quot;I&apos;m calling on the state of California to remove all the children from the home, and the doctor has to lose his license. We will ask Governor Schwarzenegger to have his social services people protect the children.&quot;

 News Link: Octuplet mom on welfare, doc investigated 
 
 Impact Segment   A-Rod admits to using performance enhancing drugs New York Yankees star Alex Rodriguez now admits that he used strength-increasing banned substances in the early 2000&apos;s. The Factor asked sports reporter William Rhoden what&apos;s in store for A-Rod in the upcoming season. &quot;This is going to be the worst year of his career,&quot; Rhoden predicted. &quot;Unlike Barry Bonds, Alex cares about what people think, and it&apos;s going to be the biggest nightmare of his life when spring training starts next week. People already despised Alex, they think he&apos;s disingenuous and phony.&quot; The Factor theorized that steroid use is one more sign of societal decline. &quot;The message society sends to kids is be a gangsta&apos; rapper and make a lot of money, do steroids and make a lot of money, cheat on Wall Street and make a lot of money.&quot;

 News Link: A-Rod admits taking steroids 
 
 Body Language Segment   Body language: Octuplet mom, John McCain, more Tonya Reiman began her segment with Alex Rodriguez and his &quot;apology&quot; on ESPN. &quot;When I see someone shrug one shoulder in the air,&quot; Reiman said, &quot;that&apos;s like a question mark, it tells me they don&apos;t believe their own statement, so I don&apos;t believe he&apos;s really sorry. And every time he answered a question he broke eye contact.&quot; Reiman turned to octuplet mom Nadya Suleman, who defended her decision to have so many children. &quot;What I see is somebody who is actually congruent, she consistently looks the same way and she makes eye contact. I can&apos;t say whether or not she has all her faculties, but I can tell you that what she&apos;s saying is genuine and coming from the heart. She doesn&apos;t think she did anything wrong.&quot; 
 
 &apos;Is it Legal?&apos; Segment   Chris Brown arrested for assaulting girlfriend Rihanna FNC legal analysts Megyn Kelly and Lis Wiehl examined the case of the Arizona rancher who has been capturing illegal immigrants on his property and holding them at gunpoint. &quot;This group of aliens,&quot; Wiehl said, &quot;claims he violated their civil rights. They&apos;re taking him into court and saying, &apos;hey, you pay us $32 million.&apos;&quot; Kelly suggested that the case may actually have merit. &quot;The lawsuit is not going to be thrown out. According to allegations, this man is a racist and he&apos;s very fond of racist slurs. And according to the complaint, he kicked one of these female Mexican illegals and that&apos;s not okay.&quot; The legal experts turned to the case of singer Chris Brown, who is charged with battering his girlfriend Rihanna. &quot;I don&apos;t care if this guy is a celebrity,&quot; Wiehl asserted, &quot;this woman went to the hospital and had major contusions.&quot; But Kelly reported that prosecutors may have a tough time if Rihanna refuses to testify because &quot;it&apos;s always harder to make the case when you don&apos;t have a complaining witness.&quot;

 News Link: Rihanna allegedly beat up by Chris Brown 
 
 Back of Book Segment   Great American Culture Quiz: Funny folks edition Steve Doocy and Martha MacCallum matched wits in another Great American Culture Quiz, this one focusing on comedians. Among the questions: &quot;Jonathan Winters played which role on the sitcom &apos;Mork&amp;Mindy?&apos;&quot; ... &quot;Carol Burnett won a huge libel lawsuit against whom?&quot; ... &quot;What was the pilot for &apos;Seinfeld&apos; called?&quot; MacCallum answered only one question correctly, and Doocy won in a laugher. The entire GACQ is here on BillOReilly.com under &quot;Fun Stuff.&quot; 
 
 Pinheads and Patriots   Salma Hayek&amp;Florida whiner Tuesday&apos;s Patriot : Salma Hayek, who has partnered with Proctor&amp;Gamble to provide vaccines for African children. And the Pinhead : The Florida man who called 9-1-1 to complain that a fast food restaurant had run out of lemonade.

 News Link: Audio: Man calls 911 when lemonade runs out 
 
 Factor Mail   Viewers sound off Steve Pooly, Las Vegas, NV: &quot;Bill, I thought you were very fair to Barack Obama during the campaign but now that he&apos;s President you are less fair. Saying that if his policies fail, the Republicans will regain power is dead wrong.&quot;

 Jerry Oglesbee, Sour Lake, TX: &quot;Mr. O, you should be respectful to Helen Thomas. She&apos;s a tough gal.&quot;

 Carmen Mendez, Des Plaines, IL: &quot;Bill, I was thinking the same thing about Helen: She does talk like the Wicked Witch! How can you be on television and think the same way I do?&quot;

 Karen Daffer, Holdrege, NE: &quot;O&apos;Reilly, so Obama talked a lot in his press conference. In case you haven&apos;t been keeping track, you do most of the talking on your program.&quot; 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Terms&amp;Conditions   |   Privacy Policy   |   Acknowledgements   |   Advertising   |   Mobile Site 
 Copyright © 2002-2012 BillOReilly.com. All rights reserved. 
 
 Videos Video of the Day 
 Backstage Conversation Webcast 
 O&apos;Reilly Factor Clips 
 Exclusive Video 
 More... TV&amp;Radio O&apos;Reilly Factor Flash 
 O&apos;Reilly Factor Archive 
 TV Schedule 
 The Radio Factor Vault 
 Radio Talking Points Memos 
 More... Premium Members Message Boards 
 No Spin News 
 Viewer Voting 
 Exclusive Video 
 Podcasting 
 More... Help/Contact Us Send a Message to Bill O&apos;Reilly 
 Knowledgebase&amp;FAQs 
 Email Customer Service 
 Site Map 
 Books&amp;Print Killing Lincoln 
 Pinheads and Patriots 
 Current Column 
 Column Archive 
 Free Newsletters 
 More... Opinion&amp;Analysis No Spin News 
 Poll Center 
 Bill&apos;s Daily Briefing 
 Stratfor.com Intelligence Briefing 
 More... About Bill Welcome Letter 
 Biography 
 Upcoming Appearances 
 Bill&apos;s Charities 
 More... The O&apos;Reilly Store Books 
 Memberships 
 Mugs 
 Hats 
 More... Fun Stuff O&apos;Quiz 
 O&apos;Reilly Crossword 
 Bill&apos;s Photo Album 
 More... Projects&amp;Campaigns Jessica&apos;s Law 
 Civics References 
 Sanctuary Cities 
 More...
	</body>
</document>
