<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002973" url="http://www.careerleak.com/mcdonalds/ronalds-ranger-1964/" time="2012-07-12-19:04" support="1" score="0.0019143488113027678" bingtitle="McDonalds Ronalds Ranger Job Reviews and Interview Questions" webtitle="McDonalds Ronalds Ranger Job Reviews and Interview Questions">
			<query id="001008" bing-rank="139"/>
	<description>... as well as clean the Playplace - including tables ... is probably the world&apos;s most famous fast food restaurant, so I ... McDonalds, Cashier; McDonalds, Cashier; Related Salaries</description>
	<body>
		[ Close ] 
You are using Internet Explorer 6 which is over 10 years old. The Web has advanced, your browser has not! Please upgrade your browser to increase safety and your browsing experience. Choose one of the following links to download a browser: Firefox Safari Opera Internet Explorer 
 
 About CareerLeak Contact Us 
 Thursday, 12 July 2012 Loading 
 CareerLeak Home Job Reviews Know Before You Apply 
 Job Reviews by Employer Job Reviews by Industry 
 Accounting Admin Charity&amp;Non-Profits Construction Consulting Education Engineering Fast Food Financial Services&amp;Banking Government&amp;Civil Service Grocery Healthcare Health&amp;Fitness Hospitality Human Resources Information Technology Insurance Manufacturing&amp;Distribution Military News&amp;Media Pharmacy Restaurant Retail Services Technology Telecommunications Transportation Other 
 Job Reviews by Job 
 Salaries What Others Get Paid CareerLeak Blog Your Job Search Starts Here 
 See Our Guides Now You Know 
 How To Research Employers How To Negotiate Your Salary How to Follow Up on a Job Application 
 Blog Categories 
 Company Articles Interviews Jobs and Education Resumes 
 
 Job Search Find the Job You Want 

 Login 
 
 Username 
 

 Password 
 

 Remember Me 
 
 Forgot your password? Forgot your username? Create an account 
 
 
 
 Sign Up 
 Home Job Reviews McDonalds Ronalds Ranger 
 
McDonalds, Ronalds Ranger Job Review and Interview
 Listed in Fast Food August 19, 2010 
 Review by McDonalds Ronalds Ranger 

 Rate This Review: 0 0 More: McDonalds Reviews | McDonalds Salaries | Ronalds Ranger Reviews | Ronalds Ranger Salaries 
 
 Workers dress up as the Hamburglar and host children&apos;s birthday parties, as well as cleaning the Playplace. 
 McDonalds Ronalds Ranger, in Fairborn, Ohio 
Ronalds Ranger Job Description
I was required to periodically dress up as the Hamburglar and host children&apos;s birthday parties, as well as clean the Playplace - including tables, chairs, floor, as well as playtubes and ball pit. Education None | Management Low Quality | Stress Average Stress 


 
 

 We work hard for you! Like Us! 
McDonalds Interview Questions
 The interview was easy and fast. I wore casual business attire. I was asked if I had any experience with children. This was my first job, at age 16, but I told the interviewer about my 19 nieces and nephews. I was asked if I had reliable transportation and if I had any issues with wearing the rubber Hamburglar suit. 
 Salary and Benefits 
 Salary - McDonalds, Ronalds Ranger is $7/Hourly. 
 Working Conditions The atmosphere is happy, clean, and safe. McDonald&apos;s is probably the world&apos;s most famous fast food restaurant, so I had been there several times before working there, and I knew what to expect. My coworkers&apos; attitudes toward the employer ranged from apathy to disgust. Most of my peers were also teenagers who found it difficult to respect an adult who chose to make a career in fast food. 
 Physical Requirements The heaviest thing we lifted was a birthday cake, but there was a considerable amount of crawling on your hands and knees inside the play tubes, while armed with spray sanitizer and cleaning rags. I once had to clean up vomit and diarrhea from the same child in the tubes. That was the last day I was employed as a Ronald Ranger. 
 Other McDonalds Job Information This job was fine for a teenager&apos;s first employment. This is not a job anyone would set as a life goal. 
 
Related Reviews

 McDonalds, Crew Member McDonalds, Crew Trainer McDonalds, Cashier McDonalds, Assistant Manager McDonalds, Crew Member 

 
Related Salaries

 McDonalds, Fry Cook McDonalds, Manager McDonalds, Cashier McDonalds, Crew Member McDonalds, Assistant Manager 

 
 
 Blog 
 
 
 How to Use Twitter to Find Your Dream Job 
 
 How to Follow Up on a Job Application 
 
 Preparing Your Resume: Three Common Mistakes to Avoid 
 
 How to Answer Behavioral Interview Questions 
 
 
Copyright©2012 CareerLeak - Trademarks and Tradenames used herein are the property of their respective holders.

 About CareerLeak Contact Us FAQ Privacy Terms
	</body>
</document>
