<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002949" url="http://www.experienceproject.com/stories/Have-Worked-In-A-Fast-Food-Restaurant/1707530" time="2012-07-12-19:02" support="20" score="0.055086841019697984" bingtitle="My First Job : I Have Worked In a Fast Food Restaurant Story ..." webtitle="My First Job : I Have Worked In a Fast Food Restaurant Story&amp;Experience">
			<query id="001446" bing-rank="24"/>
			<query id="000026" bing-rank="41"/>
			<query id="000025" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="001478" bing-rank="84"/>
			<query id="001100" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="001351" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="001469" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000007" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="001163" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="001448" bing-rank="33"/>
			<query id="000246" bing-rank="153"/>
			<query id="000001" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="001468" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000872" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000024" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000005" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000223" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000225" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000851" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="001508" bing-rank="122"/>
	<description>... Have Worked In a Fast Food Restaurant. My ... I would also end up doing all the dishes, cause the men there say &quot;that&apos;s women&apos;s work&quot;.</description>
	<body>
		Stories Confessions Questions People 
 Search Post 
 Experiences Stories Confessions Questions 
 Register Sign In Username: Password: Keep me logged in I forgot my password I forgot my username Not a member? Sign up now. 
 Full Site 
 
 Relationships Family&amp;Friends Health&amp;Wellness Culture Community 

 All Relationships Affairs Broken Hearts&amp;Betrayal Crushes&amp;Obsessions Divorce First Love Intimacy LGBT Long Distance Marriage Military Romance&amp;True Love Singledom Struggles 

 All Family&amp;Friends Family Struggles Fatherhood Loss in the Family Loss of a Child Loss of a Friend Loss of a Pet Loss to Suicide Motherhood Pets Single Parenthood 

 All Health&amp;Wellness Abuse Addiction Alcoholism Beliefs Bipolar Disorder Cancer Depression Empowerment Friendship Image&amp;Weight Loneliness PTSD Personality Disorder Phobias Rape Self Harm Self Improvement Suicide Unemployment Work 

 All Culture Books Fashion Fiction Food Hobbies Jokes&amp;Riddles Movies&amp;TV Music Poetry Politics Religion Sports Tattoos&amp;Piercings Travel Writings 

 All Community EP Quizzes WTK 
 
 Stories » I Have Worked In a Fast Food Restaurant 
 
 I Have Worked In a Fast Food Restaurant 
 
 My First Job 

By: flower4life 

Written on August 5th, 2011
 My first job, at 17, was at Long John Silvers. I worked there for a year and a half before quitting that job to go work at a Ponderosa Steakhouse. At Long John Silvers, I was a cashier. I sometimes felt like a janitor. I cleaned the bathrooms, scrubbed and mopped floors, and even took out the trash. Since I didn&apos;t have a good memory, I had to remember which customer got which meal, cause I had to bring them their food. I did train on preparing the orders on the screen and took orders on drive-thru. I&apos;m a slow learner, so I messed up the orders a few times. When business is slow, I would prepare the frozen fish, chicken and shrimp for the cooks. I would even make the batter and hush puppy batter for the cooks too. I would also end up doing all the dishes, cause the men there say &quot;that&apos;s women&apos;s work&quot;. I would stock up the condiment stand and stock it. I also stocked the desert pies in the cooler and made drinks for the customers and refilled the ice.

If money got short, from the register on my shift, I would repay it. I was voted most reliable, cause I would come into work no matter what. But when it came to cutting hours, I was first on the list. I was a good employee. It&apos;s my mouth that would get me into trouble. I would end up saying things that would get me into trouble. By: flower4life Age: 26-30 , Woman 
 
 Vote up! 1 
 | Favorite | Flag | Subscribe 
 
Please Respond to Story with authenticity, support, and respect 
 Sort By: recent oldest mvotes 

 
 I Have Worked In a Fast Food Restaurant 

 Me Too 
 
 10 Stories About this Experience Pizza Hut 303 Views Eat Fresh 177 Views Burger King 241 Views KFC A&amp;w; 420 Views (5 of 10 Stories) See All 
 
 I Have Worked In a Fast Food Restaurant 

 Me Too 
 
 10 Stories About this Experience Pizza Hut 303 Views Eat Fresh 177 Views Burger King 241 Views KFC A&amp;w; 420 Views (5 of 10 Stories) See All 
 
Baseball season is here! What&apos;s your favorite ballpark memory?
 In 1984, the Tigers had their greatest season ever, and I believe were the first... [ more ] The first time I laid eyes on a major league ballpark has got to be my favorite ... [ more ] Ummmm, who gives a ****? Sports are a mindless waste of time? My grandpa watched... [ more ] 

 Answer Question 
 Related Groups 

 See All 

 
 I Wish Non Smokers Could Take Random Breaks Every 30 Min Too 
 Members: 164 Stories: 11 
 I Want to Change Careers 
 Members: 16 Stories: 7 
 I Have Done Absolutely No Work At Work Today 
 Members: 23 Stories: 9 
 I Want to Hear Your Job Search Stories 
 Members: 22 Stories: 8 
 Search over 13 million life experiences and stories From the experience archive: I Feel Like A People Magnet , Okay , Alright , I&apos;m Poor ! All Stories Groups Answers Blogs Confessions 
 Full Site 
 Share 
This is your place to share the experiences that matter most to you.
 
 Experience&amp;Support Groups 
 Stories / People 
 Confessions / Challenges 
 Answers / Blogs 
 Dream Interpretations 
 Invite Friends 
 Explore 
From pets to cancer support, EP has something for everyone.
 
 Life / Education / Entertainment 
 Food + Drink / Friends + Family 
 Health / Recreation / Careers + Money 
 Pets / Current Events 
 Relationships + Romance / Religion 

 Search or Browse Stories 
 Play 
Relax and have some fun—check out these fun features:
 
 Causes / Petitions 
 Trending Topics 
 Free Online Games 
 Name Meanings / Song Meanings 
 Greeting Cards / Dictionary 
 Topics / BroadCause 
 About 
Experience Project is the largest living collection of shared experiences.
 
 Help + FAQs / Suggestions 
 About Us / Our Blog 
 Advertise / Contact 
 Press / Company Info 
 
 Privacy Policy | Terms of Service | Sitemap 

Site contents©Experience Project, Inc. 2004 - 2012. All Rights Reserved. Unauthorized reproduction is strictly forbidden.
	</body>
</document>
