<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002850" url="http://www.easyveganmeals.com/category/restaurant-reviews" time="2012-07-12-18:55" support="3" score="0.00471215742806368" bingtitle="Easy Vegan Meals » Restaurant Reviews" webtitle="Easy Vegan MealsRestaurant Reviews">
			<query id="001449" bing-rank="149"/>
			<query id="000852" bing-rank="34"/>
			<query id="001135" bing-rank="249"/>
	<description>What a fabulous fast-food restaurant chain that ... Incoming search terms for the article: pizza fusion; my order pizza fusion ... To end our visit, we had a trio ...</description>
	<body>
		home Recommended Reading Substitutions About Me Contact Me Log In 
 2 Feb 
 Sprinkles Cupcakes 
 by Andrea Desserts Vegan , Restaurant Reviews 
 
 

Yes, veganism is hitting mainstream! Sprinkles Cupcakes in Beverly Hills on Little Santa Monica has a vegan cupcake. The red velvet is absolutely out of this vegan world, and marked with a red“V”. If you are local, you must visit and try one for yourself!

 The Freegan Vegan 
 Eat Smart… 
 Eat Green 

Incoming search terms for the article:

 sprinkles vegan red velvet cupcake recipe sprinkles vegan cupcake recipe sprinkles vegan red velvet recipe sprinkles cupcakes vegan red velvet recipe sprinkles vegan red velvet cupcake calories sprinkles vegan vegan red velvet cupcakes sprinkles recipe sprinkles vegan cupcakes calories sprinkles vegan cupcakes recipe sprinkles vegan icing recipe 
 No Comments sprinkles cupcakes , vegan cupcakes 3248 1 Feb 
 Golden Mean Cafe’ 
 by Andrea Restaurant Reviews 
 

I’m always looking for great vegan restaurants in my local area. My daughter’s piano teacher told me about the Golden Mean Cafe’in Santa Monica, CA. I dragged my husband with me, as he is my partner in crime when it comes to new finds. Actually, I like to try what he orders, and vice versa.
 
Our server spouted off several specials, all sounding delicious. I was told prior to going to order the Lean Mean Veggie Burger with the works (added tempeh bacon, vegan cheese and avocado). The burger is made from beans, grains and veggies. My dish came with a side salad of spinach, black beans and yams dressed in a cilantro lime vinaigrette. Absolutely delicious and I would return just for this dish alone.

My husband ordered one of the specials, which was a sweet corn tamale cake garnished with a red sauce and soy cheese accompanied with a couscous side salad that was light and fresh tasting. I loved his too and would go back for this dish as well.

We decided to take home a slice of the top 3 cakes in the  picture. I love chocolate, and as this cake was delicious, I found myself loving the coconut iced cake even more. How could that be?! All 3 desserts were to die for! There are gluten-free desserts too!

Golden Mean Cafe serves up soup, salads, sandwiches, wraps, pizza, shakes, pastries and several appetizers and entrees. The cafe  is quaint and has a very comfortable and eco-friendly atmosphere using warm tones and cozy cushions.

Check out their website for location and hours and plan your visit this week.

 The Freegan Vegan 
 Eat Smart… 
 Eat Green 

Incoming search terms for the article:

 golden means recipe vegan coconut cake golden mean www easyveganmeals com what does flax-golden mean easy vegan means golden mean vegan cafe recipes Golden section cakes mean vegan coconut cake recipe vegan cafe recipes the golden mean santa monica 
 1 Comment brunch , cater , golden mean cafe , organic , pastries , restaurant review , soy cheese , the freegan vegan , thefre , thefreeganvegan , vegan , vegan burger , vegan desserts , vegan tamale 2345 16 Sep 
 Veggie Grill 
 by Andrea Restaurant Reviews 
 

What a fabulous fast-food restaurant chain that offers animal-free cuisine. I have been to the Santa Monica, CA location several times and have been impressed with each visit. The crowd of patrons was quite interesting. I was astonished with the sheer number of people walking in to order food. The ages ranged from kids to elderly. I am thrilled the veggie/vegan movement is hitting the masses and people are opening their minds to try new foods which are better for them, better tasting, and harmless to the animals and the environment. The veggie burger is mouth-watering delicious. They serve up great desserts too! Try the Chill Out Wings and the Sweet Potato Fries pictured below.

 

You and your kids will love them equally!

Visit their site for more information and locations. It’s worth a visit!

 The Freegan Vegan 
 Eat Smart… 
 Eat Green 

Incoming search terms for the article:

 vegetarian grilling blog vegan grillen vegetarian grilling blogs vegan grilling blog receitas vegans veggie grill salad dressing recipe veggie grill restaurant veggie grill dressing recipe vegan blog vegetarian grilling blogspot 
 1 Comment vegan dining , vegan restaurant , veggie grill 3166 22 Mar 
 Z Pizza 
 by Andrea Restaurant Reviews 
 

Another pizza joint that makes delicious vegan pizza is Z Pizza. They have many locations in 17 states, so check for one in your area. Order the Vegan Tuscan Pizza, just be sure to say no dairy-no cheese, but add Daiya. I’m craving more! You can also try the Berkley Veggie and California, both veganized, just be sure to mention it!

 The Freegan Vegan 
 Eat Smart… 
 Eat Green 

Incoming search terms for the article:

 z pizza review blog 
 No Comments daiya , restaurant review , the freegan vegan , thefreeganvegan , vegan cheese , vegan pizza , zpizza 3253 27 Feb 
 Pizza Fusion 
 by Andrea Restaurant Reviews 
 

 

Being vegan, ordering pizza to be delivered has always been something I never thought I would be able to do again. After all, what pizza joint makes dairy-free pizza? On my search for one that did, I was thrilled to discover Pizza Fusion, an organic pizzeria. Aside from regular pizzas, they have a few vegan choices. I have ordered pizza to be delivered on many occasions from the Santa Monica Ocean Park store, and have dined at the Hollywood Sunset Blvd location. Consistency is a good thing, and this place delivers the best tasting vegan pizzas. I opt for the Very Vegan with crimini mushrooms, roasted garlic, tomato sauce and soy cheese. I actually have them make half with soy cheese and the other half with Daiya (soy-free and gluten-free). I had this on both crusts, the organic white and the multi-grain gluten-free. I love them equally.

I always get the Fusion Salad with Goddess dressing, since these are dairy-free. My family loves the food and anyone would be happy with a place where you can order from both sides of the menu and please everyone. They even have a vegan dessert, a homemade brownie that is gluten-free and highly delicious.

The Hollywood store has dine-in specials, from free pizza Monday, wine and dine Tuesday, draft beer Wednesday, gluten-free Thursday, and a daily happy hour from 4-7p. Check them out today!

Visit their website for locations and hours.

 

 The Freegan Vegan 
 Eat Smart… 
 Eat Green 

Incoming search terms for the article:

 pizza fusion fusion pizza menu my order pizza fusion pizza fusion vegan pizza reviews pizza recipes field roast recipe for pizza for acid reflux calories in pizza fusion very vegan pizza restaurant fusion vegan pizza acid reflux vegan pizza acid reflx 
 No Comments daiya , pizza fusion , restaurant review , soy cheese , the freegan vegan , thefreeganvegan , vegan pizza 2352 25 Feb 
 KindKreme Review 
 by Andrea Restaurant Reviews 
 

 I scream, you scream, we all scream for KindKreme! 

I was thrilled to hear there was an ice cream shop that offered raw and vegan ice cream. KindKreme serves up gourmet and organic dairy-free delights in many flavors. They also serve cold-pressed coffee, fresh juice, smoothies and shakes.

I took my husband to the Studio City, CA location where we sampled many unique flavor combinations. It was such a difficult choice deciding what to get since everything tasted fresh and delicious. I was thinking strongly about getting the ginger basil, which is to die for.  However, since I am a chocoholic, I opted for the salted carmel chocolate. It was the perfect balance of goodness! My husband decided to go with a shake made with coconut KindKreme and topped it off with a refreshing passion fruit flavor.

Owner Mimi Moss and Reid served up some delicious delights that is worth the trip. Easy access off the 101 freeway. Check out the refrigerator section. They sell vegan nacho cheese dip. Go there today!

 KindKreme is easy to find. It’s on Cahuenga Blvd at Regal in the corner strip mall by Poquito Mas and The Good Neighbors Restaurant. If you can’t find a parking spot in the lot, then drive up Regal and park on the street and walk down while enjoying the stroll to vegan heaven.

 The Freegan Vegan 
 Eat Smart… 
 Eat Green 

 

Incoming search terms for the article:

 kindkreme calories kind kreme calories kindkreme kindkreme nutrition kind kreme nutrition kindkreme nutrition facts calories in kind kreme kindkreme images calories in kindkreme Kindkreme reid 
 No Comments ice cream , kindkreme , raw , reviews , thefreeganvegan , vegan desserts , vegan ice cream 2026 22 Oct 
 118 Degrees 
 by Andrea Restaurant Reviews 
 

If you’re in the Costa Mesa, CA area, visit 118 Degrees for fresh gourmet living cuisine. The restaurant  has as extensive menu, so there is something for everyone. When I visited, I started with the fried avocado mini tostado, a buckwheat shell with spicy peppita cheese, chopped spinach, cilantro, corn, and topped with fried avocado. It was absolutely delicious! I sampled the tortilla soup which was also outstanding! But I couldn’t wait to try my main course, which was the lemon pesto pasta. Imagine thin strips of zucchini (the pasta) with lemon pesto sauce, marinated portobello mushrooms, grape tomatoes topped off with fresh basil. Delicious! I took my sister there for her birthday, and she had the mole enchiladas, which she raved about. To end our visit, we had a trio sampler for dessert, which were small bites and all highly delicious.

The restaurant serves up cuisine made entirely from plant-based ingredients, such as fruits, vegetables, nuts, seeds and sprouted grains. The nut cheese is made by blending fresh herbs with sprouted nuts and seeds. The restaurant can accommodate nut-free dishes and is dairy-free, soy-free, wheat-free and high in enzymes, vitamins and minerals!

The name, 118 Degrees, refers to the commonly accepted temperature at which the natural enzyme value and nutritional contents of raw plant foods begin to break down and become useless for the body. One benefit of eating raw food is the energy derived from the enzymes and phyto nutrients available in foods that are still living.

The prices are reasonable and the experience was wonderful.  Menu and location can be found at
 http://shop118degrees.com/118.html 

 The Freegan Vegan 
 Eat Smart… 
 Eat Green 

Incoming search terms for the article:

 118 degrees 118 degrees lemon pesto pasta 118 degrees pesto 118 degrees red velvet cake 
 No Comments 118 degrees , living , living cuisine , raw , raw cuision , restaurant review , thefreeganvegan 2602 
Recent Posts

 Hibiscus Mint Iced Tea Smoothie Vegan-Dipity Coconut Lime Breeze White Sangria 
 
Categories

 Appetizers&amp;Dips Vegan Book Reviews Breakfast Vegan Desserts Vegan Drinks-Beverages Main Course Vegan Q&amp;A Reference Guide Restaurant Reviews Salads/Sides/Veggies/Wraps Vegan Videos 
 
Tags
 bob&apos;s red mill Book Reviews brunch cancer chocolate dairy diabetes friendly earth balance easy no meat easy vegan desserts easy vegan meals egg replacer egg substitute flaxseed healthy dessert recipe healthy vegetarian recipe heart disease heart healthy recipe holiday recipe meat nutrition for vegans plant based protein plant protein quick&amp;easy vegan meals raw silk soy summer meals Thanksgiving recipe thefreeganvegan tofu tofurky tofutti vegan vegan appetizer vegan breakfast vegan desserts vegan main course dishes vegan meals vegan protein vegan side dish vegenaise vegetarian kids vegetarian meat Videos whole foods 
Popular Terms in Category

 sprinkles vegan red velvet cupcake recipe sprinkles vegan cupcake recipe kindkreme calories kind kreme calories sprinkles vegan red velvet recipe kindkreme kindkreme nutrition pizza fusion vegetarian grilling blog sprinkles cupcakes vegan red velvet recipe kind kreme nutrition sprinkles vegan red velvet cupcake calories sprinkles vegan cupcakes calories sprinkles vegan cupcakes recipe sprinkles vegan vegan red velvet cupcakes sprinkles recipe kindkreme images kindkreme nutrition facts sprinkles vegan icing recipe sprinkles vegan red velvet cupcakes recipe calories in kind kreme calories in kindkreme sprinkles cupcakes vegan recipe vegan grillen kindkreme studio city pics vegan grilling blog veggie grill salad dressing recipe kindcreme calories sprinkles cupcakes calories sprinkles cupcakes calories vegan red velvet fusion pizza menu golden mean sprinkles vegan red velvet cupcake ingredients calories in sprinkles vegan red velvet cupcake vegetarian grilling blogs golden means recipe vegan coconut cake vegan red velvet cupcake recipe from sprinkles receitas vegans sprinkles vegan cream cheese frosting recipe calories of vegan red velvet cupcake by sprinkles Kindkreme reid vegan red velvet recipe sprinkles vegan red velvet calories cold pressed juice sprinkles vegan review easy vegan means easy vegan red velvet cupcakes red velvet vegan cupcakes sprinkles cupcakes nutrition golden mean vegan cafe recipes vegan sprinkles green kind kreme my order pizza fusion mimi moss kindkreme sprinkles vegan red velvet cupcake nutrition sprinkles cupcakes recipe sprinkles red velvet vegan cupcake calories kind kreme sprinkles red velvet vegan cupcake recipe sprinkles vegan frosting recipe Recipe for sprinkles vegan red velvet cupcake Golden section cakes kindkreme nutritional information sprinkles cupcake recipe sprinkles vegan cupcake what does flax-golden mean kind kreme nutrition facts reid kind kreme veggie grill dressing recipe mean vegan coconut cake recipe sprinkles cupcake red velvet recipe sprinkles cupcakes vegan vegan blog veggie grill restaurant kindkreme reviews sprinkles vegan red velvet www easyveganmeals com sprinkles cupcakes book vegan red velvet recipe restaurant fusion sprinkles cupcakes vegan red velvet calories can i order cake from golden mean sprinkles vegan cupcake icing recipe golden mean cupcakes santa monica sprinkles vegan red velvet calorie easy vegan cupcakes the golden mean santa monica calories kind kreme sprinkles vegan red velvet with frosting nutrition red velvet cupcakes hummingbird calories in pizza fusion very vegan pizza vegan red velvet recipe with mayo vegan pizza acid reflux kindkreme vegan cafe nutrition Sprinkles Cupcakes vegan red velvet cupcake recipe vegan grilling blogs easy vegan mean sprinkles vegan cupcake ingredients veggie grill sweet potato fries recipe golden mean desserts easy vegan cupcakes -chocolate 
 
Popular Search Terms

 red velvet cupcakes red velvet cupcake kenwa grain cupcake red velvet french toast cupcakes berry crumble cupcakes red velvet red velvet minerals smoothies kenwa food baked potato fruit salad kenwa grain cream cheese frosting nuts sangria thousand island dressing westsoy seitan recipes minerals in food vegan hummingbird cake bagel with cream cheese minerals food corn on the cob kenwa food vegan yams green bean casserole VELVET CUPCAKES baked potatoes mimosa vegan french toast casserole vegetarian food cranberry sauce quinoa quinoa rice smoothie butternut squash soup frosting chicken wrap chocolate frosting vegan baked french toast red velvet muffins مكسرات cookies cream cheese frosting recipe baked potato with cheese red velvet cup cakes PUMPKIN SEED CRUSTED LENTIL PATTIES baked french toast guacamole Pumpkin seed-crusted lentil patties vegetarian food pyramid for kids food minerals kenwa crumble bagel cream cheese taco salad cream cheese icing bagels and cream cheese vegan berry crumble vegetarian diet kenwa rice baked french toast casserole bagel and cream cheese cream cheese bagel sweet potato casserole mixed berry crumble gmos barley soup what is kenwa kenwa salad food pyramid for kids Pumpkin seed-crusted lentil patties with roasted garlic mashed potatoes and salad velvet cupcake vegetarian pyramid vegan pumpkin mousse grain kenwa potato with cheese chocolate icing vegan red velvet cupcakes chip dip vegan pyramid cheese platter Mineral vegetarian stuffed mushrooms mineral food thousand island sauce quesadilla bagels with cream cheese sprinkles vegan red velvet cupcake recipe frosting westsoy seitan recipes fruit cup mimosa drink kenwa grain vegan foods toast vegan hummingbird cake recipe 
 
Recent Search Terms

 baked potato kenwa food cookies red velvet cupcake french toast pics of yummy red velvet cupcakes Spinach&amp;Artichoke Dip fluffy cream cheese frosting recipe red velvet cupcakes vegan blueberry crumble cupcake red velvet red velvet cake vegan vegan oatmeal banana bread red velvet what are acidic vegetarian foods vegan frozen lima beans stuffed mushrooms does ph balance help reflux what is kenwa the red velvet cupcake kenwa food cheese cream cupcakes red velvet non dairy stuffed mushrooms vegan pyramid cream cheese frosting vegan meals red velvet cupcakes cake mix velvet cupcake vegan chip dip warm spinach salad vegetarian taco dip cream cheese chip dip vegan pumpkin mousse eggless breaded chicken kale chips banana bread with sour cream and chocolate chip recipe easy baking a red velvet cake chocolate icing image mimosa westsoy seitan recipes sweet potato and quinoa salad berry crumble what is kenwa food vegan roast beef sandwich CHEESE TOPPING FOR BAKED POTATOES vegan cupcakes red velvet cupcakes baked potatoes cheese Vegan baked french toast casserole quinoa and chicken gerd vegetarian diet vegetarian energy pyramid healthy napa cabbage salad muffin red velvet Guacamole Dip fluffy red velvet cake frosting chicken wrap golden mean vegetarian pyramid food vegetarian dishes keenwa food eggless red velvet cupcakes مكسرات baked potatoes nuts mamosa qenwa food redvelvet corn on the cob vegetarian diet cream cheese icing vegetarian stuffed mushrooms vegetarian food gmo fruit kenwa grain cup cake red velvet spinach sweet potato quinoa cupcake guacamole vegan recipes for hummingbird cake appetizer salad chocolate icing kenwa vitamins animation gif nutrition pyramid 2012 for kids vegansk diett reflux vegan berry crumble kindkreme calories vegetarian hawaiian recipes chocolate chip cookies vegan spinach sweet potato the night before french toast casserole vegan hummingbird cake tofutti cheesecake recipe vegan kenwa salad recipes desserts 
 
 
Archives

 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 October 2010 July 2010 June 2010 
 
 
Log In
 
 Username 

 Password 

 Remember Me 

 
 

 Easy Vegan Meals is proudly powered by Easy Vegan Meals 
 Entries (RSS) and Comments (RSS) .
	</body>
</document>
