<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002784" url="http://www.snagajob.com/job-search?s=virginia&amp;k=fast+food" time="2012-07-12-18:50" support="29" score="0.1038843030042925" bingtitle="Fast Food Jobs Fast Foodin Virginia | Snagajob" webtitle="Fast Food Jobs Fast Foodin Virginia | Snagajob">
			<query id="001509" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000036" bing-rank="79"/>
			<query id="000282" bing-rank="19"/>
			<query id="001071" bing-rank="6"/>
			<query id="000005" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="001079" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="001505" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000031" bing-rank="9"/>
			<query id="000537" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="001070" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="001082" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="001094" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000313" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000286" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001008" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="001069" bing-rank="14"/>
			<query id="001073" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="001536" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="001097" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="000062" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="001085" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="001066" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000881" bing-rank="99"/>
			<query id="001096" bing-rank="16"/>
			<query id="000287" bing-rank="70"/>
			<query id="000908" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="001033" bing-rank="28"/>
			<query id="000034" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000880" bing-rank="85"/>
	<description>All Fast Food jobs. View full-time and part-time Fast Food job openings from ... Smile and greet guests and request order immediately upon arrival at the menu board Take ...</description>
	<body>
		Are you an employer? To post jobs or get hiring solutions, please visit our employer website . Hide this message x 
 Browse Jobs Job Tips Join Today Sign In 
 
 FIND LOCAL JOBS 
 Search with keywords BETA 
 in 
 (job title, keywords, company, industry) You searched for: 
Fast Food Refined by:  in
 
 Virginia 
 Jobs 1 - 20 of 2,554 1   2   3   4   5   6   7    Sort by
 
 Relevancy - Date Company 
 Pizza Hut (1056) Hardee&apos;s (714) Domino&apos;s Pizza (153) Papa John&apos;s (139) Dairy Queen (135) 
 Little Caesars (96) Arby&apos;s (88) Wendy&apos;s International (40) Wendy&apos;s (28) Burger King (32) Captain D&apos;s (18) Bojangles&apos; (16) Popeyes (14) Taco Bell (11) Subway (7) Sonic Drive-In (4) Einstein Bros. Bagels (2) McDonald&apos;s USA (1) 
 
 Postal Code 
 23112 (43) 23805 (38) 23320 (32) 23666 (31) 23185 (29) 
 23228 (29) 23464 (28) 23860 (28) 24073 (28) 23235 (25) 23321 (25) 23452 (25) 24502 (25) 23454 (24) 23834 (22) 23601 (21) 23831 (21) 24018 (21) 20176 (20) 22401 (20) 23231 (20) 23505 (20) 23669 (20) 20110 (19) 23518 (19) 24012 (19) 24572 (19) 22204 (18) 23223 (18) 23322 (18) 23455 (18) 23602 (18) 24401 (18) 24501 (18) 20170 (17) 22193 (17) 22306 (17) 22554 (17) 24134 (17) 23227 (16) 23434 (16) 23608 (16) 24112 (16) 20147 (15) 23225 (15) 23230 (15) 23234 (15) 22101 (14) 22180 (14) 22192 (14) 22980 (14) 23005 (14) 23061 (14) 23111 (14) 23418 (14) 23692 (14) 24153 (14) 24266 (14) 24293 (14) 24641 (14) 22026 (13) 22601 (13) 23502 (13) 23704 (13) 23803 (13) 24202 (13) 24354 (13) 24523 (13) 24541 (13) 22309 (12) 22407 (12) 22701 (12) 23093 (12) 23181 (12) 23451 (12) 23663 (12) 23824 (12) 23851 (12) 24060 (12) 24210 (12) 24382 (12) 24522 (12) 20151 (11) 22042 (11) 22191 (11) 22207 (11) 22960 (11) 23075 (11) 23113 (11) 23462 (11) 23970 (11) 24017 (11) 24078 (11) 24141 (11) 24151 (11) 24301 (11) 24422 (11) 24426 (11) 24450 (11) 24605 (11) 24614 (11) 20121 (10) 20164 (10) 22030 (10) 22039 (10) 22182 (10) 22305 (10) 22801 (10) 22835 (10) 23060 (10) 23236 (10) 23503 (10) 23605 (10) 24084 (10) 24219 (10) 24230 (10) 24251 (10) 20109 (9) 22015 (9) 22041 (9) 22630 (9) 23229 (9) 23233 (9) 23662 (9) 23901 (9) 24343 (9) 24630 (9) 20112 (8) 20166 (8) 20186 (8) 22031 (8) 22827 (8) 22903 (8) 23294 (8) 23310 (8) 23324 (8) 23510 (8) 23701 (8) 24175 (8) 24540 (8) 20136 (7) 22003 (7) 22044 (7) 22303 (7) 22304 (7) 22553 (7) 22664 (7) 23930 (7) 24211 (7) 24333 (7) 20190 (6) 22032 (6) 22046 (6) 22315 (6) 22402 (6) 22406 (6) 22572 (6) 22901 (6) 22911 (6) 23062 (6) 23063 (6) 23114 (6) 23116 (6) 23220 (6) 23226 (6) 23325 (6) 23416 (6) 23693 (6) 23836 (6) 23847 (6) 24015 (6) 24083 (6) 24228 (6) 24416 (6) 24517 (6) 24531 (6) 24588 (6) 24592 (6) 20111 (5) 20155 (5) 22033 (5) 22150 (5) 22310 (5) 22312 (5) 22427 (5) 22448 (5) 22482 (5) 22560 (5) 22655 (5) 22712 (5) 22902 (5) 22942 (5) 23149 (5) 23188 (5) 23237 (5) 23238 (5) 23323 (5) 23430 (5) 23435 (5) 23453 (5) 23456 (5) 23604 (5) 23690 (5) 23801 (5) 23832 (5) 24121 (5) 24179 (5) 24224 (5) 24273 (5) 24277 (5) 24283 (5) 24477 (5) 24503 (5) 24651 (5) 20132 (4) 20165 (4) 20171 (4) 22201 (4) 22314 (4) 22812 (4) 22853 (4) 23487 (4) 23837 (4) 23950 (4) 24319 (4) 24482 (4) 24637 (4) 22134 (3) 22151 (3) 22405 (3) 22408 (3) 22968 (3) 23068 (3) 23541 (3) 23606 (3) 23607 (3) 20120 (2) 20191 (2) 22066 (2) 22079 (2) 22124 (2) 22206 (2) 22209 (2) 22302 (2) 23059 (2) 23072 (2) 23150 (2) 23219 (2) 24091 (2) 22508 (1) 22556 (1) 22815 (1) 23141 (1) 23661 (1) 24013 (1) 24521 (1) 
 
 State 
 Virginia [x] 
 City 
 Richmond (133) Virginia Beach (128) Chesapeake (94) Henrico (91) Alexandria (75) 
 Norfolk (73) Newport News (71) Hampton (64) Midlothian (60) Roanoke (58) Petersburg (51) Fredericksburg (50) Lynchburg (48) Woodbridge (42) Manassas (41) Arlington (37) Williamsburg (34) Falls Church (33) Fairfax (29) Christiansburg (28) Hopewell (28) Chester (27) Charlottesville (25) Yorktown (25) Vienna (24) Colonial Heights (22) Sterling (22) Danville (21) Herndon (21) Portsmouth (21) Suffolk (21) Leesburg (20) Mechanicsville (20) Abingdon (19) Madison Heights (19) Stafford (18) Staunton (18) Pearisburg (17) Martinsville (16) Ashburn (15) Ashland (14) Gloucester (14) Lebanon (14) Mc Lean (14) Onley (14) Richlands (14) Salem (14) Waynesboro (14) Wise (14) Bedford (13) Bristol (13) Dumfries (13) Marion (13) Winchester (13) Appomattox (12) Blacksburg (12) Blackstone (12) Centreville (12) Culpeper (12) Franklin (12) Glen Allen (12) Louisa (12) West Point (12) Wytheville (12) Bluefield (11) Chantilly (11) Clifton Forge (11) Collinsville (11) Covington (11) Grundy (11) Lexington (11) Orange (11) Pulaski (11) Radford (11) Rocky Mount (11) South Hill (11) Big Stone Gap (10) Coeburn (10) Dublin (10) Fairfax Station (10) Gate City (10) Harrisonburg (10) Luray (10) Burke (9) Farmville (9) Front Royal (9) Hillsville (9) North Tazewell (9) Poquoson (9) Cape Charles (8) Elkton (8) Reston (8) Springfield (8) Troutville (8) Warrenton (8) Annandale (7) Bristow (7) Crewe (7) Galax (7) Spotsylvania (7) Woodstock (7) Altavista (6) Buena Vista (6) Chatham (6) Clintwood (6) Daleville (6) Emporia (6) Gloucester Point (6) Goochland (6) Oak Hall (6) Rustburg (6) South Boston (6) Warsaw (6) Bealeton (5) Bowling Green (5) Castlewood (5) Chesterfield (5) Dahlgren (5) Fort Eustis (5) Fort Lee (5) Gainesville (5) Kilmarnock (5) Moneta (5) Norton (5) Pennington Gap (5) Saint Paul (5) Saluda (5) Smithfield (5) Stephens City (5) Stuarts Draft (5) Tappahannock (5) Tazewell (5) Vinton (5) Bridgewater (4) Chilhowie (4) Courtland (4) La Crosse (4) Pounding Mill (4) Purcellville (4) Timberville (4) Verona (4) Windsor (4) Zion (4) Hallieford (3) Quantico (3) Ruckersville (3) Floyd (2) Great Falls (2) Hayes (2) Lorton (2) Oakton (2) Sandston (2) Amherst (1) Broadway (1) Gordonsville (1) Locust Grove (1) Quinton (1) 
 
 Category 
 Part-time (2239) Full-time (2138) Temporary (9) Internship (4) Seasonal Full-time (3) 
 Seasonal Part-time (3) Summer (3) Temp to Hire (3) 
 
 Industry 
 Food&amp;Restaurant (2529) Management (315) Sales&amp;Marketing (282) Transportation (65) Retail (41) 
 Customer Service (24) Other (17) Administration&amp;Office Support (15) 
 
 Job Title 
 Pizza Hut Assistant General Manager Job (198) Pizza Hut Restaurant General Manager Job (198) Pizza Hut Shift Manager Job (198) Pizza Hut Team Member Job (198) Pizza Hut Delivery Driver Job (160) 
 Assistant Manager (136) Cooks (122) Cashier/Crew Member (118) Biscuit Makers (110) Drive-Thru Crew Members (108) Pizza Hut Server Job (104) Miembro del Personal(Crew Member) (98) Shift Leaders (66) Pizza Delivery Drivers (65) Assistant Managers (56) Team Member (53) Crew Members (47) Delivery Driver (45) Crew Member (43) Restaurant Manager (40) Shift Leader/Supervisor (34) General Manager (30) Customer Service Associate (24) Customer Service Representative (24) Shift Leader (23) Shift Manager (21) Shift Supervisor (19) Sign Dancer (19) Manager (18) Co-Manager (17) Job Fair (16) Breakfast Shift Leaders (15) Chill Staff (12) Grill Staff (12) Hourly Manager (12) Restaurant Assistant Manager - Retail Food Service Supervisor (10) Restaurant Shift Manager - Retail Food Service Supervisor (10) Cake Decorator (8) Hospitality Staff (8) 2nd Assistant Manager (7) Expeditors (6) Restaurant Manager - Retail Food Service Supervisor (Management) (6) Restaurant Manager - Retail Food Service Supervisor (5) Customer Service Representatives (4) Assistant General Manager (3) Cake Decorators (3) General Managers (3) Restaurant General Manager (3) Sandwich Artists (3) Shift Coordinator (3) Cashier (2) Other (2) Assistant Restaurant Manager (1) Car Hopper/Skater (1) GM Partner (1) Hourly Shift Manager (1) Marketing Assistant (1) Marketing Internship (1) Shift Leader Opportunities (1) Shift Leader/Assistant Manager (1) Shift Manager - Staunton, VA (1) 
 
 
 Pizza Hut Server Job 
 save job Pizza Hut - 3136 Old Halifax Road, South Boston, VA Being a server at Pizza Hut®is about making hungry people happy - with tips! It&apos;s about being independent and having fun, making new friends and earning extra cash. As a Pizza Hut server, you&apos;re the smiling face that greets and serves our customers. Working with us will give you the financial rewards and flexibility to suit your lifestyle! You&apos;ll learn new things, get recognized for your efforts and learn skills that last a lifetime. What are we looking for? The good news is that ... Updated this week 
 Pizza Hut Restaurant General Manager Job 
 save job Pizza Hut - 402 S Sterling Blvd., Sterling, VA To eat. To laugh. To share. That&apos;s why people come to Pizza Hut. It&apos;s the calling of our Restaurant General Managers to make them feel like family with smiles, teamwork and dedication. If you&apos;re an experienced restaurant or retail manager, think about a career with Pizza Hut. You know who you are - a natural leader, you love putting together a winning team. You&apos;re all about teaching new things and motivating the team to work together. At Pizza Hut, you can do all that - and more. ... Updated this week 
 Cashier/Crew Member 
 save job Hardee&apos;s - 2347 Roanoke Street, Christiansburg, VA Hardees is currently searching for outstanding Cashier/Crew Members!! Outstanding Cashier/Crew Members will serve guests quality products in a fast and friendly manner. What do we want you to do? It&apos;s simple: Smile and greet guests and request order immediately upon arrival Take orders and enter them into the point of sales terminal accurately Suggestive sell and answer menu questions Collect money and provide accurate change Assemble orders, including condiments and other service ... 
 Restaurant Manager 
 save job Bojangles&apos; - 3475 Crater Rd., Petersburg, VA Bojangles&apos; is looking for Restaurant Managers Earn $26,000 - $35,000/yr! We are currently seeking highly motivated individuals to manage the operations of a quick service restaurant. Our ideal management candidate would have at least 1 year of management experience and exceptional knowledge of food and customer service. This position requires management of food and labor cost, employee training skills, and the ability to implement company policies. Our managers provide leadership ... 
 Pizza Hut Team Member Job 
 save job Pizza Hut - 10378 Willard Way, Fairfax, VA Working at Pizza Hut®is about making hungry people happy. It&apos;s about being independent and having fun, making new friends and earning extra cash. As a Pizza Hut team member, you can be the smiling face that greets and serves the customers or a cook who make things happen in the kitchen. Working with us will give you the financial rewards and flexibility to suit your lifestyle. You&apos;ll learn new things, get recognized for your efforts and learn skills that last a lifetime. What are ... Updated this week 
 Shift Leaders 
 save job Hardee&apos;s - 310 West Randolph Road, Hopewell, VA HUNGRY FOR A CAREER GROWTH OPPORTUNITIES? We are currently looking for Shift Leaders! We offer amazing advancement potential and the chance to make a difference! Boddie-Noell is a family of motivators and encouragers. We are committed to giving our people the tools and skills they need to succeed in their career and in life. This is a family business and family (our employees) comes first. The BNE story began in Fayetteville, N.C. in 1962 when Carleton Noell and his two entreprene ... Sign up for email Job Alerts Local jobs delivered straight to your inbox. 
 Pizza Hut Shift Manager Job 
 save job Pizza Hut - 814 S Cameron St, Winchester, VA Working at Pizza Hut®is about making hungry people happy. It&apos;s about being independent and having fun, making new friends and earning extra cash. If you&apos;re ready to take the next step in your career in restaurant management, our Shift Manager position is the right place to do it. Working as a Shift Manager will let you develop your management skills while still having the time to do the things you enjoy. You&apos;ll benefit from our training and career opportunities and receive reward ... Updated this week 
 Pizza Hut Server Job 
 save job Pizza Hut - Rte 60 E., Clifton Forge, VA Being a server at Pizza Hut®is about making hungry people happy - with tips! It&apos;s about being independent and having fun, making new friends and earning extra cash. As a Pizza Hut server, you&apos;re the smiling face that greets and serves our customers. Working with us will give you the financial rewards and flexibility to suit your lifestyle! You&apos;ll learn new things, get recognized for your efforts and learn skills that last a lifetime. What are we looking for? The good news is that ... Updated this week 
 Customer Service Representative 
 save job Domino&apos;s Pizza - 4223 Beulah Road, Richmond, VA 
 Shift Leader/Supervisor 
 save job Papa John&apos;s - 20789 Great Falls Plaza, Sterling, VA Shift Leaders/Supervisors Exciting things are happening at Papa John s and our career experience just keeps getting Better ! Papa John s Shift Leader/Supervisors are motivated individuals with excellent interpersonal skills and the ability to build a team that works together, increase profits, and provide superior customer service. At Papa John s we consider all of our team members to be more than just employees! We care about you and your development. In fact, most of our promoti ... 
 Shift Manager 
 save job Arby&apos;s - Charlottesville and Surrounding Areas, Charlottesville, VA Arby&apos;s believes in the importance of flexibility for employers and employees alike, and we believe that our employees are our greatest asset. We treat our people with respect and honesty and are committed to providing our employees with a stable, safe and enjoyable work environment so they may realize their greatest potential. SHIFT MANAGERS NEEDED IMMEDIATELY!! Shift Managers are responsible for: Assisting the General Manager and Assistant Manager with all facets of the successfu ... 
 Cooks 
 save job Hardee&apos;s - 1122 S. Alleghany Avenue, Covington, VA Hardees is currently searching for outstanding Cooks!! Outstanding Cooks will serve prepare quality products that meet or exceed company standards with strict adherence to safe food handling practices. What do we want you to do? It&apos;s simple: Cook products using grill, broiler, or fryer and transfer to make up table or over shelf for holding Assemble sandwiches using the proper amount of condiments Wrap or package products Clean, slice, and prepare produce to meet business demand T ... 
 Pizza Hut Team Member Job 
 save job Pizza Hut - 1431 Mahone Avenue, Fort Lee, VA Working at Pizza Hut®is about making hungry people happy. It&apos;s about being independent and having fun, making new friends and earning extra cash. As a Pizza Hut team member, you can be the smiling face that greets and serves the customers or a cook who make things happen in the kitchen. Working with us will give you the financial rewards and flexibility to suit your lifestyle. You&apos;ll learn new things, get recognized for your efforts and learn skills that last a lifetime. What are ... Updated this week 
 Pizza Hut Shift Manager Job 
 save job Pizza Hut - 4425 Shore Dr Ste 103, Virginia Beach, VA Working at Pizza Hut®is about making hungry people happy. It&apos;s about being independent and having fun, making new friends and earning extra cash. If you&apos;re ready to take the next step in your career in restaurant management, our Shift Manager position is the right place to do it. Working as a Shift Manager will let you develop your management skills while still having the time to do the things you enjoy. You&apos;ll benefit from our training and career opportunities and receive reward ... Updated this week 
 Restaurant Manager 
 save job Hardee&apos;s - 1029 Battlefield Boulevard, Chesapeake, VA Hardees is currently searching for an outstanding Restaurant General Manager !! An Outstanding Restaurant General Manager will develop, support and lead the restaurant team. You will be accountable for sales growth by maintaining the highest standards of quality, service and cleanliness with constant focus on profitability. What do we want you to do? It&apos;s simple: Interview, hire, and schedule adequate staff to operate the restaurant based on company standards and in compliance wit ... 
 Cooks 
 save job Hardee&apos;s - 310 West Randolph Road, Hopewell, VA Hardees is currently searching for outstanding Cooks!! Outstanding Cooks will serve prepare quality products that meet or exceed company standards with strict adherence to safe food handling practices. What do we want you to do? It&apos;s simple: Cook products using grill, broiler, or fryer and transfer to make up table or over shelf for holding Assemble sandwiches using the proper amount of condiments Wrap or package products Clean, slice, and prepare produce to meet business demand T ... 
 Job Fair 
 save job Hardee&apos;s - 7917 Midlothian Turnpike, Richmond, VA Restaurant Management Job Fair - July 16 When: Monday, July 16th Where: Hardee&apos;s of Parham (Corner Of Parham Staples Mill Rd) Location: 3201 E. Parham Road, Henrico VA Time : 10:00am - 3:00pm Now Hiring Restaurant Shift Leaders, Breakfast Shift Leaders, Assistant Managers for our Hardee&apos;s locations in Richmond, Henrico, Ashland, Goochland, Midlothian Hardee&apos;s locations! Any Questions: Call 800-888-8136 ext. 4 We&apos;re looking for EXPERIENCED Restaurant Assistant Managers, Restaurant ... Updated in the last 2 weeks 
 Customer Service Representatives 
 save job Domino&apos;s Pizza - Newport News Area, Newport News, VA Now Hiring Customer Service Reps! Great things are happening at Domino&apos;s Pizza, and we are looking for exceptional people who want to be part of the best pizza delivery company in the world! You will be responsible for taking orders, making pizzas, and giving the customer the best experience possible. You must have an outgoing personality, be efficient and energetic, and be willing to work in a fun and fast paced environment. Domino&apos;s Pizza takes care of their employees, it is a f ... 
 Pizza Hut Team Member Job 
 save job Pizza Hut - 635 West Main St., Lebanon, VA Working at Pizza Hut®is about making hungry people happy. It&apos;s about being independent and having fun, making new friends and earning extra cash. As a Pizza Hut team member, you can be the smiling face that greets and serves the customers or a cook who make things happen in the kitchen. Working with us will give you the financial rewards and flexibility to suit your lifestyle. You&apos;ll learn new things, get recognized for your efforts and learn skills that last a lifetime. What are ... Updated this week 
 Pizza Delivery Drivers 
 save job Domino&apos;s Pizza - 9127 Lee Highway, Fairfax, VA Are you ready to be part of the action? Do you like money in your pocket? Domino&apos;s Pizza drivers are paid cash nightly, which includes: tips and mileage reimbursement! Our driver position is an excellent start to learn about the delivery business, customer service, and the creation of a great product ... Domino&apos;s Pizza! We are committed to promoting from within: most of our managers started as drivers! Take charge of your career in a driver role and learn valuable skills to take t ... Jobs 1 - 20 of 2,554 1   2   3   4   5   6   7    
 in 
 (job title, keywords, company, industry) Snagajob Job Seeker Security Center Local Jobs Job Tips Job Seeker Blog My Job, My Health Coupons Right-Fit Degrees Help and FAQ Contact Us Employer Solutions Post Jobs Talent Sourcing Hiring Manager Training Manager Scheduling Manager Recruitment Ad Agency Advertise with Us Affiliate Program Contact Sales About Snagajob Careers Our Story Giving Back Life at Snagajob News ©2000-2012 SnagAJob.com, Inc. All rights reserved Privacy Terms of Use Copyright Policy
	</body>
</document>
