<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002063" url="http://wiki.answers.com/Q/What_is_the_average_price_of_a_restaurant_meal_in_the_United_States" time="2012-07-12-17:58" support="1" score="0.0014925614216105957" bingtitle="What is the average price of a restaurant meal in the United States" webtitle="What is the average price of a restaurant meal in the United StatesWhat is the average price of a restaurant meal in the United States">
			<query id="000864" bing-rank="13"/>
	<description>The general range of individual meals runs from $5.00 per person (e.g. a sandwich ... Negotiating With Credit Card Companies; Best Weed Eater; How To Get Rid of Spyware</description>
	<body>
		Unanswered Questions New Answers Q&amp;A;Categories Coupons Guides 

 Sign In | Sign Up Home Search Settings Top Contributors Help Center English▼ 
 English Français Deutsch Italiano Español Tagalog 
 
 Home Answers.com &gt; Wiki Answers &gt; Categories &gt; Food&amp;Cooking &gt; Restaurants and Dining Establishments &gt; Tim Hortons &gt; What is the average price of a restaurant meal in the United States? 
What is the average price of a restaurant meal in the United States?
 In: Tim Hortons [ Edit categories ] 

 Answer: The average price of a restaurant meal in the United States is roughly $10 per person. The general range of individual meals runs from $5.00 per person (e.g. a sandwich and a side for lunch) to $25.00 per person (e.g. a steak dinner.) The cost of a meal varies depending on many circumstances, such as:

- Breakfast and lunch meals are usually cheaper than dinner meals.

- Appetizers, desserts, and drinks will increase the cost of a meal. (An appetizer or a dessert can sometimes cost as much as an entree.)
- Fine dining or gourmet restaurants charge more than chain and family restaurants.
- Steak and seafood usually carry a higher price than other entree selections.

- Fast food restaurants are much cheaper than restaurants with menus, tables and servers. These restaurants often have &quot;value menus&quot; with individual items for around $1.00 each.
- Children and senior citizens often receive discounts on the cost of their meals. 

 First answer by ID1211202183 . Last edit by RamblingGirl . Contributor trust : 0 
 [ recommend contributor recommended ]. Question popularity : 7 [ recommend question ]. [ report abuse ] 
Can you answer these Tim Hortons questions?
 
 What is the percentage of adults drinking Tim Hortons coffee in a year? Answer it! How much do Tim bits cost at Tim Horton&apos;s? Answer it! How much do Tim bits cost at Tim Hortons? Answer it! Did Tim Horton have troubles starting Tim Hortons? Answer it! Why does it say do not microwave on Tim Hortons coffee cups? Answer it! 
 
Related topics:
 
 The United States (place) United State United States (TV series) 
 
Related ads:
 

 
Shopping for Tim Hortons deals?

Find Coupons and Promo Codes on Coupons by Answers.com

 CafeFit Coupons Cafe Britt Coupons Burger King Coupons Chilis Coupons 
 FIND MORE COUPONS AND PROMO CODES Sign in using: Answers members: Username Lost password? Password Remember me Sign in 
Home
 
 Recent site activity Browse categories 
 Animal Life Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Vehicles Entertainment&amp;Arts Food&amp;Cooking Health History, Politics&amp;Society Hobbies&amp;Collectibles Home&amp;Garden Humor&amp;Amusement Jobs&amp;Education Law&amp;Legal Issues Literature&amp;Language Relationships Religion&amp;Spirituality Science Shopping Sports Technology Travel&amp;Places WikiAnswers Local 
 Random question Promoted questions Community forum Unanswered questions Advanced search Top contributors Q&amp;A;categories Coupons Guides Settings 
 
 Answer these 
 Who is the mother of 4 of Mick Jagger&apos;s children? In: The Rolling Stones Answer it! What is affixes of the word philanthropy? In: Prefixes Suffixes and Root Words Answer it! Why do businesses change suppliers? In: Small Business and Entrepreneurship Answer it! What is the name of a sweet smelling flower that starts with car? In: Scattergories Words Starting with Certain Letters Answer it! » more 
Recent questions
 
 What are the benefits of using the google site? What are the benefits of vaser liposuction? What are the benefits of using trucking software? What are the benefits of using Washington Mutual Bank? What are the benefits of using waterproof mascara? 
 
Featured guides
 
 Chronic Knee Pain Treatments Patio Canopies And Awnings Three Pharmacy Technician Career Paths Portable Air Conditioning Unit Reviews How To Get Printable Coupons Online 
 » More 
Answers Properties
 
 Answers Wiki Answers Video Answers Guides Coupons 

 Local Answers Online Answers Shop Answers Blog Sitemap 
 
Company
 
 About Terms of Use Privacy Policy IP Issues Disclaimer 
 
Community
 
 Guidelines Reputation Roles Help 
 
Updates
 
 Email Watchlist RSS 
 
 
International sites
 English | Deutsch | Español | Français | Italiano | Tagalog 
 
 Copyright©2012 Answers Corporation facebook twitter youtube blog
	</body>
</document>
