<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002179" url="http://www.kemperblog.com/imingle-blog/2012/04/04/who-founded-fast-food-drive-thru/" time="2012-07-12-18:04" support="1" score="0.0004222804823495022" bingtitle="Who founded fast-food drive-thru? | iMingle Blog" webtitle="Who founded fast-food drive-thru? | iMingle Blog">
			<query id="001044" bing-rank="246"/>
	<description>Make an Online Payment; Electronically Sign Documents ... Policy Number Remember my Policy Number Password ... To which I reply, I went to many a fast food restaurant in ...</description>
	<body>
		Manage Your Policy

Online policy management is convenient and secure!
 
 Review Your Policy Make an Online Payment Electronically Sign Documents 

 Make Changes View Recent Claims 
 Policy Number Remember my Policy Number Password Remember my Password 
 Forgot your Password? 
 Sign Up 
 iMingle - Insuring the i Generation. 

 Contact Us About Us Customer Login 
 Text size: -A A A+ 
 Auto 
 Coverage 
 
Beep! Beep! Our smarter policy coverages have your back.
 Learn More 
 Discounts 
 
So many ways to save. Dive in to find out.
 Learn More 
 Payment Options 
 
We have the payment flexibility to ease your budget, no doubt.
 Learn More Home/Renters 
 Home 
 
Your home is your baby, treat it well with iMingle.
 Learn More 
 Condo 
 
Hip, stylish condos rejoice, we can defend you from harm.
 Learn More 
 Renters 
 
Your landlord&apos;s insurance won&apos;t protect you, but we can.
 Learn More 
 Discounts 
 
Your home for discounts.
 Learn More Customer Service 
 Billing 
 
Making it easy to pay your bill.
 Learn More 
 Policy Changes 
 
Life changes, right? Your policy needs to as well.
 Learn More 
 Customer FAQs 
 
We&apos;re here to answer all of your questions.
 Learn More Claims Center 
 How to Report a Claim 
 
When something happens, we&apos;re here 24/7.
 Learn More 
 Glass Only 
 
A busted windshield&apos;s no good. Let us help.
 Learn More 
 Catastrophic Claims 
 
When a catastrophe happens, we pull out all the stops.
 Learn More 
 Roadside Assistance 
 
Stuck on the side of the road? We&apos;re here for you.
 Learn More 
 Click to Chat 
 
 
 Home Blog 
 
 iMingle Max @iMingleMax 

 iMingle Max is the voice of iMingle Insurance, which insures the i Generation and makes insurance more fun.
 Follow @iMingleMax 
 Pages 
 About iMingle Insurance® 
 Categories 
 Uncategorized 
 Archives 
 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 
 
 
Recent Comments

 Follow these tips before vac… Follow these tips before vac… Follow these tips before vac… Follow these tips before vac… 
 
4 Apr 2012

 Who founded fast-food drive-thru? 
 Rate 1431 Thanks! An error occurred! 
 Posted in Uncategorized 
 No Comments» 
 
 I’m sure you know the drill. All of us have gone through this thought process numerous times. “I’m driving my car and I’m hungry. I could stop by a restaurant, but that means I’d have to do the unthinkable – actually get out of my car! That’s unacceptable! Luckily for me, there are 20 restaurants in a three-block radius with drive-thru windows!” The ability to pick up a sandwich, fries, and Pepsi Raging Raszzberry without leaving our cars is all that separates us from the animals. What do you mean; Pepsi Raging Razzberry was discontinued over two decades ago?? You never know what you had until it’s too late. [Wipes away tear.] But have you ever wondered how drive-thru fast food came about? Well, I have too! And the answer to one of mankind’s least important questions is: nobody really knows. 

 Depending on who you ask , the concept of drive-through fast food was invented by Texas Pig Stand, In-N-Out Burger, Maid-Rite, or Jack in the Box. It’s one of those hot topics that can be a source of pride for the inventing parties, and nobody will ever know who’s telling the truth. For instance; who invented electricity? Was it Benjamin Franklin or Kathy Bates ? The correct answer is: neither of them. It’s been around since the beginning of time, it just hasn’t been harnessed for most of our history.

So anyways, I’m glad I could help you discover this important knowledge. To which you’ll reply, “But Max, you haven’t helped me discover anything! All you wrote is that you don’t know! Isn’t it completely up to you what you blog about? If you couldn’t discover the answer, why didn’t you blog about something else?” To which I reply, I went to many a fast food restaurant in my hunger for knowledge. And hunger for other things. And now, tens of thousands of calories later , I am far too sleepy to write something else. G’nite! 

 Max 
 

 Comment RSS 0 Comments Leave a comment Name Email Website Comment 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 
 
 Twitter Stream 
 
 http://t.co/SsBDrLJv - Explaining the #HiggsParticle from the #iMingle #blog ! - 2 days ago 

 http://t.co/EryIV8mT - Wanna save some green? Ride public transportation! [ #INFOGRAPHIC ] - 7 days ago 
 More Tweets 
Subscribe
 Follow @iMingleMax   
 Privacy Policy Security Policy Contact Us Blog Resources Disclaimer 
 
 Features Get a Quote Recall a Quote 

 Auto Insurance Coverage Discounts Payment Options 

 Home/Renters Home Condo Renters Discounts Payment Options 

 Customer Service Biling Policy Changes Customer FAQs 

 Claims Center How to Report a Claim Glass-Only Claims Catastrophic Claims Roadside Assistance 
 
©2010 Unitrin Direct. All rights reserved.
	</body>
</document>
