<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002167" url="http://www.wowjobs.ca/job/Food+Counter+Attendant-j+l+restaurant+partnership-saskatoon+sk-9605281" time="2012-07-12-18:04" support="2" score="0.005298607808100431" bingtitle="Food Counter Attendant Job - SASKATOON - J &amp; L Restaurant ..." webtitle="Food Counter Attendant Job  - SASKATOON - J&amp;L Restaurant Partnership Job Id: 9605281 -WowJobs Canada">
			<query id="000436" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="000624" bing-rank="108"/>
	<description>... L Restaurant Partnership o/a Tim Hortons Fast Food Restaurant is hiring Food Counter ... and keep records of the quantities of food used; Receive payment for food ...</description>
	<body>
		Employers My.WowJobs Sign In 
 
 
 Keywords (Job Title or Skill) Location (City, Province or Postal)   Advanced Search 
 


 
Food Counter Attendant job - SASKATOON - J&amp;L Restaurant Partnership
 



 
 Food Counter Attendant (Expired) J&amp;L Restaurant Partnership SASKATOON Job Order Details Food Counter Attendant Print This Job Email a Friend Information en fran??ais Job Order #: 5123903 Employer Name: J&amp;L Restaurant Partnership Wage/Salary Info: $10.72 per hour. Posted Date: 01/31/2011 Location: SASKATOON # of Positions: 30 Employment Terms: Full Time Experience: No Experience How to Apply?: Fax Resume or Apply in Person Description J&amp;L Restaurant Partnership o/a Tim Hortons Fast Food Restaurant is hiring Food Counter Attendants We are seeking 30 Food Counter Attendants for Full Time / Shift Work ? Early Morning, Evening,&amp;Overnights&amp;Weekends for $10.72 per hour. Main duties of the job: Take customers&apos; orders; Assemble and prepare food and food orders; Portion and wrap food or place it directly on plates for service to patrons, and package take-out food; Serve customers at counters or drive thru windows; Stock refrigerators and keep records of the quantities of food used; Receive payment for food items purchased; General housekeeping duties; For additional duties please set up a meeting/interview to review job description. No experience needed. No education needed. Please apply by fax or walk in. (information below) 16-33rd St. E. Saskato.... Found at Saskjobs.ca on 2011-02-01 07:00:17 



 
 Recent
	</body>
</document>
