<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002814" url="http://dietdeliverytexas.com/" time="2012-07-12-18:53" support="22" score="0.03669112202970312" bingtitle="Diet Delivery Texas" webtitle="Diet Delivery Texas">
			<query id="001244" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000993" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="001308" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="000398" bing-rank="43"/>
			<query id="001119" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000553" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="001527" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="000273" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000899" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="000428" bing-rank="51"/>
			<query id="001496" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="000366" bing-rank="125"/>
			<query id="000179" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001056" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000053" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000868" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="001151" bing-rank="158"/>
			<query id="000741" bing-rank="73"/>
			<query id="000242" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000805" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000116" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000679" bing-rank="44"/>
	<description>And throw in America’s recent thirst for ... Here’s a chance to tip your cup at some good news. ... of the bigger areas of risk is the typical fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Home Contact us 
 
 Diet Delivery Texas 
 
 Uncategorized 
 
 That Fizzy Goodness In Texas May Be Linked To Cancer 
 23rd December 2009 written by moderator 
 
It’s sweet, refreshing and fizzy, but soda pop may be doing more damage to individuals who drink it in Houston, Dallas and elsewhere in Texas, than they may think.

Recently, the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) reported that it had found a high level of cancer-causing benzene in five of the 100 soft drinks and beverages that were tested. The levels of benzene were more than the recommended five-parts-per-billion limit for drinking water.

The FDA reported that it had alerted the companies that make the soft drinks in which benzene was discovered to be over the prescribed limit. The companies had agreed to reformulate their drinks or have already done so. The FDA also maintained that there was no cause for concern, even though some environmental groups expressed disappointment regarding the organization’s recent findings.

The five soft drinks/beverages that had excess levels of benzene were:
- Safeway Select Diet Orange—one lot was found to have 79.2 parts per billion of benzene
- AquaCal Strawberry Flavored Water Beverage—one lot was found to have 23.4 parts per billion
- Crystal Light Sunrise Classic Orange—one lot was found to have 87.9 parts per billion
- Giant Light Cranberry Juice Cocktail—one lot was found to have 10.7 parts per billion
- Crush Pineapple—one lot was found to have 9.2 parts per billion

Benzene in soft drinks has recently become an extremely sensitive matter. The chemical is formed as a result of a reaction between Vitamin C (ascorbic acid) and either sodium benzoate or potassium benzoate, both of which are contained in soft drinks and beverages. However, the reaction doesn’t always occur. It takes place as an exception when the conditions are ideal for this particular reaction.

Benzene is a chemical that is linked to cancer in humans. It is found in the air as a result of automobile emissions, burning coal and oil. It is also used extensively in industries which produce chemicals, dyes, detergents, synthetic fibers, solvents, rubber and some plastics.

Employees in the chemical industry, gas stations, gasoline distribution jobs, the rubber industry, and the printing and leather industries are also at a high risk, since they are constantly exposed to benzene.

Currently, the FDA doesn’t have an upper limit for benzene in soft drinks. It follows the five parts per billion (ppb) limit set by the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency for drinking water. The FDA’s website states that benzene can cause harm at“very low levels.”Information on the site adds that exposure to light can trigger the formation of benzene in the soft drinks.

The FDA conducted a food-testing program called the Total Diet Study, in which it tested 24 samples of diet soda for benzene. Approximately 79% (nineteen) of the soft drinks was found to have benzene above the permitted levels.

According to recent research carried out by Sheffield University in the UK, a preservative that is commonly found in soft drinks can cause essential parts of human DNA to stop working, leading to serious health problems. Earlier this year, British officials pulled soft drinks and juices that contained benzene from the shelves.

A nice cold soda on a hot day may seem like just the thing. But there are alternatives, like water and natural fruit juice. What you put in your body when you’re young will certainly affect your health when you get older. Eventually, it will also affect your wallet as well.
 
 Share This 
 0 Comments Uncategorized 
 Colon Cleansing Methods in Houston Texas 
 23rd December 2009 written by moderator 
The colon, also known as the large intestine has many different ‘compartments.’ These are all linked, beginning with the ascending colon, the transverse colon, and the descending colon that leads in to the sigmoid colon. This might not mean anything to anyone but keeping your colon healthy and in full working order is very important. The colon is a sort of storage area for solid waste, it is used to extracts salts and water from the faeces before it exit’s the body through the anus. If a blockage occurs it can be life threatening as the build up of this waste leads to a condition known as volvulus or obstruction of the colon. The build up of this waste can cause internal bleeding.

Like the majority of large cities around the world, most are known for their poor diet. Colon cleansing in Houston Texas is very important, because of the lifestyles the inhabitants lead. The diet is very important, as some fatter and greasier foods cannot be digested properly, leading to colon obstruction. There are many establishments that offer methods or facilities for colon cleansing in Houston Texas. A big one is the colon cleansing and constipation resource center. It is an Internet based company that offers advice on the best methods for colon cleansing in Houston Texas and have links to medical websites where you can purchase the correct treatment for your individual needs.

Some common methods of colon cleansing you will find in Houston Texas are:

* Enema; this is the most common and most heard of type of colon cleansing treatment there is. This involves the introduction of fluids in to the colon via the rectum. It is successful in most cases and your usual doctor can normally book you in for a treatment. They are performed in most hospitals, and if the problem is serious, your health insurance will cover it.
* Oxy–Powder; this is a reasonably new method but does have very positive feedback from all users. It is an orally administered capsule that works as a dietary supplement to take the place of all of the nutrients you are missing out on. It is primarily oxygen based and works with the liquids in your colon to expand and flush out any blockages.
* Laxatives; these are only a temporary relief method as they will not cure the problem. They will aid the disposal of rectal build up but will not completely cleanse the colon.
* Colon Hydrotherapy; much like an enema, colon hydrotherapy passes warm water through the colon and over time completely removes any build up or blockages. This is more effective than the enema and when used at the same time as oxygen based treatments it is almost flawless.

Your colon is one of the most important organs in your body. It must be kept clean, the same as any waste disposal system not inside the body. For more methods of colon cleansing in Houston Texas visit your local doctor or hospital advice service
 
 Share This 
 0 Comments Uncategorized 
 Do Drink The Water In Texas 
 23rd December 2009 written by moderator 
You may watch what you eat in Dallas, Houston or anywhere else in Texas. But do you watch what you drink? A number of health problems, including tooth decay, thinning bones, heart disease, stroke, diabetes, dementia, cancer and obesity are linked to the beverages you drink.

In 2006, the Unilever Health Institute in the Netherlands–Unilever owns Lipton Tea–sponsored a panel of nutrition and health experts who published a study,“Beverage Guidance System.”This study was developed to help individuals reduce the amount of calories they are drinking when those calories contribute little or nothing to their health and, in many cases, may actually detract from it.

The panel, led by Barry M. Popkin, a nutrition professor at the University of North Carolina, was concerned by the contribution popular drinks make to weight problems. Panel experts also reviewed 146 published reports to find the best evidence for the health problems from various beverages.
At the top of the heap of preferred beverages is water. It has no calories or hazards, just benefits. But the panel expressed concerns about bottled water fortified with nutrients, implying that some individuals may think they don’t need to eat certain nutrient-fortified foods that contain substances like fiber and phytochemicals, which are lacking in some bottled waters.

Aaahh, The Sweet Nectar of Life

The panel also reported that approximately 21 percent of calories consumed by Texans, and other individuals, over the age of two comes from beverages, mostly soft drinks and fruit drinks with added sugars. There’s been an incredible increase in sugar-sweetened drinks in recent decades, primarily at the expense of milk, which, in comparison, has a number of nutritional benefits. The calories from sweetened sodas and fruit drinks account for half the rise in caloric intake by Americans since the late 1970s.
Americans are not only drinking more sweet beverages, but serving sizes have also bloated, with some restaurants and convenience stores offering 32 ounces servings as well as free refills.

And throw in America’s recent thirst for smoothies and sweetened coffee drinks–240 calories in a 16-ounce Starbucks Caffe Mocha without the whipped cream–and it’s easy to see why people are drinking themselves into stretch pants with elastic waistbands.

But calories from sweet drinks are not the only problem. In a report in The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition, it’s cited that beverages have“weak satiety properties.”In other words, they do little or nothing to curb an individual’s appetite. As a result, people do not compensate for the calories they drink by eating less.

In addition, some soft drinks contribute to other health problems. The American Academy of General Dentistry says that non-cola carbonated beverages and bottled or canned sweetened iced tea harm tooth enamel, especially when they’re consumed alone, without a meal. And a study of 2,500 adults in Massachusetts linked cola drinking, both regular and diet, to the thinning of hipbones in women.

The panel suggests that if individuals drink something sweet, they should sip a no-calorie beverage like diet soda that includes an approved sweetener, although many experts have recognized the lack of long-term safety data and the possibility that these diet sodas“condition”people to prefer sweetness.

Fruit juices are another alternative, but not nearly as good as whole fruits, which satisfy hunger better.

Coffee, Tea and You

Here’s a chance to tip your cup at some good news. Several newer studies have linked regular coffee consumption to a reduced risk of developing Type-2 diabetes, colorectal cancer and Parkinson’s disease.

Most studies don’t link a high intake of coffee or caffeine to heart disease, although caffeinated coffee raises blood pressure somewhat and boiled unfiltered coffee–French-pressed and espresso–raises harmful LDL and total cholesterol levels.

On its own, caffeine–up to 400 milligrams a day, or the amount in about 30 ounces of brewed coffee–doesn’t seem to be a health problem or affect water balance in the body. But pregnant women should limit their intake because more than 300 milligrams of caffeine a day might increase the risk of miscarriage and low birth weight, the panel reported.

There also seems to be good news on the brain front regarding caffeine. Mice prone to an Alzheimer’s-like disease were protected by drinking water spiked with caffeine equivalent to what people get from five cups of coffee a day. And a study of more than 600 men suggested that drinking three cups of coffee a day protects against age-related memory and thinking deficits.

For tea, the evidence on health benefits is somewhat uncertain. Tea lowers cancer risk in experimental animals, but the effects in individuals are unknown. Tea may benefit bone density and help prevent kidney stones and tooth decay. And four or five cups of black tea daily helps arteries expand, possibly improving blood flow to the heart.

A Drink a Day May Keep the Doctor Away.

Moderate consumption of alcohol–one drink a day for women and two for men–has been linked in many large, long-term studies to lower mortality rates, especially from heart attacks and strokes. It may also lower the risk of Type 2 diabetes and gallstones. The panel found no convincing evidence that, for example, a glass of red wine is better than a vodka rocks with a twist.

But even moderate alcohol consumption has its downside. Moderate intake can raise the risk of birth defects and breast cancer, because it may interfere with essential B vitamins. And, of course, heavy alcohol consumption is associated with several lethal cancers, cirrhosis of the liver, hemorrhagic stroke, hypertension, dementia and some forms of heart disease.

Milk and Soy Drinks.

The panel, which rated low-fat and skim milk third, just below water and coffee and tea, said that dairy drinks were not essential to a healthy diet. The panel did acknowledge the benefits of milk for bone density, while noting that the calcium and vitamin D benefits to bones are not maintained unless people continue to drink milk. Other essential nutrients in milk include magnesium, potassium, zinc, iron, vitamin A, riboflavin, folate and protein, approximately eight grams per eight-ounce glass. A 10-year study of overweight individuals found that milk drinkers were less likely to develop metabolic syndrome, which is a group of coronary risk factors that includes hypertension and low levels of protective HDLs.

The panel did emphasize the need for children and teenagers to drink more milk and fewer high-calorie, sweetened drinks. The report stated that fortified soymilk is a good alternative for individuals who prefer not to consume cow milk. But the panel cautioned that soymilk cannot be legally fortified with vitamin D and provides only 75 percent of the calcium the body gets from cow’s milk.
 
 Share This 
 0 Comments Uncategorized 
 A Cup Of Green Tea May Help Keep The Doctor Away In Texas 
 23rd December 2009 written by moderator 
There’s an ancient Chinese proverb that states,“Better to be deprived of food for three days, than tea for one.”They must have known something that Westerners are just discovering: tea, especially green tea, has numerous health benefits.

The Chinese have preached about the medicinal benefits of green tea since ancient times. They’ve used it to treat everything from headaches to depression. In fact, green tea has been used for medicinal purposes in China for at least 4,000 years and it is growing in popularity in Dallas, Houston and throughout Texas.

These days, scientific research from all over the world is providing hard evidence for the health benefits long associated with drinking green tea. A recent issue of the Journal of the National Cancer Institute published the results of a study that showed drinking green tea reduced the risk of esophageal cancer in Chinese men and women by nearly 60 percent. In a recent study, University of Purdue researchers concluded that a certain compound in green tea inhibits the growth of cancer cells. And there’s newer research showing that drinking green tea lowers total cholesterol levels, as well as improving the ratio of good (HDL) cholesterol to bad (LDL) cholesterol.

According to recent research studies in the West and in China, the medical conditions for which drinking green tea is supposed to be of help include:
- Cancer
- Rheumatoid arthritis
- High cholesterol levels
- Cardiovascular disease
- Infection
- Impaired immune function

So what makes green tea so special? Its secret lies in its richness in catechin polyphenols, particularly epigallocatechin gallate (EGCG), a powerful anti-oxidant that not only inhibits the growth of cancer cells but also kills cancer cells without harming healthy tissue. And EGCG is known to inhibit the abnormal formation of blood clots. The last benefit is important when you consider that the formation of abnormal blood clots is the leading cause of heart attacks and stroke.

Now researchers are making connections between the effects of drinking green tea and the“French Paradox.”Researchers were puzzled that, despite consuming a fat-rich diet, the French have a lower incidence of heart disease than people in the U.S. do. Red wine, which is consumed by the gallon in France, contains resveratrol, a polyphenol that limits the negative effects of smoking and a fatty diet. Researchers from the University of Kansas determined that EGCG is twice as powerful as resveratrol. This may explain why the rate of heart disease among Japanese men is also quite low, even though approximately 75 percent are smokers. But that doesn’t give anyone the excuse to start smoking or to not give it up entirely.

But why don’t other Chinese teas have similar benefits? Green, oolong, and black teas are all made from the leaves of the Camellia sinensis plant. Green tea is different because of the way it is processed. Green tea leaves are steamed, preventing the EGCG compound from being oxidized. By contrast, black and oolong tea leaves are fermented. This results in the EGCG being converted into other compounds that are not nearly as effective in preventing and fighting various diseases.

New evidence has also emerged that green tea can even help people in Dallas, Houston and elsewhere in Texas who are on diets. The American Journal of Clinical Nutrition recently published the results of a study at the University of Geneva in Switzerland. The study found that men who were given a combination of caffeine and green tea extract burned more calories than those given only caffeine or a placebo.

Green tea can also benefit your smile by helping prevent tooth decay. Just as the tea’s bacteria-destroying abilities can help prevent food poisoning, it can also kill the bacteria that cause dental plaque. Meanwhile, skin preparations containing green tea—from deodorants to creams—have started hitting the market.

Okay. So green tea is good for you. Are there any negative effects of consuming this tasty beverage? The only downside reported from drinking green tea is insomnia because, like most other teas, it contains caffeine. However, green tea does have less caffeine than coffee. There are approximately thirty to sixty mg. of caffeine in six to eight ounces of tea, compared to over one-hundred mg. in eight ounces of coffee.

Another new study suggests that green tea may also help ease the inflammation and pain of rheumatoid arthritis. The study findings are preliminary, emphasized lead researcher Salah-uddin Ahmed, an investigator at the University of Michigan Health System in Ann Arbor. For patients with rheumatoid arthritis, this lining of tissue surrounding the capsule of the joints is inflamed, leading to long-term joint damage and chronic pain. About 2.1 million Americans have rheumatoid arthritis, according to the Arthritis Foundation.

The researchers focused on whether EGCG had the ability to block the activity of two potent molecules, IL-6 and cyclooxygenase-2 (Cox-2), which play a role in breaking down bone in an RA joint. The study found that the two molecules were suppressed by the EGCG. While it is difficult to quantify exactly the effect of the suppression, the EGCG“blocked them significantly,”according to Ahmed. EGCG also blocked the production of prostaglandin E2, another compound that can cause joint inflammation.

This new study is one of the first to focus on the benefits of green tea on rheumatoid arthritis, which could be good news for rheumatoid arthritis patients, offering a non-drug option to keep their pain under control.

While the research is not yet conclusive and more study is needed, Ahmed said people might want to try drinking three or four 8-ounce cups of green tea per day.“Try different brands,”he suggested.“The flavors may taste slightly different. Drink it continuously throughout the day,”he said, to keep blood levels more constant.

As you’ll discover, what you put into your body will affect your health. And your health, good or bad, will eventually affect your bank account.

 Share This 
 0 Comments Uncategorized 
 Eating Healthy In Texas Means Paying Attention To Fat 
 23rd December 2009 written by moderator 
Fat is bad, right?

Actually, it all depends on the type of fat that’s being consumed.

In reality, there are good fats (omega 3 fatty acids) and not so good ones (omega 6s), but scientists now have a better understanding of where the good and the bad are found, which means residents of Houston, Dallas and Austin, and throughout Texas have the information they need to make better eating decisions, increasing their likelihood of living longer and healthier.

The good fats, found in fish, walnuts, and flaxseed, are known to boost brain power, stave off depression, and decrease inflammation. While the typical American diet lacks the Omega-3s, that same diet is typically full of the bad stuff—omega-6s, found in vegetable oils and processed foods.

Nutritionists agree that a diet full of Omega-6 fats may be to blame for the dramatic rise in inflammatory diseases such as asthma, heart disease, and cancer. While most omega-6s—including trans fats that come from the partial hydrogenation of vegetable oil—are unhealthy, a lesser-known member of the omega-6 family called conjugated linoleic acid (CLA) may promote weight loss, build lean muscle, boost immunity, and even halt the growth of cancer.

Levels of CLA, a fatty acid found only in the meat and milk of ruminants such as cattle, are higher in animals fed on lush pastures, but that’s not what most cows eat. Rather, they are fed mostly grains. A 1999 study, published in the Journal of Dairy Science, found that milk from grass-fed cows contained up to 500 percent more CLA than milk from cows fed a diet of 50 percent grain.

CLA is found only in the fat of milk, and not in skim milk or non-fat yogurt. People can, however, take CLA as a supplement. It is thought that CLA can also help with weight loss and increase lean body mass, although not all studies agree on this. One study that showed promise was published in the International Journal of Obesity. When 40 overweight men and women took a daily 3.2-gram CLA supplement or a placebo, those who took CLA lost an average of 1.3 pounds, while those in the placebo group gained 2.4 pounds. While the difference is small, it could be enough to halt middle-age weight gain.

The study’s lead author, Dale Schoeller, Ph.D., says CLA appears to improve fat metabolism. According to Schoeller, fat loss was statistically significant in seven out of the 18 human studies he reviewed; 11 others showed a more modest trend toward fat loss.“Most of the studies that didn’t show’statistically significant’weight loss were done for too short a time at too low a dose,”says Schoeller, who says people taking a daily supplement of CLA would lose an average of five pounds over two years.

Researchers are also investigating CIA’s potential to boost immunity and reduce symptoms of inflammatory disorders such as allergies and asthma. CLA may also have anti-carcinogenic properties, with studies showing the effect of CLA halting cancer growth—especially in breast, skin, and colon cancers.

The question of whether to drink more milk or take a supplement to get the most out of CLA may depend on the health benefits being sought. The greatest health benefits seem to be concentrated in just two of more than two dozen isomers in CLA. Those two, known as t10c12 and c9t11, may both be needed to lose weight and enhance overall immune function, and milk is rich in only one of them: c9t11. For that reason, supplements may make the most sense for people wanting to lose weight.

For people looking primarily for anti-cancer benefits, milk may be a smarter choice, since 92% of the CLA in milk from grass-fed cows is the cancer-inhibiting c9tll isomer. Further, some studies have shown that the two isomers in CLA supplements may cancel each other out in terms of anti-cancer protection.

Making healthy choices when it comes to eating remains one of the best ways to maintain good health, at any age.

 Share This 
 0 Comments Uncategorized 
 Bariatric Surgery Texas – New Rays of Hope for the Obese 
 23rd December 2009 written by moderator 
Laparoscopic Adjustable Gastric Band (LAGB) is creating ripples in the world of medicine. It is the latest weapon in humanity’s battle against obesity. Weight loss surgery has historically been considered as a solution that only came as a last resort. The complicated, and often permanent nature of the surgery, kept the general populace away from it by and large. While diet-control, exercises and even appetite-suppressants were gaining in popularity, weight loss surgery was looked upon as the final resort when everything else failed. However, with the introduction of Laparoscopic Adjustable Gastric Banding (LAGB) it is now becoming the mainstream solution for sustained weight loss.

Also known as Bariatric Surgery, LAGB or Gastric Banding is being embraced by an increasing number of people to bring about rapid weight loss and also keep it off. So what is LAGB or Bariatric Surgery? LAGB is an adjustable gastric band designed to help you lose excess weight and keep it off – for life. It is the only adjustable and reversible weight-loss procedure available in the United States and the only weight-loss surgery approved for use by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA). The band restricts the amount of food that can be consumed at one time. It also produces an earlier sense of fullness so that you feel satisfied with smaller portions.

The procedure does not require stomach cutting and stapling or gastrointestinal re-routing to bypass normal digestion. It is a minimally-invasive laparoscopic procedure which takes less than 45 minutes and is performed on an out-patient basis allowing patients to return home the same day and resume normal activities within 24-48 hours. Due to its success in enabling sustained weight loss, LAGB is now being offered to slightly and moderately overweight people and is not just for people who are morbidly obese.

According to the World Health Organization, laparoscopic adjustable gastric band (LAGB) has been used in more than 300,000 procedures worldwide, this simple medical device
has safely helped many overweight individuals successfully achieve and maintain significant long-term weight loss to reduce the health risks associated obesity.

Research has shown that the gastric band works better than a 500-calorie diet. In a study conducted in Melbourne, Australia, 80 patients who were, on an average, 52 pounds over a healthy weight, were recruited. Half of them had the laparoscopic adjustable gastric band surgery. The other half followed a medical program that included a variety of strategies such as a very-low-calorie diet (500 calories a day) with liquid meal replacements, prescription weight-loss medication and behavioral therapies.

After six months, both the surgery patients and the low-calorie dieters lost an average of 14% of their starting weight. After two years, the gastric band patients lost 22% of their starting weight. That was about 87% of their excess weight, or roughly 45 pounds. They also showed marked improvement in their health and quality of life.

For those living in Texas and considering Bariatric Surgery, iVital is the best destination. Specializing in weight loss surgery, especially Bariatric Surgery in Texas, iVital offers one of the best services in the area. iVital’s principle Bariatric surgeon is Joseph Cribbins, M.D. Dr. Cribbins has performed over 1,000 LAGB procedures in the last six years and is considered by his peers and patients to be one of the top Bariatric surgeons in the Dallas / Ft. Worth metroplex.

iVital houses some of the finest customer care advisors, advocates, nurses and physicians to ensure that you receive the utmost attention and care and the best possible weight loss solutions available today. The best address for Bariatric surgery in Texas is definitely iVital.
Suzanne

Suzanne Macguire is a veteran in Internet marketing and a wordsmith par excellence with countless articles on a wide range of subjects to his credit. She is a big enthusiast of weight loss surgery.

 Share This 
 0 Comments Uncategorized 
 Losing Weight For Texas Women An Ongoing Challenge 
 23rd December 2009 written by moderator 
It’s not that women in Texas have any greater a challenge than those living elsewhere in the U.S. But when you consider its sheer size—with cities like Austin, Dallas and Houston the Lone Star State is one of the most populous in the country—trends on issues like dieting emerge.

Like it or not, perhaps because of society’s near-obsession with how people look, there’s a continuing focus on losing unwanted pounds. With that focus comes a plethora of“suggestions”that typically take the form of diets, fad or otherwise, that typically promise wondrous results in no time at all.

Among the programs millions of women have tried with varying results: those with the names Atkins, South Beach and Weight Watchers, as well as products from companies such as NutriSystem, Jenny Craig and Slim Fast. The list goes on, and on, and on.

But have women always had this focus on weight and weight loss?

Apparently not. In the 19th century—the 1800s—the vast majority of people, 97% in fact, had a healthy weight as determined by their body size. Just 3% of people in the adult population were considered to be overweight.

Yet today, that number is something on the order of 60%, with a doubling and tripling of the number of overweight children in recent years. And, whether someone has health insurance or not, experts are quick to point out that such numbers are not something to take lightly.

So what’s changed? Willpower? The diets themselves?

Many say the real culprit is a combination of food and lifestyle, both of which aren’t improving when it comes to promoting good health. With depletion of soils and a proliferation of mega farms that are increasing so far away from where the food is purchased and consumed, the reality is that food today has far less nutrition than what our ancestors ate even just a few decades ago. In short, there’s just not as much goodness in what we put in our mouths.

While we obviously can’t change (easily that is) where we live and how food is grown and subsequently processed, taking high quality multi-vitamin supplements is one way healthy people today are coping. For women, who typically have another problem—a lack of time—another way to gain the nutritional edge they need might be through a daily protein smoothie shake, a tasty habit that’s likely to be an easy and enjoyable way to deal with the nutritional issue Texas residents face.

There’s also the issue of how much food we eat. Even a modest ingestion of excess food—100 calories a day—adds up to about 10 extra pounds a year. Five years later, it’s 50 pounds and we wonder what happened. The message: you need to stop the gain before you can think about taking off the excess weight.

Food aside (and some would underscore the point that setting at least some food aside is, in itself, a pretty good idea), the issue of exercise is another area where Texas women—especially in larger cities like Dallas, Austin and Houston where typically sedentary office work may be more common than elsewhere—can get where they want to be from a health perspective.

One of the easiest, least expensive ways to raise the bar when it comes to the exercise quotient is to take a walk. Even a half hour in place of a TV sitcom (bring your MP3 player along if nature isn’t company enough) can, over time, make a significant and healthier difference. Joining (and, more importantly, going to) a gym can be another way to sustain the exercise routine, especially if a woman can team up with a friend or colleague who also wants to benefit from the power of accountability.

Some women have also found journaling—writing down what they eat and how much (or little) exercise they do—to be a great way to hold themselves accountable. That activity is, in itself, an eye-opener. And when the one doing the journaling does a little detective work (such as finding out what is actually contained, in the form of fat and calories, in the food being consumed), it becomes a real tool for healthy life change.

Another tip for a healthier lifestyle is to limit the number of restaurant visits in any given period of time. One of the bigger areas of risk is the typical fast food restaurant, although even there healthier choices abound—think grilled chicken breast instead of the double bacon cheeseburger on the full color menu.

But is all this change worth it? And, more to the point, is it really going to make a difference? Experts will tell you, regardless of age, it’s never too late to make a lifestyle change related to weight and nutrition.

Your heart will love you for it.

Weight and nutrition are ongoing concerns in today’s modern society. But there are things that anyone can do to improve their health, regardless of their age. How you take care of yourself will certainly affect you as you age, and eventually your wallet, as well.

 Share This 
 0 Comments Uncategorized 
 Texas Runners Find Many Benefits From The Activity 
 23rd December 2009 written by moderator 
Why do runners run?

For those who haven’t taken up the activity, the question may seem to be imponderable, given the pain, boredom and exhausting nature that seem to be part and parcel of the activity.

The fact is, people living in Dallas, Houston and Austin, and throughout Texas, run for a variety of reasons, including simply to stay in shape and/or to maintain what they consider an ideal body weight.

Experts say that a combination of diet and exercise is the most effective way to lose weight, as it triggers a loss of body fat and an increase in the amount of lean tissue. Running can help a person burn an average of 100 calories per each mile while other popular activities, such as biking and walking, burn a fraction of those calories in the same amount of time. While the average human being may burn about 2,000-2,500 calories a day without exercise, they’ll burn an estimated 500 calories more through running.

Another reason for running is the accessibility of the activity. With a good pair of shoes, most people can run just about anywhere.

How fast does a runner need to run to benefit from the activity? Surprisingly, speed has little effect on the number of calories being burned. The most important factor, experts say, is weight. A 220-pound person running an eight-minute mile will burn 150 calories, while a 120-pound person running at the same pace burns only 82. As a runner’s weight goes down, they’ll burn fewer calories per mile, eventually stabilizing.

Most runners will lose weight quickly at first, but eventually, their weight stops declining and reaches a plateau. At this point, some serious runners will intensify the workouts but recreational runners can maintain their lower body weight by continuing to run consistently.

Health benefits are another motivation for runners. Running is said to help lower blood pressure by maintaining the elasticity of the arteries, expanding and contracting more than usual. Most serious runners have unusually low blood pressure. Running also helps maximize the potential of the lungs, as it keeps them strong and powerful. While deep breaths force the lungs to use more tissue, the 50% of normally unused lung potential is utilized.

Even smokers are said to sometimes recover full lung potential through running. Finally, running is said to help strengthen the heart and may help prevent heart attacks, the large muscle exercise helping to keep the cardio system efficient and strong. The heart of an inactive person beats an estimated 36,000 more times each day than that of a runner, as running keeps the arteries open and blood flowing smoothly.

Runners also say the intense exhilaration and euphoria that comes after a run is the biggest motivator. The physiological reason for the euphoria is a release of beta-endorphin, which is triggered by neurons in the nervous system. Intended to alleviate the pain after a run, it creates a feeling of extreme happiness and exhilaration. The intense high is said to sometimes replace other addictions, including drugs, alcohol, and even food. Runners claim to achieve more energy in daily life from running, but the activity also helps bring appetite, exercise and food into balance while also improving sleep, eating, and relaxation.

While some say running might increase appetite, exercise actually tends to diminish it, say experts. Runners typically pay close attention to their diets, as a means of maintaining a balanced diet that is low in fat. Carbohydrates are especially important for runners because muscles need the glycogen that comes from carbohydrates in order to produce energy. Fats, on the other hand, should not exceed 25% of a runner’s food intake, since muscles do not work well on a fatty diet.
Runners should make sure they drink enough fluids, as these are necessary in allowing blood to transfer glucose to muscles and in flushing out metabolic waste. Insufficient fluids inhibit one’s ability to sweat, necessary for a runner to cool down.

Experts say the most important and effective fluid is water, but others recommend sweetened caffeine drinks before a long race such as a marathon. These drinks are said to boost energy and stamina during a run.

Famous runners have been quoted as ingesting unusual substances as part of a training regimen. Frank Shorter, winner of the 1972 and 1976 Olympic marathons, said he had beer, ring dings, and pizza“topped liberally with mayonnaise”prior to the races. Portugal’s Carlos Lopes was said to have had a steak two hours before winning the gold medal in the 1984 Olympics.

Supplements, sports drinks and smoothies are more common for runners. Most runners are extremely careful about their diets with marathon runners claiming it is important for them to maintain an unusually low body weight in order to run their fastest and reduce the strain on their cartilage, joints, and muscles.

How you treat your body when you’re young will certainly affect your health when you get older. Eventually, it will also affect your wallet as well.

 Share This 
 0 Comments Uncategorized 
 Free Treatment For Diabetics In Texas: Exercise 
 23rd December 2009 written by moderator 
Well, well, well. I do believe we finally have a winner: free therapy for the growing number of those with diabetes. It turns out there are few excuses for diabetics—or any of us, for that matter—not to exercise. According to recent reports, nearly any form of exercise benefits the long-term control of blood sugar levels, be it aerobic, weight/resistance training, or both. Both forms in conjunction worked better than either one alone. This is great news for Texas, with more than 1.8 million estimated diagnosed and undiagnosed diabetics.

There were doubts about the safety and efficacy of weight training for those with diabetes until Dr. Ronald Sigal of the University of Calgary and his colleagues from the University of Ottawa decided to question that assumption. Together, they studied 251 individuals with type-2 diabetes ages thirty-nine to seventy, none of whom exercised regularly. Subjects were broken down into four groups: the first group participated in aerobic training three times a week; the second group did resistance training three times a week; the third upped their heart rates by doing both aerobic and resistance training, for a total of one and a half hours, three times a week; and the fourth group participated in no extra exercise whatsoever.

Participants used treadmills, stationary bikes, and/or weight machines at health clubs, exercised consistently, and were given a diet designed to prevent undo weight loss. Their blood sugar and cholesterol levels were monitored, as were other vital statistics. By the study’s end, which was published in the Annals of Internal Medicine, participants’blood sugar levels had dropped, and—more importantly—so had their A1c levels, hemoglobin that indicates average blood sugar over the past six months.

For those who participated in one form of exercise, their A1c dropped by half a point on average. For those who did both aerobic and resistance training, the average A1c drop was a full point.

A diabetic’s A1c level is of vital importance because it helps measure his or her long-term control of blood sugar. A normal A1c level is between four and six; patients in Sigal’s study began at a concerning 6.6 to 9.9. A one-point drop in this hemoglobin is associated with a fifteen to twenty percent decrease in major cardiovascular events, like heart attacks and strokes, and a thirty-seven percent decrease in complications like kidney, eye, and limb damage.

According to Sigal, there were some who brought their A1c into the normal range—a feat for nearly anyone with this condition. Some participants were even able to reduce their medications, and many lost weight and body fat.

Such studies are pertinent to Texas, which has a diabetic population higher than the national average, and one-quarter of its population going without health insurance. According to 2006 statistics from the Texas Diabetes Council, 1.3 million men and women eighteen and older in the state have the disease, as compared with 15.3 million in the entire country. Another estimated 400,000 in Texas are left undiagnosed.

More Texan men than women have it, and, while non-Hispanic blacks and Hispanics are only a little more likely to be afflicted with the condition than whites, their death rates due to the disease are more than double than that of their white counterparts. In fact, diabetes is the sixth leading cause of death in Texas, and it’s believed the condition is actually underreported on death certificates as both a cause and a condition.

What is, perhaps, even more concerning is that recent studies in Dallas, Houston, and Austin reveal that certain risk factors for the disease, such as obesity, are increasing among children. One in every 400 to 600 children in Texas have type-1 diabetes, a much more serious, autoimmune disorder than its more prevalent counterpart, type-2.

Type-1 diabetes is a condition in which the body essentially attacks its own immune system, destroying insulin-producing cells and requiring patients to administer multiple insulin shots a day, or a pump.

Type-2, on the other hand, is often caused by a combination of poor diet, lack of exercise, and genetic characteristics. Data needed to monitor diabetes trends by type in youth is not yet available, but if incidences of those with risk factors, like obesity, keep increasing, cases of type-2 (if not also type-1) are also expected to rise.

Many in Texas also lack health insurance, a factor recent reports by the Commonwealth Fund reveal to contribute to less access to quality care. Twenty-five percent of the Texas population is currently without health coverage—the worst rate in the nation—and, unless something is done, that number is not expected to improve. High premium costs of most health insurance companies and the debate over the State Children’s Health Insurance Program in Congress add to the strain. Without proper diagnosis and care, diabetes can easily lead to other, sometimes fatal conditions. Any activity a diabetic can do on one’s own that decreases the chances of complications is worth it.

“Imagine an inexpensive pill that could decrease the hemoglobin A1c value by one percentage point, reduce cardio death by twenty-five percent, and substantially improve the functional capacity [strength, endurance and bone density]”wrote Dr. William Kraus of Duke Medical School and Dr. Benjamin Levine of the University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center. They continued by saying all able-bodied diabetics should be prescribed exercise regimens.

Imagine that: something we can all actually do for ourselves—no doctor’s visits, no prescriptions, no therapy appointments, time out of the work day, or exorbitant amounts of cash out of our pockets. Just a matter of getting up off of our couches. Well, well, well.

 Share This 
 0 Comments Uncategorized 
 For Women In Texas, Heart Health Means Taking Action 
 23rd December 2009 written by moderator 
For women in Texas, notably but not exclusively in the larger cities of Dallas, Houston and Austin, health is an ongoing concern, as it is in other areas of the country. One of the biggest health issues is one that’s closest to the heart. Quite literally.

The fact is, heart disease is responsible for the death of more American women under the age of 45 than any other single disease, including breast cancer. Whether someone has health insurance or not, more than half a million women a year die from heart disease. And more than 60% of those had no previous symptoms.

When a woman does find herself suffering from heart disease, she’s less likely than a man to receive aggressive medical treatment, according to the American Heart Association. She’s also more likely than a man to die from heart disease: 38% of women (compared with 25% of men) will die within one year following a heart attack.

While two risk factors—the aging process itself and a family history of heart disease—aren’t something a woman can change, others can be changed.

Smoking is one area that can tip the scales in favor of a woman, as far as risk of heart disease is concerned. With numerous support programs available, in cities such as Houston, Dallas and Austin and throughout Texas, a woman wanting to quit smoking is well-equipped to do so, with the healthful benefits to follow.
And more and more people are deciding to quit, the overall number of adult smokers having decreased during the last 20 years.

Unfortunately, the number of teenage girls that are taking up the habit is actually increasing, which is a reason for concern. Smoking lowers levels of good cholesterol, which increases the risk of heart disease. And cigarette smoking combined with the use of birth control pills has also been shown to increase the risk of heart attack or stroke.

Another factor that contributes to heart disease is high blood pressure or hypertension. Left untreated, the condition makes the heart work harder, speeds up hardening of the arteries (known as atherosclerosis) and increases the risk of heart attack, stroke and kidney failure. While high blood pressure can sometimes occur during pregnancy, it usually goes away after childbirth. Although high blood pressure cannot be cured, doctors say it can be controlled with diet, exercise, and, if necessary, medicines.

Cholesterol levels are another risk factor when it comes to heart disease, and women in general have higher cholesterol levels than men due to the positive effect of estrogen on HDL, one of the most important predictors of cardiovascular health, according to a study in the American Journal of Cardiology. In short, the higher the level of HDL cholesterol, the less likely a woman is to have a heart attack or stroke. Once a woman goes through menopause, however, HDL levels tend to drop, increasing the risk of heart disease. HDL and LDL cholesterol levels can be improved by diet, exercise and, in some cases, cholesterol-lowering medicines.

Want more out of life? One way is to become less of a person, at least so far as your weight is concerned. Obesity is certainly a strong predictor for heart disease, but where the weight settles is also an important factor. The Texas Heart Institute, based at Houston’s St. Luke’s Episcopal Hospital, says women who have a lot of fat around the waist are at greater risk than those who have fat around the hips. A plan of diet and exercise approved by a doctor is the best way to safely lose weight.

Yet another area of health concern in women at risk for heart disease is diabetes. A correlation between obesity, physical inactivity and high cholesterol levels may be part of the reason, but studies show that women with diabetes have a higher risk of death from cardiovascular disease than men with diabetes do. Proper management of diabetes is, therefore, even more important to women, throughout Texas and elsewhere.

Birth control pills may also pose an increased cardiovascular risk for women, especially those with other risk factors such as smoking. Researchers believe birth control pills raise blood pressure and blood sugar levels in some women and also increase the risk of blood clots, risks which increase as women get older. The advice of some: communicate with your doctor about any other cardiovascular risk factors that might exist, before taking birth control pills.

Drinking alcohol on an excessive basis is another risk factor when it comes to heart disease in women, notably in terms of its contribution to obesity and the raising of triglyceride and blood pressure levels, all factors which can cause heart failure and lead to stroke. While some studies have shown that the risk of heart disease in those who drink moderate amounts of alcohol can be lower than among those who do not drink alcohol, it doesn’t mean those who do not drink should start or that those who do drink alcohol should increase the amount they drink. For women, a moderate amount of alcohol is considered to be one drink per day.

Hopefully, none of this is adding to your levels of stress, which is, itself, considered to be a contributing risk factor for both men and women. While researchers are as yet unclear about the relationship to heart disease, stress can lead to other risk factors such as smoking and overeating.

For women in particular, heart disease can be a significant health concern. Thankfully, there are things that anyone can do to reduce that risk. Yet even then, knowing that various options exist can be something of value.

 Share This 
 0 Comments Uncategorized 
ABOUT

Texas Delivery Service
 
RECENT POSTS
 23rd December 2009 That Fizzy Goodness In Texas May Be Linked To Cancer 23rd December 2009 Colon Cleansing Methods in Houston Texas 23rd December 2009 Do Drink The Water In Texas 23rd December 2009 A Cup Of Green Tea May Help Keep The Doctor Away In Texas 23rd December 2009 Eating Healthy In Texas Means Paying Attention To Fat 
 July 2012 M T W T F S S «Dec       1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31   
 
BLOGROLL


 
META

 Log in Valid XHTML XFN WordPress 
 
ARCHIVE

 December 2009 
 
 ©Copyright 2012 | Diet Delivery Texas |  Articles (RSS)   Comments (RSS) | Privacy Policies
	</body>
</document>
