<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002264" url="http://www.tobagobnb.co.za/tobagobnb_more_links.htm" time="2012-07-12-18:09" support="1" score="0.00031435837728925175" bingtitle="South Africa guest house - Jeffreys Bay accommodation" webtitle="South Africa guest house">
			<query id="001081" bing-rank="178"/>
	<description>A fast food restaurant and licenced pub, it is on the main ... For weddings we have a 150 seat chapel and ... period furniture augmented by a large collection of ...</description>
	<body>
		South Africa 
 | guest house | 
 activities | camping | guest farm | hotel | hunting | tour 

 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 

 Links 

 If you 
 are interested in exchanging links with this site please take a moment to 
 read the following. 

 We seek a 
 link from a minimum PR3 site which must also be a relevant site. 

 To 
 suggest a link, please e-mail the webmaster with your link 
 information and make mention of this site (we maintain a large 
 number of sites). If you suggest a link to a site that does not meet 
 the simple criteria mentioned above we will not link to you. 

 If we 
 like the proposed link we will put your link up and e-mail you 
 informing you where you can see it and providing in turn the link 
 information we would like you to use. 

 We 
 endeavour to do this within a week at the outside and we trust that 
 you will respond as promptly. If you fail to put up our link on your 
 site within a reasonable period then we will remove your link from 
 this site. 
 
 Below are 
 some more tourism links. 
 
 travel tourism links 
 tourist activities 
 Back 
 Tourist Activities 

 Bedford 
 Garden Festival 

 Bedford has long had a tradition of 
 gardening and to-day the area abounds in fine gardens, each one having 
 its own character. In years past, these gardens were opened to the 
 public on an informal basis but in 2003 it was decided to create the Bedford Garden Festival . 

 Cracklin Rosy 

 A fast food restaurant and licenced 
 pub, it is on the main road through town. This makes it the ideal Uniondale restaurant for a 
 lunch break or a refreshing cold drink. The menu includes something 
 for everyone&apos;s taste and the whole family will enjoy the good food, 
 relaxed atmosphere and warm hospitality. 

 Dans Den 4x4 Lodge 

 Dans Den 4x4 Lodge is a Pub, 
 camping area, 4x4 test track as well as gathering place for 4x4 enthusiasts and a departure point for various 4x4 routes in 
 the Steytlerville and Baviaanskloof areas. 

 Karoo River Rafting 

 Set in the stunning surrounds 
 of the Karoo, this perfect farm get-away combines the 
 breathtaking beauty of the veld, expansive horizons, 
 blue-grey mountains, wide-open skies and all-year round 
 exciting Karoo River Rafting . 

 Karoo Spoor 

 Karoo Spoor - Unique experiences 
 in the Schoombee Karoo, a place of vast grassy plains 
 interspersed with xerophytic shrubs, flat topped hills and 
 majestic mountains. It is also a place filled with spoor 
 from the past and the present. Perfect for a Karoo Adventure . 

 Quad East Cape 

 Quad East Cape specialises in organised 
 quad bike or ATV rallies, rides routes, events and tours in the Eastern 
 Cape Province of South Africa. For the greatest in Quad Bike Adventures . 

 Speekhout Camping&amp;Bonsai 

 Speekhout&apos;s Baviaanskloof accommodation is all about relaxed camping. Stop and enjoy the fantastic 
 collection of bonsai. 

 

 WebAdz Designs travel tourism links tourist activities 
 
 travel tourism links 
 tourist activities 
 
 
 
 travel tourism links 
 camping tenting 
 Back 
 Camping 

 Bakkrans 

 

 Sleep in the open beneath a dramatic cliff 
 overhang in a gorge close to the road and with easy access from parking. 
 The site is equipped with gas and paraffin lamps, built- in braai, hot 
 and cold shower and flush toilet, mattresses, cooking utensils for up to 
 15 people. Baviaanskloof accommodation with a difference! 

 

 Baviaanskloof Uitspan Campsite 

 

 Camp at the Baviaanskloof Uitspan Campsite 
 and really&quot;span uit&quot;amid the spectacular scenery and peace and quiet 
 of the Baviaanskloof , the scenic 
 wonderland of the Eastern Cape. There is also a charming thatched lapa 
 available for the use of guests. It comes complete with a bar and an 
 indoor braai as well as a pool table for evening relaxation. There is 
 also a big screen television for those who do not want to miss out on 
 their sport or&quot;soapies&quot;. 

 

 Bruintjieskraal Campsite 

 

 The Bruintjieskraal Campsite offers campers 
 a scenic, private camping spot to camp in the Grootrivier poort for 
 ideal Baviaanskloof camping . 

 

 Doringkloof Quads and 
 Bush Camp 

 

 In the centre of the Baviaanskloof we offer 
 five interesting 4x4 routes in the spectacular Baviaanskloof and Kouga 
 Mountains. Why not base yourself here at our shady Baviaanskloof accommodation bush campsites whilst exploring? 

 

 Peace of Quiet Campsite 

 Situated in a small walnut orchard, the 
 camp site is Baviaanskloof accommodation in a beautiful remote place to pitch a tent or sleep under 
 the stars. In summer enjoy the shade of walnut trees, and swim in the 
 concrete dam swimming pool. 

 

 Tia Ghee Tented Camp 

 

 Less than one hour&apos;s drive from Port 
 Elizabeth and even less from Jeffrey&apos;s Bay, a short way from the village 
 of Patensie, there lies a tranquil bush camp in thick indigenous forest 
 offering tented Baviaanskloof accommodation - Tia 
 Ghee. Tia Ghee is catered and fully equipped so as to make it as 
 straightforward an experience as possible. 

 

 Uniondale Caravan Park 

 

 Uniondale Caravan Park on Route 62 is the ideal stopover for caravaners and campers 
 when travelling from Johannesburg to George, Oudtshoorn, the Langkloof, 
 the Baviaanskloof or when visiting Uniondale, a holiday destination in 
 its own right. 

 

 WebAdz Designs travel tourism links camping tenting 
 
 travel tourism links 
 camping tenting 
 
 
 Back 
 
 South Africa 
 guest farms 

 Albertspark Guest 
 Farm 

 Close to the main route from Willowmore to the Baviaanskloof, 
 Albertspark is the perfect Baviaans accommodation to overnight en route to or from the 
 Baviaanskloof or to spend a few days in the country. Accommodation is 
 self catering, B&amp;B or camping. 

 Baviaans Wes 
 Guest House 

 Baviaans Wes Guesthouse and Farm Stays 
 offer a typical South African farm holiday. The farm is situated 
 approximately 30 kilometers from Uniondale for pleasant Uniondale accommodation . 

 Bokloof 

 Bo-Kloof offers self-catering or B&amp;B 
 accommodation for up to six persons in a guesthouse which is part of the 
 farmstead but which is completely self-contained and separate to ensure 
 our guests enjoy their Baviaanskloof 
 accommodation . 

 Charlottes Web - Guest Farm 

 For Port Elizabeth functions and picnics in Sardinia Bay. 

 Elandsheuwel 
 Guest Farm 

 Elandsheuwel Guest Farm is situated 
 approximately 45 Kilometers from Steytlerville on the main road to 
 Willowmore and is a working Angora goat and Merino sheep farm as well as 
 carrying much game. It offers a Karoo farm stay in bed and 
 breakfast accommodation in a separate wing of the homestead, 
 self-catering accommodation in a guest house in the veld and camp sites 
 deep in a kloof in the mountains. 

 Glen Avon 
 Farm 

 Glen Avon - A visit to this unique 
 historical farm near Somerset East is like taking a step into the past. 
 Some of the buildings date back to 1817 and the guest cottages are 
 furnished with restored furniture from days gone by. Perfect for a Karoo Farm Holiday . 

 Glenmore Farm Cottage and 4x4 

 Five 4x4 trails on Glenmore Farm, a 
 picturesque and peaceful farm in the Groot River Valley offer you ample 
 time to experience the rugged beauty of the Karoo firsthand during your Karoo farm stay . 

 Haaspoort 

 Haaspoort is the ultimate 
 luxury for the person who enjoys the outdoor life in its 
 natural surroundings. The Karoo bush camp is 
 nestled in the mountains and gives the visitor a feeling of 
 total remoteness and tranquillity is the highlight. 

 Hartebeest Post 4x4 and Farm Stay 

 Hartebeest Post is located on the Hartebees 
 River Road 19 kilometers outside Uniondale en route to the Baviaanskloof. 
 It is the ideal farm stay stopover for making an early start to explore the 
 Baviaanskloof. 

 Hillston 
 Farm 

 Escape to the tranquillity and clean air 
 of the Karoo - visit Hillston Farm for a true Karoo farm stay . Here you will 
 find vast grassy plains interspersed with xerophytic shrubs, flat 
 topped hills, majestic mountains, stars, clear skies, silence, 
 space, fresh air and peace. On Hillston Farm Mount Melsetter as well 
 as the Brak River provides ample opportunity for activity. 

 Huntly Glen 

 Only a pleasant 3 hours&apos; drive from the 
 airport cities of Port Elizabeth or East London, in the district of 
 Bedford, Huntly Glen farm stay is very convenient for a 
 hunting safari or a week-end getaway with self-catering accommodation in 
 a separate farm house. 

 Kamala Game Reserve 

 The 6000ha Kamala private game reserve is home to 
 an abundance of wildlife and offers a wide range of 
 activities and adventures in a natural setting of 
 extraordinary beauty. Our private and exclusive bush camps 
 are as close to nature as you can get and yet, offer the 
 utmost in luxury and comfort. 

 Kumnandi 
 Lodge 

 Kumnandi Lodge lies in the most 
 beautiful part of Willowmore district at the foot of 
 Aasvolberg. Only a few hundred metres from the N9 between Graaff Reinet and George it is an ideal overnight stop and 
 suitable self catering accommodation for weekend getaways or 
 a typical Karoo Farm holiday . 

 Lans Rivier Guest House 

 Ideal self catering weekend and 
 holiday farm stay accommodation in two beautifully restored and 
 decorated guesthouses dating back to the early 1900&apos;s in 
 peaceful surroundings in a valley of trees between the hills 
 of the Kammanassie Mountains. 

 Marlu Guest 
 Farm 

 Located halfway between 
 Steytlerville and Willowmore, 7 km off the R329 (easy access 
 for sedan cars) and roughly equidistant from Port Elizabeth, 
 Jeffreys Bay, Knysna, Oudtshoorn, Beaufort West and 
 Graaff-Reinet, Marlu is the ideal Karoo Farm Stay from 
 which to explore the attractions of the Baviaans region. 

 Mentorskraal 
 Venue 

 Mentorskraal is the largest venue for Jeffreys Bay conferences, Jeffreys Bay 
 weddings and has a wide variety of accommodation to 
 suit all tastes. 

 Monkeyview B&amp;B 

 Only 90 kilometres from Port Elizabeth 
 near the village of Paterson, Monkeyview Bed and Breakfast offers a Port Elizabeth accommodation farm getaway in a tranquil malaria free environment. It is centrally 
 situated amongst well-known Eastern Cape Game Reserves such as Addo 
 Elephant National Park and Shamwari Game Reserve. Game drives and 
 day trips to these and other nearby game farms can be arranged. 
 Mpunzi Game Lodge 

 Mpunzi Game and Nature Reserve 
 is a 600 hectare Port Elizabeth game lodge in valley bushveld situated only a 40 minutes drive from 
 Port Elizabeth en route to the Cock&apos;s Comb Mountains and 
 further on to the Baviaanskloof Wilderness Area. 

 Nixbe Farm Stays 

 Nixbe Farm Stays offers young people a karoo farm stay to get away from 
 the pressures of urban life and to experience the fresh air as well as 
 the safe and wholesome fun of life in the country. 

 Pinelands Farm B&amp;B 

 Pinelands farm was founded in the mid 
 1820`s at Wolwefontein in the southern Karoo halfway between 
 Graaff-Reinet/Willowmore and Port Elizabeth. It makes an ideal stop over 
 when travelling from P.E. to Graaff-Reinet or for a short weekend Karoo 
 farm stay . 

 San Valley Guest Farm and Mountain Pastures 
 Game Reserve 

 Upmarket Garden Route Game Lodge and Uniondale 
 Accommodation and game viewing at San Valley, 
 a beautiful and ecologically concerned estate. 

 Schanskraal Game 
 Reserve 

 Enjoy a Karoo farm stay on a 
 fourteen thousand hectare game reserve in the foothills of 
 the Sneeuberg Mountains in South Africa&apos;s Eastern Cape 
 province, Schanskraal offers world-class self-catering 
 accommodation at The Manor, a restored homestead furnished 
 with Cape Dutch antiques. For those on a tighter budget, 
 stay at Burgersrust self-catering lodge. Also stay in a 
 luxury guest house in beautiful Graaff-Reinet. 

 

  
 
 
 
 travel tourism links hotels 
 inns 
 Back 
 Hotels&amp;Inns 

 Africanos Inn 

 Africanos Inn, Bar, Grill&amp;Barn is the only three star graded Hotel situated in the 
 Sundays River Valley in the Eastern Cape, South Africa near 
 the village of Addo, a totally malaria free area. Enjoy 
 upmarket Addo Accommodation in 
 luxury chalets with en suite bathrooms and lounges. For 
 weddings we have a 150 seat chapel and we can seat up to 300 
 people for a reception. We also have Conference Facilities. 
 Addo Elephant National Park is only 10 minutes drive away. 

 Albertinia Hotel 

 This charming and unique 
 country hotel on the Garden Route was established in 1900 
 and has ever since built on an outstanding reputation for 
 country hospitality at its best. Its wonderful ambiance, 
 food, comfortable Garden Route Accommodation and service has given the hotel a national as well as an 
 international reputation and it enjoys a three star rating 
 by the Tourism Grading Council of South Africa. The fine 
 food served at the Albertinia Hotel has become something of 
 a legend. 

 Golden 
 Valley Country Inn Hotel 

 Golden Valley Country Inn is situated 
 midway between the Addo Elephant National Park and the Mountain Zebra 
 National Park in the Karoo Heartland near the towns of Cookhouse and 
 Somerset East. For gracious Karoo accommodation . 

 Karroo Theatrical Hotel 

 A country Hotel 
 2 kms outside Steytlerville which has been painstakingly 
 restored to it&apos;s original elegance and offers surprising 
 comfort and sophistication in the depths of the Karoo. The 
 hotel offers a variety of Steytlerville accommodation to suit different needs and budgets, has a pool,a nearby 
 golf course and more. The hosts even put on a professional 
 supper club cabaret in season. 

 Midgley&apos;s Hotel 

 Midgley&apos;s Hotel, standing in the heart of 
 Adelaide, is an historical hotel which has been carefully renovated so 
 as to make it light and cheerful while retaining its old world charm of 
 high-ceilinged spaciousness, solid wood furniture and fittings and 
 generally gracious air. Adelaide accommodation at its best. 

 Royal Herberg Hotel 

 Willowmore is on the N9 halfway between George 
 and Graaff-Reinet. Come and enjoy Willowmore accommodation and warm hospitality in our country Hotel. 

 WebAdz Designs travel tourism links hotels inns 
 
 travel tourism links hotels 
 inns 
 
 
 
 travel tourism links 
 hunting safaris 
 Back 
 Hunting 
 Safaris 

 African 
 Field Sports 

 African Field Sports is the 
 elite of hunting safaris and offers the discerning hunter 
 big game and plains game hunting safaris in 
 Botswana or in South Africa&apos;s malaria-free Eastern Cape 
 province. 

 East Cape 
 and Karoo Safaris 

 Our professionally guided hunting safaris in the pristine 
 beauty that surrounds the rugged mountains of Somerset East 
 will remain in your thoughts for ever. Our Hunting Safaris are 
 based on the Kamala Game Reserve which is home to more than 
 28 species of animals. 

 Richard Holmes 
 Safaris 

 African plains game hunting safaris in South Africa&apos;s malaria-free Eastern Cape. 

 Thembalethu Safaris 

 Situated in the fascinating 
 Noorsveld, Thembalethu Safaris is a guest farm which abounds 
 with game and is a perfect getaway for hunting safaris or 
 camera safaris. Hike or ride the 6,500 hectares by 4x4, 4x2 
 or on one of our horses and enjoy our fourteen species of 
 buck as well as the other fauna and flora. 

 Umgamanzi 
 Hunting Safaris 

 Umgamanzi Hunting Safaris for 
 hunting, photography and game viewing safaris in the 
 malaria-free Karoo and Eastern Cape Province of South 
 Africa. 

 

 WebAdz Designs travel tourism links hunting safaris 

 
 
 travel tourism links tour 
 operators 
 Back 
 Tour Operators 

 Baviaanskloof - A Virtual Tour 

 Come and enjoy a virtual tour of the 
 fabulous Baviaanskloof and whet your appetite to come and visit this 
 wilderness area in South Africa&apos;s Eastern Cape. Lots of Baviaanskloof Information . 

 Baviaanskloof Heritage Tours 

 Baviaanskloof Heritage tours commence at 
 Willowmore and terminate in either Patensie or at Steytlerville. The 
 ideal  baviaanskloof tours for holidays 
 originating in Cape Town or the Western Cape. 

 Baviaanskloof 
 Mountain Passes 

 Experience the scenic wonders 
 of the Garden Route and Eastern Cape in three interesting 
 tours, originating in George, Plettenberg Bay and Jeffrey&apos;s 
 Bay respectively. Each tour includes a visit to the 
 spectacular Baviaanskloof Wilderness Area. Along the way, travel a number of historic 
 and scenically beautiful mountain passes in the Klein Karoo, 
 the Garden Route and the Eastern Cape. 

 Baviaanskloof Tours 

 If you do not have a 4x4 vehicle, join one 
 of our baviaanskloof 
 tours to see the fabulous Baviaanskloof. 

 Shield Tours 

 For interesting and personalised conducted tours, historical tours, battlefield 
 tours in South Africa&apos;s Cape. 

 Sunrise Africa 

 Sunrise Africa for a choice selection of South Africa 
 tours, African safaris to suit all tastes and 
 pockets. 

 West to 
 Wild Coast 

 A choice selection of self-drive and 
 organised tours for the visitor to South Africa. Our Self Drive Tours are predominantly, 
 but not exclusively, in the scenic Western and Eastern Cape, many 
 originating in Cape Town. 

 WebAdz Designs travel tourism links tour operators 
 
 travel tourism links tour 
 operators 
 
 
 Back 
 
 
 South Africa 
 Guest House links 

 137 High Street Guest House 

 137 High Street Guest House, Grahamstown , 
 offers bed and breakfast accommodation in an historic house 
 in the heart of the charming university town of Grahamstown, 
 Eastern Cape, South Africa. 

 Avondrust Guest House and B&amp;B - Graaff-Reinet 

 A beautiful Edwardian 
 guesthouse in the centre of historic and architecturally 
 interesting Graaff-Reinet with five spacious bedrooms, all 
 en-suite, opening onto a lovely garden with a pool and braai 
 facilities. And all the hospitality you could want in your Graaff-Reinet Accommodation . 

 B D Lodge 

 Exclusive Mozambique accommodation on 
 Bartholomeu Dias Point, boasting long stretches of unspoilt white 
 beaches. This tropical paradise is situated in Inhassoro. 

 Buckingham 
 Place Guest House 

 Port Elizabeth Accommodation in a charming and tastefully restored Edwardian house with 
 many Oregon pine features, Buckingham Guest House provides conveniently 
 located accommodation on a bed and breakfast or self-catering basis in a 
 quiet street in Mount Croix, Port Elizabeth. The Guest House is close to 
 Greenacres shopping centre and the shops of Westbourne Road, the Cape 
 Road business district, hospitals, restaurants, cinemas and sporting 
 facilities. 

 Cape St Francis Resort 

 Cape St Francis, with it&apos;s historic Seal 
 Point Lighthouse, is a tranquil eco-destination. The pristine beach, the 
 mild temperature and the longest sunshine hours on the South African 
 Coast ensure relaxed all year round Cape St Francis accommodation 

 Cavers Country Guest House 

 Set in the picturesque Cowie 
 Valley near Bedford, Cavers Country Guest House offers 
 guests a unique opportunity to enjoy luxurious Bedford Accommodation , 
 warm hospitality and spectacular views of the tranquil 
 surroundings. 

 Cedar Guest House and Retreat 

 Our farm is in the middle of the 
 Baviaanskloof. We are surrounded by the beautiful, wild and untamed 
 Kouga Mountains - a small insignificant home in amongst the vastness of 
 this incredible wilderness landscape. A unique Baviaanskloof accommodation experience. 

 Coral Tree Guest House 

 A Port Elizabeth guest house , Coral 
 Tree guest house, offers child friendly accommodation in Port 
 Elizabeth. Coral Tree Guest House offers convenient, comfortable and 
 affordable bed and breakfast and self-catering accommodation in Port 
 Elizabeth, Nelson Mandela Bay, Eastern Cape, South Africa. 

 Enchanted Rock 

 At the foot of the Suurberg Mountains, near 
 the little town of Alicedale and only an hour&apos;s drive from Port 
 Elizabeth and the Sunshine Coast in South Africa&apos;s malaria-free Eastern 
 Cape is situated Enchanted Rock Guest House, a rather special Addo guest house . 

 Finchley Farm Cottage 

 Finchley Farm is 3 kms outside. The 
 beautifully restored cottage stands in the shady garden of the homestead 
 and dates back to the late 1800s, is tastefully furnished and decorated 
 with numerous historic items for a comfortable Karoo farm stay . 

 King Georges Guesthouse 

 King George&apos;s Guesthouse is an up 
 market, three star-guesthouse, situated in the exclusive 
 Mill Park suburb of Port Elizabeth, centrally located with 
 easy access to the airport, beaches, golf courses, shopping 
 and the city centre. This 1915 manor-style house has been 
 lovingly restored with original Oregon pine doors and 
 stained glass windows. Port Elizabeth accommodation at its best. 

 No 6 
 Guesthouse 

 This charming historic, luxuriously 
 furnished and decorated guest house is located in central Graaff-Reinet 
 and is close to all amenities, national monuments and art galleries. No 
 6 Guest House has 3 bedrooms, 2 bathrooms, kitchen, dining room, lounge 
 and garden with braai facilities ensuring a comfortable Graaff-Reinet accommodation stay. 
 It is booked out as a unit on either a self-catering, bed and breakfast 
 or full board basis. 

 Port Elizabeth St. George&apos;s Club 

 St. George&apos;s Club for Port Elizabeth accommodation , 
 conferences, functions, receptions, weddings in Port 
 Elizabeth South Africa. 

 Sederkloof Lodge 

 The ultimate Baviaanskloof accommodation getaway. The ethos of Sederkloof is the tranquil enjoyment 
 of what the spectacular Baviaanskloof has to offer. To 
 enhance the experience, the complex has been so designed as 
 to create the minimum visual impact upon the environment. 

 Somerset House Guest House and B&amp;B 

 Somerset House to-day is a guest house, both 
 spacious and elegant. Those who enjoy gracious living, silver service 
 breakfasts and the like will appreciate staying here. The very best in Somerset East Accommodation . 

 Stanley Island 

 Stanley Island is the only privately owned 
 island in South Africa for Accommodation Plettenberg Bay . 
 Accommodation is in picturesque thatched cottages with double rooms 
 (en-suite, rated for B&amp;B or dinner. Our highly acclaimed meals are 
 served in our rustic thatched waterside main house. 

 Summerblue Guest House 

 Summer Blue Guest House offers Port Elizabeth accommodation in the quiet, up-market beachfront suburb of Summerstrand, 
 Port Elizabeth, close to all beachfront amenities, offering 
 spacious, private accommodation. 5 kilometers from the 
 airport it is close to the main beaches, restaurants, pools, 
 casino, oceanarium, university, sports stadia and golf 
 course. 

 Swanze Gat Guest House 

 Conveniently situated Uniondale accommodation on the main road through the quiet and 
 picturesque Karoo dorp of Uniondale, Swanze Gat Guest House 
 is the only double storey guest house in town. 

 The Cock House 

 The Cock House, the much-loved 
 Grahamstown Guest House and Restaurant offers country home 
 comfort and elegant dining in the gracious Norden&apos;s 
 Restaurant with its yellowwood floor and period decor. Each 
 of the nine double guest rooms is individual. Grahamstown accommodation at its most gracious. 

 The 
 Village Guest Lodge 

 Just one street away from the 
 beachfront in Summerstrand, Port Elizabeth guest house 
 accommodation in spacious and comfortable 
 surroundings. 

 The Townhouse Guesthouse 

 The Townhouse Guesthouse, 
 dating back to the late 1800`s, is the oldest established 
 guesthouse offering Uniondale accommodation . 
 It was graded by the Tourism Grading Council during 2005 and 
 awarded a two star rating in the Guesthouses category. 
 Situated on the popular Route 62 through the Klein Karoo, 
 Uniondale is also the western gateway to the Baviaanskloof 
 Wilderness area. 

 Villa 
 d&apos;Lockyer Country Lodge and Restaurant 

 This delightful Willowmore accommodation is situated in the heart of Willowmore on the N9 between 
 Graaff-Reinet and George, lying in the heart of the Little 
 Karoo and the Gateway to the Baviaanskloof. It offers 
 excellent B&amp;B and self-catering accommodation as well as a 
 fine la carte restaurant. 

 Willow 
 Historical Guest House 

 Experience an important piece of South 
 African history in this historic building with Victorian furniture, old 
 world charm and unsurpassed hospitality. Ideally situated for stopovers 
 when travelling from Gauteng to George the Willow Historic Guest House 
 offers excellent comfortable Willowmore accommodation , fine food 
 in it&apos;s la carte restaurant and a homely atmosphere - a real home away 
 from home. The Guest House is tastefully furnished with period furniture 
 augmented by a large collection of Africana which will fascinate the 
 discerning visitor, providing innumerable insights into the South 
 African way of life in times long gone. 
 Xanadu Guest Villa 

 Five Star accommodation right on the beach, 
 Xanadu offers the very best in Garden Route guest house, Wilderness 
 accommodation . 
 Zeru House 

 Originally built in the 1880&apos;s it has since 
 been lovingly restored into charming Uniondale accommodation with the original yellowwood floors and ceilings and careful 
 attention to the comfort and privacy of their guests. 
  

  
 
 

 Return to top 
 
 
 2007 Tobago Bed and Breakfast 

 home    accommodation    activities    contact us    links 

 web site design search 
engine optimisation by ZAWebs Designs 
 web hosting by ZAWebs 
Hosting 

 South Africa 
 | guest house | 
 activities | camping | guest farm | hotel | hunting | tour
	</body>
</document>
