<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002659" url="http://www.atlaspackaging.co.uk/commercial-food-packaging-cardboard-food-packaging" time="2012-07-12-18:43" support="3" score="0.005019261068691951" bingtitle="Commercial food packaging and cardboard food packaging" webtitle="Commercial food packaging and cardboard food packaging">
			<query id="000535" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000540" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="001351" bing-rank="147"/>
	<description>... to easily be folded flat in order ... With jar packaging for condiments and preserves which are to be sold as gift sets ... designed to incorporate the fast food restaurant ...</description>
	<body>
		Commercial food packaging&amp;cardboard food packaging
 
Covering a range of food and drinks industries, Atlas Packaging can design, manufacture and supply a number of bespoke and unique commercial food packaging and cardboard food packaging solutions including a number of food and drink packaging for delivery, presentation and gift packaging.

BRC IOP guidelines are strictly adhered to at Atlas Packaging, to ensure that all commercial food packaging and cardboard food packaging is suitable for food storage and food transportation. This includes monitoring hygiene on the packaging production line, alcohol hand cleaning stations and a number of policies such as requirements for managing print control, safeguards to reduce the risk of chemical migration from packaging into food products&amp;an emphasis on managing the functional quality of packaging materials to meet customers specifications

Atlas Packaging is already involved in designing and manufacturing outer packaging for cheese manufacturers, producing shelf ready packaging to enable the manufacturer to box up, transport and present the product at retail with one storage package.

Cheese packaging and food packaging

Cheese manufacturers who are looking for cheese packaging and containers generally opt for Retail Ready Packaging for cheese packaging, which offers cost-effective transit and retail packaging in one box. Retail Ready Packaging benefits from quick assembly and can be filled on the processing line before being sealed and sent out to the retailer in a ready-to-use package. Atlas Packaging will design and manufacture the packaging to include manufacturer branding, logos and details, with the use of up to four colour case printing or with lithographic or lithoprint.

Bakery Packaging and baked goods packaging

Packaging for pasties, pastries and convenience food is available in the form of Retail Ready Packaging, Regular 0201 Containers and multi-point glued containers. Whichever food packaging solution the client selects, it can be finished to exacting specifications complete with four colour case printing or litho-printed designs.

For pasties, pastries and convenience food containers and boxes, Atlas Packaging manufactures a number of different products and solutions for companies including Ginsters, who use Atlas Packaging for corrugated food packaging. These products include retail ready packaging for the storing, transporting and presentation of the food, standard 0201 shipping boxes as well as bespoke die cut retail ready packaging.

Frozen meat packaging and frozen food packaging

Vacuum packed raw meats are packaged with the use of either corrugated or solid board packaging. Solid board packaging is particularly suitable for frozen meats or other high weight products due to their weight and bulky nature it can be poly coated which offers water resilience and improved strength. Other frozen meat producers who use food packaging boxes and containers from Atlas Packaging include Penny Lane Foods, DB Foods, Pipers Farm, Riverford Farm Foods&amp;Denhay Farm.

Heavy duty solid board collapsible pre-printed packaging tends to be used for frozen and pre-cooked food, as this packaging product is strong and durable and can include a polycoated finish for durability and water resistance.

Produce packaging and vegetable boxes

Fruit and vegetable boxes for both growers and suppliers can be manufactured by Atlas Packaging. This includes the use of solid board collapsible cartons as well as branded and polycoated packaging.

For vegetable packaging for produce such as cauliflowers, lettuces, broccoli and carrots corrugated cardboard boxes and trays and generally used due to their cost effective nature and their quick and easy assembly.

Riverford Organics uses Atlas Packaging for its vegetable packaging due to the versatility offered. Vegetable boxes are required by Riverford Organics in a variety of sizes as well as with a design feature which allows them to easily be folded flat in order to be collected by a delivery van. As the customer is required to leave the empty solid board collapsible box outside, there is a requirement for the boxes to be able to withstand all types of weather. For this reason, Atlas Packaging uses polycoating which both adds water resilience and added durability.

Bottle packaging and wine bottle packaging

A requirement for wine bottle packaging as well as cider, spirits and champagne, is to ensure that no damage can occur during transit. This can be achieved in a number of ways, depending on the requirements of the client and design of the bottle.

For special occasion drinks packages and presentation packaging–or gift pack boxes–Atlas Packaging can design and manufacture gift boxes to the client’s specification, focussing on packaging for bottles which enhances the product and makes it appealing to consumers who are looking for gift packs. As well as enhancing the product, presentation packs often include space for a secondary product as well as incorporate the product branding and logo. This can be achieved with 4 colour flexo print, silk screen printing or lithographic printing.

These types of bottle packaging solutions from Atlas Packaging are used by breweries, cider farms and microbreweries including Carlsberg, Cornish Orchards and St Austell Breweries.

Cake boxes and confectionary packaging

Predominately, packaging for confectionary and sweets falls into four categories, Counter Display Units, Free Standing Display Units, transit outers and Retail Ready Packaging.

Food products such as flapjacks, muesli bars and handmade sweets and chocolate bars will often require packaging which can be displayed on a counter top or free standing on the shop floor. In this situation, Atlas Packaging will use corrugated cardboard for the stands, often incorporating both the transport boxes and display boxes into one product, to allow for quick set up and reduced materials and therefore costs. This will allow for designs to be customised for client requirements and branding.

Atlas Packaging confectionary packaging clients include Tesco Finest Easter Eggs, Choc-O-Bars, Cadburys, House of Dorchester and Suzy Sweet Tooth.

Jar packaging and condiments packaging

Packaging for condiments, preserves and jarred products will either be for transporting to retailers or as gift packaging and presentation boxes. Due to the products being glass, it is imperative that all condiments packaging and storage boxes for preserves offer great protection with minimal movement&amp;minimal material.

In the case of boxes for condiments that will be transported, this is achieved with the use of corrugated cardboard divisions, with each cell sized for the jar it will hold. Four corner glued trays are also used, offering maximum packing space for jars with minimal movement. These trays can be provided with similar lids of a slightly larger size in order to allow them to be slid on top to secure the contents.

With jar packaging for condiments and preserves which are to be sold as gift sets or presentation boxes, Atlas Packaging can design and create unique packaging solutions which can enhance the appeal of the product, can include space for complimentary products and still offer complete protection from breakages during transit.

Atlas Packaging provides jar packaging for Bart Spices, Duchy Originals, Crabtree&amp;Evelyn&amp;Quince Honey Farm.

Takeaway packaging and food delivery packaging

When designing takeaway packaging, boxes for fast food and food delivery companies, an important factor is the ability for the container to retain the heat of the food being transported. Due to the design nature of corrugated cardboard, it makes an ideal takeaway packaging solution because it insulates as well as protects. The food containers can also be designed to incorporate the fast food restaurant’s logo and branding.

Atlas Packaging currently supplies takeaway carry pack packaging designs to independent food suppliers and companies throughout the UK such as Gourmet Oriental&amp;Independant Gourmet Foods.
 
Customer focused and process driven, striving towards operational excellence in a company supported by it’s people.
 
 Terms&amp;conditions | Privacy | Site map ©2012 Atlas Packaging Limited. All rights reserved
 
 HOME 
 
 STANDARD PACKAGING 
 
 CUSTOM DESIGNS 
 
 INDUSTRIES 
 
 Commercial food packaging Flower packaging Furniture packaging Pharmaceutical packaging Shelf ready packaging Transit packaging 
 
 ABOUT US 
 
 NEWS 
 
 ENVIRONMENTAL 
 
 CONTACT US
	</body>
</document>
