<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002964" url="http://www.antiessays.com/free-essays/11946.html" time="2012-07-12-19:03" support="4" score="0.012465953614989204" bingtitle="Free Popularity Of Fast Food Restaurants Essay - Spunkish" webtitle="Free Popularity Of Fast Food Restaurants Essay - Spunkish">
			<query id="000865" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="001113" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000896" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="000360" bing-rank="197"/>
	<description>... not necessary in the creation of a fast food restaurant. ... Today, many people eat fast food instead of cooking meals at home. ... behind the steering wheel of a car. ...</description>
	<body>
		Search 
Type in your essay topic: ex. Vietnam War
 
 Join Login Custom Essays Help Contact 
 
 Popularity Of Fast Food Restaurants Essay 
 
Below is a free essay on &quot;Popularity Of Fast Food Restaurants&quot; from Anti Essays, your source for free research papers, essays, and term paper examples.
 Fast food restaurants are exceedingly popular because they prove to fit comfortably in our active, modern day lives. Today, many people eat fast food instead of cooking meals at home. The reason for this is that many of us are constantly busy with our daily responsibilities and we are continuously on the go. We believe that we have a limit of time, and fast food restaurants are at the maximum of convenience for everyone at any hour. You can pretty much find a fast food restaurant at every corner of a street, and most of these establishments usually include a drive through. With this they were able to introduce a way to eat food without knives, forks or plates, and most meals can even be eaten while behind the steering wheel of a car.

While fast food demonstrates to be a quick and easy way to satisfy the hunger of the busybodies of today, this also includes the convenience it provides for mothers and their offspring. Many fast food restaurants provide play areas to occupy the children, giving their mothers a break and some time to socialize. There is a specialized kids menu, which usually, comes with toys that change periodically, therefore, enticing children to continue returning for more.

Most of the time, the products of the fast food industry are inexpensive, yet delicious. For fewer than five dollars you can usually get a meal that’s satisfying and filling. This is fitting for people who don’t wish to spend much money and even a child, it would seem, could afford their own meal at such low prices. When you can find and easy, filling, convenient and inexpensive meal at every street corner, fast food seems like the logical choice to cut out the stress in today’s hectic world. 
 Read Full Essay 
 Join Anti Essays to read full essay.
Already a Member? Login Now 

Please upgrade your account to view this essay on Popularity Of Fast Food Restaurants.
 
 Submitted by: spunkish on July 9, 2008 Category: Social Issues Length: 302 words Views: 3606 

 Report this Essay Save Paper 
 
 Related Essays 

 Popularity Of Fast Food... Explain The Causes For The... Popularity Of Fast Food... What ARe The Causes Of... The Effect Of Fast Food... Blaming Fast Food... Causes For Popularity Of... Fast Food Advantage Of Fast Food Fast Food Cause-Effect Essay Fast Food Nation Fast Food Nation Fast Food Global Market-Kfc BrAndIng And PositionIng... Fast Food And The American... Fast Food Does Fast Food Have To... Fast Food Fast Food Fast Food Fast Food Fast Food Burgers Or Fat... Fast Food Nation Analysis Top 11 Reason For Fast Food Fast Food Fast Food Are Fast Food... Fast Food Sector Research: Japanese... Fast Food Is Bad 
 
Plagiarism Warning
 
The essay examples on Anti Essays are for research purposes ONLY. Do NOT submit an essay example as your own. If you use any information from a sample essay, please cite it. MLA and APA citations can be found at the bottom of this free essay.
 
Citations 
 
MLA Citation

&quot;Popularity Of Fast Food Restaurants&quot;. Anti Essays. 12 Jul. 2012

&lt;http://www.antiessays.com/free-essays/11946.html&gt;
 
APA Citation

Popularity Of Fast Food Restaurants. Anti Essays . Retrieved July 12, 2012, from the World Wide Web: http://www.antiessays.com/free-essays/11946.html
 
 
©2012 AntiEssays.com
Use our free essays properly by reading our disclaimer and learning how to cite .

 Privacy Policy Contact Advertising Copyright Sitemap
	</body>
</document>
