<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002520" url="http://www.sonnysdirect.com/t-Equipment-Selection-Car-Wash-Equipment-Layout-101.aspx" time="2012-07-12-18:35" support="2" score="0.0018923629632888826" bingtitle="SONNY&apos;S The CarWash Factory - Car Wash Equipment Layout 101" webtitle="SONNY&apos;S The CarWash Factory - Car Wash Equipment Layout 101">
			<query id="001273" bing-rank="11"/>
			<query id="000676" bing-rank="93"/>
	<description>SONNY&apos;S The CarWash Factory - Car Wash Equipment ... now be longing for the simplicity of owning a fast food restaurant ... like to present a brief guide to equipment selection ...</description>
	<body>
		Language:  Currency: 
 
 

   You have 0 item(s) in your custom quote  View Quote Search:      

 New Customer   |   About Us   |   Customer Service   |   Trade Shows   |   Resources   |   Service and Support   |   Contact Us   |   News 
 
 
 
Now In: Car Wash Equipment Layout 101 
 
 
 
 
   
 CarWash
Equipment Layout 101 
 Getting a clean dry shiny car without labor 
 By Anthony Analetto 
 Chief Operating Officer - SONNY&apos;S The Car Wash Factory 
 Originally published in AutoLaundry Magazine 

 WATCH NOW - Factory Tour 
 

Have you ever stopped to think about the fascinating dynamics of modern road grime? You could spend years analyzing the different types and combinations of soil, air pollutants, precipitation, insects, and thousands of other things that can get stuck on a vehicle&apos;s surface. As a professional car wash operator you have only one concern; how to get everything off in 3 to 5 minutes or less, with no damage, at a profit margin that makes sense to do so.

Seem challenging? Road grime is just the beginning. Now factor in the daily and seasonal weather changes under which you are expected to produce an identical product inside a semi-enclosed tunnel. It gets better. Every car is a different size at a different temperature, and that’s before people start bolting aftermarket items onto the exterior.

Some of you may now be longing for the simplicity of owning a fast food restaurant; working inside a climate controlled environment with known inputs to production. For those of us who find the challenge of car washing fun and invigorating – I’d like to present a brief guide to equipment selection and its placement.

Be forewarned. There are many passionate opinions related to this topic, like deeply guarded and revered family recipes. When asked to write this article I cringed at the anticipated emails and calls in disagreement with anything I would write. So let me stand behind the following disclaimer – this is only how I do it. Also, I am using only generic equipment types and their basic properties, not manufacturer-specific technologies or improvements. If I can’t think of at least 2 manufacturers that make a similar product then it won’t be included in this article. Let’s get started.

The Golden Rule of Equipment Selection

Produce a clean, dry, shiny car with no manual labor for the maximum anticipated wash volume in 3 to 7 minutes, depending on how you plan to compete in the marketplace. It seems obvious but it is impossible to begin selecting equipment without knowing how many cars you need to process during the busiest hour on the busiest day. The equation is simple: the number of cars that pass your location (car count) multiplied by the percentage you will wash (capture rate). In reality, capture rate can be a tricky number to accurately predict. Average capture rates published by the International Car Wash Association are a good place to start, but how you run and market your business will dramatically impact the actual number. It all comes down to matching your quality, value, and convenience to what you believe is most desired by the demographic profile of the cars passing your wash. A business that is dead on can easily surpass the published capture rates. One that misses the mark can easily under perform, which is what a market economy is all about.

Maybe your entrepreneurial innovation has designed a new wash format and marketing plan that will capture 100% of your daily car count per month. Possibly you have decided that your customer base desires either the speed of service and discount price of an Express Exterior or the personalized attention and interior cleaning of a Full-Serve wash. Regardless, the site style combined with pricing, marketing, customer service, visibility, and your skill as an operator will contribute strongly to your actual capture rate and required equipment package.
Next throw in the inconvenient reality of land. I could not imagine attempting a well-marketed $3 dollar-3 minute Express Exterior with free vacuums on a half acre lot with a 55,000 daily car count. I would anticipate a capture rate and peak volume requiring a larger tunnel than would fit on the property. Once you have defined the variables that dictate your peak wash volume on your busiest day, and evaluated them against the attributes of the land where the wash will sit, you are ready to begin equipment selection. There is not a specific wash package ideally suited to Full Serve, Flex Serve, or Express Exterior. Equipment selection is all about how fast, how clean, how safe, and how much labor, if any, is involved.

 The Hybrid Wash Process Step by Step

Before I address several exceptions to the hybrid wash process to accommodate conditions of heavy snow, ice, bugs, or mud, let me first outline the basic best practices.

 Step 1 - Detergent application: Upon entering the wash the first thing to touch the car is a wet foamed alkaline detergent. The combination of arches and floor-mounted applicators required will vary depending on conveyor speed. Simultaneously, wheels and tires will receive an application of a non-acidic cleaner. This too should be a wet foamed detergent applied via two floor-mounted CTA applicators per side spaced, 40 inches apart.

Next, a second application of a foamed, low PH lubricating soap is applied immediately before the first friction wash component. This is commonly a mitter or wrap-around washer and often the foaming applicator is attached to the entrance of the wash unit. Lubrication of the wash material is vital. If your low PH detergent does not include a lubricant, then you must apply one separately. Three reasons support my preference for foaming all detergent. First, you can visually monitor that all areas are covered. If the detergent does not reach a specific section, such as the front and rear license plates, that area will not be properly cleaned no matter what equipment you use. Second, a properly applied wet foam detergent will drag dirt off the car even before the first equipment item touches the surface. Third, the lubricated detergent keeps friction wash media moving smoothly over surfaces for a safer wash. Developing a close relationship with your selected chemical supplier is vital. Ideally, the representative will function like a trusted member of your staff, tailoring detergents to your road grime considerations.
 Step 2 – The First Friction Wash: After detergent and lubricants are applied, the vehicle will enter the friction wash. This increases the dwell time, agitation, and cleaning performance of the initial detergents before they are removed. It is important to note that modern wash materials do not hold dirt and that equipment is engineered to constantly flush the material with either fresh or reclaim water. The quantity and type of wash components are directly related to the type of dirt and maximum conveyor speed. This topic will be expanded upon later. Regardless of conveyor speed, all vehicle surfaces must receive at least one friction cleaning action before leaving this first phase of the friction wash. Additionally, it is recommended to always include at least one set of wrap-around washers. These can be mounted in either a standard or reverse configuration, emphasizing rear or front surface cleaning, respectively. Other products exist in the market to clean front and rear surfaces but it is difficult to get a complete result without at least one set of wraps.

 Step 3 – The High-Pressure Wash: This is the turning point of a hybrid wash. Emphasis will slowly shift from the wash process and begin preparing the surface for rinsing and drying. Flat surfaces of the vehicle are relatively clean. A healthy application of both high and low PH detergents must allow ample dwell time to break the bond of road grime to the paint. The action of the friction wash media has moved detergent extensively, forcing it into grooves and crevices. Placement of the high-pressure wash system after the initial friction wash allows it to easily strip the loosened dirt. Simultaneously, a system of appropriate strength and placement for the conveyor speed will blast the mix of low and high PH detergent from all parts of the vehicle, including mirrors and other troublesome crevices. Stripping all alkaline detergent is critical. It will hinder the rinsing and drying process.

 Step 4 – The Second Friction Wash: The function of the second friction wash is twofold. The motion of the wash equipment and type of media used should be different than that in the first friction wash. This will provide alternate cleaning actions to remove any residual dirt that was missed by the previous components. Secondly, foamed detergent applied during this stage will have a low PH. Upon leaving this final stage of the hybrid wash process the cleaned vehicle surface is prepared for efficient rinsing and drying.

The Hybrid Wash Advantage

Brushless, Touch-Free, Soft-Cloth, Touch-Less; there are enough terms floating around to thoroughly confuse customers and operators alike. Many simply try to tell customers that the wash doesn’t use obsolete technology common over 50 years ago. All relate to either high-pressure streams of water or some form of material contacting a vehicle&apos;s surface to agitate a detergent and remove dirt. With that said, I’m going to stand behind my disclaimer – this is only how I do it – and say that no wash should use exclusively high-pressure OR friction wash material. Don’t get me wrong, there have been tremendous advances in technology with both formats. Either can produce a quality wash. The problem is that each has advantages and limitations. To produce the highest quality wash that is quick and economical, I recommend using a hybrid combination of BOTH technologies in every conveyorized tunnel. This leverages the ability of high pressure to clean within wheels and other grooves while friction materials clean flat surfaces with less detergent, water, and electrical expense. In the same vein of mixing technologies for a better wash, I equally recommend varying the types of friction wash materials within the same wash. Varying the selection of cloth, foam, and soft tufted media throughout the tunnel, and even on the same equipment item, can produce stunning results. The same logic applies; utilize the best suited technology to clean different parts of the vehicle. The goal is to produce the cleanest, shiniest, and driest car – safely, reliably, and economically – with absolutely no manual preparation.

Exceptions to the Hybrid Wash Process

Except during extreme weather conditions involving snow, ice, or mud, it is unnecessary and costly to pre-wash vehicles with high pressure before entering the first friction wash cycle. Those conditions are periodic. If they exist for parts of the year at your location, it is necessary to include a pre-wash capability, but it is only activated when the conditions demand. I am sure there is someone out there operating in a climate where days requiring a pre-wash greatly exceed those that don’t. You have my sympathy. But since I haven’t yet seen the situation in over 25 years of washing cars, even with washes I am familiar with in rural northern Canada, I’ll stand by my recommendation to pre-wash as the exception, not the rule. Pre-washing increases the consumption of electricity, detergent, and water, and resources are becoming increasingly expensive. Now a brief look at some common exceptions:

 Regions with Heavy Mud, Ice, or Snow: Regions with these characteristics will want to examine a supplemental application and pre-cleaning process. Prior to entering the foaming pre-soak applicator arch or system I mentioned above, vehicles should be cleaned with a high-pressure wash system, emphasizing wheel wells and lower surfaces. It is imperative that the water is infused with an alkaline detergent that matches the PH of the first detergent application. This will prevent excessive dilution of the first pre-soak application which will disrupt the wash quality. 

 Regions with Heavy Bug Seasons: Seasonal bug removal requires the same detergent infused high-pressure, pre-cleaning involved for heavy mud, ice, or snow, though focus should be concentrated on the front grill and windshield. Additionally, the vehicle will require an application of what is commonly referred to as “Bug Juice” before the pre-wash. This application can occur via a combination of floor- and arch- mounted applicators triggered before the photo-eyes. Another option found at some express-exterior locations are bug wash stations where customers can apply the solution themselves with a supplied brush. Using an attendant is a viable, though cost-prohibitive option as well. 

Complete Rinsing

When done correctly, the primary drying of a vehicle occurs while rinsing. The standard process is to apply a drying agent, followed by a sealer wax, with a final setting rinse of either fresh or spot-free water. Like application, this is another area where you will want to involve the assistance and specialized knowledge of your chemical supplier. The objective is twofold. First, remove all detergent from the surface, grooves, and mirrors so it does not spill out during drying. Second, bead the water so it breaks in large pools and runs off the car to begin the drying process. Rinsing, like everything in an automatic car wash, is dramatically affected by conveyor speed and water quality. Softeners and other equipment are available to correct water problems, and some types of chemicals work better with different water conditions. At slower conveyor speeds, rinsing is often handled by a series of manifolds that stream water like rain over the surface. This rinsing method breaks the bond the water has to the surface and helps it bead and flow. Additionally, it doesn’t produce mist that can get circulated by air dryers, which is highly counterproductive. Faster chain speeds will require additional rinsing to strip excess detergent before entering a rain system. Normally powered with a pumping system, these products can be targeted at trouble areas such as mirrors, the entire vehicle, or all of the above, depending on conveyor speed and the placement of your high-pressure wash components and detergent application.

Drying

Drying a car is easy. Drying a car with minimal electrical consumption in a compact space is difficult. Add in the sound restrictions imposed by many municipalities. Now consider the limitations of your available electrical service, along with changing requirements as temperature varies, and drying becomes a much more challenging task than it may have first appeared. Like high-pressure washing, results are directly related to conveyor speed. Many different blower designs are available. Some disperse air via a manifold to remove water from large flat surfaces, others direct a strong jet of air, which covers a smaller area but delivers the force necessary to strip water out of grooves. Mixing blower types and power ratings is frequently necessary to provide complete surface coverage with enough strength to remove water from inside crevices. The optimal angle of the producer will also vary, depending on conveyor speed. Look for products that have some ability to adjust to changing conditions. Although there is no perfect rule, plan for approximately 1 HP per car per hour for your peak anticipated volume.

Extra Online Services

Extra services can refer to anything not included in a wash’s base exterior package. The variations on wheel cleaning packages, undercarriage treatments, and other applications are endless. For brevity I’m going to highlight three of the most common and requested services; tire dressing, triple foam conditioner, and most recently, total body protectants&amp;glass treatments.

 Tire Dressing: The foundation for a good tire dressing is a clean tire. I referenced tire and wheel applicators above and high-pressure washers that clean out wheels, but the tire itself is most commonly cleaned with a horizontal tire brush. Some new brush designs available from several manufacturers have recently increased the scope of this unit’s ability to deliver good wheel cleaning as well. Once you have a clean tire, automated online dressing machines are readily available. Tire dressing will either be wiped or sprayed on as the vehicle passes the unit, most commonly installed in the drip space between the final rinse and dryers.

 Triple Foam Conditioner: The popularity of this service stems from the fact that a customer can see that they are receiving a special application even in the absence of signage. A powerful up-sell, triple foam conditioner is normally applied via a free-standing arch or foaming attachments. Its placement in the wash is constantly evolving. Traditionally it was located just before the final cleaning action immediately before rinse. This setup presents some difficulties in completely removing the conditioner and some operators have moved it earlier in the wash.

 Total Body Protectants&amp;Glass Treatments: It’s difficult to explain this new class of service without mentioning specific manufacturers. The two that come to mind are SIMONIZ’s Double Bond with VisionClear, and Ecolab’s Rain-X online protectant. These products coat the surface of the vehicle with chemicals engineered to protect painted surfaces, glass, trim, and chrome. The treatment, delivered online, can increase shine, water repellency, and provide lasting protection. Both suppliers provide a separate application system with excellent signage to promote the service to customers.
Guideline for Hybrid Equipment Selection

Now I’ll chart some very generic guidelines for the minimum recommended cleaning actions to each surface and the required conveyor length to produce a clean, dry, shiny, car at each corresponding speed. Many options exist from the various equipment manufacturers to accomplish each item. The critical aspect when selecting equipment is to mix motion and wash media. If the conveyor speed dictates 2 top surface actions, they should be different. One might be rotational, the other side to side. If you do select two similar motions, then one should incorporate a flat cloth and the other a plush material or closed-cell foam. Equally, many options exist within high-pressure wash units. When choosing these components you will want to evaluate surface coverage and impact. Let’s get started with the minimum guidelines:

 
 Chain – Speed 
 
 Friction 

 Top Surfaces 
 
 Friction 

 Wrap-Around 
 
 Friction 

 Side Washers 
 
 TouchFree 

 Side/Wheel 
 
 TouchFree 

 Top Surfaces 
 
 Rear Wheel Push Conveyor 
 
 Front Wheel Pull Conveyor 
 
 60 C.P.H. 
 
 2 
 
 1 
 
 1 
 
 1 
 
 - 
 
 70 feet 
 
 60 feet 
 
 90 C.P.H 
 
 2 
 
 1 
 
 1 
 
 1 
 
 1 
 
 95 feet 
 
 85 feet 
 
 120 C.P.H. 
 
 2 
 
 2 
 
 2 
 
 1 
 
 1 
 
 120 feet 
 
 110 feet 
 
 150 C.P.H. 
 
 2 
 
 2 
 
 3 
 
 2 
 
 1 
 
 145 feet 
 
 135 feet 
 
 180 C.P.H. 
 
 3 
 
 2 
 
 3 
 
 2 
 
 2 
 
 170 feet 
 
 160 feet 
 

 *Assumes 17 foot average vehicle length with 3 ft 6 in roller spacing where chain speed = approximately the cars processed per hour 

The relationship between conveyor length, chain speed, and number of cleaning actions is relatively straightforward. The faster the chain speed, the less contact time the vehicle has with each equipment item. This in turn necessitates a longer tunnel with more equipment to produce the same result. The numbers above approximate the minimum tunnel length and wash actions to produce a clean, dry, shiny car without the need for manual prep in approximately 2.5 minutes. It assumes a well-tuned hybrid equipment package in good repair. In most express-exterior and flex-serve locations the chain speed is set and seldom, if ever, changed. Customers at these formats are often promised a 3-minute wash and expect a consistent product. For many full-serve operators this may seem like a strange concept. The predominant practice at these washes is to constantly change conveyor speed, depending on wash volume. Developing a rhythm to speed up or slow down the wash to match traffic has a strong argument. Slower conveyor speeds increase detergent dwell time and friction contact time for a better wash. When properly managed, this practice has a place, especially at existing locations that experienced a rapid market expansion. Land restrictions don’t always permit a tunnel long enough to accommodate the peak wash volume.
Common Tunnel Equipment Items

 Friction - Top Surface Components: The two most prevalent technologies are “Mitters” and “Top Brushes”. Mitters were originally designed to simulate a human hand washing a car with a mitt that moves back and forth over the vehicle surface. They are very gentle and available in front-to-back, side-to-side, circular, and diagonal movements. Top Brushes feature a balanced or weighted rotating hub that spins as it contours the car passing beneath. Recent improvements in wash materials and automated retract capabilities have dramatically improved upon the safety of this very effective cleaning technology.

 Friction – Wrap-Around Washers: These highly effective washers clean all vertical surfaces of a vehicle. They feature two slightly overlapped rotating washers that wash the front of the vehicle as it passes through. Slight pressure keeps the brushes in contact with the sides of the vehicle before moving in together to clean rear vertical surfaces.

 Friction – Side Washers: Rotating brushes that clean the side of cars. Various heights and angles are available to provide concentration to different side surfaces. Shorter units will often focus on lower rocker panels while taller units can reach the tops of the highest SUVs.

 High-Pressure – Side Washers: These washers blast high pressure streams of water at side surfaces and wheels. Many variations exist that are either stationary or feature some combination of spinning, oscillating, or pivoting movement. The spray pattern is normally very compact and preferably at zero degrees for greatest impact. When evaluating systems it is vital to consider conveyor speed. The simplistic guide above indicates an approximate number of manifolds, but as speed of vehicle travel increases you must combine this with the total number of nozzles, their movement, and the pressure of the water. Try to imagine a car passing by an oscillating stream of water. If the car is moving slowly it may perform well. If conveyor speed is increased and the coverage or speed of oscillation is not sufficient, you will have one clean stripe down the side of an otherwise dirty surface.

 High-Pressure – Top Washers: As with high-pressure side washers, there are many excellent choices on the market and the same considerations apply. Often mounted to an overhead arch, these washers feature various numbers and types of moving nozzles that blast high pressure streams of water at top surfaces. It is important to match surface coverage and impact with the maximum conveyor speed you anticipate running. It is common to use reclaim water in many high-pressure wash applications.

Summary

There are many approaches to getting a clean, dry, shiny, car with no manual labor. When selecting wash equipment always start with the car count and anticipated capture rate at the facility. There are many different options to clean a car – the most important consideration is guaranteeing that your customers will receive a consistent product in a consistent time. I have had the opportunity to meet and work with hundreds of tremendously successful car wash owners all across the country. Many have drastically different equipment packages and approaches to washing a car. What they all share in common is the desire and dedication to put their customers first.

Anthony Analetto has over 26 years experience in the car wash business and is the President of SONNY&apos;S The Car Wash Factory&apos;s Equipment Division. Before coming to SONNY&apos;S Anthony was the director of operations for a 74 location national car wash chain. Anthony can be reached at 800-327-8723 x 104 or at aanaletto@sonnysdirect.com 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 Home | Contact Us | Car Wash Equipment and Systems | Free Catalog | Service&amp;Support | Careers | Privacy Policy | Site Map 
Car Wash Business Since 1949!
 SONNY&apos;S Car Wash Equipment Company is the largest manufacturer of conveyorized car wash systems in the world. We also have a full line of OEM parts for Hanna , Peco , PDQ , Belanger , Macneil , Ryko , and other car wash equipment manufacturers. Decide With Confidence 
SONNY&apos;S financial strength is recognized by Dun&amp;Bradstreet, the world&apos;s leading source of commercial information and insight on businesses. Copyright©1995-2011. All Rights Reserved. 
All prices&amp;availability subject to change without notice.
	</body>
</document>
