<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002807" url="http://ca.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20110807094151AAdefc7" time="2012-07-12-18:52" support="1" score="0.00039366900478873633" bingtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - How can a 15 year old make money fast?" webtitle="Yahoo! Canada Answers - How can a 15 year old make money fast?">
			<query id="000938" bing-rank="164"/>
	<description>just ask around, leave your phone number ... Summer job at a fast food restaurant, clothing store, or any small company ... If Bill gates and Blip gates got into a ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to search. 
 New User? Register Sign In Help 
 Upgrade to Safer IE8 
   Notifications Help 

 Mail 

 My Y! Yahoo! 
 
 Yahoo! Canada Answers 
 
 Search Search Web 
 
 Home Browse Categories 
 Arts&amp;Humanities Beauty&amp;Style Business&amp;Finance Cars&amp;Transportation Computers&amp;Internet Consumer Electronics Dining Out 

 Education&amp;Reference Entertainment&amp;Music Environment Family&amp;Relationships Food&amp;Drink Games&amp;Recreation Health 

 Home&amp;Garden Local Businesses News&amp;Events Pets Politics&amp;Government Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 

 Science&amp;Mathematics Social Science Society&amp;Culture Sports Travel Yahoo! Products 
 My Activity 
Sorry, you need to be Signed in to see this.

Not a member? Join Here .
 About 
 How Answers Works Points&amp;Levels Community Guidelines Leaderboard Suggestion Board Answers Blog (USA) 
 
 
 
 Ask 
 What would you like to ask? 
 Answer 
 
 Discover 
 
 What are you looking for? Advanced Search 
 Home &gt; All Categories &gt; Pregnancy&amp;Parenting &gt; Teen&amp;Preteen &gt; Resolved Question 
 Eden Member since: September 09, 2010 Total points: 2,333 (Level 3) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
Resolved Question
 Show me another » 
How can a 15 year old make money fast?
 in the UK 
 11 months ago Report Abuse 
 by Rachel Carleton Member since: July 01, 2011 Total points: 737 (Level 2) 
 Add Contact Block 
 
 Best Answer - Chosen by Asker
 basically, get a job!
sole trader shops, ie like, take two shops around where you live. sayy, Asda, and the corner shop called&quot;Annies little shop&quot;asda, has supermarkets everywhere, this isn&apos;t a sole trading business. but Annies Little Shop, has only one store, that is a sole trader. you can ask for a job in there.

just ask around, leave your phone number, name, age, and anything else they ask for. obviously dont leave your address for safety reasons Lol

i started working in a local bakery, when i was 15, been working there a year now :D earned myself a tidy amount of just over a thousand pounds.

it takes time, unless youre some child genius hehe :) 
Source(s):
 myself! 
 11 months ago Report Abuse 
 Asker&apos;s Rating: Asker&apos;s Comment: Thanks :) 
 Action Bar: 0 stars - mark this as Interesting! Email Comment ( 0 ) Save 
 Add to My Yahoo! Add to Del.icio.us RSS 
 
 
There are currently no comments for this question.

* You must be logged into Answers to add comments. Sign in or Register .
 
This question about&quot; How can a 15 year ol… &quot;was originally asked in Yahoo! Answers United Kingdom 
 
 Other Answers (3)
 Show: All Answers Oldest to Newest Newest to Oldest Rated Highest to Lowest 
 by angelify Member since: July 11, 2011 Total points: 142 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Summer job at a fast food restaurant, clothing store, or any small company will do. 
 11 months ago Report Abuse 
 by poιѕoɴ ιvy™ Member since: February 18, 2011 Total points: 17,216 (Level 6) 
 Add Contact Block 
 Prostitution.

*kidding*

Uh babysit..yard work..chores..petsitting.. 
 11 months ago Report Abuse 
 
 3 people rated this as good 
 by Blip Gates Member since: August 06, 2011 Total points: 72 (Level 1) 
 Add Contact Block 
 If Bill gates and Blip gates got into a fist fight, who would win? 
 11 months ago Report Abuse 
 
 
Discover Questions in Teen&amp;Preteen 

 Whats the next step? mom conversation gone wrong? What are the engineers called that design trains and their transportation? Help please I&apos;m 16 and my mom died ? Teens, Have you ever been rushed to the hospital? 
 
Ready to Participate? Get Started! 
 
 ADVERTISEMENT 
 
 
Categories

 All Categories 
 Pregnancy&amp;Parenting 
 Adoption Baby Names Grade-Schooler Newborn&amp;Baby Other - Pregnancy&amp;Parenting Parenting Pregnancy Teen&amp;Preteen Toddler&amp;Preschooler Trying to Conceive 
 
 
 
 Who found this interesting? 

Be the first person to mark this question as interesting!
 
Sponsor Results
 Earn money from visitors Fund your website through banner ads. Register now and earn... www.stargamesaffiliate.com Sponsor More Reps. Attract Endless New Leads And Prospects To You, Free Videos www.magneticsponsoringonline.com No Credit Check Loan £50-£1000 In Your Bank Within 1hr. No Credit Check&amp;No... www.first4payday.co.uk See your message here... 
Answers International

 Argentina Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany Hong Kong India Indonesia Italy Japan Malaysia Mexico New Zealand Philippines Quebec Singapore South Korea Spain Taiwan Thailand United Kingdom United States Vietnam en Español 

Yahoo! does not evaluate or guarantee the accuracy of any Yahoo! Canada Answers content. Click here for the Full Disclaimer. 

Help us improve Yahoo! Canada Answers. Tell us what you think. 

Copyright © 2012 Yahoo! All Rights Reserved.

 Copyright/IP Policy - Privacy Policy - Terms of Service - Community Guidelines
	</body>
</document>
