<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002888" url="http://www.merchantcircle.com/business/Gasthaus.Zur.Elli.803-364-9008/review/list" time="2012-07-12-18:57" support="2" score="0.004195926122668191" bingtitle="Reviews of Gasthaus Zur Elli Prosperity, 29127" webtitle="Gasthaus Zur Elli, Prosperity SC 29127">
			<query id="000253" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="000973" bing-rank="177"/>
	<description>... but were told before we sit - this is not a fast food restaurant ... bad day in YOUR restaurant, if you don&apos;t like my food ... to choose from 3 entrees and it is cooked to order.</description>
	<body>
		Loading... Autos Home&amp;Garden Real Estate Health&amp;Beauty Legal&amp;Financial Food&amp;Dining All Join Now Login Help Dashboard Sign Out Autos Business to Business Community Education Electronics Entertainment and Arts Legal&amp;Financial Food&amp;Dining Health&amp;Beauty Home&amp;Garden Professional Services Real Estate Recreation Retail Shopping Travel&amp;Lodging Find A Merchant Find A Deal Get Advice 
Find
 Merchants Deals Advice 
In or Around
 I&apos;m Insured I&apos;m Uninsured National  SC  Prosperity  29127 
 Food&amp;Dining | Restaurants | Family Style Restaurants 
 
 Info Map Blog Products Offers Newsletter 
 
We found 11 MerchantCircle reviews

Reviews found as of August 21, 2008
 Gasthaus Zur Elli 5 
 5 Great Food&amp;great service 

Been there many times&amp;gets better each time we visit!!!1


 by Martins Performance Boating in Prosperity, SC 
 on October 02, 2008 

Merchant Response: &quot;Thank you for your SUPPORT, hope to see you soon.

Wendy&quot; - October 15, 2009 
 Gasthaus Zur Elli 5 
 5 The Most Personable German Dining Experience in S.C. 

Truly delicious Schnitzel, the best ever, Her Mother held a Gourmet Chef License in Germany and taught Wendy her secrets. Call for Reservations and Menu Selections. Ms. Wendy may also grant request for that Special Occasion.


 by Bennett Garner in Prosperity, SC 
 on October 15, 2009 

Merchant Response: &quot;Mr Bennett and Ms Angie

Thank you for the fine Review and thank you for your SUPPORT.
Gasthaus zur Elli
Wendy&quot; - October 15, 2009 
 Gasthaus Zur Elli 5 
 5 Excellent - Fantastic food 

Food was wonderful - Great German - Gasthaus Zur Elli. It was great to personally have the owner and chef, Wendy entertain you. Service is slow but were told before we sit - this is not a fast food restaurant - Wendy prepares the food in her own kitchen as if you are dining in her home!! Great atmosphere!


 by King&apos;s in Chapin, SC 
 on May 04, 2009 

Merchant Response: &quot;Dear Sir

Thank you for that nice Review, hope to see you soon.

bestgermanrestaurant.com
We had a contest: Best German Restaurant in America, Gasthaus zur Elli made # 1 in SC and # 10 in the Nation, out of 410 German Restaurants.
Thank you to all my dear Customers.
Wendy&quot; - October 15, 2009 
 Gasthaus Zur Elli 5 
 5 Staff very cold 

Meal was hot
not great
staff very unfriendly


 by Main in Prosperity, SC 
 on April 20, 2009 

Merchant Response: &quot;Dear Sir or Madam
My Wait Staff is very friendly and helpful, you must had a bad day in YOUR restaurant, if you don&apos;t like my food enjoy yours.
Gasthaus zur Elli
Best German Restaurant in America, we had a Contest # 1 in SC and # 10 in the Nation out of 410 German Restaurants in America.&quot; - October 15, 2009 
 Gasthaus Zur Elli 5 
 5 Wonderful Authentic German Food 

This is the most authentic German Food found in the US. Without having to book a flight to Germany, this is the most authentic. The food is always fresh and prepared with love. Wonderful dining experience. This is not meant for fast food, so do take your time. It is well worth it. Bring your appetite, it is a full course meal.


 by Steffi in Columbia, SC 
 on April 13, 2009 
 Gasthaus Zur Elli 5 
 5 Great food and atmosphere 

I always enjoy going to Miss Wendy&apos;s. The food is excellent and the atmosphere is always great. We drive over an hour to get there and go every chance we get.


 by Constance Ennis in Aiken, SC 
 on January 18, 2009 
 Gasthaus Zur Elli 1 
 1 NO MENUS/LONG WAIT/EXPENSIVE 

Despite what the owner of this restaurant says, there were no menus on our table the night we came in. In fact, we asked the waitress for a menu and she said there was no menu. Also there certainly WERE NOT 6-12 items to choose from. We were only offered 3 different menu items. We were never offered half portions at reduced prices. We had to wait 1-1/2 hours to get our food which I thought was a little ridiculous. We did not expect &quot;fast food&quot; but we did not expect to wait 1-1/2 hours either when there was only one other couple in the place at the time. The waitress was not overly friendly and we WILL NOT go back. If you want good German food without the long wait and steep prices I suggest Huller&apos;s German Restaurant in Harbison in Irmo. They also have a buffet.


 by Anonymous in Chapin, SC 
 on August 26, 2011 
 Gasthaus Zur Elli 5 
 5 We loved it! 

Authentic German food; Wendy went well out of her way to give my 82 year old native German mother a memorable birthday! Only wish Gasthaus zur Elli was closer to Aiken so we could visit more often.


 by Dolores Mueller in Aiken, SC 
 on May 03, 2011 
 Gasthaus Zur Elli 5 
 5 Great Resturant 

Miss Wendy told me to smile as soon as I walked through the door. I knew the party was on then! Great food and good beer with a very friendly enviroment. I just wish I could have gotten the boot.


 by Mike in West Columbia, SC 
 on October 03, 2010 
 Gasthaus Zur Elli 4 
 4 GREAT FOOD BUT A LITTLE PRICEY 

We have only eaten here once and the food was very, very good. However, I found the prices a little steep. There is no menu and no prices for their food items were listed anywhere that you could see. You get to choose from 3 entrees and it is cooked to order. We had to wait over an hour before we finally got our entrees. The bill for 2 people that night was $45. Again, the food was very good but a long wait and I felt a little too expensive.


 by S.E. in Prosperity, SC 
 on August 25, 2010 

Merchant Response: &quot;I have half portion dinners from $ 13.99 to $ 19.99 that includes Soup, Salad and Dessert, I type the daily MENU on my Computer and print them out.
Each table has a Menu, 6 to 12 Different dinners to choose from it depends on how many Customers I have in my Restaurant on that day.
This is a German Restaurant, the old way.......NO FAST FOOD......come in and enjoy.....

Gasthaus zur Elli
Prosperity SC&quot; - August 25, 2010 
 Gasthaus Zur Elli 5 
 5 Great Cozy, friendly place for dinner. 

It is very neat place, different then most places to eat dinner.


 by Dell Paxton in Cayce, SC 
 on July 24, 2010 

Merchant Response: &quot;Thank you for your nice review, hope to see you soon.
Out of 410 German Restaurants we are on the 5th Place
www.bestgermanrestaurant.com 

Thank you for your SUPPORT

Gasthaus zur Elli&quot; - July 26, 2010 
 
 Write a Review for this merchant.
 
Click to Rate:
 Summary: Gasthaus Zur Elli Average rating: 3.6 Rating Count: 11 
Browse By Category 
 Banquet Rooms Beverages Candy&amp;Sweets Catering Services Grocery Stores Meats Produce Retailers Restaurants Specialty Food Stores view more 
Related Businesses
 
Sponsored Links
 
Other Local Businesses 
 
Follow Us
 MerchantCircle on Facebook Twitter @merchantcircle MerchantCircle Blog Home | About Us | Blog | Forums | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service | Support | Answers | Advertise with Us | Developers | Expert Articles Our Partners: Ask Answers  |  Life 123  |  Citysearch  |  Insider Pages  |  Urbanspoon MerchantCircle is a Reply! Inc. property. Other Reply! sites include: Bloglines | iMotors | Contractors.com | EducationHub ©2012 Reply! Inc. All Rights Reserved. CLOSE
	</body>
</document>
