<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002270" url="http://reportyourcomplaint.com/cookout-fast-food-restaurant-review-amazing-cheap-milkshakes-and-not-just-another-fast-food-joint/" time="2012-07-12-18:10" support="47" score="0.14293141160661735" bingtitle="Cookout Fast Food Restaurant Review - Amazing Cheap Milkshakes and ..." webtitle="Cookout Fast Food Restaurant Review - Amazing Cheap Milkshakes and Not Just Another Fast Food Joint | Report Your Complaint.com">
			<query id="001184" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000443" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000852" bing-rank="54"/>
			<query id="000227" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="001481" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="000550" bing-rank="69"/>
			<query id="000916" bing-rank="90"/>
			<query id="001166" bing-rank="31"/>
			<query id="000245" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000555" bing-rank="155"/>
			<query id="000233" bing-rank="223"/>
			<query id="001493" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000607" bing-rank="197"/>
			<query id="000909" bing-rank="67"/>
			<query id="000682" bing-rank="109"/>
			<query id="001172" bing-rank="89"/>
			<query id="000119" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="000619" bing-rank="233"/>
			<query id="000915" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000239" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="001183" bing-rank="101"/>
			<query id="000922" bing-rank="208"/>
			<query id="000226" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="001361" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000947" bing-rank="37"/>
			<query id="000953" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="000883" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000663" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000965" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="001175" bing-rank="68"/>
			<query id="001187" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="001487" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000676" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000959" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="001511" bing-rank="15"/>
			<query id="000101" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="001021" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="001178" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="000037" bing-rank="21"/>
			<query id="000934" bing-rank="146"/>
			<query id="000664" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000248" bing-rank="199"/>
			<query id="000925" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="000600" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000544" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="001009" bing-rank="40"/>
			<query id="001367" bing-rank="85"/>
	<description>I can’t tell you how amazing their food really is. ... 6 Responses to Cookout Fast Food Restaurant Review – Amazing ... Then as I was picking up the order from the window ...</description>
	<body>
		Log In 
 
 RYC (Home) Companies Complaints Reviews Compliments Helpful tips&amp;info Credit repair About us Site Index Blog 
 

 
Random Posts

 Presbyterian Hospital and gross overcharging of patients with or without health insurance! Public Storage-$1 For First Month is Really a Scam!! Koofers.com - a review of a college resource loaded with professor reviews, past exams, study guides and more! Rent A Center (RAC) - a review of a racist scam that preys on the poor, blacks and minorities! Tysons Ford car dealership complaint - they sold me a wrecked car! Aldi Grocery Store Complaint - Low Priced Groceries With Horrible Customer Service and Horrible Product Quality!! Are Hertz promotions just a way to get your money? Miracle Gro Liquafeed plant feeding system review - this liquid plant feeder is easy to use and works great. Amazon.com stole my hard earned money and closed my seller account! Charlotte Knights baseball review - they could be the worst baseball team alive! 
 
Recent Comments

 skyday on Great Stuff insulating foam sealant review–this stuff works great for sealing and insulating gaps and cracks SCAM on Childhood leukemia Foundation–a review of a shady charity that uses auto dialers and other shady practices to get donations Mike on HomeVestors home buyers is a shady scam and offers you far less than your home is worth! Chris Brady on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? Lee on Stanley Steemer–fraudulant business practices, abusive telemarketing and a bad rug cleaning experience! Lisa Carroll on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? brenda on Walgreen’s pharmacy–incorrectly filled prescription and they refused to fix it! S.K. Thompson on Virginia State Troopers Complaint–Police officers have too much power and get away with breaking laws! 
 Privacy Policy 
Cookout Fast Food Restaurant Review–Amazing Cheap Milkshakes and Not Just Another Fast Food Joint
 By businesstravelor21 
 




I recently moved from NY down here to NC and I am really not familiar with any fast food places.  The only restaurants I know are McDonald’s and Burger King because they are located at every corner from here to China.  As I was driving down the road I saw a fast food joint called Cookout so I decided to go there.

When I pulled in, they were hoping with a large crowd so I was pretty sure it must be a place to get good food.  They didn’t have any place to go inside to eat but there was a window where you order.  When you were done ordering, they had tables and chairs located all along the side of the building.

As I was looking at the menu, I noticed that they had 20+ flavors of milkshakes and were only priced at $2.39! I was definitely going to try their strawberry cheesecake milkshake before I left.  Cookout also has a combo deal that includes a lot of food that will fill you up completely.  It includes 1 main item, 2 side choices, and a fountain drink (or a milkshake for $1 more).


 Your Ad Here 


After reading over the menu for about 5 minutes, I had made my choice of a double cheese burger, side of hush puppies, side of chicken nuggets, and a strawberry milkshake.  I can’t tell you how amazing their food really is.  If you think it is just another fast food place like McDonald’s or Burger King, you are wrong!  The milkshakes alone are filling but for the price you pay, you can’t get it anywhere else!!

The service at Cookout was very fast and definitely had the southern comfort that anyone likes to feel.  I was able to have a conversation with the guy that took my order and actually was down to earth unlike some of the weird wackos that you get at other fast food places.  I recommend everyone to go to Cookout whenever you see one and at least stop in for a famous milkshake!!



 
Posts Related to Cookout Fast Food Restaurant Review - Amazing Cheap Milkshakes and Not Just Another Fast Food Joint

 
 Hot fast food restaurant complaints here on ReportYourComplaint! 

Here are some super hot fast food restaurant complaints from our readers and contributors here on ReportYourComplaint.com! // Here are some of the latest and ...
 
 Subway, burned meatballs, rude employees and an overall poor fast food restaurant experience and review! 

// My girl friend and I got hungry the other day and so we decided to head to a Subway restaurant on the outskirts of Los ...
 
 Asian Garden Chinese restaurant review–great Chinese food and they give you big servings! 

// I love great Chinese food and lately I have found a new Chinese restaurant here in Charlotte, NC that just makes me have to ...
 
 IKEA Pruta plastic food storage containers review–these reusable plastic food containers are great and very cheap! 

// The family and I happened to go to IKEA a few weeks ago and while I was there I saw this great deal they ...
 
 McDonald’s, happy meals, unhealthy greasy burgers that taste like crap, terrible french fries and how they are ruining the health of America and the world! 

// We were just discussing, earlier today, McDonald&apos;s greasy burgers and disgusting french fries and McDonald&apos;s failed mission statement. Anyone can go and access the ...
 
 
 Tags: burgers , chain restaurants , combo , combo meals , cookout , excellent customer service , fancy milkshakes , fast food , fast food restaurant , food , hot dogs , milkshakes , recommended , restaurants 
 
7 Responses to Cookout Fast Food Restaurant Review–Amazing Cheap Milkshakes and Not Just Another Fast Food Joint 

 cheap restaurant on September 3, 2010 at 12:27 AM 

If we think it is just another fast food place like McDonald’s or Burger King, we are wrong! The milkshakes alone are filling but for the price we pay, we can’t get it anywhere else!!

Like or Dislike: 3   0 
 kugcecanfy on December 4, 2010 at 11:02 AM 

I won’t eat at Cookout anymore because the guy at the drive thru was really rude to me and messed up my order on purpose.

Like or Dislike: 1   1 
 samantha on March 18, 2011 at 10:42 PM 

The cookout in aberdeen, nc has terrible service staff, oh wait its fast food go figure. All they have to do is take an order and the cant do that correctly. I also waited over ten minutes in line before my car even moved and when I did get to the window guess what, the manager was even rude. Never going there again.

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 Donna on April 28, 2011 at 9:00 PM 

I have been to the Cook Out in Roanoke Rapids, NC many times. The service was great and the food better. My husband and I like the cheeseburger meal. The price is great and I like the seasoned fries. but the onion rings are great too. I am thankful there is a easy place to go where the food does not taste like cardboard since I always seem to be in a hurry.

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 Carla Mercer on June 25, 2011 at 7:59 PM 

On June 25, 2011, when placing my order at the Cookout Durham, NC location on Hwy 70, I had to repeat our order 3 times before the clerk finally understood it. Then as I was picking up the order from the window, one of their employees twice called me an a**hole. The second time she screamed it out and my 15 year old was in the car with me. The manager of the store just apologized to me for not understanding my order in the first place, but only reminded the emloyee that the store window was open. He did not reprimand her at all for this terrible behavior. For what its worth, I plan to report this incident to the Cookout corporate office on Monday. Maybe both of them will be fired. Customers shouldn’t have to tolerate this type of behavior. But based on the posts on this web site, poor service seems to be the trend for Cookout.

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 Kimberly on December 1, 2011 at 8:28 PM 

I eat at the Cook Out in Kannapolis alot and they have the best milkshake, besides Brusters, but the price and quality are great. I’ve never had bad service, but they can get a little busy at times. Overall I’m pleased and full anytime I go there. As a matter of fact I just got a cappuccino milkshake from there…yummy.

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 nikki on June 7, 2012 at 6:24 PM 

Well while everyone is complaining about poor customer service my daughter was fired from the cookout in Raleigh, NC for giving great customer service but because she was so kind to the customer that it just pissed her off because the other cashier is the one who walked away from the register bc of the customers nasty attitude after being there for 2 years because they say customers are always right. Its alot of noise going on in this place two sides going at once so you might miss something they say you try not to but things happen so why are you so high on yourself that you cant repeat it and then pull up to tell my daughter that she repeats herself for noone she says it once and thats it and my daughter took care of her with respect! People need to really make sure it’s worth the complaint and not just bc you are having a bad day and you cause someone to lose their job can’t take care of their families. Things happen watch how you treat people vengence is Gods.

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
Search Website
 Most Popular
Complaints, Reviews, and Compliments! Want your company&apos;s product or service reviewed?
 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 Your Ad Here 
Tags
 automotive Awesome bad customer service car car dealer car dealership chain restaurants Charlotte Charlotte NC complaint compliment Customer service disgusting Educational fast food fast food restaurant food fraud health Helpful helpful information highly recommended honest review Horrible horrible customer service horrible service How to illegal Interesting Not recommended rave recommended restaurant review ripoff rude save money scam sucks Terrible unfair business practices unhealthy untrustworthy Walmart website Copyright©2012 Report Your Complaint.com . All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
