<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002935" url="http://www.savings.com/m-McDonalds-coupons.html" time="2012-07-12-19:01" support="1" score="0.0011110474840606817" bingtitle="Mcdonalds Coupons - Savings.com" webtitle="Mcdonalds Coupons - Savings.com | In-Store: Buy 1 McCafe Real Fruit Smoothie Get 1 Free">
			<query id="000245" bing-rank="230"/>
	<description>Nothing to print, just visit the nearest location and get the iced tea drink of your ... Inspired by the growing popularity of the fast food restaurant, Ray Kroc, a ...</description>
	<body>
		Register Sign-in 
 Join our community, win Savings swag! savings.com Save Money. Be Happy. 
 Top Searches: Sears , Shoes.com , JCPenney , Travelocity , Lands&apos; End 
 Home Coupons Local Grocery Community Blog 
 
 
 Categories &gt; Food&amp;Beverage &gt; Restaurants &gt;

Mcdonalds Coupons
 
Top Deals from McDonalds
 Print Coupon In-Store: Buy 1 McCafe Real Fruit Smoothie Get 1 Free 
Buy 1 McCafe real fruit smoothie, Cherry berry chiller, Frappe or frozen strawberry lemonade and get 1 free of equal or lesser value. + More 
 
Restriction may apply.

 Expires: Jul 30, 2012 Submitted: 2 weeks ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (3) Bad Deal (4) 

 Share By digitalee 
 
Top Deals at Other Restaurants Stores
 Get Code Expires today 
 Go to store 50% Off + Free Shipping 
Enter the code at checkout to save 50% on most restaurant gift certificates. + More 
 
Now, most will cost $5 for $25 worth of food and drink, instead of $10 for $25. Free shipping is included. See site for details.

 Expires: Jul 12, 2012 Submitted: 3 days ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (1) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By pmiller 
 Activate Coupon 1/2 Price Milkshake Happy Hour Every Day after 8pm 
Nothing to print, just visit your local drive-in after 8pm this summer to get real ice cream milk shakes for 1/2 price. + More 
 
 Submitted: 2 months ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (5) Bad Deal (1) 

 Share By brwood in  Fast Food 
 Activate Coupon $10 Off 
Click the link and sign up for the Maggiano&apos;s email club for a printable page to save $10 on your next visit. + More 
 
See site for details.

 Submitted: 11 months ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (17) Bad Deal (17) 

 Share By brwood in  Italian Restaurants 
 Activate Coupon Save Up to 90% on Los Angeles Deals 
Click through to save up to 90% on Los Angeles deals. + More 
 
 Submitted: 3 months ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (82) Bad Deal (1) 

 Share By SavingsMommie 
 Activate Coupon Join Denny&apos;s Breakfast Club to Receive Exclusive Offers! 
Click on the link to sign up for Denny&apos;s Breakfast Club to receive all of the latest news, offers and exclusive promotions all delivered to your email inbox. + More 
 
 Submitted: 3 years ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (24) Bad Deal (1) 

 Share By stella.louise 
 Activate Coupon 50% Off 
Nothing to print, just visit your local restaurant on July 30th to celebrate National Cheesecake Day with 1/2 priced slices of cheesecake. + More 
 
Limit 1 per customer.

 Expires: Jul 30, 2012 Submitted: about 24 hours ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (0) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By brwood 
 Activate Coupon Free Gift with Red Robin&apos;s eClub Sign Up 
Join Red Robin eClub and get a free burger on your birthday and a free gift just for signing up. + More 
 
 Submitted: 3 years ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (12) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By stella.louise 
 Activate Coupon $15.99 Eat and Play Combo 
Choose from eight entrees for $15.99 and get a $10 game card--or a $20 game card with entree for only $23.99! + More 
 
 Submitted: 3 years ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (6) Bad Deal (1) 

 Share By stella.louise 
 Activate Coupon Sign Up to Get Olive Garden&apos;s Exclusive E-mail Offers and Promotions 
Sign up for Olive Garden&apos;s online newsletter, The Family Table. + More 
 
You&apos;ll be the first to hear about news, events, upcoming special dishes we&apos;re preparing for you, limited-time offers, news from our Culinary Institute in Italy, contests, offers and more.

 Submitted: 3 years ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (48) Bad Deal (15) 

 Share By stella.louise 
 Print Coupon Expires in 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 5 days Steak, Ribs And Shrimp Dinner for $15.99 $15.99 
Print this deal and get the Summer Grill Trio with your choice of sides, 7oz sirloin, baby back ribs and grilled prawn for just $15.99. + More 
 
 Expires: Jul 16, 2012 Submitted: 1 week ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (0) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By brwood in  Fast Food 
 Activate Coupon Sign Up for Buca E-Club&amp;Get Free Appetizer or Dessert 
Get a free appetizer just for signing up for Buca e-Club. + More 
 
Also receive free brownie on
your birthday and a free dessert of your choice on your anniversary. Click through to start.

 Submitted: 12 months ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (2) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By edelweiss16 
 Activate Coupon Join the Red Lobster Club for Exclusive Promotions&amp;Birthday Coupon 
Sign up for free and get exclusive discounts, benefits, updates, promotions and sweepstakes via e-mail. + More 
 
Plus every year on your birthday get a special coupon in your inbox.

 Submitted: 3 years ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (32) Bad Deal (5) 

 Share By stella.louise 
 Activate Coupon Sign Up for Club Fondue, Receive Special Offers 
Click on the link to sign up for Club Fondue. + More 
 
Membership offers fantastic fondue features, including wine tastings, food samplings, invitations to special events and advanced holiday reservation privileges. As a member of the Club, you&apos;ll receive a free Chocolate Fondue for two when you sign up!

 Submitted: 3 years ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (10) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By stella.louise 
 Activate Coupon Sign Up for Applebee&apos;s Emails to Get News and Special Offers 
Follow this link to sign up for the email list to get news on promotions, new products, and more. + More 
 
 Submitted: 3 years ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (12) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By WiscoVixen 
 Activate Coupon See Current Promotions for Deals and Discounts 
Click on the link to view El Pollo Loco&apos;s current promotions. + More 
 
Find great savings on great El Pollo Loco meals.

 Submitted: 3 years ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (25) Bad Deal (1) 

 Share By stella.louise 
 Print Coupon 1 Free Menu Item with Purchase of a Large Drink 
Print this and take it to your local restaurant to get any menu item for free when you buy a large beverage. + More 
 
 Submitted: 5 months ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (3) Bad Deal (2) 

 Share By brwood in  Fast Food 
 Activate Coupon Pick 2 for $10 is Back - 1 Entree + 1 Dessert or Appetizer for $10 
Nothing to print, for a limited time the 2 for $10 deal is back, you can get an entree and your choice of an appetizer or dessert for just $10. + More 
 
See site for details.

 Submitted: a month ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (2) Bad Deal (1) 

 Share By brwood in  American Restaurants 
 Print Coupon Expires in 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 5 days Printable: Free Drink with Salad Wrap Purchase 
Get a free regular fountain drink or a regular bottled drink with your purchase on a salad wrap. + More 
 
 Expires: Jul 16, 2012 Submitted: about 9 hours ago 

 – less detail 
 
 Good Deal! (0) Bad Deal (0) 

 Share By nayrb23 
 
Recently Expired McDonalds Coupons
 
 $1 Off a McCafe Cherry Berry Chiller or Other Frozen Blended Drink Click the link and enter your name to print a personalized coupon for a Cherry Berry Chiller, McCafe Frappe, Real Fruit Smoothie or Frozen Strawberry Lemonade. free mcafe for signing up Sandiego only free mccafe coupon instantly san diego only McDonalds: 12 FREE Product Coupons for $1 For only $1, you can score the Spring Treat Packs Coupon Booklet. Here&apos;s whats inside: 3 Free Apple Dippers 3 Free Small Cones 3 Free Apple Juice OR White Milk Jug 3 Free Hamburgers Limit one certificate per person per visit, redeemable by children ages 12 and under only. Ask for these next time your [...] Free Medium Fries with Purchase of Soft Drink Buy a medium or large soft drink and present the coupon to get a free medium order of fries. Expires 2/4/2012. McDonald&apos;s Holiday 2011 Gift Card Deal Buy a $25 McDonald&apos;s Arch card and get a FREE Medium Extra Value Meal. Visit our extensive list of Holiday Gift Card Deals for 2011. Birthday and Dining Freebies: Be sure to check out our [...] McDonald&apos;s Printable Coupon: Free Medium Fries McDonald&apos;s has a printable coupon for a free medium order of fries with any purchase of a medium or large soft drink.  Print this coupon now and keep it in your wallet so you&apos;re always prepared.  Coupon expires 2/4. Heads up: in the past some McDonald&apos;s have not honored printable coupons, so always ask your [...] Free McCafe Smoothie or Latte Coupon in this Weekends Paper This weekend&apos;s USA Weekend insert (or Parade) will have a couple of great coupons! Free 12-oz McCafe Real Fruit Smoothie, Frappe or Frozen Strawberry Lemonade with the purchase of any sandwich or premium entree salad (exludes dollar menu items) Free 12-oz McCafe Iced or Hot Caramel Mocha, Mocha, Latte or Cappuccino with the purchase of [...] McDonalds Coupon: Buy One Drink, Get One FREE! McDonalds has a new coupon out on their website  for a FREE Frozen Strawberry Lemonade, Frappe or Real Fruit Smoothie when you purchase one! Just fill in your name on their form to print off your coupon! McDonald&apos;s Smoothie Coupon: Buy One Drink, Get One FREE! McDonalds has a new coupon out on their website  for a FREE Frozen Strawberry Lemonade, Frappe or Real Fruit Smoothie when you purchase one! Just fill in your name on their form to print off your coupon! McDonald&apos;s Coupon: Save $1/1 Frozen Strawberry Lemonade, Frappe, or Real Fruit Smoothie I usually stay far away from McDonald&apos;s but lately I&apos;ve become obsessed with their huge cup of Sweet Tea for $1. It&apos;s awesome! I&apos;m addicted. Anyway, this coupon isn&apos;t for that, but rather $1/1 Frozen Strawberry Lemonade, Frappe or Real Fruit Smoothie. Coupon is valid towards any size and expires on June 15th. Print now and [...] Sign Up for Emails to Get Promos and Special Offers First Follow this link to sign up for emails, and be the first to receive promotional offers and discounts. 
 
Comments about deals at McDonalds
 
 3 of 3 people found the following comment helpful: 
 By jenn03 11 months ago Bring back the Buy One, Get One Free drink. Thanks.
 
Was this comment helpful? yes no 
 Problem? 
 By nlbriggs a month ago I get deals from McDonalds out of newspapers and just started to receive these Savings Coupons. This is great!!
 
Was this comment helpful? yes no 
 Problem? 
 By dealtown 5 months ago Hi Bandit82, I just sent you an email to help you out with your issue!
 
Was this comment helpful? yes no 
 Problem? 
 By Bandit82 5 months ago lucillec82@aol.comwe hope that we hear from Mcdonalds concering this matter. Thank You
 
Was this comment helpful? yes no 
 Problem? 
 By Bandit82 5 months ago We went to Mcdonalds on Feb 22nd think that we could get the special Frappe for the $1.48 it was said on TV we would get it all the time it was good for that day when we got their the girl said that they stop it , that wasn&apos;t right we had to pay the full price that wasn&apos;t rightt , we go to Mcdonald 3to 4 times a week and we are not happy that they did this to us. we also had friends from out of town with us . lucillec82@aol.com
 
Was this comment helpful? yes no 
 Problem? 0 of 1 people found the following comment helpful: 
 By rhino 11 months ago I save most by not being a fan of this place. Just not my cup of tea (or quart of shake, whatever is appropriate).
 
Was this comment helpful? yes no 
 Problem? 
 Have something to say about deals at McDonalds? 
Latest Blog Posts
 
 MillerCoors Discontinues MGD 64 Lemonade and Other Short-Lived Products 

By dealtown 
at 8:55AM, 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 12 months ago
 |
 under Newsworthy 
 MGD 64 Lemonade, a lemonade-flavored light beer, or lemonade/ light beer hybrid, or something, is no more. MillerCoors has discontinued MGD 64 Lemonade after less than a year on the market. Some said it was refreshing, some said it tasted like dishwater, but most said, &quot;I&apos;ve never heard of that.&quot;

Read on to discover 5 other products that barely saw the light of day before they were discontinued. 
 Fast Food Food Stamps, Booze on the Burger King Menu and Other Marketing Mistakes 

By pmiller 
at 10:54AM, 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 a year ago
 |
 under Newsworthy 
 Photo courtesy of Ted Murphy , via Flickr 
 
Last week, Savings.com blogger Allegra clued us into KFC&apos;s misguided 
attempt to do something nice: selling huge sodas for a diabetes charity .
 Needless to say, their move did not not create the desired reaction, and laughs were had by (nearly) all.

Well, it&apos;s another week, and the trend continues as various purveyors of
 junk foods run afoul of the media. Read on to discover my personal 
favorites.
 
 Free Hot Samples: July 4th Deals and Freebies 

By FreeHotSamples Guest Blogger 
at 7:52AM, 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 a year ago
 |
 under Freebies 
 To help celebrate our independence here are a few freebies and deals.
You can get the BOGO coupon from McDonald&apos;s for smoothies or a free meal
for kids from IKEA if you&apos;re looking for food freebies. Brunswick is offering one
free game of bowling everyday until the 4th. If you don&apos;t have a live fireworks
show near you don&apos;t worry, there&apos;s an app for that. There are a couple $10 off
a $30 purchase printable coupons from Bath&amp;Body Works and World Market .
Military can take advantage of a couple free baseball games and free admission
to an amusement park. And of course there are the free printables for the kids. 
 Exposing the Calorie Count of Sushi, Salads and Other Allegedly Healthy Meal Options 

By SavingsIQ 
at 9:56AM, 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 a year ago
 |
 under Loose Change 
 How many of you go into a sushi restaurant and order a bunch of rolls thinking it&apos;s low in calories since it&apos;s supposedly good for you? Yes...I&apos;ll admit, I was one of those people until my friend mentioned that spicy tuna rolls are chock full of calories due to the large amounts of mayo contained inside the them. Now, I stick to sashimi and simple sushi.

Read on to see the breakdown of other &quot;healthy&quot; foods and the calories they are harboring. 
 25,000 McDonald&apos;s Big Macs and Man Is Still In Good Health 

By SavingsIQ 
at 10:57AM, 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 a year ago
 |
 under Newsworthy 
 When I read that Don Gorske was about to eat his 25,000th Big Mac burger on May 17, I almost fell off my chair. Then, I read that he had been eating at least two Big Macs a day since 1972! That&apos;s 39 years of eating 540 calorie burgers, minus the nine days that he took off. And, to top it off his doctor says his cholesterol is low and he&apos;s in good health!

So, how many calories and how much money did he spend in almost four decades that could have been put towards healthy food? I&apos;ll break it down for you. 
 Herding Cats: Make Sure to Buy Your LinkedIn Stock Before the May 21 Rapture 

By Dealman 
at 11:57AM, 
 

 
 
 
 
 
 a year ago
 |
 under Loose Change 
 Image courtesy of ICanHasCheezburger 

This week, we cover the LinkedIn IPO, the impending apocalypse, not raising the debt limit ( which could be apocalyptic ), Arnold Schwarzenegger&apos;s marital apocalypse, and the crusade against a hamburger-hocking clown.  Top Advice on Deals at McDonalds 
 By jenn03 11 months ago Bring back the Buy One, Get One Free drink. Thanks.
 All Comments Similar Stores Offer: 
 Restaurant Coupons Google Offers Coupons 
 More About McDonalds 
In the early 1950s, brothers Dick and Mac McDonald started the very first McDonald&apos;s restaurant in San Bernardino, California. Inspired by the growing popularity of the fast food restaurant, Ray Kroc, a milkshake maker salesman, decided to drive out to California to discuss turning the restaurant into a company of franchise stores.

In 1955, Ray opened the restaurant&apos;s first franchise store in Des Plaines, Iowa and history was made. Today, there are thousands of McDonalds restaurants all over the world. Offering everything from the signature Big Mac and the egg McMuffin to classic milkshakes and Happy Meals, McDonald&apos;s is as popular today as it ever was with generations of loyal customers and fans who&apos;ve grown up savoring the delectable items from the restaurant&apos;s ever-changing menu.

Before heading to your local franchise, grab a McDonalds coupon from Savings.com to help you save money on your next meal and indulge in your favorite McNuggets, Big Mac meal, yogurt parfait or other sinful delight without having to worry about breaking the bank.

McDonalds sometimes offers coupons like these: 

 

 

 

 
 
 About Us About Coupons Stores Brands Contact Us Affiliate Program Community Guidelines Privacy Policy Terms of Service Find More Products
	</body>
</document>
