<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002821" url="http://www.floridasupport.us/forum/viewtopic.php?f=63&amp;t=3134" time="2012-07-12-18:53" support="2" score="0.0019868096858689146" bingtitle="www.floridasupport.us • View topic - NEWS GEORGIA - GA." webtitle="www.floridasupport.usView topic - NEWS GEORGIA - GA.">
			<query id="000280" bing-rank="100"/>
			<query id="000257" bing-rank="237"/>
	<description>reconsider his order that each contribute more ... Craig was speaking in support of a bill introduced by House ... in South Carolina trying to rob a fast-food restaurant in a ...</description>
	<body>
		www.floridasupport.us

Florida death penalty

 Skip to content 
 
 Advanced search 
 Board index ‹ Main General Forum ‹ News - 2007 Change font size Print view 

 FAQ Login 
 
 NEWS GEORGIA - GA. 
 Please post news from different states here
 
 Moderators: dusty , dusty 
 Post a reply 41 posts• Page 1 of 3 • 1 , 2 , 3 
 NEWS GEORGIA - GA. 

 by dusty on Sat Nov 04, 2006 12:46 pm
 Here you can add the news of Georgia - GA. dusty   Posts: 2098 Joined: Thu Apr 06, 2006 7:41 pm 
 Website 
 Top 
 GA: A capital trial at the crime scene 

 by dusty on Tue Jan 09, 2007 10:02 am
 GA: A capital trial at the crime scene
Mon Jan 8, 2007 11:21AM
84.142.245.246


January 8, 2007

Georgia

A capital trial at the crime scene

Many will be watching as a courthouse slaying case unfolds in Atlanta. One
issue is fairness.

By Jenny Jarvie, Los Angeles Times

ATLANTA - Almost two years after a judge, a court reporter and a sheriff&apos;s
deputy were shot to death at the Fulton County Courthouse, Brian Gene
Nichols will stand trial in that courthouse for those crimes.

As TV cameras roll, the justice system will be on trial too.

After a blitz of media coverage of a nearly 26-hour manhunt for Nichols,
some legal experts question whether a fair trial is possible in the
courthouse where the attacks took place - particularly when the case is
prosecuted by former colleagues of the slain judge and court reporter.

&quot;I would be concerned, real concerned, if I were his defense attorney,&quot; said
Thomas Maher, executive director of the Center for Death Penalty Litigation
in North Carolina. &quot;The jurors may have a tough time separating themselves
from the people in the case. Sitting in the same courthouse, that&apos;s
difficult.&quot;

On March 11, 2005, Nichols was headed to trial to face rape charges and a
possible life sentence when, officials say, he overpowered a deputy, stole
her gun and opened fire in the courtroom. Atlanta residents were riveted as
officials mounted the largest hunt for a fugitive in Georgia&apos;s history.
Eventually, Nichols was apprehended at the home of a hostage, Ashley Smith,
a waitress and born-again Christian, who persuaded him to surrender and then
wrote a book about her ordeal.

In a 54-count indictment, Nichols is accused of murdering Superior Court
Judge Rowland Barnes and court reporter Julie Ann Brandau inside the
courtroom, Sheriff&apos;s Deputy Hoyt Teasley outside the courthouse, and customs
agent David Wilhelm at his northeast Atlanta home. Prosecutors are seeking
the death penalty for Nichols, now 35.

For most Atlanta residents, the facts of the case appear clear: Several
people witnessed the shootings in the courtroom; a surveillance camera in a
parking garage captured Nichols fleeing the courthouse; Nichols is alleged
to have confessed to Smith, and then to police.

&quot;So many people are aware of what happened, it&apos;s as if it&apos;s almost an
open-and-shut case,&quot; said Andrew Sheldon, an Atlanta-based jury consultant.
&quot;But as we know from the O.J. Simpson trial, you really have to be there.&quot;

Already, attorneys have sparred at a series of pretrial hearings and have
filed more than 80 pretrial motions. The defense team has attempted to block
the death penalty option and to throw out identification by some
eyewitnesses. It has also argued that live television coverage threatens
Nichols&apos; right to a fair trial, and it repeatedly sought to delay the trial,
claiming attorneys needed more time to prepare.

Although Nichols&apos; attorneys have not revealed their strategy, some legal
experts expect a mental health defense.

Prosecutors filed a motion last week to bar the defense from using such an
argument, saying that his attorneys had not shared evidence to that effect,
as the judge had required.

The trial, set to open Thursday, is almost certain to be one of the longest
and most scrutinized death penalty trials in Georgia. DeKalb County Superior
Court Judge Hilton Fuller, who was appointed to the case after all members
of the Fulton County bench recused themselves because they had connections
to the victims, has allocated three months for jury selection alone, and
county officials have sent 3,500 summonses to prospective jurors.

&quot;This is not going to be one of those &apos;What the heck, judge, everyone saw
him do it&apos; cases,&quot; said Ronald Carlson, a professor at the University of
Georgia School of Law.

Already, Fuller has assigned three extra attorneys to the case, and Nichols&apos;
defense has cost more than $500,000.

&quot;This is the most expensive death penalty case in the history of Georgia,&quot;
said Michael Mears, director of the Georgia Public Defender Standards
Council, which is paying for the three additional attorneys. The council,
which works on about 80 death penalty trials a year, has an overall yearly
budget of $5 million for capital cases.

Media scrutiny of this case, Mears said, has put a strain on the justice
system, raising the bar for future death penalty cases. Already, he said, a
number of Georgia legislators have talked to him about introducing bills to
limit the number of attorneys working on a single death penalty trial.
&quot;Everyone has bought into the idea that it&apos;s an extraordinary case,&quot; Mears
said. &quot;But basically it&apos;s just a murder case with four victims.&quot;

In February, Fuller ruled that the trial would be held in a first-floor
courtroom in the Fulton County complex because he could not find an
alternative location that would be convenient for jurors. Defense attorneys
filed a motion to hold the trial at Ft. McPherson Army base, south of
downtown Atlanta, but then notified the judge that the base&apos;s commander had
declined to make the site available for the trial.

The Nichols trial is not the first U.S. death penalty case to take place at
the crime scene. In 2001, Kenneth Baumruk, who shot and killed his wife and
wounded four others in a St. Louis County courthouse shooting in 1992, was
convicted of murder and sentenced to death in the same courthouse. A year
later, the Missouri Supreme Court overturned the conviction and death
sentence. In an opinion, Judge Michael Wolff wrote that the setting was
&quot;inherently prejudicial. The jurors, in effect, sat at the murder scene.&quot;

At least one other death penalty trial involving a courthouse shooting is
pending. The trial of Jennifer Hyatte, who is accused of shooting a guard
outside a Tennessee courthouse in 2005 to free her convict husband, has been
rescheduled to give lawyers more time to prepare a defense. Hyatte&apos;s
attorney has asked the court for a change of venue.

Despite concerns about holding the case in the same courthouse, Nichols&apos;
defense team does not want to risk a trial outside Fulton County: Jurors in
the county have tended to reject demands for the death penalty.

Steven Sadow, a veteran criminal defense attorney, said that so far Nichols&apos;
defense team had mounted a good technical legal defense but had built no
public sympathy for Nichols.

&quot;The defense has failed to humanize the defendant and give jurors a chance
to save his life,&quot; said Sadow. &quot;I don&apos;t think their defense strategy has
been designed to save him. If you go by the playbook, they&apos;ve done all
right. But it&apos;s not very rewarding to say, &apos;I&apos;ve done all right, but my
client&apos;s dead.&apos; &quot;

Still, with jury selection ahead, Sadow said it was possible that Brian
Nichols might escape the death penalty.

&quot;All the defense team is looking for is one person who can hang this jury so
the death penalty is not imposed,&quot; he said.

---

Source : Los Angeles Times

 http://www.latimes.com/news/nationworld ... nes-nation 


===============================================


GA: State, county squabble over cost of Nichols trial
Sun Feb 11, 2007 12:04PM
84.142.255.232


State, county squabble over cost of Nichols trial

By RHONDA COOK, BILL RANKIN
The Atlanta Journal-Constitution
Published on: 02/10/07

State and Fulton County officials pointed fingers Friday, claiming
the other is responsible for covering the skyrocketing costs of
defending accused courthouse killer Brian Nichols.
Lawyers from both sides asked Superior Court Judge Hilton Fuller to
reconsider his order that each contribute more money to Nichols&apos;
defense. Nichols&apos; defense has already cost $1.2 million. The dispute
has come to a head as officials from the Georgia Public Defender
Standards Council say it is running out of money and cannot continue
funding the Nichols case.
Jury selection in the case has begun, with prospective jurors
completing questionnaires. About 1,000 are scheduled to come back
beginning Feb. 26 for individual questioning.
But Nichols&apos; attorneys say the trial may need to be put on hold if
there is not enough money to pay the defense. They also say the judge
should prohibit prosecutors from seeking the death penalty if the
state cannot pay for what they contend is a constitutionally required
adequate defense.
The hours put in by the lawyers are a factor in the high cost of the
case. From July 2005 through the end of last year, Nichols&apos; three
private attorneys had billed the state for more than 4,000 hours of
legal work totaling more than $580,000 in fees. And Nichols&apos; fourth
lawyer, a state employee, was paid $162,000 during that time.
Soon after Nichols was charged with 54 felonies, including murdering
Judge Rowland Barnes, court reporter Julie Ann Brandau, deputy Sgt.
Hoyt Teasley and U.S. Customs agent David Wilhelm on March 11, 2005,
his original attorneys, all on the staff of the Capital Defender
Office, were replaced with Parker, the state employee, and three
private lawyers, earning $125 to $175 an hour. The rates for Nichols&apos;
lawyers, ordered by Fuller, exceed the $95 paid private attorneys in
other death penalty cases statewide. The transition occurred after
one of Nichols&apos; capital defenders, then licensed to practice law in
Washington, told Fuller during a May 2005 hearing that he was in the
process of being licensed to practice in Georgia. The lawyer did not
disclose that he had an administrative suspension from the State Bar
of Georgia for not paying dues for the previous four years.
Because of that, the team was replaced by the four who now represent
Nichols. Gwinnett District Attorney Danny Porter expressed surprise
at the number of hours Nichols&apos; lawyers have billed. &quot;These numbers
seem outrageous,&quot; Porter said.
There is no set standard for the amount of hours lawyers should spend
when defending a death-penalty case, according to the American Bar
Association. The ABA guidelines state that &quot;recent studies indicate
several thousand hours are typically required to provide appropriate
representation.&quot;
The guidelines cite an in-depth examination of federal death penalty
trials from 1990 to 1997. It found the total attorney hours in
capital cases that went to trial averaged 1,889 hours.
Rick Malone, a former South Georgia prosecutor who is now executive
director of the Prosecuting Attorneys Council of Georgia, said the
money spent so far on the Nichols case is &quot;ridiculous... You&apos;re not
entitled to the O.J. Simpson defense. It [the U.S. Constitution] just
requires you have competent attorneys and you have a reasonable
defense.&quot;
Dan Summer, a Gainesville criminal defense lawyer who has defended a
number of capital cases, said there should not be a rush to judgment
to condemn the fees being paid to Nichols&apos; defense team.
&quot;We&apos;ve got an oath to uphold the Constitution ... and to zealously
protect the interests of our clients and whatever time it takes to
discharge that oath is the time it takes,&quot; he said.
At Friday&apos;s hearing, neither the state nor the county wanted to spend
any more money on the case.
Last month, Fuller ordered the council to spend an additional
$150,000 on expert fees and other expenses for the defense in the
death penalty case. The council asked the judge to reconsider and
that was the subject of Friday&apos;s hearing. He also told the county to
pay about $50,000 to transcribe hundreds of hours of recordings of
Nichols&apos; conversations on a jail telephone.
&quot;It&apos;s not Fulton County&apos;s fault that the state fell into a situation
where it had a budgetary shortfall,&quot; said assistant county attorney
Willie Lovett. &quot;We did not create it.&quot;
Said Robert Remar, an attorney for the public defender council, &quot;If
the council doesn&apos;t have the money to pay for it, the court has the
authority to mandate the county to pay.&quot;
Fuller asked, &quot;Would y&apos;all prefer I go though a trial with inadequate
defense expense and wait until a retrial to address it?&quot;
The judge then held a private hearing with Nichols&apos; defense team and
lawyers for the state public defender office to talk about their
expenditures.

Find this article at:
 http://www.ajc.com/metro/content/metro/ ... nichols.ht 


=============================================== Last edited by dusty on Mon Feb 12, 2007 5:51 pm, edited 1 time in total. dusty   Posts: 2098 Joined: Thu Apr 06, 2006 7:41 pm 
 Website 
 Top 
 GA: Chatham traffic fatalities outpace homicides 3 to2 

 by dusty on Tue Jan 23, 2007 8:17 am
 GA: Chatham traffic fatalities outpace homicides 3 to2
Mon Jan 22, 2007 4:44PM
84.142.193.25


January 21, 2007

Georgia

Chatham traffic fatalities outpace homicides 3 to2

Megan Matteucci, Savannah Morning News

A bullet might be faster, but a speeding car is more dangerous.

For every two people killed in a homicide last year, three people died on
roadways in Savannah and in unincorporated Chatham County.

&quot;You or a family member is more likely to be a victim of a traffic death
than a violent crime,&quot; said Lt. Scott Simpkins, commander of the
Savannah-Chatham Metropolitan Police Department&apos;s Traffic Unit. &quot;That&apos;s in
every community, not just the city of Savannah. There&apos;s more vehicular
traffic, and it&apos;s only going to get worse.&quot;

SCMPD reported that 45 people died in 42 traffic wrecks last year. During
the same period, 29 people were homicide victims.

Vehicular homicides are not counted in the annual murder rate.

Many people talk about their fear of being shot, but rarely do you hear
worries expressed about traffic crashes, Simpkins said.

&quot;It should not be socially acceptable to kill someone in a car wreck,&quot; he
said. &quot;It should be an outrage.&quot;

Speed was the biggest factor that led to the deadly crashes, followed by
drunken driving, said SCMPD Sgt. Anthony Gallo, supervisor of traffic
investigations. More than 36 percent of Savannah&apos;s fatal wrecks involved
drivers traveling above the posted speed limit.

Simpkins said he routinely sees people act like &quot;Savannah is still a small
town.&quot;

&quot;They think they can get somewhere quickly,&quot; he said. &quot;You can&apos;t go from
Wilmington Island to Savannah Mall in 15 minutes. It&apos;s a 40-minute trip.
People try to make it in 15 minutes, and that causes problems.&quot;

Savannah drivers aren&apos;t the only ones with lead feet.

Gov. Sonny Perdue has said that more than 20 percent of the traffic
fatalities in Georgia in 2005 involved excessive speed.

Last week, Perdue addressed 2,000 lawmakers and businessmen at the Georgia
Chamber of Commerce breakfast. He called for an increase in speeding fines
for people who drive over 85 mph on Georgia roads and over 75 mph on
two-lane highways. The money will go to help provide medical care for trauma
victims.

Georgia has the 10th largest population in the nation, but the Peach State
ranks fourth in the number of traffic fatalities. The only states with more
vehicle deaths are Texas, Florida and California, said David Spear,
spokesman for the Georgia Department of Transportation.

Every five hours, someone dies in a traffic crash in Georgia. Statewide
crash numbers were not available for 2006, but state officials anticipate it
will be higher than ever.

&quot;It&apos;s entirely unacceptable we have that many fatalities in a year. It&apos;s a
very troubling, puzzling issue that disturbs us a great deal,&quot; Spear said.
&quot;The principle factor is: People drive too fast.&quot;

Spear also points to more distractions in cars, including cell phones and
Blackberries.

A growing danger

In addition to speed, police in Savannah attribute the increase in
fatalities directly to growth outside the city.

&quot;This city swells Monday through Saturday two-fold and three-fold,&quot; Simpkins
said. &quot;People come from all around to work and visit this city.&quot;

It&apos;s not just an increase in cars. Police are also working with a spike in
pedestrians spilling into the roadways. Eleven pedestrians were killed last
year.

Police reported four fatal wrecks on Bay Street in 2006, including two
pedestrians.

&quot;It&apos;s a problem area because it&apos;s a heavily traveled road in the
entertainment district,&quot; Simpkins said. &quot;So, pedestrians are coming out of
bars and not looking at the traffic.&quot;

While population also has exploded, many of the county&apos;s roadways have not
expanded.

&quot;Population growth is moving out of the urban areas and into what were rural
areas,&quot; Spear said. &quot;The roadways don&apos;t have the capacity or design to
handle the amount of traffic they need to be handling.&quot;

Often two-lane highways are just as deadly as interstates, said Jim Shuler,
spokesman for the Governor&apos;s Office of Highway Safety.

&quot;They are not designed for high speed, but people get off the interstate and
drive just as fast on these roads with curves, intersections and low
shoulders,&quot; Shuler said.

The state Department of Transportation estimates a $7.7 billion budget
shortfall over the next six years. And without the funding necessary to
widen roads, state officials are focusing on alerting drivers to slow down
and pay more attention.

Moreover, the state Department of Transportation plans to add more pavement
marks, rumble strips and other signs to alert drivers who drift out of their
lane, Spear said.

The majority of SCMPD&apos;s fatal crashes occurred in the West Chatham Precinct,
which has the largest amount of territory among the precincts to patrol -
108 square miles. The precinct also covers the major highways, including
interstates 16, 95 and 516, along with Ga. 204 and U.S. 17, Simpkins said.

&apos;Stupid hurts&apos;

SCMPD teams up with the Georgia State Patrol in patrolling the highways, but
there simply aren&apos;t enough police officers to monitor the thousands of cars
zooming into and out of Savannah every day, Simpkins said.

That&apos;s why police are looking toward technology to add extra eyes to the
roadways.

Officers are working with lawmakers to consider speed enforcement cameras in
some school and residential zones, Simpkins said. People have a tendency to
slow down when they see the cameras, just as they would when they see a
cruiser parked on the side of the road.

&quot;People respond to those cameras. It helps to modify driving behavior,&quot;
SCMPD spokesman Sgt. Mike Wilson said. &quot;The police can&apos;t be everywhere. Our
goal is to create a cautious motorist.&quot;

That&apos;s what happened at several intersections in southside Savannah where
traffic-light cameras have been installed. Police said they have noted a
decrease in crashes at White Bluff Road and Abercorn Street, also at
Abercorn and DeRenne Avenue, and at other intersections equipped with the
cameras.

&quot;Our goal is not to write everybody a ticket,&quot; Gallo said. &quot;It&apos;s to get
voluntary compliance.&quot;

And to save lives - not just civilian lives, but also those of officers
trying to enforce the law.

Two of the 44 accident victims in 2006 were police officers.

Effingham County Sheriff&apos;s Deputy Cpl. Dennis Wright was killed Nov. 17 in a
crash at Jimmy DeLoach Parkway and Benton Boulevard. Wright, who was
accompanied by another deputy in his patrol car, was on his way to a road
check.

SCMPD Officer John Wayne Allen Jr. died Dec. 27 in an off-duty motorcycle
crash on Abercorn Street. Allen was one of five people killed last year on
motorcycles.

Over the past several years, motorcycle crashes have risen across the state.
Simpkins attributes the crashes to a lack of state-mandated training. Other
states require driving lessons before a motorcycle license can be issued.

&quot;You can walk into Kawasaki and buy a 160-mph bike out of the crate. It&apos;s a
missile with wheels,&quot; Simpkins said. &quot;You&apos;re not driving it, you&apos;re pointing
it.&quot;

Police said they have seen a spike in motorcycle crashes involving soldiers.
Traffic officers are now traveling to area military bases and schools to
talk about motorcycle safety.

&quot;It&apos;s a lack of training and a lack of common sense,&quot; Simpkins said. &quot;If
you&apos;re going to go out there and act stupid, you&apos;re going to die. Stupid
hurts.&quot;

Making sense of wrecks

Tracking down the cause of these wrecks isn&apos;t just about finding out how
fast someone was going. Traffic investigations are just as in depth as a
homicide investigation, Gallo said.

&quot;It is a very lengthy and detailed process,&quot; he said. &quot;We get search
warrants for everything - from cups at bars and receipts to DNA hair
samples.&quot;

The investigation starts at the scene of the crash with photographs and
interviews, but it can extend for months. Police have to review autopsy
reports, analyze vehicle manufacturer documents and reconstruct how the
wreck occurred.

Momentum, velocity, speed - all of those high school algebra formulas you
thought you would never use come into play, Gallo said.

Everything from weather conditions and the curve of the roadway, to the time
of day and debris in the road affects a crash, Wilson added.

While murder and vehicular homicide investigations often are similar, the
punishment never is, Simpkins said.

A man convicted of picking up a gun and shooting someone faces life in
prison and sometimes the death penalty.

A man convicted of drinking a bottle of Vodka, crashing into a school bus
and killing 30 children gets a minimum of three years in prison - and 15
years at most.

&quot;It makes no sense,&quot; Simpkins said. &quot;You&apos;re operating a 3,500-pound weapon.
It&apos;s just as deadly.&quot;

---

Source : Savannah Morning News

 http://savannahnow.com/node/215446 dusty   Posts: 2098 Joined: Thu Apr 06, 2006 7:41 pm 
 Website 
 Top 
 GA: Brian Nichols - Death penalty, child support, smoking ba 

 by dusty on Fri Jan 26, 2007 8:50 am
 GA: Brian Nichols - Death penalty, child support, smoking ba
Thu Jan 25, 2007 11:42AM
84.142.197.16


Death penalty, child support, smoking bans Published on: 01/25/07 Four topics. My take. What&apos;s yours? • Bringing Brian Nichols to trial. Had the death penalty been taken off the table, Brian Nichols would be in a maximum security state prison by now serving the rest of his natural born life where he belongs. All the court proceedings to date in his murder trial for the killings at the Fulton County Courthouse two years ago have been aimed at one thing only — keeping him from getting a state-sanctioned lethal injection. Guilt or innocence is not the real issue in his case. It&apos;s all about the penalty. And, even if a jury does convict him and sentence him to death, Nichols will likely spend the next 20 or 30 years fighting that sentence while incarcerated in the same place and style he would have been if the sentence had been life without parole. In most death penalty cases these days, all the legal maneuvering is aimed at laying groundwork for the appeal of the sentence, not the conviction. Going into 2007, Cobb County had four death penalty cases finally ready, after several years, to be scheduled for trial. In one of them, county District Attorney Pat Head took the death penalty off the table just before the start of the felony murder trial earlier this month for Craig Michael Moore, accused of killing Jeffrey Stephenson, 52, a convenience store clerk in 2002. Defense attorneys agreed to forgo a jury trial for Moore if the death penalty was withdrawn. After that, the case was literally adjudicated in a matter of days. Judge Robert Flournoy III found Moore guilty of murder, aggravated assault, armed robbery and theft by receiving. He sentenced Moore to life without parole on Monday. • Not sure what it was, but it wasn&apos;t an ethics case. That complaint by state Democratic Party Chairman Bobby Kahn about Georgia House Speaker Glenn Richardson&apos;s &quot;inappropriate personal relationship&quot; with a former lobbyist simply couldn&apos;t go forward under the circumstances. Ethics complaints should always be taken seriously, but the complainers have some responsibility for providing more evidence than the alleged transgression was &quot;common knowledge.&quot; The Georgia Legislature has never been good about disciplining its own but obviously politically inspired complaints such as the one against Richardson harm the effort to make these guys take the issue seriously. • Profiles in bad parenthood. I can&apos;t decide which one of these Carl Hiaasen-like characters I have the least sympathy for in their battle over child support. There&apos;s Willie Gary, the married, millionaire Florida litigator (and one-time employer of Bill Campbell before the former Atlanta mayor&apos;s unfortunate incarceration) and Diana Gowins, a single woman from metro Atlanta who hooked up with Gary after they met at a Martin Luther King memorial event in 2000. (Right there, the gut starts to wrench.) Anyway, the two of them produced a set of twins as a result of their encounters, with the mother securing full custody. Until last year Gowins had been getting $24,000 a month in child support from Gary. But after presenting evidence that she was using a lot of the money on herself instead of the kids, Gary convinced a Georgia judge to reduce the payments to $5,000 a month. Gowins has asked the state Court of Appeals to review the award. From a strictly legal standpoint, the court&apos;s decision could set a precedent over what, if any, monetary guidelines judges should use when deciding child support payments involving the super rich. From a societal standpoint, the case sets its own precedents for sleaze. I&apos;m left thinking, wouldn&apos;t it be nice if the twins found some positive role models to replace these pathetic parental units? • My favorite new local ordinance. Bangor, Maine, enacted a law last week allowing police to stop cars if an adult is smoking while a child younger than 18 is a passenger in the same car. Bangor is believed to be the first city in the country to do this. Arkansas has banned smoking in cars in the presence of children younger than age 6, but fines can be waived if the smoker enrolls in smoking cessation classes. Other states and municipalities are considering similar laws. Smokers-rights groups hate the new laws, claiming they are based on &quot;junk science&quot; connected to limited exposure to second-hand smoke. I don&apos;t care. Ask anyone who had to grow up gasping for breath and sucking in cold air through cracked windows in the back seat of a car as their parents puffed away on Marlboro and Virginia Slims cigarettes in the front seat. Smoking in a car or in a house in the presence of children is child abuse. Book &apos;em Bangor. • Mike King is an editorial board member. His column runs Thursdays. Find this article at: http://www.ajc.com/opinion/content/opin ... mking.html 

===============================================


Lawyers fight over defense costs in Atlanta courthouse shootings case
By Harry R. Weber
ASSOCIATED PRESS
ATLANTA - The judge overseeing the murder case of a man accused of killing four people during a shooting spree that began inside a courthouse seemed perplexed Friday at how to deal with defense funding issues that could cause the trial to be suspended.

Attorneys for Fulton County and the Georgia Public Defender Standards Council told Superior Court Judge Hilton Fuller that they shouldn&apos;t have to pay some undisclosed expenses for Brian Nichols&apos; defense that Fuller has ordered them to pay.

&quot;My options are this,&quot; Fuller told the attorneys. &quot;Would you all prefer what I do is go through trial with inadequate defense resources and wait for a new trial before correcting it? What should I do?&quot;

Deputy Fulton County Attorney Willie Lovett and Robert Remar, an attorney for the public defender council, said their position simply was that their clients shouldn&apos;t have to foot the bill for the expenses the judge ordered.

&quot;Fulton County has been drawn into this case because the Georgia Public Defender Standards Council is running out of money,&quot; Lovett said.

But Remar said the expenses the judge ordered should be paid by the county, if anyone, and that the judge overstepped his authority by ordering the council to pay some expenses.

&quot;The bottom line is the council feels it is obligated to make the argument to the court ... that it doesn&apos;t believe the court has the authority to direct the payment of these expenses,&quot; Remar said.

Nichols&apos; defense lawyer Henderson Hill asked the judge to hold the remainder of the hearing in closed session so the attorneys could discuss the expenses in question in more detail. Fuller then ordered reporters and other members of the general public out of the courtroom.

Fuller did not immediately issue a ruling on motions by the county and the public defender council to reconsider his earlier order requiring the two parties to pay some of Nichols&apos; defense costs.

The exact expenses Fuller ordered the public defender council to pay have not been detailed publicly and are under seal. Fuller&apos;s order last month followed a request by Nichols&apos; lawyers for court assistance in paying for mental health experts. The expenses the county has been ordered to pay also have not been detailed, but they involve transcription and equipment costs, Lovett said Friday.

Nichols plans to use a mental health defense in his murder trial. His attorneys have not elaborated, but a recent ruling from Fuller suggests the defense argument may involve Nichols&apos; service in the Army Reserve. Fuller has ordered the military to turn over to the state Nichols&apos; service records and the military definition of &quot;situational anxiety.&quot;

The state public defender office says it already has approved more than $1.2 million for attorneys&apos; fees and expenses in the Nichols case.

Nichols, 35, was being escorted to a courtroom in the Fulton County Courthouse in downtown Atlanta for the continuation of his retrial on rape charges when he allegedly beat a deputy, stole her gun and went on a deadly shooting spree on March 11, 2005.

He is accused of killing the judge presiding over the rape trial, Rowland Barnes; a court reporter chronicling the proceeding, Julie Ann Brandau; a sheriff&apos;s deputy who chased him outside, Hoyt Teasley; and a federal agent he encountered at a home a few miles away that night, David Wilhelm. Nichols surrendered the next day after allegedly taking a woman hostage in her suburban Atlanta home.

Nichols, who faces a possible death penalty if convicted of murder, has pleaded not guilty.

Jury selection in Nichols&apos; murder trial began Jan. 11. Since then lawyers in the case have been poring through questionnaires filled out by hundreds of potential jurors. Individual questioning of potential jurors by attorneys in the case is set for Feb. 26. Opening statements are not expected until April or May.

Nichols&apos; lead attorney, Gary Parker, told The Associated Press on Thursday that Nichols has agreed to change his plea to guilty in exchange for prosecutors taking the death penalty off the table, but he said District Attorney Paul Howard has refused such a deal.

Howard has declined to comment on Parker&apos;s statements.


===============================================


D.A.: No Plea Deal For Nichols

POSTED: 6:14 am EST February 15, 2007

ATLANTA -- There will be no plea deal for the man accused of a deadly shooting spree at the Fulton County Courthouse. That&apos;s the word from District Attorney Paul Howard.

Howard said yesterday that accused gunman Brian Nichols can plead guilty if he wants to. But it will be up to a jury to decide whether to spare his life. A statement issued by Howard&apos;s office says his decision to seek the death penalty against Nichols is the right one.

The statement follows comments last week from Nichols&apos; lead attorney, Gary Parker. The lawyer said Nichols has offered to plead guilty to killing four people in a shooting rampage that began inside the downtown Atlanta courthouse in March 2005 if Howard takes the death penalty off the table.

Yesterday&apos;s statement from Howard&apos;s office said Nichols, like any defendant, is welcome to plead guilty at any time. But if Nichols enters a guilty plea without a deal with the state, there will be no guarantee he wouldn&apos;t get the death penalty.
Copyright 2007 by The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. Last edited by dusty on Thu Feb 15, 2007 12:38 pm, edited 2 times in total. dusty   Posts: 2098 Joined: Thu Apr 06, 2006 7:41 pm 
 Website 
 Top 
 Trial site set, but sealed 

 by dusty on Sat Jan 27, 2007 4:35 pm
 Trial site set, but sealed
Judge issues gag order to keep location of Turner case secret
By STEPHEN GURR
The Times

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------


The location of accused antifreeze killer Lynn Turner&apos;s death penalty trial will be a closely-guarded secret until the eve of the trial, a judge ruled this week.

Forysth County Chief Superior Court Judge Jeffrey Bagley issued a sealed order Thursday naming the county where the trial will take place. He also issued a separate, limited gag order instructing prosecutors, defense lawyers, court officials and potential witnesses to not disclose the location to members of the general public.

Turner, 38, faces a possible death sentence if convicted of murder in the 2001 death of boyfriend and Forsyth County firefighter Randy Thompson. She was previously convicted of murder in the 1995 poisoning of husband Glenn Turner. She is serving a life sentence for that conviction.

Turner&apos;s trial was moved out of Forsyth County earlier this month after Bagley found that too many prospective jurors had formed opinions about the case from intensive pretrial publicity. Of 106 jurors questioned, 92 percent had heard about the case and more than a third had formed opinions about Turner&apos;s guilt or innocence.

Forsyth County District Attorney Penny Penn on Friday confirmed that a location had been selected and that the trial would begin with jury selection on Feb. 26.

Penn said Bagley&apos;s limited gag order was intended to prevent a repeat of pre-trial publicity in the host county that might taint a jury pool.

&quot;He&apos;s trying to minimize the amount of publicity that&apos;s going to be out there,&quot; Penn said. &quot;I share in his frustration, after spending six days in a courtroom (during jury selection) going through this effort. We don&apos;t want to change venues in perpetuity.&quot;

The order naming the new trial location will be unsealed on Feb. 23, three days before the trial begins.

While perhaps not unprecedented, Bagley&apos;s gag order barring disclosure of the trial location is unusual, said Ron Carlson, a professor of law at the University of Georgia. He said the unsealing of the change of venue order three days prior to the trial made allowances for freedom of the press.

&quot;The gag order carefully does allow for a termination, so that this is not going to be a blanket situation throughout the trial, which would have raised serious First Amendment concerns,&quot; Carlson said.

Bagley, in his order, said members of the news media &quot;are to be allowed liberal access to coverage of the proceedings.&quot;

Carlson said he had not seen a similar order in local criminal cases.

&quot;In many respects, this is a very creative order by the judge,&quot; Carlson said. &quot;The arguments for this sort of order would be those generally asserted to protect the defendant&apos;s right to a fair trial,&quot; Carlson said. &quot;That is, cutting down on the media buzz in the community where this case is going to be tried.&quot;

Turner&apos;s first murder trial was moved from Cobb County to Houston County in 2004 for the same reasons. Cobb County Superior Court Judge James Bodiford announced the new venue location in open court.

The sensational case has generated national news media interest from CBS television, Court TV and, most recently, the New York Times.

Prosecutors allege that Turner poisoned both Thompson and her husband with ethelyn glycol, the active ingredient in antifreeze.

Contact: sgurr@gainesvilletimes.com , (770) 718-3428

Originally published Saturday, January 27, 2007 dusty   Posts: 2098 Joined: Thu Apr 06, 2006 7:41 pm 
 Website 
 Top 
 GA: New DNA tests OK&apos;d in 1982 Atlanta murder cases 

 by dusty on Wed Jan 31, 2007 1:00 pm
 GA: New DNA tests OK&apos;d in 1982 Atlanta murder cases
Tue Jan 30, 2007 5:01PM
84.142.224.34


January 30, 2007
New DNA tests OK&apos;d in 1982 Atlanta murder cases

ATLANTA, Georgia (AP) -- State lawyers have agreed to allow DNA
testing of dog hair that was used to convict Wayne Williams, who has
been blamed for the murders of two dozen children and young men in
the late 1970s and early &apos;80s.

Williams was convicted in 1982 of murdering Nathaniel Cater, 27, and
Jimmy Ray Payne, 21, and sentenced to two consecutive life term
Afterward, officials declared Williams responsible for 22 other
deaths and those cases were closed.

The decision Monday to allow DNA testing came in a response to a
filing as part of Williams&apos; efforts to appeal his conviction and life
sentence.

But while saying they had no xobjections to the testing, state lawyers
also said it &quot;would not change the results of this trial. Defendant
cannot show that DNA tests, no matter what the results, would create
a reasonable probability that the verdict would have been different
at the time of trial.&quot;

Williams&apos; lawyer, Jack Martin, asked a Fulton County Superior Court
judge to allow DNA tests on dog and human hair and blood that might
help win Williams a new trial.

During his original trial, dog hairs found on most victims were
consistent with hairs removed from the Williams&apos; family dog. During
the trial, witnesses testified they saw Williams with the victims
even though most of the case against him was based on analysis of
fiber and hair evidence found in Williams&apos; car and his parents&apos; home,
where he lived.

&quot;The good news is they&apos;ve agreed to DNA testing,&quot; Martin said. &quot;We
just want to see what the testing shows and we&apos;ll argue about what it
means later. It&apos;s odd that they should claim the dog hair evidence
doesn&apos;t make any difference when they made such a big deal about it
at trial.&quot;

Williams, who is black, has contended he was framed. He has
maintained that officials covered up evidence of Ku Klux Klan
involvement in the killings to avoid a racial conflict in the city,
which investigators have denied.

Copyright 2007 The Associated Press.

Find this article at:
 http://edition.cnn.com/2007/LAW/01/30/a ... ref=rss_us 

===============================================


GA: DNA refutes case for bill on death penalty
Wed Jan 31, 2007 4:13AM
195.28.224.59


DNA refutes case for bill on death penalty

Published on: 01/31/07
The tale of Willie O. &quot;Pete&quot; Williams — recently released from prison
after serving 21 years for a crime he did not commit — is yet another
reminder of the tragic flaws of the criminal justice system. It
falters under the weight of human frailty.

Williams&apos; is just the latest case of a Georgian whose innocence has
been proved after the prime of his life was stolen by a wrongful
conviction. Over the past 7 1/2 years, five other men have been
released because of DNA evidence. You&apos;d think their suffering — false
imprisonment at the hands of the state — would have shaken loose a
torrent of legislation designed to lessen the chances of such
mistakes ever happening again.

You&apos;d be wrong. Instead, some legislators have decided to do just the
opposite — increase the chances of an ungodly mistake. House Majority
Whip Barry Fleming (R-Harlem) has introduced a bill that would allow
a judge to impose capital punishment even if the jury did not
unanimously vote for death. Only nine jurors would have to approve
for the defendant to get the ultimate punishment.

Fleming cited a horrendous murder in Gwinnett County to justify his
legislation, according to a report by Journal-Constitution staff
writer Carlos Campos. In that case, all 12 jurors agreed that Wesley
Harris kidnapped and murdered a mother and her 2-year-daughter;
however, two members of the jury rejected capital punishment. As a
result, Harris is serving life in prison without the possibility of
parole.

But the viciousness of Harris&apos; crime is no excuse for making it
easier to sentence a man to die. (The public is permanently safe from
his predations.) It ought to be difficult for the state to sentence a
person to death. Even though most states require that 12 jurors must
vote for the death penalty, some men and women have still been
wrongly sent to death row. How many innocent defendants would be
executed if only nine jurors had to decide?

Here&apos;s a bedrock principle of the Bill of Rights that many Americans
cannot accept: It ought to be harder for an innocent man to be
convicted than for a guilty man to go free. After all, locking up a
person for a crime he did not commit is itself an unspeakable crime.
That&apos;s why decades of court rulings have affirmed defendants&apos; right
to an attorney; to be notified of exculpatory evidence; and to refuse
to incriminate themselves.

But many prosecutors are apparently frustrated that Americans are
less certain in their support of the death penalty and that more
jurors are reluctant to hand it out. According to a 2005 Gallup poll,
56 percent of Americans supported the death penalty, while 39 percent
preferred a sentence of life without parole. Just a year later,
Americans were roughly divided in half.

Death penalty experts cite several reasons for the declining support
for capital punishment. Violent crime has dropped; at the same time,
more states offer the option of life without parole — a guarantee
that criminals will not be freed to prey on others. But experts also
point to the scores of cases in which death row inmates have been
found to be innocent — a factor that cannot be ignored.

Since 1973, more than 120 people in 25 states, including Georgia,
have been exonerated and released after they were sentenced to die,
according to the Death Penalty Information Center. (That doesn&apos;t
count the hundreds of others exonerated of lesser crimes and released
from prison.)

So instead of making it easier to send innocent men and women to
death row, the Georgia Legislature should be working hard to plug the
holes in the criminal justice system that contribute to wrongful
convictions.

They might start by imposing standards for eyewitness identifications
in criminal cases. More than 75 percent of those freed by DNA
evidence were convicted because of faulty eyewitness identifications,
according to the Innocence Project in New York. Williams was among
those.

The General Assembly should also establish guidelines for
compensation for those men and women who are wrongfully incarcerated.
There is no way to make Williams&apos; life whole again, but he is owed
something for the years the state has taken away. And this doesn&apos;t
apply just to Williams. There will be others.

Because fear and prejudice and undue haste continue to haunt our
criminal justice system, 20 years from now we will release another
Pete Williams — maybe several of them — from prison, having stolen
the better part of his life by mistake.

• Cynthia Tucker is the editorial page editor. Her column appears
Wednesdays and Sundays.



 http://www.ajc.com/opinion/content/opin ... dtuck.html 

===============================================

[http://www.deathpenaltyinfo.org/article.php?did=2221&amp;scid=64]


Georgia Innocence Project Uses DNA To Free Man After 22 Years In Prison
Willie Williams has been freed from a Georgia prison after spending half of his life, 22 years, behind bars for a crime he did not commit. &quot;I never gave up,&quot; Williams said following his release, which came just 5 days after the Georgia Innocence Project discovered Williams&apos; DNA did not match a swab taken from the woman he was convicted of raping in 1985. After learning about the DNA evidence excluding Williams, Fulton County District Attorney Paul Howard ordered Williams released. Prosecutors now want to compare the DNA from the victim&apos;s swab to the DNA of another convicted rapist who has since been released from prison. (Atlanta Journal Constitution, January 24, 2007). See Innocence.

--
Posted By sisselnor to wrongful-convictions on 2/08/2007 08:29:00 AM Last edited by dusty on Thu Feb 08, 2007 5:56 pm, edited 1 time in total. dusty   Posts: 2098 Joined: Thu Apr 06, 2006 7:41 pm 
 Website 
 Top 
 Georgia legislative leaders: Execution made easy? 

 by dusty on Fri Feb 02, 2007 10:26 am
 Georgia legislative leaders: Execution made easy?
Thu Feb 1, 2007 8:17AM
195.28.224.59


Execution made easy?

Jan 31, 2007 05:44 AM


January 30, 2007

Albany -- Georgia legislative leaders introduce a measure to make the death penalty more common. The measure would allow a majority vote by jurors of only 9 to 3 to sentence a convicted person to death, instead of the present unanimous decision.

Many South Georgians in the judicial system say this is a bad idea.

Georgia House Majority Whip Barry Fleming of Harlem introduced the measure, to stop rigid death penalty opponents from stopping capital punishment. Fleming said the bill would prevent jurors who hide their opposition to capital punishment from &quot;sabotaging the death penalty.&quot;

Defense Attorney Pete Donaldson said, &quot;I guess they are just looking for the death penalty to be a sure thing every time they ask for it. It&apos;s all politics.&quot;

Current law requires jurors in death penalty cases to unanimously determine the defendant&apos;s guilt, then also be unanimous on whether the crime deserves the death penalty.

Donaldson says the death penalty needs to be the hardest verdict in the court system. &quot;168 people who have freed from death row on DNA examinations that have proven the person on death row was not guilty. It seems to me they are getting death penalties pretty easily now.&quot;

Judge Loring Gray also agrees this measure would not be good for justice. &quot;When you talk about the ultimate penalty, the death penalty, I think it&apos;s almost a misjustice to say that less than an unanimous verdict could sustain the death penalty.&quot;

Fleming said rigid death penalty opponents have managed to sneak through pre-trial screenings that remove people morally opposed to capital punishment, and his plan would give other jurors the ability to give that sentence.

&quot;I think it&apos;s an abomination,&quot; Donaldson said. &quot;Every time some legislator wants to make a headline or gain some votes, he waves a law and order flag around.&quot;

Both Judge Gray and Donaldson agree that the measure would almost certainly lead to legal challenges, further delaying justice.

Dougherty County Prosecutor Greg Edwards said he thinks the death penalty statute should stay the same as it is now, requiring the most thorough decision for the ultimate penalty.

Feedback: news@walb.com ?subject=DeathPenaltyChange/JW

 http://www.walb.com/Global/story.asp?S=6012167 dusty   Posts: 2098 Joined: Thu Apr 06, 2006 7:41 pm 
 Website 
 Top 
 GA: TROY ANTHONY DAVIS 

 by dusty on Wed Feb 07, 2007 8:21 am
 GA:Troy Anthony Davis - On Law and Justice
Tue Feb 6, 2007 5:51AM
195.28.224.59


February 5, 2007

Georgia

On Law and Justice

The Pacifica Board is also concerned about violence at home-including police
brutality and the death penalty.

In Georgia, an innocent Black man could soon be executed. The Pacifica Board
has resolved to report on Troy Anthony Davis. In 1991, a jury convicted
Davis for the 1989 killing of a white police officer. Fifteen people
testified against him at trial. Afterwards, 13 of these witnesses recanted
their testimony. Some admitted that they perjured themselves because of
police pressure, and some actually identified another man as the killer. But
the courts still want Davis executed.

Pacifica is calling on its listeners to stop wrongful executions and call
Troy Davis&apos; sister, Martina Correia, at (912) 484-0344 to support his last
appeal.

The Pacifica National Board also supports the demand by many organizations
and community activists nationwide for an end to police brutality.

There are many examples, including two recent extreme cases. In late 2006,
Sean Bell, an innocent and unarmed African American male, was killed in a
barrage of 50 bullets fired by five New York City police officers. Two of
his friends, also African American and unarmed, almost died. In the same
week, Kathryn Johnston, a 92-year-old African American grandmother, was
killed by police in Atlanta in a botched drug raid.

The Pacifica Board condemns these and other police killings, and the
harassment of all those who have been victimized by police brutality.
Joining Congress members Cynthia McKinney and John Conyers, the Board
demands that Congress hold hearings on the state of U.S. law enforcement
agencies&apos; use of force and deadly force against Black, Latinos and other
communities of color.

The complete texts of these motions can be found on Pacifica&apos;s national
website: www.Pacifica.org . This commentary will be aired on all Pacifica
stations. We urge you to learn more and do whatever you can to make a
difference.

To hear the audio cart, go HERE:
The motions can also be found at HERE

---

Source : Pacifica Radio (Pacifica Radio, founded in 1949 by pacifist Lewis
Hill, was the first listener-sponsored radio network in the country. It
operates stations KPFA-FM in Berkeley, KPFK-FM in Los Angeles, KPFT-FM in
Houston, WBAI-FM in New York, and WPFW-FM in Washington, DC, and has more
than 100 affiliate stations. )

 http://baltimorechronicle.com/2007/020507Pacifica.shtml 


===============================================


GA: The Possible Innocence of Troy Davis
Mon Feb 19, 2007 2:59PM
84.142.240.20


Georgia

The Possible Innocence of Troy Davis

A new report issued by Amnesty International focuses on the case of Georgia
death row inmate Troy Davis to illustrate the issue of innocence and the
legal hurdles that death row inmates face in seeking judicial relief. The
report - &apos;Where is the justice for me?&apos; The case of Troy Davis, Facing
Execution in Georgia - notes that Davis has been on death row for 15 years
for a murder that he maintains he did not commit. Many of the state&apos;s
witnesses against Davis have since recanted or contradicted their testimony,
and some have claimed that statements were made under police duress.

Given the barriers to a new trial caused by the Anti-terrorism and Effective
Death Penalty Act of 1996, Amnesty states that Davis&apos; last hope may be the
clemency process.

(Amnesty International, &quot;&apos;Where is the justice for me?&apos; The case of Troy
Davis, facing execution in Georgia,&quot; February 2007). Read the report
 http://web.amnesty.org/library/index/engamr510232007 

---

Source : Death Penalty Information Center

 http://www.deathpenaltyinfo.org/article ... 47&amp;scid=64 Last edited by dusty on Tue Feb 20, 2007 12:38 pm, edited 1 time in total. dusty   Posts: 2098 Joined: Thu Apr 06, 2006 7:41 pm 
 Website 
 Top 
 GA/LA:Shareef Cousin Ex-inmate to discuss time on death row 

 by dusty on Thu Feb 08, 2007 1:40 pm
 Ex-inmate to discuss time on death row
TAYLOR RHODES
Issue date: 2/8/07 Section: News
PrintEmail Article Tools Page 1 of 2 next&gt;What started as a death sentence for Shareef Cousin turned into a cause that inspires him to share his story.

Cousin, who was found innocent after he had been convicted of murder and sentenced to death, will be speaking at The Chapel at 5:30 p.m. today.

More than 15 years ago, Cousin was found guilty of murder, despite evidence showing he was in another place at the time the crime was committed.

After he had been incarcerated for 10 years, the Louisiana State Supreme Court overturned Cousin&apos;s conviction of murder due to improperly withheld evidence.

Cousin is now in his first year at Morehouse College. The 27-year-old is a community organizer for the Southern Center for Human Rights.

&quot;Mainly I&apos;ll be speaking about the death penalty and my experience on death row,&quot; said Cousin.

&quot;I was put on death row at the age of 16, and I left death row at the age of 21.&quot;

Cousin feels his story is important for people to hear because it&apos;s a first-hand account.

&quot;Many times we hear about the death penalty, for or against it, from an academic perspective,&quot; Cousin said. &quot;I&apos;ll be coming at it from the personal experience of being on death row.&quot;

Cousin&apos;s visit will be hosted by the University chapter of Georgians for Alternatives to the Death Penalty, National Lawyers Guild, Black Law Students Association, Amnesty International and the Center for Humanities and Fine Arts at the University, according to a news release.

Co-president of the University&apos;s chapter of Georgians for Alternatives to the Death Penalty (GADP) Katrina Wetche said she feels students should be involved in speaking out against capital punishment.

&quot;(Students) need to be aware of the injustices that are occurring,&quot; said Wetche, a senior from Atlanta. &quot;There are so many errors that occur in the process that having definite solutions doesn&apos;t make sense.&quot;

Wetche said the group seeks reform of the system.

&quot;We don&apos;t want to end the death penalty altogether necessarily,&quot; Wetche said. &quot;We just want to get a moratorium and just stop executions until you know that every single person on death row is actually guilty.&quot;

Alec Watts, a senior from Stone Mountain and co-president of the University&apos;s chapter of GADP, said the group does not take an official stance on the death penalty but offers alternatives to the sentence.

&quot;We do offer alternatives like a moratorium and life without parole,&quot; Watts said.

He also said keeping those on death row alive is more economical.

&quot;A lot of people think that it costs more to keep someone in prison than to execute them, but a lot of non-partisan studies have shown that it actually costs more to put people through the process of executing them,&quot; Watts said.

The group seeks to educate students on the issues surrounding the death penalty.

&quot;The blood of innocents is basically on our hands,&quot; Watts said. &quot;We&apos;d all be responsible for the execution of an innocent if our tax money is going towards that, and we all live in a society that generally supports the death penalty.&quot;

Watts said the group is collecting signatures from people in Athens to send to a state representative in support of a moratorium.

Today Cousin pursues a dual degree in political science and African-American Studies at Morehouse.

&quot;It&apos;s really amazing listening to (Cousin) because we&apos;re not really exposed to this side of life at college,&quot; said Wetche. &quot;Shareef Cousin is making the best of what&apos;s happened to him.&quot; dusty   Posts: 2098 Joined: Thu Apr 06, 2006 7:41 pm 
 Website 
 Top 
 GA: Bill would ease jury rules on death penalty 

 by dusty on Mon Feb 12, 2007 5:52 pm
 GA: Bill would ease jury rules on death penalty
Sun Feb 11, 2007 12:09PM
84.142.255.232


Georgia

Bill would ease jury rules on death penalty

By LATEEF MUNGIN
The Atlanta Journal-Constitution
Published on: 02/11/07
They all agreed Wesley Harris committed double murder in a horrific fashion.

But they couldn&apos;t agree on his sentence.

With the jury hopelessly deadlocked at 10-2, a Gwinnett County judge had no choice but to sentence Harris to a life without parole.

For the 10 jurors, this was an outrage, a miscarriage of justice. If anyone deserved the death penalty, they said, it was Harris.

Weeks later they were still fuming. The 10 met again, in November 2005, to commiserate about the verdict they felt was stolen from them. The meeting became the genesis of a campaign. The jurors turned their anger into letter-writing, lobbying state officials and legislators.

&quot;That night, we all felt that the law had to change,&quot; said Denise Schnieders, a Gwinnett County schoolteacher who has emerged as a spokeswoman for the former jurors. &quot;We sat and talked about how we could make a difference. So I put my girls to bed at 8 every night and spent hours writing letters. I wrote everybody I could. Even the governor.&quot;

They got some attention. In January, two years after the verdict in the Harris case, an east Georgia legislator, House Majority Whip Barry Fleming (R-Harlem) proposed a bill that would give judges the ability to act when a jury can&apos;t agree.

House Bill 185 would allow a judge to impose the death sentence if at least nine jurors vote for execution. It would not change the rules for deciding guilt: That would still require unanimous agreement.

If approved, the bill would make Georgia one of five states that allow judges to impose a death penalty without a unanimous jury vote, according to Washington-based Death Penalty Information Center, a nonprofit organization that analyzes death penalty issues.

Fleming said he &quot;fashioned a bill so that there will not be another miscarriage of justice like what happened in Gwinnett.&quot;

Opponents argue that if the law requires a unanimous verdict for finding guilt, the same standard should apply to the death penalty.

A cruel, senseless crime

The crimes that brought Wesley Harris under the threat of execution began on a November day in 1999.

According to testimony at his trial, Harris, a 27-year-old fast food worker, abducted Whitney Land, 22, and her 2-year-old daughter Jordan from a Clayton County park south of Atlanta.

At gunpoint, Harris drove them to Gwinnett County, where he executed the mother and child on the side of a busy Lawrenceville road. Police believe Land called 911 on her cellphone before she was killed. The apparent motive was car-jacking.

The evidence against Harris was overwhelming. A friend testified that he helped Harris ditch the murder weapon and burn the bodies.

The jury deliberated about 10 hours before finding Harris guilty. But the panel considered his sentence for only an hour before reporting they were deadlocked 10-2.

The two holdout jurors have never spoken in public about why they did not vote for death. They declined repeated requests for interviews after the trial and did not return phone calls seeking comment for this article.

According to other jurors, the two gave no reason other than they just couldn&apos;t vote for the death penalty.

Some say effort too hasty

When he talks about the reasons for his legislation, Fleming cites the Harris case and another from Augusta, the case of convicted cop killer William Kenny Stephens.

According to reports in the Augusta Chronicle, Stephens received a life sentence in 2000, during his third trial on the charges. The original trial, in 1980, resulted in a death sentence. An appeals court ruled the court wrongly failed to consider his mental state before sentencing Stephens to death. In 1989, a second jury said he should be executed.

A second appeal resulted in a third trial in 2000. This time, one juror did not vote for execution. Stephens is now serving a life sentence in Valdosta State Prison.

&quot;In that case, one juror overruled the decisions of 35 other jurors,&quot; said Fleming, whose bill is awaiting a hearing before the House Judiciary Committee.

Drew Findling, an Atlanta criminal defense attorney, is among opponents of Fleming&apos;s bill.

&quot;It is a sad day when we are trying to make it easier for the state to kill a citizen,&quot; Findling said. &quot;It takes a unanimous vote for the guilt or innocence phase, why would you lower the standard when it comes to taking a human life?&quot;

Feelings hard to fathom

Under law and the rules of courts, any potential juror in a death penalty case is questioned by attorneys and the judge before the trial. They are asked if they could impose the death penalty. Those that cannot are usually not allowed on a jury.

Critics of the current system in Georgia say it is too easy for would-be jurors who oppose the death penalty to lie — or to believe they could vote for execution and then simply change their minds when faced with a life-or-death vote.

Augusta District Attorney Danny Craig said he has seen this happen several times in death penalty cases.

&quot;It could be that jurors don&apos;t know exactly how they feel about the death penalty during the time they are questioned,&quot; Craig said. &quot;They try to answer the question to the best of their ability, but then learn that they unintentionally misrepresented their willingness to impose the death penalty when it is time make a decision.&quot;

Beth Bailey, one of the 10 Gwinnett County jurors, said frustration with the system led the jurors to act.

&quot;We started wondering about how many other people have had to go through this,&quot; Bailey said. &quot;And we decided that we could make a difference.&quot;

Schnieders, the jury spokeswoman, recounted the horror of the crime in her letters to state and local officials.

&quot;Whitney was shot first. He shot her in the back, pulled her from the car, shooting her twice more in the chest,&quot; Schnieders wrote. &quot;When he got back in the driver&apos;s seat of the car Jordan was crying; frightened and screaming. He shot her in the chest while she was helplessly strapped in a car seat.&quot;

Gwinnett District Attorney Danny Porter, who prosecuted the Harris case, said he is surprised by the passion of the former jurors.

&quot;I have never seen a jury so connected to a case,&quot; said Porter. &quot;I have never seen a jury push so hard to change the law. Based on my conversations with legislators, what they have done absolutely got their attention.&quot;

Whatever the outcome, the jurors&apos; work has gained them one fan: Sheila Howell, Whitney Land&apos;s mother and Jordan&apos;s grandmother.

&quot;I am still surprised that after all this time, some of the jurors are still working on this,&apos; said Howell. &quot;It is surprising that someone still cares.&quot;

Schnieders said she is pleased that state lawmakers are listening. The grade school teacher said the Harris case was the first time she was on a jury, and she hopes it was her last.

&quot;Everybody expects the feelings to go away, but for me it has not,&quot; said Schnieders. &quot;We are still ready to do whatever we can, because for us the system did not work.&quot;

Find this article at:
 http://www.ajc.com/metro/content/metro/ ... nalty.html dusty   Posts: 2098 Joined: Thu Apr 06, 2006 7:41 pm 
 Website 
 Top 
 LYNN TURNER:Trial for Lynn Turner will be held in Whitfield 

 by dusty on Wed Feb 14, 2007 8:27 am
 LYNN TURNER



Trial for Lynn Turner will be held in Whitfield County

The Associated Press
DALTON, Ga. — Whitfield County has been picked as the new location for the trial of a woman accused for the second time of killing a man by poisoning him with antifreeze.

Forsyth County Chief Superior Court Judge Jeffrey Bagley had ordered the new site in northwest Georgia be kept secret until Feb. 23 — the Friday before the trial there is to begin Feb. 26. But court documents obtained by The Atlanta Journal-Constitution under the state&apos;s Open Records Act reveal the new location for the trial of Lynn Turner.

Turner is charged in the 2001 poisoning death of Randy Thompson, a firefighter and the father of her two children.

She had been scheduled to stand trial last month in Forsyth County Superior Court. But Judge Bagley stopped jury selection on Jan. 16 and ordered the trial moved out of county due to pretrial publicity. At that point, about 100 potential jurors had been interviewed and roughly 90 percent knew some details of Turner&apos;s case.

Whitfield County sheriff&apos;s Maj. John Gibson told The Daily Citizen of Dalton that the sheriff&apos;s office began preparing security for the trial about three weeks ago. The trial will require extra deputies and overtime, Gibson said. Forsyth County will pay the bill.

At least 500 Whitfield County residents will be called as potential jurors in the death penalty case, records show.

Turner is already serving a life sentence for the 1995 death of her husband, Cobb County police officer Glenn Turner. Lynn Turner&apos;s 2004 trial took place in Houston County after pretrial publicity prevented prosecutors from trying that case in Cobb County.

Copyright 2007 The Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten or redistributed. dusty   Posts: 2098 Joined: Thu Apr 06, 2006 7:41 pm 
 Website 
 Top 
 GA: Prosecutor argues that death penalty reform is needed 

 by dusty on Sat Feb 24, 2007 1:23 pm
 GA: Prosecutor argues that death penalty reform is needed
Thu Feb 22, 2007 5:55AM
195.28.224.59


Wednesday, February 21, 2007
Prosecutor argues that death penalty reform is needed
By SHANNON McCAFFREY, Associated Press Writer

ATLANTA (AP) — A lone jury holdout should not be able to sabotage a
death sentence, a prosecutor told a state House panel on Wednesday.

At a hearing packed with supporters and opponents of capital
punishment, Augusta District Attorney Danny Craig said Georgia&apos;s law
should be changed to allow the death penalty in cases where a jury is
not unanimous in the sentencing phase.

Craig was speaking in support of a bill introduced by House Majority
Whip Barry Fleming, R-Harlem, that would allow a judge to impose the
death penalty even if as many as three jurors cast a vote against
execution.

He was the only witness to testify on Wednesday in the first of what
are expected to be several hearings on Fleming&apos;s bill.

Opponents argue the system works as it is and is designed to provide
a system of checks and balances.

&apos;&apos;Sometimes a juror votes against the death penalty because issues
are raised that convince them that the defendant does not deserve to
die, not because someone is out to sabotage the process,&apos;&apos; public
defender Gerald Word said in an interview after the hearing.

Craig argued public support for the death penalty remains high across
the country and in Georgia.

&apos;&apos;Yet we have a law that allows one juror to veto the votes of the
other 11,&apos;&apos; he said.

As evidence that the law was needed, Craig pointed to the case of
William Kenny Stephens. Two separate juries sentenced Stephens to
die. Legal problems prompted a third trial and in those proceedings a
sole juror voted against capital punishment. Stephens was sentenced
to life without parole.

Fleming&apos;s bill would still require that a verdict of guilt or
innocence must be unanimous. The change would apply only to the
sentencing phase.

Rep. Kevin Levitas, an Atlanta Democrat and former prosecutor, said
he had concerns that the state would be imposing an easier standard
for the execution than for guilt or innocence. And he wondered if the
measure would be ultimately pass muster with the courts.

&apos;&apos;I&apos;m a little concerned that we should be supporting a penalty of
death based on majority will,&apos;&apos; Levitas said.

Craig said three other states — Delaware, Alabama, Florida — also
have laws that allow for a sentence of death in cases where the jury
is not unanimous.

&apos;&apos;This is definitely a constitutionally safe bill that&apos;s been
introduced to you,&apos;&apos; he said.

Craig said he did not believe most jurors who ultimately vote against
a death sentence do so to hinder the process. He said some may
believe they are pro-death penalty but find they cannot follow
through once the emotions of the process sink in.

&apos;&apos;I don&apos;t think most people during jury selection truly know what
they feel about the death penalty,&apos;&apos; Craig said.



 http://www.dailyreportonline.com/Editor ... ublic_.htm dusty   Posts: 2098 Joined: Thu Apr 06, 2006 7:41 pm 
 Website 
 Top 
 Death Penalty Reinstated for Deputy&apos;s Killer 

 by dusty on Mon Feb 26, 2007 7:06 pm
 Death Penalty Reinstated for Deputy&apos;s Killer






ROBERT WAYNE HOLSEY

Provided By: The Associated Press
Last Modified: 2/26/2007 12:06:58 PM


ATLANTA (AP) -- The Georgia Supreme Court has reinstated the death penalty against a man convicted in 1995 of murdering a Baldwin County sheriff&apos;s deputy.

Robert Wayne Holsey, now 41, had been on death row for the 1995 killing of deputy William Robinson IV.

In May, Superior Court Judge Neal Dickert overturned the death sentence, citing ineffective defense counsel. The judge ruled that Holsey&apos;s defense did not go far enough in detailing his troubled family background or mental health issues before the jury.

But in a unanimous decision released Monday, the state&apos;s high court ruled that Holsey&apos;s claims regarding ineffective counsel &quot;must fail given the lack of resulting actual prejudice.&quot;

In his appeal, Holsey submitted evidence about the defendant&apos;s &quot;limited intelligence, his troubled and abusive home life, his positive contributions at home and elsewhere, and his mother&apos;s and sister&apos;s mental health issues.&quot;

Justice P. Harris Hines wrote in the decision that &quot;introduction of Holsey&apos;s new evidence at his trial would not have had an impact on the jury&apos;s sentencing deliberations sufficient to help sustain a successful ineffective assistance of counsel claim regarding the sentencing phase.&quot;

Holsey was found guilty and sentenced to death in 1997.

Robinson was killed in December 1995 while trying to arrest Holsey in connection with an armed robbery.



(Copyright 2007 by The Associated Press. All Rights Reserved.) dusty   Posts: 2098 Joined: Thu Apr 06, 2006 7:41 pm 
 Website 
 Top 
 Georgia/US: OK, scrap the Bill of Rights 

 by dusty on Thu Mar 01, 2007 9:22 am
 Georgia/US: OK, scrap the Bill of Rights
Wed Feb 28, 2007 11:57AM
84.142.237.218


February 28, 2007


OK, scrap the Bill of Rights

Politicians and public don&apos;t want it anyway

By BOB BARR, Atlanta Journal Constitution

Just last month in testimony before the Congress, Attorney General Alberto
Gonzales again dismissed the notion that habeas corpus guarantees the right
of all persons detained by the government to have access to a court to
determine if they are being held lawfully.

Gonzales reached this conclusion because he apparently discovered that the
Constitution of the United States did not &quot;expressly&quot; guarantee the right of
habeas corpus. The attorney general&apos;s distressing conclusion followed by two
months a speech by former Speaker of the House Newt Gingrich that the
guarantee of freedom of speech, enshrined in the First Amendment to the
Constitution, is at least to some extent incompatible with the need to wage
all-out war against &quot;terrorists&quot; and we should therefore consider curtailing
that particular freedom.

Then, just last week here in Georgia, during a debate under the Gold Dome
whether to allow juries in Georgia to decide application of the death
penalty with less than unanimity, a local district attorney - Danny Craig of
Augusta - argued that because &quot;70 percent of people in Georgia support the
death penalty&quot; a law that requires 100 percent agreement among juries
considering whether to apply it in a particular case is inappropriate.

I have reacted with profound disagreement to these attitudes that are
dismissive of fundamental rights and procedures reflected in and based on
our Constitution and its Bill of Rights. However, on more careful
examination, it appears that perhaps the attorney general, the former
speaker, and the district attorney are on to something here. Why shouldn&apos;t
the Bill of Rights reflect simply the popularly held views of &quot;the people&quot;?

Moreover, insofar as recent studies seem to confirm that most people don&apos;t
understand the Bill of Rights anyway, changing them to reflect such
ignorance would make the job of the government - and the courts - simpler.
In much the same way that biblical scholars have taken the King James
Version of the Bible and through successive revisions dumbed down that
magnificent tome so it is more &quot;readable,&quot; we could shorten and simplify the
Constitution.

For example, the First Amendment - which guarantees the rights to freedom of
religion, speech, the press, peaceful assembly and to petition for redess of
grievances - is so often misunderstood by government, the courts and the
people that we&apos;d probably all be better off if it were simply repealed. Few
people really understand anymore why it might be necessary to &quot;assemble&quot;
anyway, and who worries in this day and age about something as arcane as a
&quot;redress of grievances&quot;?

Then take the Second Amendment - that pesky sentence constantly getting in
the way of efforts by big city mayors in New York, Washington, San Francisco
and elsewhere to disarm the populace. Insofar as many government officials
view the clause as applicable simply to a &quot;militia&quot; - which they in turn
believe we no longer need because, after all, we have the military and the
police nowadays to &quot;protect&quot; us - wouldn&apos;t it greatly simplify their jobs to
just repeal the amendment?

Of course, there&apos;s that old Fourth Amendment, with its particularly long and
convoluted sentence having to do with &quot;searches and seizures&quot; and &quot;warrants&quot;
and &quot;probable cause.&quot; Since most people probably view the Fourth Amendment
as concerning itself only with criminals, who shouldn&apos;t have any rights
anyway, why do we really need to concern ourselves with such things? After
all, if the Fourth Amendment inhibits President Bush from ordering
electronic surveillance of whoever he wants without bothering to get a court
order, so he can protect us against terrorists, isn&apos;t the amendment a bad
thing anyway?

The list goes on and on. The Fifth Amendment, the Sixth, the Eighth, etc.
All these provisions written so very long ago (well over 200 years) contain
pledges of rights guaranteed to people charged with crimes, or in other
instances of limitations on the power of the federal government.

In this wonderful and modern 21st century, in which most people lack any
meaningful understanding of the Bill of Rights, and a time in which a
majority of the citizenry - and of our elected officials - appears willing
to let the government have just as much power as it wants, wouldn&apos;t it make
sense to just drop a few words from the Bill of Rights; make it more helpful
to government and less coddling of criminals?

We easily could trim the cumbersome, nearly 500-word document down to a more
manageable couple of dozen words: &quot;... The right of the people to be secure
in their persons, homes, papers and effects ... shall ... be ... delegated
to the United States.&quot; Much simpler. Much easier. Now back to Britney Spears
and Anna Nicole Smith.

---

Source : Atlanta Journal Constitution (Former congressman and U.S. attorney
Bob Barr practices law in Atlanta. Web site: www.bobbarr.org .)

 http://www.ajc.com/opinion/content/opin ... dbarr.html dusty   Posts: 2098 Joined: Thu Apr 06, 2006 7:41 pm 
 Website 
 Top 
 GA: Amended bill would let 11 jurors decide death penalty 

 by dusty on Fri Mar 16, 2007 10:02 am
 GA: Amended bill would let 11 jurors decide death penalty
Thu Mar 15, 2007 6:06AM
195.28.224.59


Georgia
Amended bill would let 11 jurors decide death penalty
By Jeremy Redmon | Wednesday, March 14, 2007

The Atlanta Journal-Constitution
A bill that would allow only 11 jurors — instead of all 12 — to
recommend a death sentence has moved a step closer toward a vote in
the House of Representatives.

Existing law requires a unanimous jury decision to impose a death
sentence. House Bill 185, however, would allow judges to impose the
death penalty if 11 of 12 jurors make such a recommendation.

Supporters say the bill would prevent a lone juror from sabotaging a
death penalty sentence in murder cases. Opponents argue the bill
would put death penalty decisions in the hands of elected judges who
could be swayed by politics.

As introduced by House Majority Whip Barry Fleming (R-Harlem), the
original version of the bill would have allowed nine jurors to
recommend the death penalty.

The House Non-Civil Judiciary Committee amended the bill Tuesday,
however, raising that number to 11. The panel then approved the bill
and sent it on its way to the House Rules Committee, which sets the
agenda for House floor votes.



 http://www.ajc.com/blogs/content/shared ... ll_wo.html dusty   Posts: 2098 Joined: Thu Apr 06, 2006 7:41 pm 
 Website 
 Top 
 3 charged with murder in Ga. boy&apos;s death 

 by dusty on Thu Mar 22, 2007 6:55 pm
 3 charged with murder in Ga. boy&apos;s death
Mike Barrios, right, the father of Christopher Michael Barrios, is hugged by a mourner at the visitation for his son in Brunswick, Ga., Wednesday, March 21, 2007. A steady stream of mourners visited the funeral home to pay their respects to the family of the slain 6-year-old boy who disappeared for a week before his body was found dumped near a roadside about three miles from his home. A convicted child molester and his parents were indicted Wednesday on charges they molested and then murdered Barrios. (AP Photo/The Florida Times-Union, Chris Viola)
By Russ Bynum, Associated Press Writer | March 22, 2007

SAVANNAH, Ga. --A convicted child molester and his father took turns sexually assaulting a 6-year-old boy while the molester&apos;s mother watched, then they choked the boy to death, according to an indictment issued Wednesday. The indictment charges all three family members with murder and child molestation in the slaying of young Christopher Michael Barrios, whose body was found last Thursday inside a trash bag dumped by a roadside.

Attorney Stephen D. Kelley said he will seek the death penalty against 32-year-old George David Edenfield, who has a prior child molestation conviction from 1997, and his parents, David and Peggy Edenfield.

&quot;This is one of the most horrific crimes that I have seen in 21 years of prosecutions,&quot; Kelley said.

Christopher went missing for a week before police found his body about three miles from his trailer park home outside Brunswick, a Georgia port city 60 miles south of Savannah. The suspects lived in a mobile home across the street from the boy&apos;s grandmother.

The indictment contains grim details about the case that police and prosecutors had not previously revealed. It says Christopher died from asphyxiation March 8 -- the day he was reported missing -- after the suspects choked him while &quot;ignoring his complaints that they were hurting him.&quot; The indictment does not say which of three caused the boy&apos;s death.

It also claims George Edenfield and his 58-year-old father sodomized the boy and forced him to perform oral sex while Peggy Edenfield watched and masturbated.

&quot;They deserve the worst, for them to torture my son like that, every last one of them,&quot; said Mike Barrios, the slain boy&apos;s father.

A friend of the Edenfield family, Donald Dale, was indicted on charges of concealing a death and tampering with evidence. Kelley said Dale did not become involved until after Christopher had been killed.

Nathan Williams, the attorney for 57-year-old Peggy Edenfield, declined to comment Wednesday. Attorneys for George and David Edenfield did not immediately return phone calls.

Glynn County police arrested the Edenfields four days after the child vanished while playing alone outside. Police Chief Matt Doering said all three suspects confessed to playing roles in the boy&apos;s abduction.

Police have said Dale admitted to investigators he helped the Edenfields dispose of Christopher&apos;s body.

Other charges against the Edenfields include false imprisonment, cruelty to children and enticing a child for indecent purposes.

Police have described George David Edenfield as mentally slow, but not retarded and capable of understanding right from wrong.

Ironically, the Edenfields moved into the trailer park where Christopher lived last year because of a Georgia law intended to keep child molesters away from children. Sheriffs&apos; deputies told George Edenfield in September that he had to leave his home near downtown Brunswick because it was too close to a playground. Georgia law prohibits registered sex offenders from living within 1,000 feet of schools and other places that draw children.

His family went to live in the trailer park in October after George Edenfield was arrested for failing to move as ordered. He pleaded guilty to the charge and was sentenced to probation March 5, three days before Christopher disappeared.

George Edenfield was required to register as a sex offender after he pleaded guilty in 1997 to molesting two boys, ages 7 and 9. Prosecutors said he rubbed his clothed body &quot;in a sexual manner&quot; against the boys, who also were fully dressed. He was sentenced then to 10 years on probation.

His father, David Edenfield, pleaded guilty to incest in 1994. He was accused of having sex with an adult relative who was not his son.

© Copyright 2007 Associated Press. All rights reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed.


 dusty   Posts: 2098 Joined: Thu Apr 06, 2006 7:41 pm 
 Website 
 Top 
 NATION/WORLD: Convicted child molester, man’s parents charge 

 by dusty on Thu Mar 22, 2007 6:59 pm
 NATION/WORLD: Convicted child molester, man’s parents charged with murder in 6-year-old Georgia boy’s death

A convicted child molester and his father took turns sexually assaulting a 6-year-old boy while the molester’s mother watched, then they choked the boy to death, according to an indictment issued Wednesday. The indictment charges all three family members with murder and child molestation in the slaying of young Christopher Michael Barrios, whose body was found last Thursday inside a trash bag dumped by a roadside.

District Attorney Stephen D. Kelley said he will seek the death penalty against 32-year-old George David Edenfield, who has a prior child molestation conviction from 1997, and his parents, David and Peggy Edenfield.

“This is one of the most horrific crimes that I have seen in 21 years of prosecutions,” Kelley said.

Christopher went missing for a week before police found his body about three miles from his trailer park home outside Brunswick, a Georgia port city 60 miles south of Savannah. The suspects lived in a mobile home across the street from the boy’s grandmother.

The indictment contains grim details about the case that police and prosecutors had not previously revealed. It says Christopher died from asphyxiation March 8 — the day he was reported missing — after the suspects choked him while “ignoring his complaints that they were hurting him.” The indictment does not say which of three caused the boy’s death.

—From the Associated Press dusty   Posts: 2098 Joined: Thu Apr 06, 2006 7:41 pm 
 Website 
 Top 
 GA: An Innocent Man on Death Row in Georgia? 

 by dusty on Tue Jun 05, 2007 8:03 am
 GA: An Innocent Man on Death Row in Georgia?
Mon Jun 4, 2007 6:00PM
84.142.223.106


Monday, June 4th, 2007

An Innocent Man on Death Row in Georgia? British Journalist David Rose on the Case of Carlton Gary and the &quot;Stocking Stranglings&quot;

In 1986 Gary was convicted and sentenced to death for three murders despite no physical evidence that tied him to the crimes. Last week a federal judge upheld his conviction despite new evidence that casts doubt on his conviction. David Rose examines Gary&apos;s case in his new book &quot;The Big Eddy Club: The Stocking Stranglings and Southern Justice.&quot; [includes rush transcript]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
A man who has been sitting on death row for over two decades was denied a new trial last week in a highly publicized and controversial case known as &quot;the Stocking Stranglings.&quot;
The case dates back to the late 1970s when a serial killer in Columbus, Georgia, raped and murdered several elderly white women by strangling them in their beds. In 1986, eight years after the last murder, an African American man, Carlton Gary, was convicted and sentenced to death for three of the murders. No physical evidence was ever produced to tie him to the crimes. Gary has been on death row ever since.

In 2005, a new piece of evidence that had been missing for 25, a bite-mark mold taken from the last victim, was presented. Gary&apos;s attorney argued that the mold did not match his teeth and it was evidence that pointed to his client&apos;s innocence. But last Wednesday, U.S. District Court Judge Clay Land ruled that the mold doesn&apos;t cast enough doubt on Gary&apos;s case to undermine the 1986 conviction. Carlton Gary&apos;s case now goes to the 11th circuit court of appeals in Atlanta.

Award-winning journalist David Rose has followed this case for more than ten years and has just published the book &quot;The Big Eddy Club: The Stocking Stranglings and Southern Justice.&quot; David Rose is a contributing editor at Vanity Fair and has worked for The Guardian, The Observer, and the BBC. He is the author of five previous books, including &quot;Guantanamo.&quot;

David Rose joined me in the firehouse studio last week - just two days before Judge Land&apos;s latest ruling on the bite-mark mold - to talk about the case and the significance of this piece of evidence.

David Rose, British journalist and author of the &quot;The Big Eddy Club: The Stocking Stranglings and Southern Justice.&quot;

--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
RUSH TRANSCRIPT
This transcript is available free of charge. However, donations help us provide closed captioning for the deaf and hard of hearing on our TV broadcast. Thank you for your generous contribution.
Donate - $25, $50, $100, more...

AMY GOODMAN: A man who has been sitting on death row for over two decades was denied a new trial last week in a highly publicized and controversial case known as “the Stocking Stranglings.” The case dates back to the late 1970s. A serial killer in Columbus, Georgia, raped and murdered several elderly white women by strangling them in their beds.

In 1986, eight years after the last murder, an African American man, Carlton Gary, was convicted and sentenced to death for three of the murders. No physical evidence was ever produced to tie him to the crimes. Gary has been on death row ever since.

In 2005, a new piece of evidence that had been missing for twenty years -- a bite-mark mold taken from the last victim -- was presented. Gary’s attorney argued that the mold did not match his teeth, and it was evidence that pointed to his client’s innocence. But last Wednesday, US District Court Judge Clay Land ruled the mold doesn’t cast enough doubt on Gary’s case to undermine the ’86 conviction. Carlton Gary’s case now goes to the 11th Circuit Court of Appeals in Atlanta.

Award-winning journalist David Rose has followed this case for more than ten years and just published the book, The Big Eddy Club: The Stocking Stranglings and Southern Justice. David Rose is a contributing editor at Vanity Fair and has worked for The Guardian, The Observer and the BBC. He’s the author of five previous books, including Guantanamo. David Rose joined me in the firehouse studio last week just two days before Judge Land’s latest ruling on the bite-mark mold to talk about the case and the significance of this piece of evidence.

DAVID ROSE: Right now, the case is at an absolutely critical stage. Perhaps the most important piece of evidence that I’ve dug up is a bite cast made from the killer’s teeth. The story behind this is extraordinary. At the trial, the defense attorney, Bud Siemon, who had no money, could see from the photo of one of the victims, Janet Cofer, that she had been bitten savagely by the murderer, and there was a very distinctive pattern of tooth marks on her breast. And so, he asked the judge, “Can we get an expert to compare this photo with Carlton Gary’s teeth?” because it looked like, you know, these teeth were very jumbled up. And Carlton Gary was a very good-looking guy. Unlike most serial killers, he had a number of successful relationships with women. He had even worked as a model. At the time of these murders, he was appearing five times a night on television modeling clothes. And I’ve always thought that makes him unique among alleged serial killers, that he was actually, you know -- it’s very easy to identify someone if you’ve seen him on TV. You don’t have to give a vague description to the cops. You say, “It’s that guy, the guy who’s in those commercials.”

Well, of course, nothing happened with that at the trial, but then, later, in the ’90s, the defense attorney who represented him at his state appeal, Jeff Ertel, thought he’d revisit this issue, and he went to Atlanta -- or he lived in Atlanta -- he found that in Atlanta was an expert in the field of forensic odontology called Thomas David, and he might be able to compare the photo with the bite -- with Carlton Gary’s bite. And, well, he called Dr. David, and he said, “I know about this case. Come and see me straightaway.”

And it turned out that Ricky Boren, the former chief detective of Columbus, now the chief of police; the District Attorney Bill Smith, at the time, and his assistant Doug Pullen -- both men now are superior court judges -- had come to see him before Carlton Gary’s trial with a cast that had been made by a local dentist of the killer’s teeth. And they said to him, “If this matches our suspect, you know, is this good evidence? Can you testify that this means he’s the killer?” And he said, “Yeah. That’s pretty good. If that matches, you have the right guy.” And then they said -- very strange question -- they said, “And if it doesn’t match, would you be able to testify that this doesn’t necessarily exclude him?” And he said, “No, no. If that doesn’t match him, you have the wrong man. This would exclude him.” And they said, “Just forget this meeting ever happened. Don’t tell anybody about it.”

Well, years passed, he told the defense. The defense contacted the dentist in Columbus who had made the bite. Very strangely, he told them that the cops had given it back to him. They hadn’t kept it in an exhibit store, this potentially critical piece of evidence. They had given it back to him. And he said, “Well, can I come and see it?” And the dentist, Carlos Galbreath, said, “Sure, come by next week.” Well, Jeff Ertel, the defense lawyer, and a colleague went to see the dentist. And he said, “I’m so sorry. I can’t find it. I think I destroyed it five years ago.” And that seemed to be the end of the matter.

But then, a number of years ago, about 2001, I went to see the dentist. And I said, “Dr. Galbreath, what happened with that bite cast? Why did you destroy it?” And he looked at me, and he said, “I didn’t destroy it. I know it’s still in existence.” And I said, “Well, why did you say you couldn’t find it back in the early ’90s?” And he said, “Well, you see, the district attorney at the time, Doug Pullen, he’s my best buddy. We go bird shooting every Sunday, we have done for the last thirty years.” And he showed me. He had blown the top of three of his fingers off bird shooting with Doug Pullen. And that’s why he had shut down his practice. And he said, “When the defense attorney called me, I called Doug, and I said, ‘Doug, what shall I do? This guy wants to come and see the bite cast.’” And Doug, he said, told him, “You tell him any story you want, but don’t let him see that bite cast. Tell him” -- a very strange phrase, I don’t know quite what it means -- he said, “Tell him his reputation precedes him and he can’t see the bite cast.”

Astonishingly, he repeated this in an affidavit, and this was filed with the federal court. And then this hunt began for the bite cast. And all kinds of people testified that they couldn’t find it. The dentist said he had given it to the coroner, who had in fact passed away. His family said they couldn’t find it, although they said they remembered seeing it. They said he used to take it out and show visitors and say, “These are the Stocking Strangler’s teeth.” But it was going nowhere.

And then, finally, at the end of 2005, at a point when Carlton Gary’s case had left the district court -- it was now in the 11th Circuit, he had lost the first stage of his federal appeal, it wasn’t looking good for him -- it was just a few days before he was due in the 11th Circuit Court in Atlanta for what would have been probably his last appeal, suddenly the assistant attorney general of Georgia, Susan Boleyn, who conducts death penalty appeals on behalf of the state, called Carlton Gary’s lawyers and said, “The folks in Columbus have found that bite cast.”

All last year, it was an analyzed, and Dr. David, the same expert, photographed it from every which way under a high-resolution microscope. He made a cast of Carlton Gary’s teeth. And finally, on February the 14th of this year, there was an evidentiary hearing in Columbus at which the expert testified that this bite cast excluded him to a level of reasonable scientific certainty. And we’re waiting for the judge.

And there is another aspect to this, which is just extraordinary. In my book, I’ve not just talked about the case. I’ve talked about the whole kind of history of race relations in Columbus, Georgia. And I’ve gone back to even before the Civil War and shown, I think, how that history of violence and racism and oppression has fed into this case. But there is one incredible thread that runs through it, which is the role of a single family, begins with a man called Aaron Brewster Land, who was responsible for two absolutely horrendous lynchings in the early part of the 1900s. We move to his son, John Land. John Land covers up the death of the black civil rights leader in Columbus, Thomas H. Brewer, in 1956, and he then makes the decisions in Carlton Gary’s case, by the time of which, of course, he’s become a judge. He had been the district attorney in ’56. He makes the decisions, which deny Carlton Gary funding for his trial. And now it’s his great-nephew who is the federal judge, who holds Carlton Gary’s fate in his hand. It’s Judge Clay Land of the federal court of Columbus who now has to decide whether to give him a new trial. So there’s this extraordinary continuity of more than a century, and this one family kind of represents this. And it’s down to Clay Land to decide whether to do the right thing.

AMY GOODMAN: David Rose, investigative reporter, author of The Big Eddy Club. We’ll come back to him in a minute.

[break]

AMY GOODMAN: We return to our conversation with the award-winning Vanity Fair reporter, David Rose, about his new book, The Big Eddy Club: The Stocking Stranglings and Southern Justice, about the death row case of Carlton Gary. I asked David to go back to the ’70s and lay out the story.

DAVID ROSE: Well, the Stocking Stranglings was a serial killing spree in the late 1970s in eight months in Columbus, Georgia, a very conservative city in the deep South, about a hundred miles south of Atlanta. Seven elderly, mainly rich, white women, who lived alone, were brutally raped and strangled, mostly with their own stockings, by a serial killer, whom the police seemed completely unable to apprehend. He seemed to be able to rampage through an upscale white neighborhood known as Wynnton with complete impunity. And for many years, the police had no really viable suspects, until finally in 1984 they arrested a guy called Carlton Gary, who was no poster boy. He, by his own admission, had a criminal record of some length, but he had always maintained he had never committed any violent crimes. And in 1986 he was convicted and sentenced to death, and he’s on death row now, twenty-one years later.

AMY GOODMAN: How was he picked up?

DAVID ROSE: Well, that is a very interesting and complicated process. But the cop who probably can claim to have solved the crime more than anybody else, a man called Detective Michael Sellers, looked me in the eye in a hotel in Gwinnett County, north of Atlanta, and said that his investigation began with a phone call from God.

The simple answer is there is no clear reason why they picked on him as a suspect, other than the fact that he had been involved in a crime in Albany, New York, in Upstate New York in 1970, where an elderly woman was raped and strangled, although he had always maintained that he had not committed this crime, that he had only acted as the lookout. Indeed, he wasn’t charged with this murder; another guy was.

When he came to his trial in Columbus, Georgia, the district attorney there, Bill Smith, said that in fact he had committed this murder, although he couldn’t produce any evidence that this was in fact the case. I’ve since found evidence to show that it’s quite clear that he didn’t, in the form of footprints that the killer left in the murdered woman&apos;s apartment and forensic tests that were done on those footprints by the scientists in New York in 1970. And what they showed is that the killer there had size 9.5 shoes, whereas Carlton Gary has size 13.5 or 14 shoes. He has unusually large feet. So there’s good reason to suppose that he didn’t do that murder, but belief that he had was really why Columbus Police Department made him a suspect. And then there was, as I say, this mysterious phone call from God to the detective, which put him on the scent.

AMY GOODMAN: Talk more about how they picked Carlton Gary up, what role he played in the community. And then talk about the community and the response and how the investigation went on for eight years.

DAVID ROSE: Well, Carlton Gary was born in Columbus, and he lived there ’til he was thirteen years old, and then his mother moved to Florida, and so he left the city. He had a pretty itinerant lifestyle in his late teens. He was a musician for a time. He was working in a variety of jobs in Upstate New York and other places in the sort of Northeast. And he also was committing crimes. He was, as I say, convicted of this robbery, as being an accomplice of the killer in Albany, and he went to prison for about five years for that. But he made his way back to Columbus, Georgia, in the early fall of 1977 and just before, or maybe just after, the Stocking Strangling murders began.

Now, he continued to live in Columbus for about a year after they finished. There&apos;s a myth that’s very widespread down there, which says, oh, well, the murders began when he moved back to Columbus, and they stopped when he left. In fact, that’s not true. He was living in Columbus for longer after the murders ended than the entire period of the murders.

But in 1979, in the spring of 1979, he was arrested in South Carolina trying to rob a fast-food restaurant in a rather inept fashion. He held a gun to the cashier, and she said, “I don’t believe that gun’s loaded,” which indeed it wasn’t. Then he ran out the back into a swamp and was arrested in rather deep water by the police. And I think he was worried that an alligator might be about to eat him.

So, you know, he looked like a plausible suspect. I think what probably happened is that the South Carolina authorities, when he left prison in 1984, before his arrest, told the Columbus

So, you know, he looked like a plausible suspect. I think what probably happened is that the South Carolina authorities, when he left prison in 1984, before his arrest, told the Columbus Police Department that he might be headed their way, as indeed he was. And I think what probably happened is that this detective thought, “Hmmm, look at his record. Maybe he’s the Stocking Strangler murderer.”

But what is very much the case, of course, is that these murders were the most enormous blow to the community of Columbus. They were happening in an all-white upscale neighborhood, and the police seemed completely unable to do anything to prevent them from happening. And there was really a reign of terror for the period of those killings. The area was swamped with cops, with state troopers, with soldiers from Fort Benning, the nearby military base, and, as I say, nothing seemed to be able to stop this guy from killing.

I think there’s a real possibility that the killer was actually white, because this is an all-white neighborhood. I think any African American insinuating himself into that neighborhood at night and trying to break into women’s homes would have been easily apprehended, whereas they weren’t looking for a white person. Incidentally, the reason they believed that the killer was black was because the local coroner, who actually had no training as a mortician -- sorry, he had training as a mortician, but not as a doctor, as a pathologist, any kind of forensic scientist -- but he told the cops that pubic hairs found at the crime scenes displayed what he called “Negroid characteristics,” by which he meant they were black and curly, and perhaps he had never seen a white person with black and curly pubic hair.

But in any event, the police were convinced that the killer was black. And, of course, in the deep South, especially in the 1970s, I mean, this added an enormous charge. The fact that an African American was violating vulnerable, elderly white women, the racial dimension to that gave these crimes an even greater impact.

AMY GOODMAN: Criticism of you in the Ledger-Enquirer in Columbus, the author talks about how, for a couple hundred pages, you didn’t say you were a paralegal in this case. Talk about your access to this case -- were you a paralegal? -- and your interviews with Carlton Gary.

DAVID ROSE: Well, for a long time, I got drawn into this slowly from about 1996. And as soon as I looked at this case, I thought it just stank. I had actually gone to Georgia initially to write an article for a British newspaper about the death penalty. And I went to Columbus, because Columbus had sent more people to death row than anywhere else in Georgia and indeed, per capita, may well have sent more people to death row than anywhere else in the United States.

And, you know, I had begun to find out about the case, and all kinds of things intrigued me. One of the most extraordinary things is that the defense had absolutely no money. They had no funding at all, by which to defend Carlton Gary. And, of course, this was a very complex case with all kinds of scientific evidence that has turned out to be extremely questionable. But a senior judge, the chief judge at the circuit, a guy called John Land, who had a very interesting family background, had made decisions which meant he had no funding.

And so, as I started gradually to get drawn in -- I went to visit Carlton many times; I mean, I think I’ve seen him ten times now -- I began to dig up evidence that further undermined the prosecution’s case, which -- beyond what had already come out at his state appeals. He was now in the federal court in his federal habeas corpus appeal. And I felt that if I was coming up with evidence that could exonerate this man, I had a simple moral duty to share it with the defense. It would be wrong to stack up evidence over perhaps a period of years, as indeed turned out to be the case. I was working on this for about nine years, which were then -- if I didn’t give it to the lawyers, they might miss a filing deadline. He could literally be executed on a technicality, in a sense. There could be evidence out there, which might well have got him a new trial, but he wouldn’t get one, because his lawyers had not filed it in time. So I said, “Look, I’m basically working as an investigator here. Why don&apos;t you make me officially a paralegal investigator?” And I’ve been completely transparent about this. Well, OK, I mentioned it on page 200, but that’s just where it happens in the narrative. And, you know --

AMY GOODMAN: It also gave you access to Carlton Gary.

DAVID ROSE: Well, it gave me much better access to him. It meant that when I went in to see -- I mean, you can go into death row as a friend, as a visitor, but you can’t take any notes. So, you know, I would go in and see him, and he would pour out this story, tumbling out, desperate to tell me about his life. I’d just be trying to remember it, and I’d get out into the parking lot, and I’d be scribbling notes. Once I was going in as a paralegal, I could take in documents, he could give me documents, and I could take notes. And I could do other things. On one occasion, I smuggled out his semen from death row.

AMY GOODMAN: How did you do this?

DAVID ROSE: Well, I gave him an envelope and a piece of paper and some cling wrap, and I said, “I’m going out for lunch. I’ll come back this afternoon. You produce a semen sample in your cell, and I’ll collect it later.” And then, when I did that, I gave him another envelope, and I said, “Pluck some hairs from your head in front of me, so I can then do a DNA cross match between the hairs -- the hair roots and the semen, prove it’s your semen, and then we can test the semen.”

Now, I should say, we couldn’t do a DNA test. We couldn’t just, you know, send off his semen and compare it with the crime scene samples, because the state claimed -- and indeed the former district attorney of Columbus, now a superior court judge, Doug Pullen, actually testified in his state appeal -- that the semen samples from the crime scenes had been destroyed, because they were, as he put it, a biohazard.

But what you could do was another kind of testing. In the 1970s, when these crimes happened, they did this thing called serology typing. Most people are what are called secreters. That means that in their other bodily fluids, such as semen or saliva, they excrete or secrete the blood group chemical, the antigen that defines you as blood group O, blood group A, and so forth. And it was quite clear from the tests that the killer was a non-secreter. They had tested Carlton Gary’s saliva when they arrested him, and he, equally clearly, was a blood group O secreter.

Well, the state&apos;s expert at the trial said, “Well, maybe he just changed over time, or maybe he was a secreter in his saliva but not his semen.” And, of course, the defense, which had no money at the trial, couldn’t challenge this. They couldn’t call an expert to delve into this deeper. And, in fact, you read the transcript, they’re begging the judge for funds, and he won’t give it to them. So the state was still sticking to this position in the federal court. And so, I conducted this test to see if he really was a secreter in his semen, and, of course, he was actually found to be secreting about 10,000 as much of the chemical as the killer was.

AMY GOODMAN: We’re talking to David Rose, author of The Big Eddy Club: The Stocking Stranglings and Southern Justice. David is a contributing editor at Vanity Fair and has worked at various British papers, The Guardian, The Observer, worked also with the BBC. Well, the title of your book is The Big Eddy Club. Talk about the Big Eddy Club.

DAVID ROSE: Well, the Big Eddy Club is a venerable institution for Columbus&apos;s elite. It stands in a beautiful location on the Chattahoochee River, a promontory between the main river, which is damned at that point, and a tributary, Standing Boy Creek. It was founded by a wealthy industrialist in 1920 to provide a retreat for Columbus’s richest families. And Columbus is a very wealthy place; it always has been. It’s, you know, the place where Coca-Cola was financed. It’s the home of AFLAC, the huge insurance company, of the CB&amp;T Bank, of other big corporations.

And the Big Eddy Club, until 2006, was an all-white institution. And five of the victims of these murders were either members of the club or very regular visitors, as were all the senior white officials who were involved in prosecuting and trying Carlton Gary. And so, although I’m not suggesting that the club actually has a sort of functional role in the case, it’s kind of symbolic of the way that things have been done in Columbus for a very long time. And also the fact that it has now admitted an African American member, I think, is also evidence that Columbus, like many places in the South, is now beginning to change. In fact, arguably, I think, the criminal justice system there is one of the most resilient bastions of kind of old South values. It’s most resistant to try to, well, perhaps come into the twenty-first century. But the club, you know, it’s a place where people mingle and network. And you have to wonder whether, you know, the fact that these women were members of the club and the officials who prosecuted Carlton Gary were, too, if that added yet another edge to the way that they prosecuted the case.

AMY GOODMAN: Award-winning Vanity Fair reporter David Rose, talking about the Carlton Gary case, his new book, The Big Eddy Club: The Stocking Stranglings and Southern Justice. And we’ll continue to follow that case.

To purchase an audio or video copy of this entire program, click here for our new online ordering or call 1 (888) 999-3877.

 http://www.democracynow.org/article.pl? ... 04/1334225 dusty   Posts: 2098 Joined: Thu Apr 06, 2006 7:41 pm 
 Website 
 Top 
 

 by janneke on Tue Jun 12, 2007 12:15 pm
 Judge: Wilson Can Go Free

6/11/2007 12:13:10 PM
Web Editor: Kari Webb

A judge says a man convicted of a sex crime can go free after 28 months.

Genarlow Wilson petitioned a judge in Monroe County last week for an early release. Wilson was sentenced to 10 years in prison for having sex with an underage girl. Under a so-called &quot;Romeo and Juliet&quot; statute, cases like his were changed to misdemeanors after he was sentenced.

He has some major league supporters including former President Jimmy Carter, who wrote the judge last month saying the no-parole sentence is disproportionate to the crime.

Monroe County Superior Court Judge Thomas Wilson heard arguments on both sides of the case last week and issued his ruling around 11:30 a.m. Monday.

He wrote, in part, &quot;If any case fits into the definitive limits of a miscarriage of justice, surely this case does.

&quot;If this court or any other court cannot recognize the injustice of what has occurred here, then our court system has lost sight of the goal our judicial system has always strived to accomplish: justice being served in a fair and equal manner.&quot;

His order voided Wilson&apos;s previous sentence, changed his sentence to 12 months with credit for time served and ruled that Wilson does not have to register as a sex offender.

The state is likely to appeal the ruling from Judge Wilson.

Genarlow Wilson -- who has already served more than 27 months -- is expected to remain behind bars while that appeal proceeds.

Genarlow Wilson appeared in Monroe County Superior Court last Wednesday, asking a judge to release him immediately.

According to court records, a camera recorded him and six male friends at a 2003 New Year&apos;s Eve party having sex with teenage girls.

Wilson has been in jail since February 2005 serving a mandatory 10-year sentence for aggravated child molestation.

Wilson was convicted of having oral sex with a 15-year-old. Wilson was 17 at the time.

A jury agreed that the sex was consensual, but under Georgia law the age of consent is 16. Wilson was given a mandatory 10-year sentence and forced to register as a sex offender.

Not long after he was convicted, a Romeo and Juliet statute became law in Georgia. The law says no teen prosecuted of consensual sex can receive more than a 12-month sentence.

 http://www.13wmaz.com/news/local_story. ... ryid=39780 janneke   Posts: 4267 Joined: Sun Oct 02, 2005 11:49 am Location: Netherlands Top 
 

 by janneke on Tue Jun 12, 2007 12:16 pm
 Judge: No 10-year sentence for teen sex
By SHANNON McCAFFREY Associated Press Writer
Article Launched: 06/11/2007


ATLANTA—A Georgia judge ordered the release Monday of a man sentenced to 10 years in prison for having consensual oral sex with a 15-year-old girl when he was 17.
The judge threw out Genarlow Wilson&apos;s previous sentence and amended it to misdemeanor aggravated child molestation with a 12-month sentence, plus credit for time served. Under the new ruling, he will not be required to register as a sex offender.

Wilson, now 21, has been behind bars for more than two years.

&quot;If this court or any court cannot recognize the injustice of what has occurred here, then our court system has lost sight of the goal our judicial system has always strived to accomplish ... justice being served in a fair and equal manner,&quot; wrote Judge Thomas H. Wilson, no relation to Genarlow Wilson.

The original sentence, for aggravated child molestation, was widely criticized on the grounds it was grossly disproportionate to the crime. State lawmakers later passed a law to close the loophole that led to the 10-year sentence.

&quot;The fact that Genarlow Wilson has spent two years in prison for what is now classified as a misdemeanor, and without assistance from this Court, will spend eight more years in prison, is a grave miscarriage of justice,&quot; the judge wrote.

The attorney general&apos;s office did not immediately comment.

A Georgia Department of Corrections spokeswoman said the agency cannot take any action regarding Wilson nor comment on his case until it receives
a copy of the judge&apos;s order. Wilson&apos;s lawyers said they expected to talk with prison officials in the afternoon.
Genarlow Wilson&apos;s lawyers applauded in their office and hugged his mother, who wiped away tears, as the order came over a fax machine.

&quot;We right now have an order of release and I beg the attorney general of the state of Georgia please do not file an appeal,&quot; said Wilson&apos;s lawyer, B.J. Bernstein.

Wilson&apos;s mother, Juannessa Bennett, said, &quot;I just feel like a miracle happened.&quot;

A jury found the honor student guilty in 2005 of aggravated child molestation for having oral sex with a 15-year-old girl during a 2003 New Year&apos;s Eve party involving alcohol and marijuana. Although the sex act was consensual, it was illegal under Georgia law.

Wilson was also charged with rape for being one of several male partygoers at the Douglas County hotel to have sex with a 17-year-old girl, but was acquitted. The party was captured on a videotape that was played for the jury.

Several influential people, including former President Jimmy Carter, stepped forward to support Wilson.



 http://www.mercurynews.com/news/ci_6113992 janneke   Posts: 4267 Joined: Sun Oct 02, 2005 11:49 am Location: Netherlands Top Next Display posts from previous: All posts 1 day 7 days 2 weeks 1 month 3 months 6 months 1 year Sort by Author Post time Subject Ascending Descending Post a reply 41 posts• Page 1 of 3 • 1 , 2 , 3 


 Return to News - 2007 
 Jump to: Select a forum ------------------ Main General Forum   Messages from / to Admin   Florida Support   Visit death row and stay here   Florida Support Newsletter   Order domains/hosting here   News - 2007   News - 2006   News-archieve - before 2006   USSC news   Florida - In Remembrance   Florida News   Florida Justice System   Florida Death Row Defense   Florida Judges   Florida DOC problems   Florida - Warrant   Florida Sex Offenders   Florida Juveniles on Death Row   Florida Deathrow conditions   Texas News   Texas death row   The Governor Election 2006   General Anti Death Penalty Discussion   General Anti Death Penalty News   Death Penalty Defense in US   Vienna Convention - Foreign Nationals   Guantanamo   Lethal Injection   The Electric Chair   Actions   Campaigns   Petitions   Scheduled Executions in US   Human lives killed   Moratorium   Mitigation   Mental retardation   Mental illness and DP   Insanity   DNA issues   Juveniles   Kids in Court - Cases   Torture   Sex offenders and Death Penalty   Jessica&apos;s Law   Wrongful convictions   Volunteers   Prison Issues   Reports   Cases   The Frank Valdes case   Terri Schiavo   George Ryan For The Nobel Peace Prize   The American Persecution of George Ryan   Sid Kleiner - exchange   Art from our friends   Inmate support   Various Articles   Interesting&amp;Useful Weblinks   Literature   Media lists   Legal Files 
 Who is online 

Users browsing this forum: No registered users and 1 guest
 
 Board index The team • Delete all board cookies •All times are UTC 
 Powered by phpBB ©2000, 2002, 2005, 2007 phpBB Group
	</body>
</document>
