<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002356" url="http://dietcalc.com/" time="2012-07-12-18:16" support="4" score="0.018815259284518354" bingtitle="DIETCALC - Diet Plan Organizer" webtitle="DIETCALC  - Diet Plan Organizer">
			<query id="000124" bing-rank="160"/>
			<query id="000907" bing-rank="245"/>
			<query id="000624" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000613" bing-rank="176"/>
	<description>... comes with over 2,000 common and popular fast food restaurant ... To place an order now, please press the &quot;Buy Now&quot; button ... DIET CALCULATOR - CARB COUNTER - CALORIE COUNTER</description>
	<body>
		DIETCALC - Our newest Diet Plan Organizer (Dietcalc Professional) with expanded memory and
more functions to set, track and monitor daily nutritional goals, weight and
BMI.

Dietcalc comes with over 2,000 common food items and popular fast
restaurant foods stored in its permanent database. Nutritional food information
can now be easily looked up and displayed and more new foods can be added.

All 9 nutrient goals set are now automatically compared against the
food item displayed and Dietcalc will flash to alert you if any food item in
the portion size entered, exceeds your own personal established daily nutritional
goal.

Dietcalc records and tracks daily food nutrition, weight
and calculates BMI. This measurable data can be recalled at anytime and used to
adjust your diet to achieve the desired result. 
 
 Dietcalc Pro is the new top-of-the line diet plan organizer that tracks nine (9) of the most important nutrients in diet.
Dietcalc provides clear understandable nutrient data needed to make smart eating
decision and is a great motivation tool that is 100% compatible with all popular
diet plans.

Dietcalc now comes with over 2,000 common and popular
fast food restaurant items stored in its food database. Additionally, you are
now able to add your own favorite food items into the database and also edit
or delete them at any time.

Dietcalc&apos;s &quot;FIND&quot; button allows you quickly
lookup any food item, adjust the portion size and see real measurable nutrient
data that is instantly compared to the 9 nutrient goals established: Calories, Carbs, Total Fat, Saturated Fat, Sugar, Sodium, Protein, Cholesterol and
Fiber . 

 Dietcalc can save the displayed nutritional data of all the foods eaten into its
90 day revolving memory, so that this real measurable data is available to be recalled
and compared to the daily nutrient goals, weight and BMI. With this recorded information it is easy see if the diet is producing the desired
result or if the nutrient goals should be adjusted. 

Dietcalc&apos;s
new &quot;BMI&quot; key allows the user to record and track their daily weight in pounds
or kilos and calculates BMI. With this new function you only need to enter
your weight once a day and Dietcalc will automatically calculate (BMI). This function
key also allows you to scroll back 90 days (one day at a time) to review
or edit weight and BMI.

Dietcalc Pro is known for its ease-of-use with all function keys clearly marked. Many users have stated that they never looked
at the operating manual and are already entering their goals and following
the diet plan of their choice in only 5 - 10 minutes.

For more detailed
information you can contact us directly at orderdesk@dietcalc.com or your nearest Dietcalc dealer. 

 To place an order now, please press the &quot;Buy Now&quot; button under the Dietcalc picture and we will immediately process your order on our
secure web site. Please allow 7 days for normal delivery from our warehouse
in the U.S.A. or Asia. 
 
 TOTAL FAT - SAT. FAT - CARBS - CALORIES - SUGAR - SODIUM - PROTEIN - CHOLESTEROL
- FIBER 
 
 DIETCALC DIET CALCULATOR - FOR ALL DIET PLANS CALORIE COUNTER - CARB CALCULATOR  
 
 THE DIET PLAN ORGANIZER FOR ALL DIETS - DIET CALCULATOR - CARB COUNTER - CALORIE
COUNTER 
 
 Dietcalc Health Care Products 
 
 Email 
 
 More Info 
 
 Contact 
 
 Affiliates 
 
 
 
 About Us 
 
 
 
 Denron Int&apos;l Ltd. - The Marketing Team
	</body>
</document>
