<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002697" url="http://www.menupages.com/restaurants/5-napkin-burger/" time="2012-07-12-18:45" support="11" score="0.03836823927190495" bingtitle="5 Napkin Burger - New York Restaurant - MenuPages Burgers ..." webtitle="5 Napkin Burger - New York Restaurant - MenuPages Burgers, American (Traditional), Sushi Restaurant Search">
			<query id="000155" bing-rank="2"/>
			<query id="000133" bing-rank="4"/>
			<query id="000956" bing-rank="215"/>
			<query id="001427" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000248" bing-rank="163"/>
			<query id="000968" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="000142" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000154" bing-rank="1"/>
			<query id="000144" bing-rank="3"/>
			<query id="001439" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000675" bing-rank="32"/>
	<description>Despite it being a hot spot in midtown, 5 Napkin Burger is a disappointment. ... Movies near 5 Napkin Burger</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to MenuPages - Please Select a city:

 New York City San Francisco Los Angeles Philadelphia Boston Chicago Washington, DC South Florida 
 New Menupages Desintations London   Paris 
 hide 
 
 Home Blog My MenuPages Restaurateurs Submit a Menu Change City Food Delivery Login 
 
 MenuPages 

Now Serving: 11173 Menus for New York City Restaurants
 
 Search Advanced Find-A-Food 
 
 Areas Neighborhood All Areas Brooklyn East Village/ LES Midtown East Midtown South / Chelsea Midtown West Murray Hill / Gramercy Soho/Trbca/FinDist Upper East Side Upper West Side Uptown Village/ W Village All Neighborhoods Bath Beach Bay Ridge Bedford-Stuyvesant Bensonhurst Borough Park Brighton Beach / Manhattan Beach Brooklyn Hts / DUMBO Brownsville Bushwick Canarsie Central Village / Noho Chelsea / Midtown South Chinatown / Two Bridges Cobble Hill / Carroll Grdns Coney Island Crown Heights Ditmas Park Dyker Heights East 30&apos;s East 40&apos;s East 50&apos;s East 60&apos;s East 70&apos;s East 80&apos;s East 90&apos;s East Harlem East New York East Village Financial District Flatbush Flatiron / Union Square Flatlands Fort Hamilton Ft. Greene / Clinton Hill Gramercy / Kips Bay Gravesend Harlem Kings Highway / Homecrest Lefferts Gardens Lower East Side Marine Park / Gerritsen Beach Midwood Mill Basin / Bergen Beach Morningside Heights Park Slope / Prospect Hts Prospect Park South / Kensington Sheepshead Bay Soho / Little Italy Sunset Park Tribeca Washington Hts / Inwood West 30&apos;s West 40&apos;s West 50&apos;s West 60&apos;s West 70&apos;s West 80&apos;s West 90&apos;s&amp;100&apos;s West Village Williamsburg / Greenpoint Cuisines All Cusines Afghan African American (New) American (Traditional) Argentinean Asian (other) Asian Fusion Australian Austrian Bagels Bakeries Bar Food Barbecue Belgian Bistro Brazilian British (Modern) British (Traditional) Burgers Burmese Cafes&amp;Coffeehouses Cajun&amp;Creole Californian Caribbean Central American Central Asian Cheesesteaks Chicken Chinese Cocktails Crepes Cuban Delis Desserts Dim Sum Diners&amp;Coffee Shops Dutch Eastern European Eclectic&amp;International Ethiopian Filipino Fish&amp;Chips French Gastropub German Greek Haitian Hawaiian Health Food Hot Dogs Indian Indonesian Irish Italian Jamaican Japanese Korean Kosher Latin American Local/Organic Malaysian Mediterranean Mexican Middle Eastern Moroccan New England Noodle Shops Nuevo Latino Other Pakistani Persian Peruvian Pizza Polish Portuguese Puerto Rican/Dominican Russian Salads Sandwiches Scandinavian Seafood Small Plates/Tapas Smoothies/Juice Bar Soups South American Southern&amp;Soul Southwestern Spanish Sri Lankan Steakhouses Sushi Swiss Teahouses Thai Tibetan Turkish Vegan Vegetarian-Friendly Venezuelan Vietnamese Wild Game Wine Bar Wings Street Zip code Cross street Restaurant name 
 
Hold down Control (PC) or Command (Mac) key + mouseclick to select more than one option
 
 
5 Napkin Burger
 + SHARE 


 $$$ 
 Rating Avg. Dinner Entrée $$$$$ Greater than $25 $$$$ $18.01 - $25 $$$ $12.01 - $18 $$ $7.01 - $12 $ Less than $7 
 Burgers, American (Traditional), Sushi 630 9th Ave , New York   NY 10036 40.760022 -73.991308 (Btwn 44th&amp;45th St) Subway Directions 
 
 Make a Reservation Online» 
 
 
 
 Phone: (212) 757-2277 
 
 Profile&amp;Reviews Menu http://www.menupages.com/restaurants/5-napkin-burger/menu Report Errors Add to
My MenuPages Email 
 Facebook Twitter + MORE 
 
 
 Reviews + Photos from nymag.com
 
User Ratings (Based on 83 reviews) 
 3.30 5 
 Food 3.6 Value 2.9 Service 3.3 Atmosphere 3.4 
 
 Rate and Review this restaurant 
 
Other Restaurant Info
 Phone: work (212) 757-2277 Website: www.5napkinburger.com Notes: Take Out Visa, MC, AmEx Hours: Lunch Mon-Fri: 11:30am-4pm Dinner Daily: 4pm-12am Brunch Sat-Sun: 11am-4pm Serves: Lunch,
 
 Dinner,
 
 Brunch Features: Outdoor Dining,
 
 Bar Scene,
 
 Online Reservations,
 
 Accepts Credit Cards,
 
 Take Out 
User Reviews
 
 5 Napkin Burger 
 Posted by Cindi on 06/22/2012 
 
We loved it!
 
Enjoyed 5 Napkin Burger very much! Food and service was great! Will go back again next time we&apos;re in the city!
 5 Napkin Burger 
 Posted by Anonymous on 05/13/2012 
 
Excellent
 
The perfect $15 burger. That is to say: NOT some high-end&quot;reinterpretation&quot;calculated to allow foodies to indulge in the humble hamburger guilt-free by larding it with fancy (and pricy) gourmet frills. And NOT your neighborhood greasy-spoon&apos;s fast, cheap and reliably mediocre $6 special. This is simply the classic burger, done in five or six varieties (beef, turkey, veggie, etc.), generously proportioned (10oz.) and executed exceptionally well. Fresh high-quality ingredients are flawlessly prepared, juicy, delicious, and matched with equally mouth-watering sides and desserts (and a daunting bar selection). One could wish the prices were a few dollars lower -- but my waistline is thankful that they&apos;re not, or I&apos;d be eating there far too often. As it is, I&apos;ve visited 5NB perhaps half a dozen times in as many months, and never left feeling less than deliriously satisfied.
 5 Napkin Burger 
 Posted by Anonymous on 11/27/2011 
 
Won&apos;t Need 5 Napkins
 
I did not eat at this location, but the one in Astoria. This was a big disappointment. If you are on the search for the best burger, you wont find it here. I don&apos;t love thick burgers because they almost always are overcooked (if you&apos;re not ordering rare). At this place, the burgers are big with only one piece of cheese --- seriously? There was truly nothing special about the burger or fries, btw, the fries are an additional fee. You will find a way better burger at your local diner.
 5 Napkin Burger 
 Posted by Anonymous on 07/16/2011 
 
Overpriced, crowded, soggy fries
 
Despite it being a hot spot in midtown, 5 Napkin Burger is a disappointment. The atmosphere is extraordinarily loud, the crowds are out of control, you&apos;ll have a long wait, and the fries are ALWAYS soggy and greasy, the burgers are too big to enjoy. I&apos;ve never had a good meal there. Overrated and overhyped.
 5 Napkin Burger 
 Posted by dpayne on 07/02/2011 
 
Great burgers
 
Very good burger, juicy (let&apos;s face it a burger without grease is pretty boring), wish i had ordered the rings,had fried dill pickle appetizer and with burger there would have been no room for the rings. I will go there again, for sure.
 5 Napkin Burger 
 Posted by Fabiana on 06/01/2011 
 
Nice late dinner
 
We had some late dinner there and it was very nice. Good food and place. Recomend it
 5 Napkin Burger 
 Posted by Barbara624 on 05/30/2011 
 
Great burgers, great service!
 
This is a great, go-to place for pre-theater, but we went on Memorial Day Monday, and we had a great meal. Portions are huge, so appetizers aren&apos;t exactly a great idea, but my brother wanted to try the artichoke dip, and it was excellent, served with both crostini and endive for dipping. I had the bacon cheddar burger, just as well done as I like it; my brother had his burger rare, and both came at the same time and were perfect. Good French Fries, amazing onion rings. Too full for dessert. Highly recommended.
 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 › » 
 
 Rate and Review this restaurant 
 
Advertising
 
Movies near 5 Napkin Burger
 Regal E-Walk Stadium 13&amp;RPX 
247 W. 42nd St.

New York
 The Amazing Spider-Man 3D  (PG-13) The Amazing Spider-Man  (PG-13) Brave  (PG) Brave 3D  (PG) Seeking a Friend for the End of the World  (R) Rock of Ages  (PG-13) Show More [+] More Nearby theaters» 
 Ticketing provided by
 
Hot and Fresh Restaurant News Delivered Weekly
 You are signing up to receive: Weekly updates delivered straight to your inbox covering the latest restaurant news, menus, openings, closings, and food events Menupages NYC Newsletter You may also be interested in: Hear about special offers from MenuPages or its partners about future events, promotions and features. Offers&amp;Promotions Sign Up 
Thanks for subscribing!

You will soon begin to receive the newsletters you selected.

To enjoy more benefits and personalization available on MenuPages.com, register now! 
 Checkbox is required 
Advertising
 
 About Us Careers Contact Us Advertise With Us Restaurateurs Privacy Policy Legal Notices Copyright Notice 

©2002-2012 Slick City Media, Inc. All Rights Reserved. MenuPages®is a trademark of Slick City Media, Inc. Disclaimer
	</body>
</document>
