<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002672" url="http://gfd123.deviantart.com/" time="2012-07-12-18:44" support="1" score="0.0011152501856405877" bingtitle="gfd123 on deviantART" webtitle="gfd123 on deviantART">
			<query id="001147" bing-rank="212"/>
	<description>Cup 1/2 empty or 1/2 full? 1/2 full 15. Where ... Favorite fast food restaurant? dont go to them 37. ... Which store would you choose to max out your credit card?</description>
	<body>
		deviantART 
 Browse Art Prints Shop T-Shirts&amp;Gear Groups Deviants 
 Sta.sh dA muro Chat Journals Today Forum Find More Art 
 Daily Deviations Discover beta Critiques Critiqueable Wallpaper Random 
 Random Deviant Random Deviation Random Group 
 
 Search Username or Email 

 Password 
 Stay logged in 
 Login 
 Join deviantART for FREE Take the Tour Lost Password? Deviant Login Buy Art Buy T-Shirts&amp;Gear Buy adCast Buy Premium Upgrade Shop   Join deviantART for FREE Take the Tour 
 
~ gfd123 
?????? + Watch Send a Note Give 
 Profile Gallery Prints Favourites Journal 
 About Me Deviant Member unknown United Kingdom Recent Activity Deviant for 3 Years Needs Premium Membership Statistics 3 Deviations 16 Comments 491 Pageviews 3 Deviations
 16 Comments
 491 Pageviews
 0 Scraps
 2 Watchers
 0 Critiques
 0 Forum Posts
 2 Favourites More Stats This deviant&apos;s full pageview
graph is unavailable. Member I am a Deviant of Many Talents unknown United Kingdom Why I Am Here - To find other furries - To herd llamas - To become a better artist Last Visit: 123 weeks ago ?????? Art Zone Personal Zone Misc. Zone 
 This is the place where you can personalize your profile!
But, how? 
 By moving, adding and personalizing widgets. You can drag and drop to rearrange. You can edit widgets to customize them. The bottom has widgets you can add! Some widgets you can only access when you get a premium membership. Some widgets have options that are only available when you get a premium membership. 
 

 We&apos;ve split the page into zones! 
 Certain widgets can only be added to certain zones. &quot;Why,&quot; you ask? Because we want profile pages to have freedom of customization, but also to have some consistency. This way, when anyone visits a deviant, they know they can always find the art in the top left, and personal info in the top right. Don&apos;t forget, restraints can bring out the creativity in you! 
 

 Now go forth and astound us all with your devious profiles! 
 OK 
 
 
 Join Now  
 Buy T-Shirts&amp;Gear  
 Advertise Here 
 [x] 
 Newest Deviations
 Fursten Dragon by ~ gfd123 3 Comments more biscuit by ~ gfd123 6 Comments bourbon by ~ gfd123 5 Comments Browse Gallery 
 Watchers
 
 ~ iWillAlwaysWatchYou ~ thehotfuzz 
 
 Devious Journal Entry 

 

 Sep 4, 2009, 3:06:18 AM by ~ gfd123 Journals / Personal 
 1. What time did you get up this morning?
Oh about 10ish

2. How do you like your steak?
Rare

3. What was the last film you saw at the cinema?
New Harry Potter

4. What is your favorite TV show?
No Idea

5. If you could live anywhere in the world where would it be?
Spain

6. What did you have for breakfast?
Havent had it yet.

7. What is your favorite cuisine?
Chinese.

8. What foods do you dislike?
Mushrooms

9. Favorite Place to Eat?
Home

10. Favorite dressing?
I don&apos;t usually have any...

11.What kind of vehicle do you drive?
Im only 14

12. What are your favorite clothes?
Jeans and T shirt

13. Where would you visit if you had the chance?
????

14. Cup 1/2 empty or 1/2 full?
1/2 full

15. Where would you want to retire?
At Work then go home and relax

16. Favorite time of day?
Night

17. Where were you born?
Hospital

18. What is your favorite sport to watch?
Football

19. Who do you think will not tag you back?
No one havent tagged anybody XD

20. Person you expect to tag you back first?
Read the last question dipshit

21. Who are you most curious about their responses to this?
Dont care

22. Bird watcher?
Hell no

23. Are you a morning person or a night person?
Night.

24. Do you have any pets?
no

25. Any new and exciting news you&apos;d like to share?
No

26. What did you want to be when you were little?
A motorbike racer XD

27. What is your best childhood memory?
...

28. Are you a cat or dog person?
Cat

29. Are you happy?
Always

30. Always wear your seat belt?
On journeys over a mile

31. Been in a car accident?
No

32. Any pet peeves?
Huh?

33. Favorite Pizza Toppings?
pepperoni

34. Favorite Flower?
dont have one

35. Favorite ice cream?
Mint choc chip

36. Favorite fast food restaurant?
dont go to them

37. How many times did you fail your driver&apos;s test?
read qu 11

38. From whom did you get your last email?
My Canadian cousin  (who I frickin hate)

39. Which store would you choose to max out your credit card?
HMV

40. Did you do anything spontaneous lately?
no

41. Like your job?
no

42. Broccoli?
Where!?

43. What was your favorite vacation?
Turkey

44. Last person you went out to dinner with?
Parents

45. What are you listening to right now?
Broken beat and Scarred - Metallica

46. What is your favorite colour?
Black

48. How many are you tagging for this quiz?
read qu 19

49. What time did you finish this quiz?
I haven&apos;t finished it yet XD

50. Coffee Drinker?
sometimes

51. What&apos;s your favorite movie?
Too many

52. Do you have any hobbies?
Golf, Tennis(table + normal)&amp;failing at guitar

53. What do you do to relax?
sleep

54. What do you like to do for fun?
sport 2 Comments 
 Mood: Humor Listening to: Broken beat and Scarred - Metallica (qu45) Reading: nowt Watching: myself type this message (obviously!) Playing: fable2 Eating: rasin biscuits Drinking: cuppa T 
 Devious Journal Entry September 4, 2009 2 Comments No Favourites More Journal Entries 
 deviantID
 
 [link] 
 [link] 
 [link] 
 
 Devious Info
 
 Current Residence: Horbury Interests: sport, art etc Favourite band or musician: Not sure Favourite genre of music: heavy rock, metal MP3 player of choice: sony walkman (phone) Skin of choice: Brick (it hurts more when I punch someone XD) Favourite game: too many Personal Quote: (point and laugh) hah thats a funny mask! ...oh wait Tools of the Trade: a large shotgun 
 
 AdCast - Ads from the Community
 [x] 
 Friends
 
~ thehotfuzz 
 Comments
 
 Add a Comment:   Preview   Add Comment Emoticons Load All Images ~ thehotfuzz May 16, 2009 you&apos;ve been tagged again Ben! I think you&apos;ll like this one.

--
&quot;What&apos;s the matter? You never seen a convexity dragon before?&quot;

Icon made by ~ BlackSolstice Reply ~ thehotfuzz May 6, 2009 Congratulations! You&apos;ve been tagged! Now go do it before I get bitey 

--
&quot;What&apos;s the matter? You never seen a convexity dragon before?&quot;

Icon made by ~ BlackSolstice Reply ! YuudaiYuuta May 4, 2009 I would seriously recommend Frank Zappa and the Mothers of Invention. I would VERY seriously recommend it.

--
&quot;A composer is a guy who goes around forcing his will on unsuspecting air molecules, often with the assistance of unsuspecting musicians.&quot; - Frank Zappa (1940 - 1993) Reply ~ thehotfuzz May 4, 2009 Hey Ben ^^

--
&quot;What&apos;s the matter? You never seen a convexity dragon before?&quot;

Icon made by ~ BlackSolstice Reply ~ gfd123 May 5, 2009 heyz

--
 [link] 
 [link] 
 [link] 
 [link] Reply ~ darkdragon5 Apr 30, 2009 thanks for the watch

--
please check out my gallary [link] Reply 
 Previous Next 
 Add a Comment:   Preview   Add Comment Emoticons ©2012 deviantART. All rights reserved About Us | Contact Us | Developers | Careers | Site Tour | Help&amp;FAQ Advertise | Premium Membership Etiquette | Privacy Policy | Terms of Service | Copyright Policy
	</body>
</document>
