<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002027" url="http://occupythedrivethru.blogspot.com/" time="2012-07-12-17:56" support="1" score="0.001344791130769968" bingtitle="Occupy the Drive-Thru" webtitle="Occupy the Drive-Thru">
			<query id="000690" bing-rank="189"/>
	<description>I had some girlfriends heading to the park right ... Never did I think about chemicals in my food or how ... Well, today is the final day of dining at a fast-food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Science
 
 Home About Us The Guidelines Healthy Alternatives! 
 
 Wednesday, February 15, 2012 
 
 Treating Yourself 
 At work I listen to a lot of podcasts. One of my favorites is the Jillian Michaels Podcast. She gives listeners a lot of great tips ranging from fitness, nutrition and overall emotional health. One tip I thought I would share with you all is about rewarding yourself. Jillian talked about how she hears a ton of people tell her that they like to reward themselves with food. She does not recommend this because most people use junk food as their treat. Instead of rewarding with junk, she advises that you put the money you would spend and put it towards a fund for yourself. This fund should be used on something that will help make you feel good about yourself. This could include a mani/pedi, a book, going to a movie or a new pair of earrings. This way we can feel rewarded for staying on track with whatever our goals are, fitness and health or otherwise, without harming our body and in turn feeling badly about it. 
 
 Try this out and let me know how it works for you! Instead of buying a burger, you could that money into a vacation fund. I think I will start saving for Disneyland! Posted by Brynn at 9:58 AM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: Jillian Michaels , money , podcasts , Rewarding 
 Good News for Pigs 
 While I am against McDonald&apos;s because of their unhealthy food and unethical ways of obtaining meat, I can now rejoice as the company has done something honorable. McDonald&apos;s has teamed up the the Humane Society and is now making their pig suppliers stop using crates to hold pregnant sows. These crates have traditionally kept pigs away from each other so they can&apos;t fight over food, but many activists say this is unnecessary and finally McDonald&apos;s agrees. While I still won&apos;t be eating McDonald&apos;s anytime soon, I can sleep easy knowing they are starting to realize that unethical meat producing is simply unnecessary and disgusting. I hope they continue on to reform the way they raise their cows and chickens. Also, let&apos;s encourage other fast food chains to follow the example of McDonald&apos;s. 
 Remember that no matter what you eat, try to find out where that food is coming from and how it is produced. This matters greatly to your health and the health of the environment. Most fast food chains sell food that has been obtained in very unethical, unsustainable ways. This is one of the big reasons why I have chosen not to eat fast food. You can make a difference by voting with your dollars, so choose ethical meats! 
 Aricle from NPR: http://www.npr.org/blogs/thesalt/2012/02/14/146863301/mcdonalds-teams-up-with-humane-society-to-phase-out-pig-crates Posted by Brynn at 12:22 AM No comments: Email This BlogThis! Share to Twitter Share to Facebook Labels: fast food , McDonald&apos;s , meat , pigs , sustainability , unethical 
 Saturday, January 28, 2012 
 
 Not all oatmeals are created equal 
 I just saw this on Twitter. Pretty gross! Just because it&apos;s a healthy food, doesn&apos;t mean it&apos;s healthy at a fast food place. Makes me rethink that salad I had last week...
	</body>
</document>
