<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002653" url="http://chicago.cbslocal.com/2011/01/01/amtrak-train-strikes-car-killing-woman/" time="2012-07-12-18:43" support="3" score="0.0029372272721251867" bingtitle="Amtrak Train Strikes Car, Killing Woman « CBS Chicago" webtitle="Amtrak Train Strikes Car, Killing WomanCBS Chicago">
			<query id="000699" bing-rank="60"/>
			<query id="000239" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="000713" bing-rank="79"/>
	<description>... Robinson died Thursday night when the car ... Peppers Chicago Bears #90 Replica Name &amp; Number ... Robertson, was driving her to work at a fast-food restaurant in Calumet Park ...</description>
	<body>
		85° Buy Tickets Order Food More Channels Buy Tickets Order Food Your Home Contests Mobile Alerts Email Alerts 
 Daily Deals 49% off at Breath Appeal Buy Team Gear Nike Brian Urlacher Chicago Bears Women&apos;s Game Jersey - Navy Blue Events Pitbull 
 Facebook Twitter Follow Us 
 Home News Sports Health Audio Video Best Of Events Traffic Weather Places Deals Autos 
 
 Local Investigative Politics Business Consumer Entertainment Health National World Photos 
 
 
 
Local
 
Amtrak Train Strikes Car, Killing Woman

January 1, 2011 8:47 AM
 Share this View Comments More Activity Facebook Activity What&apos;s this? Add to Timeline - What&apos;s This Click &quot;Add to Timeline&quot; to publish
what you read to Facebook See what your friends have read
on CBS Local sites Use &quot;Remove&quot; or &quot;Turn off&quot; to
disable at any time 
Photo Of Amtrak Rail Car. (Scott Olson/Getty Images)
 
Filed under
 Local , News 
Related tags
 Amtrak train , Patrice Robinson , Railroad Crossing Gates , Train Strikes Car 
 CHICAGO (STMW) - Patrice Robinson died Thursday night when the car she was riding in allegedly went around railroad crossing gates and was struck by a New York City-bound Amtrak train. 

The 20-year old’s father, Terry Robertson, was driving her to work at a fast-food restaurant in Calumet Park when authorities say the vehicle went around the gates at 97th Street and South Eggleston Avenue at 6:55 p.m. 
Robertson, an auto mechanic, was in stable condition with broken ribs at Christ Medical Center in Oak Lawn, family members said. No charges had been filed in the crash on Friday, police said.

Robinson was a single mother of a 1-year-old son, and she recently had enrolled in a nursing program at Olive Harvey College in Chicago, her grandmother Patrice Emery said.

“Patrice was a very sweet girl, full of life,” Emery said. “She graduated high school and was enrolled in a nursing program and had started working at Wendy’s to make extra money for Christmas. She was trying to get her life on track. She was a beautiful, bubbly girl.”

Amtrak Train No. 50 bound for New York had 245 passengers and departed Union Station at 5:58 p.m, Amtrak spokeswoman Christina Leeds said. The train remained on the scene for two hours after the crash.

© Sun-Times Media Wire Chicago Sun-Times 2010. All Rights Reserved. This material may not be published, broadcast, rewritten, or redistributed. Share this View Comments More Activity Facebook Activity What&apos;s this? Add to Timeline - What&apos;s This Click &quot;Add to Timeline&quot; to publish
what you read to Facebook See what your friends have read
on CBS Local sites Use &quot;Remove&quot; or &quot;Turn off&quot; to
disable at any time 
 http://wp.lv369.com/index.php/archives/720 Amtrak Train Strikes Car, Killing Woman | Lv369&apos;s News For China&amp;US 
[...] more on CBS Chicago This entry was posted in Something For Cars.«Sanchez’Series heroics tops list [...]
 http://wp.lv369.com/index.php/archives/885 Car chase ends with arrest | Lv369&apos;s News For China&amp;US 
[...] more on CBS Chicago Car chase ends with arrest BRISTOL TOWNSHIP–What started as a police chase involving a [...]
 
 blog comments powered by Disqus Listen Live! 
Follow CBS Chicago
 Follow @CBSChicago 
 Most Popular News 

 5 Teens Among 8 Wounded By Gunfire In Another Violent Night It was another night of violence across Chicago, with five teenagers among the wounded in eight separate shootings. 5684 Fiery Crash Shuts Down Multiple Lanes Of Northbound Route 53 A fiery crash shut down multiple lanes of Route 53 in the Schaumburg corridor early Thursday. 137 West Nile Mosquitos Could Be Big Problem This Year Experts have warned 2012 could be a bad year for West Nile -- and it is. 272 Man Tries To Sexually Assault Two Women At Knifepoint Police are looking for a man who tried to sexually assault two women at knifepoint at their West Side homes. 201 Key Witness Admits He Lied; Testimony Sent Man To Jail In 2006 A prosecution witness who helped put a Chicago man in prison is now saying his testimony was a lie--all because the man embarrassed him. 340 
 
 Contests&amp;Promotions 

 Win 4 Tickets To Blue Man Group July 9, 2012 Listen to WBBM Friday, July 13 in the 4 o’clock half hour for the contest keyword to be announced and get ready to text 780-780. Your chance to score 4 tickets to experience Blue Man Group from the Poncho Seating area at Briar Street Theatre! Summer Barbecue Giveaway July 9, 2012 Summer is finally heating up and what better way to celebrate than a Summer BBQ? By entering to win (up to once daily), you may be the lucky winner of a brand new grill with BBQ tool set, a $150 gift certificate for Omaha Steaks, and 2 CBS Local aprons - a prize worth over $500! Def Leppard/Poison Ticket Giveaway July 9, 2012 Enter for your chance to win a pair of tickets to the Rock of Ages Tour, featuring Def Leppard and Poison. Blue Harbor Spa Getaway July 7, 2012 Register for a chance to win a one (1) night stay in one (1) Family or King Suite, and enjoy a massage for two (2) at Blue Harbor Resort and Spa. Two (2) winners will be selected at random from all the eligible entries. 
 More Contests&amp;Promotions… 
 Pregnant Celebs: Who’s Knocked Up? 
 
 Best Celebrity DUI Mugshots 
 
 Newly Single Celebs 
 
 Get Cookin’! 
 
 News 
 Local Neighborhood Investigative Politics Consumer Entertainment Health National World Business Photos 
 Home 
 Contests&amp;Promotions Events&amp;Appearances TV Shows&amp;Listings Deals Directory Weather Traffic Fan Shop 
 Sports 
 Bears White Sox Cubs Blackhawks Bulls Fire DePaul Illinois Notre Dame Northwestern Podcasts Blogs 
 Scores&amp;Stats 
 NFL Football MLB Baseball NBA Basketball NHL Hockey College Football College Basketball Tennis Golf 
 Watch + Listen 
 Seen on CBS 2 Heard on WBBM 780 Heard on 670 The Score Video on Demand Audio on Demand Podcasts Music 
 Contact Us 
 CBS 2 WBBM Newsradio 780&amp;105.9FM 670 The Score 
 Corporate 
 About Us Advertise Business Development Contact Mobile Connect 
 
 
Chicago Business Listings

 Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Shopping Professional Services Search Listings 
 
 Privacy Policy Terms of Use Advertise With Us Contest&amp;Promotion Rules EEO Reports Deals 
 Powered by WordPress.com VIP Facebook Twitter RSS 
 ©2012 CBS Local Media, a division of CBS Radio Inc. All rights reserved. 
 Buy Tickets Order Food More Channels Buy Tickets Order Food Your Home Contests Mobile Alerts Email Alerts 
 Daily Deals 49% off at Breath Appeal Buy Team Gear Nike Brian Urlacher Chicago Bears Women&apos;s Game Jersey - Navy Blue Events Pitbull 
 Follow Us Facebook Twitter 
Select a Live Stream
 
News, Sports and Talk Radio
 
 Click to listen to WBBM Newsradio 780&amp; 105.9FM Click to listen to 670 The Score 
 
Music Radio
 
 Click to listen to WBBM-FM Click to listen to WJMK-FM Click to listen to WUSN-FM Click to listen to WXRT-FM 
 
 Click to listen to Last.fm Click to listen to radio.com Click to listen to MP3.com
	</body>
</document>
