<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0002149" url="http://insidethemindoftobyeddings.freedomblogging.com/" time="2012-07-12-18:02" support="2" score="0.004043346990934802" bingtitle="Yikes! (inside the mind of Toby Eddings)" webtitle="Yikes! (inside the mind of Toby Eddings)">
			<query id="000784" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="001412" bing-rank="198"/>
	<description>How … does a fast-food restaurant run out of sweet iced tea at ... to pull forward as I had Tuesday night while my food ... A lot of fast food places were closed because of a ...</description>
	<body>
		Gaston Gazette 
 Get Email and Mobile | Newspaper Subscription | Online Subscription | Mobile Apps 
 
72°
 Cloudy 
 Home Sections 
 News&gt;&gt; 
 Local Headlines Nation&amp;World 
 Opinion&gt;&gt; 
 Debate Freedom Politics Elected Officials 
 Sports&gt;&gt; 
 Local Sports Belmont Abbey VarsityNC.com American Legion Baseball Carolina Panthers Charlotte Bobcats Colleges Gastonia Grizzlies NASCAR News National Video Highlights CarolinaGrowl 
 Business&gt;&gt; 
 Local Business Nation&amp;World 
 Lifestyles&gt;&gt; 
 Anniversaries Community Spotlight Engagements Events Calendar Health TV Preview Recipes School Menus Restaurant Sanitation Grades Travel Weddings Poetry Corner 
 Archives Special Features 
 Blogs Obituaries Info Center 
 Public Notices Births Building Permits Gaston County Lockup Local Restaurant Directory Sexual Offenders in North Carolina Gaston Area Salaries Lottery Numbers Other Databases 
 Events Contests Services 
 Advertising&gt;&gt; 
 Legals Local Business Listings Place A Classified Ad Rates Today&apos;s Ads Online 
 Subcription Services&gt;&gt; 
 Manage Your Subscription Where to Get A Paper 
 Contact Us Coupon Center Employment Application Mobile App 
 NIE Jobs Autos Real Estate Classifieds 
 
 Don&apos;t Miss: Celebrity divorce | Countdown to DNC | Wildfire tracker | Health care | Supreme Court | 
 
 Yikes! (inside the mind of Toby Eddings) 


The only thing he writes for newspaper pages are headlines ... but he&apos;s not afraid to open his mouth (then it becomes awfully tough to get it closed!
 
 Cooking Channel drives through Fine Living 
 May 31st, 2010, 12:32 pm by Toby Eddings 
Fine Living, which you’ve probably never watched on your cable or satellite, became The Cooking Channel Monday. On Time Warner Gastonia, it’s up on Channel 353 on the digital tier, where it won’t bother anyone. It’s a Scripps channel, an outgrowth of Food Network.

At my dialysis clinic, we used to have four televisions in the big room to watch during treatment. (We now have individual TVs at each cheir, which is fine except for the fact that some rightwinger figured out how to block MSNBC. I’d really like to watch“Morning Joe”in the mornings, because the morning shows on Charlotte stations are so dreadful with their news actresses .)

Anyway, when we had the common TVs, there was a lady at dialysis who thought she owned the TV as soon as she walked in. Sometime last year when I was going on Saturday mornings. I was watching“Blazing Saddles”on AMC. She came in and the first thing she did was change the TV over to Food Network. Never bothered to ask if anyone was watching. About all I ever saw her watch was Food Network.

The hang of it is that most of things cooked on that channel are NOT on our diet, a renal diet. Got her back one day (totally against our style, you understand)…she had a propensity to go to sleep quickly as soon as she started watching. With the“help”of one of the techs, I changed the channel to something vicious. Take that, Scooter. Hope you’re enjoying your own TV. I know I am. I have an appointment with Horatio Caine and Calleigh Duquesne three times a week at 9 in the morning.
 
Posted in: Uncategorized | Post a Comment» 
 
 An ode to a ketchup packet 
 February 5th, 2010, 11:48 am by Toby Eddings 
On the news that Heinz is apparently doing away with my beloved ketchup packets…

For your consideration:
I gave my love a packet/That had no tear
She couldn’t get it open/And she started to swear
I gave my love a story/That had no end
I gave
 

 SQUIRT
 Sorry. I was hungry.

The previous ode was partially mine and partially Stephen Bishop’s from“Animal House.”And speaking of Stephen Bishop,  save it for a rainy day.

Like today.
 
Posted in: Uncategorized | Post a Comment» 
 
 Is it going to snow? Yeah, somewhere 
 January 27th, 2010, 1:13 pm by Toby Eddings 
It’s almost time to break out into an end run for your favorite (or if you wait too long, your unfavorite) grocery store to buy the dreaded bread and milk, or something else. The National Weather Service is calling for frozen precipitation in the next couple of days. RUNNNNNN!

OK, just run. Don’t need all that yelling IN ALL CAPS.

I’m not a meteorologist, and I don’t even play one on TV or the newspaper. I wanted to do the weather on TV when I was much younger, but I had a body for radio, so I went in that direction. (But I STILL have those TV star good looks. Yeah, sure.) And I still like weather

A TV news Web site I read daily was the first place I saw TV weather people called“weather guessers,”and that is fairly accurate. Think about that tonight when you watch Eric or Steve or Brad or Mark or Jeff or Reg.

The National Weather Service Web site is the only place I go to read the forecast. It’s official, and it has radar. I’m a big fan of radar (liked him on“M*A*S*H”as well. Watching radar is fun in the summer during bad weather. I am fascinated watching storm systems explode into something bigger. You don’t get that in the winter during snowstorms. Frequently, snowfall (for example) is too light to be picked up by the radar site.

A weekend snowfall was first mentioned in the NWS forecast as early as last weekend, I believe. The first mention I remember was rain or snow beginning Friday night and into Saturday and Saturday night. A day or so ago, snow was moved up to the post-1 p.m. period Friday. I looked this morning before I went to dialysis and the start of snow was advanced to a mix of rain and snow before 1 p.m. Friday, then snow likely after 1 p.m. Sleet was added to Friday night, then snow and sleet Saturday, with snow likely after noon on Saturday.

Oh, joy.

I may need to wander out Thursday morning and get some stuff. I’m running low on“stuff.”I can’t drink milk; I only drink sweet tea and water. And I probably need to make a new pitcher of tea. I have vanilla wafers, Cinnamon Chex and a bunch of other kidney-legal snacks. Got some stuff I brought from home in my refrigerator’s freezer (like burger patties, barbecue and the like). But I still might need to go by Chick-fil-A and get a fewsandwiches in case the weather gets nuts.

And it can. Really and for true. As long as it’s cold, it can snow. It’s cold. My former car battery can attest to that, wherever it is now.

Looking at the forecast, I agree with the NWS. It’s going to do something funky. Depending on the weather system headed this way, temperature will be the key factor as to what we get. Just bundle up and get ready for something. Brrrrr.
 
Posted in: Uncategorized | Post a Comment» 
 
 The mountains are pretty this time of year… 
 October 29th, 2009, 11:57 am by Toby Eddings 
 















 
 
Posted in: Uncategorized | Post a Comment» 
 
 Chick-fail-A? 
 October 7th, 2009, 12:55 pm by Toby Eddings 
It hurts me to say something bad about Chick-fil-A, but I must. I’m just not a particular fan of the lineup from wherever you are for a store’s grand opening to get free food.

I’ve been at Chick-fil-A grand openings. They are fun (except when you’re trying to get to sleep in a hotel room across the parking lot from the nearly-all-night festivities, which I did when a new store in Durham opened).

I blogged about Chick-fil-A a couple of years ago because chain founder Truett Cathy is a hero of mine, both in his business practices and personal life. As the years go on, he might be my ONLY hero. It is truly (and sadly) hard to find someone you would like to emulate and not be embarassed. I got to spend about 30 minutes talking with him and felt honored.

Having said that…

It’s nice that a new Chick-fil-A standalone store is opening in Belmont Thursday morning. It might be the closest store to I-85 (the one in Gaffney is almost as close). Great location, right down from the only Wal-Mart in the area I will spend money at (a certificate on the wall says it was the Store of the Year in 2008. Good job, folks. And thanks.).

There is a tradition at new Chick-fil-A stores that has followed  to Belmont. The first 100 customers in line through the door at 6 a.m. get a free combo meal each week for a year. Now, watch the local morning“news”shows Thursday morning and you’re likely to see live shots from the parking lot or inside the doors. I can think of only one Charlotte morning show of the four this would be appropriate on. The others will attempt to make it“news.”

It’s 4:43 Wednesday afternoon and a story on the Gazette Web site reflected that at 1:14 p.m. (when the story was posted), the drawing for spots in line has already been held, nearly a day before the fact. Daniel Jackson’s story (welcome back to work, pop) reads that 74 have camped at Chick-il-A events before. There are people who travel the country and go to these grand openings. It’s college students, retirees, anyone at all (I met some of these people at the one I attended in Durham). Do these college students miss classes for free food? The story says some of the campers will donate their free food to youth groups or other charitable organizations. But is that fair to the locals, the residents of Belmont and Mount Holly? Not really. It’s the people of Gaston County who will be  going to this restaurant six days a week…not the people of Florida and other parts of the populace.

I told someone the other day that I don’t mind spending a little more to eat at Chick-fil-A because I know the quality of the food, the quality of the employees (and it’s always MY pleasure to go there; I like hearing that phrase), and I know where the proceeds are going. My deep Baptist roots come out when I say that spending money at Chick-fil-A is like tithing, in a way. I hope that didn’t come out the wrong way because I mean it reverently. I also felt like I had been to church that morning at the Durham grand opening. Every business should be run like that.

I just wish locals would get first crack at those free meals. That’s all. Welcome to Belmont. And don’t fergit to eat mor chikin.
 
Posted in: Uncategorized | Post a Comment» 
 
 I don’t live in G-town 
 October 3rd, 2009, 12:22 pm by Toby Eddings 
Hi. I’m Toby and I live in Gastonia. G-town is Georgetown, correct?

Yer durn tootin’it is. There has been a recent rash of G-town sightings around here, and Gastonia is nowhere near Georgetown.

Say it…G-town. Do you know how Jerry Springerish that sounds? Need I break it down and explain it to you? Think of the color that rhymes with fed and the part of the body that rhymes with dreck. Dreck is an appropriate word in this case, you know. Bat guano even more so.

I love Gastonia. I’ve lived here almost 5.5 years now and intend to stay here a lot longer. Yep, we’ve got problems, but doesn’t everybody? (That Life in Gastonia Web site, by the way, is worth a few minutes of your time.) I wish our Gastonia police cars were more attractive. They can be very easily; paint and some letters would do the trick. I wish our merchants could utilize electronic marquees  (and I bet they wish they could, too). The Schiele Museum was allowed to put one up out front and the world hasn’t come to an end yet, has it, City Council? Electronic marquees can be found in Dallas and Shelby and there have been no problems reported there. I’d rather see an attractive electronic sign than one with plastic letters that require the merchant to play cryptic word games with the viewer. And…what possible problems could there be with a gas station showing its gas prices in electronic digits? Progress? Methinks there are people in our city unable to spell the word“progress”…wonder if anyone running for office could win on a platform of“regress”? I’m sure there are those who would vote for that just to remain ensconsed and buried in the 1950s. I get that feeling when I pass through parts of Franklin Boulevard, or Tattooland, known by some as downtown Gastonia.

I think I’d rather see an attractive tombstone sign at the entrance to a shopping center than one with 58 tenants’names that are hard to read unless you’re stuck in traffic. Six or seven major ones, yes, but not the whole center. That sort of thing was done 30 years ago.

It’s not 30 years ago, city leaders. It’s 2009. Let’s do some simple things to make it look that way. I like that electronic billboard on I-85 just past the McAdenville exit. Attractive. It can be changed when needed. Gastonia could do with some of those.

And as for G-town? Why don’t you ask the folks in Georgetown…because that G-town nonsense is just…well, bat guano.
 
Posted in: Uncategorized | Post a Comment» 
 
 Flu update 
 September 28th, 2009, 2:16 pm by Toby Eddings 
 What is the difference between Bird Flu and Swine Flu? 

 

 For bird flu, you need tweetment and for swine flu, you need oinkment 

I stole this from a friend who sent it to me, but it’s funny. Now that you’ve laughed, go get your vaccine.
 
Posted in: Uncategorized | Post a Comment» 
 
 How do you run out of tea at 8 p.m.? 
 September 24th, 2009, 9:56 am by Toby Eddings 
How…does a fast-food restaurant run out of sweet iced tea at 8 p.m. on a Wednesday night? Hmmmmm…wouldn’t happen if the teqa was brewed.

This happened to me Wednesday night on my supper break. I won’t name the restaurant, but it sells burgers and has to do with royalty. That might narrow it down some.

This wasn’t the first time I have had issues with this particular store. I had stopped going to any of this chain’s locations at all, in fact, for much of the year. It was a trip to a location on the other side of town that soured me on this chain earlier in the year. The alleged great new tea was horrible and I figured I didn’t need to have (name censored)  in my rotation.

On Tuesday night, I went to this particular chain on my 30-minute supper break. I got a chicken sandwich and forgot how good that sandwich was at this chain. I remember when it came out back in 1979 (along with a steak sandwich, which I still miss). I eat them plain (who needs anything on chicken?) and had to wait for them, but it was worth the wait. They were hot and juicy, to steal someone else’s old slogan ( their hamburgers haven’t been juicy in years). I also got onion rings and sweet tea. The rings were great (they are the only ones I eat anywhere) but I was hoping the tea would be better than it was the last time I ordered it months ago. Nope. It was Nestea. I would put money on it…I know what fast-food Nestea tastes like (I used to get it at a Central Park location. Ever eaten at Central Park? There used to be one in Conway, S.C. Good burgers and fries.).

Great meal…so I went back at supper Wednesday night to get the same order. Sandwiches, rings, tea. I kept asking the person on the orderboard if the tea was brewed. He kept telling me it was. I asked three times and he kept telling me it was.

Of note: I am a kidney dialysis patient. Protein is good for me (meat, chicken, etc.) NO French fries or baked potatoes or brown drinks (Coke, Pepsi), because of the phosperous contained. Also, water and BREWED tea. Big difference. Chick-fil-A, Bojangles, McDonalds and most other fast food restaurants have brewed tea. Nestea in bottles and in dispensers HAS phosperous and I’m not supposed to drink it.

End of note. So, my bill rings up at 7.74. I pulled forward, had to wait about three minutes for the truck in front of me, then pulled up. I paid, and about two minutes later, the window opened and I thought he was going to ask me to pull forward as I had Tuesday night while my food was prepared.

Instead, the kid who insisted that the tea was brewed informed me that the restaurant was out of sweet tea. At 7:59 at night. Stunning. And very weak and sad. I told whoever was nearby inside that I can’t drink green tea (it’s on the can’t-drink list), unsweetened tea, brown colas, anything without caffeine (I’m at work until 12:30 a.m.)…and I was exasperated by now. Someone inside asked if I wanted my money back and noting Chick-fil-A is next door, I answered in the affirmative.

I didn’t get 7.74 back. I got a couple of ones and a dime or so. I got stiffed…but I didn’t feel like going back for my money. Thirty minutes goes fast, especially when you have driven half the time to the place you want food from. A girl opened the window and gave me some money back and told me that the tea comes in a box (gee). Kidding, right? I knew the kid had been telling me a story because I know what fresh brewed tea tastes like. But I got stiffed, too.

This…is not customer service. Clark Howard would call it customer no-service. I have worked in customer-service intense organizations before, and something like this would be something close to grounds for dismissal or probation.

I expect better from this chain. I have been eating the chain’s food since the 1970s when a location opened in Columbia, S.C. It would have nice had someone asked if they could do anything…but I’ll be dagged if I ever go back to this particular store (like one person makes a difference). There are two outstanding chains on wither side of this particular location, one being the best of all. I sent a scathing e-mail to the chain’s Web site when I got back to work Wednesday night before I clocked back in, and I also sent the e-mail to Planet Feedback Thursday morning. I love that site. You should go there if you ever have a complaint with a business. It gets results. I have friends that have gotten food, hardware and other things after complaining. Companies read that site.

I’m tired of writing. I have a taste for a chicken sandwich.
 
Posted in: Uncategorized | Post a Comment» 
 
 My Hurricane Hugo experience 
 September 20th, 2009, 2:07 pm by Toby Eddings 
I lived through Hurricane Hugo from a different point of view than many of you (“many of you”being a inaccurate, worthless throwaway phrase said too frequently on TV news). But this time,“many of you”is likely an accurate description. My point of view is of a Myrtle Beach resident who had to evacuate and honestly didn’t know if he would  have a dwelling for he and his family to return to.

I moved to Myrtle Beach in 1985 to work at The Sun News, which once was a great newspaper until all the good newspeople who were there when I was were forced to (and choose your phrase), move elsewhere,“quit”or“leave.”In 1989, we were a great newspaper with great people and a great editor, Gil Thelen. Hurricanes were a way of life in Myrtle Beach, and we had been brushed by a few my first few years there. Hugo was a different animal. We had followed its progress in the Atlantic and took special notice when it had its eye (literally speaking) on the south Atlantic coast.

I was one of the top weather freaks in the newsroom and anytime the weather got dicey, the TV over in the design/sports area stayed on The Weather Channel, which was a handy thing in those days because weather was actually shown. NO DOCUMENTARIES. Actual weather. We would be watching for those updated hurricane advisories every six hours and for the strike charts in particular.

Hugo kept up its progress  and we started making contingency plans to produce the  newspaper in Columbia at The State, then as now owned by the same company. The designers and an editor or two would be going to Columbia, the other folks fanning out in the county and beyond if they were going to evacuate. Florence would be a safe destination. Yep.

The hurricane kept the coast in its sights and the decision was made Wednesday morning that the team would go to Columbia Thursday because things were starting to look ominous. I started to get a little nervous. A lot of other people in the newsroom were getting very nervous.

The morning of Thursday, Sept. 21, dawned beautifully. How ironic. My family of four lived in an apartment at the time, and listening to all the descriptions of the damage that could occur with this storm, I was honestly worried that I might not have an apartment building to come home to. Suddenly,“things”weren’t that important. I had no idea how long it would take to get back home, so I filled my car and my trunk with lots of my clothes and my wife’s (at that time). I also made sure to get all the photo albums and a few other important type things. Just in case, you understand.

Thursday was our normal pay day, so I wandered by the office on my way out of town (the rest of my family left for Columbia earlier) to pick up my check. It could be cashed later. We were hearing horror stories in the newsroom that U.S. 501, at that time the only way across the Intracoastal Waterway, was jammed. Packed with cars. I had already choden to take a different route. I went down U.S. 17 to Georgetown, where I could get on U.S. 521 and go north. (I also knew I could go by Cruisers when I was down there and  get burgers and fried to eat on the way. Always thinking about food!)

I reached 521 and started heading inland, through Andrews and Salters to Manning, where I got on S.C. 261 and took a shortcut through Paxville and Pinewood and came in on U.S. 378 far west of Sumter just past Shaw Air Force Base. I had noticed the sky looking a hair unusual on 521, as I looked southeast and sawan odd cloud formation. Half of the sky was clear; the other half, omniously cloudy.

I got to Columbia and before I went to my in-laws’house (where we would be staying), I went by Kroger to cash my paycheck (there was an in-store location of my bank there). We had already determined that we would meet at The State at 6 to check in and get comfortable with the surroundings and our workspace. We also saw some folks from The Post and Courier in Charleston, who were going to bunk over at The State.

Around 9 or 10, I headed back to the in-laws’house, which wasn’t that far away. I started watching TV coverage of the storm in the kitchen on the portable TV, which limited me to over-the-air stations. I believe it was CBS that had live coverage of the coast, then NBC. Around 2 a.m., all of the TV options were gone and I headed to bed. No problems so far, althoufght I went to bed knowing that the hurricane had come ashore near Charleston. That’s all we knew at that time.

At 5:30 a.m. (and I knew this because I looked at the alarm clock), I was awakened by a freight train overhead. That would be Mr. Hugo F. Hurricane making its presence known in Columbia. It knocked out power…and scared me to death.

I woke up at 7:30 to no electricity and got dressed to go to work that way. I road I took to the newspaper thankfully wasn’t blocked by limbs or power lines. There was power at the newspaper office and we somehow managed to produce Saturday’s newspaper. But it was a smaller one in terms of pages. We had one sports page that I remember doing. Most of it was reports from our reporters.  The word from back at the beach was that it wasn’t as bad there as it was down the coast near Charleston…and inland, like in the Charlotte area.

We got the paper done around 7ish and I went looking for food, but that was tough. A lot of fast food places were closed because of a lack of power and I honestly can’t remember if I ever found anything. I don’t remember that I even had lunch that day. I got back to the in-laws and they were still without power…and air conditioning. That was a long Friday evening, kids. No radio, no TV, no moving air…whew.

I got out of there Saturday morning and started heading back to the beach. It was an interesting drive to see holes in forests where trees had formerly been. There was a long line of cars trying to get back to the beach and we were slowly allowed back in. My apartment was still stading…less a grand total of two shingles, which I was good with. The next three or so weeks were interesting. There were curfews and life was briefly changed. We could have done much worse at Myrtle Beach. We could haver been in Charlotte.

Other hurricanes while I was at the beach were more interesting…like the one that left enough water to flood the downstairs of our house. We had been talking about getting new carpet…

But meteorogically speaking, 1989 was a doozy at Myrtle Beach. We had Hugo in September and on the night of December 22, snow began falling. When it eneded on Christmas Eve morning, a foot and a half of snow had fallen at Myrtle Beach. Even ON the beach. What a fun day or two or three that was.

No one sang“I’m dreaming of a White Christmas”that year and remeined uninjured or upright.
 
Posted in: Uncategorized | Post a Comment» 
 
 Jay Leno, the future of comedy? You must mean tragedy 
 September 13th, 2009, 4:12 pm by Toby Eddings 
The alarming torso of one Jay Leno glared at me from the magazine rack as I left my CVS drug store Sunday. Last week’s Time magazine cover taunted me with the words,“Jay Leno Is the Future of Television. Seriously.”

Help. Quick.

That’s not a nice phrase to utter in such a public forum as a magazine cover. Future of television? More like the end of television.

My words my be colored by the fact that I still think Jay Leno underhanded his way into the 11:35 slot on NBC  years ago, the job that the former holder of that time period, John. F. Carson Himself, wanted to go to that Letterman fellow. But this isn’t the time to rehash the battle over that time period.

The good news for me is that I won’t have to watch Leno. I’m at work, and our TVs are on a newscast at 10 p.m. The good news for you is that your TVs can be on newscasts at 10 as well. Or, better yet, great dramas.

I watch WCNC in horror during  its newscasts. EXCLUSIVELY, as WCNC has a penchant for saying.  There are some folks on those newscasts who still could  have a career if they would go to another station. Soon.

If you watched NewsChannel 36 last week, you would think that the debut of Jay Leno’s 10 p.m. weeknight program is a world event. It was certainly treated that way, to be sure. Like a pressing news story. That ain’t news. Leave that stuff to“Access Hollywood”at 4:05 a.m.

WCNC has run NBC promos that said the NBC Research Department (oh yeah?) found that“71 percent of you want more comedy.”(All you really need to do is watch NewsChannel 36 newscasts.) And Jay Leno is comedy? Not in my book. Steve Martin said 30 years ago that comedy is not pretty. Today, just witness Jay Leno.

Hey, you Crabby Appleton Republicans, get out there and protest something new. See what you can do about“The Jay Leno Show.”

You know, if you watch Jay Leno’s bits, none of them are particularly original. Or funny. NBC is sinking deeper and deeper into the muck. Its primetime shows aren’t very good. Late night is dying as Conan O’Brien has been beaten like a drum in the ratings for about two months by that Letterman fellow. Jimmy Fallon is pretty wretched (and his show is an unfunny joke, put next to TV’s Craig Ferguson at the same time on CBS).

The thing about WCNC is that when a station is in the dregs of the ratings, it does anything it can to get out. Instead, WCNC puts its best face on the situation. But if I were WCNC, I’d do what I could to get the Fox affiliation away from WCCB. As I write this, Fox is a much better network than NBC.

I’m ending this now…because I want to go into the other room and watch the series finale of“King of the Hill.”

On Fox.:)
 
Posted in: Uncategorized | Post a Comment» 
 « Previous Entries 
 Jobs Autos Real Estate Classifieds 
 ADVERTISEMENT  ADVERTISEMENT  
 
Search
 
Pages

 About 
 
Archives
 Select Month May 2010 February 2010 January 2010 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 
Categories

 Uncategorized 
 
Tag Cloud
 
Related Posts
 
 powered by
          Search: Web   Site 
 Subscribe Today&apos;s Ads Place an Ad Advertising Rates Local News Sports Lifestyles Story Archives Obituaries Yellow Pages Apartments 
 Attorneys 
 Auto Dealers 
 Auto Parts 
 Auto Repair 
 Beauty Salons 
 Car Rental 
 Dentists 
 Doctors 
 Flowers 
 Hotels 
 Insurance 
 Loans 
 Mortgages 
 Movers 
 Pizza 
 Realtors 
 Restaurants 
 Storage 
 Tax Preparation 
 Travel 
 Featured 
 More... Employment Application Interactive 

 Carolina Growl VarsityNC Discover Gaston Gaston Politics Gaston Homes Online NC Piedmont Jobs Newspapers in Education Freedom Politics 

 Online Paper Breaking News Alerts RSS Feeds Article Map Gaston Gazette Shelby Star Local Business Listings Site Map Contact Us Privacy User Agreement 
 
Copyright©2012

 Contact Us | Privacy Policy | User Agreement | Advertising Info | Local Business Listings |

 Cars&amp;Autos | Homes | Jobs | Classifieds 
 
 Freedom Communications, Inc. 
 SEO Powered by Platinum SEO from Techblissonline
	</body>
</document>
