<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003559" url="http://aveganlife.blogspot.com/2006/03/vegan-fast-food-options.html" time="2012-07-12-19:43" support="94" score="0.518035025995567" bingtitle="My Life As A RAW Vegan: Vegan Fast Food Options" webtitle="My Life As A RAW Vegan: Vegan Fast Food Options">
			<query id="000038" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="000882" bing-rank="193"/>
			<query id="001411" bing-rank="139"/>
			<query id="001100" bing-rank="83"/>
			<query id="000878" bing-rank="23"/>
			<query id="000360" bing-rank="242"/>
			<query id="000901" bing-rank="222"/>
			<query id="001506" bing-rank="25"/>
			<query id="000442" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000257" bing-rank="236"/>
			<query id="000627" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="001443" bing-rank="190"/>
			<query id="000182" bing-rank="78"/>
			<query id="000941" bing-rank="165"/>
			<query id="000164" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="000462" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="000252" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000430" bing-rank="82"/>
			<query id="001160" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000444" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="000162" bing-rank="110"/>
			<query id="000170" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="000880" bing-rank="75"/>
			<query id="000422" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="001120" bing-rank="95"/>
			<query id="000610" bing-rank="135"/>
			<query id="000055" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="000461" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="000036" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="001530" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000630" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001512" bing-rank="176"/>
			<query id="000345" bing-rank="7"/>
			<query id="000847" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="001129" bing-rank="148"/>
			<query id="000900" bing-rank="126"/>
			<query id="000431" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000438" bing-rank="32"/>
			<query id="000407" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="001098" bing-rank="13"/>
			<query id="001003" bing-rank="220"/>
			<query id="001510" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="000183" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="000594" bing-rank="115"/>
			<query id="000054" bing-rank="138"/>
			<query id="000416" bing-rank="87"/>
			<query id="000005" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000158" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000369" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000095" bing-rank="187"/>
			<query id="000347" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="000909" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000057" bing-rank="61"/>
			<query id="001175" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000419" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000032" bing-rank="26"/>
			<query id="001348" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="001104" bing-rank="103"/>
			<query id="000376" bing-rank="66"/>
			<query id="000034" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000370" bing-rank="65"/>
			<query id="000902" bing-rank="224"/>
			<query id="001107" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="000255" bing-rank="122"/>
			<query id="000349" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="001529" bing-rank="202"/>
			<query id="000180" bing-rank="64"/>
			<query id="000903" bing-rank="131"/>
			<query id="000429" bing-rank="49"/>
			<query id="001123" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="000367" bing-rank="94"/>
			<query id="000432" bing-rank="71"/>
			<query id="000044" bing-rank="159"/>
			<query id="000001" bing-rank="114"/>
			<query id="001475" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000413" bing-rank="88"/>
			<query id="000173" bing-rank="147"/>
			<query id="000267" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000851" bing-rank="137"/>
			<query id="000041" bing-rank="194"/>
			<query id="001122" bing-rank="85"/>
			<query id="001508" bing-rank="98"/>
			<query id="001518" bing-rank="164"/>
			<query id="000056" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="000185" bing-rank="169"/>
			<query id="000351" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="001110" bing-rank="132"/>
			<query id="000002" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000167" bing-rank="96"/>
			<query id="000357" bing-rank="133"/>
			<query id="000368" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000016" bing-rank="108"/>
			<query id="000411" bing-rank="104"/>
			<query id="000925" bing-rank="207"/>
	<description>... you will eventually be in a situation where you are asked to dine in a fast food ... Vegan ingredients to chose from and customize your own order include: black ...</description>
	<body>
		My Life As A RAW Vegan 
 
 Previously this blog was dedicated to the life and endeavors of a teenage vegan navigating a non-vegan world, with recipes, tips, animal activism and more!
Now, as of March 2011, I am embarking on a raw food journey for health as well as ethical reasons. Although I am currently raw, I am leaving all of my previous content up, including cooked-food recipes, etc. Veganism is great for the planet, the animals, and YOU!, no matter which form of it you choose to follow :) 
 
 Monday, March 20, 2006 
 
Vegan Fast Food Options
 A lot of restaurant foods are vegan, but many do not know it. Here&apos;s a handy guide to use when eating out!

 Last Updated: April 30 (Taco Bell, Panera Bread, McAlister&apos;s Deli) 

 FEBRUARY 15 - The VFFO list has been completely redone, now with about 50% more options! 

 The information here is to be used as guidelines only. Menu items can change between franchises, and the information here is the from the company, checking with the individual stores is advised if you are unsure. Please be sure to ask that they hold any unvegan condiments from otherwise vegan items (ie some place will add butter to a baked potato without you asking.) 

 5&amp;Diner– Bagels, Toast (all kinds), Instant Oatmeal, Hash Browns, Tortilla, Vegetarian Burger, Veggie Delight, Breaded Mushrooms, Onion Rings, Apple Pie, Cherry Pie, Salad (w/o cheeses and croutons), Italian Dressings, Baked Potato, Corn on the Cob, French Fries, Sauteed Mushrooms, Steamed Veggies, Spaghetti with Marinara

 Applebee’s– Sizzling Vegetable Skillet, Steamed Vegetable Plate, Nachos (w/o cheese, sour cream, + beef)

 Arby’s– Garden Salad, Side Salad, Marinara Sauce, Apple Turnover, Cherry Turnover, Italian Dressing, Baked Potato (plain!), Sourdough Bread, Potato Cakes, Raspberry Vinaigrette, Seasoned Tortilla Strips, Apple Turnover, Cherry Turnover, Chocolate Twist,

 Backyard Burgers– Garden Veggie Sandwich,

 Baskin Robbins– Sorbet, Ices

 Bennigan&apos;s– Boca Burger, Garden Salad, Roasted Vegetable Primavera (w/o Lemon Butter Sauce)

 Blimpie– Italian White Sub Roll, Wheat Sub Roll, Mediterranean Flat Bread Marbled Rye Roll, Spinach Tortilla, Flour Tortilla, Ciabatta Bread, Fat Free Italian Dressing, Light Italian Dressing, Blimpie Dressing, Blimpie Sub Dressing, Apple Strudelette, Long John, Original Potato Chips, Jalapeno Chips, Pasta Salad, Guacamole, Sweet Peppers, Hot Peppers, Jalepeno Peppers,

 Boston Market - Chunky Cinnamon Apple Sauce, Fruit Salad, Steamed Vegetables, Zucchini Marinara, Apple Cobbler (not pie!), Tossed Salad (no croutons or dressing), Cranberry Walnut Relish, Cinnamon Apples, Fruit Salad

 Brueger’s Bagels– Bagels (Blueberry, Chocolate Chip, Cinnamon Sugar, Cranberry Orange, Pumpernickel, and Rosemary Olive Oil), Soups (Chili Cilantro, Gazpacho, Tuscan, Minestrone, Garden Split Pea, Marcello Minestrone, Roasted Roma Tomato, Vegetable Tomato Lentil, and Ratatouille), Sandwiches can be vegan by omitting cheese and dressing
 
 Burger King– French Fries, Strawberry Apple Sauce, Dutch Apple Pie, Plain Salad, Onion Rings, Fruit Jams, Ketchup, Mustard, Dill Pickles, Hash Browns,

 Carl Jr.– French fries, Hash Brown Nuggets, Breadsticks, English Muffins, CrissCuts, Salad Bar, 3 Bean Salad, Fat Free Italian Dressing, Great Stuff™Baked Potatoes (ask for all-vegetable margerine)

 Cheeburger Cheeburger –Grilled Portobello Mushroom Sandwich (w/o cheese), Boca Burger, Salads (minus cheese), Fries, Onion Rings,

 Chi-Chi’s –Chips, Salsa, Dinner Salad (w/o cheese), Refried beans (w/o cheese), guacamole

 Chili’s –Chips, Salsa, Veggie Quesadilla (w/o cheese and sour cream add extra veggies), Cadillac Fajitas (w/o meat), Bottomless Tostada Chips, Fries, Steamed Broccoli (no butter), Sauteed Mushrooms with Onions and Peppers (fried in vegetable oil),

 Chipotle –Vegetarian Fajita Burrito (w/ black beans NOT pinto beans), Vegetarian Burrito (with BLACK beans, no cheese, no sour cream)

 Chuck E. Cheese –Pizza Sauce, Pizza Crust

 Claim Jumper - Broiled Portobello Stack (ask for UNmarinated mushrooms, w/o cheese), Nacho Platter (ONLY with Black Beans, Salsa, Guacamole), Pretzel (w/o butter), Candied Walnut&amp;Asian Pear Salad (w/o candied walnuts, dressings, or cheese), California Citrus Salad (w/o pecans, bleu cheese, or dressing), Crunchy Spinach Salad (w/o bacon, cheese, or pecans), Produce Bar, Roasted Veggies, Roasted Vegetable Pizza (w/o pesto or cheese), Vegetable Soup 

 Cold Stone Creamery –Lemon Sorbet, Tangerine Sorbet, Raspberry Sorbet

 Cousin’s Subs –Hot Veggie Sub

 Culvers –French Fries, Seasoned Green Beans

 Daily Grill –Grilled Vegetable Plate

 Denny’s –Oatmeal Fixins’(raisins, brown sugar, sliced banana), Juice, English Muffins, Grits, Applesauce, Fresh Fruit, Frozen Strawberries, Jelly (all flavors), nut and fruit topping, fruit syrups, baked potato, marinara sauce, sautéed mushrooms, grilled onions and peppers, guacamole, barbecue sauce, vegetable plates, seasoned fries, mashed potatoes, sauerkraut, garden salads, dressings (light Italian, reduced French, Oriental dressing, oil and vinegar) light rye bread, bagel, boule bread

 Einstein Bros. Bagels –Plain, Jalapeno, Chopped Onion, Everything Bagel, Cinnamon Raisin Swirl, Chocolate Chip, Poppy Dip Bagel, Wild Blueberry, Salt Bagel, Sesame dipd Bagel, Pumpernickel, Cranberry, Sun-Dried Tomato Bagels

 Flamer&apos;s Grill –Veggie Pattie

 Hard Rock Cafe –Vegetarian Burger, Veggie Sandwhich, Salads

 Hard Times Cafe –Cafe Veggie Burger, Veggie Chili (ask for no dairy products)

 Harvey&apos;s –Veggie Burger

 Houston&apos;s–Veggie Plate, Vegetarian Burger (ask for vegan bread) 

 Jimmy John&apos;s –Vegetarian Sub (w/o cheese and mayo), Gourmet Veggie Club (w/o cheese and mayo), Pickle Spear, Whole Pickle,

 Johnny Rocket’s –the Streamliner (vegan Boca Burger), Fries, Onion Rings (no ranch sauce), Grilled Mushrooms, Garden Salad (w/o cheese)

 Krispy Kreme –Fruit Pies (not coconut)

 Little Caesars –Pizza Crust, Pizza sauce, Crazy Sauce, Crazy Bread

 Macaroni Grill –Pasta w/ Garlic and Oil, Capellini Pomodoro, Tomato Brushetta (w/o cheese), Penne Arrabiata (w/o cheese), House Salad (w/o cheese), Garden Salad (w/o cheese), Balsamic Vinaigrette, Roasted Garlic Vinaigrette, Italian Dressing

 McDonald’s –Fruit and Walnut Salad (w/o the walnuts or yogurt), Side Salad, Low-fat Balsamic Vinaigrette, Baked Apple Pie, McVeggie (only available in NYC, Canada, and California)

 McAlister&apos;s Deli - Veggie Spud (without cheese), Spud Ole (w/o cheese&amp;w/ vegetarian chili), California Classic (w/o cheeses), The Veggie (w/o cheese or dressing), Taco Salad (w/o cheese&amp;sour cream&amp;w/ vegetarian chili), Garden Salad (w/o cheese), Chili In A Bread Bowl (specify vegetarian chili), Chips&amp;Salsa, Olive Oil&amp;Balsamic Vinaigrette, Lite Italian, and Fat-Free Sun-Dried Tomato Basil Vinaigrette

 Mimi&apos;s Cafe –Veggie Stack Sandwich

 Moe&apos;s –(All tacos, fajitas, salads, and burritos are vegan if you ask for tofu/beans instead of meat and ask for no cheese)

 Noodles&amp;Company –Japanese Pan Noodles, Pasta Fresca (w/o cheese), Indonesian Peanut Sautee, Penne Rosa (w/o cheese), Tomato Marinara (w/o cheese), Rustic Roll,

 Panera Bread –Everything Bagel, Sesame Bagel, Plain Bagel, Blueberry Bagel, Sourdough Bread, Ciabatta Bread, Nine Grain Loaf, Rye Loaf, Artisan Three Seed Bread, Artisan Sesame Semolina Bread, Artisan Multigrain, Artisan French, Artisan Stone-Milled Rye Bread, Artisan Country, Lower-Carb Pumpkin Seed Bread, Lower Carb Italian Herb Bread, Mediterranean Veggie (without feta cheese)

 Papa Johns –Pizza Dough, Pizza Sauce, Thin Crusts, Veggies

Papa Murphy’s–Pizza Crust, Sauce, Veggies

 Pizza Hut –Thin n’Crispy Crust, Hand Tossed Dough, Pizza Sauce, Sweet Sauce, Spaghetti Marinara Sauce, Pasta, Italian and French Dressings, Dessert Pizza crust, Cherry topping, Icing, Garlic Bread (make sure its oil not butter),

 Pollo Tropical –Vegetarian TropiChop, Balsamic Tomatoes, Bananas Tropical, Black Beans, French Fries, White Rice, Yellow Rice, Boiled Yucca, Corn

Pyramid Brewery–Boca Burger (can be substituted for any burger, make sure its the vegan variety), Margarita Pizza

 Quizno’s Subs –Garden Salad, Potato Chips

 Rainforest Café –the Natural Burger (w/o Safari Sauce), Morningstar Garden Grill, Paradise House Salad

 Roy Rogers –Baked Potato, Vegetables (side dishes), Salad Bar, Mashed Potatoes (w/o gravy)

 Ruby Tuesday’s –Veggie Burger (w/o mayo and cheese), Veggie Burger Wrap, Salad Bar, Lettuce Wrapped Burger (substitute veggie burger for meat burger)

 Sbarro –Tomato Cucumber Salad, Garden Vinaigrette Dressing

 Shari&apos;s –Gardenburger

 Subway –Veggie Delight Salad, Italian Roll/Bread (customize a sub), Veggie Delight (w/o cheese and mayo), Fruizle smoothies, Veggies, Vegan Breads: Italian, Hearty Italian, and Sourdough

 Swenson&apos;s Drive-In –Veggie Special

 Taco Bell –Bean Burrito (w/o cheese), Bean Taco (w/o cheese–specially prepared), seasoned rice, tortilla chips, Veggie Fajita Wrap (w/o cheese), pinto beans, Cinnamon Twists, 7-Layer Burrito (w/o cheese and sour cream), Mexican Pizzas (w/o cheese, meat, sour cream), Nachos (w/o cheese, meat, sour cream), Tacos (w/o meat, cheese, sour cream ADD Black Beans/Refried Beans) Taco Salad (w/o meat/cheese/sour cream, w/ refried beans)

 Tubby&apos;s –Hot Veggie Stir-Fry Sandwich,

 Village Inn - Boca Burger (w/o cheese, w/o mayo, ask if its the vegan variety)

 Wendy’s –Plain Baked Potato, French Fries, Deluxe Garden Salad (ask for no cheese), Side Salad, Dressings (French, reduced fat/reduced calorie Italian) Applesauce, Taco Chips, Mandarin Oranges, Veggie Sandwich (everything thats on a burger, without the burger, w/o cheese and mayo)

 World Wraps –Tofu and Mushroom Teriyaki, Bombay Curry Veggie Posted by Allie B at 3/20/2006 05:36:00 PM Labels: fast food options , vegan fast food 
208 comments:
 1–200 of 208  Newer›   Newest» Onanite said... 
About Taco Bell - 7-Layer Burrito (w/o cheese and sour cream) Ask for extra guacamole.... mmmmmm

Onanite
 Monday, March 20, 2006 6:44:00 PM Adam Trent Phillips said... 
This was a good idea to put up. There is also a greek place at Tower City (Downtown Cleveland Mall) that has a butt-kick Falafel that packs a lot of flavor.

Be sure to tell them no cheese on the salad, I get extra hummus instead.

Adam
 Saturday, March 25, 2006 6:22:00 PM Sexy Vegan Chick said... 
Mmmm... Hummus
 Saturday, March 25, 2006 6:53:00 PM Adam Trent Phillips said... 
If you don&apos;t mind my asking, what are your sources for this list ?

Adam
 Monday, April 10, 2006 11:10:00 AM Sexy Vegan Chick said... 
I used both of PETA&apos;s lists for fast food and chain restaurants.

Others I got of veganporn, and other vegan websites. Some are from company websites also.
 Monday, April 10, 2006 6:01:00 PM Michael Leddy said... 
Alas, Jimmy John&apos;s bread isn&apos;t vegan. I e-mailed the company to find out.
 Thursday, July 27, 2006 9:49:00 PM Sexy Vegan Chick said... 
Thats bizarre because I heard that it was... Hmmm. Possible their &quot;not-special&quot; bread is? (Like)
 Friday, July 28, 2006 11:13:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
at cold stone creamery - i asked and they make some of their smoothies with soy milk! those are vegan right?
 Saturday, August 12, 2006 2:41:00 PM doodley ann said... 
Hungry Howies is another vegan-friendly option. The thin crust, regular pizza sauce, cajun flavoring, subsauce (I don&apos;t know what good that does anyone), garden salads (it doesn&apos;t come with cheese), greek dressing, italian dressing, lo-fat italian dressing, and french. But I really don&apos;t know what &quot;xantham gum&quot; is. That&apos;s in all the dressings so I&apos;m kinda iffy.

Eat up kids.
 Monday, January 01, 2007 8:29:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
This list is great&amp;really thorough! I&apos;m always on the go, so I&apos;ll keep this handy. Thanks, Allie! Stay firm in your beliefs.
 Sunday, January 14, 2007 1:01:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
I&apos;m pretty sure and PLEASE let me know if I&apos;m wrong -

Dominoes Pizza dough is vegan, you can get a vegan pizza if you ask for it without cheese. Be careful not to get any sauce packets though as the dipping cups of marinara have milk powder in them. I do NOT think the bread sticks are vegan? as they have butter and weird sprinkles of some sort of MSG cheese combo - unless this has changed since I worked their...
 Sunday, February 04, 2007 7:49:00 AM Anonymous
said... This comment has been removed by a blog administrator. Monday, February 12, 2007 5:22:00 AM Talia said... 
In-N-Out! Veggie burger (burger minus the burger) w/o sauce (add ketchup/mustard instead), grilled onions, french fries.
 Tuesday, February 13, 2007 2:47:00 AM Hippie Vegan said... 
This list is really great. Has anyone heard anything about options at Red Robin?
 Thursday, February 15, 2007 6:19:00 PM Wendi said... 
I used to work at Pizza Hut and here&apos;s the vegan options:

Thin n&apos; crispy and hand tossed dough. NOT pan dough or breadsticks/cinnasticks.

The beans for the taco pizza are NOT vegan.

Both the sweet sauce and normal pizza sauces ARE vegan.

We didn&apos;t serve the pasta or sandwiches, so I don&apos;t know about those.

My favorite: Hand tossed dough, extra sauce with jalapenos and pineapple. Sounds weird, but it&apos;s tasty :)
 Friday, February 16, 2007 1:54:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Quiznos&apos;s bread all has whey in it so it&apos;s not vegan
 Monday, February 26, 2007 9:22:00 PM The Vegan Chick said... 
I asked a person at quizno&apos;s about the bread, and two salespersons told me that they bread was vegan. I could be wrong, but I&apos;m relying off the information I&apos;m being given by the company.
 Tuesday, February 27, 2007 7:28:00 PM kevin said... 
Burger King&apos;s french toast sticks contain &quot;Natural flavors from animal and plant sources&quot; according to bk.com
 Tuesday, April 03, 2007 1:36:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
fuck all this garbage. go to the grocery store or go forage and learn something with some friends
 Friday, April 13, 2007 7:40:00 PM stewie said... 
pita pit, theres on in Ithaca idk where else but supposedly a chain, falafel pitas hummus pitas and salad pitas are all vegan...assuming you don&apos;t get cheese with it or tatziki sauce or greek vinagrette, french, blue cheese or ranch dressings- my favorite is falafel with hummus and italian- lettuce tomato black olives hot peppers jalepenos red onions sprouts and cucumbers...yum
 Thursday, April 19, 2007 9:17:00 PM stewie said... 
assuming you have friends you will eventually be in a situation where you are asked to dine in a fast food restaurant...instead of declining this page is a list of options, so stop being an asshole^^^
 Thursday, April 19, 2007 9:20:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
hey i found this site through a search (i&apos;m about to go on a road trip with 3 omni&apos;s, so i figured i&apos;d better read up on fast food options). my husband worked at pizza slut for years and he said that as far as he knows, their sauce has meat in it. pizza hut got sued by some vegetarians over it and he said they won because they have one of those tiny disclaimers at the bottom of their menu that said the veggie pizzas weren&apos;t actually vegetarian. so i would really double check. it might just be his store, but i&apos;m not sure...
 Saturday, April 28, 2007 1:49:00 AM Hippie Vegan said... 
I just emailed Tumbleweed and found out that their Bean Burritos with enchilada sauce are vegan without the cheese. Just FYI if there is a Tumbleweed near you. Also the Santa Fe rice is not vegan...it contains chicken broth:(
 Wednesday, May 02, 2007 8:10:00 PM Sarah Elayna said... 
Barros pizza dough is vegan as well as the breadsticks as long as you ask with absolutely nothing on them. :]
 Saturday, May 12, 2007 7:43:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
I worked at einstein bagels and i found that there is l cysteine in the bagels. Is it animal derived or plant derived?
 Wednesday, May 23, 2007 12:39:00 AM Anonymous
said... This comment has been removed by a blog administrator. Tuesday, June 05, 2007 10:26:00 PM Harrison said... 
Potbelly Sandwhich Works - Veggie sub w/o cheese or mayo (ask them to put the hot peppers on BEFORE it goes through the oven if you&apos;re a hawtie)
 Thursday, June 21, 2007 11:27:00 AM Kim said... 
Great list, but many Boca/Veggie burgers are not vegan. Have you checked them out? If so, thanks you&apos;ve done a lot of work for us.

Kim
 Thursday, June 28, 2007 9:09:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
the french toast sticks are burger king are NOT vegan, burger king lists the &quot;natural and artifical flavors&quot; as both plant&amp;animal derived.

pretty much nothing at taco bell is vegan.
- the rice is cooked with chicken stock.
-the soft shells have DATEM in them. but i&apos;m not sure about the hard shells.
-and the refried beans have pork fat in them.

but there is still tons of awesome info here! thanks!
 Thursday, July 26, 2007 3:05:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Hi,
Cool site. There is some misinformation to clear up. According to Taco Bell&apos;s website:

Beans, tortillas, potatoes, and flatbread, have no animal ingredients, as well as a few other things, see the detailed ingredients PDF link below. Now that I have read that though, I won&apos;t eat there again, too may additives and weird stuff.
-Ami

http://www.yum.com/nutrition/documents/tb_ingredient_statement.pdf
 Sunday, July 29, 2007 2:43:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
For some reason my link cuts off and will not post. For the info, go to Taco Bell&apos;s site and click on tab that says &quot;Nutition Guide&quot; then it will show the ingredient statment.

-Ami
 Sunday, July 29, 2007 2:50:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
Taco Bell&apos;s rice IS vegan and their refried beans contain no lard.
It is by far the most vegetarian/vegan friendly fast food restaurant.
 Monday, August 13, 2007 1:33:00 PM Amy said... 
But Taco Bell isn&apos;t all that vegan because the soft shells contain DATEM which is most likely animal derived.

It can be plant derived though, but I&apos;m erring on the side of caution until I hear back from Taco Bell.
 Thursday, August 16, 2007 12:26:00 AM Kevin said... 
Even if the food is vegan keep in mind that by buying fast food you are supporting the industry and helping fund some of the top companies that use animal products. Fast food resturants are incredibly detrimental to the planet as well considering all the land/resources they use, the high cost for low price.
 Sunday, September 16, 2007 2:59:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
I have trouble trusting anything a company tells me. I would like to see the packages start to finish myself. Oviously I am looking for easy options but it seems like quite a leap of faith. Not to mention that fast food turned me veg in the first place. I just think that there is a good chance that there will be some misunderstanding and miscommunications. Or blaten lies.

BOCA (which is a subsidary of KRAFT) published products on their website as being vegan when they were clearly not. They stated that some products had been made vegan recently so check the label to make sure. I wrote to them and let them know that almost all of the products advertised contained egg white (no brainer). I accused them of tricking people and hiding behind their &quot;check the label&quot; disclaimer. To my knowledge most of these products still contain egg white and are still being advertised as vegan.

Think about the people you are dealing with when you contact these companies. To believe them on a whim would be like believing them if they said their products are healthy.

P.S. BOCA seemed awfuly eager to send me free stuff concerning this matter. So, if you want some coupons then write them a letter about it. Link is on the site.
 Monday, September 17, 2007 12:02:00 AM Anonymous
said... This comment has been removed by a blog administrator. Monday, September 17, 2007 12:55:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
Brueggers &quot;minestrone&quot; soup has BACON flavoring in it. Maybe the soup varies by ingredients by market. Tricky...
 Thursday, October 11, 2007 4:35:00 PM Green said... 
The best thing is to just eat a bowl of lettuce and tomatoes, most fast food places can do this as they use lettuce and tomatoes for their burgers or tacos etc.
 Tuesday, October 30, 2007 4:16:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
The list is pretty good. However, french fries at most extablishments on the list have meat by-products added to give it &quot;flavor.&quot; There was a law suit a while back against McD&apos;s by vegetarian and Indian (from India) over eating fries that turned out not to be vegetarian.
Outside of that I was impress with the list. It looked as if a lot of thoughtful work went into it.
Phillip
 Saturday, November 03, 2007 11:10:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
Would anyone be interested in starting up a vegan fast food restaurant and convience store?
Phillip
runpacer@gmail.com
 Saturday, November 03, 2007 11:14:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
Xanthum gum is a naturally occuring fermented food product made from vegetables and sugars under a particular bacterial strain. it is vegan unless you want to sweep all your food of bacteria! Lol!
 Wednesday, November 14, 2007 8:25:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
If you all are so focused on being &quot;vegan&quot; then why are you even eating taco bell? It&apos;s not at all a healthy place to eat. Being vegan isn&apos;t just about the animal products, it&apos;s also about health and the quality of the food we put into our bodies. Lets get our priorities straight.
 Thursday, December 06, 2007 4:24:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Why are some people getting all uppity about this list? If you&apos;re vegan and you don&apos;t want to eat fast food, then don&apos;t. I don&apos;t see why it&apos;s necessary to tantrum over those who do eat vegan fast food. If you&apos;re so opposed to vegan fast food options, why are you even looking at this list in the first place? Also, not all vegans are vegan for their own health reasons, so criticizing people for eating fast food because it&apos;s unhealthy doesn&apos;t make a whole lot of sense. There are a lot of vegans who are vegan because they care about defending the welfare of animals who can&apos;t defend themselves. As far as I&apos;m concerned, every little bit counts, and giving people a hard time for eating vegan fast food is counterproductive. Maybe you should spend more time trying to encourage non-vegans to cut out animal products and less time complaining about vegans who eat fast food. Anyway, you can eat fast food once in a while and still be healthy, so calm yourselves.
 Friday, December 14, 2007 11:37:00 AM NattY CaKeS
said... 
Here is a great reference to what different ingreadients are used in different food brands, restaurants, and fast food chains! FYI Quizno&apos;s bread DOES have whey in it, the L-Cysteine is synthetic. I read this information from the Director of Quizno&apos;s quality assurance on this site, subway bread is no good either =( honey, stearoyl-2-lactylate, mono and diglycerides are used.

This is a great great site! Hard to manuever around, but once you get the hang of it, it&apos;s wonderful!
 Friday, December 28, 2007 12:44:00 PM NattY CaKeS
said... 
I guess it would help if I posted the link!! ha ha.

http://www.whatisinit.com/frames/frames/whatisinit_new.htm
 Friday, December 28, 2007 12:45:00 PM natty cakes
said... 
it didn&apos;t paste the whole thing...

http://www.whatisinit.com/frames/frames/whatisinit_new.htm

oh. and the italian bread is no good too... it contains everything the wheat does except the honey. All of the breads, wraps, rolls contain mono&amp;di glycerides which are animal fat. The alternative would be vegetable glycerides. Hope it works this time.
 Friday, December 28, 2007 12:53:00 PM EvoMan
said... 
This list does not take into account bleached flour. For instance, it is stated that the baked apple pie at McDonald&apos;s is vegan, however, when you check their site it states they use bleached wheat flour and a sugar that may or may not be bleached as well. There may be other discrepancies, but I will simply check the ingredients myself. Thanks for the list though, it gives somewhere to start. =)
 Tuesday, January 01, 2008 8:12:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Thanks for the list but just thinking...

Why sell yourself out and eat some junk at taco bell, for example? If you&apos;re vegan, why support a company whose practices largely are not?

If you can, just plan ahead - pull together your own meals. No question of what&apos;s in them then.
 Tuesday, January 08, 2008 11:32:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
If you go to Taco Bell&apos;s website, and look under &quot;Food Facts&quot;, read the answer to question #9--there is no lard in the refried beans.
 Saturday, February 02, 2008 12:09:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Hey, peoples, STOP dissing this list! Some of us (not you, of course, oh high and mighty anonymous number whatever!) have no choice but to eat out sometimes, eg those of us who live in omni households! It&apos;s only a few people, but still annoying as anything.
Anyways, thanks for posting! (And, fellow commenters, thanks for confirming/ refuting the list!) I&apos;d just like to say that McDonalds puts a small print at the bottom of their nutrition facts, saying that they can&apos;t confirm that anything that they sell is veg. Nope, not even the soda. So that should probably be everyone&apos;s LAST choice.
As for Taco Bell, I&apos;ve asked in different ones and it DOES depend on the place. We have two within fifteen miles of each other, and one has a vegan bean burrito, the other&apos;s isn&apos;t even vegetarian. So it&apos;s always best to ask!
 Sunday, February 03, 2008 2:09:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
I am a vegan diabetic. Even though I usually avoid fast food like the plague, I occasionally find myself out somewhere and in desperate need of vegan food fast. This list is valuable. Those of you who are complaining about it just need to STFU. Knowledge is power.
 Sunday, February 17, 2008 2:53:00 PM Justin
said... 
FYI everyone-- Johnny Rockets&apos; onion rings contain whey, and hence (and sadly) are not vegan.

You can check the ingredients to all of their menu items here:

http://www.johnnyrockets.com/themenu/ingredients.php
 Monday, March 03, 2008 6:28:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Hippie Vegan..
this is listed on the FAQ for Red Robins:
Do you currently have vegetarian offerings on your menu?

At most Red Robin locations, we offer meatless options as well as Boca Burgers and/or Garden Burgers, which can be substituted for any of our more than 20 gourmet burger selections. In addition, we are happy to customize other selections to meet your dietary preferences.

If your dietary preference is vegan, please note that currently Red Robin does not have any specific vegan menu items available. However, we are always happy to customize any of our salads or menu items for our Guests. Just ask your server and they will be happy to accommodate you in any way they can.
 Thursday, April 24, 2008 4:05:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
hate to break it to ya but I think taco bells beans have lard in them.
 Thursday, May 01, 2008 12:17:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
sorry guys,
but i work at noodles and company.
and the only vegan options include the japanese pan noodles and the indonesian peanut saute. both the penne rosa and pasta fresca have unfriendly products in the sauces they put in.

one interesting thing, however, is that at noodles locations where they have switched from the &quot;rustic roll&quot; to the new &quot;ciabatta roll&quot;, the new ciabatta roll is vegan.


:]
enjoy.
 Thursday, May 08, 2008 2:17:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
At my local Einstein Bro. Bagels I was told that the bagels are NOT vegan and have eggs.

Also, the CheBurgerCheBurger near me said that their was dairy in the Boca Burgers they use.
 Thursday, May 08, 2008 5:38:00 PM Katie
said... 
Hey! Just wanted to say thanks for the list. I&apos;ve been a vegetarian for a couple years and just became vegan and this was incredibly helpful. I know fast food isn&apos;t healthy, but it&apos;s often inevitable especially with non-vegan family and friends.

Also Taco Bell beans and rice are definitely vegan. I&apos;ve had multiple trustworthy vegan help sites confirm that.
 Wednesday, June 18, 2008 11:42:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
Thanks so much to chose from when traveling!
At noodles you can ask for them to hold the cream on the pesto. Very good
 Friday, June 20, 2008 3:50:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
i work at Domino&apos;s Pizza and
the hand tossed crust and thin crust are completely vegan..the sauce is also vegan as well.the deepdish crust contains milk..the cina stix(w/o butter) are also vegan(the icing is animal free as far as i know)..the butter says it is vegetable oil with natural flavoring, but im not 100% sure what these &quot;natural flavors&quot; are.Oh and the bread sticks are vegan too(w/o butter and w/o the garlic shake,as it contains cheese).the marinara sauce says nothing of milk powder.im pretty sure the only sauce&apos;s that aren&apos;t vegan would be the ranch and the blue cheese.
 Thursday, July 17, 2008 12:13:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Alright, first off, FUCK MCDONALDS! That place is not vegan period. I don&apos;t think one could call themselves veggitarian or vegan if they eat there. Also, question: Quizno why were subs not listed?
 Friday, July 18, 2008 6:02:00 PM Ian said... 
thank you, I am going to print this out and keep it in my glove box. The wife and I love road trips.
thanks again
 Wednesday, July 23, 2008 1:24:00 AM Jocelyn
said... 
Chipotle!! Their guacamole has cheese! Be careful and Wendy&apos;s now says they use the same fryers for the chicken.
 Monday, August 04, 2008 8:36:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
i dont think the guacamole has cheese in it. they have a great website with ingredients listed.

basically we are all given conflicting opinions of what &apos;vegan&apos; is, so dont trust any of them! whenever i even tell people im vegan they never understand how strict it is! i guess the four main things to stay away from are whey, milk, eggs, honey? oh and carcass of course :) it becomes so confusing b/c a lot of these places dont list things as vegan but you can make it vegan.
 Friday, August 08, 2008 1:20:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
crap! chipotles flour tortillas are not vegan as they contain gluten. go to their website and click allergins
 Friday, August 08, 2008 1:25:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
NO!!!!!!!!!!

Jimmy John Bread is NOT Vegan!!! And they wont event tell you... call them and ask...

217-356-9900

They will tell you to email the owner...and it will take you multiple emails for weeks and weeks before you get a response...but it is NOT Vegan...Jimmy Johns BAD BAD BAD
 Sunday, August 24, 2008 4:44:00 AM colin
said... 
gluten is safe! (right?)

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gluten

i got worried when you said chipotle wasn&apos;t safe (though there are always the bowl things instead of tortillas)
 Monday, August 25, 2008 2:07:00 PM The Ember said... 
To the guy two posts up...take heart! Gluten comes from grains, like wheat, rye, and barley, not animals. Something can contain gluten and still be vegan.

Just thought I&apos;d chime in!
 Monday, August 25, 2008 2:08:00 PM Vegan Eating Out said... 
My website, Vegan Eating Out, has a large list of vegan menu items updated daily:

 Vegan Fast Food and Restaurant Menu 
 Monday, September 01, 2008 12:40:00 AM Annie said... 
With all due respect, does anyone care about the chemical shit storm in these foods? I could be wrong, but...
 Monday, September 15, 2008 12:31:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Annie - yes, yes I do. But sometimes your 90 year old Grandma wants to take you out to eat to thank you for work done around her house, and as much as she supports your veganism, she won&apos;t take no for an answer. So while it&apos;s generally (or always) best to avoid these places, it&apos;s good to know what there is out there if you need it.
 Monday, September 15, 2008 7:21:00 PM Annie said... 
Roger that Anonymous!
 Monday, September 15, 2008 7:34:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Thank you for the list.

Little Caesar&apos;s Pizza, Crazy Bread is not vegan. They put butter and cheese on the bread.
 Wednesday, October 22, 2008 12:32:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Have you ever heard of L-cysteine, it is commonly, but not always made from human hair, and pig hair, and horse hair. Most large producers of bagels and breads have this ingredient in it. For example, all Panera Bread bagels, and some of their breads have it. They do have a full ingredient list at every cafe, so you know what is safe and what isn&apos;t.
 Tuesday, November 18, 2008 3:07:00 PM HollywoodHexKitten said... 
Are any of these items soy-free? I&apos;m pretty sure a large amount of them aren&apos;t.

I&apos;m a former vegan who became an omnivore after I found out I was allergic to soy and also had a thyroid problem (soy blocks the thyroid. don&apos;t believe the hype that it doesn&apos;t. it&apos;s highly likely it wrecked my thyroid in the first place).

I also can&apos;t eat anything made from white flour, anything with a lot of sugar in it, cabbage, kale, collards, mustard, peanut butter/peanuts, broccoli, Brussels sprouts, and a ton of other things.

Is there ANYTHING on this list that I can eat? Lol. =/

I&apos;m trying to find a way to be a vegan or at least lacto or ovo-lacto vegetarian again and still meet all my health requirements for all of my health issues (hypothyroid, endometriosis, Stein-Leventhal Syndrome, epilepsy, and TMJ disorder [that one really doesn&apos;t affect my food choices much] ), and not aggravate any of my food sensitivities/allergies.

I MIGHT be able to do this at home, but eating out could be a big problem.

Anybody else have similar problems that could offer me some advice?
 Wednesday, November 26, 2008 4:10:00 PM HollywoodHexKitten said... 
Oh, I forgot to ask, how can walnuts not be vegan?

And can you possibly link me to some of the sites that list this type of thing by region? I&apos;ve never heard of half of the restaurants on this list, lol.

Also, I currently live in the boondocks, so it&apos;s really difficult to find this kind of thing. A regional list would be of big help.
 Wednesday, November 26, 2008 4:13:00 PM HollywoodHexKitten said... 
Sorry for the flood, but I forgot to mention that I also cannot have anything with sage in it, for anyone who can help me out with some food choices that I won&apos;t get sick or die from, lol. :S

And to the person who was concerned about something that said &quot;bacon flavoring&quot;, it might not be real bacon. A lot of times it&apos;s just Baco-Bits and things like that, and as far as I can remember, those are made out of soy, not meat, &apos;cause I&apos;m pretty sure I ate those on salads sometimes when I was a vegan.
 Wednesday, November 26, 2008 4:48:00 PM Steph said... 
I work at Northern Lights when I&apos;m home from school which is in Iowa/Kansas/Missouri and NOTHING there is vegan. All the crust has milk and butter in it and all the sauces have cheese, just a heads up.

I also work at NAKED Pizza in New Orleans and our NAKED Bagels are vegan and our pizzas are vegan as long as you hold the cheese...and I&apos;m trying to get my boss to get some vegan mozzarella when I get back. Just an FYI in case you&apos;re from either area =)

Oh and THANKS for the list it helps a lot when friends want to eat out!! (I only have ONE vegan friend).
 Monday, January 05, 2009 9:01:00 PM Caroline said... 
I&apos;m a vegetarian-recently-turned-vegan who is constantly so busy/on my way to somewhere that I often have to stop at a fast food restaurant to get something affordable and quick to eat. I appreciate this list so much, especially since I have a road trip to make tomorrow and now I won&apos;t have to worry about waking up extra early to pack a meal! Thank you!!
 Friday, January 30, 2009 2:13:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
McD&apos;s are a crowd of w*nkers anyway, they are trying to kill us all AND make profit. That goes for omni&apos;s and vegans alike!
I wouldn&apos;t indulge there if you paid me.
Back when I first became vegan, when my friends use to always eat McD&apos;s, I would just sit there staring at the oozing animal lard coming from the fries and flesh. I had a salad w/o the dressing or cheese once or twice but then decided there was no point as i don&apos;t even want to support them in any way. When I was all calorie-conscious I use to carry around there nutritional info sheet n my purse, but that&apos;s another story.

On another note, good effort and list for the vegans eating FF.

-A-
 Thursday, March 05, 2009 1:12:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Taco Bell has lists of ingredients online for viewing. It looks as though they keep updating their recipes to keep as much animal products out of as many things as possible. The beans are now animal product free and so is the rice which used to contain casein. Even the lime red tortilla strips used to have milk, but no longer due. Here is the link:

http://www.yum.com/nutrition/documents/tb_ingredient_statement.pdf

FYI: I love to get double decker tacos with just beans, guacamole, and lettuce. They rock!
 Sunday, March 15, 2009 9:08:00 PM Former Pizza Hut employee said... 
Pizza Hut&apos;s Handtossed Dough uses Sucralose (i.e. Splenda) as an ingredient. I suggest staying away from it.

Only safe options at Pizza Hut is Thin Crust + any sauce + any combination of veggies.

Breadsticks are to be avoided as well. They use unhealthy emulsifiers in the dough.
 Saturday, April 18, 2009 7:53:00 PM Melody said... 
if you are ever in brooklyn, ny you can go to an ALL VEGAN fast food joint, Foodswings. :)
http://myspace.com/foodswings
 Monday, May 04, 2009 5:41:00 PM Leanne Hilgart said... 
fabulous super helpful list. thanks for all your hard work- I really appreciate it!
 Monday, May 25, 2009 7:25:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
i went to panera today and just as an fyi the bread that the mediterrean veggie sandwich comes on [tomatosomething] is basted with egg whites so it&apos;s not vegan. the cashier recommended multi-grain bread instead. =]
 Tuesday, May 26, 2009 5:18:00 AM Joyce P. Simkin said... 
According to Pizza Hut&apos;s newest nutrition information (http://www.pizzahut.com/Nutrition.aspx 4/17/2009), the hand-tossed crust contains milk. So it&apos;s no longer vegan.
 Friday, June 26, 2009 3:42:00 PM Nick Birge said... 
I love this, thanks for all the help! Heres an email I just received fro Red Robin. Put it on up there! haha. Much love.

&quot;Thank you for your e-mail. We appreciate your inquiry.

At Red Robin, you may customize any menu item, or create your own entrée with available food ingredients, to meet your dietary needs. For instance, any of our available salads can be made vegan by removing meat, cheese, and egg (where applicable).

While our Garden&amp;Boca Burgers are not vegan, other choices include Red&apos;s Rice Bowl, minus the fried linguini and chicken. Vegan ingredients to chose from and customize your own order include: black beans, rice, a side salad, steamed veggies, melon wedges, celery sticks, Steak Fries, if fried in a designated fryer (please inquire with the manager), and a wide variety of fresh produce items.

Thank you for choosing Red Robin!
Red Robin Guest Relations&quot;
 Tuesday, June 30, 2009 6:29:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Thanks a lot for this list. I just became vegan one month ago. I was not vegetarian before this, I went straight from omni to vegan. I am still attempting to learn what is vegan friendly and what is not, so I am still making mistakes, but lists like this help greatly.

If you find yourself in situations of travel or times where you need to eat out, spend an extra ten minutes by stopping by a grocery store and picking up some fruit and grains or buying a vegetarian chili along with some whole wheat bread, I have found this combination to be much more fulfilling and pleasurable then going out to fast food. One of my friends whom is vegan managed to hardly ever eat fast food with us, even though we were all omni, for around three years. Chipotle was probably his only exception.
 Saturday, July 04, 2009 1:28:00 AM Dee said... 
i would like to point at that Houston&apos;s veggie burger is not only not vegan like claimed, but it is not even vegetarian. after eating it for 10 years, i finally learned that there is fish oil in the sweet soy sauce they put on it. this is in addition to them carrying NO vegan bread, adding cheese, mayo, and not having vegetarian ketchup. if you want the burger vegan, you have to say VEGAN and hope they understand what it means.
 Monday, July 20, 2009 9:40:00 AM VegPanda said... 
I&apos;d really hate to break it to you. But as far as I know, Noodles and Co. Cook all their stuff in the same pans, so you risk yours noodles and tofu to be cooked in a pan that had meat product or dairy.

Panera Bagels aren&apos;t Vegan thanks to the amino acid l-cysteine used
in the bagels. [L-cysteine is derived from an animal source according to the email I received from Panera]
 Tuesday, September 08, 2009 12:44:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
I work at Domino&apos;s Pizza and the hand tossed is NOT vegan. It contains milk. Same for the deep dish and pasts bowls. Vegan items include thin crust, all veggies, pizza sauce, garlic seasoning, sandwich bread, marinara dip, habanero sauce, crushed peppers, and garlic dip. I like the Pacific Veggie minus pizza cheese, minus feta cheese. When you order, tell them&quot;write in big letters&apos;DO NOT CUT!&apos;on the box sticker&quot;because the pizza cutter is ALWAYS contaminated with grease!
 Monday, November 02, 2009 2:57:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
i didn&apos;t read, so i don&apos;t know if someone said this already, but Wendy&apos;s fries list fish as an allergen on the ingredients.
 Wednesday, December 16, 2009 8:18:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
to whoever said taco bell beans aren&apos;t vegan, you are wrong. they do not have lard in them, i worked there for several years as a vegan and i know that the beans rice are both vegan.
 Wednesday, December 16, 2009 9:10:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
xantham gum is just a binder that holds everything together. It sometimes takes the place of eggs and in gluten free recipes is a necessity or everything will fall apart. :)
 Saturday, January 09, 2010 1:06:00 PM Anthony E.
said... 
I just stumbled upon this stuff called Flavor Spray, it&apos;s different sprays each a different flavor. Not 100% sure if it&apos;s all vegan but something to like in to.

http://flavor-spray.com/
 Tuesday, January 12, 2010 3:21:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
Going back to the L-cysteine/ cysteine/ cystine discussion, if it were derived from human hair, it would still be disgusting, but would it be non-vegan? I&apos;ve read that the hair is often collected from barber shops, so no one was harmed in the collection of it...
 Friday, January 15, 2010 11:55:00 PM Davi said... 
Hello all this is regarding Taco Bell. People are going on and on about the beans. I did find that the beans are technically vegan but the beans still contain something that I don&apos;t think people should consume. It a nice chemical called TBHQ. For those of you that don&apos;t know what it is According to A Consumer&apos;s Dictionary of Food Additives, TBHQ is a form of butane (i.e. lighter fluid) the FDA allows processors to use sparingly in our food: It can comprise no more than 0.02 percent of the oil in a nugget. Which is probably just as well, considering that ingesting a single gram of TBHQ can cause&quot;nausea, vomiting, ringing in the ears, delirium, a sense of suffocation, and collapse.&quot;Ingesting five grams of TBHQ can kill.

Think about it. Do you still want that in your system?
 Wednesday, February 03, 2010 3:00:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Denny&apos;s has vegan Boca burgers available.

And I&apos;m sure all processed and fast food contains chemicals like TBHQ.
 Sunday, February 14, 2010 10:49:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
Wendy&apos;s fries do not contain fish, this is taken from their website:
&quot;Note: may be cooked in the same oil as Fish Fillets (where available), Crispy Chicken Nuggets, Crispy Chicken Patty, Boneless Wings and Spicy Chicken Nuggets. Seasoned with Salt.&quot;
 Sunday, February 14, 2010 10:54:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
I can&apos;t stand the hypocrites telling everyone to stop supporting fast food joints by eating there. You may as well stop buying anything at supermarkets because they stock tons of animal products. Think before you speak, there is virtually no way to live a 100% completely vegan lifestyle - your vegetables and grain are grown in soil fertilized with animal manure, most health food brands are owned by much larger corporations that also own brands that use animal products, and you have most likely consumed some type of preservative/food dye/natural flavor that had an animal source since going vegan. The point is everyone does the best they can to live a 100% cruelty free lifestyle - there is no reason to come in here and complain that people who support fast food places are not&quot;true&quot;vegans. Get off your high horse.
 Sunday, February 14, 2010 11:03:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
Taco Bell rice is NOT vegan. It contains Casein which is a protein derived from milk. Yum! Brands (own Taco Bell) posted their ingredients online.

I&apos;m pretty bummed about this because the rice on my fresco bean burrito was heavenly for awhile.
 Friday, February 19, 2010 11:14:00 AM shilpa said... 
Established in 1997, St. Gregorious Edu-Guidance is a leading education consultancy services providing exemplary service to students all over India. We deal in Admissions to all major professional courses in Premier Institutes across India. We are your one step solution for all career related needs, it may be MD, MBBS BE, BTech (ALL BRANCHES), , MDS, BDS, BPharm, BArch, MBA, MTech, MS, , PhD or any other courses. We provide personalized career solutions on an individual basis keeping in mind the aspirations of our client as well as the affordability factor.
FOR ALL CAREER RELATED NEEDS CONTACT US :
St. Gregorious Edu-Guidance,
#2, 2nd Floor,
J J Complex, Above Chemmannur Jewellers,
Marthahalli - P O,
Bangalore - 560037
Karnataka
e-mail :jojishpaily@gmail.com
Contact: +91 9448516637
+91 9886089896, +91 9449009983
080-32416570, 41719562
Website: www.stgregoriousedu.com
 Monday, February 22, 2010 6:40:00 AM Liana said... 
I work at Swenson&apos;s (how did it even end up on this list? It only exists in Northeastern Ohio)...anyway, a Veggie Special comes with honey mustard, which contains mayonnaise and is definitely not vegan. I&apos;m not sure if our buns contain eggs or not, but it&apos;s a possibility.
 Monday, February 22, 2010 9:56:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Your Noodles entry needs to be updated. This is what they say on their site:

While there is no commonly accepted definition for vegan, we define
it as menu items that don’t contain meat, fish, dairy, eggs or other
animal products. If your definition matches ours, try these menu items:
- Indonesian Peanut Sauté
- Japanese Pan Noodles
- Chinese Chop Salad with no wontons
- Penne Rosa with no cream and no cheese
- Pasta Fresca with no cheese
- Whole Grain Tuscan Linguine with no cream and no cheese
- Spaghetti with no cheese
- Cucumber Tomato Salad
- Tossed Green Side Salad with balsamic vinaigrette
 Tuesday, February 23, 2010 10:20:00 PM Danielle said... 
My husband and I just became Vegans a couple months ago so I have been e-mail companys about vegan things.

Einstein Bro. Bagels told me that the bagels are NOT vegan and have eggs and animals products in there bagels.

Also, the CheBurgerCheBurger near me said that their was dairy in the Boca Burgers they use.(West Palm Beach City Place, Florida)

Also, I e-mailed carabarra&apos;s and chilis and then sent me a list of everything they have that is vegan and what to ask for (to make it vegan. I made copies of the e-mail and keep it in our vehicles for when we are out and hungry.

Also, California pizza kitchen as a part on the site that says vegan options as well.

Hope this helps!!!
 Saturday, February 27, 2010 4:56:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
I&apos;ve been vegan for 10 years, if u truly want to not consume animal products you should buy the book Animal Ingredients A-Z and u will realize 85% of the things on this list contain animal ingredients. Things deep fried in the same oil as fish and chicken absorb the fat from these animals. Most breads contain mono-dyglycerids which is animal fat. Whey is from milk. The list goes on and on. Who ever made this list didn&apos;t take ANY of these things into consideration, and this list should be a&quot;strict vegetarian&quot;fast food list not a vegan fast food list. Most breaded deep fried foods have egg in them also.&quot;Natural Flavoring&quot;can be from anything&quot;natural&quot;including animals. I mean I could go on and on but I just wanted to let people know if u truly want to eat vegan food do not listen to this list.
 Saturday, March 20, 2010 6:13:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
on coldstone&apos;s website, it says that all of their smoothies and sorbet are non-dairy.
 Wednesday, March 31, 2010 6:35:00 PM Stephanie
said... 
The Little Ceasars website says that the&quot;crazy bread&quot;is vegan only when it is order w/o parmeasam just fyi. It is still the most fantastic snack EVER! yum
 Tuesday, April 20, 2010 1:43:00 PM egen glover said... 
great article i&apos;d have to agree on those restaurants! there are a lot more options than people think!
 Tuesday, May 04, 2010 12:43:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
I work at Jimmy Johns - the bread is NOT vegan. But you can get a vegetarian sub as an unwich (wrapped in lettuce) without cheese or mayo, but be advised that all of the ingredients are prepared on the same cutting board, so it is possible that your veggies will have touched meat juice/mayo. The plain and reduced-fat chips are made with potatoes, peanut/sunflower oil, and sea salt as the only ingredients, so they are vegan. The salt&amp;vinegar chips contain lactose (from milk). I&apos;m not sure about the barbeque and jalapeno chips. The pickles are vegan; the cookies are not.
 Monday, May 31, 2010 10:50:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
I appreciate the stance of Vegans; however, attempting to convert people usually comes easier when one is not so judgmental or immature in her responses. Also, I found it interesting that you have allowed Google to place ads on your blog (for which I presume you receive payment or a deal), and the top ad is for a restaurant that provides dishes to omnivores (Jimmy John&apos;s Sandwiches
5 Subs Less than 4 Grams of Fat Hold the Mayo. Click, Order, Eat!
www.JimmyJohns.com.). It just seems a bit hypocritical.

That said, I found much of your information useful and plan to use some of it in my current project, part of which is the process of converting to a Vegetarian (and eventually Vegan) lifestyle.

So, while I understand you are attempting to gather supporters, because of many of your self righteousness replies&amp;comments, I am choosing not to sign up for your blog. However, I will continue to move toward Vegan lifestyle because I think it&apos;s the right thing to do for me.

While I disagree a bit with your approach, I do appreciate the fact that as a high school student, you were and are willing to take a stand on something in which you believe.

Good luck to you!
 Thursday, June 03, 2010 1:24:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
i just cant believe that taco bell doesnt have any lard of any kind, no animal fat wut so eva?! Meowza that be crazy
Also, I really wish that fast food would make something more substantial on their menus for us vegans or vegan enthusiasts! Yeah i know the strawberry jam is vegan as well as the salad, but if im gonna drive to ur dang drive thru i want some damn protien of the plant kind, but then again that is the fast food world for ye, plus i dont really rely on fast food anyway

facebook.com/daniekat
 Friday, June 11, 2010 5:21:00 AM Alberto said... 
 viagra online 
 buy viagra 
 generic viagra 
 Monday, June 21, 2010 2:12:00 PM ali
said... 
Thanks for all the info, i&apos;ve been vegetarian for 11 years and thinking of becoming a Vegan now. The more I look into ingredients of things, the more discusted I become with companys! Just a heads up for everyone, Chilis chips are not vegan in my opinion. On their website, under the vegan menu it says that there fried foods (chips, fish, shrimp, chicken..etc.) are all cooked in one fryer and share the same oil. I called the local Chili&apos;s and spoke with a manager she confirmed that they use the same fryer, and told me they reuse the oil til its gone.. there fore there chips are covered in animal oil prettymuch. Can anyone help me figure out what Datem is? It&apos;s in most bread products, ive been told its not vegan and I cant get a exact definition on google..
 Thursday, July 01, 2010 3:33:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
mcdonalds apple pies are not vegan, they have l-cystine derived from duck feathers. thanks for the sweet blog!
 Tuesday, July 06, 2010 1:57:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
its odd to me that this list that was said to b derived from the pita site has so many false claims on it.i dont think whoever made this blog really knows what the word&quot;vegan&quot;means.if some of these items are not vegan(which for suuuuure some of them arnt)then i would not trust this list at all.its a shame that u made this list with so much confidence and guided so many people with good intensions to eating non vegan food.super weak.
 Wednesday, July 07, 2010 12:37:00 AM Kray
said... 
Anonymous above is an idiot. Not only can they not type correctly, but they are assuming that this list contains products that are labeled vegan falsely.

If you read the date of the entry, which was posted in 2006, you can see that there might be outdated information. If you aren&apos;t intelligent enough to check it out yourself and would rather complain and rant against an outdated post, perhaps you should just keep your comments to yourself.
 Tuesday, July 20, 2010 1:04:00 PM chelsea-rae
said... 
well, last time i checked.. PETAs list of vegan stuff has golden graham cereal on it.. which clearly contains honey. they also have a disclaimer stating that they consider foods that are 99% vegan to be vegan. otherwise, people wouldn&apos;t eat them and the companies might just opt to use animal products since it&quot;wouldn&apos;t make a difference&quot;.. it&apos;s all about what YOU think.. stop bashing other people and let them have their opinions.
 Saturday, August 21, 2010 10:49:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
an employee at jimmy johns told me that they use pork lard in their bread to give it that&quot;je ne se quois&quot;i am allergic to pork and now understand why i was getting stomach cramps every time i ate the veggie sandwich there. i stopped eating there because i got sick every time.
 Tuesday, September 21, 2010 2:47:00 PM Kayla said... 
i used to work at panera bread so i know all of the vegan options:
the bagels and many of the breads (including ciabatta) contain mono-diglycerides, which are (sometimes) not vegan. it&apos;s virtually impossible to trace where they get it, as i tried at my cafe to no avail.
any of the whole grain/multigrain/etc. breads have honey in them, as well as the tomato basil bread (which is what the med. veg sandwich is served on)
the breads that ARE safe: sourdough, rye, french, country, and sesame.
there&apos;s also other vegan menu options:
many of the salads are vegan (just watch dressings, like caesar, and ask for it on the side, as oftentimes bacon or cheese will fall into the bins that hold dressing on the salad line because they are in the front)
black bean soup is vegan (ask to add the black bean corn mix that they put on the bbq chopped chix salad... it makes it even more delicious)
garden vegetable soup is vegan WITHOUT PESTO. they add the pesto seperately, so just ask for it without.
the med veg sandwich is only vegan if you get it on a different bread and with no cheese. be careful with the hummus. it, like the salad dressings, is in the front, and often will get meat or mayo or some junk in it.
also, the baguettes (french or wg) aren&apos;t vegan. you have to get a different side. you can just ask for a slice of one of the other breads instead though if you&apos;re set on carbs.
 Thursday, November 18, 2010 9:05:00 PM jamieroseblog said... 
Why does the one thing say&quot;without walnuts&quot;? Walnuts are not vegan? Sorry, I&apos;m new to the vegan-world.
 Friday, December 03, 2010 11:39:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
http://koxpcu.yetkin-forum.com

http://guvercin-forum2009.yetkin-forum.com

http://timurtashoca.yetkin-forum.com
 Sunday, December 12, 2010 8:25:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
Taco Bell rice IS vegan and DOES NOT contain casein. Their beans DO Not contain lard or any other animal product. Read or research for yourself; don&apos;t just take some idiot&apos;s opinion who regurgitates what his brainless friends say.

http://www.tacobell.com/nutrition/ingredient-statement

While I am impressed with this blog and appreciate the posting of fast foods that are vegan, I am underwhelmed by the ignorance and snobbishness of many of those posting comments.

Seriously, walnuts aren&apos;t vegan?, gluten is not vegan?, etc. Since those comments don&apos;t appear to be malicious, then we can just chalk them up to pure ignorance.

And as for those who are so concerned over the purity of their vegan lifestyle that they freak out if any of their food even potentially touches the surface of anything that may have touched meat or non-vegan items, or are concerned about purchasing something that enriches a company that is not 100% vegan in everything it does..., really???

If you are that serious, then you should totally isolate yourself from society, grow all your own food, fertilize the ground all with you own waste, and STFU. Because, if that is not the way you are living currently, then there is something that you are doing, buying, contributing to, etc. that is not in 100% complete harmony with your professed vegan&quot;pureness&quot;and you are nothing more nor less than a hypocrite.
 Monday, December 27, 2010 7:03:00 PM DbSaint said... 
About Macaroni Grill–their fresh pasta&apos;s have eggs in them, and furthermore, tell them not to put butter on your pasta, because they put butter on it by default!!!
 Thursday, January 06, 2011 11:28:00 AM rancidcoucous said... 
coldstones whey in their sorbets is derived from milk.
not vegan.
if more people request soy or dairy free ice cream corporate might finally be convinced to change this.
so ask away! :)
 Tuesday, January 11, 2011 7:10:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
On Burger King&apos;s website it says that they fry the onion rings along with fried meat items. But the fries are cooked in a separate fryer.
 Thursday, January 27, 2011 10:52:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
To the person who said In-N-Out! burder without the burger/sauce



I loved eating there and also told them not to grill the bun (grilled with the meat patty next to it on the same grill) untill I found out the buns have EGG in them. BEWARE!
 Saturday, March 05, 2011 1:09:00 PM Jenny said... 
Thank you so much for that amazing list. That makes my cravings for fast food a lot easier to handle :) I am vegan for 6 month now and still having a pretty hard time sticking to it.
 Sunday, April 10, 2011 6:57:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
First of all, thank you for all the ffort and time that you&apos;ve put into this list. Second, all the self-righteous vegans out there can kiss my french vegan ass. Some of us are vegans not because we are obsessed our health or appearance but because we don&apos;t want to harm any living sentient beings. If you are vegan for your health-good for you!! Stopp judging others on their food choices- don&apos;t you get judged enough- don&apos;t you know what that feels like moron? The list is a good effort and helpful. And maybe giving money to these businesses isn&apos;t the best idea but if the consumers start taking control and buying vegan or vegetarian. Options maybe the age old supply and demand will kick in and companies will change their ways. Have faith in your fellow humans. And stop being douches. Thanks!
 Saturday, April 23, 2011 12:07:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Boca Burgers or products are not vegan. They use dairy in them as do many, many other products that claim to be&quot;meatless&quot;or vegetarian. Please consider this so as not to mislead vegans who want to avoid cruelty to animals. Thanks
 Friday, May 13, 2011 3:00:00 PM seartho said... 
it&apos;s good to see this information in your post, i was looking the same but there was not any proper resource, thanx now i have the link which i was looking for my research.

Kind Regards,
 oral chelation 
 Saturday, June 11, 2011 9:04:00 AM SENuke X said... 
I value the article post. Cool.
 Friday, June 24, 2011 5:14:00 PM Vegan Fast Food said... 
It&apos;s difficult to find vegan food when eating out. My site, Vegan Eating Out makes it easy with a menu just for vegans on any fast food chain and restaurant you could think of. Check it out!
 Saturday, July 09, 2011 8:01:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Thank you for this list! It is very helpful since I am currently trying to transition into a vegan diet :) but just one thought for those that haven&apos;t worked in fast food like I have: even the lettuce, tomato, other vegetables could have been contaminated with meat or dairy products. I work the dressing table at Steak and Shake and I know personally that sometimes cheese gets into the salad lettuce or tomato bins just by accident! So just a thought, but thank you for the list for clarification on what things are MADE vegan in fast food restaurants :)
 Sunday, July 10, 2011 1:25:00 AM erin said... 
The Penne Rosa at Noodles is NOT vegan. It has cream in the sauce.
 Sunday, July 24, 2011 3:11:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
This list is pretty old but still wanted to leave a comment,

Being Vegan should not only be about the animals but it should also be about your health. Yeah your not killing any animals but your slowly killing yourself. What good does that do?? A dead vegan can&apos;t save any animals.

Also you are supporting factory farms by giving these fast food places your money. So heck you might as well eat the crap then. The best way to stand up for animal rights is not to give mcdonalds your money. And if your so concerned about where your food comes from then go to a farmers market and buy local. At least then you would be supporting something good...your own community.

I know options can sometimes be tough and maybe I am fortunate to live in such a vegan friendly area here in Portland, OR but just decide your options carefully.
 Tuesday, August 16, 2011 4:30:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
this website has good info - http://www.veganeatingout.com/fast-food
 Sunday, August 21, 2011 3:11:00 PM buy vicodin online said... 
Thanks for the informative writing. Would mind updating some good tips about it. I still wait your next place. ;)
 Monday, August 22, 2011 4:05:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Thank you so much for creating this list! I was really skeptical that I would find anything like this out there. It was very helpful!
 Wednesday, August 24, 2011 6:34:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
If more vegans went to fast food and other restaurants and requested low fat vegan items, more places would offer them. If the demand is there, they&apos;ll accommodate it, after all, the only reason these places exist is to make money. So for those of you berating vegans for eating fast food, get off your high horse and go out and change the world!
 Saturday, September 03, 2011 10:17:00 AM best organic seo services said... 
Thanks for your post, I like this post very much.
 Tuesday, September 06, 2011 5:03:00 PM buy xanax online said... 
I really enjoy reading your well written articles. I think you spend numerous effort and time in posting the blog.
 Friday, September 09, 2011 4:21:00 PM buy codeine online said... 
Pretty cool post. I just came across your site and wanted to say that I have really enjoyed browsing your blog posts. Any way I’ll be subscribing to your blog and I hope you write again soon.
 Friday, September 09, 2011 4:21:00 PM best organic seo services said... 
Hi buddy, your blog&apos;s design is simple and clean and i like it. Your blog posts are superb. Please keep them coming. Greets!!!
 Monday, September 12, 2011 6:11:00 PM 4d ultrasounds said... 
Keep Up the good work. Everyone is Opened to there opinion. Excellent blog here,
 Tuesday, September 13, 2011 9:17:00 AM patchwork maquinas de bordar said... 
Hola,
Usted ha hecho un trabajo muy bonito. Hay mucha gente buscando por eso ahora van a encontrar suficientes fuentes de sus extremidades.
espera para obtener más consejos acerca de que
 Wednesday, September 14, 2011 9:44:00 AM watch jersey shore said... 
great share thank sfor th nice read!
 Monday, September 19, 2011 2:48:00 AM buy online vicodin es said... 
Very significant article for us ,I think the representation of this article is actually superb one. This is my first visit to your site
 Monday, September 19, 2011 5:19:00 PM the best seo company said... 
Thanks a lot for sharing this amazing knowledge with us. This site is fantastic. I always find great knowledge from it.
 Wednesday, September 21, 2011 5:56:00 PM Consumer Credit Capital said... 
Yeah the less meat in the diet the better. Throw in a day a week of fasting and you are well on your way to better diet in the western world.
 Thursday, September 22, 2011 12:42:00 AM Organic Vitamins said... 
I agree with you. This post is truly inspiring. I like your post and everything you share with us is current and very informative, I want to bookmark the page so I can return here from you that you have done a fantastic job ...
 Wednesday, September 28, 2011 4:40:00 AM post free classified said... 
I really love to read some articles that have great positive impacts on its reader and benefit by reading such...
 Wednesday, September 28, 2011 1:43:00 PM made.com vouchers said... 
Very worthwhile information, thanks very much. Such an interesting point of view.
 Thursday, September 29, 2011 2:17:00 AM рестораны в барселоне said... 
It can&apos;t work in actual fact, that&apos;s what I think.
 Wednesday, October 05, 2011 7:26:00 AM ginasr vreau sa fac bani ioi said... 
You took a wonderful decision by dedicating yourself to this cause.
 Friday, October 07, 2011 11:31:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
sounds retarded. unless you&apos;re trying to kill the vegans who aren&apos;t awake enough to look at the poisons in 75% of the foods mentioned.
 Monday, October 10, 2011 8:41:00 PM tubal ligation reversal surgery said... 
Thanks for your post, I like this post very much.
 Thursday, October 13, 2011 1:54:00 AM doctor ratings and reviews said... 
Interesting Article. Hoping that you will continue posting an article having a useful information.
 Thursday, October 13, 2011 7:33:00 AM Carpet Cleaning London said... 
I was redirected by google here Carpet Cleaning London and i have to admit that this is the article I really needed! thank you! regularly. Regards :)
 Friday, October 14, 2011 7:32:00 AM Lingerie said... 
Great post. i like it. feeling great when reading your post. The content of the articles there will be a lot of attractive people to appreciate
 Monday, October 17, 2011 1:49:00 AM Generic Viagra said... 
Great information you got here. I&apos;ve been reading about this topic for one week now for my papers in school and thank God I found it here in your blog. I had a great time reading this.
 Saturday, October 22, 2011 8:34:00 AM Thomas said... 
Being a vegan is awesome. I think it will continue to grow with time.
 Tuesday, October 25, 2011 2:57:00 PM fashion icons said... 
To be a fashion icon is really important in today&apos;s materially minded society. Great post by the way.
 Tuesday, October 25, 2011 3:15:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
There is some inaccurate information here!

Taco Bell&apos;s rice is NOT vegan and Jimmy John&apos;s bread is NOT vegan.

I haven&apos;t read the whole list, nor am I familiar with all of the restaurants on the list, so I don&apos;t know if there are any more inaccuracies.

Thank you for your efforts, though! Keep up the good fight!
 Wednesday, November 02, 2011 3:48:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
This is a great list! I did just email the Hard Rock Cafe and they told me the veggie burger (Veggie Leggie) is not vegan. I even asked if it was without the lemon mayo. It is such a disappointment :(
 Monday, November 14, 2011 1:35:00 PM Eden
said... 
Hey, just wanted to let you know that taco bell beans are NOT vegan. They are made with animal lard!!! This is something you should ask about every time you go for Mexican.
 Monday, November 14, 2011 2:59:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
At village inn, they will give your a fruit plate with pineapple, strawberries, cantaloupe, etc. if you ask!
 Tuesday, November 15, 2011 8:21:00 PM Brandon said... 
Okay so I am tired of the Veganazis...we aren&apos;t going to make an impact on the food industry by ignoring the corporations that sale animal based products. By buying from these establishments you effectively say I am one of a large group of people that would prefer more health and Vegan options. The more one patronizes these establishments the more the CEO&apos;s are going to add more healthy and Vegan options.

Being Vegan is subjective. For one person it is abstaining from animal products (while ignoring the fact that soy production, corn production, or wheat production kills animals and destroys the environment just as much). For other people being Vegan is about making health choices. For some being Vegan is a way to stick it to factory farming practices (which are here to stay...sadly...we can only emphasize more responsible farming).

I have a problem with anyone saying being Vegan is this or that. It sounds cultish and turns people off. I would much prefer a world in which we eat food derived exclusively from organic vegetables but it isn&apos;t going to happen by being fascist about it. Its about understanding we are individuals and some of us would prefer options that don&apos;t require tons of preparation or time. Yep some of us were reared on American cuisine and appreciate when a restaurant finds ways (even if inadvertently) to offer Vegan items.

All right soapbox is being pushed back under desk.
 Wednesday, November 30, 2011 8:49:00 PM mulberry outlet said... 
Thanks for your post, I like this post very much.
 Friday, December 09, 2011 12:15:00 PM Anonymous
said... 
Thanks! This is great. Also, for the comments about Einstein&apos;s having eggs? I asked the cashier if they had any vegan bagels he said no, but when he asked if there was any dairy or eggs he said it was only made of yeast. Isn&apos;t yeast vegan or does it vary?
 Tuesday, December 13, 2011 2:10:00 PM viagra australia said... 
Wow, nice post,there are many person searching about that now they will find enough resources by your post.Thank you for sharing to us.Please one more post about that..
 Wednesday, December 14, 2011 11:23:00 PM Classified Ads Haryana said... 
Nice post. We are impressed by your clear description of your topic. Thanks for the information. Keep on writing.
 Thursday, December 15, 2011 2:55:00 PM Houston Seo Company said... 
If you don&apos;t mind my asking, what are your sources for this list ?
 Sunday, December 18, 2011 5:54:00 AM Classified Ads kerala said... 
These kind of post are always inspiring and I prefer to read quality content so I happy to find many good point here in the post, writing is simply great, thank you for the post.
 Sunday, January 01, 2012 5:59:00 AM organic supplements said... 
This is really my very first time here, great looking blog. I discovered so many interesting things inside your blog especially its discussion.
 Monday, January 02, 2012 3:59:00 AM Tariq said... 
Excellent read, I just passed this onto a colleague who was doing a little research on that.

 buy watson 
 Tuesday, January 03, 2012 5:42:00 PM Best Vegetarian Fast Food said... 
Dimple Restaurant is one of the few dinner places providing Best Vegetarian Fast Food to New Jersey people that display awesome in preference.
 best vegetarian fast food 
 Thursday, January 05, 2012 4:46:00 AM medicine forum said... 
Really i appreciate the effort you made to share the knowledge.The topic here i found was really effective to the topic which i was researching for a long time
 Thursday, January 05, 2012 2:29:00 PM alex stewart said... 
I can not stop reading this. And&apos;so fresh, so full of information, I do not know. I&apos;m glad that people actually write the smart way to show the different sides of him.
 buy ritalin online 
 Friday, January 06, 2012 11:03:00 AM find doctors list said... 
This post is very well written. Thanks a lot for writing good quality posts.
 Tuesday, January 17, 2012 1:15:00 AM Colin said... 
I am very happy to find this blog.Thanks for creating the page! Im positive that it will be very popular. It has good and valuable content which is very rare these days.


 buy adderall online 
 Thursday, January 19, 2012 1:24:00 PM dietas online said... 
Este tipo de mensaje inspirador y siempre prefiero leer contenidos de calidad, así que feliz de encontrar muchos puntos buenos aquí en el puesto, la escritura es simplemente genial, gracias por el post.
 Thursday, January 26, 2012 2:39:00 AM Anonymous
said... 
This is great for a list of places to eat overall but as mentioned many times over but, are the ingredients they use at every one of these places, organic? As a vegan is this just something one should compromise on if they don&apos;t use organic products, or should this list as a whole be thrown out if one were to not compromise for the true practice and overall well being of his/her health?
 Saturday, January 28, 2012 7:37:00 PM Steven B.Macdougall said... 
 We&apos;re a group of volunteers and starting a new scheme in our community. Your site provided us with valuable information to work on. You&apos;ve done an impressive job and our whole community will be grateful to you. 
 Lapco M4/M16 Gas-Through Magazine 2011 A5 SS Markers 
 Saturday, February 11, 2012 5:56:00 AM Chicano said... 
This are some really great options. Nice list. Thanks for sharing.
 Sunday, February 19, 2012 9:56:00 PM natural sleep aid said... 
Thanks for such an interesting article here. I was searching for something like that for quite a long time and at last I have found it here.
 Tuesday, March 06, 2012 5:49:00 AM columbus arena district hotels said... 
Fantastic! That&apos;s really well done. Off to explore the rest of your site. Thank you for the post.
 Wednesday, March 07, 2012 12:29:00 AM healthiest fast food said... 
nice share and keep post.:D
 Saturday, March 10, 2012 8:24:00 AM curcumin said... 
What a wonderful piece of information Admiring the time and effort you put into your blog and detailed information you offer! I will bookmark your blog and have my children check up here often. Thumbs up
 Monday, March 12, 2012 9:34:00 AM Adim said... 
Thank you for sharing this! Just what I’ve been searching for. Great info!
 Aerospace Logo 
 Monday, April 02, 2012 5:34:00 AM Unknown said... 
 BURGER KING ONION RING is NOT VEGAN . It contains Whey which is a dairy-product.

 Burger King Menu (Revised 3/14/2012) - http://www.bk.com/cms/en/us/cms_out/digital_assets/files/pages/MenuNutritionInformation.pdf 

 ONION RINGS (Fried): water, bleached wheat flour, dehydrated onion, modified corn starch, yellow corn flour, sugar,gelatinized wheat starch, contains 2% or
less of :salt, guar gum,methylcellulose, fructose, onion powder, food starch-modified, sodium alginate, sunflower oil, natural flavors, grill flavor (from sunflower oil),
canola oil, wheat gluten, modified palm oil, sodium tripolyphosphate, whey, dextrose, garlic powder, leavening (baking soda, sodium aluminum phosphate), spice,
hydroxypropylmethylcellulose, yeast extract, corn starch, sorbitol, dried yeast, calcium chloride. parfried in soybean oil.
 CONTAINS WHEAT, MILK. 
 Sunday, April 08, 2012 5:06:00 PM Affordable Logo Designer said... 
This is a Great Website You might find Fascinating that we Motivate A person.
 Wednesday, April 11, 2012 7:45:00 AM Buy Medicine said... 
I am very happy to be here because this is a very good site that provides lots of information about the topics covered in depth.
 Thursday, April 12, 2012 3:22:00 PM buy percocet online said... 
Wow, thats amazing.I love the way you write. Do you provide an RSS feed?
 Thursday, April 12, 2012 5:45:00 PM Facebook Fan Page said... 
This is a Great Website You might find Fascinating that we Motivate A person.

 Facebook Fan Page 
 Monday, April 16, 2012 2:16:00 AM Adim said... 
Hello admin, Excellent article. You have gained a fresh reader. Please keep them coming and I look forward to more of your superb articles. Thanks a lot....

 Logo Design 
 Monday, April 16, 2012 6:23:00 AM Buy Valium Online said... 
A healthy diet is not about strict nutrition philosophies, staying extremely thin, or depriving yourself of foods you love. Rather it is to get that good to have more energy and you keep healthy as possible.
 Thursday, April 19, 2012 4:22:00 PM floridagator forum said... 
very nice post. thanksss . please continue.
 Friday, April 20, 2012 4:48:00 PM organic vitamins said... 
I am very happy to be here because this is a very good site that provides lots of information about the topics covered in depth. Im glad to see that people are actually writing about this issue in such a smart way, showing us all different sides to it. Please keep it up. I cant wait to read whats next.
 Monday, April 23, 2012 12:42:00 PM natural supplements said... 
Really i appreciate the effort you made to share the knowledge.The topic here i found was really effective to the topic which i was researching for a long time
 Monday, April 23, 2012 3:47:00 PM melbourne 24/7 computer support said... 
I just got to this amazing site not long ago. I was actually captured with the piece of resources you have got here. Big thumbs up for making such wonderful blog page!
 Monday, April 23, 2012 6:45:00 PM «Oldest ‹Older  1–200 of 208  Newer› Newest» 
 Post a Comment 
 


 
 Newer Post Older Post Home Subscribe to: Post Comments (Atom) 
Google Search!
 
Posts of Note
 
 Recipe Archive Clicks to Help Animals! Winter Pet Safety Brochure Vegan Fast Food Options Tips for Going Vegan Vegan Shopping List 
 
Misc Stuffs
 
 View My Stats 
 
 
Followers
 
Links
 
 Dog Health Problems GO VEG IN DEFENSE OF ANIMALS MERCY FOR ANIMALS PETA PETA STUDENTS PETA2 
 
Good Vegan Blogs
 
 Notes from the Vegan Feast Kitchen ROASTED CARROT, BEET AND ONION SALAD WITH GREENS AND POTTED TOFU (OR VEGAN FETA) 1 day ago Vegan Eats&amp;Treats! Summertime Grilling Fun! 3 days ago vegan-food.net Broccoli Curry( Curry - Vegetable ) 3 days ago SuperVegan: Vegan Blog and New York City Restaurant Guide Summery Salad With A Hint Of Chip 5 days ago what the hell _does_ a vegan eat anyway? Ramen with Tea Smoked Tofu and Shiitake Mushroom Broth 2 weeks ago Seitanic Vegan Heathen Stuffed Jalapenos 5 weeks ago Veggie Delight Vegan Mommy Mondays 1 month ago Vegan.com: Everything Signing Off, Again 2 months ago Vegan Lunch Box Mango&amp;Grape Tomato Salad 2 months ago eat, drink&amp;be vegan New Website: Plant-Powered Kitchen! 3 months ago Invitation to my vegan journey Breakfast is anything you want 5 months ago The Vegan Diet WORLD VEGAN DAY 8 months ago Taste Better Saving time with a little help from your friends 1 year ago veg health news follow me at science and crap 1 year ago Fatfree Vegan Kitchen This blog has moved 2 years ago Veggie Way Preparing the older sibling for the birth of the new baby 2 years ago Eat Air - A Vegan Food Log The End 2 years ago Veg Bitch Raw 2 years ago 
 
Blog Archive
 
 March (7) February (1) October (1) February (2) January (6) December (1) September (1) June (5) May (2) April (1) March (1) November (2) October (3) September (7) June (3) May (2) March (9) February (18) January (14) December (2) October (3) August (3) July (4) June (5) May (2) April (4) March (11) February (17) January (5) December (3) November (2) October (6) September (4) August (6) July (6) June (27) May (17) April (10) March (33) February (33) January (10) 
 
 
 
About Me
 Allie B Stafford Springs, Connecticut, United States Hi! My name is Allie, and I’m college freshman. I love animals and I believe that we need to treat them with respect, just like how we should treat other humans. Just because animals can&apos;t speak doesn&apos;t mean they don&apos;t have feelings.
I currently attend Eastern Connecticut State University. My major is Biology and I am going to be a doctor.
Recently I&apos;ve decided to try raw veganism, and I will be blogging about my journey! View my complete profile 
 
 
Disclaimer
 (C) 2006-2011 Alexandra Marie Byrne. Please do not copy or quote anything from this site without giving proper acknowledgment to it. Please contact the author at headbangandsk8@gmail.com if you have any questions or concerns. 
 Ethereal template. Powered by Blogger .
	</body>
</document>
