<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003949" url="http://www.getrestaurantcoupons.com/" time="2012-07-12-20:07" support="15" score="0.03377586606782604" bingtitle="Restaurant Coupons, Coupons for Restaurants - GetRestaurantCoupons.com" webtitle="Restaurant Coupons,  Coupons for Restaurants - GetRestaurantCoupons.com">
			<query id="000283" bing-rank="172"/>
			<query id="001530" bing-rank="58"/>
			<query id="000306" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="001018" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="001270" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000685" bing-rank="36"/>
			<query id="000673" bing-rank="22"/>
			<query id="000305" bing-rank="44"/>
			<query id="000862" bing-rank="157"/>
			<query id="000296" bing-rank="59"/>
			<query id="000310" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="001427" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001279" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="000307" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="001030" bing-rank="53"/>
	<description>Enter Your Location ... just want eggs and bacon, use our local restaurant coupons and find the food you ...</description>
	<body>
		View Top Cities California Cities 
 Anaheim Brea Fairfield Fullerton Irvine Los Angeles Napa Orange City Orange County Palm Springs Riverside Sacramento San Diego San Francisco San Jose Santa Ana Santa Barbara Sonoma Temecula Vallejo 
 Top Cities 
 Atlanta, GA Austin, TX Baltimore, MD Boston, MA Charlotte, NC Chicago, ILL Columbus, OH Dallas, TX Denver, CO Detroit, MI El Paso, TX Fort Worth, TX Houston, TX Indianapolis, IN Jacksonville, FL Las Vegas, NV Louisville, KY Memphis, TN Milwaukee, WI Nashville, TN New York, NY Philadelphia, PA Phoenix, AZ Portland, OR Reno, NV San Antonio, TX Seattle, WA Tucson, AZ Washington, D.C. 
 
 Welcome Back!   We have recommendations for you.   ( Login ?) Sign In   |   My Account Welcome!   Sign In   or   Register   fast and easy! 
 Home 

 Find Coupons 
 Coupons by Restaurant Coupons by Cuisine Coupons by State Top Cities 
 

 Featured Coupons 

 Restaurant Listings 

 Restaurant Guides 

 About Us 
 News&amp;Articles Blog Childrens Charities Restaurant Owners Opportunities Suggest a Restaurant Contact Us 
 
 
 RESTAURANT COUPONS - EASY TO PRINT, USE&amp;SAVE!
 
 Enter Your Location 
 
City
 
 select 
 
 
Or Zip Code

 
 
Advanced Search Options:

Cuisine Type
 
 select 
 
 Afghan African American American (New) Argentine Armenian Asian Asian Fusion Bagels Bakeries Bar&amp;Grill Bars Basque BBQ Belgian Bistros Brazilian Breakfast&amp;Brunch Brew Pubs British Buffet Burmese Cafe Cafeteria Cajun Cambodian Caribbean Central American Champagne Bars Chicken Chinese Chop House Coffee houses Contemporary Continental Costarican Creole Cuban Deli Dim Sum Diners Dining Cruises Dinner Show Dive Bars Dutch English Ethiopian Ethnic Food European Family Dining Fondue French Fusion Gastropubs German Gluten-Free Gourmet Burgers Greek Halal Hamburgers Hawaiian Healthy Himalayan/Nepalese Homestyle Hot Dogs Hungarian Ice Cream Indian Indonesian Irish Irish Pubs Italian Jamaican Japanese Jazz&amp;Blues Juice Bars&amp;Smoothies Korean Kosher Latin Lebanese Lebanese Mediterranean Malaysian Mediterranean Mexican Middle Eastern Modern European Mongolian Moroccan Noodle shop Oriental Pakistani Pancakes/Waffles Pasta Persian/Iranian Peruvian Pizza Polish Polynesian Portuguese Ribs Roadhouses  Roast Beef Romanian Russian Salads Sandwich / Subs Scandinavian Seafood Shabu Shabu Singaporean Soul Food Soups South American Southern South Western Spain Spanish Sports Bar&amp;Grills Steak House Steak&amp;Seafood Sushi Swedish Taiwanese Tea Rooms Tex-Mex Thai Turkish Tuscan Ukrainian Vegan Vegetarian Vietnamese Wine Bars 
 
Restaurant Name

 

 
 FEATURED RESTAURANT
	</body>
</document>
