<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003644" url="http://www.city-data.com/va-restaurants/Taco-Bell-17977.html" time="2012-07-12-19:48" support="13" score="0.03901950073939187" bingtitle="Taco Bell #17977, 4720 Mine Road, Fredericksburg, VA - Restaurant ..." webtitle="Taco Bell #17977, 4720 Mine Road, Fredericksburg, VA - Restaurant inspection findings and violations, food safety">
			<query id="000251" bing-rank="92"/>
			<query id="000406" bing-rank="39"/>
			<query id="000086" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000079" bing-rank="145"/>
			<query id="001505" bing-rank="192"/>
			<query id="001159" bing-rank="45"/>
			<query id="000088" bing-rank="80"/>
			<query id="000070" bing-rank="91"/>
			<query id="000625" bing-rank="76"/>
			<query id="000087" bing-rank="161"/>
			<query id="000125" bing-rank="127"/>
			<query id="000063" bing-rank="134"/>
			<query id="000094" bing-rank="3"/>
	<description>0220 - Critical The food preparation employees are drinking from an uncovered ... No disposable towels were provided at the hand washing lavatory at the front counter.</description>
	<body>
		Taco Bell #17977, 4720 Mine Road, Fredericksburg, VA - Restaurant inspection findings and violations 

 
 
 
Back to Virginia Restaurants , Virginia , VA smaller cities , VA small cities , All Cities .
 Restaurant: Taco Bell #17977 
Address: 4720 Mine Road, Fredericksburg, Virginia 
Total inspections: 17 
Last inspection: Sep 14, 2009 
 
 
Violation code
 
Inspection Date
 
Inspection Type
 
Critical violations
 
Non-Critical violations
 
Details / Comments
 
 1770 A - Corrected During Inspection Critical Repeat The following equipment food-contact surfaces were observed soiled to sight and touch: interior of the ice bin at the drive thru soda dispenser. 1320 - There were no visible thermometers in the reach in coolers. 2000 - Repeat Soda lids were observed stored unprotected at the drive thru handsink with the food contact surface facing upward. 2350 ii - Observed leaky faucets at the three compartment sink. 3180 - Floors under the fryers are noted in need of a detailed cleaning. 3080 - Repeat Less than 20 foot candles of light was noted in the warewashing area. Only 10 foot candles of light measured. 
 September 14, 2009 Routine 1 5 Details / Comments 
 1570 - The door gasket to the ice machine is in poor repair. 1770 A - Corrected During Inspection Critical The following equipment food-contact surfaces were observed soiled to sight and touch: the inside of the ice bin in the drive thru area. 1800 - The nonfood contact surface of the door gaskets to the hot holding cabinets has accumulations of grime and debris. 1890 - Corrected During Inspection Critical The food-contact surfaces of the following equipment were not observed sanitized: stainless steel food storage containers and lids. Bleach water concentration measured at less than 10 parts per million. 2000 - Clean soda cup lids and cups were observed stored unprotected from contamination from the hand in the drive thru area. 2000 - Clean soda cup lids were observed stored with the food-contact surface facing upward at the drive thru soda dispenser. 2720 - Dumpster or outside refuse container was open or uncovered. Side doors on dumpster were not closed. 3080 - Repeat Less than 20 foot candles of light was noted in the warewashing area. Approximately 15 foot candles noted at approximately 30 inches above the floor. 
 September 16, 2008 Routine 2 5 Details / Comments 
 0200 - Employees wearing jewelry on their arms and hands while preparing food. Watches and bracelets noted on the wrists of several food employees. 0220 - Critical The food preparation employees are drinking from an uncovered container in the food preparation area. 0480 - Unlabeled three compartment food container. 1570 - The plastic lids on the three compartment food container (chipped, cracked), the white spatulas used with the rice (stained, no longer smooth and cleanable), and the walk in freezer(frost accumulation) was observed in a condition that prevents necessary maintenance and easy cleaning. 1800 - The following nonfood contact surfaces have accumulations of grime and debris: the air vent on the ice machine, the door handles to the hot holding unit, the seal on the backsplash of the three compartment sink, and the hoses on the bag in box soda shelving. 1960 - Stainless steal food bins for preparation line were found stacked while wet after cleaning and chemical sanitization. 2740 - Trash and litter were observed adjacent to the refuse container outside the facility. 3080 - Less than 20 foot candles of light was noted in the warewashing area. 3170 - Several cracked floor tiles in the food preparation area, to include tile coving at the floor/wall joins, are not maintained in good repair 3180 - Walls throughout facility, and floor drain at the preparation sink noted in need of cleaning. 3260 - Corrected During Inspection Employees are storing personal items on dry storage and equipment shelving. 3660 - Permit is not posted in a place where it is readily observable by the public, the date as to when the permit expires is not visible. 
 September 12, 2007 Routine 1 11 Details / Comments 
 0540 - Critical Food in contact with soiled gloves. Employee was cleaning make line with gloved hands and did not change gloves prior to handling food for customer&apos;s order. 1780 - Critical Drive thru soda nozzles soiled. 
 April 03, 2007 Critical Procedures 2 0 Details / Comments 
 1320 - Corrected During Inspection The temperature measuring device located in the drive thru line produce bin is not easily readable. 1320 - Corrected During Inspection There was no temperature measuring device located in the main line produce bin. 1550 - The 3-compartment sink and prep sink are not properly sealed to the walls. 1570 - The door gaskets of the front line produce bin (right side), back line produce bin (left side), and walk in cooler are damaged. 1770 A - Critical The following equipment food-contact surfaces were observed soiled to sight and touch: Interior of the ice bin at the soda machine. 1800 - The following nonfood contact surfaces have accumulations of grime and debris: 1. Interior holding box next to fryer. 2. Interior fryer cabinet area. 3. Shelves inside holding box where cinnamon twists are held. 3030 - Corrected During Inspection No disposable towels were provided at the hand washing lavatory at the front counter. 3080 - Less than 10 foot candles of light was noted in the walk in freezer. (light bulb out). 3080 - Less than 20 foot candles of light was noted in the restrooms. (12 foot candles noted in each restroom.) 3170 - 1. Two broken floor tiles in cooking area. 2. Broken/loose floor tiles near prep sink. 3180 - Floors below drive thru make line unclean. Floors below ice bin unclean. 3220 - Mops not hung up to air dry. 3660 - Permit is not posted in a place where it is readily observable by the public. 
 October 25, 2006 Routine 1 10 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. October 25, 2006 Other 0 0 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. October 25, 2006 Other 0 0 Details / Comments 
 0220 - Critical Repeat Employees drinking from open beverages. 2310 - Corrected During Inspection Critical The handwashing facility located in the kitchen is blocked by a fan, preventing access by employees for easy handwashing. 
 August 22, 2006 Complaint 2 0 Details / Comments 
 0220 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Several open employee beverages in the food prep area. 0220 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Employee eating in an area other than designated break area while preparing/handling food or contacting clean food contact surfaces. 0850 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Fried Potatoes for which time rather than temperature is being used as a control was not labeled or otherwise marked with a 4 hour cook, serve or discard by time. 1700 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Chlorine sanitizing solution used was not at an acceptable concentration in the 3-compartment sink. 3380 - Corrected During Inspection Critical 2 wiping cloth buckets exceeding 200ppm chlorine. 
 April 07, 2006 Critical Procedures 4 0 Details / Comments 
 0450 - Corrected During Inspection Critical Employee observed using plastic cup to scoop ice from ice bin. 1770 A - Critical The following equipment food-contact surfaces were observed soiled to sight and touch: 1. interior of ice bin at drive-thru window2. interior of ice machine3. dirty food container lids and scoop with clean utensils at 3-compartment sink 3270 - Critical Numerous flies observed throughout facility. 
 October 26, 2005 Critical Procedures 3 0 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. October 26, 2005 Other 0 0 Details / Comments 0220 - Critical Employee drinking from an uncovered container in the food preparation area. June 27, 2005 Complaint 1 0 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. February 09, 2005 Complaint 0 0 Details / Comments No violation noted during this evaluation. January 19, 2005 Complaint 0 0 Details / Comments 
 3380 - Critical Chlorine sanitizer in the wiping cloth buckets and the 3 compartment sink at 200ppm. CORRECTED. 0140 - Critical Paper towels are not available at drive thru handwashing sink, preventing proper handwashing procedures. CORRECTED. 
 December 03, 2004 Critical Procedures 2 0 Details / Comments 
 3220 - Mops and brooms not hung up to air dry. 0220 - Critical Observed employees eating in an area other than designated break area while preparing/handling food or contacting clean food contact surfaces. 1700 - Critical Chlorine sanitizing solution used was not at an acceptable concentration. 1100 - Critical The food contact surface of the stained utensils, melted handles on spatulas, and lids on dry storage bins is not smooth, contains cracks, chips, or pits and can not be easily cleaned. 2720 - Outside refuse container was uncovered. 1960 - Repeat Food containers were found stacked while wet after cleaning and chemical sanitization. 1570 - Shelving in dishwashing area and ice machine was observed in a state of disrepair and damaged. 3170 - Repeat Cove molding in the back food prep area is not maintained in good repair 3180 - Floor drains and floor/wall junctures underneath and behind equipment noted in need of cleaning. 
 December 30, 2003 Routine 3 6 Details / Comments 
 1100 - Critical The food contact surface of the interior of the ice machine is not smooth, contains cracks, chips, or pits and can not be easily cleaned. (Rusting) 3200 - Intake and exhaust air ducts are not being cleaned (Ceiling and ventilation hood filters) 2000 - Single service items observed unprotected from contamination. (Cups) 0570 - Wiping cloths improperly stored between use. Sanitizer is at 10 ppm Cl. 1960 - Containers were found stacked while wet after cleaning and chemical sanitization. 3170 - Cove molding beside ice machine is not maintained in good repair.Observed mildew overgrown caulking along three compartment sink 3080 - Less than 10 foot candles of light was noted in the Walkin units (5) 3080 - Less than 20 foot candles of light was noted in the bathrooms (13-15) 3080 - Less than 50 foot candles of light was noted in the food prep area (25-35) 
 April 08, 2003 Routine 1 6 Details / Comments
	</body>
</document>
