<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003643" url="http://www.melslife.com/c242/l120/Diabetes_Fast_Food.html" time="2012-07-12-19:48" support="2" score="0.009147697823585602" bingtitle="Fast Food And Diabetes Recommendations with Other Healthy Fast ..." webtitle="Fast Food And Diabetes Recommendations with Other Healthy Fast Food Choices">
			<query id="000880" bing-rank="181"/>
			<query id="000034" bing-rank="189"/>
	<description>Almost everything a fast-food restaurant offers is saturated in fat and has a high ... Know the nutritional value of the foods you order. Remember that every diabetic has a ...</description>
	<body>
		Wellness is about Having Balance 
 
 Welcome 
 
   Food Passion Living 
 Life is a Journey...start here 
 
 melsBlog        Today - July 12, 2012 
   
   -     -   Years - Months - Days 
   
   Hours : Mins : Sec 
   melslife.com age   Enjoy the moment 
 Print   
 
 
 
 
 Babies Babies &amp; Pregnancy Balance Blog Energy Exercise Flowers Gluten-Free Happiness Healthy Careers  Healthy Home Live Forever Meaning Philosophy Sleep Spiritual Happiness Stress melsPhilosophy 
 
 Bad food Balance Beverages Cereals Champagne Cheese Cheese &amp; Wine Pairings Chocolate Chocolate &amp; Coffee Pairings Chocolate &amp; Wine Pairings Chocolate Show - Paris Cocktails Coffee Coffee &amp; Food Pairings Coffee Drinks Coffee Tasting &amp; Terminology Dairy Desserts Energy Drinks Energy, Protein, or Snack Bars Fast Food Companies Fast food Fats Fiber Fish Food Alternatives &amp; Healthy Choices Food Cravings Food Pyramid Fruit Gluten-Free Good Foods Herbs Ice Cream &amp; Gelato Juices Meats Mood Foods Nuts Olive Oil Organic Pizza Pizza Judging Poultry Product Reviews Restaurants Salt Soft Drinks Soy Sugar Superfoods Tea Tea &amp; Food Pairings Tea Companies Tea Readings Tea Tasting &amp; Terminology Vegetables Water Whole Food Whole Grains Wine melsDisclaimer melsReviews 
 
 Advice Babies &amp; Preganacy Cancer Celiac Disease GlutenFree Cholesterol Diabetes Heart High Blood Pressure Immune System melsDisclaimer 
 
 Baby Section Introduction Baby&apos;s Health Baby: Mom&apos;s Health Baristas Blog Cancer Careers    Cholesterol Daymaker Diabetes Drinks Energy Exercise Fast Food Fiber Gluten-Free Good Foods    Hairstylists Healthy Home Healthy Living Heart Herbs High Blood Pressure Immune System Juices Laugh Therapy Life Balance Life Meaning Life Quotes Philosophy Sleep Smoking Spiritual well-being Stress Superfoods Supplements Tea Travel    Vitamins, Minerals, &amp; Supplements Water 
 
 Baristas Cruises Flight/ Cabin Crew Hairstylists Hotels 
 
 Fats Fiber Fish Fruit&amp;Veggies Poultry Soy Superfoods Whole grains 
 
 Baristas Cruises Flight/ Cabin Crew Hairstylists Tell Us 
 
 Bakeries Blog Champagne Cheese Cheese &amp; Wine Pairings Chocolate Chocolate &amp; Wine Pairings Chocolate Tasting &amp; Glossary Coffee Coffee &amp; Food Pairings Coffee Drinks Coffee Tasting &amp; Terminology Desserts Fast Food Ice Cream &amp; Gelato Indulgences Pinkberry Pizza 
 
 Affordable entertainment Blog Cheese &amp; Wine Pairing Cheese Tasting Chocolate &amp; Wine Pairing Chocolate Tasting Daily Info Green Tips Healthy Home Life Quotes Olive Oil &amp; Tasting Pizza Tasting Question of the Day Tea &amp; Food Pairings Tea Tasting Zen Tips melsReviews 
 
 Coupons 
 
       
     
 
 
 
 
 healthy lifestyle community   
 Fast Food: Restaurants Links Beverages Fast Food Cancer Celiac Disease Diabetes Heart High Blood Pressure High Cholesterol Immune System 
 
   
   melsDiabetes Snapshot 
                     
 
 Diabetes: Fast Food   
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
   
 
 Fast Food 

Fast food is not good for you. It is usually filled with fat, refined sugars, gross amounts of sodium and countless carbohydrates, but most Americans seem to enjoy having fast food despite the bad ingredients. Besides eating a balanced diet , exercising, and taking vitamins and supplements, maintaining or improving your health is about making daily choices. 

If you have Diabetes, heart disease , high cholesterol , high blood pressure or are going to have a high sodium meal, make sure that whatever you eat the rest of the day balances with your goals. The best diet for your overall health is one rich in fruits, vegetables, nuts and seeds, and whole grains that supply a lot of nutrients, antioxidants, and fiber.

Even though I’m giving you my recommendations on what to eat at fast food restaurants, I’m not endorsing that you should eat there. I will say, however, that many of your favorite chains have done a better job recently of considering your nutrition and have provided you with some good alternatives. 

 The one thing to remember is that just because something is low in sodium or cholesterol doesn’t mean it is healthy. Almost everything a fast-food restaurant offers is saturated in fat and has a high caloric count. Even salads, which appear to be healthy, are not healthy once you add the calorie and fat laden dressing.  

 Be aware! Many of these chains have different tricks or standards for calculating sodium and cholesterol, or any of their nutritional facts for that matter. Some base it on a 2,000 calorie per day diet, others on a 1,500 calorie per day diet. Also, serving sizes might differ between chains. 
 
You can make healthy fast-food choices at fast-food restaurants. All you need to do is know exactly what you are ordering. Many fast-food restaurants still use beef tallow (fat from cows) to make their burgers, fish, chicken, and French fries. These fried foods are high in cholesterol and by cooking these foods in this kind of fat, it produces toxic trans-fatty acids, which raise blood cholesterol levels and act like saturated fats; this is no good for your Diabetes. 

 Keep the ground rules of good nutrition in mind. Eat a variety of foods in moderate amounts, limit the amount of fat you eat, and watch the amount of salt in food. Follow the guidelines you&apos;ve worked out with your health team (dietitian, nutritionist, or doctor). 

 It&apos;s easy to eat an entire day&apos;s worth of fat, sugar, salt, and calories in just one fast-food meal. Here are some steps to help you choose well 

 Know that an average fast-food meal can run as high as 1000 calories or more, and raise your blood sugar above your target range. Know the nutritional value of the foods you order. Remember that every diabetic has a different eating plan. You need to know your plan.  If you&apos;re having fast-food for one meal, make sure your other meals that day contain healthier foods, like raw fruits and vegetables. Think about how your food will be cooked. Chicken and fish can be good choices but not if they are breaded and deep-fried. Grilled without any sauce is probably your best choice 

 If breakfast is your fast-food meal, choose a plain bagel, toast, or English muffin. Regular muffins may be loaded with sugar and fat. Add fruit juice or low-fat or fat-free milk. Order cold cereal, preferably whole-grain cereal -- with fat-free milk, pancakes without butter, or plain scrambled eggs. Limit bacon and sausage because they are high in fat. 

 If you click on your favorite fast-food chain, it will take you directly to the nutritional facts section of their website and you can put together your own choices for a Diabetic diet . 

In this section, we do not focus on beverages. If you have diabetes, all sodas are bad for you. Try to drink water.

Usually in every melslife section, we offer recommendations on what to eat at your favorite fast food chain. However, with Diabetes, almost everyone has a slightly different game plan. Some Diabetics are seeking menu items with the highest percentage of protein; others are avoiding sugar, sodium, cholesterol, and high-glycemic foods . There are some diabetics searching for high carbs and some searching for low carbs. Whatever your needs are, we have provided the links for you to make your own determination on what to eat


                                   

This is a southern California chain that has an alternative bagel, which many Diabetics and health conscious people enjoy.


 
 
                       melsQuiz answer 
         
 melsBuzz 
 Fast food is about making choices. Most fast food chains offer healthier items and it’s up to you to find them and begin to make a difference your life. 
 
         
 
         
 melsAdvice 
 When it comes to fast-food, all of the chains promote beverages or shakes. Do not have either. If you are craving something sweet, you are better off having a piece of dark chocolate. You will be saving yourself from excess sugar AND a lot of calories Forget large sizes and just eat a regular portion. If your order contains a bun, take a half off and fold your sandwich. Even better, do not eat the bun. Any bread coming from a fast food restaurant usually contains some version of sugar and is usually made of enriched white flour. Stay away from the pancakes and the French toast; not only are these items not made with high quality ingredients, they require you to add additional sugar in the form of maple syrup which is not even pure Special sauces are all different. Read labels and ask questions as most of them contain a lot of hidden sugar 
 
         
 
         
 DidYouKnow? 
 Fast food is probably one of the worst kinds of food a diabetic can eat Denny’s Breakfast French Slam has 1,196 calories and 83gms of saturated fat In 1998 the Cola-Cola Company broke the Guiness Book of World Records for selling the most drinks in a day–683 million. How many do you think were diabetics? If you have a history of heart disease or high blood pressure, experts then recommend that you should have no more than 1,500mg per day of sodium Approximately one-third of all potatoes grown end up as french fries 
 
         
 
         
 melsTips 
 Carefully review your fast-food chain’s nutritional data Avoid sodas and instead drink water, tea, or coffee Order small sizes and only eat half of the order Opt for grilled items over fried foods If you are a diabetic, condiments count. Becareful of what your eat 
 
         
 
         
 melsQuiz 
 Fast food is probably one of the worst kinds of food a diabetic can eat Denny’s Breakfast French Slam has 1,196 calories and 83gms of saturated fat In 1998 the Cola-Cola Company broke the Guiness Book of World Records for selling the most drinks in a day–683 million. How many do you think were diabetics? If you have a history of heart disease or high blood pressure, experts then recommend that you should have no more than 1,500mg per day of sodium Approximately one-third of all potatoes grown end up as french fries 
 
         
 
         
 melsQuiz Answers 
 Texting 6 pounds According to the Department of Human Health and Services, no more than 2,300mg per day. The Food and Drug Administration recommends 2,400 per day, and if you have heart disease, it’s 1,500mg 1. US, 2. Japan, 3. Canada, 4. UK, 5. China Approximately 580 calories 
 
         
 
 
   
 
 melslife User Thoughts     
 
 
   Post Your Thoughts       Name : Email : Post :       
   
 
   
   
 
   Keyword   
 
 
 
 About Us | Advertise | Promotions | Contact Us | Ask mel? | Privacy | Sitemap | Richmel ©2012. www.melslife.com. All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
