<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003280" url="http://customercarecontacts.com/mcdonald%E2%80%99s-malaysia-locations-phone-of-mcdonald%E2%80%99s-delivery/" time="2012-07-12-19:24" support="1" score="0.0022585803831699602" bingtitle="McDonald’s Malaysia: Locations, Phone of McDonald’s delivery ..." webtitle="McDonald’s Malaysia: Locations, Phone of McDonald’s delivery | Customer Care Contacts">
			<query id="000747" bing-rank="187"/>
	<description>It is today the largest hamburger fast food restaurant in the world. McDonald’s employs some 1.7 million people worldwide. Read More. mcdonalds malaysia locations, ...</description>
	<body>
		Home About Browse Search 
 
McDonald’s Malaysia: Locations, Phone of McDonald’s delivery

 August 10, 2011 customer help Restaurant , 3 

 VN:F [1.9.18_1163] RATE THIS COMPANY/ SERVICE please wait... Rating: 1.0/ 10 (1 vote cast) 
 Contact McDonald’s – Malaysia : Find below customer service, phone of McDonald’s in Malaysia. You can reach the below contact for McDonald’s home delivery of burgers, restaurants or take away in Malaysia.

 McDonald’s Home Delivery (Malaysia) 
Phone: 1300-13-1300
 
 Locate McDonald’s Restaurant 
To locate nearest McDonald’s restaurant click here . McDonald restaurants are found in Johor, Kedah, Kelantan, Melaka, Negeri Sembilan, Pahang, Perak, Terengganu, Pulau Pinang, Sabah, Sarawak, Selangor and Wilayah Persekutan.

 Feedback 
To send a feedback to McDonald’s Malaysia click here

 Menu 
To see McDonald’s menu in Malaysia click here 

 About McDonald’s 
McDonald’s Corporation was founded by Ray Kroc in the year 1954. McDonald’s has more than 32,000 restaurants serving more than 64 million people in 118 countries every day. It is today the largest hamburger fast food restaurant in the world. McDonald’s employs some 1.7 million people worldwide. Read More 
 McDonald’s Malaysia: Locations, Phone of McDonald’s delivery , 1.0 out of 10 based on 1 rating 
 mcdonalds malaysia locations , mcdonalds malaysia phone 


 
3 Responses to“McDonald’s Malaysia: Locations, Phone of McDonald’s delivery”

 Meeko Chin says: March 2, 2012 at 6:08 am 
I am rather disappointed with McDonald’s at Sandakan outlet. I have been telling all my friends that Fillet O Fish is an all time favourite. In fact, the cheese burger and others are also an all time favourite. When I ordered fillet o fish a week ago, I had a very overdone piece of fish fillet–worse still, the piece of cheese came to me in less than half! However, I still went back on Sunday afternoon for a drink and a bite. I ordered oreo McFlurry. To my dismay, my friends and I were lamenting over the icy ice-cream. All we tasted was ice and not much cream at all. Another blow to our already disappointed state. My friends and I really hope that something should be done with the food quality. And hopefully, more could be done to lessen the queue at the counters. It is not too properly organized. Cheers.
 Reply maples says: February 13, 2012 at 8:34 am 
I had a very bad experience at your Big Mac outlet in Fajar, Malacca.
On Saturday, 11.02.2012 at 12.55.51 (14 Reg 13) I purchased a box of chicken nugget.
To my horror upon biting on the nuggets, I found it was not well cooked.

I requested for an exchange at the cashier counter.
The female staff instead of offering an apology for the badly cooked item, did not even bother to look at me.
Instead she just took another box of nuggets and pushed it to me without saying a word.
Her action was extremely rude. That was indeed terribly bad service to the core!

McDonald’s is an international food chain, its good reputation is at risk of being eroded by staffs with such an attitude.
Mind you, another lady who also requested for an exchange got the same treatment too!

McDonald’s in Singapore, Guangzhou, Bali which I have visited provided excellent service!
 Reply Azmi Latif says: January 22, 2012 at 9:31 pm 
I was at McD Kotamas Melaka on Jan 22 11.50pm. It’s was a super busy night but the only 2 serving counters were open. How stupid was that when this has created a havoc when some customer jumped a queue that makes other customers very disappointed. Moralle of the story is when McD has a restaurant run by a monkey has created a real monkey serving the food. McD should have open more counter when they see more customers in the queue. I have been to many McD in the world including at the busiest Chicago airport BUT the one at Kotamas restaurant, is horrible so manage.
 Reply 


 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 
 
Quick Search
 
Links
 
About Us
 Customer Care Contacts is your online source for phone, address, email and website of companies and services providers. To view latest posts click here 
Like Us
 
 
Copyright©2012 Customer Care Contacts. All Rights Reserved.   Privacy Policy | Terms&amp;Conditions | Contact Us 

Disclaimer: Customer Care Contacts has made reasonable efforts to ensure the accuracy of the contact listings of companies and service providers. We do not accept responsibility for any errors or omissions in the details listed, including the phone, address&amp;website.
	</body>
</document>
