<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003078" url="http://www.stadsstuff.com/" time="2012-07-12-19:12" support="2" score="0.0016333040023551939" bingtitle="Stad&apos;s Stuff | Your Source for Plastic Figures" webtitle="Stads Stuff | Your Source for Plastic Figures">
			<query id="000619" bing-rank="234"/>
			<query id="001251" bing-rank="208"/>
	<description>One table had a Marx item I was interested in, but ... Joe Hehn ran a mail order old time radio business. ... It is the “fast food” restaurant I would be on the look out for ...</description>
	<body>
		Stad&apos;s Stuff 
 Your Source for Plastic Figures Skip to content 
 Home Ebay Follies Flea Market 2/11/12 Heritage Toys Robin Hood’s Peasant Army Marx Skyscraper AD Sample Page 
 
Stad’s Stuff
 Comment Time 06/24/12 Marx Convention 2012 We have put up our report on the Marx Convention. You will find  a number of photos from  the show at the end. Enjoy Nick Versteeg of TSSD It is reported on TSSd’s web site that Nick is back at work. He hopes to have their new WWII Figures sets back on track. The Review  of the Russian Revolution Figures is up. Pvblivs Romans  Review is posted. I have the first review of the new Russian figures the Pvblivs Romans up on the site.  I hope to have the review of the Russian Revolution figures tomorrow.  One comment is if you are interested in either of the figure sets do not  fool around in getting them as the Russian 1/32 scale figure comppanies have a tendance to disappear.  I just had a friend ask me about the Russian made Tablian figures that were out years ago. Those were well done figure along with the Russian police were out in the market year or so and the company disappeared.  Problem is at the moment you can only get them from Russia.  If we hear of a U.S.or European source for these figures we will let you know. New Policy Starting today most of the photos that will be add to the web site will now have a copyright notice on it. I am forced to do that after someone used a photo from my web site without permission.  I have had them take it down.  If they had asked me before hand, I would have allowed them to use the picture.  They lost that privilege. One thing I am very protective is my rights on material. I will ask permission before I take pictures at shows. I have not release very little information on my book  because of fear it will be stolen. Mystery Solved Our good friend Mark Hegeman has  identified  the figure above. It is a game piece from the Perils of Pauline. This is the first time I have seen the piece. The set came with two hard plastic painted pieces villian and Pauline.  You can see the game up at Ebay at number 360443022058. Ebay Fun Time It’s Cold The weather has gotten colder so most of the outside dealers will hibernate until the weather is warmer. I will do a show in Maryland next weekend one in New Jersey week after.  These will depend on the weather. Conte Collectibles Since several people have mention the Conte Tombstone series, Conte Collectibles has placed notice on their Earps and Doc Holiday figures. Depending on response from collector will see if  these figures will come out.  These figures will be done in metal as a series of Foreign Legion figures.  Conte Collectibles is also doing a inventory clearance on their metal and plastic. If interested in their sale and check it out. Happy New Year Laurie, the boys (Sparky, Percy and Quinn) and I wish you a Happy New Year. We hope this year is a good year for you.  We had a good year and I will give a review of the year in a few days or less. I have  complaints that I have not done any pictures of the boys in a awhile so here is a picture of the three together.  In the new year I will get more pictures up of the boys.  Can you believe it we have Quinn now over eighteen months. When we got him  he was only 2 pounds now he is eighteen pounds.  Quinn has started to talk more, he has a deep voice and sometimes it sounds like he is saying I love you. Sparky is more tolerated of Quinn but every so often we have to break up Sparky trying to show his authority.  Percy is fine if he does not see another dog, person or loud car.  I will have more on them in 2012. We are hard at work on some great new surprises for 2012. you just have to wait and see what they are. Happy Holidays I hope your holidays have been going well. Laurie and I have been out doing some shopping and enjoying the season. We went to a mall today and I found some books  at book store that was closing and Laurie got my Christmas present.  It was a fun afternoon and break from work.  We got to eat again at Chipolte which we will be getting in our area next spring. We still have not gotten to White Castle as the line is around building yet. In a few days I will be talking about getting the new TSSD Earps and Doc Holiday and a few other items. Odds and Ends Sorry for not posting lately, but I have been busy with work and other projects. Laurie gets time off around this time of the year and we do day trips.  We are still debating about  if we will go to New York City or Philadelphia to see the lights. This year is the first time since we met that we have not taking a plane trip to somewhere.  We held back due to the costand the hassles at the airport.  I am not sure if we will go anywhere next year as prices are going up. More soon 32nd Germany Plastic show Our very good friend Peter Bergner will be having his Germany Plastic Show in Herne Germany on November 6. This is a great show load with plastic figures from all over the world. There will be dealers from other countries besides Germany. So if you are near Herne on sunday go and enjoy the show. 29 th East Coast Toy Soldier Show Allentown Toy Show On Saturday November 5th the Allentown Toy show at the Allentown Fairgrounds. This show will have a wide range toys and collectibles to look at and buy. My friend John will have a table with Mike Russo of Stockade Miniatures which have a great selection of plastic. There will be other dealers with plastic figures.  Each row can have surprises.  Laurie and I will be walking around.  Hope to see you there. Heil Honey One of my favorite comedy geniuses is Mel Brooks. The man has done some of my favorite comedy movies: Blazing Saddles, Young Frankenstein (did not enjoy the musical it needed more work) and the Producers (love the original movie, and Broadway show, but not musical movie it needed more work) are my three favorites of his movies with Producers being number one.  The plot of the Producers is they look for the worse play they can find which is“Springtime for Hitler”so they can make lots of money. Now I will see if I get credit for giving it to Mark Evanier over at New From Me. Floyd Wilson’s OTS Report We have another report from Floyd Wilson on the OTS 2012. Check it out in the Comment Section I am sure you will enjoy it. OTS Report Check the comment OTS Report, it has a honest and sincere report from Ed Borris which will give us much to think about. Sunday We are waiting for some reports on how today’s show went. One thing that has been been list on one of the forums is that Barzso Collectibles offering will Battle of Lexington for 2012.  This is the earliest notice of their next playset. Saturday at OTS Sales are going well at the show. If you are in Captain Gallant you get either the playset or parts. The Foreign Legion figures were going for $10.00 and Arabs were going for $25.00 and up.  One party was trying to get $50.00 a figure. Heritage Toy Figures  was there with their new Swappable Robin Hood Merrymen.  They had only 45 of the figures at the show and sold out. I hope to have pictures of them in the near future. Tomorrow will be the show itself. We got permission from  Joe Baker to put the link up of his photos from the show.  We thank  Joe for letting us share this link with you. Action yesterday was busy. There are a lot of Marx playsets at the show and prices are higher.  Treefrog forum has pictures from various metal makers, one of the most interesting is Figuarti as they have done Trojan Horse as well as one wall.  Hobby Bunker has a photo of French and Indian Fort  designed by John Jenkins which they will do in foam.  A Marx Captain Gallant display board with chocolate Arabs was seen and sold.  Many rare Marx figures were seen as well. We will have  report from Floyd Wilson after the show. Update From OTS We have checked with some people and there is more activity today.  Steve Weston has just about sold out on his Cavalry figures and doing well with his Long Branch Saloon. Playsets are selling and there are bargains if you look carefully.  Someone swipe the Sitting Bull figure from the Barzso display. In the next few days I will be doing a review of the TSSD Romans and Barbarians. I will be be doing a figure size comparsion as well. First Report From OTS Many of the dealers waited until Thursday to come in so action did take off to Thursday night. As always there is a nice selection of playsets for sale.  Clouse has put up at Playset Magazine the first set of photos he has taken. The first pictures show the new Barzso Collectibles Rev War Camp and Sioux Buffalo Hunt playsets, TSSD Romans and Barbarians and Weston toy Cavalry figures and Replicants Long Branch Saloon.  As we get more information we will let you know. OTS Next week will be the annual OTS  at the Hyatt Regency at Woodfield.  People will be arriving on Wednesday and will be opening their rooms. Each room will be like an Alladin’s treasure cave, where you will be hoping to find that missing items. There will be new items from TSSD and Barzso Collectibles.  Also Weston Toys will have two new items a set of resin cavalry figures  representing their logo with a gatling gun. The other playset is from Replicants Long Branch Saloon. The set will have 15 new figures, one reworked figure and Buffalo Bill.  The playset will have piano and building will be in cardboard. On Sunday will be the show. The show will have some dealers that do not set up in the hotel in addition to the those that did set up in the hotel. We will not be there. We will be contacting people to get reports and will be watching various forums to let you know what is going on.  We are hoping Floyd Wilson will give us another great report. The NJHMA Expo has been Cancelled This just in from the Marx Group that the NJHMA show at the Wayne NJ PAL Building has been cancelled for September 11.  From the email  they recieved the building is fine but many streets  are flooded making it impossible  to get to the show. The show is trying to get another date for the show. We will keep you posted if we get an update. Lee Laurie and I are fine during this heavy rain. We are on high ground so we are fine. Other areas are being hit by floods including the Wilkes Barre Pennsylvania. They are getting hit as hard as they did during Agnes back in 1972.  We hope the collectors up in that area are doing okay. Hurricane Irene We got 5 inches of rain. Other than knocking down some branches and some very minor water in the basement  we came through fine..  We did lose eletricity for three hours. We are lucky as some people we know do not have power and will not have it until Friday night.  What was annoying was when Laurie went to report the outage to the electric company she got into an endless loop of their system. Then today I got phone call at the house. It was a recorded message from the electric company apologizing on us not having electric.  We have had electricty since Sunday night! 
 End of Summer 
 The summer is almost over. I hope you had good hunting in the flea markets and shows. We did very well despite all the competition. For the business side I can move over to other items other than the plastic figures. I did a flea market this week the plastic figures that were available were very common or badly damaged.  One dealer was trying to get $.50 a figure for Lido Army figures. The flea market was not a bust as I did get some comic book statues and a plastic vehicle worth the trip. I also got a six inch Marx Astronaut which is a reissue. I will be doing a short article on the Marx astronaut. Next Friday and Saturday will be Toytown at the  Aws Fescht in Macungie PA.  Outdoor part will be in a field right off Route 100 before you get into the Macungie. If you go over the railroad tracks you went too far.  The dealers will start coming in on Friday afternoon with the big action Saturday morning. While there will be alot of toy cars there will be plastic figures over the place. My good friend John Reichle will have plastic and set up with him will be Mike Russo of Stockade Miniatures. Steve Falken is another person to look for. I will be roaming around the two days. Besides the field, the school will be open on Saturday. Origins of Comment Time I got the idea for Comment Time from Stan Lee and Joe Hehn. Stan Lee was the editor and later the publisher of Marvel Comics. He started a page in the comics which was for the fans.  The page became a spot where you read to get the news. Stan would let you know who did the artwork and was going on.  He personalized the books. Odds and Ends Quiet  week, I did not go out last week and with the word that the heat and humidity are going to be bad, I am going  hold back this week as well. I am not getting any reports of finds  so I will work on the stuff I have. I am using the time for other projects and work. I am still waiting to hear on the  old computer and I am doing  my report on the Marx meeting. Comments We have added a program to cut out the spam we have been getting. The new program has cut the spam to nil. It does not  effect regular comments. Happy fourth It has been a fun week for me. I had to get a new computer and now I am in the process of rebuilding everything. Had my car broken into,  they did no damage and did not get anything. Our next door neighbor was not luck he had one of his car windows smashed. The crimnals were quickly arrested as they had hit five other cars. The flea market and toy show I had planned to go to were cancel due to weather or other reasons. I am not worried on what I missed as I have plenty of material to work on for the internet. On the bright side I was able to track down some figures made for a company called U.S. Toy.  A friend in Europe wanted a series of  sport figures from U.S. Toy and they do not ship outside the United States.  I had my friend have the company ship the figures to me and then I shipped the figures on  to him.  I check the company’s web site and found they did other figures. More importantly the company had retail store not far from us so we checked it out.   I will report on my findings soon. Marx Convention Laurie and I are back from the Marx Convention. We had a great time and got lot of great items I will be putting on Ebay and we have some interesting items to share with you that we are adding to the collection. One interesting item we got was the Marx Doll House figures painted in hard plastic  from Hong Kong.  I will be doing more tomorrow after I recover from the drive home. Odds and Ends Quiet week here as I have been busy with work and Ebay. WordPress is giving me problems on this page which may have been caused by the latest Windows update.  I am going to do posts mostly until I figure this new glitch in the system.  Hope you are going to West Virginia show as Laurie and I are looking forward to a break.  The rest of the postings on this page are old. Reissues I have had  several people over the last few weeks ask me if a figure I had listed on Ebay was original or reissue. I   advised them it is original and I add my credentials as an expert on the reissues. This question has me wondering  if there have been problems  with people selling reissues. Let me know your feelings. Michigan Toy Soldier Company It has been report by various sources that the Michigan Toy Soldier Company has been sold. Reports are saying that the staff of Michigan Toy Soldier bought the business more detail as it comes available. Odds and Ends We have two companies talking about doing Earp figures related to OK Corral: TSSD and Conte Collectibles. TSSD will be showing pictures of their project at the Texas Show at the end of the month. Conte Collectibles has show photos of their prototype figures which are to be available in plastic and metal. Still have not gotten any information on what the Chinese Company we have called Supreme is doing for this year. As soon we get any information we will let you know. Steve Weston has put pictures of the new Replicants figures  men at Arms and the Battle of Culloden. Each set has four figures and look  great. The flea markets are starting to get more dealers and it will be interesting to see what comes up. I hope to get my MFCA show report up. I am still trying get the hang up of Word Press. Pictures of New Figures You can go to the blog of our good friend Brian Carrick and see pictures of the new Armies in plastic British Camel Corp and the two new Replicants figure sets. The localtion of his blog is: http://toysoldiercollecting.blogspot.com/ I will have to see the Armies in Plastic figures up close before I make my final decision on the figures. I like the new poses on the Replicants figures. I think my favorite for now is British standing with bayonet rifle.  Note the Replicant figures come unpainted. Comments If you wish to make comments go right ahead and email us.  We will post it after we review it. I have to do it that way as so  many comments are either attempts to put malware on my web site or promote product not related to what we talk about. So if you have a questions or comment feel free to respond. You Never Know Yesterday Laurie and I went roaming at some flea markets. We walked into a indoor garage sale and  had a shock. There were almost no vendors.  Most people would have turned around. We decided since we were here we would check it out.  I walked around and spotted at one table two Marx  racetrack figures, a Marx three inch Construction Figure and a Timmee knight. I later found the bag had an Auburn Farm woman without a base.  At first I thought it was a damaged figure, but I discover that the figure  was designed to be with out a base, It has a little extension on the left foot to balance the figure. I will do pictures of it. After that Garage sale we went to Beachhead Comics for Free Comic Book Day. Our good friend Jeff had good crowd  for the day as he had several comic book writers and artist in for the day.  He mentioned that his wife met Mayim Bialik who plays Amy Farrah Fowler on the Big Bang Theory the day before. Jeff’s wife Stephanie was working at the Liberty Bell Shrine in Allentown (they hid the Liberty Bell in a local church during the Revolutionary War.) A woman came in with her husband and two children. The woman told she was in the area for vacation and bought an item from the gift shop. Later looking at guest book Stephanie saw it was Mayim Bialik. Mayim gave a commencement speech at local college on Saturday. From the comic shop we walked across the street to a local Church Bazaar. Our very good friend Les had been there the day before and had said there was nothing there. I told Laurie we would still check it out. There was nothing for me but Laurie found some nice jewelry for resale.  So don’t know what you will run into. Replicants Update The Marx group has posted some more information on the new Replicants figures. Medieval men at Arms a four figure set and British for the Battle of Culloden. The British will be in tricorn hats with two extra grenadier heads for conversions. Peter Cole did this last year with the Scottish Highlanders.  These should be welcome additions to your collection. Armies  in Plastic News The Marx Group also aunnounced three new sets from Armies in Plastic coming in June/July. The set are British Camel Corps for the Gordon Relief. The first set is a officer with Bicnoculars, trooper with bugle , two troopers and two camels. Set two  has 4 troopers with camels. Set three has 2 troopers, 2 camels and 2 pack camels.  We can not wait to see the camels and see if they matched the Timpo Camels best camels done in the plastic. Plastic Warrior Show First Report We got our first report from the Plastic Warrior Show. The show was successful with 200 plus people coming through the door. The show has only 55 tables but as we mention before it is always loaded with plastic. Reports are saying prices on many plastic figures have increased. One dealer had one of the Marx 6 Inch Scottish Highlanders badly painted for 25 pounds or $42.50! Even with increase of prices there were treasures to be found at reasonables prices. Spotted at the show were Mokarex WWI French in soft plastic.  The show is a place to find unusual figures. People are were able to find figures from around the world. Our friend Don Ducotte was there with his swappables and was the hit of the show. The new Replicants figures are two sets British to go against Scottish Highlanders and Peasant Levies for the knights. I may have the names wrong and will correct as I get more information. We will have more information coming in on this great show. One interest story we heard was a dealer had a junk box loaded with broken and damaged  figures. He had a sign on it that the figures in the box were free. It is great that this dealer shared these figures instead of throwing away as some collector might be able to  take figure and us them for conversions. Many collectors over in the UK like to do conversions and I have acquire some great conversions for my collection from there. Gettysburg Toy Soldier Show Our friend Mark Hegeman report that the Gettysburg Toy Show was good time.  At the show with plastic was Alan Ford, Kerry Dunable, Steve Thompson, Rick Eber, Calvin Ploughman, and several others beside Mark. Mark has grown from one table to three tables at the show and he said sales were good.  Mark got an unusual Marx Robin Hood  Castle with high Walls! Mark said sales were good and Kerry next to him had sold quite a few items. The foot traffic was busy from 10AM to 12PM then started to decress until the close. Another party told us he did well with his sales, but he felt the crowd was down.  We heard that Renningers Flea Market had great day as well. Some of the dealers were from the Renningers Extravengza which was held Thursday through Saturday. so it was a good weekend. Plastic Warrior Show Don’t forget the Plastic Warrior Show this Saturday May 7 at Queen Charlotte Hall in Richmond which is a suburb of London. The show is only 55 tables but it is plastic, plastic and some metal. There will be collectors and dealers from many different countries.  This is a show you can walk around ten times and still find treasures. Heritage Toy Soldiers Inc will be making its first showing in the UK of their Swapable lines. Sadly Laurie and I will not be there this year. We had some major bills last year, the high cost of  traveling and some other factors made us make the decision not to go. The show is one of the high point of the year for us not just what we can find but to see old friends. Over the 30 years we have made many great friendships from the show and we wish them good hunting. We are promised reports and photos and will share them as soon as we get them. Chiller Laurie and I went to Chiller instead of Gettysburg Toy Soldier show. We wanted to meet Ernest Borgnine. We have enjoyed his work. He had been at a previous Chiller but I had to work. This year I was able to arrange my schedule to go to the show. We decided to go on Sunday as the last time we went on a Saturday and it was a madhouse. The trip to show was pleasant. I was wondering what the gas price would be in New Jersey. Over in Pennsylvania  we are paying between $3.85 to $3.89 a gallon. The price in New Jersey was the same $3.85 a gallon. We arrived at the show and exchange our tickets for wrist bands. We had no wait and as we walked in I noticed that the line was not long for Ernest Borgnine so we went to his line first. The wait was not long about ten minutes. When we had waited for Leslie Nelson the wait was an hour.  Waiting in line can be interesting the person behind us  was figuring what he was going  get just and autograph or  an autograph and a photo. He finally decide to get an autograph and picture.  The stars today charge for their autographs which is only fair  as people are selling their autographs on Ebay and other venues. The person before us put out a photo from Devil Rain. Ernest commented that he was still owe $25,000.00 from his role in that movie.  We decided to get an autograph and photo.  As Enrie was signing the autograph on the photo I asked him about some movies and people. You had to bend over for him to hear you. The one movie I asked him about Super Fuzz he said it had a crazy Italian director.  He enjoy working with Gary Cooper on Vera Cruz and call him a gentleman. After he signed our photo, we got our picture with him.  Before we left him we each shook his hand. For a man, who is 94 he has  strong hand shake. Next we went over Hal Linden of Barney Miller Fame.  We picked a photo from Barney Miller. While Hal was signing I mention  that I saw on IMDB he had done dubbing for some Japanese Monster movies. Hal replied that he had done alot of dubbing in his early days including dubbing on I am Curious Yellow. He stopped doing it after he got successful. After Hal had signed the photo we got a picture with him. The first picture came out fine, Hal had the person take another picture with us.  I will share the pictures with everyone in the near future. After getting  the picture with Hal Linden, we walked around and looked at the other stars. The show has a wide range of people from movies and television.  They had Butch Patrick and Pattie Priest  from the Munsters and the people who played the children from the first Willy Wonka. The stars were nice and happy to meet their fans.  We always stop and say hello to Zacherly. Zacherly is an old horror host from Philadelphia/ New York area. After seeing the guests we went to the dealers area. The dealers area was full but there were dealers missing from previous show. This show had more model dealers than previous show.  There was one stand where you could get a vampire teeth fitted on to your teeth.  I got some items for resale. One table had a Marx item I was interested in, but the people working the stand did not know the priceas the person that had the items was not there. I walked back three times and still got the blank answer.  I will see if the dealer has it in October if we go. Laurie got a great shirt with dogs in halloween costumes. She also got a a small print that fits on wooden easel from Ken Kelly. Ken Kelly is a world renown artist who done various fantasy paintings. The painting is of the rock band Kiss as Vikings on a Viking ship.  Laurie has enjoyed Gene Simmons on his reality show and hopes to meet him someday. I told Ken Kelly who is very good friends with Kiss that if Laurie ever meets Gene she be in shock while I will talking with him on collectibles and comic books.  Ken told us that both Gene Simmons and Paul Stanley are very smart  businessmen on the marketing the Kiss brand. After the about two hours we left the show. The show was good but the crowd was down on Sunday. You had a very short or no wait to meet someone and get their autographs . The dealers did not seem to do well and there were all kinds of special. We stop at one of our favorite restaurants Clinton Diner on the way home. MFCA First Thoughts I did the MFCA yesterday and came away disappointed. I had done this show off and own for over 40 years.  I have had a good time at most of the shows.  This is the first one  where I came out and felt do I want to come back. I will have a full report in a few days and I have pictures of  the show as well. We will not be at Gettysburg Show on Sunday as we are going to Chiller instead to see some old movie and tv stars.  We hope someone will give us a report on the show. Projects As some of you know I have some other projects I have been working on.  The first one my book which is nearly finished. I have two sections to complete and then one more review and then it will be published. I think I will do it as an ebook to get some feedback and hopeful catch the eye of some publisher. If not I have had lots of fun doing it and will go on to the next book in the series. The story is about a man who wanted to be a merchant but was falsely accussed of crime, so he lost his chance to be a merchant. Since he could not become a merchant he became a soldier. Through the years he rose through the ranks until he became his country’s greatest general. Now when he could finally became a merchant, he is made a lord. The other project is our comic video. Laurie and I are naturals in comedy. We have been wanting to do comedy for the last few years, but have not been able to due to our schedule. I hoping to start this project next month.  It is should be interesting as Laurie is not sure she can go from a script so we will try it first without a script. Fortunatily I have had some training in improv so we will see how it goes. If it works it goes up on Youtube. We will have videos of the dogs up as well.  We will keep you posted. Soldat Plastique 1/32 Correction I heard from Mathias the admin of the forum that I made a mistake in regards to the  forum. The forum is interested in all plastic figures not just French Plastic figures. We sorry for the error. Flea Market Day I was glad I went to the flea market today despite the threat of rain.  As I was going out to the car a front loader and dump truck came down the street.  I knew what they were going to do, the neighbor across the street had removed his loose stones he put down to replace his grass on his lawn two years ago.  He decided to sell his house and I figured he was told that he had to get rid of the stones and put a lawn back in.  I delay my trip and moved Laurie’s car.  I had to yell at the workmen to stop with the front loader so I could get out of the way. Once this mess was taken care off I went off to the flea market. On the way I had to go through a few little rain showers and got to the flea market.  The market had  most dealers I had seen but the quality was  down. In the plastic figures I saw several junk boxes  but only one was worthwile.  One dealer had some Beton rectangle base civilians and another dealer had  Marx Western Ranch Playset for $75.00. I found a several cars  and headed back home. French Plastic Figure Forum There is a new forum for plastic soldiers. It is called Soldat Plastique 1/32. The forum main interest is French Figures, the members are also interested in other figures. Most of the posts are in French, some people respond in English or place first in French second in English. The group is small right now, so give them a look. Ihave posted the web site below. http://soldatplastique-1-32.forumgratuit.fr/forum Marx Color Variation The latest issue of Figuren Magazine from Germany has an article on Marx 60mm GI’s. The figures are in a light green instead of the traditional colors of brown.  The interesting thing I can discern from the article is they are marked  Germany instead of Heimo. Heimo is the company that did the figures in Germany for Marx.  Marx let Heimo sell the figures in  Germany. When they sold the figures  in Germany they had Heimo mark. When they were sent to the United States they had  Germany on the bottom. This was done by having a different slug for either term and it could be easily changed.  We found out on the Heimo connection back in 1993 when Laurie and I attend the first German Plastic show. I acquired a box with the Heimo logo on it. Our very good friend Andreas Dittmann tried to contact the company Heimo which was still in existence, but no one at the plant had any information on the figures. Lido I was watching an old episode of Zane Grey theater and the town was named Lido interesting. HobbyTown This weekend we had some obligations in an area where there is Hobbytown that I like to visit.  This Hobbytown would get some TSSD figures. We drove up to the shopping center and found it gone.  This is a sad situation we are in that hobby shops are going by the wayside.  I will see if I can pick up some of the items that I would have gotten at the Hobbytown at the MFCA Show. Odds and Ends This week the time to do flea markets was limited due to weather,work and other commitments. I was able to find a few items when I did get out.  The number of dealers have been down so far for this season. I do not know if it is the weather or something else. To take care of Ebay I have to look beyond my old areas and keep a look out for non-toy soldier items.  I have been buying items lately that three years ago I would have not given a second look. One of the items  that I picked up recently was a plastic statue of the Pieta. On the side of the statue is Vatican Pavilion World’s Fair. In the past I would not bothered to ask a price.  Now with my presence on Ebay, I asked the price and it was in my perimeters so I bought it. Even in plastic toy soldiers I am buying items that I would not have purchased in the old list days. I see myself now looking at Payton and Rel because I have people who want them. If another person passes on it, they do not have a client for it. Toy Soldier Collector Magazine (April/May) has an article on Ron Barzso and his company. The four page article has list of the various playsets Ron has done plus pictures of the various playsets. I am still learning my new software. I hope to have some pictures up of items I have added to the collection soon. The boys are doing fine. Quinn is  copying his older brothers in some of the things they do. I have spotted Quinn covering himself with a blanket like Sparky.  Quinn also likes to go on the top of the sofa like Sparky. Sparky is not happy with sharing his special space with his younger brother. Nick Veersteg Updated We have received word that Nick will have 2 1/2 week rehab ahead for him. Nick Veersteg Various forums are reporting that Nick Veersteg of TSSD had a stroke last week. He is right now recovering in rehab facitily. If you want to wish him well you can sign at his  guest book at the address below. http://www.caringbridge.org/visit/nickversteeg 
 
 Great Allentown Comic Book Con I do not always go to shows just to buy items for resell or the collection. Sometimes it is to see old friends as I did yesterday when I attended the Great Allentown Comic Book Con. An old friend Bruce Rosenberger was there to promote his book Dutchy Digest. Dutchy Digest is a small press printing about Amish Detective Amos Dingledorfer. Bruce does this series with Steve Hager who does the scripts and Bruce does the art work.  Next to them was Gary Petras who is a writier has done various books. I tried to  take a picture of Bruce and the camera was on video. Annoyed not knowing how to change it I whipped out my Blackberry and took some pictures. When I got home later I found what was wrong and straighten  the camera. Bruce and I caught up on family. Bruce has three boys one who is graduating from college next month. After buying some books from Bruce and Gary I decided to walk around the show. Most of the dealers had boxes and boxes of comic books which I had no interest in.  I do not collect comic books anymore as my interest is with the toy soliders. The toys that were there were nothing I could used.  At one table a dealer had a load of DVD many good and interesting  titles. The price was right $3.00 a DVD or 4 for $10.00. Among the titles I got were Restless Gun and Zane Grey theater.  So it turn out a good day, Some prices from Last Roy Rogers Auction Accord Western Clippings they held the last 300 items  from the Roy Rogers.  I have listed  some of the items of interested to us pirce includes 15% buyers premium. Harland Figures of Roy Rogers and Dale Evans went for $690.00 Hartland Trigger Autographed $690.00 Roy Rogers Ideal Chuck Wagon and Jeep $575.00 Roy Rogers Trigger Marx Tin Toy Truck Trailer $690.00 Interesting the toy is shown with the Stuart Roy Rogers and Trigger and Marx 54mm Roy Rogers and and 54mm running saddle horse. Singing Cowboys Western Clippings  also had a notice in the month of July on Fridays nights TCM will be running movies from singing cowboys era. There will be 25 films including  Gene Autry and Roy Rogers. Check it out. Bill Hamilton We have recieved word that Bill Hamilton has passed  away. Bill was from the early days and had ads in PFPC. He helped collectors sell some their extras before the advent of Ebay. He will be missed. Gettysburg Toy Soldier Show The show will be on May 1 at the Historic Gettysburg Hotel. The show will be from 10 AM to 3 PM.  Admision is $6.00.  You will have wide selection of new and old material. MFCA The MFCA  will be held on April 29 and 30 at the Valley Forge Conference Center King of Prussia, PA. Show hours are 12 to 5 PM on Friday and 9 AM to  4 PM on Saturday. The high point is to see the exhibits of  figures. There will be dealers with new and old material. Chiller Once again Chiller is on with lots of great people including Ernest Borgnine. Ernest had been there before but I had to work. This year I have the Sunday so we are going to meet him. Beside Ernest  Borgnine they are schedule to have Hal Linden, Lonnie Anderson, Michael Gross plus many more.  The show is from April 29 to May 1. I would reccomend to get tickets  in advance as the line can get long to buy tickets and the fire marshall may  restrict the crowd. Sunday Before going to Fun Fair which we had free tickets, we went to Renningers.  The market had more dealers than before about 3/4 full.  Laurie found some jewelry and I found a couple of  Timpo solid GI’s and a Britains Super Deetail British. We found our very good friend Gerry Watts three rows over than usual. Gerry was very happy with his sales he had made and I was able to  find a nice selection of items for resale.  Laurie and I went inside for her to get some jewelry and have a sausage sandwich.  I left Laurie to buy her jewelry and walked back to Gerry. Gerry was happy as he had just sold a load of  model kits.  Having a good day Gerry decided to leave. He pulled a  box up from the ground and I found a castle with Timpo knight copies and MPC dinosaurs which I bought.  I went back to Laurie who had found some jewelry which we purchased and head out. We went to the  Fun Fair. This show is a two day show.  We went on the second day. The crowd was down, we were able to get a parking space fairly close to the door.  We walked in and gave our free tickets started to look around. We notice right away that there was very little crowd.  The dealers were sitting around most of the stands were empty of buyers. There were nice pieces in many of the stands but at very good prices. Plastic figures were few and far between. One person had a Marx partial Army training center with the one story cabin no figures and bunch of accessories for $85.00. They had a Keystone garage which I had picked up last week. Mine was in better shape so I did not ask the price. Another dealer had the Processed Plastic Fanstasy Figures which are base on the Marvel Figures Processed Plastic  did years earlier.  The dealer had them at $15.00 each. One of the figures Caveman/Hulk had a broken club.  Not worth buying in my book. We did find some items. Laurie found some jewelry and mold rama Alligator we did not have. We also found a Marx item the Mami and Dwight Eisenhower on a card.  I will be doing a picture in the near future. We headed out  and headed home. Still Learning I am still trying to get time to learn the new software, but I have four other projects plus Ebay and the human job to fight for  my time.  I got to a flea market on Wednesday where I saw my friend John. He  found a few items and I purchase some other items  that  he had passed over. The items I bought were items that in the old days I would pass on as well, but sell on Ebay.  today I found some old vehicles at yard sale just two blocks from the house before going to work. We are going on Sunday to new indoor antique show that is run by the person that use to have the show at Atlantic City. A good friend of ours gave us free tickets for the show. Will let you know how it was. Disney Zorro I just found a great web site for the Disney Zorro series.  The author Bill Cottercovers the series and gives detail description of the various episodes plus much more. Check it out http://www.billcotter.com/zorro/index.htm Gary Dutko Due to our site being down I could not report that Gary Dutko is back making his conversion and has them for sale up on Ebay.  He also seling some other items as well. His ebay id is Duktotoys. Old Comment Time I just found out my old Comment Time is still up on the web. . You go to the link below.

http://www.stadsstuff.com/comment_time_iii.htm

Once I figure the new system out I will be putting up lots of great stuff. For now I am doing reporting on the main page. It has been fun trying to learn a new system and do my other work. So stick around The Big Weekend As I mention in my previous post we were doing a weekend of shows and flea markets. Saturday Morning I did the Indoor Garage Sale at the Allentown Fairgrounds.  I had done well there before and decided to do it again. I arrived early and was there for the 8 o’clock opening. I got in and headed for a stand where I had done well before. Bad news the item I wanted was gone. Someone had bought them the day before during set up. I left the stand and started to do the sale. Right away in the second row I got some items plastic toy soldiers. The person had various bags of figures including Auburn civilans and a Marx Warrior of the World Marine. I went down another couple of tables and got more plastic figures 54mm Marx pioneers and Indians. Two more rows over I found some nice collectibles including a Dumbo squeeze toy.  I got some other items cake decoration of baseball figures by Wilton and a Moldarama Dinosuar. The tip of the tale was broken but for $1.00 I got it.  I put the items into the car and did a second go round. I ran into a Ebay dealer and sort of burst his bubble when I said that I already put stuff in the car. I headed to 31th Street Flea market and found nothing so after doing some errands I headed home. When Laurie got in from her nail appointment, I told her she need to go to the garage sale as there was alot of jewelry for to look over. We started about 2 years ago putting jewelry items up on Ebay, which she takes care of.  I took her in the back of the sale and we worked forward.  She found jewelry at two places and was pleased. The third spot she had a nice pile of jewelry and it was counted out by the son of the  owner and was given a price. The woman owning the stand came from another sale looked at the items and started to give prices.  This annoyed Laurie greatly that she told person what to do with the items. The woman should have had better items marked or had train her people to wait until she was there. We went to another stand and Laurie found some more jewelry that got her back in the spirit.  While she was looking I bought some cermanic items from Japan.  We did one more stand headed home to relax. The next day we change our plans and did a flea market that our very good friend Gerry Watts told us about. We got to the flea market and started to get disapointed. The material was too new and not very exiciting. We found Gerry as he was heading out to check some other markets and got some items he had for sale. His friend Chris had a lot of loose action figures which he was putting out when we left them. On the way back to the car Laurie found three nice bracelets. We headed for our original destination the toy show. We got there a few minutes before the doors open so we waited instead of getting early rights. We got in the door and right away I could see the quality was down. We went to one of our sources Tom who had some Lido aliens in soft plastic which picked up along with junk lot. One of my challenges anymore it is to buy a junk lot and see if I can make a profit.  I bought some more junk lots from Carey and we looked through the show and found other items. Still it was less than what I had bought from them before. In a second go around I spotted a 45mm Napoleon from France for the collection.  I also got Play along Lord Rings item which I do not know if I have it or not but it is marked special convention issue. Laurie got for herself a nice metal triceratops from a dealer we had gotten some loose Lido knights in our first trip.  The back room  of the show since Gerry was not there was  filled out with dealers  who were given extra tables.  After an hour and half we left the show did a farmers market. There too the quality was down. Tired of the grind we went to a favorite Mexican restaurant in the Farmers market. The food is of good quality and is true Mexican food. Once we had eaten we headed for home. Getting Ready for A big Weekend Getting ready for a busy weekend of  flea markets, indoor garage sale and a toy show. It will be interesting to see what turns up. Usually the first shows and markets are the best as the dealers have been storing up for the year. I will not try all the markets and try to pace myself. We will have a report of what I saw. Allentown Toy Show Merchant’s Square This is a report I had ready  just before the  software crashed. In Allentown we have a toy show twice a year at Merchants Square an antique mall on the south side of town. I had gone to the last two toy shows and had a good time of buying and finding items so I decided to take the day off from work.  I got at the show about fifteen minutes before it opened.  I did not see my friend John there at the show like he usually is instead I ran into Tom Stine another collector I know. While waiting to get in we talked about various things in our hobby. Tom lamented about have over a hundred pieces of battleground accessories and not able to color match them to make one complete set.  Tom also has the same problem 54mm pioneers. The doors open promptly at 10 and we headed toward the large room where the show was being held. Merchant’s Square has a very large room that is rented out for various collectible shows and even wrestling. Once I entered the room, I got a feeling that the show was off. The number of dealers was down. I found out later that the promoters had given extra tables to the dealers to cover the lack of dealers at the show. Even doing that there were empty tables. I started to walk around and I was able to find various items for resale. One dealer had Britains Herald figure on a stand and laying camel.  From another dealer I got a bunch of trucks for resale. I was able to get a figure I need for a person and few odds and ends, but it was not the show as before. I left after an hour. We had to get Quinn a new pack and play as the old one would not stay up on one side. We are using it for him at night instead of the crate and he seems to be happy with it. It is interesting in the morning to come into the room where he is and see a bouncing daschund. We let him share the other rooms with Sparky and Percy  during the day while we are at work. I am still trying to learn Word Press and it will be a few days more for the regular Comment Time. In the meantime I am going to post a few things here on our hobby etc. Someone on Ebay tried to sell 150,000 pieces of Helen Toy figures.  This was one of the companies that advertised in the Comic Books various figure sets over the years.  So far no one has bought it that I know of as they were asking $25,000.00. CTS has done a new set of Union Figures. Three of the poses are copies of the Andy Gard Figures. I hope to pick up a set at MFCA. One feature with Word Press is you can make  comments on the blog. So if you want to  speak your two cents go ahead.  I will review them if they are approate I will post them. The boys are doing good and are demanding a page of their own. We will have pictures of them up on their own page as soon as I learn how to post pictures.  Quinn will be one year old in June.  He has learn to get up on the top of the sofa which is Sparky’s spot which has made Sparky unhappy. I have been getting out to some flea markets and shows. The flea markets have been weak in number of dealers, but I have made been some good buys. I was able to find a Marx army truck in excellent shape minus an axle which I was able to get off from a friend.  I just got in a Eldon Naval Sea Plane which I have never seen before that I can remember.  Laurie has been finding jewelry which she is slowly posting to our Ebay store. The one stand she was buying jewelry I found a Britains horse. The next time back I found the Britains Eyes Right Mountie with lance. The figure is only missing the saddle and the paper pendant. When I go out anymore I am not looking just for plastic toy soldiers. I can end up buying anything collectible that I think can sell. Today I was out and bought two Tv Guides as I have done well with them the last few months. One of the funny things I sold on Ebay recently was aSanta pop on Flashlight. It is the head of Santa to go on a flashlight. I had it given to me by a party for free as we were buying other stuff from him.  I just put it up on Ebay as a lark. Well enough for now It will take me awhile to get things back up to what we had.  Comment Time will be up shortly in a new format and we have much more planned. So stay tune. Thanks for your patience and understanding while we work through this. Check our items up at Ebay under user id stadsstuff.  We keep adding alot of new items every week. 
Joe Hehn ran a mail order old time radio business. He lived two blocks away from the old house in this two bedroom apartment. I met him and got involved in his mail order business. From him I learned about the cover letter.

From learning from these two gentlemen, I decided to do Comment Time as part of my list.  At that time we had no outlet for information. I took one page for the news and commentary. Also I did not want the list to be cold and dry as other lists that just printed sales item. Stad’s list did.  I am quite proud of what I did with it as it helped start the formation of our hobby.

As to the grammar and spelling on Comment Time, I agree it was horrible. Why it was that way there a several possibilities. I might have a hidden learning disability. I was not great in English in school or college.  I think faster than I write. I was always in a rush to complete the list and did not go back and check or have someone else.  If you meet me in public or talk on the phone, my grammar is excellent. I used to be very touchy on this subject; I have mellowed over the years. (Laurie might disagree). One improvement if I use it, the word processing programs are doing a great job on spelling and grammar.

From the response I am seeing people are enjoying seeing the old Comment Times. Do I a favorite tell your friends where we are? So they can also enjoy my new comments on the hobby.

 

 I will also be doing an article on the Dollar Tree painted mounted knights. There are four different mounted knights two different with a lance, with sword and mace.  The knights remind you of Lido. The horses are little disappointing as they are not armored, but they are better than Dulcop’s generic horses that were used with their knights. 

 ToyTown 
 
I’ve posted some pictures of my time at OTSN at http://playsetaddict.com/OTSN2011report.html 

 
 More on OTS 

Mel is not the one to use Hitler for Comedy. A party from the UK did a sitcom in the 1990’s called“Heil Honey”.  It is a situation comedy with Hitler and Eva Braun living together with next door Jewish Neighbors!  I am not making this up, Hitler sounds like a Ralph Kramden.

If you want to see it go the spot listed below to see a sample of the show. Pop Matters which listed it as the worst TV screw up noted that a list of UK“Greatest TV moments from Hell”listed Heil Honey as only the 61 worse moments in British Comedy.

 http://www.popmatters.com/pm/post/149761-the-10-most-spectacular-screwups-in-television-history/P1 

On Sunday November 6 th the 29 th East Coast Toy Soldier Show will be held at the Rothman Center Farleigh Dickinson University in Hackensack New Jersey.  This is a great toy soldier show that I have enjoyed going to since the beginning.  The center will be loaded with all kinds of toy soldiers for everyone’s budget.  If you are into metal there will be dealers with old and new metal.  For the plastic collector you have a wide range plastic to choose from. At this show you will have to look both on and under the table.  You will get to see samples of the new AIP Camel Corp which will be out later this month.  If you are looking for new plastic figures, there will be a number of dealers with them on their stalls. The doors will open at 9:00AM. Laurie and I will be there and we hope to see you there.

For more details go to http://vintagecastings.com/

 Several collectors have emailed me about some of the prices they have seen on Ebay. One collector noted a small Marx Civil War Playset still stapled, the person wanted $7500.00! The person is requiring the person to pick it up because of fear of shipping it. 

 Another collector sent me two listings for the Marx 60mm knight horse. One person wanted $35.00 for two horses and one of the tails was broken. The other had the Marx 60mm knight horse in white for $19.99. At this moment your mind should be going Marx did not do the 60mm knight horse in white. That color was done when it was reissued. 

 Yes Ebay has these silly prices. I just saw someone wants $40.00 for a 45mm Marx fireman. The key point is to learn your hobby and be patience. Most figures come up again. Do not get caught up in the auction silliness. I put a price limit on what I will pay and if I get it fine, if not there will be other days.  As I mentioned recently one of my recent purchases was Medieval figure with weapon and shield for $.50 and I like him for the pose.  I am not worried if he is rare or not. 
 
40 Responses to Stad’s Stuff 

 Don Perkins says: March 27, 2011 at 9:26 PM 
Hi Paul: I’m glad to see you’re back up. I usually check out Comment Time a couple of times a week, and couldn’t figure out what was happening when I kept getting the Joomla face page. My wife and I are going to the Indiana Toy Soldier Show in Indianapolis this coming weekend. It is a Sunday show so we’re staying at the show site hotel on Saturday. Supposedly, the Indiana show has room dealers the couple of days before the show, like OTSN. So we’ll see. Barzso always shows up at this show, and will have his new Fort Apache—just the fort, not a whole playset. You can see it on the Barzso website if you haven’t seen it yet. It seems somewhat expensive, like all his stuff these days. But it looks pretty nice, and I’ll probably end up getting one.
Then, as I mentioned, I’m planning on going to OTSN this year. I’ve already got my room reservations on either 4th or 5th floor. Since my wife doesn’t want to go to Chicago with me, I’m spreading the word around the hobby that I’m open to sharing the room with any other hobbyist or dealer who wishes to split the cost of the room. If I don’t get any volunteers, I’m going anyway, just like I did on the show before last. I’ve got reservations for Friday night and Saturday night, but I always check in on Friday morning.
As you probably have heard, Rick Berry has cancelled his April and November Michgian Toy Soldier Show, but Joseph Saine from Toledo is trying to put together a Michigan Toy Soldier Show in July. He says he hopes to distribute a flyer at the Indianapolis Show. We always had a pretty good attendance at the Michigan Show, with Marxman, Hobby Bunker, Alan Ford, Michigan Toy Soldier Co., Joseph Saine, and others. We never had Conte or Barzso.
Well, anyway, hope your wife and dogs are all doing well. Look forward to you getting Comment Time up and running again. Don Perkins
 Reply 
 admin says: March 28, 2011 at 9:39 PM 
Hi Don
Laurie and I had thought of doing the Indy show, we decided against doing the show as it is the same time as another show we love to do. Also we found a Mexican restaurant that is authenic Mexican. Since making that decision we have found two more flea markets and indoor garage sale.
Please give us a report of the show as I am sure your fellow collectors will to love to hear about the show.
Sorry to hear that the Michigan shows have been cancelled. Hopefully Joe will get a new one together.
 Reply 
 chris says: March 27, 2011 at 11:31 PM 
paul-neat figures on ebay- #250793992795
 Reply 
 admin says: March 28, 2011 at 9:32 PM 
Hi Chris.
It is always interesting about figures like the ones you pointed out. These are two figures done by Mattell. The seller knows that the figures are uncommon and the buyers know they are hard to find and willing to pay the price. It will be interesting thing as most people do not know these figures you could find them in a junk box for less than a $1.00.
 Reply 
 Wayne says: March 29, 2011 at 5:48 PM 
Paul, great to see you up and at‘em again. Got a bit worried when I got the Joomla page, was wondering if you and Laurie were all right. Glad to see it was just tech problems; understand completely–just had to buy a new desktop and now my laptop’s gone kaput! Doncha love life in the 21st Century?

Regards, Wayne, the Old All American
 Reply 
 admin says: March 29, 2011 at 9:53 PM 
Hi Wayne
Sorry with the scare on the Joomla page, I was not prepared for the change either. Using WordPress I was able to get the front page change in a hour. Now I have to figure the blog aspect. Joys of technology.
I have lost count on the number of computers I have gone through since my first one which was an Apple II Plus. I now have a lap top which Laurie will use soon for her items that we are putting up on Ebay. We have to get a second computer for the video side.
Stad
 Reply 
 Arthur Belshaw says: April 9, 2011 at 3:39 PM 
Hi Paul. I,m checking your website, as I am trying, without success, to Email Mike Russo, at Stockade, about the Handcart poineers, that you reviewed for PW Mag.. Could use these&amp;any other 54mm US 1860 ish civvies to expand my Union Army, any clues how I find these little guys&amp;ship them to my side of the pond????? I,m stuck at home , convalecsing after surgery,&amp;NEED more figures to work on ANY contact info would be much appreciated
Best regards Arthur Belshaw…
 Reply 
 admin says: April 9, 2011 at 10:52 PM 
Hello Arthur
I call Mike Russo and he got your email but is busy. He does have the Handcart pioneers but does not do foreign mailing. Many people have had bad experience with sending aboard from the states. I do foreign mailing and I plan to get up to his store in the next few weeks and can pick up a set or two. As to civilan figures it gets tough. Replicants has done some civilan figures. Don Ducotte is suppose to be at Plastic Warrior show with his swapables which have some 54mm people that you can use as townspeople. Plasty of Germany did some Western civilan figures in 54mm. Once again some of the German dealers may have them at the Plastic Warrior show. Also Look at the Starlux line as they have Western women and some of their farm people can be adapted. Likewise Elastolin did some soft plastic 54mm farm people who can be used in Civil War. Hope you recover from your surgery to get to the Plastic Warrior show on May 7 in Richmond.

Stad
 Reply 
 Arthur Belshaw says: April 12, 2011 at 2:21 PM 
Hi Stad.
The surgery was for Cancer,&amp;now I,m on Chemo!!! so I ain,t going anyplace very soon!!! They tell me that iWILL be OK., long term, so I,m stuck at home , reveiwing my troops,&amp;converting them into ACW, Just done HAT, Wurtemberg Grenadiers, now starting on the Musketeers( anither 24 troops!!. If YOU get hold of a set of Pioneers, I,LL TAKE THEM!!! Do you have a site that I can send pictures to????
Very best regards Arthur Belshaw.
 Reply 
 admin says: April 12, 2011 at 11:06 PM 
Sorry to hear that that the treatment will not klet you out of the house. I do not get much time to review my figures due to my other work. I hope to get up to Mike in the next two weeks. I am still working on the web site and how to do things I will let you know when to send pictures.
Stad
 Reply 
 Arthur Belshaw says: April 18, 2011 at 11:02 AM 
Thanks pal!! Nice to talk to pllastic figure people, even if I can,t get out&amp;about amongst you
Cheers Arthur Belshaw…
 admin says: April 18, 2011 at 1:43 PM 
Arthur
It looks like it will be next week before I can go and pick up your item from Mike. I am always happy to talk about plastic figures. I remember how it was in the dark ages when you could not mention you collected plasttic figures in fear of people thinking you strange.Tthat has change. I have fun with the people I used to have that junk then I tell them what it is worth they shake their heads. When I collect I do not look at an item is worth, I go for the pose. It goes back to my childhood when I would do stories with them. Laurie like the figures that way as well. Some of my favorite figures are worth only a few dollars. So enjoy the figures they are alot of fun.
 
 
 
 
 Bill Nevins says: April 15, 2011 at 12:07 AM 
Bill Hamilton was one of the nicest guys I have ever met in this hobby. He was honest, cheerful and always fun to chat with. His passing is a loss to all of us who remember when. Our ranks are thinning as the years roll by. My deepest sympathies to his family and friends. God bless you, Bill…..Bill Nevins
 Reply 
 admin says: April 15, 2011 at 2:16 PM 
Yes Bill was a good guy. Last time I saw him was at a Hackensack Show many years ago.
 Reply 
 admin says: April 18, 2011 at 1:36 PM 
We always like the kind words from our readers. I glad to hear people enjoy my comments.
 Reply 
 admin says: April 18, 2011 at 9:17 PM 
We are still learning Word press thanks for your comments. I have deleted them.
 Reply 
 Arthur Belshaw says: April 26, 2011 at 6:41 PM 
Hi Paul
thanks for the kind sentiments, It does get lonely without fellow collectors/convertors to chat to. Could you drop me an Email, when you get those bits,&amp;we,ll work out the“how&amp;whys!”
best regards Arthur Belshaw..
 Reply 
 admin says: April 26, 2011 at 10:44 PM 
I will let you know when I get the items. I hope tp get up to Mike next week. This week I have theMFCA Show on FridayI know how you feel it does get lonely at times. The nice thing with email you can drop a person a line. I will email you tomorrow.
 Reply 
 Lynn Graves says: May 24, 2011 at 11:39 AM 
Paul, I have a photo of a space figure that may be a companion to the one you have posted. But I don’t know how to email it to you now.
 Reply 
 admin says: May 24, 2011 at 12:16 PM 
Lynn send the picture to my email address I will then copy and post it to web site.
 Reply 
 Bill nevins says: June 23, 2011 at 5:06 PM 
I just picked up a group of off white hard plastic knights that are marked :SEVEN ARTS INC. WARNER BROS in a circle underneath the bases. Thre is a mounted figure along with a Queen and a few men at arms. There is also a guy shooting a bow and arrow (maybe Robin Hood?).
Anyone have info on these?
 Reply 
 admin says: June 25, 2011 at 7:21 PM 
Bill
sorry I was not able to reply sooner to your question but I was in West Virginia and could not response to yopu question. The hotel had a computer but it very untrust worthy. As you found out from the Marx Group, the figures were done by Aurora for Camelot. They were on a blister card which is hard to find. The figures are a hard plastic and are one of three groups they did. The other two are Tarzan and Wizard of OZ.
 Reply 
 Whit Knight says: July 7, 2011 at 2:57 PM 
Paul, please let your viewer/readers know that I have a number of toy soldier (and Marx dinosaur) photo albums posted on my profile page on Facebook. Thanks!
 Reply 
 admin says: July 7, 2011 at 9:29 PM 
We have listed your comment and should tell us more
 Reply 
 BILL NEVINS says: July 17, 2011 at 5:59 PM 
Paul can I mention my plastics conversions group here? Here is the link

 http://groups.yahoo.com/group/CUSTOMCONVERSIONS/ 

If anyone here is interested in 54 mm plastic toy soldiers
and enjoys making conversions, feel free to join the group on Yahoo. We discuss reworking plastic figures and making unique poses to go along with our stock figures. All manner of collecting plastic toy soldier (and metal, too) are discussed and plenty of photo’s and“how to’s”are in the files.

Everyone is welcome and encouraged to share their creations. It OK to just lurk and learn, too.

Anything to do with 54 mm toy soldiers is open to discussion. Come by and join us.
 Reply 
 admin says: July 17, 2011 at 6:44 PM 
Bill
I have posted your request. I enjoy conversion figures. One of the conversion figures in the collection is a Marx 60mm Pirate changed to Turkey with a spear. The best conversion I have seen was a soccer player that my very good friend Peter Evans converted into a Reinassace figure with a sword. It sit in a honor spot in the collection
 Reply 
 admin says: August 24, 2011 at 10:08 PM 
Hi Carolyn
I do not know of a store jn New York. Perhaps one of our readers can give a suggestion. I would suggest you check your local hobby store as they should have figure sets. In November if you can get to Hackensack New Jersey the first Sunday in November there is toy soldier show with a great selection of figures at various prices.
 Reply wm mcdonnell says: October 1, 2011 at 9:09 AM 
i have bought the four mounted knights they are realy nice and go well with many of the other knights in my collection inoticed pictures of foot knights on the blister card also does anyone know where i can find the foot knights
 Reply 
 admin says: October 1, 2011 at 10:37 AM 
Hi William
I have not heard of anyone getting the foot figures. When we do we will let you know.
 Reply 
 Greg Anglin says: October 10, 2011 at 9:17 AM 
Paul-I was unaware that Bill Hamilton passed away! When did this happen. DO you know why? I know I had visted him last about 1 1/2 yrs ago,&amp;he had been suffering from Lyme disease. It was pretty serious&amp;he was getting better but had a relapse. Is this what killed him?? I’m really shocked over this as he&amp;I were friends. Greg
 Reply 
 admin says: October 10, 2011 at 6:43 PM 
Hi Greg
It was a great loss when Bill Hamilton pass away. He was a great guy and I enjoy talking to him when I saw him at a show. He passed away in the last few months. One of the other reader can give more details.
 Reply 
 Andy Keliar says: October 11, 2011 at 5:29 PM 
Bill died on March 31, 2011. I cut&amp;pasted obituary below.

 http://www.legacy.com/obituaries/timesunion-albany/obituary.aspx?n=william-j-hamilton&amp;pid=149869163&amp;fhid=4784 
 Reply 
 admin says: October 11, 2011 at 7:04 PM 
Thanks Andy for the informqation
 Reply 
 Ed Borris says: December 9, 2011 at 7:13 AM 
Not sure if you guys happened to see these on e-bay, but the Plastic Underground has come out with some new Robin Hood figures, so far there is just the four, Robin, Will Scarlet, Friar Tuck and Little John. ( you can view by searching on seller vikingpope) They are really nice looking figures with excellent pain jobs, really worth a look if you are into Robin Hood. I spoke with him and he intends to go further with that line with additional figures including the Sheriff’s Men. Some may consider them a bit pricey, but they are nice and worth the trouble to take a peek.
 Reply Ed Borris says: December 22, 2011 at 8:11 AM 
White Castle highly over rated, I have had White Castle available to me my whole life. At one time I lived two blocks from one and in the 10 years I lived there I never went once. They were more desirable in my youth because they used to costs 12 cents for a hamburger.
 Reply 
 admin says: December 22, 2011 at 10:12 AM 
Ed
I am not going to disagree with you on White Castle. It is something I want to try at least once. We never had one around here and I want to see what it is all about. I have been amaze the number of cars that have been going there and it nearly three months. They have not opened the normal way in yet due the lines.
Laurie and I have only a few places we like to eat. Of those places two stand out Olive Branch and Chipolte. Olive Branch is a family run Mid Eastern restaurant that food is home made and great. Chipolte is another great place and what I like about it the food is healthy. The beef, pork and chiken is free range and does not have the chemicals in it. It is the“fast food”restaurant I would be on the look out for on a trip.
I hope to get into White Castle soon so I can give you my feelings.
 Reply 
 Ed Borris says: December 22, 2011 at 3:02 PM 
Well, usually you either love them or hate them, they are unique, quite small by the way. In fact, many restaurants and bars sell small burgers of their own and call them sliders which is a popular name for the White Castle burgers
 Reply 
 admin says: December 23, 2011 at 12:16 AM 
I agree with you Ed. We will love them or hate them. We had the sliders at a place in Hackensack New Jersey White Manna and like them. I read a blog where you had people like them or hating them. There are people that rave about Five Guys. They think it is best thing in the world. Laurie and I are unimpressed with Five Guys. We have tried it several times. If we were hungry and no where else was convient we would eat there. Other people would go out of their way to Five Guys.
 Reply 
 George Albany says: May 24, 2012 at 12:15 PM 
Question for everyone. My wife and I are taking a short trip up the coast to Boothbay Harbor in early June. Are there any unique toy soldier retailers or manufacturers along the New England Coast? I’ve done a couple quick searches and can’t find anything. Don’t care if it’s metal or plastic, just would like to see something different for a change.
 Reply 
 admin says: May 25, 2012 at 9:36 AM 
George
Sadly I do not know of any toy soldier shops as it is getting harder to find them. Close toy shop I would know is Hobby Bunker and I am not sure if you will be any way near close.
 Reply 
 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 Comment 

You may use these HTML tags and attributes: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;abbr title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;acronym title=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;cite&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;del datetime=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;q cite=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;strike&gt;&lt;strong&gt; 

 

 
 
 Search for: 
Recent Posts

 London Toy Soldier Show Moving Ernest Borgnine Polish Figures Part One Coreography for Plastic Soldiers Russian Romans Part Two 
 
Recent Comments

 admin on Flea Markets Don Perkins on Flea Markets Wayne Wood on Flea Markets admin on Russian Romans Part Two Don Perkins on Russian Romans Part Two 
 
Archives

 July 2012 June 2012 May 2012 April 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 March 2011 
 
Categories

 Uncategorized 
 
Meta

 Log in Entries RSS Comments RSS WordPress.org 
 
 Stad&apos;s Stuff Proudly powered by WordPress.
	</body>
</document>
