<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003622" url="http://reportyourcomplaint.com/brusters-ice-cream-parlor-compliment-amazing-and-delicious-ice-cream-with-awesome-promotions/" time="2012-07-12-19:47" support="2" score="0.005702712355554435" bingtitle="Bruster&apos;s Ice Cream Parlor Compliment - Amazing and Delicious Ice ..." webtitle="Bruster&apos;s Ice Cream Parlor Compliment - Amazing and Delicious Ice Cream with Awesome Promotions! | Report Your Complaint.com">
			<query id="000163" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="000412" bing-rank="133"/>
	<description>When you sign up on the home page, you will receive ... So much so that I cancelled my order on the spot (as ... Customer service disgusting Educational fast food fast food ...</description>
	<body>
		Log In 
 
 RYC (Home) Companies Complaints Reviews Compliments Helpful tips&amp;info Credit repair About us Site Index Blog 
 

 
Random Posts

 Filing your consumer complaints here on ReportYourComplaint.com to get the best results of any consumer reporting website! Walmart cashier and customer service complaint - customer service at Walmart downright sucks! Town&amp;Country Fence installation review - I had them install an aluminum fence for my backyard and it looks great! Chalean Extreme Workout with Weights review - a great workout dvd set! Krieger Ford Columbus Ohio car dealership review - bad, rude customer service all the way around. Ollies Bargain Outlet, Compare Prices to Other Stores Before Buying From Here! HSBC Big Lots Credit Card Complaint - They Debited My Bank Account And Told Me They Never Recieved A Payment And Applied Interest Charges! AMTC Auditions - a mega scam for Christ! Beware of and avoid this scam! AAA Roadside Assistance Review - Long Wait Time If You Need Any Roadside Assistance! Burger King Complaint - Found Plastic Wrap In My Burger And No Response From Corporate! 
 
Recent Comments

 skyday on Great Stuff insulating foam sealant review–this stuff works great for sealing and insulating gaps and cracks SCAM on Childhood leukemia Foundation–a review of a shady charity that uses auto dialers and other shady practices to get donations Mike on HomeVestors home buyers is a shady scam and offers you far less than your home is worth! Chris Brady on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? Lee on Stanley Steemer–fraudulant business practices, abusive telemarketing and a bad rug cleaning experience! Lisa Carroll on Lowe’s and Harbor Breeze ceiling fans–are the ceiling fans they sell of good quality and durability? brenda on Walgreen’s pharmacy–incorrectly filled prescription and they refused to fix it! S.K. Thompson on Virginia State Troopers Complaint–Police officers have too much power and get away with breaking laws! 
 Privacy Policy 
Bruster’s Ice Cream Parlor Compliment – Amazing and Delicious Ice Cream with Awesome Promotions!
 By MyrtleTraveler 
 




When my family and I go out for ice cream, we always go to Bruster’s.  Bruster’s ice cream is the best ice cream I have ever had in my entire life.  Every time we go, I always order the white chocolate raspberry truffle ice cream.  We go to Brusters because of their amazing customer service and of course their amazing quality ice cream.

Bruster’s ice cream is very creamy and full of delicious flavors.  The prices at Bruster’s are very reasonable for the amount of ice cream you receive.  I order the single scoop in a waffle cone and I have a hard time finishing it.  I am always so full that I think my family needs to roll me to the car!

Bruster’s menu includes waffle cones, splits, blasts, smoothies, shakes, pies, ice cream cakes, and also sundaes.  Another great part to Brusters is the promotions they run all season long.  One great promotion is called Banana Thursday.  This entails that a customer can bring a banana to Bruster’s and they will pay only half price the original price of a banana split.  So in the end, you provide the banana and Bruster’s will provide the ice cream and the toppings.

 Have an axe to grind? Want to get even? Leave your own complaints here at ReportYourComplaint.com and help others avoid businesses and companies with which you’ve had terrible experiences! 

Another great promotion at Brusters is called the “Quart Club”.  This promotion entails that after ordering your sixth quart of ice cream, you will receive the seventh quart for free.  This plays out nice if you are the type that stops at Bruster’s and brings home ice cream for the whole family.  Brusters will give you a card that they punch and then when you receive your free seventh quart you turn it in and start all over again.

The next promotion that they have is an older generation oriented promotion called the “Kid at Heart Club”.  This club is for the opposite generation that you would think it would be for.  It is for customers that are over 60 and gives them $.25 cents off their purchase every time they go to Brusters.


 Your Ad Here 


The true kid’s promotion allows any child that is less than 40 inches tall receive a free Baby Cone.  This is to allow even the smallest family member enjoy everyone’s favorite food, ice cream!  Even though this promotion if for the smallest family member, they still didn’t leave out the other small family member, the dog.  Bruster’s even has a promotion for the family dog, which is “Doggie Sundae”.  This entails the family dog to get a free doggie sundae whatever day you go.

The last promotion that Brusters offer is called “PJ Day”.  When Bruster’s has its official PJ Day, anyone can roll out of bed in their PJ’s and receive a free single scoop waffle cone for free.  Although this promotion is ran once a year, it is awesome to roll right out of bed and head to the ice cream parlor for a free treat.

Even though Bruster’s has many promotions for money saving opportunities, you still can find coupons in the clipper magazine, Entertainment book, and also the Bruster’s club that you can sign up on their homepage.  When you sign up on the home page, you will receive emails that have all sorts of coupons and notifications about certain deals.  These deals include buy one, get one free single scoop waffle cone, couple cents off your purchase, or savings on a cake.  I highly recommend everyone to go to Bruster’s and try their amazing and delicious ice cream.



 
Posts Related to Bruster’s Ice Cream Parlor Compliment – Amazing and Delicious Ice Cream with Awesome Promotions!

 
 Dippin Dots Compliment and Review–Amazing Frozen Ice Cream Treats That Everyone Should Try! 

// The other day I took my kids to a NBA game and while we were there I bought my kids Dippin Dots.  They wanted ...
 
 Cold Stone Creamery Complaint – Ridiculous Priced Ice Cream With Horrible Wait Times! 

// Last night I went out with a group of friends to a movie and then out to ice cream.  We were all debating which ...
 
 Edys Shakes and Smoothies Review–Personal Shakes and Smoothies Where You Only Need To Add Milk And Stir! 

// Today I was able to experience a brand new product of Edys Ice Cream called the Slow Churned Shake.  I really thought that it ...
 
 Lowe’s Foods Bakery Review–Delicious and Incredible Desiged Cakes With Amazing Customer Service 

// Yesterday my family and I had a baby shower for my sister at our local clubhouse.  We had gone through all the planning for ...
 
 Dermalogica dry skin care treatment review–I bought a few of these Dermalogica products at Ulta and they are amazing! 

// I am an older woman with sun damaged skin. I wish I had known better when I was younger to not tan so much ...
 
 
 Tags: amazing , amazing food , awesome customer service , Brusters , compliment , food , ice cream chains , ice cream parlors , money saving opportunities , promotions , recommended , rediculous prices , review 
 
2 Responses to Bruster’s Ice Cream Parlor Compliment – Amazing and Delicious Ice Cream with Awesome Promotions! 

 barry on March 29, 2011 at 12:51 PM 

The store manager, SANTO, at the Prattville, Alabama store told me that if there were a particular ice cream not on the menu, they could make it for me, but I would need to get a half gallon and let them know a day ahead so they could prepare it. Last Friday March 25, 2011, I went to the Prattville store and I spoke with Jennifer and requested a half gallon of hersey chocalate at the Bruster’s store in Prattville and she called the manager, SANTO and he told her I would need to get a gallon and I told her that were not what he had told me before, she relaid the message and he told her if I would wait three days than he would make my request. This is very unprofessional. I frequent this business on a regular basic and as a customer if this is how I am going to be treated I will have to go somewhere else.

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 Alisha N on August 2, 2011 at 2:52 PM 

I went to the Busters Ice Cream Shop located in Albany Georgia and received the worst customer service I have ever experienced in my life. The woman, whom I believe to the owner (elderly, Caucasian, blonde hair with gray) was highly unprofessional. So much so that I cancelled my order on the spot (as much as I love butter pecan). After experiencing the death of a loved one two days prior, her attitude was the very last thing that I needed.

Like or Dislike: 0   0 
 
 
Leave a Reply Cancel reply 
 
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked * 

 Name * 

 Email * 

 Website 

 

 

 
 
Search Website
 Most Popular
Complaints, Reviews, and Compliments! Want your company&apos;s product or service reviewed?
 
Archives
 Select Month June 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 June 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 December 2010 November 2010 October 2010 September 2010 August 2010 July 2010 June 2010 May 2010 April 2010 March 2010 Your Ad Here 
Tags
 automotive Awesome bad customer service car car dealer car dealership chain restaurants Charlotte Charlotte NC complaint compliment Customer service disgusting Educational fast food fast food restaurant food fraud health Helpful helpful information highly recommended honest review Horrible horrible customer service horrible service How to illegal Interesting Not recommended rave recommended restaurant review ripoff rude save money scam sucks Terrible unfair business practices unhealthy untrustworthy Walmart website Copyright©2012 Report Your Complaint.com . All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
