<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003275" url="http://www.play.com/Books/Books/-/159/216/-/14878198/The-Takeaway-Secret-How-to-Cook-Your-Favourite-Fast-food-at-Home-Kenny-McGovern/Product.html" time="2012-07-12-19:24" support="2" score="0.00577042992586755" bingtitle="The Takeaway Secret - Kenny McGovern - Food &amp; Drink Books at Play ..." webtitle="The Takeaway Secret - Kenny McGovern - FoodDrink Books at Play.com (UK)">
			<query id="000238" bing-rank="93"/>
			<query id="000895" bing-rank="231"/>
	<description>Food and Drink; For Her; For Him; Pamper; Unique Gifts; See all Experience Gifts; Games ... Our Credit Card. Representative 16.9% APR (variable) Rewards scheme; Credit Card FAQ</description>
	<body>
		Hello, Welcome to Play.com.   . ( Not you Sign in ?) | Create an account 

 All Departments Baby Books Blu-ray Clothing Computing DVD Electronics Gifts&amp;Gadgets Mobile Music Office Sports&amp;Outdoors Toys Video Games GO 
 
 
Search Suggestions
 
 
 £  €  

 Your account Help 
 
 View Basket 
 
 DVD 
 DVD Categories 
 
 Action&amp;Adventure Adult Animation Anime BBC Box Sets Christmas Classics Comedy Complete Boxsets Crime&amp;Thriller Cult Movies&amp;TV 
 
 Disney Documentary Drama Fitness Gay&amp;Lesbian Hobbies&amp;Interests Horror Kids&amp;Family Martial Arts Music DVDs Musicals 
 
 Romance Science Fiction Sport Stand-up Comedy Superheroes Television TV Boxsets Vampires&amp;Zombies War Westerns World Cinema See all DVD 
 
DVD Charts

 Top Sellers New Releases Pre-Order Chart Notify Me Coming Soon Recommends 

 DVD Bargains 

 Action Adventure Best of British Film and TV Box Set Bonanza Disney Summer Magic DVD Clearance Entertainment Blitz Great Titles, Great Prices See all DVD Bargains 
 Blu-ray 
 Blu-ray Categories 
 
 3D on Blu-ray Action&amp;Adventure Animation Anime Box Sets Christmas Classics Comedy Crime&amp;Thriller Cult Movies&amp;TV 
 
 Disney Documentaries Drama Hobbies&amp;Interests Horror Kids&amp;Family Martial Arts Music Blu-rays Musicals Romance 
 
 Science Fiction Sport Stand-up Comedy Television War Westerns World Cinema See all Blu-ray 
 
Blu-ray Charts

 Top Sellers New Releases Pre-Order Chart Notify Me Coming Soon Recommends 

 Blu-ray Bargains 

 Best of British TV Deals of the Week Disney Summer Magic Great Titles, Great Prices See all Blu-ray Bargains 
 Music 
 Music Categories 
 
 Blues Christmas&amp;Seasonal Classical Compilations Country Dance Easy Listening Folk Hip Hop&amp;Rap Indie Jazz Kids 
 
 Metal&amp;Hard Rock Pop Reggae Reissues Rock Soul&amp;R&amp;B; Soundtracks World&amp;International See all Music 

 See all MP3 
 
Top Artists

 Adele Blur Bruce Springsteen Bruno Mars Coldplay Ed Sheeran Iron Maiden Jessie J Madonna Meatloaf Olly Murs Paul Weller Pink Floyd Whitney Houston See all 
 
Music Charts

 Top Sellers New Releases Pre-Order Chart Coming Soon Recommends 

 CD Bargains 

 Indie Greats Play.com exclusive CDs See all bargains 
 Video Games 
 Xbox 360 Games 

 Action&amp;Adventure Driving&amp;Racing Kinect Shooter See all Xbox 360 Games 

Xbox 360 Hardware&amp;Accessories

 Accessories Consoles&amp;Bundles 

 Xbox 360 Charts 

 Top Sellers New Releases Pre-Order Chart Coming Soon 

 See all Xbox 360 
 
 PS3 Games 

 Action&amp;Adventure Driving&amp;Racing Shooter Sport See all PS3 Games 

PS3 Hardware&amp;Accessories

 Accessories Consoles&amp;Bundles 

 PS3 Charts 

 Top Sellers New Releases Pre-Order Chart Coming Soon 

 See all PS3 
 
 Wii Games 

 Action&amp;Adventure Health&amp;Fitness Kids&amp;Family Party, Music&amp;Dancing See all Wii Games 

Wii Hardware&amp;Accessories

 Accessories Consoles&amp;Bundles 

 Wii Charts 

 Top Sellers New Releases Pre-Order Chart Coming Soon 

 See all Wii 
 
Other Formats

 DS, DSi&amp;3DS PC Games PS Vita PSP 

Top Searches

 Battlefield Call Of Duty Black Ops 2 Far Cry 3 FIFA Street Max Payne 3 Resident Evil Retro Games Skylanders Star Wars UEFA Euro 2012 Uncharted 
 
Games Offers

 2 for £20 Disney Summer of Magic Games from £4.99 New for 2012 Platinum and Classics Play Recommends 
 Books 
 Books Categories 
 
 Art&amp;Photography Biography Business, Finance&amp;Law Classics&amp;Poetry Computing&amp;Internet Crafts&amp;Hobbies Crime&amp;Thrillers Education Fiction Food&amp;Drink Game Guides Graphic Novels Health&amp;Fitness History Home&amp;Garden Horror 
 
 Humour Kids Mind, Body&amp;Spirit Music&amp;Film Reference Religion Science&amp;Nature Science Fiction&amp;Fantasy Society&amp;Politics Sports&amp;Games Teen Travel&amp;Transport See all Books See all Audiobooks Kobo eReaders The Hunger Games 
 
Top Authors

 George R. R. Martin James Patterson Jamie Oliver Jennifer Worth J. K. Rowling Jodi Picoult Karin Slaughter Karen Rose Katie Price Lee Child Lesley Pearce Lindsay Kelk Martina Cole Sophie Kinsella Stephen King Stephenie Meyer Terry Pratchett 

 Kobo eReader 

 Kobo eReaders Kobo Accessories 
 
Book Charts

 Top Sellers New Releases Pre-Order Chart Coming Soon Recommends 

 Books Bargains 

 New for 2012 See the film, read the book See all Book Bargains 
 Clothing 
 Men&apos;s Clothing 

 Coats&amp;Jackets Footwear Hoodies&amp;Sweats Jeans Knitwear Loungewear Shirts Socks Swimwear Trousers&amp;Shorts T-shirts&amp;Polos Underwear See all Men&apos;s See all Men&apos;s Footwear 

 Shop Clearance 
 
 Men&apos;s Accessories 

 Bags Belts Hats Socks Sunglasses Umbrellas Wallets Watches 

Shop by Size

 Small Medium Large X Large XX Large XXX Large 

 A-Z of Brands 
 
 Women&apos;s Clothing 

 Coats&amp;Jackets Dresses Hoodies&amp;Sweats Jeans Knitwear Loungewear Skirts Tops Trousers&amp;Shorts T-shirts Underwear See all Women&apos;s See all Women&apos;s Footwear 

 Shop Clearance 
 
 Women&apos;s Accessories 

 Bags Belts Hats Jewellery Sunglasses Tights&amp;Socks Umbrellas Watches 

Shop by Size

 8 10 12 14 16 

 A-Z of Brands 
 
Boys

 Accessories Clothing Footwear See all Boys&apos; 

Girls

 Accessories Clothing Footwear See all Girls&apos; 
 Sports&amp;Outdoors 
Shop by Activity

 Badminton Boxing and Martial Arts Camping Cricket Cycling Darts Fishing Fitness Football Golf Hockey Nutrition Rugby Running Squash Swimming Tennis Walking Snow Sports 
 
Men&apos;s Clothing

 Cycling Football Outdoor Running, Fitness and Leisure Swimwear 

 Men&apos;s Footwear 

 Boots and Shoes Court Fitness Football Running See all Men&apos;s Footwear 
 
Women&apos;s Clothing

 Running and Fitness Swimming Tennis Walking Snow Sports 

 Women&apos;s Footwear 

 Court Fitness Running Tennis See all Women&apos;s Footwear 
 
Kids&apos; Clothing

 Football Running and fitness Boys&apos; Outerwear Girls&apos; Outerwear Boys&apos; Snow Sports Girls&apos; Snow Sports 

 Kids&apos; Footwear
(3 - 5.5) 

 Football Running See all Kids&apos; sizes 3 - 5.5 

 Kids&apos; Footwear
(10 - 2) 

 Football See all Kids&apos; sizes 10 - 2 
 
 Shop by Brands 

 adidas Asics Bear Grylls Columbia Dare2b Fitness Mad High Street TV Highlander London 2012 Mitre Pineapple Puma Raleigh Reebok Regatta Shock Absorber Speedo Trespass York Fitness A-Z of Brands 
 
Bikes

 Adult Bikes Kids&apos; Bikes 

 Rucksacks 

 Outdoors Sports 

Sports and Outdoor Offers

 Everything for €6.49 Did You Know We Sell... Over 50% off jackets Up to 60% off Mitre Clothing 
 Electronics 
 Televisions 

 3D TV Internet TV LCD TV LED TV Set-Top Boxes TV DVD Combi See all Televisions 

 Home Cinema 

 2.1 Home Cinema Systems 5.1 Home Cinema Systems Blu-ray Players DVD Players See all Home Cinema 
 
 iPod&amp;MP3 Players 

 iPods MP3 Players iPod Docks Covers&amp;Cases See all iPod and MP3 Players 

 Headphones 

 In Ear Over Ear Noise Cancelling Sports See all Headphones 
 
 Audio Systems 

 DAB Radios Internet Radios Micro Systems Portable Radios See all Audio Systems 

 Cameras&amp;Photo 

 Cameras Camcorders Digital Photo Frames See all Cameras and Photo 
 
 Memory Cards 

 SD Cards Memory Stick Compact Flash See all Memory Cards 

 In Car Entertainment 

 Sat Nav Portable DVD Players Portable CD players See all In Car Entertainment 

 Kobo eReader 

 Kobo eReaders Kobo Accessories 
 
Top Brands

 Apple Canon Monster Panasonic Samsung SanDisk Sennheiser Skullcandy Sony 

Electronics Offers

 Headphones - Save up to 50% Memory Cards - Save up to 40% Small Screen TVs from€164.99 
 Computing&amp;Office 
 Computers 

 Accessories Desktop PCs Laptops Monitors Tablets&amp;iPads See all 

 Components 

 Desktop Memory DVD&amp;Blu-ray Drives Graphics Cards Laptop Memory See all 

 Kobo eReader 

 Kobo eReaders Kobo Accessories 
 
 Storage 

 External Hard Drives Flash Drives Internal Hard Drives Network Hard Drives See all 

 Networking 

 Homeplug&amp;Powerline Media Streamers Network Cards&amp;USB Wireless Networking See all 
 
 Peripherals 

 Keyboards Mice PC Gaming Accessories Webcams See all 

Printers, Ink&amp;Paper

 Ink Cartridges Photo Paper Printers&amp;Scanners 

 Software 

 Antivirus&amp;Security Business&amp;Office Photo&amp;Video Editing See all 
 
 Office&amp;Stationery 

 Calculators Educational Supplies Electronic Dictionaries Filing&amp;Storage Markers&amp;Highlighters Office Furniture Padded Envelopes&amp;Bags Paper Supplies Pens and Refills Post&amp;Packing Post-it&amp;Sticky Notes See all Office 
 
Top Brands

 Acer Apple Hewlett Packard Logitech Microsoft Samsung SanDisk Seagate Sony Western Digital 

Computing Offers

 Tablets from €81.49 New Laptops from £249.99 
 Mobile 
 Sim-free Phones 

 Apple BlackBerry HTC LG Motorola Nokia Samsung Sony Ericcson See all Sim Free 
 
 Pay As You Go Phones 

 3 O2 Orange T-Mobile Virgin Vodafone See all Pay As You Go 
 
 Accessories 

 Batteries Bluetooth Car Kits Cases Data&amp;Connectivity Headphones&amp;Speakers Memory Cards See all Mobile Accessories 
 
Special Offers

 Sim Free Top Sellers Pre-pay Top Sellers Accessories Top Sellers Car Kits from €12.49 Latest Android Smartphones from €93.99 
 Gifts&amp;Gadgets 
 Home and Office 

 Bathroom Candles&amp;Fragrance Home Mugs Kitchen Office See all Home and Office 

 Fancy Dress 

 Accessories Decades Masks Superheroes&amp;Comic Book Wigs See all Fancy Dress 
 
 Experience Gifts 

 Drive Food and Drink For Her For Him Pamper Unique Gifts See all Experience Gifts 

 Games 

 Board Games Puzzles Sport See all Games 
 
 Memorabilia 

 Action Movies Comedy Horror Gaming Music Sci Fi TV See all Memorabilia 

 Posters 

 Art Comedy Comics Film Gaming Music See all Posters 
 
 Girls Allowed 

 Beauty Fun&amp;Games Gifts See all 

 Lads&amp;Dads 

 Fun Games Novelty See all 

 Remote Controlled Toys 

 Cars And Boats Helicopters See all Remote Controlled Toys 
 
Top Brands

 Star Wars Doctor Who Marvel DC Comics Harry Potter Twilight 

Gifts and Gadgets Offers

 Top Sellers Coming Soon Did You Know We Sell... 3 For 2 On Posters And Prints The Hunger Games 
 Toys&amp;Baby 
 Toy Categories 
 
 Action Figures Arts&amp;Crafts Baby Toys Construction Discover&amp;Explore Dolls&amp;Playsets Dressing Up Electronic Toys Figures&amp;Playsets Games 
 
 Kids Room Outdoor&amp;Sport Playground Crazes Pre-School Puzzles Role Play Soft Toys Stationery Vehicles See all Toys 
 
Top Toy Brands

 Alex Crayola Fisher Price Galt Toys LeapFrog LEGO Little Tikes Mega Bloks Nerf Orchard Toys Playmobil Tomy Trunki Vtech Worlds Apart 
 
Favourite Characters

 Barbie Bob The Builder Cars 2 Disney Princess Doctor Who Fireman Sam Hello Kitty Moshi Monsters Peppa Pig Star Wars Sylvanian Families Thomas&amp;Friends Toy Story WWE 
 
Toys Hot Lists

 Coming Soon New Releases Top Sellers 

Toys Offers

 Arts and Crafts Did You Know We Sell... Toys under £10 

Baby Offers

 Items under £10 
 
 Baby Categories 
 
 Baby Toys Car Seats, Carriers and Accessories Nappies and Bathtime Nursery and Furniture Playtime Pushchairs, Buggies and Accessories Safety Weaning and Mealtime Visit the Baby Store 
 
Top Baby Brands
 
 Britax Clippasafe Concord Cosatto Fisher-Price Graco Hauck Jane Obaby Philips Avent Saplings Tomy 
 
 
 Home Books Food&amp;Drink 
 
 Larger image 
 
 
 
The Takeaway Secret: How to Cook Your Favourite Fast-food at Home | Paperback

Author: Kenny McGovern | Format: Paperback



 4.50 out of 5 ( 11 customer reviews)  |  Write a review 
 
 9 new  from  €6. 16 
 
Also available used  from  €5.62 
 ▼ View product details 
 All 11 from€5.62 New 9 from€6.16 Used 2 from€5.62 
 
Results 1-5 of 9 
 Sort By: Price Condition Seller rating Estimated delivery 
 Product Buy 
Sold by: Play.com 
 
 Condition: New 

 In stock | Usually dispatched within 24 hours.
 
 €7. 49

Free Delivery
 View Full Details  › BUY 
Sold by: pbshopatPlay  |  98% Positive Feedback  (from 15521 ratings) 
 
 Condition: New 

 In stock | Usually dispatched within 24 hours.

 Comment: Shipped from UK in 3 to 4 business days. Established seller since 2000
 
 €6. 16

Free Delivery
 View Full Details  › BUY 
Sold by: AphroheadBooks  |  91% Positive Feedback  (from 783 ratings) 
 
 Condition: New 

 In stock | Usually dispatched within 24 hours.
 
 €6. 78

Free Delivery
 View Full Details  › BUY 
Sold by: HopeBookstore  |  94% Positive Feedback  (from 741 ratings) 
 
 Condition: New 

 In stock | Usually dispatched within 24 hours.

 Comment: Brand New. Delivery Via Royal Mail.
 
 €8. 72

Free Delivery
 View Full Details  › BUY 
Sold by: quidbooks  |  85% Positive Feedback  (from 80 ratings) 
 
 Condition: New 

 In stock | Usually dispatched within 24 hours.

 Comment: Brand New Item direct delivery from UK.
 
 €10. 54

Free Delivery
 View Full Details  › BUY 
 
Results 1-5 of 9 
 
 ‹ 1 2 › 
 
 Description Technical Details Customer Reviews (11) Delivery&amp;Returns 
 &quot;The Takeaway Secret&quot; is a book which will enable readers to cook their own tasty takeaway food at home. After over 5 years of research and investigation, the secret ingredients and cooking techniques used by takeaway and fast food restaurants can now finally be revealed. In today&apos;s increasingly health conscious and now financially cautious world, there&apos;s never been a better time to learn the secrets of cooking your own takeaway food at home. From now on, the takeaway menu will become an inspiration to cook, not an expensive option for dinner. Some of the recipes which can now be faithfully recreated at home include Lamb Donner and Chicken Kebabs, Chicken and Vegetable Pakora, Szechuan Chicken, Sweet and Sour Chicken, Chicken Wings, Spare Ribs, Triple-Decker Burgers, Chicken Burgers, Spiced Onions, Kebab Sauces, Sub Rolls, Wraps and many more. Many recipe books call for an extensive and expensive list of ingredients, often interesting to read but impractical for everyday cooking. &quot;The Takeaway Secret&quot; will stand out as the modern cookbook, ideal for a generation of people who desire delicious food, delivered quickly without the need to slave over a hot stove for hours on end.The recipes included make it possible for home cooks, both novice and professional, to recreate their favorite takeaway and fast food restaurant dishes in their own kitchen. 
 Author Kenny McGovern Publisher Constable and Robinson (United Kingdom) Year 2010 ISBN 9780716022350 Format Paperback - 176 Pages 
 
customer Reviews

   Average rating (11 reviews)
 
 Write a review See all reviews (11) 
 
 5   A Pizza Hut, A Pizza Hut, Kentucky Fried Chicken..... 

 Tractorboy | 30/03/2011 | See all Tractorboy&apos;s reviews (27) 
 Top 100 Books  Reviewer 
And a Pizza Hut!! You can now create the tastes and smells of your favouritre fast food outlets in your very own kitchen!
I am so impressed with the book that I am planning a trip to the supermarket to buy a load of ingredients as tonight I fancy American style burgers! This book is a must buy for fast food fans.
 
 4  of  4 people found this review helpful. Did you? Yes | No | Report abuse 
 
 5   Finger lickin&apos; good! 

 JohnnyHell | 30/03/2011 | See all JohnnyHell&apos;s reviews (19) 
 
I loved &apos;The Curry Secret&apos; (which you should totally get too by the way) and someone mentioned this book to me. It&apos;s just as amazing! The KFC recipe is pretty good, but the the burgers and Chinese recipes are great. Haven&apos;t tried the kebabs yet but heard they&apos;re genius so I&apos;m going to give them a try. Better than the takeaway and waaaay cheaper! Buy this book and save a fortune!!!
 
 4  of  4 people found this review helpful. Did you? Yes | No | Report abuse 
 
 5   Excellent Book 

 TheBelly | 23/03/2011 | See all TheBelly&apos;s reviews (1) 
 
Love this gem&amp;the service was spot on................ Thank`s Kenny
 
 2  of  2 people found this review helpful. Did you? Yes | No | Report abuse 
 
 5   Such a good buy! 

 Farsla | 23/05/2011 | See all Farsla&apos;s reviews (1) 
 
Literally the best cookbook we&apos;ve ever bought.

The special burger sauce has made every burger, sandwich or salad ridiculously tasty, and you can make it so healthy too because you&apos;re in control of exactly what goes in.

The burgers, kebabs and curries are all we&apos;ve tried so far, and we&apos;ve loved every recipe.

About the only negative to the entire book is most of the best recipes require preparation the morning or night before, but honestly that&apos;s just good food discipline and it&apos;s left us excited to try what we&apos;ve prepared the night before.

Don&apos;t be put off by the images on the cover, the old saying don&apos;t judge a book by it&apos;s cover has never been more true!

Don&apos;t be put off by it being a book about take away food and assume it&apos;s all unhealthy, this couldn&apos;t be less true, you can control sugars, salts and fats and we&apos;ve found even the healthiest versions are still just as tasty.

We can&apos;t recommend this enough, no matter your level of cooking experience this book will gently teach and reward you.
 
 1  of  1 people found this review helpful. Did you? Yes | No | Report abuse 
 
 5   Full of great ideas 

 Wilko5toke | 07/04/2011 | See all Wilko5toke&apos;s reviews (2) 
 
Never fails....As it says on the cover.....You will not be dissapointed.
 
 1  of  1 people found this review helpful. Did you? Yes | No | Report abuse 
 
 Write a review See all reviews (11) 
 Play.com Delivery&amp;Returns 
 Free Delivery to the UK: within 3-5 working days from dispatch date Free Delivery to Europe: within 7-10 working days from dispatch date UK First Class Delivery: within 2-3 working days UK Express Delivery: next working day if ordered before 3pm 
 
We want you to be happy every time you shop with us, but if you ever need to return
anything, we&apos;re here to make things as easy and convenient as possible.

If you&apos;re not completely satisfied with your purchase, you can return the item to
us in its original condition within 30 days of receipt and we&apos;ll issue a full refund,
or replace the item, if preferred. To return an item, please go to your  order history  page, select the order you would like to return, and follow the simple steps at our online returns centre.
 PlayTrade Delivery&amp;Returns 
Items purchased through PlayTrade are usually dispatched within 24 hours.
Please see individual product listings for more information.

PlayTrade purchases need to be returned directly to the seller. If you wish to return a PlayTrade purchase,
please contact the seller through your  order history  page.
 More Information 
Delivery:  To find out more, please read our returns policy. 

Returns:  To find out more, please read our returns policy. 
 Return to top 
 
 Our Credit Card 

 Representative 16.9% APR (variable) Rewards scheme Credit Card FAQ 

 Selling on Play.com 

 What is PlayTrade? Fees for selling Sign up 

 Follow Us 

 Facebook Twitter 
 
 Contact Us 

 Affiliates Create Account Product Queries Work@Play.com 

 Gift Vouchers 

 Buy Gift Vouchers Gift Vouchers Help 
 
 Our Departments 

 Blu-ray Books Clothing Computing&amp;Office DVD Electronics Gifts and Gadgets Mobile Music Sports&amp;Outdoors Toys Video Games 
 
 Rakuten Family 

 About Rakuten Buy.com - USA PriceMinister - France Rakuten - Austria Rakuten - Brazil Rakuten - Germany Rakuten - Indonesia Rakuten - Japan Rakuten - Taiwan Tarad - Thailand 
 
 
V9.280.069/1/49

 Privacy Policy&amp;Cookies | Terms&amp;Conditions 

©1998-2012 Play.com
 
 
 
We accept:

 
 &lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;DCSIMG&quot; id=&quot;DCSIMG&quot; width=&quot;1&quot; height=&quot;1&quot; src=&quot;///statse.webtrendslive.com/dcsv9a9m6wz5bdfwgywcp0c4b_2n6f/njs.gif?dcsuri=/nojavascript&amp;amp;WT.js=No&amp;amp;WT.tv=9.3.0&amp;amp;WT.dcssip=www.play.com&quot;/&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
	</body>
</document>
