<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003805" url="http://losangeles.citysearch.com/profile/35775531/los_angeles_ca/popeyes_chicken_biscuits.html" time="2012-07-12-19:57" support="1" score="0.002334086022201905" bingtitle="Popeyes Chicken &amp; Biscuits - Los Angeles, CA, 90028 - Citysearch" webtitle="Popeyes Chicken&amp;Biscuits - Los Angeles, CA, 90028 - Citysearch">
			<query id="000658" bing-rank="42"/>
	<description>In Short – This Cajun-style fast food restaurant ... food quality: 100.0% positive “This ... not have to wait for long time by my food!” “in this place ...</description>
	<body>
		Deals Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Hotels Shopping Best Of Citysearch 

 Mobile Login / Join 
 More More Go! Advertise With Us 
 Citysearch has shed its old skin! In addition to our new look, there&apos;s a boatload of new features. Poke around! Tell us what you think! 
 Los Angeles, CA Metro &gt; Los Angeles &gt; Restaurants &gt; Popeyes Chicken&amp;Biscuits 
Popeyes Chicken&amp;Biscuits
 (323) 467-7909 
 6384 Hollywood Blvd , Los Angeles , CA | Directions  
 90028 34.101501 -118.329401 View Website 
 Menu Share Save 
   Own this Business? Recommend this business? Thumbs Up Thumbs Down ? 34 % 100 3 3 Votes Add a Photo Neighborhoods: Hollywood, Central LA Categories: Catering , Restaurants Cuisine: Fast Food , Southern , Cajun&amp;Creole Price: $ 
 View More 
 Restaurant Special Features: Carry Out , Family Style Dining , Family-Friendly Dining , Lunch Spot 
 View Less 
 At a Glance ? 
 100% food quality
 “in this place, you can enjoy a delicious food.” 
 100% service
 “This restaurant this very clean and they has much pleasant people working at this place, the teller offers me the specials, and i save really a little money, and the best part:... I did not have to wait for long time by my food!” 
 100% value
 “This restaurant this very clean and they has much pleasant people working at this place, the teller offers me the specials, and i save really a little money, and the best part:... I did not have to wait for long time by my food!” 
 100% wait time
 “This restaurant this very clean and they has much pleasant people working at this place, the teller offers me the specials, and i save really a little money, and the best part:... I did not have to wait for long time by my food!” Site Feedback 
 Overview Tips (3) Photos (0) 
 Write a Tip for Popeyes Chicken&amp;Biscuits… 
 Sign in to Write a Tip 
 Write a Tip... optional 
 
 
Tips for Popeyes Chicken&amp;Biscuits
 Recommends gussy24 Joined 2 years ago 5.0 June 03, 2010 
 The best popoyes!!. This restaurant this very clean and they has much pleasant people working at this place, the teller offers me the specials, and i save really a little money, and the best part:… I did not have to wait for long time by my food!!!! , they gave my food me at the same time as my change. in this place, you can enjoy a delicious food. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Doesn&apos;t Recommend bk2la Joined 4 years ago 1.0 October 20, 2008 
 Terrible...one of the worst meals of my life. WOW...my 3 pc meal was 90% chicken skin...at least the clientele is lively...hobos rifeling in the garbage for food...creackheads doing kung fu outside...55 cents for refills? I&apos;ve had better meals on airplanes. I can still taste the skin and grease...Yum! … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart Cadien Clark Joined 9 years ago September 20, 2007 
 Cajun-inspired chicken and biscuits chain proffers classic Southern favorites, seafood, sides and desserts with a tangy twist.. In Short
 This Cajun-style fast food restaurant first opened in New Orleans in 1972 and has since achieved domestic and international fame for its flavorful mild and spicy chicken. In addition to the storied buttermilk biscuits, seafood menu items range from fried popcorn shrimp and shrimp snack &quot;Craver Paks&quot; to chicken sausage jambalaya, catfish baskets and shrimp etouffee. More festive Louisiana regional fare--think red beans and rice, and Mardi Gras cheesecake--rounds out the menu. … 
 View More View Less 0 Heart 
 
 
People who viewed this also viewed…
 
 Ajito Sushi 1302 N Highland Ave 
 Los Angeles, CA 
0.7 mi away KFC - Kentucky Fried Ch… 1357 Vine St 
 Los Angeles, CA 
0.4 mi away Wendy&apos;s 7135 W Sunset Blvd 
 Los Angeles, CA 
0.9 mi away 
 
Things to do near Popeyes Chicken&amp;Biscuits
 
 Restaurants Movie Theaters Banks 

 Bars Shopping&amp;Malls Hotels 
 
 About Apps Careers Privacy Policy Terms of Use Contact Us Blog FAQs 
 
Partner Sites:

 Ask Kids     Bloglines     Expedia     Hotels     Hotwire     Insider Pages     MerchantCircle     Reference     The Daily Beast     Thesaurus     Urbanspoon 
 ©2011. Citysearch is a registered trademark of CityGrid Media. Data provided by Infogroup. All rights reserved. 
 Popular Categories Restaurants Bars&amp;Clubs Spa&amp;Beauty Shopping Hotels Deals Sports&amp;Recreation Cafes Movie Theaters Directory&amp;Services 

 Change City New York City Los Angeles Houston Chicago Atlanta Seattle Portland Philadelphia Austin San Francisco More…
	</body>
</document>
