<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003387" url="http://www.wnho.net/nh_news_2007.htm" time="2012-07-12-19:31" support="2" score="0.001264458191630621" bingtitle="NATURAL HEALTH NEWS 2007" webtitle="NATURAL HEALTH NEWS 2007">
			<query id="000092" bing-rank="196"/>
			<query id="000089" bing-rank="173"/>
	<description>05 Nov 2007 - The Truth Behind Fast-Food Restaurant&apos;s ... 22 Oct 2007 - Study Indicates Diet Soda ... 08 June 2007 - Bill Would Force Pharmacists To Dispense Plan B: Refusal ...</description>
	<body>
		NATURAL HEALTH NEWS
2007
 


The newest items are listed at the top of the below list. The dates that you see by each headline are the date when it was posted here. If you know if a news story, research, or information that should be posted here, please let us know what it is and please provide us with a link. The articles and links posted here and for informational and educational purposes only and do not necessarily imply endorsement by the World Natural Health Organization. The articles posted for previous years have been archived and links are provided to them, by year, at the bottom of this page.

30 Dec 2007 - Aspartame Turns Tissues To Plastic; The Formaldehyde Embalms The Body And Damages DNA. NutraSweet Is An Excitoneurotoxic Carcinogenic Drug 
30 Dec 2007 - Will Autism Speaks Fire Donald Trump? 
30 Dec 2007 - Fluorescent Lighting In Schools Found To Give Children Headaches 
30 Dec 2007 - Formaldehyde - A Solution To Fighting Deadly Hospital Bug [The use of formaldehyde in the DTP and other vaccines has already failed as a vaccine germicide. So, how in the world is the use of it in yet another vaccine going to result in &quot;intended&quot; antibacterial results???? What a bunch of QUACK science!]
30 Dec 2007 - Vaccine, VAERS And CDC Abbreviations 
30 Dec 2007 - Cell Phone Radiation Triggers Measurable Brain Cell Changes In Mere Minutes 
28 Dec 2007 - Aspartame In IV Dye, And In All Barium!? 
28 Dec 2007 - Letter To FOIA/FDA: President Reagan&apos;s Executive Order Making FDA Powerless And 20% Deleted From FDA Audit, Bressler Report 
28 Dec 2007 -
	</body>
</document>
