<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003879" url="http://encyclopedia2.thefreedictionary.com/food+chain" time="2012-07-12-20:02" support="2" score="0.007385775447187012" bingtitle="Food Chain definition of Food Chain in the Free Online Encyclopedia." webtitle="Food Chain definition of Food Chain in the Free Online Encyclopedia.">
			<query id="001106" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="001317" bing-rank="210"/>
	<description>... intertwine locally into a food web because most organisms consume or are ... Fast Food Restaurant Investigated for Negligence ... food tray rail</description>
	<body>
		Printer Friendly 
 Dictionary, Encyclopedia and Thesaurus - The Free Dictionary 4,028,658,142 visitors served. forum Join the Word of the Day Mailing List For webmasters 
 TheFreeDictionary Google Bing ? Word / Article Starts with Ends with Text 
 

 Dictionary/
thesaurus Medical
dictionary Legal
dictionary Financial
dictionary Acronyms
  Idioms Encyclopedia Wikipedia
encyclopedia ? 

 
Food Chain
    Also found in: Dictionary/thesaurus , Medical , Legal , Financial , Wikipedia 0.01 sec. 

 Advertisement (Bad banner? Please let us know ) food chain: see ecology ecology, study of the relationships of organisms to their physical environment and to one another. The study of an individual organism or a single species is termed autecology; the study of groups of organisms is called synecology.
 ..... Click the link for more information. . 
food chain

Sequence of transfer of matter and energy from organism to organism in the form of food. These interconnected feeding relationships intertwine locally into a food web because most organisms consume or are consumed by more than one other type of organism. Plants and other photosynthetic organisms (such as phytoplankton ), which convert solar energy to food, are the primary food source. In a predator chain, a plant-eating animal is eaten by a larger animal. In a parasite chain ( see parasitism ), a smaller organism consumes part of a larger host and may itself be parasitized by even smaller organisms. In a saprophytic chain, microorganisms live on dead organic matter. Because energy, in the form of heat, is lost at each step, or trophic level, chains do not normally encompass more than four or five trophic levels.
 food chain Ecology a sequence of organisms in an ecosystem in which each species is the food of the next member of the chain food chain [ ′füd‚chān ] (ecology) The scheme of feeding relationships by trophic levels which unites the member species of a biological community. Food Chain   
the interrelation of various species of plants, animals, fungi, and microorganisms that are connected to each other as food and food consumers. Each of the successive feeding links consists of organisms that consume those of the preceding link in the chain; the resulting transfer of energy and matter lies at the foundation of the cycle of matter in nature. As much as 80 or 90 percent of the potential energy is lost in each such transfer, being dispersed in the form of heat. Hence the number of links, or sets of species, in a food chain is usually no more than four or five.

At the base of every food chain are the producer species—the autotrophic organisms that synthesize organic matter. These are primarily green plants, consisting of water, inorganic salts, and carbon dioxide, that synthesize organic matter by assimilating the energy of sunlight; also included in this category is a group of bacteria, such as sulfur and hydrogen bacteria, that use the energy obtained from the oxidation of chemical compounds to synthesize organic matter.

The next link in a food chain consists of the consumer species—the heterotrophic organisms that consume organic matter. The primary consumers are herbivorous animals that feed on grass, seeds, fruit, the underground portion of plants (roots, tubers, and bulbs), and even—in the case of some insects—wood. Carnivorous animals are classified as secondary consumers and are subdivided into (1) those that subsist on great quantities of small prey and (2) active predators, which frequently attack prey larger than themselves. The great majority of these consumers subsist on a variety of foods, including a certain amount of plant food. Thus, for example, the size of the marten and sable populations depends not only on the plentifulness of small mammals and birds but also on fruit and seed crops, and particularly the available yield of pine nuts. At the same time, herbivorous animals also consume a certain amount of animal food, thereby obtaining essential and irreplaceable amino acids of animal origin.

Finally, the saprophytic organisms—chiefly fungi and bacteria—obtain their essential energy by decomposing dead organic matter.

In the case of animals that develop by metamorphosis, the larvae and the adult individuals require different types of food and occupy different positions in the food chain. The ecological niche of a given species (or of a given phase in its development) is determined by its position in the food chain and its relation to its partners—the organisms at higher and lower levels of the food chain. The various populations or age groups of a single species may be part of several different food chains, thus forming a more complex set of relationships.

Two major types of food chains are found in biocenoses, or biotic communities—the“pasture”and the“detritus”type. The pasture type of food chain begins with photosynthesizing green plants and usually forms the basis of the biocenosis. The detritus type begins with saprophytic organisms, which utilize the energy liberated by the decomposition of dead organic matter (fungi and many microorganisms). Together, these two types of food chains ensure the functioning of the three principal stages in the cycle of matter, as reflected in three trophic levels: the producers—plants—are at the first level; the consumers—primary consumers (herbivorous animals) and secondary consumers (carnivores)—at the second; and the reducers—the saprophages that break down organic matter—at the third.

The designation of trophic levels groups together types of activity rather than species; the population of one species may occupy one or more trophic levels, depending on its energy source. The flow of energy through a trophic level equals the total amount of energy assimilated at this level; in its turn, the total energy assimilated equals the total biomass produced plus respiration.

Biotic communities usually contain a number of parallel food chains—for example, the chain of herbaceous vegetation-rodents-small predators together with the chain of herbaceous vegetation-ungulates-large predators. While the inhabitants of different strata (soil, grass, and trees) often belong to parallel food chains, relationships may also be found to exist between them. The complex structure of food chains ensures both the integrity and the dynamic nature of the biotic community. Any reduction in the number of individuals in a species constituting a link in a food chain—whether due to human activity or other factors—inevitably brings injury to the integrity of the biotic community.
 
REFERENCES
Naumov, N. P. Ekologiia zhivotnykh , 2nd ed. Moscow, 1963.
Odum, E. Osnovy ekologii . Moscow, 1975. (Translated from English.)
Williamson, M. Analiz biologicheskikh populiatsii . Moscow, 1975. (Translated from English.) 
N. P. N AUMOV 
 
 
Want to thank TFD for its existence? Tell a friend about us , add a link to this page, add the site to iGoogle , or visit the webmaster&apos;s page for free fun content . 
 ? Page tools 
 Printer friendly 
 Cite / link Feedback 
 
 
 Advertisement (Bad banner? Please let us know ) Advertisement (Bad banner? Please let us know ) Advertisement (Bad banner? Please let us know ) 

 Mentioned in ?   References in periodicals archive ?   Encyclopedia browser ?   Full browser ? No references found   A FAST food chain in Huddersfield has raised pounds 1,167 for the World Food Programme. Finger lickin&apos; good by Huddersfield Daily Examiner (Huddersfield, England) Four in 10 children, aged eight to 11, said McDonald&apos;s was their favourite fast food chain because of the toys and Happy Meals. Fast food calories alert for children by Daily Post (Liverpool, England) Some well known food chains have been found to be underperforming in the areas of food hygine. Fast Food Restaurant Investigated for Negligence by catherine ehite / Law community   Fonteyn Fonteyn, Dame Margot Fonteyn, Margot fontology Fontware Fonvizin, Artur Fonvizin, Artur Vladimirovich Fonvizin, Denis Fonvizin, Denis Ivanovich Fonvizin, Mikhail Fonvizin, Mikhail Aleksandrovich foo foobar Foochow Food Food Acids food additive food additives food adulteration food allergy food analog Food and Agriculture Organization Food and Agriculture Organization FAO Food and Drug Administration Food Appropriation Detachments Food Chain food chemistry food color Food Concentrates food display counter food engineering Food Industry, Institute of the food infection food irradiation food manufacturing food microbiology Food Monopolies Food Poisoning food preservation Food Preserving food pyramid food science Food Service Industry food spoilage Food Storage, Animal food technology food tray rail food vacuole food waste disposer Food Waste Product food web   Food Bank of Northern Nevada 
 Food Bank of Oakland County 
 Food Bank of South Central Michigan 
 Food Bank of South Jersey 
 Food Bank of the Southern Tier 
 Food Bank of Waterloo Region 
 Food Banks 
 Food Base Dietary Guidelines 
 Food Basket Foundation International 
 Food Beverage Canada 
 Food Biological Agent Detection Sensor 
 Food Biotechnology and Engineering Group 
 Food Biotechnology Communications Initiative 
 Food Biotechnology Communications Network 
 food bodies 
 food body 
 food borne disease 
 food borne disease 
 food borne disease 
 food borne disease 
 Food borne illness 
 Food Bowl Modernisation Project 
 Food Bronchial Stimulation Test 
 food bumps 
 food bumps 
 food bumps 
 food bumps 
 Food Business Operator 
 Food by Prescription 
 food cache 
 Food Chain Food chain and webs 
 Food chain and webs 
 Food chain and webs 
 Food Chain Assurance Advisory Group 
 Food Chain Goblins 
 Food Chain Information 
 Food Chain Multiplier 
 Food Chain Research Group 
 Food chains 
 Food chains 
 Food chains 
 food challenge 
 Food Chemical Codex 
 Food Chemical Codex Papain Unit 
 Food Chemical News Guide 
 Food chemistry 
 Food chip 
 Food Choice Questionnaire 
 food color 
 food color 
 food coloring 
 food coloring 
 Food coloring agents 
 Food colorings 
 Food colors 
 food colour 
 food colouring 
 Food combination 
 Food combination 
 Food combinations 
   
 
 Encyclopedia TheFreeDictionary Google ? Word / Article Starts with Ends with Text 


 Free Tools: For surfers: Free toolbar&amp;extensions | Word of the Day | Help 
 For webmasters: Free content | Linking | Lookup box | Double-click lookup 
 Terms of Use | Privacy policy | Feedback | Advertise with Us |
Copyright©2012 Farlex, Inc. Disclaimer 
All content on this website, including dictionary, thesaurus, literature, geography, and other reference data is for informational purposes only. This information should not be considered complete, up to date, and is not intended to be used in place of a visit, consultation, or advice of a legal, medical, or any other professional.
	</body>
</document>
