<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003357" url="http://www.thefreelibrary.com/11th+Annual+flavor+survey.+(Cup+Service).-a083554486" time="2012-07-12-19:30" support="2" score="0.001764307579682533" bingtitle="11th Annual flavor survey. (Cup Service). - Free Online Library" webtitle="11th Annual flavor survey. (Cup Service). - Free Online Library">
			<query id="001277" bing-rank="124"/>
			<query id="001182" bing-rank="141"/>
	<description>(Cup Service). by &quot;Tea &amp; Coffee Trade Journal ... See also: Fast-food restaurant, Casual dining, List of reference ... The selection of bean flavor characteristics, bean ...</description>
	<body>
		Printer Friendly 
19,791,913 articles and books Periodicals Literature Keyword Title Author Topic 
 Member login User name    Password     Remember me 
 Join us   Forgot password? 
 The Free Library &gt; Business and Industry&gt;  Business &gt;  Tea&amp;Coffee Trade Journal &gt;  January 20, 2002 The Free Library &gt; Business and Industry&gt;  Food and beverage industries &gt;  Tea&amp;Coffee Trade Journal &gt;  January 20, 2002 The Free Library &gt;  Date &gt;  2002 &gt;  January &gt;  20 &gt;  Tea&amp;Coffee Trade Journal 
 
11th Annual flavor survey. (Cup Service).

Every year Tea&amp;Coffee Trade Journal reports on the coffee and
tea flavoring industry. After speaking with some of the top flavor
specialists in the industry, we learned some interesting facts about
this integral part of the coffee and tea industries.

Hazelnut, Vanilla Nut, Irish Cream For the novel of the same name, see .
 Irish Cream is a cream liqueur based on Irish whiskey, coffee, cream, and other ingredients. Well known brands include Baileys Irish Cream, which was the first Irish Cream, Carolans and St. Brendan&apos;s. , Chocolate, Amaretto am·a·ret·to  
 n. pl. am·a·ret·tos 
An Italian liqueur flavored with almond.

 
[Italian, diminutive of amaro , bitter , from Latin am , these
flavors are what consumers traditionally request when ordering a
flavored coffee beverage. Lemon, Earl Grey Earl Grey 
 Noun 

a variety of China tea flavoured with oil of bergamot , Peach, Rasberry, sound
familiar, of course because these flavors often appear in a steaming cup
of tea. However, the varieties of flavor extend way beyond these popular
flavors. There are more exotic flavors found in both coffee and tea,
flavors such as cookie doodle, apple toddy, and rainforest crunch spice
up a cup of joe, and tropic diablo crunch, cinnamon banana, and even
cola flavored tea. These are combinations that only a flavor specialist
could dream up. There are coffee and tea traditionalists who will argue
that a flavored beverage is not real coffee or tea, but with around 30%
of the specialty coffee market sales, someone is drinking these
beverages. Flavored beverages are a good transition for coffee and tea
drinking amateurs, those who haven&apos;t discovered the subtle nuances
of a plain cup. We asked some flavor experts the follo wing questions
about their industry. They provided insight in to this highly profitable
industry and some figures that open one&apos;s eyes to the expansive
influence of this industry.

Of the total specialty coffee market, what would you estimate the
dollar volume of the flavored coffee segment to be?

In the multibillion dollar specialty coffee industry, according to according to 
 prep. 
 1. As stated or indicated by; on the authority of: according to historians. 

 2. In keeping with: according to instructions. 

 3.  the experts, flavored coffee accounts for approximately 20-30% of total
specialty coffee sales. Having an established industry as a foundation
for promoting a product helps the flavor industry maintain healthy
profits. Willy Palmer of Flavor&amp;Fragrance Specialties provided the
following, &quot;We believe the flavored coffee market at retail to be
about $750,000,000. That&apos;s based on the assumption that nearly 30%
of all specialty coffee sold is flavored. This number is for sales of
unbrewed coffee, add brewed coffee to the mix and the number goes up
significantly.&quot; Seconding the amount of 30% of sales, Jeff Nichols
of Danisco Cultor said, &quot;Flavored coffee in the whole bean segment
represents about 29-30% of all specialty coffee sales. The ground
segment does include flavored coffees but not near at the levels found
in whole bean. Since specialty coffee utilizes an assortment of
distribution channels, establishing a valid dollar total would be very
difficult. At best you could extrapolate extrapolate - extrapolation  this data using an average
selling price The average sales price of goods or commodities. Especially used in the retail sector and technology distribution. , green bean data and the 30% coffee share, but this would
still be a rough estimate.&quot; Flavor Waves representative Michael
Abrams Mike Abrams (born July 16, 1953) is an American psychologist and co-author with Albert Ellis of several works on Rational Emotive and Cognitive Behavior Therapy. He was instrumental in the formalisation of Ellis&apos; model of personality while coauthoring Ellis&apos;s only college textbook.  estimated a bit lower than others, he added, &quot;If one could
find an accurate statistic reflecting total dollar volume of the
specialty coffee market, then one could calculate 20% of that volume,
and that would be a good estimate.&quot; And Donald Wilkes of Blue
Pacific, did not provide a percentage amount, but an estimated dollar
amount, &quot;This is a very difficult question to answer given the
various product categories that make up &quot;flavored coffees&quot; For
example, many specialty shops serve syrups as their &quot;flavored
coffee&quot; where other shops might feature flavored beans. If you look
at the total syrups and flavored beans it is estimated to be between $20
to 30 million annually.&quot;

Do you think the flavored coffee market will continue to increase
its market share or just hold onto what it has? Or has the flavored
coffee market declined?

The flavor industry&apos;s sales seem to have either slowed or
completely flattened flat·ten  
 v. flat·tened , flat·ten·ing , flat·tens 

 v. tr. 
 1. To make flat or flatter.

 2. To knock down; lay low: The boxer was flattened with one punch. , with increases in sales here and there. They also
seemed to agree that when more roasters and fast food chains jump add
flavors to their product line-up, sales would, of course, increase. Bill
Sieber, director of the Coffee&amp;Tea Flavor Division of Melchers,
said, &quot;The market for flavored coffees continues to grow but at a
very slow pace compared to what we experienced in the eighties.&quot; He
believes that &quot;volumes will increase when fast food chains enter
the marketplace.&quot; Palmer, of Flavor&amp;Fragrance Specialties,
said, &quot;The majority of my customers tell me their flavored coffee
sales have leveled off. However several companies that market flavored
coffee well, with seasonal items, web pages, and catalogs continue to
have growth that exceeds their regular sales (Stock Exchange) sales of stock deliverable on the day after the transaction.

See also: Regular . As roasters of
international stature continue to introduce flavored coffees to
supermarkets and mass marketers, the volume increases dramatically,
though with just a few pr oducts. More high volume restaurant chains The following is a list of restaurant chains .

See also: Fast-food restaurant, Casual dining, List of reference tables. International 


 Bennigan&apos;s Burger King Charley&apos;s Grilled Subs Domino&apos;s Pizza Hard Rock Cafe 
  added flavored to their menu this year.&quot; Bernd Zimmer, Frey&amp;Lau Gmbh, said, &quot;We think the European Market is just starting and
will increase.&quot; Jeff Nichols said, &quot;Our market research data
repeated over the past five years indicates that the flavored coffee
market share within specialty coffee has remained fairly constant. The
data indicates that within a 1% range, the flavored coffee portion
remains around 30% of total whole bean coffee sales.&quot; Michael
Abrams factored in demographics in his response; he said, &quot;As more
of our population advances in age closer to the twenties, then flavored
coffee consumption should rise. It must be remembered that flavored
coffees are for non-coffee drinkers. Thus as our population increases,
more flavored coffee drinkers will be added to the list, in direct
proportion.&quot; Donald Wilkes, Blue Pacific, had a decidedly different
view of the sales. He sees declining sales as imminent. He noted,
&quot;I think the market will be downsizing (1) Converting mainframe and mini-based systems to client/server LANs.

 (2) To reduce equipment and associated costs by switching to a less-expensive system. 
(jargon) downsizing  over the next few years as
the flavor industry goes through consolidation and the larger
manufacturers change the minimum order requirements of the acquired
companies. This will mean higher minimum orders or inventory issues for
roasters and will most likely require them to limit the variety of
flavors purchased to only higher volume items.&quot;

Can flavored coffee mask an inferior coffee?

The resounding re·sound  
 v. re·sound·ed , re·sound·ing , re·sounds 

 v. intr. 
 1. To be filled with sound; reverberate: The schoolyard resounded with the laughter of children. 

 2.  answer to this question was No, flavored coffee
cannot conceal a poor quality coffee. This mentality helps bolster the
flavor industry&apos;s reputation of supporting the specialty coffee
industry&apos;s quest for Verb 1. quest for - go in search of or hunt for; &quot;pursue a hobby&quot;
quest after, go after, pursue

look for, search, seek - try to locate or discover, or try to establish the existence of; &quot;The police are searching for clues&quot;; &quot;They are searching for the  a high quality cup. William Sieber, Melchers,
responded, &quot;Flavors cannot mask the taste imperfections in poor
quality coffees.&quot; Jeff Nichols agrees, &quot;No. A critical step in
the building an excellent flavored coffee is in fact bean/roast color
optimization. The selection of bean flavor characteristics, bean quality
and roast color has as much to do with product quality as the flavor
itself does. The goal is to establish a fine flavor balance between the
coffee and the flavor, to reach the rich sweet creamy taste preferences
of the flavored coffee consumer. Small flavor attributes can be
effectively masked by the added flavor. Only excellent coffee and
flavors produce those winning combinations.&quot; Willy Palmer provided
an almost scientific approach to the idea of flavors covering an
inferior coffe e, &quot;The question is, can flavored coffee mask an
inferior coffee. If by inferior coffee you mean one with faults, the
answer is a simple no. Oxidized oxidized

having been modified by the process of oxidation.
 
 oxidized cellulose 
see absorbable cellulose. , stale, or otherwise blemished blem·ish  
 tr.v. blem·ished , blem·ish·ing , blem·ish·es 
To mar or impair by a flaw.

 n. 
An imperfection that mars or impairs; a flaw or defect.  coffee
will taste like bad flavored coffee. Good coffee flavors are designed to
balance the profile of good coffee. If inferior refers to bland, or
coffee available in large quantities, yes, flavor can work well. We
prefer mild coffees with balanced acidity acidity  /acid·i·ty/ ( -i-te ) the quality of being acid; the power to unite with positively charged ions or with basic substances. 
 a·cid·i·ty 
 n. 
The state, quality, or degree of being acid.  and body for flavored coffee.
Outstanding assets might determine the characteristic of a varietal va·ri·e·tal  
 adj. 
Of, indicating, or characterizing a variety, especially a biological variety.

 n. 
A wine made principally from one variety of grape and carrying the name of that grape. , but
they usually alter the balance we seek for a flavoring blend.&quot;
Michael Abrams of Flavor Waves, approached the question a different way.
He thinks certain flavors may improve the taste a bit, but he does not
recommend using low quality beans, &quot;Strong flavors such as
Cinnamon, Amaretto, and perhaps certain liqueur liqueur   (lĭkûr`) , strong alcoholic beverage made of almost neutral spirits, flavored with herb mixtures, fruits, or other materials, and usually sweetened. The name derives from the Latin word to melt.  flavors can have some
ability to mask inferior grade coffees. However, we never recommend
using lower grade coffees for flavored varieties. Stale, fermented, and
harsh Robusta coffees will have an overall negative impact on the final
taste profile of any flavored coffee. If one sets up a taste panel with
any flavored Arabica a·rab·i·ca  
 n. 
 1. 
 a. A species of coffee, Coffea arabica, originating in Ethiopia and widely cultivated for its high-quality, commercially valuable seeds.

 b. The beanlike seed of this plant.

 2.  coffee, and compares the taste to the same
flavored, inferior grade coffee, the liking score will always go down.
This is also true for Cinnamon and Amaretto flavorings. It should be
remembered that flavored coffee consumers want a peak flavor experience,
just as regular coffee consumers. We need to treat the flavored coffee
segment of consumers as a real live group of our fellow humans looking
for Looking for

In the context of general equities, this describing a buy interest in which a dealer is asked to offer stock, often involving a capital commitment. Antithesis of in touch with.  a peak taste experience. Turning them off early in their coffee
consuming years, will certainly risk their growth potential into
non-flavored coffee, future consumers. Thus, please never use inferior
grade coffees for your flavored products.&quot; Donald Wilkes, noted,
&quot;No. Flavoring has masking properties but bad coffee is usually due
to the complexity of the acids (over 20 various acids found in coffee)
and high caffeine from the origin of the beans used. To mas k the
bitterness of low quality Robusta ro·bus·ta  
 n. 
 1. 
 a. The coffee plant Coffea canephora that is commercially grown but whose beans are of lesser quality than arabica beans.

 b. The seed of this plant.

 2.  beans, you would be better to roast
the bean at a higher temperature than to add additional flavor or
so-called flavor masking agents. The key is to get rid of the caffeine
and reduce the acidity. Breaking the chemical bonds through buffering
agents or enzymatic pretreatment pretreatment, 
 n the protocols required before beginning therapy, usually of a diagnostic nature; before treatment.

 pretreatment estimate ,
 n See predetermination.  of the beans is also an alternative,
but is a rather labor intensive Labor Intensive

A process or industry that requires large amounts of human effort to produce goods.

Notes:
A good example is the hospitality industry (hotels, restaurants, etc), they are considered to be very people-oriented.
See also: Capital Intensive, Trading Dollars  and difficult to control process.&quot;
One dissenting voice was that of Bernd Zimmer of Frey&amp;Lau, when
asked about flavored coffee masking an inferior coffee, he responded,
&quot;This depends on the quality of the flavor, but we think clearly
yes.&quot;

In Part 2, we will look at the demographics of the flavored coffee
drinker, its seasonability and how the large fast food chains in the
U.S. use flavored coffee. Stay tuned. COPYRIGHT 2002 Lockwood Trade Journal Co., Inc.
No portion of this article can be reproduced without the express written permission from the copyright holder. Copyright 2002 Gale, Cengage Learning. All rights reserved. 
 Reader Opinion
 Title:
 
Comment:
 

 
   
 
 Article Details Printer friendly Cite/link Email Feedback Author: Leverett, Lyn Publication: Tea&amp;Coffee Trade Journal Geographic Code: 1USA Date: Jan 20, 2002 Words: 1601 Previous Article: The many faces of chai. (From Traditional to Trendy). Next Article: New flavors and uses. (Syrups Continue to Pour Out). Topics: Coffee (Beverage) Coffee industry Product information 
 Coffee processing Analysis 
 Flavor Surveys 
 Tea Production processes 
 Tea (Beverage) Production processes 
 Tea (Plant) Tea industry Product information 
 




 Related Articles Demand for flavor. Coffee and tea flavor trends, part 2. Specialty teas as a growth category. SCAA adds new advanced and intermediate level coffee seminars to 1996 conference curriculum. Aromatic teas post big holiday gains. A stash of tea to please your palette. Torani Barista Cup Winners. Guatemala&apos;s &quot;Cup of Excellence&quot; Competition To Be Held. 11th annual flavor survey. (Cup Service). Sweeten your beverage business at Tea&amp;Coffee World Cup Rome. 
 
 
 Publications by Name Publications by Date Authors Literature A-D E-O P-T U-Z before 1995 1995-1999 
 2000-2004 2005-2009 2010- A B C D E F G H I J K L M 
 N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z A B C D E F G H I J K L M 
 N O P Q R S T U V W X Y Z 

 Terms of use |
Copyright©2012 Farlex, Inc. | Feedback | For webmasters | Submit articles
	</body>
</document>
