<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003140" url="http://www.outandaboutinjax.com/2009/03/family-safety-night-at-chick-fil.html" time="2012-07-12-19:16" support="9" score="0.012792171167026611" bingtitle="Out and About in Jax: Family Safety Night at Chick-fil-a Oakleaf ..." webtitle="Out and About in Jax: Family Safety Night at Chick-fil-a Oakleaf Towncenter">
			<query id="001323" bing-rank="207"/>
			<query id="000690" bing-rank="235"/>
			<query id="000757" bing-rank="203"/>
			<query id="000006" bing-rank="178"/>
			<query id="001318" bing-rank="229"/>
			<query id="001009" bing-rank="200"/>
			<query id="000695" bing-rank="184"/>
			<query id="000127" bing-rank="206"/>
			<query id="000132" bing-rank="184"/>
	<description>They have a great toddler play place and ... The polite young man who had taken my order was ... There is no other fast food restaurant like this that I know of.</description>
	<body>
		Out and About in Jax 
 
 Events in the River City 
 
 Thursday, March 26, 2009 
 
Family Safety Night at Chick-fil-a Oakleaf Towncenter
 
 Satuday, May 23rd the Chick Fil A in Oakleaf Town Center will be having a Memorial Day and Spring Carnival Celebration. The Coast Guard Auxiliary Honor Guard will perform The Missing Man Ceremony. There will also be a flag raising and unserviceable flag disposal center. This ceremony will be a wonderful tribute to the men and women who have lost their lives keeping us safe. There will also be a free bounce house and pony rides for the children and games for everyone to participate in. 
 
The event is planned for 3:00-5:00 with the ceremony beginning at 4:00. 
 
 
 A couple of days ago, an email was forwarded to me by a friend announcing that the Chick- fil -a here in Oakleaf was having a &quot;Family Safety Night&quot; sponsored by Jacksonville Sheriff&apos;s office. I&apos;d been to our Chick- fil -a handful of times to meet up with other moms and kids. They have a great toddler play place and occasionally have arts and crafts for preschool age kids, so they are a favorite among the moms in Oakleaf . 
 
 
 
So, Jim and I decided to go and check it out. On our way to Chick- fil -a, I told Jim what I knew, which wasn&apos;t much. I expected we might see some cop cars, and maybe some people at a table handing out brochures and favors for the kids. 
 
 
 
 
 
 Boy was I wrong. The restaurant and parking lot were packed! In the parking lot, there were cop cars set up, cops on motorcycles, and a large SWAT team van as well as a bomb squad van with some sort of large robotic vehicle parked next to it. Jim and I still managed to find a parking spot right near the front door of the restaurant. We pulled Christian out of his car seat and headed inside. The restaurant was bustling with activity, and crowded, but happily crowded. Let me explain. 
 
 
 
 
 
 Everyone was well taken care of, and everything ran so smoothly that there was no congestion or confusion. It was immediately apparent to me that the staff was used to large crowds and were very organized and well equipped to handle them. The restaurant was full of people eating, yet there was no line at the counter. We were able to walk right up to the counter and order. Then, after ordering, in the time it took me to gather some straws and ketchup from the condiment area, my food was ready! The polite young man who had taken my order was carrying it over to me. He asked where I would like to sit, and brought the tray to my table. He was well dressed, (wearing a tie) and so polite, saying things like &quot;yes ma&apos;am,&quot; and &quot;my pleasure,&quot; with a smile. It was so refreshing. Sometimes it feels like customer service is dead in America, but not here. While my family and I sat and ate, several staff members greeted us, asked us if we needed anything, and handed us wet napkins, straws and pieces of candy. 
 
 
 
 
 
 There is no other fast food restaurant like this that I know of. And while I&apos;m at it, there&apos;s no business quite like Chick- fil -a that I am aware of either. They are closed on Sundays, giving their staff time to rest and be with family, and they are so involved in the community, which I think is just awesome. I saw a First Coast News story recently about a &quot;marriage stimulus&quot; date night at the Chick- fil- a in Tinseltown where 50 couples were treated to a night out and given materials about enriching their marriage. Chick- fil -a had partnered with a local nonprofit called &quot;Marriage for Life&quot; to sponsor the event. You can read about it here: 
 
 
 http://www.firstcoastnews.com/news/local/news-article.aspx?storyid=134568&amp;provider= rss 
 
 
 
 
 
 I&apos;m sure this goes without saying, but the food was fantastic. It was hot and fresh, and pretty healthy. I read somewhere recently that Chick- fil -a is one of the top fast food chains when it comes to the number of relatively low calorie items on their menu. Just as we were finishing our meal, a well dressed woman walked up and announced that some police officers would be having a &quot;motorcycle rodeo&quot; outside momentarily. I really hadn&apos;t planned on writing about tonight&apos;s visit to Family Safety Night up until this point, but I realized that this event was just going to be too interesting to pass up. So I whipped out a pen and a piece of paper for note taking and we walked outside. 
 
 
 
 
 
 As we walked outside, a well dressed, well spoken young man opened the door for us. His name was Brian and he was a member of the Jacksonville Police Explorers. He told me that they are young adults ages 14-21 who are interested in becoming officers, or at least learning more about law enforcement. They volunteer with the Sheriff&apos;s office and get to do ride- alongs and learn a lot about police work during a two month long academy. He explained that after completing their explorer training, they may get the opportunity to become CSOs or Community Service Officers. Brian pointed out the CSOs -- they were wearing bright neon colored shirts. I&apos;ve seen them before at the scene of traffic accidents and such. He went to tell me that CSOs can work in that program for five years and get their college paid for before going on to become officers. He also introduced me to his class leader, named Mike and asked me to mention his senior advisor, Kendall Anderson. While I never got to meet Mr. Anderson, I know he must be doing a good job -- the youth I observed wearing the Police Explorer uniforms were really impressive. 
 
 
 
 
 
 Next, I watched the motorcycle rodeo which was really cool. A couple of officers were riding these large police motorcycles -- doing tricks like small circles and figure eights. These were pretty cool tricks considering how bulky the motorcycles were. Each time one of the officers would lean into a sharp turn, you could hear parts of the vehicle scrape the pavement. The loud rumbles given off by the motorcycles had all of the kids transfixed. 
 
 
 
 
 
 After the motorcycle demonstration, I headed straight over to two of the cutest dogs I&apos;ve ever seen! The picture in this post is of me and one of the dogs. Her name&apos;s Thelma and she&apos;s a blood hound. She searches for missing persons. The officer working with Thelma, Officer Hall was really nice and answered all of my police dog questions. 
 
 
 
 
 
 I wondered how they teach dogs like Thelma to find missing persons. He explained that they give her an article of clothing with a person&apos;s smell and then hide that person nearby. Thelma will follow the trail and find the person pretty easily. The trainers then give her lots of praise and reward her. From there they make the trail harder to follow and the person harder to find. &quot;Once she followed a trail over 50 hours old&quot; he told me proudly. 
 
 
 
 
 
 &quot;What&apos;s the weirdest place Thelma has ever tracked a person to?&quot; I asked, &quot;Like, has she ever found someone in the water?&quot; 
 
 
 
 
 
 Officer Hall thought for a minute, then chuckled. &quot;She found someone hanging from a tree once.&quot; Wow. Then a fondness came over Officer Hall&apos;s face as he told me the story of Thelma once finding an 11 year old girl who had run and hid from her parents because she thought she was in trouble. Thelma found that little girl asleep hiding behind a brick wall! 
 
 
 
 
 
 &quot;I&apos;ve heard people say that in order to get drug dogs to search for drugs they get the dog addicted to that particular drug. Is that true?&quot; I asked. 
 
 
 
 
 
 Officer Hall laughed. &quot;No, we just put that drug&apos;s scent on the dog&apos;s toy and play with him a lot. When a drug dog searches for drugs -- he&apos;s really thinking he gets to play with his favorite toy.&quot; How cute. 
 
 
 
 
 
 Next I moved on to the Bomb Squad van. Two officers stood outside the van next to a robotic looking vehicle. One of the officers was Detective Chris King. He explained that the robot, which they call &quot;Bomber&quot; will approach a suspicious package and investigate it. Mounted on the robot were several cameras, and a robotic arm that the members of the Bomb Squad could operate via remote control. &quot;How far away can you control the robot from?&quot; I asked. 
 
 
 
&quot;Sometimes as far as 1500 meters,&quot; Detective King replied. 
 
 
 
 
 
 &quot;So what happens when she finds an actual bomb?&quot; I asked, &quot;What can she do with that bomb?&quot; (Detective King had used &quot;she&quot; several times when talking about Bomber so I followed suit.) 
 
 
 
 
 
 &quot;It depends on the situation,&quot; the detective explained. &quot;She may be able to disarm it, or she may have to detonate it.&quot; 
 
 
 
 
 
 I gasped. &quot;Won&apos;t that destroy her?&quot; 
 
 
 
 
 
 &quot;She&apos;s designed to break apart in pieces, so we may just have to replace parts of her.&quot; I asked Detective King what were the most common types of places he had to respond to bomb threats. He seemed reluctant to answer that question, with good reason I&apos;m sure. I also asked him to tell me a story of an encounter with a real bomb. He said he really didn&apos;t like that term... &quot;real bomb&quot; and preferred &quot;suspicious package&quot;, and he&apos;d rather not say. I understood. 
 
 
 
 
 
 Then a fellow Bomb Squad officer stepped over and told me a story about Detective King. &quot;I&apos;ll tell it because he won&apos;t,&quot; Detective King&apos;s associate said. There was an accident on the James Street Bridge and a woman ended up falling into the water. Detective King was in a police helicopter sent to investigate and when he caught sight of the woman in the water, clinging to a piece of debris he jumped out of the helicopter into the water to save her. I turned to Detective King in awe. &quot;You jumped out of the helicopter?!&quot; 
 
 
 
 
 
 &quot;Yeah, a perfectly good helicopter, too&quot; he laughed. I don&apos;t know about you, but there are very few things in this world that could ever motivate me to jump willingly out of a helicopter. For officers like I was meeting tonight, it&apos;s all part of a day at the office. It was so very cool to meet them and hear their stories. 
 
 
 
 
 
 As I walked around the Chick- fil -a parking lot, I was so floored at how much there was to see. Some kids were playing inside a cop car and turning on the sirens to various settings. Also, some officers in what looked like flight suits stood outside the SWAT team van showcasing an M-4 rifle and some riot gear. There was a huge police boat parked outside and also a trailer holding a horse that some policemen ride. McGruff the Crime Dog made an appearance too(the kids mobbed him). I couldn&apos;t believe how big of an event this was really turning out to be! 
 
 
 
 
 
 Just then, I spotted the same well dressed lady who&apos;d announced the motorcycle rodeo. I noticed she was wearing a name tag that said &quot;marketing director&quot;. I introduced myself and found out her name was Jean Cain and she was one of the people who made this entire event happen. I congratulated her on such an impressive event and asked her how the event had been planned. She told me that an officer named Officer Jowers came in frequently for lunch and she got to talking to him about having an event coordinated with the Jacksonville Sheriff&apos;s office as one of their Family nights. Chick- fil -a has a Family Night every Thursday night where they usually have some sort of theme, and fun activities for the kids like clowns, caricature drawings and face painting. &quot;How long did you and Officer Jowers work to plan tonight&apos;s event?&quot; I asked. 
 
 
 
 
 
 &quot;Three months,&quot; she replied. She was so warm, friendly and welcoming. Judging by today&apos;s event, I would also say she is very dedicated to her work. Wow -- three months she planned this one event. It is so amazing that Chick- fil -a cares so much about having great community events like this. I feel so lucky to be living nearby. 
 
 
 
 
 
 As we were getting ready to leave, we heard a small cheer and saw everyone gazing and pointing up into the sky. A police helicopter was circling overhead! The kids were really excited, and let&apos;s admit it -- so were the parents. I should point out here too that I think it was really awesome that all of the officers took the time out of their hectic schedules (I&apos;m sure they are short handed and low on budget funds like most of the country) and worked so hard to put on such an awesome evening. It makes me feel very well protected and safe to live in a city with such dedicated and talented men and women who protect and serve. 
 
 
 
 
 
 **** Disclaimer - I really wasn&apos;t prepared to write about tonight&apos;s event, so my notes were scribbled on little bits of whatever scrap paper I could find. Also, my understanding of the police: their training, titles, rank structure, procedures and equipment is pitiful -- probably at somewhere around a second grade level. Even though my twin sister is a state attorney , my entire understanding of law enforcement could be summed as &quot;they are the good guys who put people in jail.&quot; That being said, I may have gotten names and ranks wrong, as well as facts about the evening wrong. If you are reading this and notice any errors PLEASE email me. I really appreciate the feedback and I will fix it to the best of my ability right away. Trust me, I don&apos;t want to look any more ignorant than I have to... 
 
 
 
 
 
 Posted by Erica at 5:56 PM Labels: Family Night Chick-fil-a , Family Safety Night Chick-fil-a Oakleaf Town Center , Jacksonville Sheriff&apos;s Office 
No comments:
 
 
Post a Comment


 
 Newer Post Older Post Home Subscribe to: Post Comments (Atom) 
&quot;Out and About in Jax&quot; is mentioned in Jacksonville Magazine!
 
 Check it out in the section about The Best of Jax Party (p 49) 
Share it
 
Follow me on Twitter!
 Loading... 
New! Check out the Out and About in Jax Facebook Group
 Check out the Fan page to see what events are coming up and what&apos;s new in Jax! Drop me a line on the wall and let me know what you&apos;re up to in the River City...
 http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=178358688881 
 
 
About Me
 Erica Jacksonville, FL I, like most people, love to get &quot;out and about&quot; in my favorite city! I created this site to help the reader find lots to do in Jax. Here you will find a listing of interesting charity and community events by week as well as blogs of the events I attend. Is there an event missing you want to tell me about? Email me at outandaboutinjax@gmail.com Interested in an event and wondering what it was like to be there? Read on! View my complete profile 
Subscribe To Out and About in Jax!
 Posts Atom Posts Comments Atom Comments 
Apartment Finder
 Looking for an apartment in the River City? Check out www.apartmentfinder.com/Florida/Jacksonville 
 
Sponsor Me!
 Do you see a particular event you are interested in? Would you like me to go and blog about it? You can sponsor me to go to an event of you choosing. Write me at outandaboutinjax@gmail.com and I will quote you a price for a particular event. This price will be based on price of admission to the event and the amount of time it will take me to attend. Payment will be handled through paypal.
 
Great Community Events Calendars
 Check out the Times-Union website for a great calendar of local events You can search by date, location or type of event:
 http://www.jacksonville.com/ 

Another website I really like for local events is Experience Jax. It isn&apos;t as high tech as Jacksonville.com but it doesn&apos;t have quite as many events listed, so it&apos;s a little easier to view events by day:
 http://www.experiencejax.com/ 



 
Some of My Favorite Area Event Websites
 The Library has a TON of free programs and classes for kids all the way up through adults. Their calendar is really good. You can see all events, or view events by Library Branch:
 http://www.jpl.coj.net/ 

Jax 4 Kids is a great site that has lots of local events and places to take kids:
 http://www.jax4kids.com/ 

Dowtown Vision has all of the happenings Downtown like The First Wednesday Art Walk every First Wednesday, and Destination Dowtown every Friday. There&apos;s also a great listing of events at the Landing like Yappy Hour and Free Live Music in the Courtyard 
 http://www.downtownvision.org/ 

 http://www.metrojacksonville.com/ is a local forum filled with all kinds of local topics like &quot;culture&quot;, &quot;dining and nightlife&quot;, and &quot;urban issues&quot;. You can even discuss topics by neighborhood.

 www.areaautism.blogspot.com is a blog all about local events and resources for those with autism.

 
Jacksonville Area FREEbies
 
 Affair in the Square, Every Third Thursday San Marco Square, 6-9pm Free Wine and Cheese Tasting Every Thursday, 6pm, Whole Foods Market Friday Musicale, Every Friday, 11am and 7:30pm, Friday Musicale Performance Hall Block Party in Five Points, First Friday of Every Month, FREE Healthy Beer and Wine Sampling, Every 3rd Thursday, Native Sun Natural Foods Market Baymeadows Orange Park Mall Art and Farmers Market, Every Saturday Starting October 3rd, 10am-2pm, FREE Oakleaf Green Market, Every Saturday, Bealls/HH Gregg Parking Lot, 10am-1pm Mandarin Farmers Market, Every Sunday, Whole Foods Market Parking Lot, 2pm-6pm Free Art and Farmers Market at the St. Johns Towncenter Every Friday 3pm-8pm Free Arts Market Every Saturday From 10am-4pm, Riverside Arts Market Square Free Live Entertainment in the Courtyard at the Jacksonville Landing Every First Wednesday, and Most Fridays Free Salsa and Latin Dance Classes at the Grape Wine Bar in the St. Johns Towncenter the First and Third Tuesday of Every Month 7-8:30pm Free Art Walk in St. Augustine the First Friday and the Last Saturday of Every Month Free Art Walk Downtown the First Wednesday of Every Month Get in Free to the Museum of Contemporary Art on Sundays for Families Get in Free to the Cummer Museum Every Tues 4-9, Sponsored by the Players 
 
 
Blog Archive
 
 ►  2011 (3) 
 ►  October (1) 
 St. Johns Town Center 2011 
 

 ►  August (1) 
 Jacksonville.com&apos;s&quot;One of Us&quot;Column 
 

 ►  April (1) 
 Prayer Walk at the Church at Argyle 
 
 

 ►  2010 (25) 
 ►  December (1) 
 Considering Relocating to Jacksonville? 
 

 ►  November (3) 
 St. Johns Town Center Holiday Spectacular Interview with Lead Singer of Vertical Horizon Mat... One Ocean Resort Gallery Re-Opening 
 

 ►  October (1) 
 The Premiere of Gore-E-ography: The Making of Deat... 
 

 ►  September (1) 
 State of the Re:Union -- A Celebration of Communit... 
 

 ►  August (1) 
 Jacksonville Music Video Revival in Five Points 
 

 ►  July (2) 
 Shoot for&quot;Open Skate (Zombie Disco)&quot;Music Video Buddhist Meditation Class in Orange Park 
 

 ►  June (1) 
 Lowe&apos;s Build and Grow Workshop 
 

 ►  May (3) 
 Make-Up Bar at Daniel James Aveda Salon Make-Up Bar Weekend in Savannah 
 

 ►  April (2) 
 The Ritz Chamber Players Spring Concert Clay County Agricultural Fair 
 

 ►  March (4) 
 Spring for the Arts at Deerwood Country Club I will be at Spring for the Arts Friday Meeting Jeannie Blaylock From First Coast News Fashion-First Thursday at One Ocean Resort 
 

 ►  February (1) 
 Marilyn: Forever Blonde Performance at The Museum ... 
 

 ►  January (5) 
 Platinum Promises Gala to Benefit DOSA Camps Best of Jacksonville Party 2010 at MOCA I&apos;ll be at the Platinum Promises Gala This Saturda... Happy New Year! Ollie Koala&apos;s Backyard in Mandarin 
 
 

 ▼  2009 (38) 
 ►  December (2) 
 The Jacksonville Symphony Orchestra- Handel&apos;s Mess... Opening of III Forks Restaurant in Southside 
 

 ►  November (4) 
 Opening of III Forks Restaurant in Southside 8th Annual Cirque Du Cabaret to Benefit the Limeli... Limelight Theatre Presents Celebrity Cabaret 2009 Premiere of Chiaroscuro Baby at the Florida Theatr... 
 

 ►  October (4) 
 Upcoming Trivia Night to Benefit Catholic Charitie... Conner&apos;s A-maize-ing Acres 80s Themed Birthday Party at Skate Station Cars and Coffee River City Marketplace 
 

 ►  September (1) 
 Afternoon in San Marco 
 

 ►  August (3) 
 Night at the Hyatt Art and Winefest 2009 to Benefit Shands NICU Oakleaf Green Market 
 

 ►  July (1) 
 Riverside Arts Market 
 

 ►  June (2) 
 Destiny Dance Center Recital and River City Brewin... Jacksonville Suns Game 
 

 ►  May (3) 
 Toddler Time at the Main Library and Hemming Plaza... Chiropractic Care in Pregnancy Lecture in Mandarin... Mommy and Me Cecil Recreation Center 
 

 ►  April (4) 
 UF Dancin&apos;Gators Showcase Catholic Charities Black and White Ball at Sawgras... 
 

 ▼  March (7) 
 Country Music Concert at the Landing and Junior Bo... Family Safety Night at Chick-fil-a Oakleaf Towncen... Spring For the Arts to Benefit the Cathedral Arts ... Opportunity to Get Involved 2009 Jax Irish Fest in Metro Park Florida Museum of Natural History Butterfly Rainfo... First Wednesday Art Walk Downtown 
 

 ►  February (5) 

 ►  January (2) 
 

 ►  2008 (1) 
 ►  November (1) 
 
 
 
Followers
 
Sitemeter
 
 
 Watermark template. Powered by Blogger .
	</body>
</document>
