<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003124" url="http://www.hungrygowhere.com/m/singapore/shokudo_streets_of_japan_the_heeren/" time="2012-07-12-19:14" support="22" score="0.0651381638538191" bingtitle="Shokudo Streets of Japan (The Heeren) - Singapore Food Reviews ..." webtitle="Shokudo Streets of Japan (The Heeren) - Singapore Food Reviews, Promotions and Information">
			<query id="000264" bing-rank="240"/>
			<query id="000257" bing-rank="140"/>
			<query id="001076" bing-rank="112"/>
			<query id="001067" bing-rank="12"/>
			<query id="001506" bing-rank="174"/>
			<query id="001287" bing-rank="105"/>
			<query id="001082" bing-rank="182"/>
			<query id="001161" bing-rank="173"/>
			<query id="001094" bing-rank="107"/>
			<query id="001071" bing-rank="38"/>
			<query id="001095" bing-rank="47"/>
			<query id="000266" bing-rank="202"/>
			<query id="001066" bing-rank="106"/>
			<query id="000973" bing-rank="97"/>
			<query id="001073" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="000438" bing-rank="226"/>
			<query id="001079" bing-rank="74"/>
			<query id="000878" bing-rank="211"/>
			<query id="001081" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="001096" bing-rank="63"/>
			<query id="001004" bing-rank="130"/>
			<query id="001090" bing-rank="142"/>
	<description>I need to hunt for my own table. I need to wait in queue to order food ... typical of the one you get from a fast food restaurant. ... Confirm plus gurantee chop i will return ...</description>
	<body>
		Find: Near: 
 
Shokudo Streets of Japan (The Heeren)
 32% 19 votes Overall 4.6 16 Reviews Food 4.7 Value 3.6 Ambience 5.5 Service 3.7 Call Directions Restaurant Information Restaurant, Kiosk/Stall Asian, Japanese Large Group, 
 Dinner, 
 Lunch, 
 Children/Family, 
 After Work, 
 Quiet/Peaceful, 
 Vibrant/Noisy, 
 People Watching, 
 Chillout, 
 Girls Night Out, 
 Hi Tea, 
 Brunch, 
 Romance/First Dates, 
 Hidden Find, 
 Boys Night Out, 
 Wheelchair Friendly, 
 Healthy Eating, $$ $$$ (S$6–35) 260 Orchard Road 
 #B1-01 The Heeren +65 6736 1216 Daily: 11.30am–11.00pm
 Must Tries omelette (3 Votes)
nil (2 Votes)
any burger from mcdonald across entrance (1 Votes)
cheesecake (1 Votes)
desserts (1 Votes) All Must Tries
 omelette 3 nil 2 any burger from mcdonald across entrance 1 cheesecake 1 desserts 1 nothing 1 omu rice 1 robatayaki 1 rosti 1 salmon rice bowl 1 teppanyaki 1 waffles 1 
 Reviews The Line 
 1 
 Ken Lim 475 
 Overall
 1 Food 1 Value 1 Ambience 3 Service 1 
 28 March 2010 

 Not worth it 
 Bad experience, regretted entering this place to have dinner.

The ramen was simply bad with tons of MSG, you could feel the MSG and will get very thirsty after the meal. The beef stew is from the fridge and being heated up in the microwave, what an insult.

Lastly, can you believe it, this place actually included 10% service charge into my total bill, felt cheated. Why do I have to pay 10% for zero service? I need to hunt for my own table. I need to wait in queue to order food, and when it’s my turn, I ordered my food, the intern looking cook, shouted across, “card please”, and said, “come back in 5 mins”. I’ve to walk to my table and return after 5 mins, and it was not ready and I’ve to walk back again after a few more minutes. I then collected my own cutlery, sauce and side plate.

Totally disappointed with this place, and will avoid it.



 The Line 
 96 
 Julian 
 Overall
 8 Food 9 Value 8 Ambience 9 Service 1 
 4 March 2010 

 Great prices for set lunches 
 Shokudo has been having a promotion for a while now - each stall has one item for $4.80++ for lunch. This is a great deal, because the food is actually meal sized and at such a decent price.

I ordered the Tonkatsu curry ($5.65) , and it was delicious. Not sure if the other whiners on this site tried this, but this has a healthy portion of pork and rice and a very nice, albeit mild, curry. It also came with miso soup, which was awesome.

But, I do have to agree with others here, and a common theme amongst all the criticisms of this place and others in Singapore - why is there a ++? The actual price is $5.65, which is still good, but why not just advertise that price instead? And, why service charge of 10% when I self-collected the food? The Line 
 2 
 Chocolatey Cho 
 Overall
 6 Food 7 Value 6 Ambience 8 Service 8 
 17 February 2010 

 worth every cent... 
 my trip to Shokudo at Heeren was worth every cent. i had no difficulties entering the restaurant cos there were only a few people in the queue and a table was allocated to us rather quickly.

food there was good. we ordered the usuals, ham and cheese omelette, their robatayaki, rosti bacon and a few others. the popular dishes i guess since we waited about 10-15mins for our food. the staff there did offer to check up on our food for us as well. thumbs up for that point.

the staff there were friendly and ever ready to help. clearing our plates once we were done with the food and providing us with serviettes.

went there with a 3 of my friends and all of us felt that it was a really good experience. I guess besides the ambience, the company matters as well.

 The Line 
 2 
 Chocolatey Cho 
 Overall
 7 Food 7 Value 7 Ambience 6 Service 8 
 17 February 2010 

 no complaints about service charge... 
 I\&apos;ve read a few of the reviews below and felt that Shokudo does have the rights to charge a service charge. Here\&apos;s a few pointers on why I think so:

1. Walking into Shokudo is similar to walking into a restaurant. It takes up its own retaurant space and there is always someone to invite you in and bring you to your seat.

2. I\&apos;ve been to Shokudo a few times and know well enough that they regularly change their menu or add new dishes. I guess that is also why the management would prefer that customers order their own food. So that all customers will know what are the new dishes and also to experience the feel of the a la minute open kitchen concept.

3. As I\&apos;ve personally experienced, the staff there as well will help to clear the used plates, provide serviettes and order or collect your food on your behalf.

Plus, walking into a reaturant that serves buffet, customers are also expected to walk to counters to pick up their own food. These places also do charge service charge. I mean, no offence to anyone but if a customer is not willing to pay for service charge and complain about food being expensive and all, then why choose to dine at a restaurant in the first place? Maybe paying for food at a food court will be a better option for you?

 The Line 
 16 
 Nate 
 Overall
 6 Food 6 Value 3 Ambience 5 Service 1 
 11 January 2010 

 You serve yourself and pay for service charge. 
 Ridiculous. I ended up going there as TGIF had a waiting time of 1 hour. Most of my mates don&apos;t eat meat so we basically had salmon steak, and salmon rice bowls, deep fried tofu, canned drinks and beer. Here you have servers walking around and when you asked them to collect your food, they claim that they&apos;re busy, and you pay 17% for nothing!

 The Line 
 2 
 Juan Lim 
 Overall
 1.5 Food 0.3 Value 1.5 Ambience 4.2 Service 0.1 
 1 August 2009 

 prepare to pay service charge for nothing 
 I hate this place!

this is my first, and my last visit to this place.

but firstly, i must admit that their ambience is not bad. :)

however i will not give any &quot;pass&quot; rating for this restaurant.

food, is not up to my standards. too salty and not filling.

service, is non existent.

I was given cards to order food. when I placed my orders, the chef told me to come back after 10mins to collect the food. ok so after 10 mins i collected my food, i wasnt given any sauce to go with my tempura. I returned to the counter in search of the missing sauce. the chef then observed me while i look around for the missing tempura sauce. finally he told me the location of said sauce. so he knew that i was looking for it all along! he wanted to see if i am capable of finding it myself. helpful......

after eating, i headed to the cashier with my mom to make payment. i asked the cashier what is the service charge for, since i found my own seat, ordered and collected my own food and utensils. guess her reply.

&quot;our management said its compulsory to impose a service charge because our food is relatively cheaper than outside. so instead of raising the cost of the food, we imposed service charge.&quot;

hmm. i believe their staff were trained to say this. if not why would she answer me in such a flawless way as if she was saying it to every customer?

so i told her i actually collected my own food, so i didnt know why i am paying the 10%.

cashier told me that i could ask the chef to deliver to me if i want. hello??

the chef sort of ordered me to go collect the food after 10mins. i didnt know i was allowed to order him back. :o

of course i was angry. can i dont pay any service charge if i want? since i can ask the chef to deliver to me if i want. :)

lastly, the food is very salty. i just hope they know that as customers, we will pay for good food, but we will not pay for no service. its okay to raise the cost of food, but definately not to impose service charge if the food is too cheap.

please. compare apples to apples. food does not equate service. The Line 
 5 
 MD Tan 
 Overall
 0.4 Food 0.1 Value 0.1 Ambience 0.5 Service 0.8 
 30 June 2009 

 Bad japanese food spin off 
 The japanese food are not authentic and sucks!

Not to mention the expensive prices given such quality.

i would not go there again, 1st time and last time! The Line 
 5 
 Arin Grey 
 Overall
 1.8 Food 0.1 Value 0.1 Ambience 5 Service 2 
 30 June 2009 

 The FOOD SUCKS my friend! 
 The only good thing about this place is probably the concept. Its uber cool and modern japanese restaurant transport you to a page in a manga comic. Service is so-so, typical of the one you get from a fast food restaurant. Nothing much can be said.

However, the food here is extremely dissapointing. I really has doubt that the chef (if you can call them that) know what they are cooking. Apology if you are reading this but THE FOOD SUCKS my friend!

Tried the salmon fried rice and it tasted like leftover from previous day. Its bland, too dried with 4 pathetic tiny piece of salmon. Even the salmon is not fresh.

The karrage curry rice was overly cooked and dry. Again, its bland and portion are pathetic. There was this omelette which taste better than all the rest. Reason? It taste like an omelette. I mean what could go wrong with an omellete?

To sum up, its not worth it, given the price you are paying. You thought its fairly price but when you see the food and tried, you realised how disapointing and expensive there are.

Initially, I am tempted to try alot of other stuff but didnt bother cause we cant seem to eat and finish anything what we ordered. No wonder the portion are small. Its not meant to be finish I guess. Didnt try the rest of the stuff but I guess they are just as bad.

Luckily there is Mcdonald just right across the entrance. We have to settle for a burger cause we left the place still feeling hungry and angry. For those people who have not tried this place, please have a plan B cause you definetly have to go somewhere to fill you up afterwards. The Line 
 6 
 C F 
 Overall
 3 Food 3 Value 4 Ambience 5 Service 0.1 
 21 June 2009 

 not worth it 
 This was my first time at Shokudo with my friends yesterday. We decided to try out the food, and the location was convenient for all. To get straight to the point, the food was so-so for the price charged. Each dish cost less than $10 before tax and service charge. Talking about service charge ... I was shocked that this was included in the final bill, because my friends and I were asking ourselves : &quot;What service???&quot;!!! We had to go to the food sections to order and collect our food. Throughout our 2 hours there, we had to clear our own used plates and cutlery. We had to search for the bin area (tucked in a dark corner). I found the service staff chatting between themselves in the corner. The service charge is not justified in any way, even though only 10% of our bill. We were wondering if we would have enjoyed our dinner better if we had gone to any one of the restaurants in the same building or nearby where food was served and cleared promptly by the servers. Or should we have gone to a food court, since we would have cleared our used plates and cutlery anyway? The Line 
 12 
 Dave Ding 
 Overall
 2.1 Food 4 Value 0.2 Ambience 4 Service 0.3 
 12 June 2009 

 Over priced substandard Japanese cuisine + Poor service = No GO. 
 Had a dinner at Shokudo outlet in The Heerens with some of my good friends on a Sat evening.

First impression of the restaurant: small, compared to the previous occupant, Vil&apos;lage. The service crew directed us to a table for three upon arrival. Before we left the table to make our order, we were given a &apos;reserve&apos; sign by the crew to signal to the others that the table has been taken.

However, when my friend came back with food, he informed me that the table was occupied by two young ladies. After asking the ladies, they informed me that it was a crew member that directed them to our table. Immediately I talked to one of the crew member that our allocated table was given to others by the staff. However, the response was they didn&apos;t know the table was taken up.

I demanded for their manager and explained to them on the situation, and he told me he will allocate another table for us. Before we were allocated to another table, I gave a piece of my mind to the manager that paying 10% service charge doesn&apos;t justify the poor service given by the crew member (Note: earlier on when we were given the first table allocated to us, the crew just throw in three items on the dining table: chopsticks, serviettes and a sulky face.)

So back to the food. I ordered a Chicken Karrage Curry rice ($8.50) and deep fried soft shell crab ($8.80). The average waiting time for both items takes about 10 minutes. My friend ordered a bacon omelette and Chicken Katsu curry rice ($8.50). Drinks, we had a coke light and coke zero ($2.60 each).

My comments on the food:

Chicken Katsu Curry Rice: portion looks big and filling for a average male adult, but a bit too much for someone with a smaller appetite. Plenty of potatoes and carrot slices were given in the curry. So I suppose too much carbohydrates and too little fibre for an average adult? Chicken cultet is big and really crispy. Good with the curry sauce. Value for money.

Chicken Karrage Curry Rice: a let down for someone who is looking for a value for money one meal dish. Same as the curry rice mentioned above, except that you get 5 small pieces of deep fried chicken that is overly dry and bland. A far cry from the chicken karrage you had in those small little Japanese bistro run by the Japanese. Even the instant deep fried chicken karrage sold in supermarket frozen food section do a better job.

Deep fried soft shell crab: a letdown, compared to the one served in Marche. Portion is small (about 5 small little crabs) and not really fried till crisp.

Bacon omelette: Omelette is thick and sweet, with chewy bacons and plenty of bonito flakes as dressing. Drenched with plenty of mayonaise, this is catered to those who wants a overload of cholestoral (or you decided to consume the recommended serving of eggs per week at a go.)

Of course there are other different types of Japanese cuisines served and sold in Shokudo, but failed to bring in any surprises.

Overall, dining at Shokudo Heerens simply means dining a mediocre Japanese food at a un-wallet friendly price is not recommended. There are better Japanese restaurants in Orchard Area which is worth visiting. The Line 
 14 
 ps 
 Overall
 1.5 Food 1.2 Value 0.6 Ambience 1.8 Service 2.3 
 17 May 2009 

 HO-HUM. won&apos;t be going back 
 Intrigued by how it looked from the outside, we went in for lunch on a Sunday afternoon, and was very much drawn in to the displays and stalls.

However, the food itself left much to be desired.

We ordered the spicy dry ramen with tempura, and some sticks of grilled meats (which came with a bowl of rice).

Very salty, amateur, tempura tasted bland and blah, ramen was just okay, but honestly very plain and ordinary.

Almost like the standard Japanese stall at food courts around the country.

HO HUM!! The Line 
 30 
 Heather Sung 
 Overall
 6.6 Food 6.5 Value 6.1 Ambience 8.5 Service 5.1 
 6 May 2009 

 Nice layout for gatherings, if you don&apos;t the over-pricing. 
 I was given a voucher to try out this highly raved eatery. Deco wise, the colours were great and conducive for small group gatherings. There were at least 3 different styles of seatings and provided sufficient physical barriers for a good conversation. The seats were comfortable. The hawker concept and layout is not too bad.

Items ordered:

- BBQ Prawn Roll with Bacon SGD3.8

The prawns were crunchy and fresh. The bacon was not too salty.

Just nice. However, it was over done and the bacon truned out a tad dry for my liking.

- BBQ Asparagus with pork belly SGD 3

Asparagus were bite size and not over done. The pork belly was too thin and overdone. Let&apos;s just say that I had better and cheaper ones in restaurants @ Cuppage.

- Jap curry rice with katsu SGD 8 - 10

The curry sauce is not bad. The potatoes and carrots were stewed til the edges were rounded. Not much msg used, yet flavourful and i was quite pleased with that. They used japanses pearl grain rice, unlike some places that mix normal grain rice with pearl grain ones. The katsu was a bit thin but i am not complaining as the this dish is value for money. The batter was not too thick and I could tatse the pork. It was lean pork, so don&apos;t expect the juicy, fatty effect that one can get from Tonkichi pork cutlets.

- Sashimi SGD 21 - 35

It was fresh but i have to say, tasted like SAKAE sushi. Nothing unique and worth skipping.

If i had more time, I would have tried the desserts. My gut feel tells me that the desserts are yummy but will come in small and very manageable portions for 1 pax. The Line 
 1 
 Happy_Bear 
 Overall
 4 Food 3.7 Value 0.5 Ambience 3.7 Service 8 
 6 May 2009 

 OVERPRICE FOOD 
 Went over with my friend this evening to try out this new version of &quot;MARCHE&quot;. We went in around 7plus with i think i am the fourth table (i guess so). Went i look around the place, the food menu is very common which we can find in food courts or even japanese restaurant, and the varieties of food is also lesser compare of MARCHE.

Order to share Rosti W sausage with egg, Chicken&amp;egg rice bowl, soda, and LASTLY This overprice salmon fried rice with omelette which cost me $9.80 ++ with just one slice of salmon (appox 30gm), oily fried rice and omelette. i was like&amp;*(*^&amp;*%^$#@# ....&quot;come on ..my grandma can cook better then this&quot;. Being a &quot;SINGAPOREAN&quot;, of course i complain to the service crew which in turn call the manager here. I ask him whether he will buy this $10 fried rice with just this small bits of salmon? He apologise and den return with more rice and salmon. I feedback to him saying that i wasnt aiming for free stuffs but hope the management understand how expensive that plate of fried rice was and service charge was included which i don&apos;t see any kind of service being render.

Just want to praise this manager JASON for his effort for good recovery service. The Line 
 7 
 Missy Jen 
 Overall
 5.8 Food 5 Value 4 Ambience 7.5 Service 6.5 
 4 April 2009 

 Not reallly very fantastic 
 Was looking forward to dine at Shokudo as its seems like a new concept to have a Japanese Restaurant to work in the same way as its past tenant Marché.

Made a call in the morning (to the branch at Raffles City) wanting to make a reservation but to my disappointment, the staff told me &quot;Sorry the reservation is full today&quot;.

Seems like its really a popular place huh?

Fortunately managed to make a reservation for the branch at Heeren.

The restaurant is pretty spacious and there&apos;s only like less than 10 sections for selections.

Dishes that we have tried

- Sashimi

- Grilled stuffs from the grilled counter e.g Grilled saloms etc

- Sobas

- Pizza style pan fried potato (cant rember the name.. but its like the Rosti in Marché, just that there are cheese added to it)

- Shabu Shabu

- Kakiage

- Pastas

- Fried egg roll with Bacon and cheese

- Curry rice

- Waffle Desserts

Personally I feel that the food is overly priced for the servings and quality.

While waiting for my rosti, overheard one of the customer requesting for extra Sour Cream sauce for the Rosti that he have ordered and the staff actually told him that for extra sour cream, you are required to pay additional $1.

I find it rather ridiculous. Just one more scoop of sour cream cost $1?

Of all the food that was ordered, the only dish that I will recommend is the Fried egg roll with Bacon and cheese.

If you are one who really likes Japanese food, I would recommend you to patronise an authentic Japanese Restaurant. 
Photos Uploaded
	</body>
</document>
