<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003882" url="http://www.hot-screensaver.com/2008/05/19/aw-fast-food-restaurant/" time="2012-07-12-20:02" support="2" score="0.001200484884245546" bingtitle="A&amp;W fast food restaurant - Hot-screensaver" webtitle="AW fast food restaurant -  Hot-screensaver">
			<query id="001453" bing-rank="247"/>
			<query id="001466" bing-rank="63"/>
	<description>... can see, it may be able to be completed by the end ... Luckily the world number one could bounce back in ... root beer drink only available at A&amp;W fast food restaurant.</description>
	<body>
		Home About Hot-Screensaver 
 
 Hot-screensaver 
 Lifestyle, Hotels, Travel, Interesting People, Celebrities, Places and Property 
 A&amp;W fast food restaurant 

May 19th, 2008 by Neo 
 


Sunday, it’s time of the week to jump over to the shopping centers and do some window shoppings and checking out what’s hot in town. Unfortunately, nothing much to see and do in the one which I chose to go to, IOI Mall . This might be a popular shopping center for people around this area of the town, but it certainly is a boring place because there isn’t enough of varieties of shops compared to much larger shopping centers such as One Utama and Mid Valley.

 

Anyway, the good news is that IOI is expanding the mall and construction work is already under way…the structures is already up and from what I can see, it may be able to be completed by the end of the year! Looking forward to that. 

OK, that aside, I was surprised to see the A&amp;W restaurant is still there! Wow, I haven’t dine at this place for ages…

 

 

That’s what we had. One Chicken Sandwich set, one chicken rice and one Connie Dog. Oh yes, they serve chicken rice too, but you can be certain that The Chicken Rice Shop still serves the best chicken rice in town.

 

That’s the chicken rice, pretty small portion and it only consist of one piece of chicken. I would prefer it to come with at least two pieces otherwise I will need to find supper for the night. 

 

The chicken burger from A&amp;W is pretty fresh and juicy too! I quite like how it tasted although it was absolutely different from that from Mc Donalds. It tasted a little bland but I don’t mind having this once in a while just for a change. On top of that, I have to admin A&amp;W’s root beer with the vanilla ice cream afloat is one of the best drink I have ever tasted in a fast food restaurant.

 

Not an eventful day…but I had a nice dinner, and glad to find no more ants in my house (yes, the ants powder works like a magic!), and even more glad to know that China has overpowered Korea to win the Thomas Cup one more time! An uneventful day ended with cheers and applauses over the Thomas Cup live telecast. 
 Bookmark to 
 
 Read my site in your Email :

 
 
By FeedBurner 
 
   Email This Post Tags: fast food , food , ioi mall , restaurant 

 
Posted in Food Watch 
 
12 Responses to“A&amp;W fast food restaurant”

 on 19 May 2008 at 12:47 am 1 Raymond Chan 
At least China managed to retain their title after winning Malaysia. If not, Malaysia has lots to worry about. lol
 on 19 May 2008 at 1:11 am 2 Anston 
I luv A&amp;W Rootbeer 

You are damn right, the taste of the burger cannot compared to others, still A&amp;W burger is my favorite!

(woops, not to mention the BigMac lar! lol)
 on 19 May 2008 at 4:49 am 3 clement 
there’s a restaurant??? ha ha…
 on 19 May 2008 at 10:24 am 4 Neo 
Raymond Chan,
Yes, glad that the Chinese managed to grab the Thomas Cup again. The first set between Lin Dan and the Korean was such a worrying one, wasn’t it? Luckily the world number one could bounce back in time to win the first important point!

Anston,
A&amp;W burger is your favorite!? You mean McDonalds, I suppose?

clement,
Long time no see you lor. 
 on 19 May 2008 at 3:53 pm 5 Che-Cheh 
I like A&amp;W’s fish burger, onion rings and of course their famous root beer.
Didn’t blog about Thomas Cup ar? 
 on 19 May 2008 at 6:38 pm 6 willchua 
No more A&amp;W in sarawak but their canned root beer still my fav soft drink.
 on 20 May 2008 at 6:53 am 7 keeyit 
I seldom go to A&amp;W for fast food. Normally will go to McD. McD supporter le…But once a while will go to KLCC for A&amp;W la…Like the onion rings..
 on 20 May 2008 at 8:07 am 8 Khengsiong 
I prefer A&amp;W’s Mozza Burger and fries to those of McD. I also like its curly fries and onion rings. But due to mismanagement, this fast food chain just doesn’t do very well.

When I was in the States some years ago, I only came across 1 or 2 A&amp;W outlets during my 1-year stay there.
 on 29 May 2008 at 12:36 am 9 satkuru 
the only reason i drop by A&amp;W is for their rootbeer/float and their curly fries. it has been eons since i have set my foot in any of their outlets -_-”
 on 07 Jul 2008 at 1:44 am 10 Food photography - Hot-screensaver 
[...] Root Beer. This is of course the authentic root beer drink only available at A&amp;W fast food restaurant. This glass was an upgraded one with two scoops of ice [...]
 on 22 Jul 2008 at 5:21 pm 11 pnky 
i wonder why people dont like dine in aw.
 on 23 Aug 2008 at 11:13 pm 12 KFC chicken rice and flavored French fries - Hot-screensaver 
[...] not so new anymore, just that it was my first time trying this. It tasted good, but I still heart A&amp;W’s fries [...]
 
 
 Trackback URI | Comments RSS 
 
Leave a Reply
 
 Name (required) 

 Mail (hidden) (required) 

 Website 


 Check/tick this and I will notify you of followup comments via email. 


 

 

 
 « The ants Ice cream waffer » 
 Hot-screensaver 
Lifestyle, Hotels, Travel, Interesting People, Celebrities, Places and Property
There are 991 Posts and 10,144 Comments so far.
 

Last Comments

 situs web : Thankfulness to my father who told me regarding this blog, this website is genuinely remarkable. XBox : It’s appropriate time to make a few plans for the future and it is time to be happy. I have learn this... ??? ??? ????? : hello there and thanks on your information ? I’ve certainly picked up something new from right... Newberg : Excellent post! I completely agree with all of your points. Melbourne Australia Tours : Wow!! did she do a tour in Australia? She must be very good. Do you have a link to her... 
 
Recent Posts

 Juwita Suwito one of the Best Female Solo Artist in Malaysia Henry Winkler‘The Fonz’not hindered by Dyslexia Steampunk Loft in New York, Worth $1.75M Monsopiad Cultural Village: Sabah’s Cultural Heritage Retrospecting Andy Gibb Top restaurants with good ambience and food 
 
Categories

 Architecture (2) Blogging (32) Cars&amp;Driving (52) Celebrities&amp;Entertainment (52) Cool Gadgets&amp;Toys (49) Family, friends&amp;I (52) Food Watch (158) Free Downloads (7) Hot Cartoons (10) Hotels (21) In my Inbox (68) Interesting Places (72) Internet (51) Lifelog (41) Light Moments (100) Malaysia–my home (89) Misc (24) Photographs (226) Property (7) Site Update (16) Sports&amp;Athletes (52) Malaysia Property 
 
Archives

 December 2011  (1) September 2011  (2) August 2011  (3) July 2011  (3) June 2011  (3) April 2011  (2) March 2011  (3) February 2011  (3) January 2011  (4) December 2010  (8) November 2010  (6) October 2010  (6) September 2010  (3) August 2010  (4) July 2010  (7) June 2010  (6) May 2010  (6) April 2010  (8) March 2010  (10) February 2010  (11) January 2010  (12) December 2009  (13) November 2009  (4) October 2009  (5) September 2009  (5) August 2009  (11) July 2009  (11) June 2009  (11) May 2009  (11) April 2009  (12) March 2009  (14) February 2009  (9) January 2009  (10) December 2008  (14) November 2008  (13) October 2008  (12) September 2008  (12) August 2008  (13) July 2008  (16) June 2008  (18) May 2008  (14) April 2008  (15) March 2008  (16) February 2008  (13) January 2008  (21) December 2007  (15) November 2007  (18) October 2007  (21) September 2007  (16) August 2007  (20) July 2007  (22) June 2007  (17) May 2007  (14) April 2007  (15) March 2007  (18) February 2007  (15) January 2007  (20) December 2006  (22) November 2006  (19) October 2006  (16) September 2006  (18) August 2006  (23) July 2006  (30) June 2006  (23) May 2006  (26) April 2006  (26) March 2006  (26) February 2006  (27) January 2006  (15) December 2005  (12) November 2005  (20) October 2005  (37) September 2005  (36) 
 
 
 
Tags

 babes badminton bandar puteri bikini camera car christmas dance diy donuts dslr f1 fashion food funny girls holiday hotel hotel blog hotels malaysia klcc kuala kangsar malaysia Malaysia hotel blog Malaysia travel blog mid valley model models nikon one utama pc fair penang photo photography photos photoshop puchong race queens restaurant sepang sexy sunway pyramid super gt tennis travel blog 
 
Pages

 About Hot-Screensaver 
 
 
 
Site Updates

 
 Read my site in your Email :

 
 
By FeedBurner 
 
 Site feed 
 
 
 Hot-screensaver ©2005 - 2012 All Rights Reserved.
	</body>
</document>
