<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003794" url="http://friendseat.com/restaurants/King-of-Prussia/Baja-Fresh-Mexican-Grill_99" time="2012-07-12-19:57" support="1" score="0.0005849375418423147" bingtitle="Baja Fresh Mexican Grill - Fast Food Restaurant King of Prussia ..." webtitle="Baja Fresh Mexican Grill - Fast Food Restaurant  King of Prussia, PA 19406">
			<query id="001472" bing-rank="45"/>
	<description>Baja Fresh Mexican Grill is a Fast Food restaurant located at 340 ... William™ ... I usually end up going at least once a week!</description>
	<body>
		Welcome to FriendsEat :: Login       
 
Baja Fresh Mexican Grill
 
Average User Rating
 
5
 
Average
 
Sponsored Link


 
(610) 337-2050

 http://bajafresh.com/ 
 PA &gt; King of Prussia &gt; Restaurants &gt; Fast Food Signup to FriendsEAT Business 
To claim Baja Fresh Mexican Grill listing. Please enter the following details.
 
 Email Address 
 Last Name 
 First Name 
 I am authorized by Baja Fresh Mexican Grill to claim this listing. 

 
 

By clicking the button below, you agree to the FriendsEAT Terms of Service and Privacy Policy .

 
 
Is this your restaurant?

 Claim This Business Listing 
 
 Profile Stats Edit Map Coupons Social 
 profile_tab profiles 
Sponsored Link
 
About Baja Fresh Mexican Grill
 Baja Fresh Mexican Grill is a Fast Food restaurant located at 340 W Dekalb Pike in King of Prussia, PA 19406. Baja Fresh Mexican Grill has been described as an Good Fast Food restaurant and has received an average rating of 5 by our members. 
Quick Facts
 
 Cuisine: Fast Food Accepts Credit Card: Yes Parking: N/A 

 Atmosphere: N/A Take Reservations: Yes Serves Alcohol: N/A Smoking Allowed: No 

 
User Reviews for Baja Fresh Mexican Grill
 
 
 
All Reviews for Baja Fresh Mexican Grill


 
 
 1 2 3 4 5 6 Showing 1-4 0f 15 Reviews 
 
 Add a Review 
Statistics about Baja Fresh Mexican Grill:
 Profile Views :   

 Ad Views :   0

 Ad Clicks :   0

 Fans :   0

 Reviews :   0

 
Comments
 
 
Tweets from Baja Fresh Mexican Grill
 Thursday is Definitely a Burrito Day! Try a tasty and filling Classic Burrito from Baja Fresh!
 about 13 hours ago.   Reply 
BAJAFRESHNYC HAPPY HOUR 3pm-9pm! Every Day at Baja Fresh NYC! $3 Coronas! $3 Margaritas! $3 Wines! Come cool off at Baja!
 1 day ago.   Reply 
BAJAFRESHNYC Find the Baja Fresh Taco for cool discounts and information! He&apos;s roaming around Times Square and Grand Central.
 6 days ago.   Reply 
BAJAFRESHNYC Thursday is Definitely a Burrito Day! Try a tasty and filling Classic Burrito from Baja Fresh!
 7 days ago.   Reply 
BAJAFRESHNYC An Entree, Reg Drink, and side of Chips for $8.99 plus tax. Don&apos;t forget about our complimentary Salsa Bar. Every Day at Baja Fresh NYC!
 9 days ago.   Reply 
BAJAFRESHNYC 
Baja Fresh Mexican Grill Tips
 Baja salsa is sooo good!
 
Lauren S. Try the new fire grilled chicken bowl.
 
William™ Two taco combo!!! :)
 
Kevin I. This place rocks! Food is always great. I usually end up going at least once a week!
 
Kevin I. Love the fresh pico!
 
Lee 
Baja Fresh Mexican Grill News
 Oakland&apos;s bounty! Baja Fresh Mexican Grill 1357 Coolidge Highway ... and the owners of Brooklyn Pizza describe their pies as New York-style pizza cooked in a brick oven, fueled by coal or wood. This method creates a thin, crisp crust that snaps and shatters when you ... 
Related Links
 Powered by Bing Baja Fresh Check out the NEW Baja Fresh Party Pack Catering Menu Now at select locations Baja Fresh Mexican Grill in Downtown Atlanta – We Cater The Best ... See what’s coming to Baja Fresh this Summer! New Fired Grilled Achiote Chicken Taco: Achiote marinated fired grilled chicken, avocado, romaine lettuce, salsa Verde ... Baja Fresh Mexican Grill - Campbell, CA Category: Restaurants Mexican Mexican. 1976 S Bascom Ave Campbell, CA 95008 (408) 377-2600 Baja Fresh Mexican Grill - San Ramon, CA Category: Restaurants Mexican Mexican. 132 Sunset Dr San Ramon, CA 94583 (925) 866-6667 Find Baja Fresh Mexican Grill Locations in Your Area - Insider Pages Baja Fresh Mexican Grill Location Finder. The first Baja Fresh Mexican Grill restaurant opened in 1990, serving all-fresh, traditional, fire-grilled Mexican favorites. 
Related Video
 
Sponsored Link
 
Map and Directions
 
 Get Directions by Car 
 
Weather:
 
Today
 
 88° 
Fri
 
 66° - 84° 
Sat
 
 72° - 90° 
Sun
 
 73° - 93° 
 
Address
 
Baja Fresh Mexican Grill

340 W Dekalb Pike

King of Prussia, PA 
 
19406
 
Telephone
 (610) 337-2050 
Baja Fresh Mexican Grill
 
 Rating :  5 out of 10 based on 5 reviews. 
 Under $20 per entree 
Baja Fresh Mexican Grill Photos
 
 Fast Food 
 
 Local Places
 
 Baja Fresh Mexican Grill 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Bear Rock Cafe 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Bassett&apos;s Original Memphis BBQ 
 Coupon 
Cuisine: Fast Food Sleep Inn King of Prussia 
Cuisine: Hotels Motels Bare Escentuals 
Cuisine: Day Spas Crabtree Evelyn 
Cuisine: Day Spas Sona Med Spa 
Cuisine: Day Spas The Healing Point 
Cuisine: Day Spas 
 

See all King of Prussia Hotels Motels 
See all King of Prussia Day Spas 
See all King of Prussia Department Stores 

 
People Reached This Page By Searching For
 
 Baja Fresh Mexican Grill Coupons 

 Baja Fresh Mexican Grill King of Prussia 

 Baja Fresh Mexican Grill Menu 
 
 Searches 
 Coupon Discounts Sitemap Local Businesses Restaurant Coupons 
 King of Prussia Restaurants 
 A | B | C | D | E | F | J | K L | M | P | R | S | T | W 
 Cuisines 
 American Chinese French Indian Italian 
 Cuisines 
 Japanese Mexican Pizza 
 Friendseat Links 
 About US &amp; Contact FAQs 
 FriendsEAT Tools 
 Sitemap Terms of Use Privacy Policy 
 
 
 About Privacy Invite Terms Contact Us Mobile Advertise Developers Banners Copyright 
 Binary Bits LLC©All Rights Reserved |
	</body>
</document>
