<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003721" url="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0203259/episodes" time="2012-07-12-19:52" support="22" score="0.0717842781003376" bingtitle="Law &amp; Order: Special Victims Unit (1999) - Episodes - IMDb" webtitle="Law&amp;Order: Special Victims Unit (1999) - Episodes - IMDb">
			<query id="001373" bing-rank="113"/>
			<query id="001361" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001372" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000604" bing-rank="117"/>
			<query id="000541" bing-rank="30"/>
			<query id="000119" bing-rank="81"/>
			<query id="001367" bing-rank="18"/>
			<query id="000620" bing-rank="77"/>
			<query id="000619" bing-rank="177"/>
			<query id="000618" bing-rank="189"/>
			<query id="000556" bing-rank="57"/>
			<query id="001484" bing-rank="55"/>
			<query id="000118" bing-rank="119"/>
			<query id="001358" bing-rank="27"/>
			<query id="001498" bing-rank="142"/>
			<query id="000104" bing-rank="46"/>
			<query id="000383" bing-rank="86"/>
			<query id="001499" bing-rank="136"/>
			<query id="001355" bing-rank="52"/>
			<query id="001450" bing-rank="56"/>
			<query id="000555" bing-rank="72"/>
			<query id="000557" bing-rank="2"/>
	<description>In order to bring down a Russian mobster running an international prostitution ... TV Online: Prime Instant Video Unlimited Streaming of Movies &amp; TV: Amazon Germany</description>
	<body>
		IMDb More All Titles TV Episodes Names Companies Keywords Characters Videos Quotes Bios Plots Register | Login | Help 
 Movies 
 In Theaters Coming Soon Top Movies Showtimes Trailers Watchlist MyMovies New: DVD&amp;Blu-Ray Top 250 Genres Editors&apos; Spotlight Independent Film Summer Movie Guide 
 TV 
 TV Home TV Listings TV Episodes&amp;Clips Best TV Series 
 News 
 Top News Movie News TV News Celebrity News Featured News 
 Trailers 
 Trailer Gallery 
 Community 
 Message Boards Contributor Zone Newest Lists Your Lists Your Ratings 
 IMDbPro 
 IMDbPro IMDb Resume 
 Apps 
 Apps Home iPhone App iPad App Android Phones App Android Tablets App IMDb App on Kindle Fire Windows Phone App IMDb Trivia App IMDb Buzz App IMDb Mobile Site 
 
 Your Watchlist 
 ◄  Law&amp;Order: Special Victims Unit 
 
Episode List
 Season: 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13  OR  Year:   1999 2000 2001 2002 2003 2004 2005 2006 2007 2008 2009 2010 2011 2012   
Season 13
 S13, Ep1 Sep. 21, 2011 Scorched Earth An African immigrant working as a maid accuses an Italian diplomat of rape, but is she really in it just for the money? Meanwhile, Stabler&apos;s return remains in doubt after his latest shooting.   S13, Ep2 Sep. 28, 2011 Personal Fouls SVU investigates an accusation that a revered high school basketball coach sexually abused his players, but they ultimately may need the cooperation of a reluctant pro superstar to make the case.   S13, Ep3 Oct. 5, 2011 Blood Brothers A pregnant 13 year old girl from Washington Heights claims that the son of an ambassador raped her, but the accused goes missing before SVU can question him.   S13, Ep4 Oct. 12, 2011 Double Strands Detective Rollins believes that SVU has caught a serial rapist from one of her earlier cases in Georgia, but a passioned request after a suicide attempt leads Amaro to suspect that they may have the wrong person.   S13, Ep5 Oct. 19, 2011 Missing Pieces When a baby of a couple from out of town, goes missing, the team tries to find him. But they later turn their focus on the parents cause the story they tell doesn&apos;t add up. And they find evidence that leads them to think that the baby died and they brought it to New York to dispose of the body.   S13, Ep6 Nov. 2, 2011 True Believers A.D.A. Cutter tries to prosecute an African American drug dealer who raped a 19 year old music student, but his opposing counsel is a high-priced attorney who is devoted to protecting the civil rights of accused minorities.   S13, Ep7 Nov. 9, 2011 Russian Brides In order to bring down a Russian mobster running an international prostitution/kidnapping ring disguised as a Russian bride website, Kragen steps from behind the desk to go undercover as a &quot;John.&quot;   S13, Ep8 Nov. 16, 2011 Educated Guess Benson and Rollins investigate whether a psychiatric patient was raped in her hospital ward, which ultimately leads to a possible predator close to her home.   S13, Ep9 Nov. 30, 2011 Lost Traveller The child of a Romani couple in Brooklyn disappears on his way home from school, but the neighborhood&apos;s rom-baro may be interfering with SVU&apos;s investigation.   S13, Ep10 Dec. 7, 2011 Spiraling Down A retired pro quarterback is busted for having sex with a 14-year-old prostitute, but he may be suffering from diminished capacity because of all the concussions he had on the field.   S13, Ep11 Jan. 11, 2012 Theatre Tricks SVU tries to figure out who was responsible for the real-life rape of an actress during an interactive theater performance that everybody just assumed was part of the show.   S13, Ep12 Jan. 18, 2012 Official Story SVU investigates an accusation of a brutal rape in Iraq involving a private defense contractor, and Olivia takes a romantic interest in the ADA who is prosecuting the case.   S13, Ep13 Feb. 8, 2012 Father&apos;s Shadow A 19-year-old creates a hostage situation after his father is accused of sexual assault, and Olivia uses her personal experience to help defuse the situation.   S13, Ep14 Feb. 15, 2012 Home Invasions After a couple is murdered in their home and their daughter is critically injured, SVU uncovers a number of twisted family secrets, as well as detective Rollins&apos; gambling addiction.   S13, Ep15 Feb. 22, 2012 Hunting Ground An underage escort is reported missing, and SVU soon discovers that they are dealing with a serial killer who may be playing games with his victims.   S13, Ep16 Feb. 29, 2012 Child&apos;s Welfare While Olivia tries to help her brother regain custody of his two children, SVU discovers that a baby abandoned in front of a church belongs to a missing teen.   S13, Ep17 Apr. 11, 2012 Justice Denied Benson&apos;s relationship with ADA Hayden threatens to be exposed after she discovers that she helped put the wrong man in prison eight years earlier for rape.   S13, Ep18 Apr. 18, 2012 Valentine&apos;s Day A husband believes that he&apos;s witnessed his wife&apos;s rape during a video call from overseas, but SVU soon discovers that there could be more to his wife&apos;s story than meets the eye.   S13, Ep19 Apr. 25, 2012 Street Revenge The task of find a serial rapist becomes more difficult when a team of neighborhood vigilante &quot;superheroes&quot; starts trying to avenge the crimes.   S13, Ep20 May 2, 2012 Father Dearest Is a sperm donor father trying to have babies with the children he fathered, or could it be part of an even more fiendish plot?   S13, Ep21 May 9, 2012 Learning Curve As Fin tries to get justice after his gay son&apos;s fiancé is brutally beaten in a hate crime, SVU uncovers a scandal involving a teacher sexually abusing a student at a prep school.   S13, Ep22 May 16, 2012 Strange Beauty The investigation of the homicide of a young woman who recently had her leg amputated sends SVU into the strange culture of body modification.   S13, Ep23 May 23, 2012 Rhodium Nights The murder of a prostitute at a bachelor party sends SVU on a dangerous investigation that could lead all the way into the highest reaches of New York power and influence.   «  Season 12  |   Season 13   ad feedback Share this page: 
Quick Links:
 overview full cast and crew - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - taglines plot summary plot keywords - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - quotes trivia crazy credits connections soundtracks - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - release dates official sites company credits filming locations technical specs literature - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - photo gallery trailers and videos posters - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - newsdesk recommendations - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - awards faq user reviews user ratings external reviews message board - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - miscellaneous photographs - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - episode list episode cast episodes by rating episodes by date episodes by vote tv schedule Create a list  » 
Related Lists
 90S rules! TV Shows that the 90s gave us a list of 58 titles by castillourbano created 15 May 2011   Tv Series a list of 133 titles by wginc1 created 21 Dec 2010   Top 25 Crime TV Shows a list of 25 titles by khanrhine created 5 months ago   Best TV shows of 2011-2012 a list of 40 titles by Kelbelllv created 6 months ago   top tv shows of the 2000&apos;s a list of 121 titles by hhh_91 created 2 months ago   See all 1011 related lists  » Getting Started | Contributor Zone  » 
Contribute to This Page
 Add episode 
 
Explore More About Law&amp;Order: Special Victims Unit
 
Credits
 full cast and crew 

Story
 taglines 
 plot summary 
 plot keywords 

Did You Know?
 quotes 
 trivia 
 goofs 
 crazy credits 
 alternate versions 
 connections 
 soundtracks 
 
Details
 release dates 
 official sites 
 box office/business 
 company credits 
 filming locations 
 technical specs 
 literature 

Photos&amp;Video
 photo gallery 
 trailers and videos 
 posters 
 
Opinion
 awards 
 faq 
 user reviews 
 user ratings 
 external reviews 
 metacritic reviews 
 message board 

External Links
 miscellaneous 
 sound clips 
 video clips 
 photographs 
 
Related Items
 NewsDesk 
 showtimes 

TV
 episode list 
 episode cast 
 rated episodes (by date / vote )
 tv schedule 

Professional Services
 get more at IMDbPro 
 add posters&amp;stills to this title 
 
 
   
 
 Home | Search | Site Index | In Theaters | Coming Soon | Top Movies | Watchlist | Top 250 | TV | News | Video | Message Boards | Press Room 
 Register | RSS | Advertising | Contact Us | Jobs | IMDbPro | IMDb Resume | Box Office Mojo | Withoutabox | LOVEFiLM 

IMDb Mobile: iPhone/iPad | Android | Mobile site | Windows Phone 7 | IMDb Social: Facebook | Twitter 

International Sites: IMDb Germany | IMDb Italy | IMDb Spain | IMDb France | IMDb Portugal 



 Copyright© 1990-2012 IMDb.com, Inc. 
 Terms and Privacy Policy under which this service is provided to you.
An company.

 Amazon Affiliates Amazon Instant Video 
 Watch Movies&amp;
TV Online
	</body>
</document>
