<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003276" url="http://hamptoninn.hilton.com/en/hp/hotels/index.jhtml?ctyhocn=NYCMTHX" time="2012-07-12-19:24" support="2" score="0.0036282249592820056" bingtitle="New York City Hotels - Hampton Inn Manhattan/Times Square Hotel ..." webtitle="New York Hotels | Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North | New York, NY">
			<query id="000270" bing-rank="121"/>
			<query id="000281" bing-rank="84"/>
	<description>Your Confirmation # ... Hotel + Air + Car Reservation; Air Itinerary; Car Rental ... Suites Hotels Enjoy a complimentary cooked-to-order ...</description>
	<body>
		Skip to Content 
 
 My Reservations My Reservations View Promotions 
 Sign In Not a Member? Explore the Benefits       /   My Account Sign Out     Username or HHonors # Password or PIN Sign In   Remember Me Forgot Password? Sign in to view all reservations in your account: Username or HHonors # Password or PIN Sign In   View/change a specific reservation: Your Confirmation # Last Name Find   Existing Travel Reservations: 
 Hotel + Air + Car reservation Air itinerary Car rental details 
 Your Next Stay: See all 
     
 View/Edit 
 Your Last Stay: See all 
     
 View Receipt Book Again 
 Join Hilton HHonors™ Upgrade your account and earn points at over 3,600 hotels in 82 countries around the world. Join HHonors                       
     HP 
 Skip brand navigation 

 Find a Hotel Offers Meetings&amp;Events About Hampton 
 Search 
 skip form 
 
 Where are you going? City, airport, address, attraction, or hotel 
 Arrival You are now focused on a datepicker field. Press the down arrow to enter the calendar table. Once focused on the table, press left or right to navigate days. Press up or down to navigate between weeks. Enter to select. Escape to close datepicker. Your arrival date must be within the next year.   Departure You are now focused on a datepicker field. Press the down arrow to enter the calendar table. Once focused on the table, press left or right to navigate days. Press up or down to navigate between weeks. Enter to select. Escape to close datepicker. Your departure date must be within 4 months after your arrival date.   
 Rooms Adults (18+) Children Rooms 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26+ Adults in Room 1 1 2 3 4 Children in Room 1 0 1 2 3 4 Room 2 Adults in Room 2 1 2 3 4 Children in Room 2 0 1 2 3 4 Room 3 Adults in Room 3 1 2 3 4 Children in Room 3 0 1 2 3 4 Room 4 Adults in Room 4 1 2 3 4 Children in Room 4 0 1 2 3 4 
 
 Use HHonors Points 
 
 Use flexible dates 
 Add special rate codes (AAA, AARP, etc) 
 Promotion/Offer code: 

 Group code: 

 Corporate account: 
 
 Travel agent 

 AAA rate * 

 AARP rate * 

 CARP rate * 

 Government / Military rates * 

* ID required at check-in
 Close Find it   Find it Check Availability Our Best Rates Guarantee 
 
 close tab panel 
 offers Browse our specials and packages to find great deals for your next Hampton stay. see our specials and packages 
 featured offers last minute deals popular offers 
 End of tab panel 

 
 close tab panel 
 groups Taking a trip with a travel sports team or group? Hampton can help you book five rooms or more at a special rate. reserve a group of guestrooms meetings We can help you make your meeting run smoothly when you reserve a meeting room at Hampton. book a meeting social occasions Hampton is the perfect place for your guests to stay during your special event. We can help you organize and plan for your big day. start planning your special occasion End of tab panel 

 
 close tab panel 
 why Hampton? Learn about how Hampton can help you along your journey. see all our amenities locations No matter which one of our locations you visit, you’ll get the full Hampton experience. find a Hampton new hotels Find out about our newest hotels and where we’re scheduled to open soon. see all new hotels End of tab panel 
   Not what you&apos;re looking for? Find Nearby Hotels HHonors Reward Category: 6   

 Hotel Information Check-in: 3:00 pm Check-out: 12:00 pm Smoking: Non-Smoking Parking: Self parking: Not Available Valet: 
 
 $40.00
 
 
 (Click for details) Pets: Service animals allowed: Yes Pets allowed: No Hotel Policies Where we are 
Find where we are located
 View the Maps&amp;Directions Page 
 New York,NY NYCMTHX Local Weather 
This content will open in a overlay
 Five Day Forecast While You&apos;re in Town Restaurant and attraction reviews near this hotel – from travelers like you View Now NYCMTHX 
Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North
 851 Eighth Avenue, New York, New York, 10019, USA TEL: 1-212-581-4100 Book a Room 
 Built in 2005, the impressive Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North has the best Times Square location just steps from Broadway theaters, Restaurant Row, Central Park, Carnegie Hall, many museums, Radio City Music Hall, Rockefeller Center, Jacob Javits Convention Center and all major bus and subway lines. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_exterior3_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Exterior 0 
 Exterior 
 Conveniently located on Eighth Avenue at 51st Street, the hotel is fast becoming the preferred choice of business and vacation travelers seeking the high-end accommodations and professional services that you would expect from a quality New York City hotel. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_exterior2_2_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Exterior 1 
 Exterior 
 Hampton Inn Manhattan Times Square North features an array of complimentary amenities and services to ensure your stay in the Big Apple is fun, affordable and hassle-free. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_entrance2_3_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Interior Entrance 2 
 Rooms&amp;Suites 
 Check-in time at the Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North is 3pm and check-out is 12 noon. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_frontdesk2_4_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Front Desk 3 
 Rooms&amp;Suites 
 Complimentary wireless Internet access and complimentary USA Today (Monday through Friday) are both available in the hotel lobby. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_lobbydesk2_5_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Reception 4 
 Rooms&amp;Suites 
 Hampton Inn Manhattan Times Square North has a full-service concierge and theater ticket desk in the lobby. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_concierge2_6_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Concierge Desk 5 
 Rooms&amp;Suites 
 The hotel has 300 oversized guest rooms (including 150 rooms with two queen beds) with luxurious details and traditional furnishings reminiscent of the style, elegance and sophistication of New York City. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_twoqueens1_7_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Two Queens Bedroom 6 
 Rooms&amp;Suites 
 Guestrooms feature one King or two queen beds and are the largest guestrooms of any Hampton Inn in New York City. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_twoqueens2_8_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Two Queen Beds 7 
 Rooms&amp;Suites 
 In-room amenities include 32-inch flat screen television and easy to operate alarm clock/radio. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_twoqnbedsng2_9_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - 2 Queen Beds 8 
 Rooms&amp;Suites 
 All guestrooms feature business amenities including large work desk and chair, plus a lap-desk for your comfort. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_doublequeen2_10_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Double Queen Beds 9 
 Rooms&amp;Suites 
 Complimentary high-speed wireless Internet access, complimentary local telephone calls and complimentary long-distance access when using a calling card–is provided in all guestrooms. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_kingbedroom_11_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - King Bedroom 10 
 Rooms&amp;Suites 
 Cloud Nine, the Hampton Bed Experience - is found in each guestroom. The upscale bedding package includes plush down-like comforter, crisp white duvet, 500 thread sheets and signature pillows. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_kingstandard_12_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - King Standard 11 
 Rooms&amp;Suites 
 Hampton Inn Manhattan Times Square North has spacious guestroom bathrooms, newly renovated with upscale bath amenities. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_bathroomng2_13_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Bathroom 12 
 Rooms&amp;Suites 
 Hampton Inn Manhattan Times Square North has accessible rooms with king beds, 2 double beds and 2 queen beds. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_accessbath_14_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Accessible Bathroom 13 
 Rooms&amp;Suites 
 The hotel&apos;s fitness center is complimentary, and available 24-hours per day. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_fitness_32_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Fitness Center 14 
 Amenities 
 /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_giftshop_28_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Gift Shop 15 
 Amenities 
 Hampton Inn Manhattan Times Square is located steps from Broadway theaters, Restaurant Row, and the best Times Square has to offer. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_sign_17_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Broadway 16 
 Amenities 
 We are located just five blocks from Central Park. Guests just make a left outside of the entrance, and can be at the world&apos;s most famous park in minutes! /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_park_37_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Central Park 17 
 Amenities 
 Walking distance to Rockefeller Center, Radio City Music Hall, and NBC Studios, the hotel is convenient to most Midtown attractions. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_flags_38_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Rockefeller Center 18 
 Amenities 
 Enjoy the performing arts at Lincoln Center or Carnegie Hall, both venues are walking distance from Hampton Inn Manhattan Times Square. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_lincoln_21_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Lincoln Center 19 
 Amenities 
 Hampton Inn Manhattan Times Square North has two COMPLIMENTARY computer kiosks for guests use - located in the lobby. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_center_21_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Computer Kiosks 20 
 Amenities 
 Hampton Inn Manhattan Times Square North&apos;s breakfast room is conveniently located in the hotel lobby, so families and business travelers can quickly dine before heading out on the town. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_breakfastroom01_23_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Breakfast Room 21 
 Dining 
 Choose from a variety of delicious breakfast items, including freshly made waffles, hearty oatmeal with toppings (offerings vary daily), and enjoy all the juice or coffee you can drink. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_breakfastroom03_24_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Breakfast Room 22 
 Dining 
 Complimentary On the Run Breakfast Bags™are available from the front desk, Monday–Friday. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_breakfastroom02_25_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Breakfast Room 23 
 Dining 
 Hampton Inn Manhattan Times Square North offers fresh coffee and tea in the lobby, 24-hours per day. /resources/media/hp/NYCMTHX/en_US/img/shared/full_page_image_gallery/main/HX_coffeebar_23_425x303_FitToBoxSmallDimension_Center.jpg Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North Hotel, NY - Coffe Bar 24 
 Dining 
 
 
 Skip secondary navigation 

 At A Glance Hotel Details Maps&amp;Directions Rooms&amp;Suites Plan An Event Special Offers Dining Things To Do 
   
At A Glance
 

Explore the best that New York City has to offer at Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North


Stay in the heart of Midtown at the Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North hotel, conveniently located on Eighth Avenue at 51st Street. Walk from our contemporary hotel to attractions such as Broadway theaters, Times Square, Central Park, Restaurant Row, Carnegie Hall, Rockefeller Center, museums and shops. The hotel is also convenient to Jacob Javits Convention Center. Take advantage of easy access to all major public transportation, including the Port Authority Bus Terminal, to get around New York City.



Enjoy many modern and complimentary amenities at the Hampton Inn Manhattan-Times Square North hotel. Savor a complimentary hot breakfast. Get to work in the complimentary business center or work out in our complimentary fitness center. Stay connected to your office, friends and family using complimentary internet access. Enjoy these and other thoughtful amenities at this Manhattan hotel.

 
About The Hotel
 
Hotel Facts
 

 Modern hotel with many complimentary amenities Best Times Square location, steps from Broadway theaters 300 oversized guest rooms, featuring signature bedding and a 32-inch flat-screen television Full-service Concierge desk 

 Rooms&amp;Suites 
Included in Every Stay
 

 Hampton&apos;s free hot breakfast Complimentary fitness center Complimentary business center Complimentary internet access 

 Amenities 
 Share Print 
 
 
   
 Skip to top of page 
 
 Hilton HHonors Worldwide Waldorf Astoria Collection The luxury brand offering a unique service experience and world’s landmark hotels. Conrad Hotels&amp;Resorts A world of style, service and connection for today’s sophisticated traveler Hilton Hotels The global leader in hospitality with more than 540 hotels&amp;resorts across six continents. DoubleTree Warm. Comfortable. Smart. The hotel that turns travel into a human experience again. Embassy Suites Enjoy a complimentary cooked-to-order breakfast and more at our upscale all-suite hotels. Hilton Garden Inn Treat yourself with amenities that help you work smarter, eat well, sleep deeply and stay fit. HamptonInn Count on Hampton to deliver quality, value, consistency and service with a smile. Homewood Suites Whether you&apos;re traveling for a few nights or for a few months, you can Make Yourself at Home® Home2 Suites Introducing Home2 Suites by Hilton®-- an all-suite brand of extended stay hotels. Hilton Grand Vacations Enjoy all of the benefits of
owning your own vacation home–with none of the
hassles. About our brands 
 
 Global Sites: 

 Germany Japan United Kingdom 
 
 About Hampton Site Map Hilton Worldwide Careers Development Media RoomKey.com Customer Support 1-800-HAMPTON Privacy Policy (Updated Dec 2011) Site Usage Agreement ©2012 Hilton Worldwide
	</body>
</document>
