<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<document id="doc0003674" url="http://www.luuux.com/food/white-chocolate-brownie-recipe" time="2012-07-12-19:50" support="1" score="0.0005886400974260737" bingtitle="White Chocolate Brownie Recipe | LUUUX - LUUUX Add - Earn - Spend" webtitle="White Chocolate Brownie Recipe | LUUUX">
			<query id="000680" bing-rank="135"/>
	<description>Sport &amp; Fitness; Entertainment; Places; Food; Community ... birthday and we basically went to every fast food restaurant in ... 2 2/3 cups all-purpose flour 2 1/2 teaspoons baking ...</description>
	<body>
		Login Join Now! Log In or Sign Up to LUUUX.
 Click here to learn more. Click Here To Learn More. 
 Luuux 
 
 All Fashion Technology Health&amp;Beauty Design Sport&amp;Fitness Entertainment Places Food Community Shop 
 Home ›› Food ›› White Chocolate Brownie Recipe 
 Food »White Chocolate Brownie Recipe
 
Last weekend it was a friend of mine&apos;s birthday and we basically went to every fast food restaurant in town and our last stop was for dessert and I mentioned how they had an awesome dessert (the white chocolate brownie) and so we went there. I remember I would always tell my friends about it and they wouldn&apos;t understand why I&apos;m so passionate about it when I talk about it. LOL. But, when they tried it they understood why.... And you will too :)
xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx
 By sarah farah  |  June 9, 2011 |  Follow sarah farah Report 
 If you feel this post is incorrect or infringing on the rights of another person or organization, please click the &quot;Report&quot; link 
 22   likes Select rating Like It   Log in or Sign up Share Share on Tumblr Share it anywhere and earn Luuux$ 
GET A LUUUX SHARELINK
 Drop the link to your post on your Blog, YouTube, or Twitter Feed, Facebook wall or anywhere on the Internet and earn Luuux$ for clicks. You\&apos;ll even earn extra for anyone who signs up and becomes a member after clicking your ShareLink. Get embed code for the Luuux button Get text link Tags: Brownie  • White Chocolate 
More Food posts

 Nautical Cupcakes BurgerKing Whoppers! Big Strawberry Small… Summer Treats! All You Can Eat Sushi:… Kiwi Strawberry Snapple $5 off Godiva Frozen Grapes Tom&apos;s Coney Island Novo Compal Melancia… CHCOLATE CHCOLATE… Homemade Burgers for… FRUIT FOR DESSERT Vegan Brownies! Dunkin Donuts Turkey Pot Pie! Yuumm Naked Juice Linner of the Day:… Lunch - Oxtail&amp;… I Baked: Mini Chocolate… 
 
Comments (22)
 Joanaa . : 
looks good! :D
 June 11, 2011 - 02:00 
 Abuse 
 LoveLover A : 
so yummy
 June 10, 2011 - 17:23 
 Abuse 
 Faye Faye : 
tHIS LOOK yummy
 June 10, 2011 - 09:43 
 Abuse 
 Qing Z : 
i tried this at moxie&apos;s and it was delish
 June 10, 2011 - 06:50 
 Abuse 
 My V. : 
that looks good
 June 10, 2011 - 03:25 
 Abuse 
 sarah farah : 
Marissa Parks:
Just posted it up!!
 June 10, 2011 - 03:10 
 Abuse 
 sarah farah : 
Marissa Parks:
sorry about that, I just posted it up right now!
xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx
 June 10, 2011 - 03:07 
 Abuse 
 sarah farah : 
Moxie&apos;s White Chocolate Brownie

2 2/3 cups all-purpose flour
2 1/2 teaspoons baking powder
1/2 teaspoon salt
2/3 cup butter
2 1/2 cups packed brown sugar
3 eggs
1 cup chopped walnuts
1 cup semisweet chocolate chips

Preheat oven to 350 degrees F (175 degrees C). Grease a 15 x 10 x 1 inch baking pan.

Sift flour, baking powder and salt together, and set aside. Using a large pan, melt the butter and stir in the brown sugar. Let this cool for about 10 minutes and then add the eggs one at a time. Be sure to beat well after adding each egg. Add the flour mixture, the nuts and the chocolate chips and blend well. Spread in the greased pan.

Bake 25 to 30 minutes in the preheated oven or until the edges begin to pull away from the sides. Cut into small squares when cool.

**Garnish with Vanilla Ice Cream, Whipped Cream and Chocolate/Fudge sauce
 June 10, 2011 - 03:06 
 Abuse 
 Susanna F. : 
That looks delicious, I&apos;ve never had a white chocolate brownie before.
 June 10, 2011 - 02:54 
 Abuse 
 STEPHANIE B : 
omg that looks so yummyyyyy
 June 10, 2011 - 01:26 
 Abuse 
 Emily Chan : 
wow, looks gooood
 June 10, 2011 - 01:17 
 Abuse 
 Catia M : 
Looks delicious.
 June 10, 2011 - 01:12 
 Abuse 
 YY D : 
Looks yummy!
 June 10, 2011 - 00:48 
 Abuse 
 Michelle&lt;33 : 
that looks so good!
 June 10, 2011 - 00:46 
 Abuse 
 Sam ... : 
omg looks so yummy
 June 10, 2011 - 00:45 
 Abuse 
 D. Ning : 
oh so yummy!
 June 10, 2011 - 00:27 
 Abuse 
 Vyvie Cupcakes : 
looks good !
 June 9, 2011 - 23:57 
 Abuse 
 Ginger :) : 
you didn&apos;t give a recipe...
or even where you bought this,
that would be nice :)
 June 9, 2011 - 23:41 
 Abuse 
 João Pereira : 
Looks so tasty!
 June 9, 2011 - 23:39 
 Abuse 
 Whitney Hiner : 
It looks great but..where&apos;s the recipe?
 June 9, 2011 - 23:15 
 Abuse 
 T W. : 
OMG SO YUMMYYY LOOKING!!
 June 9, 2011 - 22:42 
 Abuse 
 iris villena : 
looks good! yummy!
 June 9, 2011 - 22:27 
 Abuse 
 
Popular posts

 
 Lilly Mae&apos;s Cinnamon… 

There is this little place on Cannery Row in Monterey called Lilly Mae&apos;s Cinnamon ...
 
 HUGE late lunch 

my friend and i met up for a really late lunch and we were both starving... leave ...
 
 Rolled Tacos w/ Cheese… 

During my lunch break, I went to a small family owned Mexican taco shop and ordere...
 
 Mango Sushi Roll 

I tried this new sushi roll awhile back and it was sooo good! This is a summer rol...
 
 Homemade Chicken&amp;amp;… 

I had posted, well over a year ago, about chicken and dumplin&apos;s that my mom makes ...
 
 SnackOTD: Cheetos… 

I just had to have my two favorite snacks in the whole world: Cheetos Jalapeno Che...
 
 
Posted by
 sarah farah Female 19 from brampton, Canada Add as friend | Follow 
 
 
Popular posts

 
 DessertOTD: Dole… 

If you&apos;ve been to Disneyland in California, then you know that there&apos;s a huge thin...
 
 LOTD: Korean Pork +… 

Was really craving for some Korean food today so I went to one of my favorite Kore...
 
 Berry Smoothie to Start… 

A smoothie in the morning is such a good way to start the day! I had this berry s...
 
 California rolls! AGAIN… 

My guilty guilty pleasure. I just had to get some california rolls after the gym. ...
 
 Ultimate Breakfast… 

Sometimes I really don&apos;t feel like cooking breakfast and I end up going to Cora&apos;s ...
 
 Homemade Taco Soup 

A few night back I made some really delicious taco soup. Hear me out before you t...
 
 ©2011 Luuux 
Footer
 
 About Press Advertising Jobs Help Privacy Copyright Policy Site Terms Shop Terms Delivery Info
	</body>
</document>
